Scott: It's Thursday April 10th.
Rym: I'm Scott.
Scott: I'm Rym, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Scott: What if we were supervillains of evil?
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: What a lovely day.
Scott: I don't think that's got to stop right now But it was a lovely day No, wasn't?
Scott: it was just nice out.
Scott: It was love.
Rym: It was beautiful.
Rym: I took like an hour wasn't?
Rym: Love?
Rym: what a lovely time.
Rym: Sun is singing the birds are shining.
Scott: No, it wasn't that no.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: It was.
Rym: it was so nice out.
Rym: I went I had lunch in Bryant Park, and there were.
Rym: there were at least like 3,000 people just crammed 3,000 and there was this sea of people everywhere and the streets were full.
Rym: you couldn't even walk past Bryant Park.
Rym: It was great.
Rym: All right It was a nice day.
Rym: What do you want?
Rym: I went running?
Rym: Yeah, you don't go outside you don't?
Scott: I Went outside.
Scott: It was nice.
Scott: Ah, and that it's not an excuse to make all sorts of annoying noises.
Rym: It was a really nice day.
Scott: Yeah Is that all you got?
Scott: Yeah, it's not very exciting.
Rym: It's exciting to me.
Rym: A nice day is something to be treasured.
Scott: Now you're gonna have like a billion nice days, and you know what each one of them is amazing.
Scott: No, not really They're all the same.
Scott: Okay, just better than the bad days.
Rym: Okay Yeah, well then do your news if you know if you're just gonna be there.
Scott: Do we don't have anything else to say.
Scott: that was that was pretty late.
Scott: You told me you had like a quality opening bit that I didn't.
Rym: I said I'll start Because you didn't seem to have anything.
Scott: All I had was the fact that I did a bunch of work at work, which is incredibly unusual.
Rym: I mean the only kind of thing I can talk about since you don't want to hear about what a lovely day Stop saying that.
Scott: Yeah It's a little bit annoying was that it was funny.
Scott: I'm sure people have already stopped listening.
Rym: So I ended up talking to the conductor because I've noticed something pretty much every day the trains that come to beacon.
Rym: They're there one train car longer than the platform.
Rym: because so many people come up this way.
Rym: Yeah, like more people that could fit on the trains.
Rym: They originally expected so.
Rym: the front car Never opened.
Rym: the doors do not open.
Rym: they announced this multiple times on every train but that car will not open at any of those stops.
Rym: and despite this Every single day people like I get off the train.
Rym: I try to get off the train like two stops before beacon people start lining up and lining up to get out near the front of the train and Every day I like I. one day by accident I sat in the front front car partly because I was in no hurry and pretty much everyone in that car was getting off in beacon and they all stood up and they stood up and waited in line to get out of the car like two stops before and It took them so long to get off because they had to walk all the way back and get off in the next car.
Rym: That people who were sitting one or two cars back were already like at their cars before those people even got off.
Rym: Yeah, but those people who and I heard him complain is why I sit in the second car as do I and as do all Smart people or possibly the third car.
Scott: of course I sat in the second car not today But yesterday and so I don't know what was going on, but it was so bumpy I couldn't even use my laptop like it was.
Scott: it was like this incredible like crazy shaking going on Like all the people around were laughing, but I wasn't laughing cuz I couldn't do anything.
Rym: I could have been read because the book was shaking, but I was thinking all right It's the same people every day who sit in that front car And then it takes them like five minutes to get off the stupid train.
Rym: this train stuck there forever because everyone else is off but the people from that front car walking back and I was sitting next to a conductor and I brought it up.
Rym: I was like hey, so what's the deal with those people?
Rym: and he looks at me and he goes You realize how Me and many meetings we have trying to figure out what to do with these people who just don't get how to get out and off trains.
Rym: And apparently and he's even like we've tried announcing That's why we started announcing for the longest time the front car doesn't get off But the same people sit there every day And then the same people
Scott: maybe instead of just saying the doors in the front car won't open They should say if you're in the front car You should probably think about you know moving back to one of the other cars
Rym: that he's tried it.
Rym: They've brought it up.
Rym: He's actually like said to people in the front car You know if you sat in another car you'd actually be off the train and off the platform faster than if you're sitting in this front car.
Rym: and He pretty much said that usually they get all indignant.
Rym: or how dare you tell me where to sit on the train?
Rym: But apparently the issue of people not thinking about where they sit on the train and then complaining about the train Despite the fact that all they have to do is sit somewhere else and the problem goes away.
Scott: You don't have to sit somewhere else.
Scott: you can sit in the front car But instead of lining up at the door of the first car like the only one that opens Walk back a few cars and then go in line.
Rym: You can't because all the people in the second car are lined up facing that car to get off in the same door.
Scott: Yes, that's another problem.
Scott: is the people lining up to get off the train.
Rym: The funniest thing is when you get to Grand Central There's always people like the.
Rym: I'm saying I'm sitting near the back of a car.
Rym: people will line up Facing forward all the way to the back of the car and wait to get to the front of the car and get off.
Rym: Meanwhile, I just walked backward like four seats get off the back of the car Yeah, and then I walk and I see those people waiting in line inside the cars.
Rym: I walk past them.
Rym: yeah, I don't get it, but Apparently the conductors on all these trains like notice this every day and it bothers them immensely.
Rym: I'm sure it must so I no longer feel about it.
Rym: Now.
Rym: I just laugh.
Rym: Yeah and sit in the second car.
Scott: I empathize with the conductor though.
Rym: I did something crazy three days ago.
Rym: I actually as an alarm because I was sitting in the back of the train to get off on the other side I got up four stops before beacon and stood in the vestibule To be the first one off the train right next to the way to get out.
Rym: Yeah, and one there was already someone waiting there.
Scott: Well, how do you sure it wasn't?
Scott: someone just didn't want to sit because I noticed a lot of people.
Scott: They'll stand in the vestibule like the whole ride just because they don't want to sit anywhere.
Scott: Maybe they're too lazy to go.
Scott: look It's weird because like I'll go like when I get on the 509 train, right?
Scott: I'll get on the 509 train at like 10 to 5 5 to 5 something like that, right and In the back cars of the train, there'll be people sitting on the floor The people standing in the in the doorway, right?
Scott: And I just walk all the way up to the first and second car and there are seats.
Scott: and I'm like Are they just so lazy to walk the distance of the train?
Scott: They have plenty of time to do it To get a seat that they just did rather just sit in the back car.
Rym: I think they don't like sitting next to people and they just sit on the floor.
Rym: A lot of people get real uncomfortable now that I'm doing my sit in the middle of a three-seater.
Rym: A lot of people get real uncomfortable and I usually get a three-seater to myself.
Rym: Yeah, I've been doing this every.
Rym: it's it's it's kind of mean but it's funny Because they have the right to sit next to me and I'm not.
Rym: I'm taking up not even a full seat because I'm much narrower Than one train seat.
Rym: Yeah, but people just can't deal with it and they they freak out and then they leave me alone and then I have the whole thing to myself.
Rym: Anyway, I don't I don't want to keep talking about the the intricacies of seating on Metro North trains.
Rym: So now Scott now I've noticed if I have a nice happy optimistic like yay.
Rym: What a great day.
Scott: It wasn't the fact that it was yay.
Scott: What a great day is that.
Scott: in fact you did an annoying voice.
Rym: I don't think it was that annoying.
Rym: It's pretty annoying.
Scott: It's pretty annoying.
Scott: The Sun is singing the birds are shining and you're being loud and it's kind of painful.
Rym: Anyway, okay.
Rym: So what do you have in the news captain Scott?
Scott: Well, you know, we don't watch the television.
Scott: Right, no cable.
Scott: No antenna.
Scott: No, no satellites.
Scott: No nothing.
Rym: Well, I watch DVDs.
Scott: Yeah, but that's not television.
Rym: Well, I watch it on the television and I watch television shows But that isn't television.
Scott: television requires the teller in addition to the vision.
Scott: You're just.
Scott: you're sort of watching things that could be Delivered by television, but you're watching them with just the vision.
Rym: So if I use a TiVo and timeshift if is it still television?
Rym: No, okay, because you're not watching it via the teller But you are just time shifted.
Rym: it came in by the teller if that doesn't matter.
Rym: So what matters?
Rym: what's the line?
Scott: The live broad whatever.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: I'm curious.
Scott: The point is we don't watch the television if we don't listen to the radio except sometimes in the car, but rarely right.
Rym: I haven't you know, what actually?
Rym: I took the antenna out of my car a long time ago So I can't listen to the radio in the car.
Rym: Yeah Cuz that it makes my RF transmitter work a thousand times better.
Scott: Yeah, I have the wire so I don't need to do that but anyway.
Scott: So if there's like an emergency like emergency broadcast system emergency Like I don't know a tornado warning or you know, that doesn't happen here often, but it could it could happen.
Rym: Um, yeah, I don't.
Scott: actually now that I think about go on or or maybe uh, you know Something else like that happens, right?
Rym: Cuz there's there's one.
Rym: I have a really important anecdote.
Scott: But anyway, yeah, then we Really despite our being high-tech and fancy we won't find out because the emergency broadcast system is pretty much radio and TV and It's based on the assumption that you're going to either have a radio or a TV on pretty soon.
Rym: I mean, I remember at RIT when the September 11th attacks happened.
Rym: There was no way any of us would have found out at all until we went and checked the news but because we were all in college and because the odds of at least a Quarter to half of the front row crew being online Actively using the internet at any given point in the day 24/7 seven days a week Like if the odds were pretty much a hundred percent that someone was online like actively searching and surfing whatever.
Rym: So pretty much we had our own FRC emergency broadcast system.
Scott: I mean for something like that.
Scott: It'll work out like.
Scott: I got an I am that told me to turn on the TV and we had TV at RIT Cuz.
Scott: they had free cable in the apartment, but you know if something happens like I use my tornado warning example No one in the front row crew is gonna find out about that and be able to tell us because they don't have radio or TV either.
Scott: and it's a local problem not a huge problem that you're gonna find out about.
Scott: like, you know Our friends in Albany aren't gonna find out about the beacon tornado warning on the internet.
Rym: Yeah, there's not get.
Rym: a FARC is not gonna say tornado coming in beacon.
Rym: FARC is going to say tornado destroyed beacon.
Scott: Yes, exactly.
Scott: So where it's sort of kind of, you know, whenever there's like a big storm or something I'll always go to like, you know, always go to like weather websites just to make sure you know Cuz like.
Rym: well the weather example is interesting because the one that's actually the thing I care about the least even though I mean I grew up in Michigan, which is pretty much one of the most tornado in states There is.
Rym: there are a lot of tornadoes.
Rym: We get tornadoes came frequently to the point that you hear a tornado warning you go up tornado.
Rym: Ah Sometimes we'd go watch him.
Rym: It was great fun.
Rym: But one because there were tornadoes.
Rym: in danger of tornadoes, you know every town There's always like the air raid siren or the loud siren that can.
Rym: it seems like out here Because it seems like they go off kind of randomly and whenever I hear it go off I think tornado.
Rym: Because in Michigan it goes off once a month to test and otherwise it goes off when there's a tornado warning.
Rym: So there's no way you can miss the fact that there's a tornado in the area.
Rym: Mmm, but around here They don't seem to do that.
Rym: So what's the point of the stupid siren?
Scott: They use them here for like fires and they.
Rym: that doesn't help me.
Scott: It helps the volunteer fire department pagers.
Scott: They might not have the pager on.
Rym: Yes, they do.
Rym: I know volunteer firemen always carry their pager.
Rym: They want that pager to go off, you know how awesome it is when that pager goes off.
Scott: They also.
Scott: they also use it in case the nuclear power plant has a problem.
Rym: That's a different one.
Rym: I remember we had there's one siren that's like And then there's this other siren that's like in the distance and I never knew what that other one was.
Rym: then we found out That's Indian point.
Rym: Yeah, if Indian point blows up.
Rym: We'll hear.
Scott: Anyway, of course, no one will know what it is, right?
Scott: We will tell the emergency broadcast system turns up anyway You know what?
Rym: That is that's the.
Rym: well, let's start driving north alarm.
Rym: So
Scott: this is really you know, and it's funny, you know that as connected as we are probably the you know, the most important thing we don't get and it's because Being so connected and smart we pull our information, you know We don't have people pushing information at us that we don't want.
Scott: we go and handpick what we want But by hand picking there we're gonna miss something.
Rym: It's also kind of that we only connect to.
Rym: I guess usable or you know, well put together information sources.
Rym: so the same problem here is also why we don't often have a lot of Knowledge about local events because there's no modern way to find out about local events and it's not worth the effort To use the old archaic methods like the terrible local papers we have right
Scott: but something Like an emergency broadcast you.
Scott: the goal is to push that to everyone and it makes sense because everyone wants it.
Scott: No, there's no one who doesn't want the emergency broadcast Right.
Scott: So what do we do?
Scott: and Surprise surprise of all things.
Scott: It's amazing.
Scott: the government the federal government the United States specifically the FCC Which is stupid in so many ways Actually has a smart answer and they're gonna make it happen.
Scott: I can't believe it.
Scott: It's tax dollars doing right.
Rym: See, this is why we are libertarians with a lower fucking case L. Yeah lowercase.
Rym: That's very yeah.
Scott: This is not police or courts or defense Alright, this is something else.
Scott: But you know those crazy libertarians would say, you know This is the kind of thing that they wouldn't budget for.
Rym: you want a school.
Rym: you'll pay for your own goddamn school, right?
Scott: Anyway, yeah, if you don't have the school, how are the people gonna understand the emergency broadcast?
Scott: Basically what they're gonna do is they're gonna have a thing where They send out SMS messages on your cell phone where there's an emergency.
Rym: That's brilliant because Everyone has a cell phone.
Scott: Yeah Pretty mighty.
Scott: well least anyone who doesn't watch TV and doesn't listen to the radio has a cell phone Pretty much.
Rym: the only exception are homeless people who well homeless people and Luddites are screwed anyway.
Rym: That's what I was gonna say.
Scott: nothing.
Rym: not homeless people hobos because there's a difference between I mean homeless person is a large category and then independent of homeless person There's the transiently homeless and then there are hobos and then there are bombs.
Rym: all the different but anyway.
Scott: but anyway the point is is that it really depends on how this is implemented how quality it is.
Scott: because I mean Like if they go by say area code, right?
Scott: I'm gonna get emergencies for like Connecticut and I'm gonna get emergencies for Poughkeepsie, right?
Scott: That's not so good.
Scott: We want the beacon ones.
Scott: if they go by GPS, which is what they should do then this could be awesome.
Rym: That without that makes it like the best thing ever.
Rym: cuz.
Rym: then if I'm on a business trip in in Florida and Florida is about to blow up.
Rym: I'll get a hurricane.
Scott: You'll get an SMS while you're in Florida saying hurricane get the hell out of Florida with hurricanes You know, they're coming a long time in advance I know I know.
Scott: but plus the other thing about you know The SMS is you can actually give detailed Instructions that are sort of written down that people can look at and read and look at and read again.
Scott: So they won't mess them up and say, you know having to write down You know what the emergency broadcast on the radio is saying, you know or write down where the TV is saying or cop.
Scott: You know, you'll have it and you'll be able to take the information with you.
Scott: So as you're evacuating you can read the evacuation directions on the phone that came in the SMS message.
Rym: No, the thing is though the example about weather doesn't really I can't say I care about that.
Scott: No, I'm just saying weather is the really good example because it's something that's localized.
Rym: Yeah but at the same time I just want to point out that for the majority of the United States where There is a possibility of tornadoes and dangerous weather like that.
Rym: It's actually The conditions are very specific and you can pretty much.
Rym: I'd like to do a little.
Rym: maybe I'll do a little like quick.
Scott: You can tell when they're coming without a brush.
Rym: You can know pretty much all day if it's a tornado day and you'll know long before a tornado comes if tornadoes are coming.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, but I think this is a really good idea.
Scott: It would make.
Scott: it makes me pretty happy to know that you know.
Scott: sometime in the future I won't have to worry about.
Scott: I wonder if there's an emergency broadcast and I'm missing it because I'm too high.
Rym: the worst thing is whenever like Whenever there's a problem like the internet goes down or on my cell phone Stop working like the power goes out and doesn't come back on right away.
Rym: We are we always look at each other and go is There's something going on?
Rym: because there's no way for us to know?
Scott: it's knowing for us to know no way at all.
Scott: But now they'll be like for us to know.
Rym: remember the great Northeast power outage.
Rym: Remember?
Rym: I called Scott on my cell phone and I was like, yeah.
Rym: Oh my god I'm an IBM the powers using the landline phone in Connecticut.
Rym: Oh, yeah I forget exactly what the conversation is like.
Rym: Hey is the power out where you are?
Rym: Hahaha, and then Scott was like, yeah Yeah, I was like, uh Really?
Rym: powers out here - shit.
Rym: And my co-workers are like what's going on?
Rym: Oh shit in the factory is going berserk because you know, it's a factory that suddenly lost power.
Scott: Just got home.
Scott: I did generators at the factory.
Rym: Yes, but this It was crazy.
Rym: I'll put it that way.
Scott: Anyway, so you got a news over there.
Rym: I got a news.
Rym: indeed This is something that I have very very conflicted feelings about not just this news But the issue in general.
Rym: and of course, I want to point out that this Like most things that I am interested in Involves my favorite US Circuit Court of Appeals number nine number nine Number nine.
Rym: the ninth US Circuit Court of Appeals.
Scott: to take that, you know, that's long love potion number nine.
Scott: We should remix it to be like, oh, oh, oh number nine Anyway, that wrong song.
Rym: I know I was thinking like table five though different thing cuz.
Rym: it's also funny.
Scott: You didn't even sound right.
Rym: I can't sing.
Scott: It's gotta be like oh, oh, oh, oh table nine table nine.
Scott: I was like that.
Rym: you gave me crap when I tried to sing.
Rym: those were the days.
Rym: So I guess you can't really expect anything better.
Rym: But the Ninth Circuit Court of Appeals in the US is pretty much the most overturned court in the world.
Scott: It's in San Francisco.
Scott: It's a bunch of hippies.
Scott: They basically say yeah, that's on the constitutional Whatever they don't like and then it always gets sent to a higher court that says all right or no?
Scott: No, you crazy thing.
Rym: is this courts important?
Scott: because it is important.
Rym: They're the court that kind of.
Rym: they're almost a bellwether in some ways and a lot of times an issue that otherwise is just set In stone, they'll be the ones who instigate kind of a reevaluation of the situation.
Scott: Yeah, I also think that there are a lot of people like when they have a case, you know Like they'll purposely file their case where they know they'll get to this court, you know when it's in when it's like a constitutional issue They want to make.
Rym: but I'm this is a very short AP wire thing.
Rym: I'm just gonna read it verbatim and then we can discuss it.
Rym: All right quote a federal appeals court in San Francisco.
Rym: Whatever an article starts that way I go.
Rym: Oh man here comes overturned.
Rym: What a law says that a website can be found liable for violating fair housing laws by matching Roommates according to gender sexual orientation and whether or not they have children.
Rym: Well on Thursday the 9th US Circuit Court of Appeals Decided that roommates.com could be brought to trial for possibly violating Anti-discrimination laws because it asks users to give detailed information to screen participants for matches.
Rym: The court says federal law protecting websites quotes was not meant to create a lawless no-man's land on the internet end quote.
Rym: The ruling deals a major blow to the immunity shield that federal law is provided to the Internet.
Scott: Well, I have to read the opinion of the court to know I'm not even gonna talk about.
Scott: the court know what their law basis.
Rym: There are federal laws that basically say if you're like the Fair Housing Act and all these things if you were Advertising housing you cannot advertise based on certain requirements Yep, and if you are like seeking housing for other people, you cannot allow them to give you certain parameters.
Rym: to look yep, and I Don't know.
Rym: I mean, I still don't know how I feel about these things because on one hand Obviously, there are very important applications for this.
Rym: you I don't think you should be able to have a website or have a realtor where you can say All right.
Rym: I want to rent my house out, but no blackies.
Rym: No, no whitey's no brownies.
Scott: No, yellowy's no orangey's only greenies.
Rym: but at the same time Say I live in New York City and I have a one bedroom or a studio apartment and I need a roommate.
Rym: I Don't feel comfortable just having some guy I don't know live with me.
Rym: I think it should be okay for me to advertise or just another woman
Scott: or what if I am a Crazy Hasidic Jew, right, you know, even if I wouldn't mind, you know Like living with some you know, non type of you know, Hasidic Jew at least in principle, you know Like.
Scott: there would be serious problems if like they were messing up my kosher action.
Scott: So should you know.
Scott: but I need a roommate because I can't afford to live there.
Rym: while you can have these Anti-discrimination things in place to you know prevent people from screening.
Rym: you can't second-guess someone's motivation And if I just happen to only let the one woman who applies be my roommate and I reject the other hundred men And I don't say anything How are they gonna prove that I was?
Rym: Violating this?
Scott: I mean it had lots of lawyers.
Rym: But I guess in the end I feel like if I if someone wants to find a roommate that in the end they should be able to for their own personal personal space.
Rym: They can pretty much decide based on whatever parameters they want.
Rym: Yeah, and even though this allows a lot of people to be racist or homophobic or horrible in all sorts of ways at the same time It's I mean you're gonna force the the KKK guy to move in with the black guy.
Scott: That's not gonna work out.
Scott: He probably wouldn't I know but I'm saying it's like you're good.
Rym: But I guess I in this specific case.
Rym: I feel like a site like roommates calm.
Rym: I almost feel like they should allow you to look at like.
Rym: if you put in the information It should be optional.
Rym: you could say I would like to put in this information or not and it should be optional.
Rym: I would like to search for this information or not, but like kids say I'm but then again There's also discrimination about say I have it out.
Rym: I rent out a little house Alright, what if I don't want the gays to move in?
Rym: so I say only available to families now that could be discriminatory.
Rym: But at the same time what if I don't want loud punk kids to live?
Rym: it's complicated.
Scott: Yeah, if you're quiet old people and you don't want punk kids to live in there?
Scott: I mean on the one hand it's sort of like yeah, but on the other hand But I see even forget about the discrimination right forget about all the discrimination parts of this issue, okay?
Scott: What if roommates calm just move their servers to like Canada, but so the service they provide isn't you know?
Scott: It's like people from the US could go to the Canadian website, you know and fill and find housing in the US.
Scott: It's just it could be anywhere.
Rym: Well, you know what.
Rym: you know what.
Rym: that is the answer to this problem.
Scott: well, I know.
Scott: but the thing is right is the US?
Scott: Why even bother making a law that can be so easily?
Scott: Evaded it's like you know.
Scott: if you're gonna make a law, you know, even if the law is is right in principle Right.
Scott: Let's say you have a law that's right.
Scott: Well, I've got a that we agree with a hundred percent that that should be the law.
Rym: if it's not in front Well, there's no point in having the law, right?
Rym: I want to even say something further.
Rym: a law up like this at least for individuals All it does it doesn't really end discrimination.
Rym: It pushes the discrimination one step closer to the person where instead of like alright, they can't discriminate in the search They'll just discriminate in the decision instead.
Rym: It's like it doesn't really accomplish anything.
Rym: now I want to qualify all of this by saying that I think these laws are very important for say large organizations.
Rym: I feel like laws like this should not apply to individuals, but they should apply to like an apartment building.
Rym: Yeah Exactly apartment building should not be able to discriminate on pretty much anything other than we're like Yes, do you have the money you can live here?
Rym: But if I own my house Like there should be kind of for all laws like this like the ADA and everything There should be a line.
Rym: in the ADA There are lines but below which like if your company has two employees You shouldn't have to like fully comply with all these laws.
Rym: if I have a tiny like attic apartment in my house I want to rent out.
Rym: I shouldn't have to comply with these laws, but Me and rims start GeekNights the company.
Scott: Do we really need workers comp shit in case the Rym like hurts himself and falls out?
Scott: Really Me and rims started a company.
Scott: can I claim disability thus bankrupting Rym and living a life of luxury?
Rym: So, uh and no work, I guess in the end I'm conflicted about this issue on a number of levels.
Rym: but from the technological geek standpoint this law and this lawsuit are so easily circum circumvented that it like it's laughable to the point that Roommates.com Regardless of anything just move your servers to Canada.
Scott: It's like making a law that says don't look at the sky.
Scott: It's like there's no way that you can stop.
Scott: I'm not looking at the sky I'm looking at that bird, but there's no way you can enforce the law that says don't look at the sky.
Rym: So, yes, you can.
Rym: if yes, you could how good you all right?
Rym: Well, one way is you have you.
Rym: you hire a policeman to follow everyone around?
Rym: But then who watches the Watchman's you gotta have.
Rym: someone follows policemen around or you just put Gigantic Eyeball destroying lasers in the sky, but I look for eyeballs and shoot them.
Scott: Anyway, you know it stop being silly.
Rym: The point is not that silly.
Scott: I open it.
Scott: The law is don't look at the sky.
Scott: Why even if it's you know?
Scott: You really people looking at the sky is a bad thing and we all agree that people looking at the sky is a bad thing.
Scott: It's impossible to stop people.
Scott: So why waste our resources and time trying?
Rym: it's kind of like how with prohibition Don't make laws to stop people from drinking.
Rym: People are gonna drink.
Rym: people are gonna drink.
Rym: people drank completely all through prohibition before it.
Rym: after Nothing changed, but beer baron, but the laws caused a lot of problems.
Rym: So don't make the drinking illegal because that doesn't really work, but it's still illegal if you hit someone with your car.
Rym: Yep things of the day now.
Rym: the previous three days were not really cop-outs but pretty much.
Rym: this has been my thing of the day all week because I really wanted to bring this up and I figured that Since this thing is so cool in my opinion What better way than to just kind of build up to it?
Scott: Because actually I think my thing of the day today is better.
Rym: Thing of the day came out of nowhere and it's like fucking amazing.
Rym: Don't get me wrong Scott's thing of the day Fucking is made of wind, but my thing of the day is somewhat poignant.
Rym: Now all week I've been talking about this song.
Rym: those were the days that was a Super like pop success all over the world at least in the Western world And it had ties to like the birds and Paul McCartney and all these things.
Rym: It was based on this old Russian folk song.
Scott: people have heard this story three times.
Rym: Yeah, but actually a lot of people only listen to Thursday That's it.
Rym: And a lot of people only listen to Wednesday and a lot of people only listen to Tuesday.
Rym: I think you see where I'm going with this.
Rym: yeah, but the deal is it all kind of comes full circle because this song which was originally a Russian folk song and then was kind of translated into a pop a pop song and then Was kind of covered in modern eras by a Norwegian finish or die.
Rym: There was a Dutch band comes full circle and was performed kind of epically by the Leningrad cowboys Which I point out is a Finnish band was close to the Dutch band So that that's a tiny link there.
Rym: this Finnish band performed this song in conjunction With the Soviet red star red army chorus.
Rym: It's a grim favorite that that band is one of my favorite bands ever and they actually Collaborate often with the Leningrad cowboys, which is also one of my favorite bands.
Rym: So this concert This is filmed live is the red star red army chorus singing Those were the days which is a pop song that was based on a Russian folk song with the Leningrad cowboys a Finnish pop band.
Rym: That their hair is awesome.
Rym: If nothing else, they kind of have that.
Scott: they have that sort of crow Marti hair.
Scott: Oh, they're sticking out that guy from the movie the Kamikaze girls.
Rym: Oh, yeah that guy.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I heard that's like goes way forward.
Rym: I love that hair.
Rym: I love those guys.
Scott: I I like the look at that hair, but I would never have that hair.
Rym: I'd be afraid I'd like hit someone with it.
Scott: Yeah I don't know
Rym: but the thing that I find really interesting is that one is this song kind of came full circle from Russian poem to Russian folk song to popular song in the West to popular song moving back toward Europe and then finally The red star red army chorus with this like super not serious Leningrad cowboys band.
Rym: But if you look at it even further the song the gist of the song both in English and in Russian is kind of this nostalgia for the past and this kind of transition and The song being performed by these two groups Especially because this was this concert was actually not too long after The fall of the Soviet Union and the you know, the opening up at the end of the Cold War.
Rym: the song is really kind of poignant and Seeing the red star chorus performing alongside a band like this in the post-soviet world and the fact that the song Itself is so kind of meaningful.
Rym: There's a lot there.
Rym: And also this concert is fucking epic and I would have loved to have been there All right.
Scott: So check this story out right?
Scott: is one of the guys who writes for Kotaku?
Scott: He puts up a post and he's like is Transformers still good right?
Scott: and he's sort of referring to you.
Scott: We all know it.
Scott: Well, you know you like transformers as a kid You like he-man as a kid.
Scott: you go back and watch it now that you're older and you go.
Rym: Oh, it's bad.
Scott: Oh, it's bad.
Scott: So I basically said yeah Transformers it holds up better than he-man but doesn't hold up as well as Voltron and Thundercats, which is true.
Rym: Yeah, I mean as much as I like the Transformers movie.
Rym: I tried to watch it again actually Me and I think yeah God this was way back.
Rym: instead of doing work for projects like me and I do just sat and watched the Transformers movie all night in college and I can say one thing That movie is spastic and ADD and you can't even tell what's going on.
Rym: I know what's going on Yeah, but like though you can barely tell.
Scott: but anyway, you know some of the Transformers TV series kind of okay some not.
Scott: But anyway, he posted up another post that was like, yeah, it didn't hold up.
Scott: so well What was I thinking?
Scott: and in the comments of that post someone put some links to some videos and thus the thing of the day.
Scott: There's a guy named Dr.
Scott: Smoove D R S M O O V and he has the YouTube account and on his YouTube account he puts the videos and basically what he does in these videos.
Scott: what he does in these videos is he takes GI Joe and transformers primarily but also some other things.
Scott: I guess I've only watched one of these videos so far.
Scott: I'm assuming the rest are just as good and He edits them and redubs them and he actually is a really good voice actor like for a second like at first I Thought it was the original Transformers voice actors like you know having fun sort of like those Thundercats outtakes which are the Thundercats voice actors having fun.
Scott: But no he really does.
Scott: he just does a really good shockwave a really good Megatron and a really good Starscream and a really good optimus prime.
Rym: I don't think there's any way to overstate how Absolutely perfect and hilarious.
Rym: This is so he redubs.
Scott: They sort of these clips and It sort of makes more sense the original show and is actually funny and cool and awesome.
Rym: now the defining moment when Scott showed this to me was when Someone shows up, and there's there's our friend our man.
Rym: shockwave the best transform.
Scott: Let me tell you about.
Scott: let me tell you about shockwave.
Scott: right the story of Transformers in brief at least the beginning of transformers is you have these transformers They're on Cybertron.
Scott: Autobots are good decepticons are bad.
Scott: They fight, okay They leave for Earth.
Scott: released a bunch of them.
Scott: leave for Earth.
Scott: the decepticons are still sort of in charge of Cybertron, right?
Scott: So Megatron the leader of the decepticons he went to Earth all right.
Scott: He said shockwave you stay here.
Scott: You're in charge.
Scott: Shockwave is like the most powerful fucking normal-sized Transformer.
Scott: you know not counting things like Unicron and whatnot.
Scott: he turns into a laser gun.
Scott: I mean Megatron turns into like a handgun, but shockwave turns into a laser gun like the wicked laser gun.
Scott: He can like blow shit up crazy, but he's super loyal to Megatron.
Scott: So he doesn't you know fuck around Megatron was just so in confidence the opposite of Starscream like he's.
Scott: Starscream is super smart But he's an asshole.
Scott: He's super disloyal asshole.
Scott: Who's weak, but Shockwave is a super strong super smart not asshole.
Scott: Who's loyal?
Scott: and that's why he's able to rate maintain control of Cybertron for four million years.
Scott: You know what you know what.
Rym: in a way shockwave?
Rym: And and it's kind of like the Justinian Belisarius relationship, right?
Scott: But basically it's shockwave is on Cybertron bored and all Super alone for four million years plus and then suddenly like Megatron wakes up and starts taught and you know Contacts him like four million years later and whatnot.
Scott: but it's it's the video that we watch.
Rym: Shockwave answer the phone.
Rym: There's nothing to do up there.
Rym: What do you yeah?
Scott: We're watching this.
Scott: the what the one video dr.
Scott: Smoove made that was really funny with shockwaves burden.
Scott: I haven't watched the other ones yet But I must assume that they are all as awesome if not more awesome.
Rym: The uh, the defining moment for me was just when the line of don't worry shockwave can't shoot for shit.
Rym: He's like the worst shot in the world is.
Scott: but yeah, I'm gonna link you to dr Smoove's YouTube page so you can watch all his videos But the one that we actually watched so far that was the highest quality is shockwaves burden and it's funnier the more you know about Transformers.
Scott: that's why I tried to tell you the story of shockwave.
Scott: But yeah the the if you like if you have nostalgia for Transformers or GI Joe just watch these videos instead of watching the real deal and you'll be much better off.
Rym: Yes, and while the juggernaut is hilarious.
Rym: These are so much better done.
Scott: Yeah, this is better than the juggernaut bitch.
Scott: It's in the same sort of I guess camp, but it's better.
Rym: Of course We found that juggernaut bitch did not lose its A few like months ago like a month or two ago.
Scott: We watched juggernaut.
Scott: bitch Was still really funny.
Rym: Hey got you with my pimp cane.
Rym: Oh Okay Fuck is this shit?
Scott: What the fuck is this shit Charles?
Rym: Okay.
Scott: Anyway, hey miss Charles anus.
Rym: Hey, miss.
Scott: Hey, miss.
Rym: Okay, that's enough of that No more.
Scott: No more.
Rym: Whoa, okay.
Rym: so Well, this came up in the forum a while ago and I I came up with it.
Rym: yes, and you know what it generated a lot of interesting discussion and We're kind of lazy.
Rym: if you couldn't tell yesterday's show was kind of a total cop-out.
Rym: So what better way to end the week than to cop out again?
Rym: Oh, man Double cop-out double kappa.
Rym: So what are we doing the show on?
Scott: All right, what are we doing this?
Scott: I said you could decide we're doing the what if you were a blank and Rym is gonna fill in the blank.
Rym: Well, I think we're gonna have to go straight away with what would I do if I were a super villain?
Scott: Okay, I'd probably actually take over the world and no one would fuck with me.
Rym: Well, that's easy.
Rym: Yeah, but how I mean super?
Scott: well, what's my superpower?
Scott: See here's the thing.
Scott: first I got to start off right people They say superpower.
Scott: that like there was a discussion.
Scott: I read somewhere that was like what's the lamest superpower?
Scott: and I'm like If a power is lame, it's not super.
Rym: right just a power.
Rym: There's no power and you have a power.
Scott: it's like make eggs appear out of thin air.
Scott: that could be cool and useful and funny.
Scott: It's not super.
Rym: Okay, I don't know.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: you get it.
Rym: You get a million dollars for one by having it.
Rym: it is any power Includes.
Rym: get a million dollars.
Scott: any supernatural power.
Scott: I could have a natural power like what just jump five feet in the air.
Rym: Ah That logic.
Rym: everyone has a lot of powers.
Rym: They're just really really weak.
Rym: I mean look well, no, they're not weak.
Scott: They're stronger than most animals.
Scott: other animals powers.
Scott: They're just the same as every other humans power.
Rym: We have podcasting power.
Rym: I think we're only gonna count a power if it is beyond what a normal human can have.
Rym: like D&D stats I think a 17 or higher counts as a power.
Scott: Yeah Now here's the other thing which Rym brought up is that you know in comic books and things we have the superheroes and the supervillains Right.
Scott: It's generally sort of like well-defined like.
Scott: he's the good guy.
Scott: He's the bad guy.
Rym: That's what always bothers me like how come in.
Rym: a lot of this is like the especially DC Comics.
Rym: I guess though Marvel is not.
Rym: it's not like they've ever done.
Scott: They're both the same in this regard, but I feel like all right.
Rym: the superheroes they're good.
Rym: What do they do?
Rym: they fight supervillains supervillains?
Rym: They're bad.
Rym: What do they do?
Rym: and Usually it's just fucking be evil for no good goddamn reason.
Rym: just complete assholes Almost bad anime where it's like the bad guys are an evil corporation and they murder their employees and they pollute and they kill.
Rym: and why Fucking huh?
Scott: I mean you'll always get those stories, you know You always get.
Scott: some of the supervillains have a reason for what they do.
Scott: They're well-written almost like magneto You know, sometimes you'll get the story where the good the superhero goes bad or the supervillain goes good.
Scott: But it's a story where supervillain goes good or super hero goes bad.
Scott: It's like the person maintains their superhero or supervillain label and they just switch sides Temporarily or sometimes for an extended period of time.
Scott: I contend they don't lose the label.
Scott: It's like there's something about it like but in the real world that the label wouldn't exist.
Rym: That's what I was about to say.
Rym: I contend that there are no supervillains because No one who is a super blank Thinks that they're a super person.
Rym: Yes, I mean Try to think dr.
Rym: Doom Should whatever he's after he's after it because that's what the world needs.
Rym: He's the good guy in his book Yep, but well, I guess except in crappy books where someone's just a bad guy, but or where they're just crazy There's a lot of that mad scientist kind of stuff.
Rym: Yeah, that's the other thing.
Rym: I'm sick of supervillains whose plot is Complicated blah, but in the end it's just I'm depressed I want to destroy the world because fuck all of you.
Scott: It's just so overdone and lame Yep, so but I mean if I had a superpower of some sort, you know And I was and I'm gonna basically take the villain.
Scott: I'm going to interpret that as Scott's moral code goes out the window.
Scott: That's all right.
Rym: Because the other way because there's two ways to look at it Because a lot of the things we want that would probably be good would make us villains in most people's eyes.
Rym: That's true also, but I can't let's do.
Rym: we can start with no moral code right?
Scott: No moral code, you know Superpowers and whatever I want.
Rym: I hate to say it if we had no moral code.
Rym: We wouldn't even we we already have superpowers.
Rym: We'd sell a Randy things and make a pile of money.
Rym: I know the cult is so easy.
Rym: I know it'd be trivial.
Scott: I know like now a lot of it depends on what power I have, right?
Scott: So I'm basically I'm gonna consider like, you know, like two different levels of power here, right?
Scott: One level of power is like crazy super.
Scott: I can do whatever I want.
Scott: in which case I would probably like, you know Like turn the earth into a utopia for me And then I would maybe fly out into space make another utopia for me and fly around space.
Rym: I Think that's not.
Rym: even we should go a little bit lower.
Scott: We all have it lower.
Scott: Okay, so of course then again Maybe there's the altruistic.
Rym: you're a super villain, but that's just because you fuck everything up.
Rym: You know, you have all this power.
Rym: you're a demigod of some kind and you decide all right I'm going to make the world utopia and as we know from all literature it becomes a dystopia.
Rym: Yes, all utopia becomes dystopia.
Scott: Yep Okay, let's take a level of power where I'm not really flying around space.
Scott: evil super crazy.
Scott: But basically I can kill anyone and beat anyone up and but no one can touch me because I'm such a badass Death note basically Kara death note.
Scott: He's not.
Scott: I'm talking like invincible.
Scott: Like I'm Superman, but I mean, I Don't know how interesting that is.
Rym: What do you do?
Rym: What would I do if I didn't have a moral code either?
Rym: Well, I would probably just live a life of decadent luxury.
Scott: No, pretty much anyone who pissed me off.
Scott: I'd beat the shit out of them.
Rym: That's not that interest I know.
Scott: and then you know, basically the world would end up being.
Scott: you know The way I thought it would be.
Rym: I think a better way to go about this is Forget, you know toss away the moral code.
Rym: What about twisted moral code or a Moral in terms of?
Rym: you know and justifies the needs that the means supervillain we have?
Rym: So let's take goals that we might have but remove all moralistic obstacles and then give ourselves varying levels of superpower.
Scott: Okay, so one goal would be to get rid of like religion.
Scott: So I would go and I would just smash all the churches if you were Superman.
Rym: that doesn't work.
Rym: That'll just make people believe more.
Scott: Okay, then I would kill all the priests.
Rym: that probably wouldn't work.
Rym: You got to be more.
Scott: I would use my superpowers to convince them that I had killed God.
Rym: God You're like the worst supervillain.
Rym: All right, so I'm a supervillain.
Rym: Well, I'll be real generic about my powers and I want to destroy religion.
Rym: All right, what I would do is orchestrate all Ozymandias style some sort of like.
Rym: because look he runs the giant Boy.
Rym: he can do whatever he wants to do.
Rym: He's a superhero who has like every he has all the power.
Rym: He's like Batman times 10.
Rym: He's like open Batman.
Rym: It's like if Batman Bruce Wayne now, there's a spoiler turns out Batman.
Rym: But Instead of being Batman Bruce Wayne was just like, you know what?
Rym: I'm fucking Bruce Wayne.
Rym: I'll do whatever I want.
Rym: I'm Batman, but it doesn't matter.
Rym: Yeah, I don't even do Batman things privately.
Rym: I'm just Bruce Wayne.
Rym: suck it bitches.
Rym: Yeah, so I want to destroy religion, right?
Rym: I use all of my means to trick the world bit by bit into believing that the second coming is happening.
Rym: and either that me or even better if I find someone else Especially if I find a superhero who could emulate the supposed powers of the supposed of Jesus Then I would make the world believe that there's Jesus second coming and then at the moment of truth I'd reveal that it was I I'd set it up to convince everyone that God died and That was it and it was over and there was no more religion.
Scott: The thing is, you know, they did you.
Scott: the thing about Convincing people that God died is sort of like.
Scott: well, they're still believing in magical thinking.
Rym: you have to eliminate the magical thinking That in the end all magic is all Religious blah blah has been destroyed and all that's left is logic and this is the last whatever thing and I'm gonna destroy it Right now.
Scott: I see his is another question right if I get some sort of crazy powers, right?
Scott: Will I still only have my very human desires or will I gain some sort of?
Rym: Transhuman or post human thinking Doc Manhattan style?
Scott: because if I have if I still have my human desires You know, I get mad moneys mad ladies mad, you know, what famous people get, you know all that stuff, right?
Scott: Not well, if I'm immune to drugs, maybe I'll do those two, right?
Scott: But if I have some sort of post human desires and you know money and ladies and cars and mansions Well, then you become Hannibal.
Scott: don't do it for me.
Rym: Actually that that I realized something It's a transhuman very very likely becomes automatically in the eyes of Non-transhumans a supervillain quite possibly.
Rym: I mean look at Hannibal The only I mean the fundamental.
Rym: messed up.
Scott: the thing is you can be transhuman without eating people.
Scott: No, no No, you can't.
Rym: yes You can't know but but but it doesn't have to be eating people.
Rym: the idea there if you break it down Is that he is transcended all.
Rym: he's not human.
Rym: He's something different not better.
Rym: I'm not.
Rym: I mean not necessarily better or anything But just after after and as a result more powerful and His desires and wants and needs are so utterly alien and so utterly contrary.
Scott: Yeah, it's as if he's like was an alien from outer space.
Rym: I mean It's.
Rym: it's almost like if you become powerful in this way that maybe you don't intend to be a supervillain.
Rym: You just the way you perceive the world is such that the things you do are perceived by others as supervillainy.
Scott: Yeah, it's just like because you know you become something that's not human right in a way and you don't.
Scott: you no longer want the Things humans want.
Scott: your you know, the your perfect, you know.
Scott: I mean even though every human has a different idea what the perfect world is like.
Scott: There are a lot of you know common themes, but if you become something else other than human You're gonna.
Scott: maybe you won't have any common themes with that humans want.
Scott: I'm sure that like raccoons I mean their perfect world is like a pile of trash.
Scott: They don't have any common themes with what humans want, right?
Scott: So maybe you know You're.
Scott: you would just I would try to fight for whatever that was and I'd probably achieve it because I'd have great power but all the humans would be upset because My wants are nothing like their one.
Rym: instead of with great power comes great responsibility.
Rym: It's with great power comes eating people.
Scott: Well, no, I hope I wouldn't want to eat people but you might you don't know.
Rym: I might watch you become Transcendent and suddenly like oh hopefully I'm eating people is the way I. how could I not have known this until now?
Scott: Here's my hope right?
Scott: is it?
Scott: humans want fast cars mansions members of the opposite sex there or hoping the same sex.
Rym: They're hoping that transhuman Scott just wants enlightenment or something.
Scott: No transhuman Scott just wants bigger mansions faster cars.
Rym: See, I think the more because it's hard to get into specifics.
Rym: I think one thing that's definitely been illustrated is that the Rym supervillain regardless of his desires Orchestrates the large and complicated subtle plan that culminates in an epic.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: I've done it And your plan is the look at me.
Rym: I'm the supervillain.
Rym: Fuck you all.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much.
Scott: I would do.
Scott: I would be a lot more like Let's try to think of supervillains that we would be like.
Rym: I'm Batman I'm evil Batman.
Rym: you'd be evil Batman.
Rym: I'd be evil not depressed Batman.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I don't know enough superheroes to come up with who that would be.
Scott: see I would be a lot.
Scott: I would be a lot more like rezo.
Scott: I'd be like doing the ritual right now.
Rym: Ah rezo my man.
Scott: I'm more like rezo or Perhaps I'm so great.
Rym: He's like, hey, I'm after this.
Rym: Oh, look there it is.
Scott: Or perhaps I would be more like, you know magneto with less restraint.
Rym: See I'm more like zellows.
Rym: I'm more of the.
Scott: I've got this plan Of course know what I'm?
Scott: maybe maybe if I was posthuman though, I might be more like Galactus.
Scott: just eat the world.
Scott: But it's just a world is just food to me.
Rym: It's not a you know, oh, yeah You're but then that's the same as Hannibal.
Scott: I know Galactus is the same as Hannibal.
Scott: So only bigger and dorky looking.
Rym: Wow There we go.
Rym: Yeah, don't call him dark.
Rym: He'll fucking eat you.
Scott: He doesn't even know I'm an ant to him.
Scott: That's like.
Scott: it's like telling an ant don't call the human dorky.
Rym: What if?
Rym: what?
Rym: if an ant crawled into your ear and was like hey, I'm an ant It wouldn't be an ant it would.
Scott: it would suddenly be post ant.
Rym: it'd be post ant but it still looks like an ant because Hannibal still looks like a human.
Scott: I know that's that's the thing.
Scott: Galactus I guess looks like a human to humans.
Scott: But actually if you're not human Galactus looks different to everybody.
Scott: That says I just I was picturing what he looks like to you But to me he looks like, you know, I guess to humans He looks like the pink blue thing, but to lie.
Rym: Why do you look like a pink thing to humans?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: There's an explanation.
Scott: That's probably really dorky.
Rym: Speaking of what's the deal with all these different colored lantern?
Rym: Whatever is now?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I read one shitty green lantern that was only green and I'm not gonna read me the other one cuz.
Rym: I can't think of anything Dumber than having a blue find out about that shit.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Maybe I made it up, but I thought I heard something somewhere.
Scott: Well, you're right, but all I know about as much as you do great.
Scott: Yeah Do we got anything else to say about that?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: It's kind of a cop-out.
Rym: we explored a lot of ideas and I kind of want to make some potatoes or a sandwich or something and Actually have a big presentation on game theory at work tomorrow for like half my company.
Rym: So I kind of got to prepare that.
Scott: Let's see.
Scott: Who is the the coolest super villain in you know in any fictional work Hannibal you think so?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: It's hard to say.
Rym: hmm Constantine fictional.
Rym: well, it depends.
Scott: we're talking fiction fiction.
Rym: It's hard to say I could name any number of people from the prince of nothing the darkness that comes before.
Scott: I'm a fan of Not Sauron, but you know What came before Sauron?
Scott: Morgoth whatever it was.
Scott: I'm gonna have to can't believe.
Scott: I forget the name.
Rym: It's tricky.
Rym: Maybe Cthulhu.
Scott: Cthulhu is not really a villain He's transhuman he's just an alien sort of transcending.
Rym: hmm See, it's tough.
Rym: It is pretty tough because it's come up recently.
Rym: I might have to go with the no god.
Rym: Yeah, hardly just because I don't know what his deal is.
Rym: Yeah, I know his deal like.
Rym: well, then I'll reevaluate.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know the no gods deal, but I did.
Scott: there was that no man in the prologue.
Scott: He was pretty cool.
Rym: Ah the non men the non man.
Scott: I like the non man.
Rym: They're kind of Hannibal - they're kind of they were Something but now they're transcendent as a result Crazy appearing to people who aren't at that level, but that level is not necessarily better.
Rym: Yeah, I mean I don't think that guy was having a good time.
Scott: No no not at all.
Rym: You're gonna find out more about them.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I'll say one thing they have the best reliefs of any reliefs ever.
Rym: You think you think you can imagine an awesome relief?
Rym: It's better.
Scott: you know if I was like a crazy super villain you know what I would do have a building full of reliefs.
Scott: I'd just make reliefs.
Scott: I'd make the craziest most evil reliefs ever.
Rym: Wait till you find out about the reliefs in that book cuz they're crazy.
Rym: They're beyond your edge.
Scott: We should get some reliefs.
Rym: What kind of reliefs?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I'm gonna go on eBay.
Scott: I'm gonna search for reliefs.
Rym: Whoa, here's an idea for all you artists out there in the artist alleys make simple clay relief tablet.
Rym: Oh look that are all Cthulhu.
Rym: We and sell them in the art Search release on eBay.
Scott: guess what I found you found Cthulhu.
Rym: We reliefs.
Scott: I found a. not only that I find reliefs.
Scott: I found a rare Ancient Egyptian huge Sun God wall relief.
Rym: how much is it?
Rym: 50 bucks really?
Rym: Yeah, not a replica.
Scott: It might be a replica.
Rym: You see y'all.
Rym: relief says replica.
Rym: It doesn't matter if it's a really well my relief says Kind of think of something funny other than Desert Eagle.
Rym: My relief says Ozymandias look the mighty mine says Cthulhu relay photography, I believe it's Cthulhu photography.
Rym: the other word like whatever It's Lee.
Scott: whether this relief is genuine or not it actually looks pretty cool.
Rym: buy it safety box.
Scott: What do I get?
Scott: deal with it.
Rym: put it in your room?
Scott: No?
Scott: I don't need a relief in my room.
Scott: Thank you That's that's what the supervillain does.
Scott: he slips his evil reliefs into other people's rooms.
Rym: Well if I woke up and there was a large relief just kind of staring me in the face in my bedroom I don't know what I would do.
Rym: I should buy the relief, but I really don't know what I would do.
Rym: I'd be like the monkeys.
Rym: just It's like the monolith.
Scott: I should buy a relief and play room.
Rym: What did you pick?
Rym: the wrong relief and I become transhuman and then I eat you?
Scott: Well, who am I to say you're wrong?
Scott: who am I to?
Scott: that'd be like an ant telling the lack of Judge Hannibal, you know what?
Rym: Yeah, I'd probably lock him up.
Scott: Anyway, I probably would do it's tricky.
Rym: It's like wow, you've transcended humanity.
Rym: That's great back to jail with you.
Scott: Well, you didn't transcend him enough to get the hell away.
Rym: Yeah, except he does.
Scott: but he he can get away but he can't get away perfectly Kind of can.
Scott: if he was perfect then they never would have caught him ever.
Rym: Yeah, but what if he got caught on purpose because it was fun or because he had more power that way?
Rym: Well, they can't second-guess someone like that.
Scott: That's the if that's the truth.
Rym: That's the biggest problem with transhuman.
Rym: Every second guess them.
Scott: if that is true, then basically you have no choice in the matter.
Scott: So just let it be.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.