Scott: It's Monday October 13th.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Scott: I'm Rym, and this is GeekNights tonight unfocused rambling about old computers.
Scott: Let's do this Alright, so we're not doing a tech news roundup, but we are doing an actual show.
Scott: But I got a lot of little things to go over here.
Rym: So well you see tech news roundup is basically code for we couldn't think of a Monday.
Scott: It's already here.
Rym: It's already Monday.
Scott: the first thing right is um I went to get a haircut today.
Scott: not very exciting right?
Scott: go get a $14 haircut from the.
Scott: you know the generic barber or whatever.
Rym: Man, you know what I haven't had a haircut since the last time I got.
Rym: I got that like $80 haircut at Grand Central.
Rym: All right, that was like a year and a half ago anyway.
Scott: I go in and he's cutting my hair whatever.
Scott: It's not very hard to cut my hair And you know I noticed as he's you know combing and cutting and whatnot that my my scalp is being real nice.
Scott: You know it's got.
Scott: it's like something is scratching it But is you know also sort of massaging it, and it feels really good, and I look pet rat dude's got a metal comb Like I'm like whoa metal comb.
Scott: I never actually you know it's like huh like you would think that would be obvious right cuz plastic combs They're sort of like the hair beats.
Scott: It's like the plastic combs can't defeat the hair but a metal comb got a hair.
Rym: Do you have like?
Scott: a metal comb is just like hair out my way?
Scott: You know.
Scott: so just slide smooth no matter what your hair is up to.
Rym: I guess it depends on the metal.
Rym: I mean wrought-iron not doing so well.
Scott: I guess I think it was like.
Scott: you know aluminum stainless steel something like that I guess cold iron aluminum if you were a demon.
Scott: I think it's probably aluminum, but Anyway, so I'm like wow metal comb.
Scott: I've never seen a metal comb before, but it's so obvious, and he's like yeah I hate plastic comb, and you know this guy was from Russia.
Scott: He's like this comb.
Scott: I bring with me from Russia.
Scott: Oh, man, he's two more than X, and then he's got like a little.
Scott: you know Instead of having a thing of Barbasol right he actually had like this little like it looked like a microwave that Sterilized whatever was in it.
Scott: it might have been like a mini Clave thing.
Scott: you know autoclave.
Scott: I don't think it was an autoclave, but it was a tiny You know hairdresser sterilizing thing that was like a microwave.
Scott: He opens it up and inside he takes out this other comb, and he's like here This is also from same set, but I do not use this and it was like this pristine Different metal comb.
Rym: ooh, I wonder if he ever uses it.
Scott: He said he doesn't use it.
Rym: wonder what it's for.
Rym: I wonder.
Rym: maybe it combed the hair of someone important.
Scott: I don't know, but I'm gonna go on Amazon And I was looking.
Scott: I saw some metal combs there.
Scott: I'm gonna try to pick one up, but the shipping's too much.
Scott: So I'm gonna look in the store first.
Rym: huh is this gonna be a trend?
Rym: we had we went to our fancy shaving.
Rym: You're gonna go to fancy combing.
Scott: I'm gonna get.
Scott: it's just.
Scott: I'm not gonna do any fancy combing.
Scott: I'm just gonna get a metal comb because it Because it feels better on the on the scalp than a plastic one, that's pretty much it.
Rym: Well, I actually you know I've been saying pretty much all last winter.
Rym: I kept saying man I'm gonna buy blank, and I totally didn't.
Rym: and then this summer I was like I'm gonna buy blank while they're cheap, and I totally didn't.
Rym: and then last weekend I said this weekend.
Rym: I'm definitely going to buy blank.
Rym: I'm no matter what going to buy blank, and I didn't buy blank.
Scott: Why do I always play this game of keeping a secret?
Rym: I don't know it.
Rym: Should we stop?
Rym: No you do it - you can't just say our Rym always.
Scott: I don't do it so blatantly like that.
Scott: you gotta do it suddenly.
Scott: You can't just be like blank.
Scott: you gotta.
Scott: You know you gotta dodge around something.
Rym: you say finally bought blanks for my pistol.
Scott: great now.
Rym: I finally bought skis Because you see as I think I talked about this a lot when I went skiing last winter and almost broke my neck because Scott Johnson I can't say it was his fault, but basically we're standing at the top of.
Rym: you know hadn't skied in a long time?
Rym: I wasn't that good at skiing when I was a kid, so we do the big bunny hill.
Rym: No, we didn't die all right.
Rym: We do the blue square.
Rym: Hey, we didn't die.
Rym: that was kind of easy all right.
Rym: Do the black diamond.
Rym: hey we didn't die.
Rym: I guess we're invincible.
Rym: we did the double black diamond, and I almost died Uh-huh, so uh you know it was time.
Rym: I decided this saw this winter.
Rym: I'm gonna go to lessons.
Rym: I'm gonna ski like as many we get lessons.
Rym: Well, I got lessons when I was a kid and a lot of lessons.
Rym: That's how I learned how to ski.
Scott: because you see yeah But I mean if you can do every you know our lessons gonna help you go from you know hard to stupid hard.
Rym: Well, there are definitely some techniques in my.
Rym: you know you can learn a lot about something in computers.
Rym: But then because you learned it on your own you're missing like one or two fundamental things.
Scott: You're getting by, but you're doing it wrong or like.
Rym: I'm doing most things right, but when I hit a mogul I just fucking die.
Rym: cuz I can't deal with them at all Cuz you're not using the technique.
Scott: you just sort of doing it natural like with intuitions as opposed to doing it by the book.
Scott: I'm
Rym: using the technique But you have to use a different technique with moguls like the way you got to turn differently on those things
Scott: Uh-huh, but
Rym: anyway the one thing I remember was that I was not that good at skiing like I couldn't do a black diamond The last time I skied and then this winter I was doing black diamonds just fine.
Rym: So I finally go to buy skis and you know I walk in and I'm not gonna pretend that I Know a lot about skis because they've changed a lot.
Rym: so I walk in to the ski house I find this guy, and I'm like look.
Rym: I haven't skied in like 10 years.
Rym: I skied last season I was doing really well for some reason.
Rym: and he stops me.
Rym: He says well you were using a shaped ski right and I was like you mean like those.
Rym: and I point and he's like yeah Pretty much all skis are like that now, and I said does that matter?
Rym: and he said well basically If you were skiing on one that wasn't shaped like that, and then you ski it on one that was shaped like that You're gonna be about ten times better because those skis are just absolutely better, and you're stupid to use an older ski
Scott: Uh-huh,
Rym: and it's basically skiing as a sport has been made monumentally easier because of the advances of technology.
Scott: So usually like even a sport when the technology advances it like you know allows you to push the limit But it usually doesn't make it easier.
Scott: You know it's like fancy ice skates and fancy sticks don't make it any easier to be great at hockey.
Scott: But no, but if you're great at hockey they allow you to you know even go give me even greater and greater.
Scott: But if you suck at hockey doesn't matter what curve you got on the blade You're not gonna score any goals, but shape skis just make it so much easier.
Rym: He was like yeah in the old days like now if you want to turn you just turn and it just works.
Rym: So he pretty much said that was the reason I felt like I was so much better than I used to be and that it Wasn't me losing my bad habits or just innately having skill.
Rym: It was just far superior technology Mm-hmm.
Rym: so then you know I'm looking in.
Rym: the skis range from like 400 bucks to like $2,000.
Rym: so of course
Scott: I see the more expensive skis hurt or vastly so
Rym: I Look around for a bit, then I say all right What's the difference between this ski and I hold up this like $600 ski and this ski and it's $800 And he's like about 200 bucks and that one's blue.
Rym: Yeah, and I was like seriously.
Rym: He's like.
Rym: There's no difference.
Rym: look This one's like a tiny bit narrower, but that's not gonna matter.
Rym: They're shaped the same.
Rym: They're the same basic length.
Scott: Make any money.
Scott: He should have told he should have made up some bullshit about how the $200 one was $200 better.
Rym: I think part of the reason is that he could tell I don't know if he could tell that I wasn't gonna take any BS Or if he just because he seems like he actually skis a lot.
Scott: But see and that's the other thing right is if if you're let's say if there's nobody in the world who that blues ski would Have been better for Then why even stock it?
Rym: you want to know why.
Rym: one I think I realized what it is.
Rym: one if you are an expert skier Like.
Rym: I pointed some other skis And he put he said like well that one has this special binding and it'll it'll prevent the ski from flattening out Completely when you're taking a car Which is kind of the way you turn on hard pack.
Rym: and I was like well that affect me at my skill level.
Rym: And he said I've been skiing for 20 years.
Rym: that doesn't affect me, and I said will it affect anyone?
Rym: he said yes There are people for whom this would be an advantage.
Rym: None of those people are in this store right now.
Rym: Okay, you know.
Rym: and finally I'm like all right what ski should I buy?
Rym: he's and he just grabs one And he says this one and I said what length.
Rym: and he looks at me And he looks over.
Rym: he grabs a one specific length and says this leg 169 All right, and I was like how much is this?
Rym: 260 bucks.
Rym: What I thought it was 600. now This is last year's key.
Rym: this year's keys are all 600. last year's keys are like 200 bucks because no one wants them.
Rym: What's the difference about?
Rym: So all right, I need ski boots.
Rym: I'm not gonna tell this.
Rym: so basically he did the same thing with ski boots.
Rym: I'm like what ski boots should I buy?
Rym: and he just says this one.
Rym: It's like why that's the one I use.
Rym: It also happens to be the second cheapest one in the store.
Rym: Should I buy the cheapest one?
Rym: No, it's terrible.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: What does he even have them?
Scott: It's terrible.
Scott: I seem to have it in case people are poor.
Scott: if you're poor why he was going skiing?
Rym: you can actually ski for pretty cheap.
Rym: It's only really that expensive if you Buy your own equipment and don't use it all the time or you go to like fancy places far away to ski.
Scott: Yeah, but if you're poor rent Don't do it that often.
Rym: if you already own skis and there's a local little ski place skeins not that expensive.
Rym: Anyway, if any of you know skeins real cheap.
Scott: it on it on has the cheapest skiing.
Rym: if anyone out there wants to ski with Me I'm gonna be skiing a lot in the mid Hudson Valley this winter on my brand-new super cheap skis.
Rym: Oh, man It's all I got really.
Rym: so what do you got in the sciency techie news?
Scott: I got three.
Scott: quick news is here right?
Scott: number one?
Scott: I'm probably not gonna talk about this because they're not gonna announce anything exciting But tomorrow is Apple laptop announce II day, right?
Scott: The only things you should actually be concerned with.
Scott: right people are spreading rumors about this brick Thing where they're gonna make a laptop out of a solid piece of aluminum and sort of carve it out and screw that whatever.
Scott: Well, you should be concerned about is number one.
Scott: They're they're discussing making an $800 Apple laptop Which is not a bad idea.
Scott: And here's the reason that this is very likely is because I think This is what I heard right that somehow it was calculated that because you know Apple likes to sell Laptops at these incredibly huge margins.
Scott: So if you look at just the power of the hardware versus what you could get for the same amount in a PC It's like Apple's hardware.
Scott: the speeds and the amount of RAM is so weak, you know, cuz they just overcharge for everything.
Scott: But what's gonna do if they do an $800 laptop?
Scott: They're gonna do it on a low margin.
Scott: It's actually gonna be pretty comparable to a PC laptop, which is good in this bad economy.
Scott: But someone's like why would they do this after their years and years of you know, having these, you know, ridiculous margins and everything?
Scott: Somebody said that by their calculations if Apple doesn't put out an $800 laptop That the stock would devalue so much that they would actually lose more money than they lose by decreasing the margins on this thing.
Rym: I have all my opinions about that, but I'm not allowed to talk about them.
Scott: You're right, but basically Apple laptops tomorrow and I was walking on the street to the Apple store together because there's a recall on the.
Scott: you know Power adapty things for the iPhone.
Scott: Oh, yeah, so I want to take care of that.
Scott: They make.
Scott: they make.
Scott: you give them like your iPhone serial number.
Scott: They don't just trade in for the.
Scott: you know The physical thing, huh?
Rym: Well, I got maybe if you had one of the new ones and then you dropped it or soaked in water or something And I don't know how many people break those things.
Scott: No, cuz the new ones have a green dot on them and the plugs are shaped differently a little bit.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Scott: But anyway, I saw a guy walking down the street away from the Apple store Or the MacBook and it was in one of those, you know, the boxes that looked like he just bought it.
Scott: Yeah, if he uses that as his case then alright, but if if he just bought a MacBook, I'd Does he not?
Scott: I mean in the Apple store, they're pretty well.
Scott: I didn't even see any MacBooks.
Scott: It was just all new iPods everywhere.
Scott: So I don't know what that guy was doing.
Scott: I guess maybe he could have had an emergency situation But I have a feeling that guy mistakenly bought a MacBook on the worst possible day, okay Second tiny news ready is real tiny.
Scott: There's a study warning of hearing laws from music players.
Rym: I was gonna talk about that because it's basically.
Rym: it's not BS.
Rym: I mean the news is true, but the answer is just where.
Rym: isolation earbuds and you won't have a problem, right?
Scott: We've talked about this a million times before but it needs to be repeated again for the sake of people's hearing which is very important.
Scott: Right, I hate how all these studies say you hearing losses from the portable music player It's not from the portable music player.
Scott: The portable music player is not to blame.
Scott: What is to blame is that you have these crappy earbuds?
Scott: and if you have earbuds in and there are noises around you like you're walking on a city street or you're sitting at a Place where a lot of people are talking the the noise of the people talking the background noise also gets in your ear.
Scott: So you have to crank up the volume on your iPod or whatever in order to make your music or your podcast Louder than the noises around you and thus everyone who uses iPods and as these crappy headphones like the ones that come with the iPod Cranks it way up.
Scott: and by cranking the volume way up.
Scott: You're having more decibels per unit time constantly and that damages your hearing.
Scott: The solution is to a don't turn it up if you don't have you know Isolation earbuds or noise cancelling headphones.
Scott: It does a lot of background noise.
Scott: Just turn your iPod off.
Scott: don't listen in that situation because you're gonna hurt yourself and Get either a lot of money, but they're worth it.
Scott: get isolation earbuds or noise cancelling headphones.
Scott: You put them in and they either use noise cancelling technology to cancel out noises Or they seal your ear so that other outside noises don't get in at all And all you can hear is the music.
Scott: and let me tell you when I was using normal iPod headphones I used to have to turn my iPod mini up to like 80% of the max volume to hear it.
Scott: now With my you know, ever since I started using etymotics like a couple years ago I can turn the thing down on my iPhone to like 25% and it's loud.
Rym: and you know, honestly while we're at it You really should own.
Rym: I say this because it's relevant since ed packs.
Rym: I saw that very few people had them.
Rym: but Buy a nice pair of earplugs like concert earplugs if you like to go to metal concerts Because if you're at a concert and you're not wearing earplugs, you're pretty much stupid.
Scott: Yeah, I mean there are some situations.
Scott: we go to a concert you take your earplugs out for a little bit to rock out Pretty hard, but for you should not do that for an entire concert you will guaranteed Especially like a metal concert or something or any sort of rock pop concert even at like in a dance club If you don't have any earplugs in you are damaging your hearing And it's impossible to repair.
Scott: it will be damaging it permanently.
Rym: someday.
Scott: We'll have the bionic ears someday while the bionic ears until then if you want to hear and not have hearing aids when you're old Do what we say, okay, but also it's a crime.
Rym: I see people wearing those like foam ones.
Rym: They bought for like five bucks before the concert.
Rym: They just make it sound terrible.
Rym: They make.
Scott: did you make things sound terrible, but they're better than nothing?
Rym: Yeah, but it's so little more money to buy like professional Equal decibel reduction plugs.
Rym: We got a modic or some other company.
Scott: This is what people don't realize.
Scott: is that those foam things that you buy right?
Scott: because music is all about frequencies, right?
Scott: So if you want to make music quieter, you need to reduce the volume of all the frequencies, you know of audio equally.
Scott: Those foam things reduce some frequencies more than others.
Scott: So maybe you won't hear the bass as much or maybe you won't hear the trebles as much, you know If you go and buy I think we what are they called the eddie 15s that we have?
Rym: Yeah, because they've reduced it by 15 decibels.
Scott: eddie 15s.
Scott: or you know, you can get any other earplugs.
Scott: It's just the ones we buy.
Scott: because we're animatic fanboys I guess I don't know but because they're like 10 bucks because they're they're like 10 15 bucks and you put these in and it Reduces every frequency of audio by exactly 15 decibels.
Scott: So the music sounds exactly the same just quieter and a live concert was better than that, right?
Scott: So you should just carry them with you anywhere, especially if concerts are gonna happen.
Scott: Okay and my final tiny news is that open office 3.0 came out today ish and their website is totally ruined and basically all they have is a download page up and everything else is down.
Scott: but They added some new features like compatibility with the new, you know, Microsoft office formats and Some other BS like that.
Scott: and people are discussing, you know, is this really enough to call it 3.0?
Scott: Is it really that different from the previous one?
Scott: Apparently you can open PDFs in it and possibly edit them and you know open office has long had the feature to export to PDF.
Scott: So that's that's a good enough reason to upgrade right there.
Scott: But you know really open office is sort of big and slow and people only really use at least, you know It has like drawing and all these other at.
Scott: you know, it's a suite.
Scott: It's an office suite.
Scott: has all the different parts.
Scott: I've never seen anyone use any part except for the word processing the spreadsheet and the you know presentation.
Scott: I've never seen anyone else use any of the other parts of open office So I don't even know why they keep making them or anything, but really in my opinion, you know You either got Microsoft office for free or your company paid for it or something.
Scott: or you know, that's fine.
Scott: but if not just use you know a word processor and a spreadsheet like I use a B word and numeric and For I use Google Docs, you know, what do I need this big clunky office suite for?
Scott: that is a million features?
Scott: I'm never gonna use.
Rym: honestly, I have open office installed and part of the reason is that what I often open word doc I have it installed.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, but I use it for like.
Rym: if I make a Google presentation, I Export it to PowerPoint and then I open it in open office.
Scott: Yeah, you know I'll do.
Scott: I'll use it for you know, sort of like these off situations.
Scott: I won't use it like regularly I won't go to it, but sometimes I'll have it there just in case there's like a you know, like what's it called?
Rym: Well, I'll also use it to one of those outlying situations.
Rym: I'll use it to make presentations because if I'm not on the internet then Google gears is basically useless.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: It's true.
Scott: But yeah, if you're uh, you know If you need an office thing or maybe you're using open office already You need to upgrade it or you know You're interested in trying to open up PDFs and edit them.
Scott: maybe make it a character sheet for a game or something like that You know and you go for it.
Rym: So I got to talk about this.
Rym: I'm not going to talk about it at length because Eventually, we'll either have to do a show on it or I'll have to write some sort of angry thesis about it, but well in this case is good news Thomas, which is the kind of Legislative information part of the Library of Congress and yes, it's named after Thomas Jefferson.
Rym: Oh, yeah One of my favorite presidents even though his Navy not such a good idea.
Scott: Well, that's the thing is like every.
Scott: it seems like every president throughout history had like greatness But also terribleness and I think that is the mark of a great president.
Scott: greatness and terrible Is he'd both.
Rym: what bad did William Henry Harrison do?
Scott: Harrison do so.
Rym: we balanced out.
Rym: that's better than we can hope.
Scott: No, you need to have a greatness and a terribleness at the same time greatness more people remember his name than many other presidents.
Scott: No, you have to.
Scott: you have to achieve greatness in your life.
Rym: Taft achieved great corpulence.
Scott: now is to keep Taft as an example of bad president.
Scott: only terribleness.
Rym: No greatness I think Grant drank more alcohol than all the rest of them combined.
Scott: again only terribleness.
Scott: Right Lincoln had greatness and terribleness.
Scott: win civil war.
Scott: be an asshole.
Scott: You see the greatness and the terribleness.
Scott: Andrew Jackson Be have huge huge balls and do what you want.
Scott: That's greatness.
Scott: do a bad thing though Because what he wanted was bad terribleness.
Scott: James Madison's eyes on the $20.
Scott: James Madison's.
Rym: my man Even though I'll bet a lot of you listening can't name anything.
Rym: He did.
Scott: I can't name anything.
Rym: Anyway, I'm not gonna belabor the point because it's all quick news here, but Thomas publishes permanent.
Rym: I just wanted to do that alliteration their links.
Rym: Basically the news is that there is now an official permanent way to link to Legislation.
Rym: so if you want to reference in for bibliographies, yes It's basically a way to have a permanent link to legislation.
Rym: that is itself enshrined in the protocols of the Library of Congress.
Scott: So you could then send one of those links to the Library of Congress and they can send you to law.
Rym: Or well, you can just click on that link and see the law.
Scott: That's good, too.
Rym: Basically, I'm gonna actually read from the slash shot here with prompting from the Sunlight Foundation's open house project Which is a very good thing.
Rym: By the way, the US Library of Congress has announced today that it's online database Thomas will now generate persistent URLs.
Rym: They're gonna call these legislative handles for legislative documents.
Rym: Quote, it is certainly nice to be able to link to legislation with a persistent link.
Scott: Can I link to like different like, you know, maybe I'll link to say the DMCA, right?
Scott: Can I link to like?
Scott: I don't know how the laws are arranged.
Scott: I'm not a lawyer like clause 33 of the DMCA, you know get to the middle of it and such like that.
Scott: Honestly, I have no idea because Hey lawyers figure this out for us.
Rym: basically though I think it's a step in the right direction because I'll
Scott: definitely
Rym: I'm of the mind that one every single law in the United States from the federal to the state to the International to the local
Scott: to the to the small podunk ordinance
Rym: needs to be online Not just online and free to everyone online for anyone to link to look at copy whatever.
Rym: it should also be available in Every library in your locale at least your local laws and basically needs to be available at zero cost to anyone any citizen Who has no anyone in the world who asks?
Scott: Mmm, that is my feeling and that is and needs to be in the public domain.
Scott: Yeah, so you could take it and do shit with it and you know include it, you know I thought just so.
Scott: I can link to it But I need to be able to like take it edit it and put up a new document on my site and then etc.
Rym: At least luckily all those instances of Copyrighted law in the US are very slowly being overturned by a small number of very vocal activists.
Rym: but I feel like in the end the law needs to be codified entirely in digital form and Sadly while a lot I would say that's a great step forward.
Rym: That's maybe one tenth of a percent of what I actually want to happen with law.
Rym: But this is such a step in the right direction that I encourage all of you to go here follow this link Read about this and get involved in all these initiatives because I don't think very many people in the u.s Let alone do they know the law?
Rym: They don't even have access to the law or don't know they have access to the law.
Rym: It's very different.
Scott: even if they did have access and they tried to read it.
Scott: They wouldn't understand it.
Rym: It's very difficult for non lawyers to understand or even get access to the law.
Rym: I mean, I have browsed the law library in my building at work.
Rym: you know my building has a law library for all of us to access and I have may I've made heads and Almost a tale of exactly one thing.
Rym: I read there once it's just.
Scott: uh, so I can sometimes understand a clause or two.
Scott: But I think if you actually if they had every law online like that then people who were lawyers You know who either were being paid as part of or volunteering or something like that could go through and sort of translate laws You know sort of into Colloquial speak for people to understand and then link to the original and so like a second database of you know Understandable to the layman
Rym: law if you want my kind of
Scott: binding obviously in court or anything.
Scott: But it would just be for people to look up, you know And to help themselves without having to pay a lawyer for basic things.
Rym: What I really want is that from there.
Rym: I feel like all laws should be hyperlinks Maybe not using the hyperlink transfer protocol, but something where all all kind of hypertext transfer protocol Yes but any term in a law that's a legal term should always have a link to a Kind of legal definition of that term.
Scott: Well, usually when I've looked at some laws and what they'll do is the top of a law will define like the the magic terms It's gonna use in itself.
Scott: but you know even that is when you're reading law.
Scott: anytime the term appears you'd be able to click on it and it'll take you to the Top or pop open that little definition from the top in a window or something, you know, something like that.
Rym: But my long-term like 50-year out ideas that we should have all law should be written in some kind of markup language.
Rym: I always say XML, but you need some sort of special markup language for laws such that say on a federal level, right?
Scott: I think raw law sort of is written in a language, but it's a legal language.
Rym: Yes, it needs to be a language that is much more understandable to computers.
Scott: So we need law ML basic something like that.
Rym: I mean imagine this Ml possession, you know the idea of possession is defined in all different states and all different towns in different ways.
Rym: But the basic idea of possession should be defined Universally I think across the entire country and then anytime possession is referenced in a law that state is already defined by this top thing.
Rym: and then you only supersede that kind of like inheritance if you're writing object-oriented code if you need a very specific altered definition For your specific law and most laws shouldn't need that and maybe you define possession of and then there's different possessions depending on what you are defining possession of.
Rym: and If we spent 20 or 30 years sorting all this out I think we could solve the majority of the legal problems we have in the u.s.
Rym: Today.
Scott: it'll take a lot less time to figure stuff out.
Scott: at least.
Scott: the problem is how many errors would be in there after people Are typing all this shit in.
Rym: yeah Yeah, but this is one of my kind of long-term pipe dreams.
Rym: that just probably good We're gonna have to wait until AI is around.
Rym: that'll just do it for us.
Scott: Yeah They'll be the AI judge of the world and then it'll kill us all as long as it doesn't turn into judge.
Rym: dread rims guilty Things of the day.
Rym: so I would say you've all but I know a lot of you were just.
Scott: you know You're gonna say y'all instead.
Rym: You know when I lived down south for a short for not a short time But a month or so while I was at space camp and traveling I got real close to saying y'all a couple times All right It went away.
Rym: But so all of you are probably either already already already had this experience or someday will the experience of having an RA This video on CollegeHumor a
Scott: resident advisor
Rym: Yeah, and then there you know, there's other terms but basically it's that dude in college who is kind of the leader of your floor in your dorm and Your goal is to have as little interaction with this person as possible, but that will often be unavoidable.
Scott: But well, it depends, you know and what you're exact, you know The the social nature of your floor is like at how much interaction you'll want to have.
Scott: but generally, you know Well, you don't want them to come bothering you unless you're friends with them.
Rym: I skipped every single floor meeting on my because it was pointless and they couldn't do anything to me.
Scott: But they barely had any floor meetings.
Rym: as our RA was the best RA in the universe We had floor meetings kind of often because of what went on in Fish B.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: You lived in Fish B. Yes.
Rym: I lived in the infamous fucking Fish B. Well, I wouldn't say the worst place to live because that would be over in some of those other dorms.
Rym: But I won't name but Fish B was special.
Rym: But RAs are a certain breed of person.
Rym: they are either the rare Incredibly awesome RA and those are is are all kind of the same or they're like mine or they're the normal RA the eponymous RA the the RA that you expect.
Rym: and that RA is what you see in this video.
Scott: Yeah that in his video.
Scott: It's the stereotypical RA.
Rym: and let me tell you most RAs I met were exactly like that to the point that if I if like if I if this video had been older I would almost guess that they were affecting the behavior of this video in their RA-ness.
Rym: But no RAs are really like.
Scott: I think it's that type of person who was like.
Scott: that is the type of person that sign ups to be Signs up to be an RA.
Rym: only two kinds of people sign up to be RAs People who have no money and need free dorms or people who are like this.
Rym: Yep, and the people who have no money are the ones who end up being the awesome RAs.
Scott: Yep, because they don't they either don't give a shit or they're awesome.
Rym: But anyway, well watch this video because next Thursday's show I think we're gonna do a show about college dorms.
Rym: I was inspired.
Scott: Alright, so, you know, there's a lot of rich people out there.
Scott: Well, not that many but people always make fun of rich people for spending their money on stupid shit.
Scott: They'd be like, oh you bought your golden toilet seat.
Scott: Oh You bought your a hundred Porsches, you know, what the fuck's wrong?
Scott: is this?
Rym: a collection of stupid crap?
Rym: rich people bought?
Scott: No, not at all.
Scott: There's one rich man.
Scott: His name is Jay Walker.
Scott: He's the guy who made a bunch of money from priceline.com.
Rym: Johnny Walker.
Scott: No, Jay Walker.
Scott: Jay Walker.
Scott: Yes Okay, his name is Jay Walker.
Scott: How you like that?
Rym: JAY or J period.
Scott: JAY.
Scott: All right, but He's rich.
Scott: He was.
Scott: he got rich from priceline.com among other things, right and he spent his money on Well a lot of things but what we're focusing on here is the library in his house or one of his house.
Scott: I don't know how many houses he has but let me let me list some of the things That are in this library.
Scott: and you tell me if this is a man This is a rich person who knows how to spend their money.
Scott: Let me tell you.
Scott: All right, you ready?
Scott: He has a Sputnik.
Rym: The first one no, but one of them Just pre-bought it from Russia.
Scott: One of the ones that wasn't sent into space.
Scott: Wow Wait, wait, but wait a minute.
Scott: Wait a minute.
Rym: There is totally a business opportunity for fake Sputniks.
Rym: Oh my god, if I lived in Russia, would I be selling fake Sputniks with certificates of authenticity to rich people?
Rym: Oh my god, what I'm doing?
Scott: that books bound in rubies.
Rym: Which books?
Rym: and one why not human flesh?
Scott: Oh, what are the name for books?
Scott: You know that they're all you know old medieval picturesque books.
Scott: What are those called?
Scott: is the word for them tomes?
Scott: No, there's like a fancy word for them.
Scott: I forget.
Rym: I don't know they're illuminated.
Scott: Yeah 20th century vibes of jeweled bindings crafted the legendary firm sangorski and Sutcliffe.
Scott: something something something.
Rym: Okay, so he bought a book covered in rubies a bunch of them.
Rym: Um, he's got a bunch of books covered in rubies or one book covered in a bunch of rubies a bunch of books Many of them which are encrusted with gems.
Scott: He's got an enigma machine.
Scott: That's pretty cool.
Scott: Wow He's got the original thing from the Adams family and it's holding on to a little case filled with all sorts of glass Eyeballs, huh?
Scott: He's got a. he's got a Civil War Surgery set.
Scott: Whoo He's got a a model of I think the the x-29 Just a model.
Scott: He's got it the instruction manual for the Saturn 5.
Scott: He's got the chandelier from a James Bond movie, which one cuz that matters Die another day.
Scott: All right.
Scott: He's got Fred FDR's napkin with the plan to win World War two Not it.
Scott: Wow He's basically got a whole bunch of shit in this library.
Scott: You really always got um a model a basically a moon globe.
Rym: Wait, what was the plan?
Rym: industrialize dot-dot-dot.
Scott: He's got a moon globe signed by most of the people who have been on the moon.
Rym: I thought you were going to say Moses.
Scott: No But that wouldn't be too bad either.
Rym: Moses Moses Moses Basically this.
Scott: there's like a million other awesome crazy things in this dude's library like fossils and and Like, you know famous.
Rym: I can dig this because I feel like I would.
Rym: if I were that rich I would probably own a similar if not quite as ludicrous collection of things.
Scott: No, but you really like what I you know, I don't think I've correctly Communicated the amazingness of this but when you see it you go.
Scott: Oh That guy has spent his money wisely.
Rym: Was the famous Lewis black?
Rym: what'd you buy another car?
Scott: Yeah something like that.
Scott: Yeah, look at you Bill Gates and Jerry Seinfeld, you know, this this is a lot better than a personal ball washer.
Rym: Let me tell you so well, it depends Is it a personal ball washer that washes golf balls or something far more sinister just when you see this library Rym?
Scott: I think you'd be like oh Oh.
Rym: So, uh, what were we talking about?
Rym: since we tend to record, you know little-known fact we record the arm Rym And I'm Scott and this is GeekNights After we record the show Didn't we?
Scott: I guess he decided to go at the crab people idea of just Talking about really old computers at least old personal computers.
Rym: Yeah, I guess luckily we went kind of long in the front.
Rym: That was intentional.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, let's I'll just start.
Scott: when I was in kindergarten, right?
Scott: Was the first time I ever actually used a computer.
Scott: they had Apple - and in elementary school every classroom had Apple - but there was some Mac 512 and the library eventually got a really fancy Mac that had a CD-ROM but that was.
Scott: that was my experience.
Scott: most of my experience with old computers was you know, Old Macs in elementary school and you know doing logo on the Apple - and all that business.
Scott: Wow Honestly the first computer I owned as I've said before Was a 486 SX - no the first computer I owned was a 486 dx4 But before that I was you know, using lots of computers in school and in summer camp.
Rym: the first computer I used was a 386.
Scott: Wow, so fifth grade so I was using computers four years before you.
Rym: that explains a lot I don't know because the thing is I had a good computer.
Rym: I got the 486 SX - right when it came out - the x4 100 megahertz With 8 megs of RAM, but then a quad That penny and pro which basically gave me the biggest dong in the world for a long time.
Scott: Yeah for a while, but we're not.
Scott: we're talking about computers older than those.
Scott: 486 is talking about Mac 512 K's Mac pluses IBM xt's.
Rym: Honestly, the first time I ever typed a document on a computer Was in fifth grade When I typed an essay that basically it was funny because you know We wrote a some dumb essay about this book called my side of the mountain.
Rym: I read my snow.
Rym: No, it wasn't that I. I take that back.
Rym: I like my side of the mountain.
Rym: The essay was about bare stone.
Scott: I don't know what that is.
Scott: It's about.
Scott: it's about a bare stone anyway Stone that looks like a bear.
Scott: basically in fifth grade a bear was at the stone where a bear lives.
Rym: They did they decided after we wrote this essay that they took the five smart kids in the class and said You get to go to the computer lab, which is kind of new and type your essay on the computer.
Rym: So I went there and I typed my essay on the computer kind of slowly because I I typed at a mediocre pace.
Scott: I didn't learn how to type until 10th grade.
Rym: You know when I learned how to type really when I got ICQ and you know, you know, what's ironic, right?
Scott: All those years have been using Apple twos max better max, right?
Scott: Had the 486 even still didn't know how to type.
Scott: Tenth grade went to learn how to talk about it And you know what?
Scott: I took the keyboard in class at high school with this incredibly old teacher.
Scott: She must have been like 80 something and it was like her last year there she retired pretty much right after she taught me how to type and The one lab that she used to teach people how to type the rest of the school had like Pentium 75 Pentium 200s, right
Rym: the lab
Scott: where you learned how to type had IBM XTs.
Rym: Oh man the parochial school I went to had IBM XTs.
Rym: I used them a little bit, but I didn't really use them.
Scott: I only used them to learn how to type and to play typing games.
Rym: See, it's weird that I use computers a lot like in fifth and sixth grade like as soon as I got access to computers I immediately started like rebooting to DOS and running Q basic and like typing stuff and like writing programs and figuring stuff out, but I really couldn't type honestly Until I got instant messaging Yeah and pretty much as soon as I got ICQ.
Rym: and I got ICQ like as soon as ICQ was available and I was using it like betas and I typed to people all the time.
Rym: And that was how I learned how to type because I refused like.
Rym: it wasn't even like.
Rym: well It wasn't like.
Rym: I don't want to be like these other people who can't type.
Rym: I get online and everyone Typed in complete sentences with periods partly because the mechanism design of ICQ encouraged that sort of typing as opposed to AOL which encouraged OMGBBQBBL AFK MOF or MOS.
Scott: Yeah, kind of.
Scott: I think it also had to do with the community somewhat.
Rym: Yeah, let's see AOL American punk kids ICQ cool Israeli geeks and geeks from all over the world.
Rym: Yep, yeah English for whom English is not the first language most of the time But at the same time the people anyone who used ICQ back then in that early short period Was generally more geeky than anyone using AOL at the equivalent time.
Scott: Oh, definitely most definitely All right, but then let's talk about the old computers.
Scott: So when I was in high school actually, right because around that time, you know The schools are trying to get rid of a lot of the older computers and I sort of got into it And I started to pick up old computers and actually have an Apple to GS in the closet.
Scott: I also have a Mac Plus in the closet with one megabyte of RAM.
Scott: No that first.
Scott: so people understand this right.
Scott: the Apple to GS was an Apple to but it came out in 1986 and their GS stands for graphics and sound.
Rym: and now I just want to point out for context the 386 was produced from 1986 on right.
Scott: So this is the error that they wrote.
Scott: This is an Apple to just like those, you know, when people think of the Apple to they think of the green screen Apple to Right.
Scott: This is that same computer.
Scott: It runs the same software as the as the.
Scott: you know, the Apple to But there's colors a lot of colors at least compared to an Apple to and a lot of sounds.
Scott: you can actually get really good Sound out of this thing and a lot of people today, you know Well, not a lot.
Scott: but there are people today who have so much shit hooked up to their Apple to.
Scott: These still use it as a primary computer.
Scott: these things.
Scott: people have them playing Wolfenstein.
Scott: People have them connected to the internet with modems and instant messenger.
Rym: That as cool as this is these people don't know to candle to those Amiga people.
Scott: Well, I think the Amiga was somewhat more powerful machine and it's you sort of had to go through less greatly.
Scott: It just shows, you know, the versatility of the Apple to I mean the Apple to is sort of like.
Scott: I think if it is Like Wozniak's masterpiece, you know, you open up the Apple to GS and it's just these open slots that are all identical.
Scott: It's like perfect for just making it do anything.
Scott: it's a it's a beautiful machine and people have overclocked the CPUs install different CPUs in there and It's it.
Scott: the Apple to GS is really something beholden I'd.
Scott: really there's no reason to get a regular old Apple to except for Historical purposes.
Scott: if you can get your hands on a GS and on eBay It's not too hard and I use my GS play some Oregon Trail.
Scott: At least I did a long time ago.
Rym: Yeah, except the thing is I I like to own awesome old things.
Rym: but I generally don't like to own awesome old computers because I can just emulate the software and The hardware just takes those face and smells vaguely of like old ozone.
Scott: I love the way it smells.
Scott: it smells so great.
Scott: And yeah Plus you never get a flipping the five and a quarter floppies over and then here to go do those noises that the drive makes.
Rym: You know, I don't even own.
Rym: I used to own this big bundle of five and a quarter floppies.
Scott: I don't know where any of them when I have drives, but I'm too many the floppies left.
Scott: I need to get some of those because all the images to you know Put on those floppies are online.
Scott: So if I get a five and a quarter drive that could go in my regular computer.
Scott: I could then download images of Apple to software put them on those discs In the Apple that someone makes USB ones.
Rym: Oh, maybe I'll definitely bet.
Rym: if someone doesn't there's a business opportunity for geeks.
Scott: Yeah, maybe I'll go pick one up.
Scott: Yeah, the Mac Plus people don't realize.
Scott: right?
Scott: the Mac and the Mac Plus the Mac 512 K Those are the Mac's where it's just one box with a screen and the auto ejecting three and a half inch floppy drive Right under the screen.
Scott: That's what those are.
Scott: I know, you know It's sort of like that's the one we turn it on.
Scott: it goes do and there's a smiley face or more often the brownie.
Scott: Right, that is the first.
Scott: that's the Mac people don't?
Scott: you know, a lot of people don't seem to get this.
Scott: You know the difference in their minds very easily, you know, because they weren't you know paying attention back then But the Mac and the Apple to very different very different.
Scott: But the the thing about the Mac is it's kind of crazy that on my IBM PCs You know these four 100 megahertz deals with 16 megs of RAM.
Scott: You were lucky if you had scuzzy and you were super lucky if it worked.
Rym: like a hundred times lucky I remember because when I built my first computer, I bought that scuzzy Plex tor 8x burner.
Rym: there wasn't even RW.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I spent so much money on that stupid thing.
Scott: And I remember when I bought my Pentium 3450, right?
Scott: It was pretty much like IDE drives are normal.
Scott: scuzzy drives are way better and way awesome But pretty much your only good if you have a lot of money, so I didn't get those.
Scott: but my Mac 512 K Mac Plus It has scuzzy.
Scott: that's all it has.
Scott: and I have an external 20 megabyte hard drive for it.
Scott: that has Carmen San Diego and a bunch bunch of other things on it and All it is.
Scott: you open the box and there's a semi modern ish 20 megabyte Seagate drive in there a Connector a little board a power supply and then a scuzzy connector.
Scott: And it's a 20 megabyte scuzzy drive and it you can boot off it.
Rym: It's just weird to think and I think we've talked about this before but how differently we use computers before they were on the internet and like what computers were foreign computers were pretty much entirely for Typing papers for school and otherwise like tinkering.
Rym: there was nothing to do on a computer to play games Tinker or type something.
Scott: Yep, pretty much or I guess do accounting.
Scott: Yeah, I get you know, if you're doing some sort of business I mean a lot of people there was spreadsheets and that you could do.
Scott: a lot of people do print shop things You know like Microsoft publisher stuff like that, you know print out greeting cards If you had a printer, there was a lot of stuff you could do and sort of.
Scott: you know Desktop publishing was really a desktop publishing.
Rym: I should add that in.
Rym: but outside of those things There was no reason to use a computer.
Rym: and I remember I had a lot of friends who even if their family like I had A computer they didn't use them because they thought they were boring.
Rym: There's nothing.
Scott: the computer is basically a gaming machine that you could also do your homework on And that was it pretty much it.
Rym: No one used it to do anything else except the geeks who would constantly break it and then try to unbreak it.
Scott: Yeah, just constantly fiddling with everything that was on there just to find something to do.
Rym: But I would as a kid spend hours when I found out about MIDI.
Scott: eventually when he had CD roms he had Encyclopedias, but that even those weren't.
Rym: so we'd all watch that same 14-second clip of like Martin Luther King saying I have a dream.
Scott: Is that in X Microsoft Expedia?
Rym: Yes, maybe.
Rym: or that banana spinning in space or I had that Microsoft video.
Rym: It was this uh, oh my god it's a music video called octopus of love and all I remember is that the lyrics were I got a girl who's got eight arms Wraps him around me holds me tight.
Rym: It was I was on my computer, I don't know where it came from.
Rym: I don't know if it was from Microsoft or from like one of those multimedia CDs or maybe Media CDs are great.
Rym: Maybe here's from Packard Bell.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, I remember back then it was like all you could get on your computer is what you had a disc for.
Scott: So it was all about getting discs.
Scott: You know you get as many CDs as you could.
Scott: cuz more CDs meant you could have more stuff cuz you weren't getting anything.
Rym: Other way, I remember buying when we first bought the computer.
Rym: It was called 31 and then in tiny print shareware back to big print games for windows.
Rym: It had Miles bones Solitary.
Scott: I like my house bones.
Scott: Oh One other old computer.
Scott: I remember is my.
Scott: we had some friends and their dad worked for IBM.
Scott: I think he still works for IBM and You know not the same IBM Rym worked for the other one, right, you know in another state.
Rym: Well, it was the same IBM.
Scott: Yes, the same big giant company around the world But it was a separate building as he's doing different work.
Scott: Anyway They had an IBM ps1.
Scott: now people might notice, you know, oh man on the back of your computer You know most today most mice and keyboards a USB.
Scott: But some people have ps2 mice and keyboards.
Scott: right there the circle things with a bunch of pins in the middle.
Scott: That's called a ps2 port because the IBM ps2 Was the first computer to have those kind of ports and they invented those ports for the mice and keyboards on the IBM ps2.
Scott: Before that, you know keyboards use the XT connectors or the AT connectors for the IBM XT or the AT.
Scott: The IBM ps1 was what came before the IBM ps2.
Scott: It did not have ps2 ports, but they had this machine.
Scott: It was really sort of crazy compared to every other computer out there, you know, if you know There's really nothing else out there.
Scott: That's like an IBM ps1.
Scott: I mean we play Monopoly on this thing.
Scott: We play a lot of.
Scott: What's that game?
Scott: like you walk around the school and you like take pictures of the robots and figure out which one's the criminal.
Rym: Oh, yeah, I hated that game, but I remember playing it at school because it's all I could do.
Scott: It was it.
Scott: Oh, I love that game.
Scott: It's a great doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo.
Rym: Oh my god midnight rescue.
Scott: Yep, and there was another game just like it where you were an elf on a mountain and these dwarves came up and pestered you.
Scott: But it was this basically the same game and you caught them in a net.
Rym: It's a good game was like wizard something or other even though Basically the school had all these games that we were supposed to play.
Rym: But I always like every computer in the secret directory for when the either when the real Teacher wasn't around or like you were in the room because you were in the room for some reason or after hours when the cool Teacher who ran the computer club was there.
Rym: We had scorched earths tons 40 racing lhx.
Rym: That's what I was later.
Scott: That was yeah, but that was one thing about this IBM ps1 that I remember so much.
Scott: right was that it had prodigy right and Prodigy.
Scott: yeah, but you're what was your prodigy running on.
Rym: I was running it on a 486 486.
Scott: prodigy Was nothing like IBM ps1 prodigy.
Scott: I can bet IBM ps1 prodigy.
Scott: first of all a lot of the things that people don't realize this right.
Scott: who weren't way around back then?
Scott: nowadays When you get an internet connection, it's like aha.
Scott: I'm connected to the internet.
Scott: then you can run any Software that uses internet.
Scott: so you can run Skype you can run aim you can run your web browser Anything that uses the internet connection.
Scott: you run and you're always connected.
Scott: right back in the day you would dial up.
Scott: So you weren't always connected.
Scott: you're only connected when you double-clicked on the telephone and you were.
Scott: then you disconnected when you were done.
Scott: Also, the only thing that could really connect was the program We use.
Scott: so if you were on prodigy right that that meant that you would double click on prodigy.
Scott: it would connect and you could Do prodigy things and then you close prodigy.
Scott: and that was it.
Scott: you didn't have other internet programs Especially on a non multitasking IBM ps1.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: I mean, I remember even when I had prodigy it was over 2,400 bought modem.
Rym: I could do more by dialing into local BBS's than I could on prodigy prodigy.
Rym: All I did was well chat and Be the leader of the black guild of our magic the gathering clan.
Scott: Yeah, I remember on the IBM ps1 or that prodigy Mostly what we did.
Scott: it was he played like mad maze because there were a lot of things.
Rym: My modem was too slow.
Scott: No, they had a little faster modem than that.
Scott: Plus it was IBM ps1 version of mad maze.
Scott: It was a little different than the later version and you could.
Scott: we would always fill out surveys You know in polls and things give me think about.
Scott: a poll now is like a standard feature on the side of a website.
Scott: Imagine if it was like go to the polls and you fill out the polls and see the results.
Scott: It's like oh my gosh.
Scott: And that was our.
Scott: that was we'd spend a lot of time doing that because it was fun.
Rym: Yeah, I remember I had a pirated copy of Autodesk animator and another pirated copy of a macro media Action, which was that was like free free flash free everything.
Rym: it was basically a way to make the what we now call a PowerPoint presentation a Long time ago and let me tell you I would spend hours as a kid because you know with again not online.
Rym: There's nothing to do with the computer but fiddle with it Was.
Rym: I like figured out the logic of this program cuz I pirated.
Rym: I didn't have any instructions or anything and there was no online To tell me what to do.
Rym: making animations by having like fonts and wingdings and pictures move around and embedding video from my multimedia CDs.
Rym: and those were good times.
Rym: I made the credits to a movie that me and my friends never made but kept saying we would Mmm, I made the opening and closing credits.
Scott: Yeah, the one thing about prodigies and AOL's and stuff back in those days would it really?
Scott: You know, even though it wasn't it really felt like you know AOL or prodigy were games in themselves and that Basically, you were exploring a lot like and it felt like a lot like how you explore in Metroid or Castlevania.
Rym: Even later the early internet.
Rym: when I first got real internet Like I skipped prodigy I'd prodigy internet and that which was basically prodigy.
Rym: But they also let you go in the real internet and even the internet was exploring like I'd go to a website like wow I'm at a website.
Rym: What's here?
Rym: And the links from that website weren't just links or citations They were like doors to other parts of the internet and I'd walk around the internet.
Scott: Yeah, nowadays that fascination sort of gone.
Scott: It doesn't like that anymore.
Rym: Basically Google killed it.
Rym: Mostly.
Scott: Yeah Google was really the.
Rym: Google was the first time I could search for things reliably and it worked.
Rym: I could find when I was looking for like AOL like you could open up the thing and type in a keyword and Sometimes the keyword took you where you want it sometimes took you somewhere scary.
Scott: I remember.
Scott: I said they're all these like, you know, they're a secret hidden keywords people talk about.
Rym: I would go to.
Rym: I remember their rumors around my school.
Rym: people are like if you type in this keyword they give this long Keyword.
Rym: it'll show you boobs.
Scott: Yeah, like you click here here and here There's like a bunch of games to download and play and there was like a bunch of crappy games You could download and and I remember we'd sit there on cuz prodigy had a similar to AOL keyword thing.
Rym: I remember we'd sit with our friends like late at night and we'd type in random keywords and see what it found us.
Rym: Mm-hmm Demystification is a sad thing.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: It's weird.
Rym: I we said this about calculators and I hate to say things like this because it's always the thing that the old man says Kids today using their fancy calculators.
Rym: slide rules made me a better man, but at the same time The fact that the computer was only useful either to do tasks play games or Tweak it and explore it to no end whatsoever.
Rym: I feel like that is what gave me my love of computers more than anything else ever could.
Scott: yeah I really think that's why you know people today even like younger people, you know There's always the stereotype that younger people know how to use technology.
Scott: the older people don't.
Scott: well They know how to use they know how to do their myspaces and their whatnot, but they don't know used to.
Scott: you know Generation, you know because our generation of people when we were kids some people used computers and some people didn't right.
Scott: It wasn't like every kid was using one like now It was.
Scott: we used them other people didn't use them.
Scott: and the people who did because of the nature of the machines Available at the time to the average person those who did Actually learned, you know, if you were a PC gamer in those days of DOS you learned about.
Scott: you know Memory and low memory and boot disks and batch file.
Rym: that knowledge is obsolete today Like knowing how to move stuff into high memory and the difference between extended and expanded memory is useless today.
Scott: Well, it's if you're guessing if you're writing x86 assembly DOS stuff today.
Rym: Well, then it's useful, right?
Rym: all right, really it's useless.
Rym: but the Process of figuring that out on my own because there was no one to tell me there was no internet to tell there was nothing I would sit there and like I heard rumors that high mem and mem maker gave you more memory
Scott: And so
Rym: I typed them and they broke things.
Rym: but then I learned what they did and turning off smart drive.
Rym: Oh my god.
Scott: But I think that because of that is sort of the reason that you know when we have a problem with computers.
Scott: Well, we generally don't or it's a hardware problem.
Scott: We couldn't do anything about just broke and other people are asking us questions That could be answered just by typing the question into Google.
Scott: and I think if you really want to know and learn Computers for real maybe it's worth your time Maybe to go and get like an old computer and sort of you know Play with it and explore it and and sort of figure it out.
Rym: You know what here it is.
Rym: buy and find a 486 somewhere.
Rym: they're not that hard to find and Hardware is better because you'll learn a lot of really weird stuff.
Rym: But I guess a Plex like emulator or something would work.
Rym: Get an old DOS game like fantasy empires or something and just try to without looking online Get it installed.
Rym: Mmm, like from the discs Mmm, yeah, you'll learn more from doing that and get the sound to work.
Rym: You might be asking too much.
Rym: You realize that I never got the sound to work and have my games I play.
Scott: I got the sound to work in every game.
Scott: cuz I had a Sound Blaster 16.
Rym: I had a Forte 16.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: That isn't some ad-lib bullshit.
Scott: I had is perfect a Completely average run-of-the-mill Sound Blaster 16.
Scott: So in every single game I said I have a Sound Blaster 16.
Scott: That means you're gonna work and it said hells.
Rym: Yes, but I I I came.
Rym: I didn't come before you obviously, but I superseded you because I remember when I Was really getting into music and I had like a keyboard and I remember one day Like I was playing with my Casio CT 655 and you know I was looking at the back of it and I was trying to figure out cuz all these other things.
Rym: and finally I was like what the fuck is that MIDI thing anyway and About a month later as I'd figured all this out went to my dad and I said dad I need an upgrade to the computer.
Rym: I need a sound card.
Rym: He was like it makes sound and I was like, no, it doesn't make real sound.
Rym: I can make it make real sound.
Rym: he was real dubious and Eventually, I don't think he understood what I was trying to explain and I didn't really understood.
Rym: but he said how much of this cost?
Rym: I said, I don't know.
Rym: Let's go see.
Rym: and when it was under $100.
Rym: He let me buy it.
Rym: I bought a SoundBlaster advanced wave effects 32.
Scott: that's fine because my next sound card was a Sound Blaster live value Which I still have and still works and it goes on CCI slot.
Rym: the live came so far after the all 32 But that live.
Scott: I was rocking the 4.1 surround with the EAX back in 98 99.
Rym: you realized in the Linux box.
Rym: I got going here.
Rym: I'm still using my Sound Blaster live.
Rym: I'm using my onboard and video Platinum, but you know what for recording the show.
Rym: I have a $20 External USB sound card.
Rym: that is better than any sound card I ever owned.
Rym: But the point is I got the all 32 and the thing is the all 32 was just.
Rym: it was basically two sound cards in One.
Rym: it had a Sound Blaster 16 just in it complete.
Rym: It worked perfectly.
Rym: it also had basically a MIDI card and they had there were.
Rym: it had separate DMAs and separate memory addresses and I remember in TIE fighter which hitherto it had no sound.
Rym: I Did the configuration after I got this all 32 installed?
Rym: I figured it out And I and I set up the wave sounds and all those things to play from the Sound Blaster.
Scott: Also the red book audio from the CD.
Rym: Yes, all that played through the Sound Blaster.
Rym: but there I could specify in TIE fighter and a lot of other games a Separate memory location to send the MIDI information to.
Rym: so it played the MIDI which was all the music in that game from this separate thing and It was like night and day.
Rym: it sounded better than I had ever heard it sound before Because the MIDI just sounded like crap on the old Sound Blaster.
Scott: Yeah, the MIDI is like people don't realize this right MIDI.
Scott: we could do a show.
Scott: I'll have to do a show on MIDI but some day.
Scott: the MIDI basically instruments that were in the Sound Blaster 16.
Scott: They're classic.
Scott: I love them, right?
Scott: But if you take those same MIDI files and send them to a modern sound card or even to an all 32.
Rym: Yeah It's completely different because it had sound fonts.
Rym: I could load different instruments into my sound card on the low level in its own memory.
Rym: Oh my god I would go around like I remember I would invite friends over and we would sit around Listening to MIDI files.
Scott: Yeah, because they're basically MIDI is a set of instructions that tells a machine You know what to play.
Scott: so they'd a with the instrument in this memory address Say hit the drum now and then again now and then again now and then now three times, you know It's just instructions on how to play a music.
Scott: So if you have a Sound Blaster 16, you just send a MIDI file to it, you know, how does it play this file?
Scott: Well, it has in digital instruments in it and it plays them.
Scott: If your sound card is different or better digital instruments in it the same file the same set of instructions will sound different Because what's actually generating the noise is different.
Scott: it's interpreting those instructions differently.
Scott: It's not like a an actual analog wave recorded like you'll get an mp3 or wave file.
Scott: It's you know, just you know, it's like sheet music if I give the same sheet music to different people with two different instruments.
Scott: Right, so different sound cards are different instruments when it comes to MIDI.
Scott: So when I played MIDI files in the Sound Blaster live and they didn't sound like the Sound Blaster 16 I was simultaneously amazed and disappointed.
Scott: Okay, this show didn't have a lot of focus but I don't really care.
Scott: that's fine.
Rym: it's all Dave and Joel style.
Scott: I wanted to talk more about like, you know, the old nostalgia of taking an Apple 2 and you know The noises when you turn it on and the smells and the.
Rym: I remember the old nostalgia of holding down f5 to boot into.
Rym: I remember the old nostalgia of breaking into the computer in the over here to go.
Rym: Every time I turned on an old computer it checked to see if there was a floppy to boot You want me to go to.
Scott: I can go plug the computers in and turn them on.
Scott: we can hear the noise.
Rym: I have the drive death rattle of a cup when you and you know it.
Rym: I remember as a kid sitting there and you know you'd be in the computer lab like after school and someone's loading up a game.
Rym: or they're like They've got the disc with their project and they're gonna like read it and then you hear And then suddenly everyone looks over because we all know that that disc is fucked.
Scott: Yeah, hi floppies are so bad.
Rym: remember you could make a bomb out of a floppy.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know.
Rym: You can't do that with the CD.
Scott: No All right.
Scott: I think the show is over.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: we talked a lot about other stuff.
Rym: I talked about my skis.
Rym: I'm excited.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: Oh, yeah The stock market, right?
Rym: So on Friday like went down a whole bunch and it was ready to put this in the wrong part of the show.
Rym: I just it's a it's a. it's not a stinger, but it's a follow-up it.
Rym: so I was sitting at work and I'm working on stuff and I'm in this meeting and I'm working on stuff and listening and talking working listening talking and Then I notice that the Dow has just gotten to 9,000.
Rym: Oh, so I go to YouTube and I turn my speakers up and I play.
Rym: his power level is over 9,000 9,000.
Rym: Everyone looks at me and they didn't know what it was, but they got it.
Rym: I don't know if it's gonna become a meme at my work.
Rym: I don't know if I've spread that in some small way But I was happy that later when I went to FARC someone posted that pretty early as well.
Rym: They should have.
Rym: it's.
Scott: it's sort of the obvious joke to make which is always.
Scott: the problem is when a joke is obvious is less Funny, but at the same time I will all.
Scott: but at the other hand if it wasn't made if no one made the joke It would be sad.
Scott: It's like a joke that must be made Always fine, it's over 9,000.
Rym: hilarious for the rest of my days.
Scott: We got to find something else that's gonna go over 9,000.
Scott: Maybe some football player were like, you know achieve 9,000 rushing.
Rym: Oh my god You realize the nine thousandth episode of GeekNights is gonna be fucking fantastic.
Scott: I don't even know what episode this is Like six hundred and something.
Scott: I think we're at 1000 yet.
Rym: We got a long way to go.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.