Rym: It's Tuesday December 23rd.
Scott: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights tonight Illuminati from Steve Jackson games.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: I'm not doing any one not going to work at least until January 5th.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, it's weird to come home and have Scott already home doors still locked because he clearly hasn't gone outside.
Scott: Why would I go outside if I didn't have to?
Scott: don't you bring in the mail cuz I didn't you know what?
Scott: no no Maybe you should.
Scott: there's probably mail in there.
Scott: It could be good mail - it's holiday time.
Scott: Maybe there's like something awesome out there.
Rym: Maybe maybe if someone went outside.
Rym: He could get it.
Scott: I'm not going outside.
Scott: Well.
Scott: It's cold.
Rym: So what are you gonna?
Rym: Do when I'm out of town?
Rym: What are you gonna?
Rym: Do when you run out of food?
Scott: I'm not running out of food.
Scott: first of all I got plenty of food food to last until Tuesday.
Scott: I got plaid.
Scott: Don't worry about it.
Scott: I'm I got it covered.
Rym: Don't eat my ramen.
Scott: I'm gonna eat all your ramen My fancy ramen.
Rym: I bought the dollar 80 ramen from the Yaga Ramar kidding.
Scott: I'm gonna eat the $3 ramen.
Rym: That's how I'm taking it with me.
Rym: you add that that ramen.
Rym: I'm looking forward to that.
Scott: I'm gonna eat it today.
Scott: You know what I already ate it.
Scott: Oh, did you know I did?
Scott: Anyway, so of course you know I'm working on the website.
Scott: I'm doing all sorts of other stuff.
Rym: Work it out.
Rym: when I came home you were playing dr.
Rym: Mario by.
Scott: your started playing dr.
Scott: Mario five minutes before he came.
Rym: That's what I used to tell my mom.
Scott: But it's true.
Rym: well see when I told my mom it wasn't yeah I know, but she'd like get up in the morning.
Scott: Don't look at my computer.
Scott: the VMware is open.
Scott: this website working.
Rym: It's kind of like that old Foxtrot from way back.
Rym: But my mom would get up in the morning when I was in high school on like a weekend or in the summer and she'd Come down and she'd be in the kitchen She see me in the den, and she'd be like up early a and I'd be like yes.
Rym: I am up early.
Rym: I did not in fact stay up all night.
Rym: I used to stay up all night playing games.
Rym: Yeah, those were good days.
Scott: No they weren't hurt the worst days.
Scott: Those were great.
Rym: It's not like I went to school.
Scott: So I played some NS today, and it was just one game of NS.
Scott: That was just so so great.
Scott: It's great.
Scott: I was on the aliens all right.
Scott: We had like two hives, but we were having trouble.
Scott: He couldn't really really overpower him.
Scott: You know it's like we tried to go into biodome.
Scott: No good, you know lately.
Rym: I've been in a lot of these not really a full stalemate But like the Marines will get outside There'll be a two hive game.
Rym: Marines are outside of one of them And they build sieges and the aliens respond by having like six gorgeous heal the thing yeah And the Marines can't quite break through and it's just a race of who can hold out longer.
Scott: Yeah, we couldn't.
Scott: you know we had a bunch of rez, but they you know we were holding them tight and you know we pushed him back from furnace and They tried to reach out and get laser drilling.
Scott: we pushed them back over there.
Rym: I learned if you stand just like under like right inside that lava waterfall, and you do it just perfectly Skullics will jump at you and die.
Rym: yeah, and fades can't get you.
Scott: the lava waterfall is pretty fun.
Scott: In fact when we when we won the map or was it a previous iteration I don't know if it was the same game, but when we won that there was a victory jump into the lava.
Rym: I The last and as game I played the absolute last one.
Rym: I was entrusted with the one jetpack and the one GL And my job was to go around all the places where gorges were laming it up, and you flew into the lava.
Rym: I was doing fine.
Rym: for like 10 minutes I was I was kicking some ass with my jetpack and the whole time the commander's like Rym I swear to God if you die and like man.
Rym: I'm cool.
Rym: I haven't died in like 10 minutes.
Rym: I'm doing fine, and then I you know no scam around the corner, and I went ah right into that Lava.
Rym: All right, anyway, so I quit the game before the commander could yell at me.
Scott: Yeah, what's so?
Scott: where we're?
Scott: you know we're trying to.
Scott: we do like a Hive drop in bio and it goes down real quick And we got plenty of res But it's like we can't get in there to drop it.
Scott: so I go over there as a skulk And I poke my head.
Scott: they got one vent is welded up And I poke my head through one of the vents.
Scott: bullets come at me.
Scott: So I go to another vent.
Rym: So they got motion.
Rym: they see your ass.
Scott: I go to.
Scott: I go like one of the big open doorways bullets come at me.
Scott: There was like no way I could get into bio to drop this hive.
Rym: right you have sense because you could have done the slow walk way.
Scott: We had the freaking movement and defense right so we actually won before we could put the sense up.
Scott: So some some other people try to drop the hive.
Scott: it didn't work.
Scott: some other people didn't work right.
Scott: so then One guy's like a days down, so I'm like this is a chance.
Scott: so I go.
Scott: I'm run over to the biodome.
Scott: right I'm already kind of close to it because I was skulking around there anyway, and I'm waiting as a marine.
Scott: there There's no Marines gorge Running hive.
Scott: it was like I'm like I'm doing it.
Scott: I'm doing I'm doing it.
Scott: Everyone's like oh my god, and then it actually worked.
Scott: I dropped this hive and then immediately like the whole team appeared And it was like this place was covered with turrets and sieges and all sorts of nasty things that are all mechanical And within 30 seconds
Rym: there were like 10
Scott: bros ease Whole bunch of DC's and MC's and every mechanical thing was.
Rym: my god general bro regard You are a credit to the service Which my proceeds man NS is making me say bro a word that I would never use in my real life.
Scott: I only use it to say bro see I will sometimes say Brovman's has been used.
Scott: What kind of chambers you want?
Scott: we need our tea Bronos.
Rym: Okay, I was eaten by a bro knows.
Scott: Yeah, I was too.
Scott: All right anyway That was good.
Scott: You mean that sounds like a good game.
Scott: That's one of those epic victories, especially since I dropped the hive.
Scott: that did the win.
Scott: It's like and I was so nervous like I'm like oh my god.
Scott: Oh my god.
Scott: Oh my god Oh my god, it worked.
Rym: Oh my god I know that feeling like when I'm ninjaing a hive and I'm like alone and I see skulks like spawning Turning into lurks and flying away not noticing me and I'm like creeping behind.
Scott: Build the face.
Scott: I never do it.
Scott: I pulled it off like once.
Scott: but speaking of games that we play that are
Rym: old and awesome You know NS is pretty much the number two game, but yeah, you know that tribes too has always had this kind of insurmountable possibly rose-colored glasses Spectacle of amazing history in our view like we look back at this game And that's like the best game ever made in any genre any medium ever.
Scott: Well, uh, well greatest PC FPS.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, I guess it's a real good game.
Rym: As penny arcade said it probably accounts for a third of their total gaming memories.
Scott: Yeah, it's also.
Scott: they made like more comics about that one game probably than any other.
Scott: well, maybe Wow They made more comics about yeah.
Scott: Wow, but after Wow tribes, they've made more comics of that bang.
Rym: but Omnutia in the forums has done some research and there's a movement to bring tribes to back and it's a very tiny movement.
Scott: It consists of us.
Scott: if you download this file and you put it in your tribes directory Basically, you got to get tribes too, which is I guess you can get it from torrents or things like that, right?
Scott: You know what?
Scott: It's legal though because they made it free, but we've got it.
Rym: Maybe we should just host the executable.
Scott: Well, that's you got.
Scott: yeah Anyway, you get the file put it on libsyn and it's the patched up tribes too And then you install it and then you put this file in the tribes to folder and then you start a LAN.
Rym: Yeah, I want to play LAN single-player and if you go to a list of servers It'll show you pretty much every tribes to server that still exists and you know what?
Rym: There are about 70 people playing tribes too regularly.
Rym: as far as I can tell.
Scott: it's not really enough.
Rym: Half those people are playing on these bullshit mod servers, but half of them I played the other day Three full games of tribes on Katabatic or Katabatic, which is one of my favorite maps.
Rym: There were 20 people on each team.
Rym: It was the tribes that I remember.
Scott: Yeah, but it while it's the right map It's not some weird mod map and it's it is like a modded rule set.
Scott: It's not classic mode.
Scott: It's like version 2 with a lowercase V.
Rym: However, the changes as far as I could tell were minor.
Rym: one I had a tiny bit more energy than I expected and To the blaster shot twice as fast and bounced more which made it not the most useless thing in the world.
Scott: It's supposed to be useless.
Scott: That's the point of it.
Rym: No, it actually.
Rym: it was interesting having it actually work a little bit.
Rym: Yeah, you still can't take out the generators with it.
Scott: So I don't care Blasters supposed to be useless.
Rym: Anyway, I recommend all of you who are interested in tribes to click it on this link doing what it says and Keep playing and hopefully we'll get critical mass and bring this game back.
Scott: Yeah, one thing though is the game does feel a little bit dated.
Scott: I mean, it's like There's no voice chat built in.
Scott: Yeah, you guys everyone's doing the Shaz bots and things which is good Because that's the style of the game You play like you know, he's a voice chat like the terrain textures.
Rym: There's these blocky things kind of stretched over these polygons.
Scott: But when the game was new that like looked amazing.
Scott: But now it looks like poop when that game was new.
Scott: like NS looks better than that game.
Rym: I remember everyone standing around watching like the first people who got it at RIT playing it going.
Rym: Holy shit Look at those graphics.
Scott: Yeah now Waiting NS which is half-life 1 looks better than tribes 2.
Rym: However tribes 2 still has the fact that it's gigantic and it is indeed gigantic.
Rym: So plate drive - is great.
Scott: And now you gotta redo all my controls and relearn everything because the game is actually complicated.
Rym: Yeah, it's worth it though.
Rym: So I feel like if nothing else if you guys just play there and get proficient at the game with what servers there are We can have some sort of giant FRC like staged events where it's two teams that are playing ahead of time and we fight.
Rym: Maybe It'll take a while to get that thing going.
Scott: So don't don't think this is happening tomorrow But I just need a lot of people.
Scott: just start playing tribes - regularly lots of people.
Scott: We'll see what happens.
Rym: So anyway, you got any gaming news other than the fact that EA games are on Steam?
Scott: Yeah, so check this out.
Scott: This is crazy guy.
Scott: He's obviously a nut job and his name is Bob and he's got a company called Bob's games.
Scott: I don't know if it's the name of his company, but he made a game a DS game called Bob's game a game by one Person.
Scott: he's apparently spent 15,000 hours of his life making a DS homebrew game.
Scott: Whoo, he's a crazy, dude It's a complete nut job and you look at his game and his game looks like the game of a nut job.
Rym: I just got to clarify.
Rym: Is this the game of a Chiro style nut job or of a dwarf fortress Tarn Adams style nut job?
Rym: I don't think of what kind of that turn Adams is a nut job.
Rym: Well, not really a nut job, but there's a level of surprising and single-minded dedication.
Scott: Yeah, this guy's not these days.
Scott: He's a different kind of nut than either of those.
Scott: Uh-huh, but he's a nutty guy.
Scott: he spent 15,000 hours making a homebrew DS game and You know it's a top-down 2d adventure game and it's I looked at the video of it that he made and The games obviously also nutty but it's basically like an earth bound ish kind of.
Scott: You know, I'm not too interested in the game.
Scott: The point is is that he spent he made this game and he wants to now that the game is finished Like sell it as a real DS game, you know.
Scott: And even though I have no interest in the game and I think the guys are not Why shouldn't he?
Scott: I mean he made a DS game.
Scott: All he needs is basically Nintendo to give him like this DVD of DS stuffs and then he can make it a real DS game and it'll be on the shelf in the store And if people buy it, he'll make money.
Scott: I seen you know, and what?
Scott: why shouldn't he right?
Scott: You should be allowed to do that.
Scott: So a pair according to him, right?
Scott: He met with Nintendo in February to ask for the SDK He teleconference them and flew to the game developers conference that a face-to-face meeting.
Scott: He went to the Wario world website Which is if people don't know like Wario world is like the name of Nintendo's developer like, you know Like division.
Scott: So if you want to make Nintendo games you talk to Wario world and they hook you up.
Scott: He talked to them and they sent him to the marketing department.
Scott: I don't know why.
Scott: That makes no sense to me.
Scott: He talked to the marketing department and they of course said go to Wario world Which is the correct thing.
Scott: you go to Wario world that you buy dev kit.
Scott: So he applied at Wario world, you know filling out the application and it states that he will receive a decision in six to eight Weeks.
Scott: it has been according to him 17 weeks and he has not received a yes or a no, right?
Scott: He says he fulfills all the requirements.
Scott: But actually if you look at the application Nintendo has if he meets all of the like Objective requirements, but Nintendo sort of puts in some subjective ones in there.
Scott: So basically they can say no to ever they want, you know.
Scott: But they didn't say yes or no to him.
Scott: I mean like.
Scott: if they said no to him, I'd be like, alright They said no to him Sure.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: They didn't say yes or no.
Rym: so this guy being a nut job is Barricading himself in a room until that is clearly the correct course of action when such a thing is when such an Injustice has been put upon you.
Scott: He's barricading himself into a room until Nintendo lets him have the stupid dev kit so he can Sell his DS game that he spent 15,000 hours of his life making.
Scott: now This really is sort of the same situation that's going on with the iPhone, right?
Scott: You have a platform and people want to make software for the platform But there are some people making decisions as to yes or no, right you this can this is okay, and this is not okay.
Scott: now The problem here is not I mean.
Scott: ideally we would rather have just let anyone make anything They want as opposed to someone saying yes or no.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: No, there are two extremes.
Rym: I mean on one hand there's the Nintendo seal of quality the Apple whatever but on the other hand There is the video game crash in the old days caused primarily by the fact that a million non working unplayable Amazingly awful Atari games were made flooding the market and basically destroying video games.
Scott: that's true, but look at look at more recent video game history, right.
Scott: the ps1 the ps2 the Xbox one the 360 the GBA and the DS All of those systems have had floods of terrible games that were all approved Cielo approval on those games officially licensed games floods of them floods of terrible games and it hasn't done any harm.
Scott: really You know.
Rym: I definitely think that anyone who makes actually makes the argument that if we let bad games appear on our system Then our system will collapse.
Rym: That was true a long time ago.
Rym: I really think it was.
Rym: but nowadays With the wide access to development tools and programming tools and game design and publishing and all that stuff homebrew and I guess indie games is really where it's at.
Scott: Yeah, and in addition to that, right?
Scott: You've got I don't mind if they like Nintendo seal of quality used to mean we check it for bugs, right?
Scott: It's like we don't want you to put any buggy crap on here.
Scott: That's not gonna work, you know, because then someone says titty bucks in a Nintendo game and it doesn't work.
Scott: We're not gonna let that happen.
Scott: All right, and the thing is it doesn't even mean that anymore.
Scott: I mean that Zelda game.
Scott: there was a problem.
Scott: if you saved in the wrong spot you were you're fucked you're done, you know.
Scott: and there was.
Scott: There was a DS bubbly bubbly bus to move game where it just couldn't be beaten.
Scott: It was buggy and crashy all over the place.
Scott: So even now it's like if you're gonna pick and choose which games are gonna say yes to and which you're gonna say no to Then I expect there to not be floods of crap.
Scott: I expect you to not.
Scott: nothing should have a bug on it Everything should be perfect and nothing should be crappy or in the very least.
Rym: I would even be okay With them just having a clear objective list of what will and will not allow a game to be approved Instead of it being ambiguous like you don't know what's going to be improved or not.
Rym: and if they gave clear Prompt answers as to yes or no, and if no then why?
Scott: yeah, I mean look at the iPhone, right?
Scott: You have people saying yes or no, right?
Scott: But there are some things that violate the rules as Listed and there are some things that were rejected without violating any rules according to some.
Scott: you know Interpretations of such and you look at the App Store floods of crap floods and floods of crap.
Scott: So it's like if what the fuck is going on with these people.
Rym: the main thing I want what really bothers me Is that I look at my DS and I hardly ever play it anymore because I've already played.
Rym: like every good game That's out there other than a few that I know we're good as haven't gotten to.
Rym: but What new great games are coming on the DS in the next, you know, six months to a year?
Scott: Hopefully something let's see.
Scott: Waiting for the fucking fire emblem that I think is already out in Japan.
Scott: Where is it in the US people?
Scott: or fire emblem DS?
Scott: Step it up.
Rym: another advanced wars.
Rym: I've already gotten an ass in everything in the current advanced wars.
Rym: I need a new advanced wars.
Rym: I'll pay a lot of money for it.
Scott: I'm gonna get.
Scott: I'm waiting for the fire.
Scott: I guess chrono trigger just came out anyway.
Rym: There is other gaming news and I believe we should mention it being a gaming podcast right now.
Rym: gaming night show.
Rym: but uh EA games on steam and I think I can sum that up in a very short interesting phrase Too little too late.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, you know spore was having a lot of the EA games especially spore.
Scott: We get all this flack for their DRM, right?
Scott: So they put their PC games on steam now, but now those games are already old.
Scott: So it's like you think that now you put them on steam which has DRM.
Scott: the gamers accept and don't care about that.
Scott: Suddenly people bunch more people are gonna buy spore.
Scott: I mean, I guess some people buy it but not you know it's not gonna.
Scott: the numbers are not gonna look good on EA's end and I Think that they might you know either turn around on this or just sort of lazily go about it.
Scott: But I think if they stick with it and they put out like the next new game on steam right away Like when it's brand new then they'll see the sales on it and they'll go.
Rym: Yeah, it's hard to say.
Rym: I mean Maybe this is one of those situations where they're doing it people have suggested this on the internet or of course Everything is true that maybe EA is doing this now with the games.
Rym: They're doing so that when they don't sell well, they can use that as an excuse to say.
Rym: Well, well fuck that.
Rym: Yeah, maybe companies have done things like that in the past.
Scott: I don't know if yeah I mean you do something that you know Will fail because you want it to fail and then you point out that it failed but you set it up to fail and it Wouldn't have failed if you would have done it properly.
Rym: Perhaps perhaps I mean, I don't know.
Rym: I'm not interested in most of the games EA has to offer anyway.
Rym: So it doesn't really affect me as a gamer.
Rym: I mean in the end I would rather if every game I bought was just on steam because For all the problems team has it's the.
Rym: it's basically the Apple iTunes store of gaming as in it's the best one.
Rym: It just works.
Rym: the DRM doesn't really get in your way unless you're doing something stupid.
Scott: You know how to worry about losing your CDs or DVDs or anything like that or CD keys?
Scott: Oh my god game you have ever is always there.
Rym: always the fact that when I bought my new laptop I put steam on it and I just clicked on all the games I own that I also wanted to be on the laptop and now they're all there and they work.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, you know all these other DRMs, you know, fuck you.
Scott: You can't install your games on every system.
Scott: This DRM on the steam games.
Scott: It's you can't give the games to your friends, you know, but you know what?
Scott: No other limitation on it that gets in your way at all.
Scott: You can install it in as many systems as you want Then you can play it.
Scott: every works every time.
Scott: It's never a situation where you want to play your game when you can't or you want to install it and you can't.
Scott: So it's like the DRM is not even there.
Scott: I mean even the iTunes store has DRM that gets in your way You know, oh I bought 10 max.
Scott: I want to listen to my music and all 10 max.
Scott: Sorry It's not gonna happen.
Scott: you get there's like a limit of so many and it's you know, you gotta rip the DRM as bullshit.
Rym: Yep, so we'll see what happens with this.
Rym: I don't really have any predictions.
Rym: either way I mean, I don't know.
Rym: I don't know if anyone even cares about crisis anymore.
Rym: Like do people still play that game see that gay crisis?
Scott: like who actually plays crisis or cares about it?
Scott: It's something that just people who like to overclock their PCs get so they can show how many FPS is are there?
Scott: It's not actually a game people play.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: maybe PC gaming history ever since quite you know quake one has been filled with plenty of games like that where the Games existed not to be played because they were terrible to play.
Scott: They just existed to push the video card as hard as possible to show off all the fancy graphics That Nvidia and ATI could make more money, but maybe it's not terrible to play.
Rym: I mean, I haven't played it.
Scott: I can't say the company that makes the game makes a bunch of money because now everyone who wants to test out their Nvidia's and ATI's will buy that game to test it out.
Rym: But most of the people who care about overclocking also don't care about pirating.
Scott: I Don't know.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know either.
Rym: I don't know if I honestly do not know if crisis was a good game or not.
Scott: I played the demo of it and it was an FPS reshoot.
Rym: shit You know, I feel sadly like that.
Rym: that's the review I have for a lot of games that have come out in the reason recent memory.
Rym: It's an FPS.
Scott: Yeah Nothing special to write home about.
Rym: It's no try if you want.
Scott: It's no NS.
Scott: You want me to write home about your game?
Scott: You gotta be more than just another FPS.
Rym: You got it, you know writing home is perhaps not the best analogy because I don't think my parents even really understand to this day What kind of games I play?
Rym: But anyway things of the day.
Rym: I got two quickies here.
Rym: Quickie number one Voldo and Voldo dressed up as Michael Jackson Dancing to smooth criminal.
Rym: All right This was on Kotaku.
Scott: This is the people know plays Voldo.
Rym: You know, I hate that fact.
Rym: It's one of those like.
Rym: it's something that kind of bothers me.
Rym: But I remember I always played like Siegfried when I've been playing Siegfried since soul edge.
Scott: That's how awesome I am.
Scott: but Siegfried slash nightmare.
Rym: I always avoided characters like Voldo.
Rym: I never liked playing ugly characters.
Rym: I always play either of a shown any looking guy or a girl like in Street Fighter.
Rym: I always played you and Lee.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, she's not bad.
Scott: I was always M bison.
Rym: Ah, you see I always avoided him bison cuz it felt cheap.
Scott: No, it's not cheap.
Scott: It's awesome.
Scott: You get the slide.
Scott: Let's get the psycho crusher.
Scott: Oh, he's got the step on your head move and in the later ones He's got the jump up in the air and drop his hand on the back of your head.
Scott: move As a good moves, but anyway one day plus when he punches his fist is on fire But psychic fire.
Rym: when we had Soul Calibur 2 at RIT We were all playing passing it around and I started playing random characters just for fun And I ended up on Voldo and I started winning a lot and I realized over time that I'm naturally good with Voldo.
Rym: Voldo is my natural Soul Calibur, buddy.
Rym: Yeah, I Feel sick about that fact, but at the same time I would rather win shamefully than lose.
Rym: So I always play Voldo now and I'm really good as Voldo.
Rym: Yeah, but I don't know.
Rym: Voldo and Michael Jackson seem to have this sort of Association in my mind.
Rym: So when I saw this video it just fit.
Rym: I don't know what else.
Rym: I can say.
Rym: It's a pretty good video - I'll admit I started laughing toward the end.
Rym: It starts getting really crazy.
Scott: Yeah, it's like in the beginning.
Scott: It starts to get a little long in the tooth But then they sort of do more goods.
Rym: So but number two, I have to mention this the World of Warcraft Mouse for $100 $100 Mouse.
Scott: $100 I mean like $400 you can get like the best logic Mouse in the universe $100 World of Warcraft Mouse.
Scott: So anyway, does it have like?
Scott: let me guess if you just hold down the mouse button It actually clicks repeatedly for you.
Scott: Well, so you can use it for Diablo 2 as well.
Rym: Well, it's funny.
Rym: You should ask that because if you read down at the review the last positive note here quote works like a charm.
Rym: I'm just going to read this verbatim because this says More than anything what it is that I hate about the World of Warcraft.
Rym: Alright after a slight struggle getting my fingers used to the strange button configuration I found that I could completely change the way I played the game using the wild gaming mouse.
Rym: I Was never big on macros previously, but now I cannot imagine living without them Especially on my priest who can now cast healing on any member of the party with one click of the assigned button
Scott: While
Rym: it is nothing new for players who have already modified the hell out of their UI and set up 200 macros in the game for every possible spell and ability.
Rym: For a guy like me who's pretty much relied on the tools blizzard has given me in the past four years It makes a big difference.
Rym: If macros make that much of a difference the game is broken.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: I'm done.
Rym: That's all I got to say.
Rym: That's all I've got to say.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, what is a macro?
Scott: it is a tiny program that you know, basically allows the user to put in a more simple input in the place of a complex input and Thus the complex input was simple to begin with and a computer in it.
Scott: I'm not even gonna go down this road.
Rym: All I want to say is if macros like that or they are allowed then why isn't my macro that?
Rym: Walks out to the spot and kills monsters for an hour allowed.
Scott: Yeah, exactly, right?
Rym: Anyway, I don't have anything else to say.
Rym: I'm not gonna rag on Wow anymore.
Rym: I think everyone knows how I feel about it.
Rym: Though my boss showed me an interesting article about how IT recruiters if they will basically tell new people who are getting sent out Not to mention that they play Wow because apparently there's a big backlash among IT hiring.
Scott: Well, because originally people were saying yes, but I guess now they're saying no, which is good.
Rym: Yeah, I could talk more about that.
Rym: I'll talk about it on Monday.
Scott: Anyway, alright, so here's this cool video this guy took.
Scott: You know, I'm doing some Arduino actions, right?
Scott: Programmable electronics.
Scott: I actually saw the soldered the board.
Scott: It was actually.
Scott: it worked really well.
Scott: It's pronounced solder not in Australia, and I did a very good job of it.
Scott: Nevertheless It's pretty did a very good job of it.
Scott: It actually worked and I was very proud.
Scott: but so I'm looking for like, you know Mostly like electron simple electronic toys to you know interface with because that's how you get started with this action But also making it fun.
Scott: and this guy here He's got eight R2D2s, right that I think these are program like supposed to be programmable R2D2s.
Scott: you know, it's.
Scott: it's like you didn't hack them or anything.
Scott: and he programmed them all to do a gay gay dance.
Scott: and He's got 16 of them lined up and he has them all.
Scott: do the gay gay dance simultaneously.
Rym: It's beautiful.
Scott: It is a work of art.
Scott: And I just want to remind you it's a little Star Wars thing of the day.
Scott: It is the holiday season.
Scott: Everyone should remember Celebrate.
Scott: I Don't know if every geek out there knows this.
Scott: This is something that everyone should know but not everyone necessarily knows.
Rym: there are only three reactions to this Depending on what kind of person you are either the I already know about this reaction the falling to the ground Into the fetal position reaction or the there's more Star Wars Reaction.
Scott: Yeah, if you did not know I hope most of you know this already there is and was in the 70s I think late 70s.
Scott: I don't remember the exact year.
Scott: There was a Star Wars Christmas special.
Scott: it was the real deal made by Lucas, you know Everyone.
Scott: all the characters are in it.
Scott: the bookies are in.
Rym: it Worked at IBM.
Rym: the eunuch Santa gave that as a secret Santa gift on DVD to my boss.
Rym: Oh my god, and basically all the nerds in the department go.
Rym: Oh And she goes I didn't see this Star Wars movie.
Rym: Is it any good?
Rym: and she looks up having no idea.
Scott: If you have not seen or heard of these Star Wars Christmas special just you know.
Rym: when we got back after New Year We were sitting in his office talking and she walked up to the door threw the DVD at him and walked away without a word.
Scott: You need to see it because if you are a geek that is something you need to know about and have seen.
Scott: That's all I'm saying.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I don't know if you should see it.
Scott: No, every.
Scott: you can't call yourself a geek slash nerd if you have not known about and seen the Star Wars.
Rym: But I warn you this holidays It's kind of like no kung-fu master Can truly call themselves a kung-fu master if they didn't spend that month Punching that brick or whatever.
Rym: it is that the kung-fu people exactly exactly Punching that bag of sand breaking your arm on the whatever.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: That's you gotta do.
Rym: however Breaking your arm on the whatever is what watching the Star Wars but like you might think it'll be funny.
Rym: You might think if you have lots of drugs Available you might even imagine that you could sit around with your friends and make fun of it.
Scott: The thing is the amount of.
Scott: I don't do any of the drugs, you know this but not even the alcohols and the tobaccos.
Rym: Scott Like half a teaspoon of rum once just to see what it tasted like.
Scott: it was bad.
Scott: It tasted like medicine.
Scott: It was bad.
Scott: if if you Want to make you know, the Star Wars holiday special good by you know with some mind-altering substances Not LSD because you'll never recover.
Scott: the amount of mind-altering substances.
Scott: You'll have to Use in order to make it enjoyable is so great that you will not actually end up watching it.
Scott: You will end up simply, you know Having your mind occupied by the substances and the and the wall.
Scott: the TV will not come into play at all.
Rym: I'll say one thing What if you have not seen it?
Rym: once you have seen it the prequels to Star Wars are suddenly citizen Kane.
Scott: Yeah You need to know about it and watch it.
Rym: That's awesome Right, so I can't believe we haven't talked about this like I.
Scott: it's one of those things where let me check one more time To make sure we talk about even.
Scott: I'm pretty sure we did not.
Rym: it's one of those things where we're sitting around.
Rym: We're like, what are we gonna do Tuesday show on?
Rym: what do you've been playing?
Rym: and ass?
Rym: What do you been playing?
Rym: tribes?
Rym: Gregola, yeah, great.
Rym: What are we gonna do?
Rym: the freaking show on?
Rym: and then I'm like, hey, wait a minute New Year's is coming up.
Rym: Let's uh, we'll have the annual game of this because it can only be played once a year Or you'll never be friends with your friends again.
Scott: Yeah But that's sort of just a joke.
Scott: I don't know how true it is.
Scott: I could actually play this game quite a few times.
Rym: I could too but the game is One of those games where if you're let's I'll put it this way if your friend group is on tenuous grounds Anyway, or if there are people in your wide group of friends who take games personally You cannot play this game more than once a year once a year or you will not be friends with those.
Scott: even once a year Might be too much.
Scott: But you know for people like us we could play it more.
Scott: We just don't.
Rym: yeah.
Rym: Well, we can only play it once a year for other reasons because the first half of playing the game again is oh, yeah I remember this game.
Scott: No, the second half is oh, yeah I remember if you play it too often that first half doesn't exist anymore because you remember the game.
Scott: So the game is Illuminati in by Steve Jackson in 1981.
Scott: I was negative one years old.
Rym: the game didn't actually come out until 1982 in July.
Scott: I was zero years old.
Rym: I had been alive for quite some time for almost six months.
Scott: in July you said yes Hey So I was at two and something months old.
Rym: I was six and something months old being the elder GeekNights.
Scott: Oh, no, it's the elder GeekNights.
Rym: four months It's a long time.
Rym: No, not really to a fish fly.
Rym: Yeah, maybe a moth goldfish In dog months.
Rym: anyway Illuminati the game is Based nominally on the illuminatus trilogy in terms of style.
Rym: I'm not going to talk about the illuminatus trilogy.
Rym: We're not going to bring that up.
Rym: That is a show unto itself.
Rym: I should have made that my my book club.
Scott: I Had to read it.
Rym: You've never read it.
Rym: No, it's uh Rambling is one way to put it.
Rym: Yeah incoherently hilarious Awesome.
Rym: I don't know but we're not gonna talk about it.
Rym: We're talking about illuminati a card game by Steve Jackson and Steve Jackson games It is.
Rym: it is a game that if you consider yourself a gamer that and your game your definition of gaming involves pens papers dice boards non-computers.
Rym: You have to have played the Illuminati game at some point.
Scott: I mean if you're one of those he was playing munchkin.
Scott: now You got to realize Illuminati was what munchkin came out of.
Rym: I mean Illuminati is one of those games where it's not the best game in the world by any stretch But it has game mechanics that will be novel to the majority of gamers out there and also the cards are humorous.
Rym: Yes, you see there are two elements to this game.
Rym: the theme and style alone.
Rym: if you had never played the game before Playing it as a group of friends without reading through the cards Will provide half the entertainment this game has to offer already.
Scott: Yeah, cuz all the interesting cards that come up It's like you turn over new cards every turn and you turn over a new one.
Scott: You never seen it before you go.
Rym: Oh my god, lol.
Rym: the first time I turned over the smoth and I read what the smoth was And I realized that I knew people who were in fact that kind of person.
Scott: I like the orbital space lasers orbital mind control lasers.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: Everyone wants to play him.
Rym: No one ever does because everyone's fighting over him.
Scott: Yeah, it's how it goes.
Rym: Illuminati is a game that simulates Illuminati.
Scott: Yeah, it basically simulates a worldwide conspiracy of organizations.
Scott: You know you start with this one.
Scott: every player gets an organization, right?
Scott: so someone's the gnomes someone's the Illuminati someone's the network someone's the The search Church of the subgenius.
Rym: now remember they're all.
Rym: basically they're all based on quote unquote real world Illuminati Conspiracy group.
Scott: the Church of the subgenius is real the Illuminati is real the network is real.
Rym: The gnomes of Zurich are definitely real.
Scott: I mean, I don't know what part is not real.
Rym: basically, it's a game, you know Twilight struggle is a game where what if the kind of Doctrine of the Cold War like the domino theory and all that BS was true Like really real?
Rym: then this game simulates the real world.
Rym: the Illuminati game Assumes that all the conspiracy theories in the world are real.
Rym: Yeah, and they're all competing.
Scott: so you start with this one group.
Scott: right and there are groups on the board.
Scott: You know every card is a group, you know some group on of people on the earth.
Scott: You might get newspapers You might get I don't know evangelicals or I try to remember rockers Psychiatrists.
Scott: you got a list of cards the city of New York.
Scott: That's good.
Scott: Cuz I don't remember too many cards the KKK the KGB Girly magazine.
Scott: Girly magazine is a great card.
Scott: See all these cards and you control the cards, right?
Scott: You take them over.
Scott: So you got you know, the I'm the slam the Bavarian Illuminati.
Scott: I take over the girly magazines.
Scott: Well, now the conspiracy is the girly magazines are actually run by the Bavarian Illuminati.
Scott: They're infecting the minds of all them the perverted men.
Rym: But then you can use cards to take over other cards and you'll build this chain where you have cards Hanging off of your main Illuminati from other cards.
Rym: you have the best conspiracy network.
Scott: Yep, so it's like, you know, the Illuminati controls the girly magazines controls the newspapers controls the orbital space lasers You know, so it's like orbital mind control lasers.
Scott: So it's like oh man, the newspapers are controlling our minds in.
Scott: you know all for the girly magazines all for the Illuminati.
Scott: and then you make this web that goes out in different directions of things all linked together and you try to build a bigger Network than the other people and you also in addition to building a big network you attack and defend the other players networks directly.
Rym: now Here's the meat of this game because that you know that that mechanic is in and of itself.
Rym: Not many games have used it effectively.
Rym: This game actually uses it better than a lot of games has.
Rym: this game was very revolutionary in a lot of ways.
Rym: But the meat of the game is that victory conditions are symmetric in one way and asymmetric in another way.
Rym: There's a base victory condition.
Rym: if you have X things connected to your thing at the end of a turtle at any point You win immediately game over.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Your network is this big depending on the number of players you win.
Scott: You have.
Scott: you don't say 10 you win.
Rym: Congratulations, but there are two more important mechanics.
Rym: Number one every player has a second victory condition.
Rym: For example, if I'm the UFOs Well, that's not a good example.
Rym: Actually the gnomes Ever have a certain amount of money on their home base mega bucks.
Rym: Yes, they win immediately game over.
Scott: So let's say right on the gnomes.
Scott: I've got one group, but I've got a bajillion dollars I win and that's it.
Scott: game over game over.
Rym: So everyone has these two Goals to strive for and you only need one of the goals.
Scott: you can ignore one and go for the other.
Scott: But really you all if you want to get chief your goal You're gonna need more groups to do it not less.
Scott: less groups is not gonna help you towards your goal.
Rym: now Here's part number three and then pursuant to that part number four part Number three is that you can help and hinder other players Directly with money and other influence.
Rym: Yeah, of course the game.
Rym: So say I'm trying to take the Robot sea monsters away from our friend Luke.
Rym: All right And Scott is mad at Luke for whatever reason and Scott decides that he wants this to happen.
Rym: I put my money in and I'm making my attack and we keep going around the table and people can take turns tossing in money to help either side.
Rym: So this Scott starts tossing in money to back me because he wants Luke to get fucked.
Rym: so then he can fuck Luke further.
Rym: But then Pete says you know what?
Rym: I don't want Luke to get fucked because that makes room and Scott way too powerful.
Rym: So I'm gonna start backing Luke.
Scott: Yep, so the way everyone has all this money and you have your money like, you know dispersed throughout your network You know and if you disperse your money throughout your network properly, it keeps it strong You know because money.
Scott: if you give money to a group it helps that group out and attack and defense, you know.
Scott: but you can keep most of your money in the central area where you can sort of spread it around as need be right.
Scott: and When you attack, you know, you use money to boost your attacking and other people, you know When you attack them use money to defend.
Scott: and but of course even if you're not involved in a fight You can put money in one side or the other.
Scott: so When someone actually fights someone or even just tries to pick up a new group off the table all Every single person on the board like throws money at it to try to make it happen or just not put any money to let It happen.
Scott: So you look like the gnomes who can win by having the most money, right?
Rym: They're real stingy and they try to keep all their money But at the same time they might have to intervene like say I'm about to win I have what like I need one more control of something and I win.
Rym: so I attack this low-hanging fruit somewhere.
Rym: Basically everyone in the game has to gang up on me or else I win in the game's over.
Scott: I'm the gnomes.
Scott: I don't want to put in that much money.
Scott: I want to put in just enough to keep him from winning.
Scott: but Everyone knows I'm the gnomes and that I'm hoarding money and that I have the most money and I'm loaded.
Scott: so they're gonna say I'm Not putting anything in.
Scott: you gnomes you do it All this money.
Rym: while Twilight struggle was supposed to be a game of brinksmanship Illuminati is a game of brinksmanship where Scott's about to win and Pete has a lot of money and Emily has a lot of money and I have a lot of money.
Rym: and I said You know what?
Rym: Fuck it.
Rym: I'm not putting in shit.
Rym: either you guys put up or peaches gonna win and the game's over.
Rym: Yep, and The brinksmanship gets epic.
Scott: But Danny if it actually comes down to the line and no one else puts the money in you go off fucking.
Scott: I have to Put the money.
Rym: Yeah And be out that people make deals with each other like tell you what I'll fuck Pete now But you have to promise to fuck him next round when he tries this shit again.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Cheating is also legal.
Rym: Well, no, there's.
Rym: there is the cheating rules and you know cheating rules because if you just cheat it's stupid.
Rym: But if you play by the cheating rules, there's like you're allowed to cheat at certain things But not at other things and it makes the game really fun.
Rym: Of course, it breaks the game too if you're good And basically the rule aid.
Scott: the cheating rules are like if you get caught you're fucked, but if you don't get caught it's okay.
Rym: Yeah, but there's certain things you can't cheat at.
Rym: Otherwise, it's just stupid.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, like when you're taking your income if you just take like a bunch of 50s and it's hiding in your network It's stupid.
Scott: Yeah, cuz you keep all your money upside down so no one can see it But you don't have to.
Rym: that's another cool thing about this game.
Rym: you have the choice always of having your money be open or not open as Then you can just put it face up on your thing or face down and you can control the pile and moves.
Scott: Yeah If you keep if you use for example a pile of all ones you can make it look like you have a really big pile Unless people are really paying attention if nobody's counting your money.
Scott: They don't know how much you really got under there.
Scott: Is it just a big intimidating pile of ones?
Scott: I mean I could put like two 100s and then like ten ones.
Scott: and so you think I got a lot.
Scott: But you maybe think I'm hiding it.
Scott: But actually I have a lot.
Rym: also like money on a thing is worth more in the defense of it than it is if it's From somewhere else.
Rym: So say I have a thing I really want to keep or I I really don't want anyone to attack it.
Rym: Maybe I put a bunch of money on it face up.
Rym: So I got 30 money face up on it.
Rym: Everyone can look at that and know there's no way in hell.
Rym: they can take it away from me.
Scott: Yep, don't even try try something else instead.
Rym: Yep, but uh, here's the thing that makes this get that.
Rym: This is what makes the game.
Rym: if multiple people Make their victory condition simultaneously They all win right?
Scott: So for example, right?
Scott: Let's say Let's use the gnomes cuz.
Scott: they're still the easiest example, right?
Scott: I need one more group and I win.
Scott: Rym is the gnomes.
Scott: He is ten dollars short and he will win, right?
Scott: I Just say hey Rym.
Scott: I'll give you ten dollars.
Scott: Give me a group.
Scott: Congratulations.
Scott: We both win Ta-da.
Scott: everyone everyone else loses.
Rym: now Scott and I have actually pulled this off together more often than other people because I Value.
Scott: we go for it.
Scott: I'm more willing to be a lot easier to win in a tie than it is to win alone.
Rym: I am more willing to be one of five winners against one loser than I am to be one winner by myself.
Scott: As long as you're a winner, what does it matter how many other winners there are see.
Rym: but at the same time?
Rym: Betrayal will often happen because it's like yeah, we'll have soft deals like I'll do this you do this.
Scott: Well, that's the thing is even though you agree to go in with someone on a tie, right?
Scott: If the game just as you play the game if you pull way ahead of them and they're sort of useless and they can't really Help you and you can win without them You don't keep going for the tie Just to give them a win when you don't need them to make the wind.
Scott: or the same time.
Rym: I mean, I've seen games where the game gets really into the game theory kind of stuff where you know Scott's being a dick and you know what?
Rym: I'm gonna totally betray him because I can pull it off and win anywhere.
Scott: I realize that the reason to go in on the tie is to make winning easier to sort of guarantee the win But I can get.
Scott: you can win on your own.
Scott: You don't need that shit.
Rym: if I can get Scott to keep helping me because he thinks I'm still playing along But I'm setting up the giant betrayal because I know I can pull it off then Well, that's great because the victory as opposed to defeat is great But the sweetest victory in the world is the full-on betrayal victory where you win alone Having betrayed all in your path.
Scott: Yeah, it's really even though the game's rules, you know are pretty, you know And you know, it's.
Scott: it's the attacking of the groups and the networks of the groups, right?
Scott: The the mechanic of everything is money being spent and everyone can spend money on everything Really makes it just like this giant Bargaining sort of disc.
Scott: It's almost like diplomacy.
Scott: in a way It's everyone discussing things everyone arguing and everyone fighting with each other all the time and then eventually someone wins.
Rym: it's It's an absolutely fantastic game because it's really really fun.
Rym: It's not the most Heavy on the strategy and tactics game.
Rym: There's a lot more Second-guessing and bluffing and I guess it's not mostly social mechanisms that are being exercised.
Rym: Not a good game to play with strangers I mean, it's a good way to get to know people but to get the full enjoyment kind of like mafia.
Rym: It's a game where you have to play with a bunch of people who you all know Really really well because then all that sort of metagame stuff comes in and it's like oh, I know he's a sap I'll take advantage of him.
Rym: Oh, he's got teamed up in one the last three games.
Rym: We know what shit they're trying this time.
Rym: Yeah, right Now one thing that I will point out Illuminati is a great game mostly because of the style and the theme and just because it's a good game.
Rym: but Steve Jackson games in general have a history of making good games and they actually made a game that is very similar to Illuminati but is more like I don't know.
Rym: Here's how to take the game.
Rym: That was okay and make it better.
Rym: it's basically just a an incremental improvement of Illuminati.
Rym: I Forgot what it's called.
Rym: I'm trying to find it on the Wikipedia page right now.
Rym: It's like a mafia one.
Rym: Yeah, what's it called called crime Lords?
Rym: Yes, Illuminati crime.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know if that's actually.
Scott: I've never played it So I don't know if it's actually better, but basically it's an Illuminati ish game.
Scott: But it's it's.
Scott: it's like there are expansion packs for Illuminati.
Scott: We just have more cards I'm all.
Rym: they just make the game better like that 2k pack.
Scott: Yeah, they make.
Scott: they make the game better because there's more cards and it's more interesting and more funny and more varied.
Scott: But the crime lords game is actually a different game that has slightly different rules.
Scott: as far as I know I've never played it But supposedly it's just a more modern Illuminati with a crime lord theme.
Scott: on
Rym: what Steve Jackson said himself when he talked about it at a penguin con a long time ago was that it basically fixes all the things that were obviously wrong with Illuminati and Fiddles with the game mechanics and the balance to just make it a much more solid overall better game But yet keeping all the fun parts of Illuminati.
Rym: Hmm someday, I'll just buy it.
Rym: we can play it and find out for sure, but I'd recommend checking it out.
Rym: I definitely recommend one person in your group of friends should own Illuminati and with us.
Rym: It's kind of the tradition that every year They'll be at the time at which the whole crew gets together and right around.
Rym: that time is usually the time when the chosen ones will sit down and play a full no holds barred game of Illuminati though.
Scott: another thing about Illuminati is that when you get the expansion packs more people can play it once.
Scott: yes Which makes it even better?
Rym: However, the dune game might really give Illuminati or unferns money in terms of being their traditional game.
Scott: Yeah, it's like the dune game.
Scott: diplomacy and Illuminati are all actually a lot more similar than their game mechanics would suggest.
Scott: yes because the overriding Aspect of players bargaining with each other You know You know arguing with each other and just sort of that whole thing sort of overlays.
Scott: all the other game Mechanics are just.
Scott: it's just what you're arguing over.
Scott: They're actually just argument games and bargaining games and diplomacy games.
Rym: That's all I got.
Rym: it's almost the xmas Festivus and such with the best of us today.
Scott: Yeah, but I Had the pole all set up.
Scott: I I'm about to air the grievances.
Rym: Do you have you suck?
Rym: cuz you realize after the airing of grievances are the feats of strength mister?
Rym: Can't do a push-up.
Scott: I have a feat of strength ready.
Rym: We're gonna roll a d20.
Rym: That's right.
Rym: I don't think that counts.
Scott: it does So know what the feet of strength was?
Scott: I set the pole.
Rym: There's gonna be no Thursday show.
Rym: don't even pretend and we'll see you guys We have our epic bacchanal of awesome with the front row crew.
Scott: well New Year's is what.
Scott: let me look at the calendar here.
Rym: We may or may not do shows next week.
Rym: I'm gonna try to record some sort of big epic thing with the crew But I'm not gonna promise anything.
Rym: is that often doesn't come to fruition?
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at frontrowcrew.com Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Scott: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.