Rym: It's Thursday March 6th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights Tonight the tale of why there was no show two days prior.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So as we alluded yesterday last night and as you were probably aware there was no show on Tuesday.
Rym: Normally, that's just because it's New York City.
Rym: a lot of times when things happen here Even if they're not the craziest news They tend to make the national news.
Rym: But because there was more important news going on a lot of people actually didn't know what happened to us on Tuesday.
Scott: yesterday It was like the biggest news day in a long time and the day before do all the news.
Scott: people were probably like yes Fucking news goddamn, but at the same time they were like fuck.
Rym: I have to work fuck Yeah, Tuesday was crazy.
Rym: I mean it was a my Super Bowl again Baraka.
Rym: Yeah, I'm not gonna talk about that, but the elections are close.
Rym: I want to talk about it though.
Scott: What do you it?
Scott: What do you have to say that the news didn't already say?
Rym: the news didn't say crap?
Scott: Uh-huh so what?
Scott: but everything you know about it is just from the news.
Scott: so if the news only said crap You know what you know crap?
Rym: no because you see I read blogs and oh cuz the blogs they know.
Rym: you know I know Barack Obama.
Rym: He's in fact.
Rym: He's in right there.
Scott: He's your best friend.
Scott: You call him on the phone every night.
Rym: We've actually got him here live in the studio, and I would if I had his number.
Rym: yeah Anyway, so uh we're gonna talk about that because we realize that Our experiences on Tuesday if nothing else kind of constitute one of those geek fables.
Rym: We haven't had a geek fable in quite some time.
Scott: We sort of hope forgot that whole geek fable.
Scott: how to not suck deal, but we should bring that back.
Scott: I think that's our Thursday foundation.
Scott: I think Thursday's been dry, so if we go back to our roots on Thursday We might find some some artists had like their blue periods or their metal periods or whatever.
Rym: It seems like GeekNights.
Rym: Thursdays had the movies period where we reviewed a movie every week.
Rym: Yeah And then we moved on into talking about food a lot And then we had the how to not suck it until we ran out of we sucked it.
Rym: how to not sucking?
Scott: Yeah, let's go back to you fables.
Rym: I think so cuz at least for now.
Rym: There's a lot to learn from our lives because once again We have triumphed or we're really good at taking Completely mundane things and trying to ham-fist some sort of moral into them, man So I was eating this peanut butter and jelly sandwich.
Rym: ah I don't think I can make that epic.
Rym: No, I think I could.
Scott: it was so fucking good.
Scott: Let me tell you the secret wheat bread.
Rym: so how to not suck at making a PB and J Step one not white bread.
Rym: first off you got to take the peanuts right.
Rym: don't get crunchy peanut butter.
Rym: stuff is usually nasty.
Scott: No, you know you do.
Rym: don't get normal peanut butter and then crunch up some fresh peanuts.
Scott: No, you're a fool.
Scott: Also, you see while I purchase the skippy peanut butter also you guys you want apricot jelly.
Scott: Yeah, that's apricot.
Scott: Jelly is good But while I you know I purpose I personally buy skippy peanut butter because that is the brand I like this available in the store.
Scott: That is not the best option.
Scott: No no no the best option is to go to the deli If you have a not shit supermarket and get the fresh just fucking made in the store.
Rym: peanut butter farmers markets are also good.
Scott: Yeah, I guess sometimes Usually the best place the one supermarket I know as excellent peanut butter is line No Publix in Florida.
Scott: if you go to the deli counter and ask for peanut butter pretty much every Publix has amazing peanut butter at the Deli counter.
Rym: all right Darryl Surratt go get some peanut butter.
Rym: there you go.
Scott: I wonder if he has Publix or if he has like Winn-Dixie.
Rym: well We'll find out if he's listening because he'll I'll get one of those messages a week later.
Rym: even likes peanut But he'll just be like yes, and I'll be like what?
Rym: Anyway, so uh yeah, I guess we should talk about some news.
Rym: I'm gonna hold Scott off new my news because Scott's news is uh No one was paying attention to the news at my job because you know we're busy unlike other jobs.
Rym: We do work all the time.
Rym: I'll say this I've had more fun doing this job Where I actually do work that I've ever had in a job before with the possible exception of the job at RIT Where I was a confidential courier.
Scott: You like being a confidential courier.
Rym: You know what because RIT jobs all pay the same.
Rym: It doesn't matter you get paid crap, and you don't do any work.
Scott: well you get paid not according to have what you do But according to the the level of the position you're.
Rym: it's kind of like the government.
Scott: the face It's like the per.
Scott: you know the person who was my boss when I was a student worker at RIT.
Scott: You know they.
Scott: she basically went and tried to make our the job that me and this other kid sort of shared.
Scott: You know ten hours a week each.
Scott: She tried to sort of make that position the highest level position She could get it to be at the student employment.
Rym: actually my last job at RIT was the second highest level.
Rym: No, I made like eight dollars an hour.
Scott: You know what I realized.
Scott: What do you think minimum wage is?
Rym: Like five something?
Scott: no, it's like six something and it's gonna be seven something.
Rym: It should be.
Scott: it might even I think in like a some years it might even get up to eat something.
Scott: You know what it should.
Scott: New York.
Rym: It's like has a higher minimum way.
Scott: You know New York State is much higher than the federal minimum Which is what it.
Scott: but actually the federal minimum wage is gonna go up and force the New York one to go up by a Little bit then the federal ones gonna go up again.
Scott: I was looking at a chart on the wall in the office near the sink.
Rym: Oh that man that chart that must be posted here under penalty of whatever the generic have to buy it at Staples labor chart The.
Rym: if you get hurt at work you can call these people well, that's the the word compensation.
Rym: Well, there's all those charts.
Rym: They're like your company can't do this to you And this is to you and they can't do this to you.
Rym: Yeah, you're not allowed to do this.
Scott: Staples basically sells to the federal one in the state one.
Scott: He just put them both up and each one sort of has the combination of all the little things that needs to have anyway.
Rym: Yeah, but I knew Adam Smith said minimum wage necessary.
Rym: All right, I go by Adam Smith.
Scott: What's your news?
Rym: Well speaking of Adam Smith One thing about New York City that is wonderful and horrible mostly wonderful because I don't care is that if you want a Versace or a Dior or a Prada or a full X or any of those things?
Rym: Rolik say what you do is full X. is you head down to or folklies a place called Chinatown and You can buy you know legitimate Chinese Versace bags for like five bucks.
Scott: in other words It's just a completely normal five dollar bag that happens to save for a space on it.
Scott: Of course, you know what a Versace bag is a completely normal five dollar bag that happens to save for a space on it only it costs a bajillion dollars.
Rym: Because I've wandered into some of those designer crazy stores and looked at some of these because there's stuff for men too.
Rym: Like.
Rym: there are designer messenger bags that don't look at like a Tag Heuer watch.
Scott: That's that's something that you don't want.
Rym: Well watch our chronometer.
Scott: It's it's a. yes it they're fancy.
Rym: No What you got to do is you go to have one sponsors that tells you the kind of money to go to the sharper image And get those like Soviet surplus like bomber chronometers.
Scott: No, you don't.
Scott: Yeah, you do.
Rym: Anyway, anyway You can get everything down there for super cheap Including the photoshops and the adobe.
Rym: adobe I actually have and I still use them because the thing is they're super high quality And I really don't feel bad about this at all, but I bought some really fancy Quote-unquote like designer leather hat like black driving gloves Down in Chinatown for four dollars.
Rym: total bootlegs.
Rym: They're just.
Scott: what did they do?
Scott: What did they say?
Scott: some brand on them?
Scott: Yeah, they do.
Rym: Okay worn off now.
Scott: So I figure you just go down there and buy generic leather gloves for four dollars.
Rym: I also have another.
Rym: They're thin solates but thins a late is spelled wrong.
Rym: You know, that's crazy.
Scott: They're not they're not.
Scott: no, they're not even bootlegging the name brand.
Scott: They're bootlegging the the trademark of the patented like insulation material.
Rym: You know what though?
Scott: That's like if they sold like dare text boots.
Rym: It seemed just as warm and just as comfortable and I still have both those pairs of gloves.
Rym: They haven't worn out at all.
Rym: They're great.
Rym: Yeah Meanwhile, I spot like $40 ski gloves when I was a kid and those wore out after like two seasons.
Scott: When you're a kid, you know technology of gloves was not as good as it is now.
Rym: Yeah, I definitely did learn that because ski technology is of course technology of toy has decreased.
Rym: Yes toys need to be made out of metal and if they shoot something they need to shoot it at eye breaking speed eye Breaking like how about gut-piercing?
Scott: anyway spring-loaded.
Rym: so New York City Decided to crack down on this and you know what?
Rym: It's trivial to crack down on this.
Scott: basically walk down the street You open your eyeballs.
Rym: Oh, look They said it is done a bunch of cops down to Canal Street and just roughed Everybody up because everybody was selling bootleg shit and there's.
Rym: I'm not gonna talk about the details But it's this crazy.
Rym: like they they busted a lot of people.
Rym: Yep, but Here's what bothers me about this article.
Rym: I'm not gonna debate the rightness or wrongness of Bootlegging or fighting bootlegging because it's a complicated issue.
Scott: It's mostly an issue of trademark infringement.
Rym: Yes, and I mean these people are breaking the law and what they're doing is wrong on a number of levels.
Rym: However, I'm going to quote a sentence from the article.
Rym: Well, actually no, I want to quote this other sentence first from the New York Police Commissioner.
Rym: Nobody's being tricked here.
Rym: Everybody knows what this stuff is.
Rym: My knockoff good see my weight.
Scott: if people know it's knockoff goods then there's no dilution of trademark going on.
Scott: So where is the wrong seat?
Rym: I'm not a lawyer.
Rym: So I'm not sure.
Rym: Yeah, but I can say this I'm not talking from a legal standpoint.
Scott: I'm arguing from the standpoint of what harm are they doing?
Scott: So it should.
Scott: should it be okay not be speaking of what harm are they doing?
Scott: Here's the sentence that bothers me because I want to do a whole People honestly not buying real for say's because they can buy fake per se.
Rym: I'll just say right now because I know someone's gonna try because we know how to pronounce these things.
Rym: We're making fun of them much like how movies you should see a really good podcast.
Rym: It's like Joe reviewed Alfred Hitchcock's classic pessite show.
Scott: Oh beside Joe.
Rym: That's a really good movie.
Scott: You know before like I knew the word psycho But I didn't always know how to spell it.
Scott: and when like Street Fighter 2 was like sort of a new game on the consoles And I got the instruction book and it said M bison.
Scott: His move was the pessite show crusher Because I didn't know better.
Rym: Ah You know what?
Rym: I'm sure no Bunga is right there with you.
Scott: No Bunga No Bunga, he's very he's very ambitious Dr.
Rym: Chaios, dr.
Scott: Chaios.
Scott: No, I knew dr.
Scott: Chaos.
Rym: anyway Here's the the the the sentence that bothers me in this article because this has come up in the video game industry in the anime Industry in the software industry and now it's here on Thursday in meatspace Quotes, I'm building up to this.
Rym: you see in New York.
Rym: The trade was worth 80 billion dollars and cost the city $1,000,000,000 a year in lost sales tax revenue now.
Scott: Oh, they're not paying sales tax.
Rym: Well, that's not.
Rym: no as in this is what they're saying.
Rym: all of those people who bought the knockoff Versace Would have bought a real Versace if they hadn't been able to get the bootleg.
Rym: So therefore 80 billion dollars.
Rym: The city lost a billion dollars in sales tax because obviously all those people would have bought the real ones and paid the exorbitant sales Tax because I'm sure all those people could afford the real ones.
Scott: I would like a $5,000 bag as opposed to the $5 bag with the same bag amount of money that perhaps None of the people who bought those bootlegs would have ever even considered.
Scott: buying a real legitimate Designer Versace, I would have to pretty much agree.
Scott: I I can't see anyone or I think we really think about it, right?
Scott: Okay, you got someone who just wants a bag.
Scott: They don't care about the name brand, right?
Scott: The name brand doesn't really mean anything to them.
Scott: They just want a bag.
Scott: They're not gonna buy a $500 thousand dollar bag no matter what.
Rym: nor are they going?
Scott: So it doesn't matter if this bag says Versace on it or not.
Scott: They're going to buy the cheap functional bag that suits them.
Rym: now They're probably gonna buy a legitimate bag not the knockoff bag.
Rym: the knockoff bags very specifically for people who want to appear hip But right.
Scott: so so take the rest of the people right?
Scott: These are people who actually care about the name brand.
Scott: right the name brand means something to them But they can't you know they?
Scott: so if the name brand means something to them And they could afford it Wouldn't they get the real stuff and then say look at me because they're so vain right that they care about name brands?
Scott: They would say look at me.
Scott: I have a non knockoff one.
Scott: I'm special.
Scott: if they're buying the knockoff one Obviously they can't afford the real one and they wouldn't have bought it if the knockoff wasn't available.
Rym: I am highly dubious of New York City claiming that they lost a billion dollars a year from this.
Scott: Yeah, that's pretty much.
Rym: I like the fact that basically what this Bloomberg told the news is that the city is going to force the landlords to get push All those people out and if they don't put legitimate businesses in their place there might be some big trouble in Chinatown.
Scott: Well, you know if they do put legitimate businesses in there I mean it doesn't really upset me too much and some of those legitimate businesses might be things that I want.
Scott: So you know it'll be okay.
Rym: Yeah, I just find this.
Rym: You know, I don't I really don't want knockoff merchandise personally no, but it's just it bothers me that so many people.
Rym: I mean, it's one thing to say, you know piracy is wrong and knockoffs are wrong and fighting It's a good thing cuz that's that's fine.
Rym: But to claim that all of that you lost all that money Because all those people would have bought your product if they couldn't have fired at it is not entirely true and not entirely legit Completely false.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So your news is much more important.
Rym: So yeah, you shouldn't spend too long on this.
Scott: I figured I couldn't save this until Monday, but a lot of people don't realize today was an appley day.
Rym: It was a big appley day, right?
Rym: We're talking about New York City two times a big appley day.
Scott: Okay, so basically Steve Jobs, he didn't say much but he had the.
Scott: he had his VPS who know more about what was going on saying stuff and Basically the only thing they came out with is the SDK for the iPhone which means People can make software for the iPhone right and looking at it from the standpoint of someone making Applications they made it pretty nice.
Scott: It's gonna be nice and easy to make iPhone applications if that's what you want to do and you have those skills and the tools available to you, right?
Scott: however I There's one issue that's not super 100% clear.
Scott: That's basically okay.
Scott: I make the application.
Scott: How do I give it to people right?
Scott: Well, what they're gonna do is they're gonna have not iTunes.
Scott: But we're like now.
Scott: or if you want to get an application for your iPod, you know You buy it on iTunes and then you transfer it to your iPod with the wire.
Scott: They're gonna have a store on the iPhone.
Scott: So on the iPhone there's a button that says, you know apps and you push it and then all the applications show up and you Push them and you I guess you touch them and they install on your iPhone, right?
Scott: now if you make one you sort of have to get your application into the store.
Scott: and If you decide you want to charge money for your application Let's say I make a game and I want to charge 10 bucks.
Scott: Every time someone buys that game for 10 bucks I get 7 bucks and Apple gets 3 bucks and that's how it's gonna work.
Scott: If I want to give the game away for free, then I don't have to pay anything It's just it gets given away for free, which is which is pretty nice.
Rym: Yeah, I mean while obviously Apple's going to have a lot of control over this and they're not gonna let us unlock Cards or anything.
Rym: Yeah, but I Can also see that because it's a piece of hardware like that and there is a lot of chance for problems or malicious applications.
Rym: While I don't fully agree with exactly how they're handling this and I think they could be a little bit more lenient I'm kind of okay with it because I can see how trivial it would be for people to make really really malicious applications.
Scott: I think they're trying to avoid the palm situation where you know people have these trios and they install all these applications on them and they crash all the time and they're Unstable.
Scott: and what you know, they're trying to put some quality control.
Scott: But the real question is is they they gave some details as to which applications would be allowed in the store and which would not.
Scott: For example, they said no porn applications.
Scott: There will not wait.
Rym: What kind of porn Application wouldn't that be?
Rym: Firefox?
Scott: Well, you could possibly make doki-doki mahoshin pan for the iPhone.
Scott: In fact, it would be multi-touch doki-doki mahoshin pan.
Rym: Oh snap Yeah, but I don't know.
Rym: I can't imagine.
Rym: Now I don't want to continue.
Scott: continue doki-doki mahoshin pan live-action Multi-touch iPhone.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Okay with downloadable additional action.
Rym: Anyway, continue proceed.
Scott: There's not gonna know malicious applications.
Scott: So if I write an application that just takes your credit card information and gives it to me or just calls all your friends All the time and bought and relieves the nasty messages.
Rym: They're not gonna let that go through and that would be the best application.
Scott: well, I guess if it lets you know what it's doing, it doesn't on purpose right now.
Scott: and Wow, they're not going to allow an application that unlocks the SIM card and allows you to switch away from AT&T.
Rym: As Scott pointed out when we were talking over pizza, I like how engage it posted that question.
Scott: Yeah, cuz rare.
Scott: this is a rare thing.
Scott: if you should go to engage it You know for no other reason at this particular Apple event You had the rare rare Circumstance where they actually did a Q&A like Steve Jobs and his two VP guys sat there for 10 minutes and took questions From the press which is so fucking rare.
Scott: I mean usually he's just like here's the shit.
Scott: See you guys now He's like, okay, we will take questions and it was like oh snaps.
Scott: So in gadget was like let me let me read exactly what in gadget ass because they basically Phrased it in such a way to try to get Steve Jobs to give the wrong answer.
Rym: They using a combination of negative not allow us to not make fall applications that don't unlock the SIM card.
Scott: Yeah, so let me read it exactly.
Rym: Come on I'm not pausing this again not editing tonight.
Scott: Here we go In.
Scott: gadget asks will sim unlock software be considered software Not allowed in the App Store?
Scott: The and then this is just a you know, they're they're live blog.
Scott: and it says answer colon a colon Steve colon parentheses pause parentheses double-quote dot-dot-dot Yes period quote space Laughter period.
Scott: So basically, I mean think about it.
Scott: will sim unlock software be considered software not allowed in the App Store?
Scott: Yes, you mean you said to think.
Scott: wait if I say yes, that means it's not allowed $20.
Scott: will this be considered not allowed in?
Scott: Yeah, that was a good good showing gadget way to go.
Scott: They asked the best question.
Rym: I think yeah, what did gizmodo do?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: It doesn't because for all the other questions, it just says q a q a but for that one It says Q. we asked, you know.
Scott: But yeah, the only question I read this really sort of makes the iPhone hot stuff.
Scott: You know the only other things I have to say or that first of all the iPhone.
Scott: basically They added every feature that a corporate Company would want in a portable phone.
Scott: So basically exchange integration.
Scott: They paid Microsoft money to make the iPhone work with Microsoft Exchange as well as that is possible.
Scott: full push email calendar syncing Everything and it's just full-on Hardcore.
Scott: so blackberry best watch the fuck out.
Scott: Also spore iPhone aim iPhone some other things you don't care about, you know.
Scott: But yeah, basically this is pretty hot because it means the iPhone is gonna you know have applications that work And it's gonna be you know more open than some other platforms like say your Verizon phone but less open than say the palm and I don't know.
Scott: It kind of makes me want an iPhone a little more.
Scott: the only disappointments I have are number one where the Google Apps Google Apps.
Scott: Where are you?
Rym: Hello the Google Apps don't even work because we have Google for domains.
Scott: half our stuff doesn't work right I know because we have Google for domains instead of regular Gmail.
Scott: You think maybe having Google for domains would give us an advantage over people with regular Gmail?
Scott: No, it totally shafts you if you try and use the mobile stuff.
Rym: Yeah, I mean Google groups is anyway.
Rym: anyway and to What you lost your train of thought.
Scott: sure it's over.
Rym: Anyway Things of the day.
Rym: I'm not gonna talk about this a lot as pretty self-evident But some of my favorite people to ever live were the Duke.
Rym: By the Duke, I mean Duke Ellington not too ill duchet.
Rym: Not that he isn't awesome, but he might not have existed.
Scott: One dude with seven guns, that's silly six guns.
Rym: Yeah, it's six guns but yeah or Dizzy Gillespie or any of those people?
Rym: this is a blog I found that is just videos of Awesome trumpet players.
Rym: wouldn't you just need the audio?
Scott: Do you really need the video?
Rym: you need the video?
Scott: What does it add?
Rym: let me put it this way if you're a trumpet player besides watching like incredibly inflated cheeks That that was I don't know how he played that way.
Rym: It's not a good way to play But you get to see like a lot of famous trouble players use kind of weird trumpets They always had like their one weird thing.
Rym: and also there's some trumpet battles.
Rym: a lot of like a bunch of famous trumpet players get Together and they all kind of jam and it's it's cool.
Rym: So check this out.
Rym: That's all I got to say.
Rym: What do you want?
Rym: Trumpets.
Scott: All right, so I found this dude on YouTube Via James Randi and his name on YouTube at least is captain Disillusion, I saw the camel case in the URL.
Scott: Yeah, anyway captain disillusion here He he has some really high production values on his little YouTube videos that he does.
Rym: his special effects were actually pretty crazy.
Scott: Yeah, it's it's rather impressive the the quality of these videos.
Scott: And basically what he does is he sort of makes these Children targeted videos even though they're good for I think adults as well, but they're I guess Supposedly targeted towards children.
Scott: and he sort of says hey, look at this In a in a sort of children's show kind of way.
Scott: see this.
Scott: This is a video someone took.
Scott: you see that.
Scott: Yeah, that's not a ghost.
Scott: That's a lens flare or you know, hey, look at this see this video these people made.
Scott: Yeah, this is how they made that video.
Scott: It's not real.
Scott: It's it's actually fake.
Scott: like now the best one is there's a video you might have seen the video on the on YouTube before of a Penguin like bitch slapping another penguin and then that penguin falls through the ice and he shows you look it's actually a fake.
Scott: the the first penguin fell through the ice on its own and They just photoshopped in the slapping penguin, you know, and he shows you how it was done and it's it's very good for Sort of teaching people.
Scott: Hey, this is real and that's that's not real All right.
Rym: So, um, we're tired and we won't talk too long about this and we went kind of long yesterday.
Rym: So it's okay.
Scott: We can get to bed.
Rym: Yeah, that is necessary.
Scott: But very necessary.
Rym: So there's no show on Tuesdays.
Rym: I've said a bunch of times and the reason for that was that some Abandoned Prostitution filled building and that's not just me saying that that was actually in the news now Just collapsed around 345 on Tuesday at 124th Street and Park Avenue.
Rym: now pretty much every Metro North train that goes anywhere near where we live goes through from Grand Central up, you know through Harlem and all that to 125th Street in Harlem goes.
Scott: a lot of people don't realize this.
Scott: you go into Grand Central Station, right and There's a whole bunch of tracks in there, but all those tracks you know, they sort of mix together and mix together and mix together and Coming out of Grand Central, you know other than the subway which doesn't really count But all the commuter trains the other trains at Grand Central all of them go out on four tracks.
Scott: There are only four tracks that actually leave like the tunnel and come out into the sunlight You know.
Scott: and they all all four of those tracks go straight to 125th Street.
Scott: So at 124th and Park If a building collapses, that's right next to the trains.
Rym: So all of them all for you Approximately two or three hundred thousand people use Metro North every day.
Scott: Yeah a lot.
Rym: So well that was from the news.
Rym: I didn't actually know how many I just know Sounds about right.
Rym: Yeah, cuz my trains always crowded my trains at the crack ass at dawn.
Scott: Yeah, and we're only on you know, one half of the Hudson line, you know This is the other half of the Hudson line.
Scott: Then there's two halves of the Harlem line and there's like three different or four different parts of the New Haven line.
Rym: Yeah, it's all.
Rym: there's a lot of people using Metro North.
Rym: but so basically this a semi abandoned under construction building Collapsed and it didn't get on the tracks, but they were worried that vibrations from trains might collapse it further.
Scott: Yeah, Metro North didn't give a shit about the building collapsing but the police are like don't run the trains like god damn it We can't do anything.
Rym: Yeah, there's also issues with.
Rym: they had to spend some time making sure the tracks were clear and making sure it was all okay.
Rym: Yeah, they always make sure of everything but as a result Scott calls me I'm getting I'm standing up to walk down Maybe get a drink or something to get on my train and Scott calls me.
Scott: cuz I get emails from the MTA.
Rym: if anything happens To my train I do too, but I wasn't looking at the computer.
Rym: I was standing up and Scott calls me.
Rym: Scott never calls.
Scott: The funny thing is not like to check.
Scott: the email said 315 on it But it was well after 315 that I received that email.
Rym: So, uh, he says yeah Metro North's not running building collapse and I go ah Damn it What.
Scott: and I'm thinking well if I'm stuck here, I'll just go to my cousin's apartment or my aunt's house or something.
Rym: Yeah, actually all of us us and Emily and Alex and everyone there were places.
Rym: we all could have stayed.
Rym: So we were pretty much already okay.
Rym: But still you know It kind of sucks to not be able to shower in your own house or change clothes or shave Or make a podcast not that we made one anyway, so I'm like trying to think of what we can do.
Scott: I'm like, well we can get a car service.
Rym: Now this is this is the whole geek fable part.
Rym: I'm not gonna like do the whole story and then lead up to the geek fable because I want to get this over with and Because it's pretty straightforward.
Rym: When does that?
Rym: when life gives you lemonade kick its ass so Lemonade has an ass.
Rym: Since when does lemonade have something pithy to say, you know like that old, uh, if life gives you lemons make lemonade.
Rym: But what if you're allergic to lemons?
Rym: if life gives you lemons?
Rym: Well, I'm just shit.
Scott: make shit aid.
Rym: But When faced with adversity pretty much there are two kinds of adversity Adversity that can be overcome through efforts and adversity over which you have no control.
Rym: You need to make the determination right away.
Rym: Can you control it?
Rym: If the answer is no There is no point in even caring at all at any point beyond that.
Scott: for example, the Sun is going to explode.
Scott: well What the fuck can I do?
Scott: Not much sunglasses pretty much maybe a little little.
Rym: Or if Metro North had said Metro North and or if like say there's I don't know.
Rym: I'm trying to think of something crazy.
Rym: for whatever reason there was no way off of Manhattan Island Like there was no physical way to get off of Manhattan.
Scott: Escape from Manhattan Movie called that.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: I never seen it.
Scott: I know nothing about it other than there is a movie called Escape from an.
Rym: you really are lacking in your post-apocalyptic Mad Max kind of movie watching.
Scott: I saw your thing of the day yesterday.
Scott: I think that fills my quota.
Scott: That wasn't even in your thing of the day yesterday.
Rym: Yeah was no isn't.
Rym: oh that was it.
Rym: That was the kernel that we didn't link to.
Scott: no wasn't the kernel.
Rym: It was the yeah, but by the Attata was in the kernel.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Scott: You're right.
Rym: Well, it was on him and then it was in him.
Rym: Yeah Good guy anyway, so uh, and if you can deal with it, then basically don't panic Just think about what your options are.
Rym: So, you know, there's the four of us who all work in the city in different places.
Rym: We all call each other like alright, here's the situation.
Rym: let's mobilize now to avoid the the badness That's about and you had to think about this, right?
Scott: We're in the island of Manhattan, which is the center of civilization or effectively.
Scott: So right it is.
Scott: It's as much Center of civilization as there's ever been.
Rym: now I don't want to hear any crap from any of you like oh but Paris or Chicago, New York City is still the greatest city in the world.
Scott: Make an argument for say Beijing or something like maybe Hong Kong or Tokyo maybe.
Rym: yeah I think Tokyo New York and Hong Kong are at a similar level.
Rym: Beijing also.
Rym: Yeah, maybe LA has an argument, but not as much.
Rym: New York City is like the center.
Scott: Anyway, you know, we're here.
Scott: We have money and we have time.
Scott: There's a. there has to be a way for us to get from here to our house Without using the train that is not working now, of course we mobilize immediately.
Rym: So Emily and Alex are both like searching online from their job like figuring out different ways and I work across from Grand Central.
Rym: So I physically go to Grand Central and start like asking people and looking and trying to figure out what I can do.
Scott: I'm trying to think like well if the trains aren't leaving or coming into Grand Central Can I go to 125th Street on the subway and then get on there?
Scott: Can I take the subway to the Bronx and get on the train at Marble Hill?
Rym: Can I take a bus to the Bronx and then get on a train?
Rym: Can I take?
Rym: there's a million things and we had to you know?
Rym: Discount all these options and figure it out cuz and you got a kind of.
Rym: you got to think rationally.
Scott: You gotta take the water taxi to like, you know Sing sing and then get on the train.
Rym: Yeah, so everyone's researching and I go into Grand Central and I'm gonna say this this is why this is a geek fable the majority of the people there.
Rym: We're not reacting in a calm Calculated manner.
Rym: people were crying people were yelling at police officers people were like trying like standing in line on platforms that they assumed trains would come on and this large crowd was gathering and gathering and gathering and I actually got out of Grand Central because it was getting Extremely crowded and uncomfortable.
Scott: I went in I went up the stairs.
Scott: They took a picture and then I went out.
Scott: Yeah, but pretty much I saw like a pregnant lady like sitting on the ground against the wall like she's like Oh, well gonna wait and I'm like, yep, some why are you waiting?
Rym: that like not it?
Rym: Like.
Scott: I guess that's a good.
Scott: it's better than what it does other people doing.
Scott: but why are you waiting here?
Scott: Why don't you make a move?
Rym: Yeah, pretty much.
Rym: I'm gonna sum this up.
Rym: Here's what you need to do whenever disaster strikes like this think react and avoid the crowd.
Rym: Any disaster ain't no matter how big or how small?
Rym: You really don't want to be where all the other people are like for example that the Grand Central trains are screwed up.
Rym: Don't go to Grand Central.
Rym: That's where everyone else is.
Scott: if even if the trains start running it's gonna suck You yeah, let's say let's let's assume you go to the crowd and the best possible situation happens.
Scott: Right, the best possible situation is this you get on the first train that is going to your house, right?
Scott: You're the first one on that training.
Scott: you get a seat the train is still stupidly crowded and you're packed in like sardines.
Scott: It's hot and nasty It's going really slow and it's making a whole bunch of stops and it's gonna take you forever to get home.
Rym: You had to wait in the train station full of an angry mob being subdued by the police for a long time And it was incredibly unpleasant.
Scott: That is the best situation staying at Grand Central in this situation.
Scott: So why would you do that?
Rym: We were looking at different options like all right, we could just stay in the city.
Rym: we could get a hotel.
Rym: We all have friends around here.
Scott: We can stay well if I stay in a hotel I can go buy new clothes and take a shower.
Rym: We were looking like what if we take the Port Jervis line because there's a station that's not that far from Beacon and then hire?
Scott: Well, that's from there, but we could take Jersey transit from Penn Station But that only gets us to the northern part of Jersey and then from there We have to find a way to get back to New York across the Hudson River.
Rym: Yes, and not a good.
Scott: it doesn't work.
Scott: It's not a good plan for us.
Rym: Emily and Alex actually Came to the rescue.
Rym: like we're doing all our research and I'm in.
Rym: I fought my way up to the information desk and I asked The Metro North guy and other people I don't get these people who are going up to the MTA Like conductors and yelling at him like you.
Rym: better make my train go.
Rym: what's going on?
Rym: What?
Rym: and the guys are like, I don't know.
Rym: don't talk to me I'm stuck.
Scott: what you think you're yelling at the guy is gonna solve this big problem.
Scott: But somehow that's gonna help.
Rym: as the best part as we're leaving Grand Central The barricade truck was coming up and they actually were setting up queues to kind of keep people in an orderly manner.
Scott: Yeah, when I when we left there a whole bunch of police on the corner of you know, like 46 and The 42nd and what that?
Scott: what's that Street?
Scott: It's not it's that little tiny Street.
Rym: Yeah, but it's yeah, you know Those streets don't have names.
Rym: as far as I they're just those streets.
Scott: Yeah, I forget the name a little tiny Street, but they're all standing there getting ready for action.
Scott: So I'm like I'm getting the hell out of here.
Rym: Yeah, so basically we're not.
Rym: the whole story is after all our research Emily and Alex made the decision.
Rym: and see here's the other thing.
Rym: because we worked as a group out we all of us who trusted each other went in different directions trying to figure out What to do and then the first person to come up with a good solution Made a snap decision took care of it and then inform the rest of us to call off our searches.
Rym: Yeah, Emily bought us for Amtrak tickets to Poughkeepsie because Amtrak uses different tracks.
Scott: Yeah, well Amtrak uses pretty much the same track except instead of the problem right was at 124th Street The track.
Scott: the Amtrak train goes out of Penn Station up the west side of the island and then Onto the same tracks.
Scott: we use, you know, usually use well after the problem.
Scott: So it debts well.
Scott: above that It doesn't meet up with the.
Scott: you know Tracks don't merge until you get up to like way north of the Bronx.
Scott: Like maybe is that like?
Scott: I think it's like sputum doival around there.
Scott: That's what it's called.
Rym: So everyone's they a lot of people are panicking or stock or stock or that.
Rym: and instead, you know We already had we made our decision.
Rym: We had our tickets.
Rym: We went had a nice Chinese Korean fusion dinner a nice leisurely walk.
Scott: take it was only $25.
Rym: We went to the store We went to a bookstore.
Rym: We chilled.
Rym: Scott Didn't seem to understand how Amtrak worked and got really antsy When there was one minute before the train was supposed to arrive and they didn't say what track it was gonna be.
Rym: I yeah, I'm trying.
Scott: I don't like that action Scott.
Rym: You got to calm down.
Rym: Amtrak's not gonna be.
Rym: you don't need to worry It's no good.
Scott: I don't like it.
Rym: It's not like they're gonna say the train is on track for go go go.
Scott: Oh my god, that's sort of what they did.
Scott: We didn't have long to get on this.
Rym: Besides all the tracks are right there.
Scott: Yeah, I still don't like that action.
Rym: Also, you realize Amtrak actually waits for you for a while before they give up.
Rym: They'll actually pay like if if someone has a name ticket and they haven't showed up yet They'll page him a couple times.
Scott: They didn't look at my ticket to know my name or anything.
Scott: Well, I think track in any way done that in the past.
Rym: They did that a couple times when I took them track to Chicago.
Scott: Yeah, well, I mean that's a. that's a much longer kind of trip.
Scott: That's the kind of triple people bring luggage and you're waiting a lot.
Scott: You know, this is anyway.
Rym: I think you were overly nervous about the Amtrak.
Scott: I don't I don't like the Amtrak.
Scott: Anyway, it's good.
Rym: It's comfortable It's real comfortable.
Rym: Yeah, so yeah, we took that to any food though, and then on Poughkeepsie I had a dining car.
Scott: We pulled that dining car along with us.
Scott: We didn't get any food.
Rym: You could have gone down there and bought some.
Scott: no fuck that.
Rym: I've done.
Rym: I tried to do that.
Scott: I should have gotten free food for go.
Scott: anyway.
Rym: Yeah, so we know.
Rym: and the thing is the train was actually kind of full of other people who are smart like us and did The same smart thing.
Rym: Yeah, there were a few smart people a few people going to Albany normally like, you know all kinds Yep, and we get to Poughkeepsie and we check and Metro North doesn't seem to be going back anytime soon.
Scott: So I wasn't gonna wait around to see if there was a metro north train going in the reverse direction.
Rym: So we just hire a cab now.
Rym: This is this is probably when we risked our lives the most because that cab driver.
Rym: I Don't know if he could see.
Scott: I don't think I don't think he could see cuz he was leaning forward and driving poorly.
Rym: He might have been blind.
Scott: I don't think he was blind.
Scott: I think he just needed to go.
Scott: the I man crossed the center line more often than He was hanging well over that center line and he bumped the curb on the right.
Rym: They're like four times where I brace myself for impact.
Scott: Yeah, not a good try for that guy.
Scott: However, yeah, I didn't really think is you're in a relatively big safe vans?
Scott: I wasn't too worried about being injured, but I wasn't confident that he was gonna make it without incident though Yeah, but then we know we got up.
Rym: we realized we actually had a way to make.
Scott: you're in a cab and they crash.
Scott: Is the ride free?
Rym: Actually, I saw a situation where a cabbie was pulled over and the cop was writing him a ticket.
Rym: cuz he ran a red light Mm-hmm and the customer opens the door and the cop looks like yeah cuz the door open and the customers like Can I just go?
Rym: this is where I wanted to be.
Scott: Anyway, yeah, but you know.
Rym: And then the cop said yeah, and then she's like, well do I have to pay the cabbie and the cops like hell no Ah So that's I think the situation.
Scott: who knows what the law says about whether you have to pay the cabbie?
Scott: But regardless that cop that cop wasn't gonna arrest her for it.
Scott: Then basically if there was a law it wasn't going to be enforced.
Rym: if a camera doesn't exist I'm not paying that cabbie.
Rym: In fact, I might be suing that cabbie, but I digress.
Rym: Yeah Anyway, so our measure of success we realized on the way home was how many cars are still in the parking lot in beacon?
Scott: Yeah, cuz if the parking lot in beacon was still full of cars that meant that either those people who have given up right, those people were staying over the night anyway, or Those people hadn't made it back to beacon yet because you know for whatever reason they're waiting for a train.
Scott: who knows?
Rym: The parking lot was about half full.
Rym: Yeah, it was.
Scott: it was much more full than it usually is at that time of night.
Scott: so I think we got back to beacon before a lot of we But before we could have gotten back waiting for trade.
Rym: pretty much to have gotten to beacon at about the same time We got via Metro North would have involved the risk of Metro North not starting up again Because they were talking like it was gonna be down all night at first.
Scott: Yeah, we basically there was no information for us to make a decision.
Scott: We didn't know when it was gonna be back up, you know or anything.
Scott: So, you know waiting around for it was that was a big risky move.
Scott: The Amtrak was a sure move and also the Amtrak allowed us time to eat dinner and relax.
Rym: Yeah, if we to take Metro North and get back at any reasonable time We would have had to bang in Grand Central that whole time Miserable hungry hot sweaty and bored and taking a big risk on having that been a waste of time.
Rym: Yes, I have slept on the streets outside of Grand Central more times in my life than I care to and I do not want To repeat that you mean one.
Rym: Yes, that is more times than I planned on in my life.
Rym: when I was a kid I did.
Rym: I put the threshold of sleeping on the streets of New York City at zero and I've already breached that threshold.
Rym: I don't want to breach it further.
Scott: We should purposefully go sleep on the streets for fun.
Scott: That was gonna sleep in Lake Central Park.
Rym: I remember that cop was more comfortable and he was like you guys okay, and I was like, yeah waiting for a train.
Rym: He was like, okay He kept going Meanwhile it.
Scott: then in the morning when it was actually time for trains we go in and we see that all these other people were inside.
Rym: Well, they were just in the front.
Rym: There's like one cop watching him.
Rym: Yeah Oh, well that didn't look any more comfortable or safe to be honest.
Scott: No, we should have gone to like Central Park and slept in the grass been more comfortable.
Rym: Yes alone in Central Park Asleep is much safer than next to police officers.
Rym: at a well-lit populated area.
Scott: You could go where there's a light and a bench and a cop in the park.
Rym: Yeah, you do that.
Scott: The bench is more comfortable than the sidewalk at least.
Rym: Anyway, the moral not gonna do the wheel of morality.
Rym: Whatever.
Rym: It's pretty simple.
Scott: It turns it turns.
Rym: don't panic.
Rym: And if I don't panic, I mean don't lose your shit when things go bad.
Rym: Think react and stay away from crowds and everything will turn out.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Also Sadly money can pretty much solve any problem.
Scott: Yeah, that's it.
Scott: That's another thing.
Scott: if you want to be like Penn Jillette because this is something he often espouses is don't go anywhere or put yourself in any situation where money can't save your ass and I always have enough money to save your ass no matter what happens.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: No, that's not.
Rym: I mean I don't stand by that 100%.
Rym: That is the advice of a person who is a libertarian solely because he is wealthy enough to afford everything you could ever want.
Scott: Yeah, he's that's the advice.
Rym: Why don't people just buy their own police?
Rym: Haha.
Rym: I could afford it you can too.
Scott: That's that's the advice of a rich and famous person with a mansion in Vegas.
Rym: Yeah, it's easy to be a libertarian with an uppercase L. If you're incredibly wealthy you have your own compound.
Scott: Great.
Scott: All right, we're done.
Rym: We're done.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our crapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew calm.
Scott: Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Scott: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.