Rym: It's Tuesday, April 29th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, the board game Risk.
Rym: Let's do this.
Scott: So way back, someone lent me, you know, before I had played any Fire Emblem's, someone lent me the GBA Fire Emblem's 1 & 2, right?
Scott: I played the first one.
Scott: It was okay, but and then I played the second one, you know, since I had them both at the same time, and the second one was far as I didn't bother with the first one, and I got way into the second one, but then I forget why, it was when I was working in the middle of nowhere, you know.
Scott: I kind of put it down, and then even though I really liked it, like I couldn't pick it back up.
Scott: It was sort of one of those things where it's like, if you don't stay on the track, it's like if you get off, you have to get back on at the beginning, or else you're kind of in.
Rym: Kind of like way back in the day, I never actually beat Final Fantasy Legend 1.
Scott: Legend 1?
Scott: Good deal, who cares?
Rym: That was a good game!
Scott: Wait, wait, was Legend 1 the one with the tower that goes- Oh, that's a good one, nevermind!
Rym: Yeah, it is!
Rym: But Legend 2 was good, because that had that ultimate moment with the bad guys.
Scott: Legend 2 is the one I didn't play, but Legend 3 is my favorite one.
Scott: Actually, I think Legend 2- Even though most people hate Legend 3.
Rym: Legend 2 is probably the best one in terms of gameplay.
Scott: Man, I don't know, I'm not gonna bother about talking about that.
Rym: Scott, if I explain to you how the robot works, I think you'll convert to Legend 2, but anyway- No, Legend 3, your dad is a B2.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, yeah, but- The reason I stopped playing and never beat Legend 1 was that I was playing, and then I didn't for a while.
Rym: I was playing other Game Boy games and Game Gear games, and like a year later, I was like, "Oh yeah, I should finish this
Rym: game.".
Rym: And I didn't know which way was up and which way was down.
Rym: And I walked a bit in one direction, and then like 20 minutes later, I was like, "Am I going the wrong
Rym: way?".
Rym: So I walked in the other direction, got back 20 minutes, walked another 10 minutes, wasn't sure if that was the right way, said, "Fuck it," and never played the game again.
Scott: I started the same thing with Golden Sun.
Scott: I love Golden Sun, right?
Scott: And I beat Golden Sun 1.
Scott: But Golden Sun 2 is so much bigger.
Scott: And you reach a point in Golden Sun 2, this is a little bit of a spoiler, you basically have four characters in Golden Sun 1, and you have four different characters in Golden Sun 2.
Scott: But you reach a point in Golden Sun 2 where the four characters from Golden Sun 1 join the party, so now you have eight people, but you have to, you know- You sort of have to arrange a party of four, so four people sit on the back burner while you actually play with the other four.
Rym: Hey, what about Final Fantasy 6?
Rym: You have like 12 people.
Scott: I know, I know.
Scott: But the thing is, right, is that you bring over, you use a code, or you use a link cable to bring over the characters you played with in Golden Sun 1 to Golden Sun 2.
Scott: So it's not just, I mean, if you didn't play Golden Sun 1, they just give you four characters.
Scott: But if you did, they load your shit in as your stuff, exactly as it was when you beat Golden Sun 1.
Rym: Hey, even better, Destiny of an Emperor.
Rym: You had like 400 characters.
Scott: Yeah, but the thing is, is you get to this point, and now you have to manage, right, the items and the gins and the magic of eight people, which is pretty- And it's like at that point- Putting stuff in, taking stuff out.
Scott: Right, it's like.
Scott: at that point in the game, I'm like,
Rym: ugh,
Scott: and I started, and Golden Sun 2 is a lot longer and bigger than Golden Sun 1, so at that point in the game, I'm just kind of like, ugh, and I put it down, and then I really have a hard time picking it back up because I got to manage all that shit, so I got to restart Golden Sun 2 again, but then I forget the story, so I got to restart Golden Sun 1.
Rym: Did you ever actually play through like Final Fantasy 3 or 5?
Scott: What, the real 3?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: No.
Scott: Okay, because 3 has a similar- 5 was the job one, right?
Rym: Oh, so was 3.
Scott: Oh, those were both the job ones?
Scott: I thought 2 was the job one.
Rym: 2 was different.
Scott: Okay, but 3 and 5 were the jobbers.
Rym: 3 and 5 are the kind of modern style hardcore jobbers.
Scott: Yeah, I can't play them.
Rym: Both games had the syndrome of, alright, we're in the world, in the world, oh shit, that was a tiny part of the world, here's the real world.
Scott: Yeah, I like that part, that's a cool part.
Rym: Yeah, of course 4 was even better, where it had 3 completely independent worlds.
Scott: Huh, they should make Chrono Trigger DS, I'd play that.
Rym: You know, I probably would too, because Chrono Trigger is not the best game ever, from a game mechanic perspective, but in terms of one of those RPG style games, that game was badass.
Scott: I think the reason that Chrono Trigger is so great is that it's a turn-based, you know, RPG, just like the Final Fantasies, but it's still playable today, whereas the others are not so much.
Rym: 6 is, but only because of the story.
Scott: Right, yeah, pretty much.
Rym: The story kind of pulls me along.
Scott: And because it's easy, if it was a little bit harder, I wouldn't play it.
Scott: And also if the Ultros wasn't there, I wouldn't play it.
Rym: Ultros, I remember the best thing in the whole game.
Rym: Forget all the tragedy.
Scott: When you go up to that painting.
Rym: When you go up to that painting, you're like, wow, you see a painting of Ultros, and you walk up to it, and you wonder what the character's going to say, hit A, and it says, wow, that looks familiar.
Rym: And then Ultros fucking pops out of the painting and attacks you.
Rym: That's awesome.
Scott: Anyway, so back to my original point was that, you know, I picked up Fire Emblem, and I liked them, but I didn't finish them.
Scott: So I've been waiting for Fire Emblem DS, and they have said there's going to be Fire Emblem DS.
Scott: I'm not a fan of the console GameCube Wii Fire Emblem.
Scott: I want the DS game going well, right?
Scott: But it's not, they don't even have a release date.
Scott: There's barely any screenshots.
Scott: There's almost no information.
Scott: It's like coming later, maybe in the holiday season, maybe even later than that, right?
Scott: It could be a year away for all I know.
Scott: So I said, you know, I'm going to, there are plenty of, you go to the DS shelf and you see a lot of those no name RPG ish.
Scott: They look like JRPG games, but they're not quite really, you know, and you see plenty of them.
Rym: And it's hard to say.
Rym: I mean, I remember way, way back we were in a store and we saw a thousand arms and someone was like, I don't recognize, what's that game?
Rym: And then we realized it was kind of a JRPG, but also a dating game.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So Atlas are the people who made golden son.
Scott: I kind of trust them to be quality, right?
Scott: They had this game rondo of swords coming out and I looked at it and I'm like, oh, it looks sort of like fire emblem, but you can attack more than one guy at a time.
Scott: So like if there's three guys lined up, you can just go stab, stab, stab, and stab all three of them in a row.
Scott: Just like move your guy right through him.
Scott: And I said, oh, that could be interesting.
Scott: Right?
Scott: So I said, you know what?
Scott: Fuck it.
Scott: I'll pre-order this shit and then I'll screen it for everybody.
Scott: Well, actually I got it and it's like, it's okay, but I haven't played it that much.
Scott: And I don't feel this urge to play it some more, but I think I'm gonna, but it's not bad, but it's sort of weird.
Scott: It's not what I expected.
Scott: I expected sort of a fire emblem type of game, right?
Scott: A little, you know, tactics, final fantasy tactics, kind of move around a grid, cast magic spells, stab with swords, right?
Scott: But it's actually the fact that you could just walk right through the other guys and they can walk right through you and stab multiple guys in a turn basically means that it's not a tactics game.
Scott: It's a puzzle game.
Scott: They give you a map of bad guys and you have your guys and you have to sort of, you know, figure out.
Scott: how do I move my guys along what path, you know, considering how far they can move to where I can kill all the guys that are near enough to me to do some serious hurt,
Rym: but,
Scott: you know, be out of range of getting seriously hurt on the next round.
Scott: And if you like a puzzle game like that, it's, it's kind of a good puzzle game.
Scott: There's, you know, some RPG stuff thrown in there, like leveling up and, you know, magic and items or whatever, but that stuff's just all BS because it's not like you really have much of a choice.
Scott: You're just sort of going through the game, solving the policy.
Scott: You can't grind or anything.
Scott: You just kill all the bad guys on the screen, you know, but there's multiple endings and there's different, like I'm pretty like on the first map, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, you start as a shit ton of bad guys, like way more than you can handle.
Scott: And you've only got like three guys.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And like a, there's like a giant army coming from the South.
Scott: I'm pretty sure that if you found some way to kill that giant army from the South, then you get like the immediate awesome ending.
Scott: But yeah, if you, if that little puzzle game sounds okay, Rondo of swords, but it's not a fire emblem.
Scott: It is not, don't, don't think it's the wrong thing.
Scott: Like I did.
Rym: See, it's tough because on one end I want to play a different game, but on the other hand, I'm working on turning all my A's into S's in advanced wars.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I mostly picked this up because, uh, I kind of stopped with the advanced wars.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But instead of playing mediocre games, maybe you could watch some anime.
Scott: Yeah, maybe.
Rym: Got to watch that Bocorano.
Rym: I kind of want to review it full on.
Rym: Oh, well.
Rym: So, uh, in the news, instead of talking about gaming news in particular, I want to talk about something that we missed talking about last week, partly because, uh, we totally copped out on half our shows.
Scott: Yeah, something like that.
Rym: But at the New York comic con, we were walking around being pressed and I got some good little interviews that I'll pop in here and there whenever they come up.
Rym: And someday we'll do a show on like French comics and that interview I did with the French people will be relevant.
Rym: I do want to say the French comics are kind of awesome looking, but we, uh, we wanted over to the upper deck area, upper deck, as you know, it's making the world of Warcraft CCG or T C G as people like to say.
Scott: Basically I would have nothing to care about that game whatsoever.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But Gabe and Tyco of penny arcade who have opinions I often respect, uh, they were like, Oh man, this game is so great.
Scott: And also it wasn't the fact that they were saying the game was great.
Scott: It was the fact that Tyco was alluding to in the comics and in his post role playing aspects to the game.
Rym: And I was kind of like, Oh, which made us realize something awesome.
Rym: So this is an aside, but you'll hear about it soon.
Rym: You might all be familiar with the game of diplomacy.
Rym: If you're not, it is known.
Rym: Like if you don't know, if you're not a gamer, like a tabletop board gamer, or you've never heard of this, find one of your neck bearded gamer friends and be like, Hey, you want to play diplomacy?
Rym: Because he will explain to you that diplomacy is otherwise known as our breaker of friendships.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But, uh, we realized we take a game like diplomacy and add a role playing elements, even if it's a diplomacy sort of has a role playing element, but you can play it in a completely game theory.
Rym: Like, all right, Scott, let's gang up on Alex because of blah, but magic.
Scott: The gathering does not have a role playing element, but it did.
Scott: One could be added.
Rym: When I was a kid, remember there was that official way of playing the five pointed star where there were five decks of five different colors and you had to beat the two people across from you.
Scott: But it didn't have a role playing element in the rules.
Rym: Oh no, no, I guess like diplomacy does.
Rym: And diplomacy barely does.
Scott: it did barely, but it has some and it does have some, but, um, yeah.
Scott: So I was intrigued by that.
Scott: And actually a lot of people were saying, you know, Oh, D and D, you know, which we basically forsaken, right.
Scott: It's going to become more like a card game.
Scott: Oh, it's going to be like a video game on back in the nineties.
Rym: That was like the biggest fear of everyone in the world.
Rym: People like dragon magazine would have articles from DMS who were like, my game was ruined.
Rym: Everyone comes over and this want to play.
Rym: goddamn magic.
Rym: Damn you, Watsy.
Rym: Damn you.
Scott: And then they bought D and D.
Rym: But, and then everyone went on, like, but I don't think you understand the level of bitching that we had to go through.
Scott: But after reading Tyco's posts about how they were introducing war role playing elements into the world of Warcraft card game, you know, despite not liking the MMO, you know, just because they put the same theme on a card game doesn't mean it's got the same problems the MMO has.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I can't immediately just associate the hate based on the, you know, uh, light license of the property.
Scott: Um, you know, I said, Hey, that, that could actually be good academically thinking about it.
Scott: Like, huh, a card game with some role-playing.
Rym: And we, we even have some ideas, sort of a new thing.
Rym: I imagine you could make a kind of simple role playing game with cards.
Rym: That would be awesome.
Rym: But I also imagine if you took some mechanics from say birding wheel, but you had this kind of drafting card based character creation for one off scenarios, especially if it's interactive and a shared space kind of deal,
Scott: or even
Rym: like collectively making all the characters with the cards,
Scott: or even like if somehow, you know, like not your whole campaign or whatever, but like encounters could be set with cards, you know, it can have some of the fun elements that like the star fairs of Catan had with like the, you know, the little yes, no pads.
Rym: Or even say you, you, all the players in the game, there's this meta element where you have cards that cause external events, not from your character.
Rym: It's kind of like every player has a hand of like hand of God.
Rym: dungeon master does something things.
Rym: So we're playing and then say, I'm like, I want to spice this up.
Rym: And I just toss out ogre attacks in the night and see what happens, even though I'm in the party.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So that that element of role playing in the card game interested me.
Scott: So I said, Hey, we got nothing to do here, right?
Scott: Let's go over and we have press badges.
Scott: They will totally like lick our kiss our feet and let and run us a demo of the card game.
Scott: And we won't have to pay any money.
Rym: Now.
Rym: It was funny.
Rym: We walked over there and we're like, Hey, we kind of walk in front of this line.
Rym: We're like, Hey, we want to demo the card game and we'd like to film it and record it.
Rym: And the guy's like, uh, uh, uh, then he looks, he's the press badge.
Rym: He's like, Oh, right this way, sir.
Scott: And then, but first they were trying to push us on their world of Warcraft miniatures game.
Rym: I want to talk about that first.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And they're not, they haven't announced all the details yet by packs.
Rym: They're going to have all the details out actually somewhat before then, but there is going to be a world of Warcraft collectible miniatures game and warning bells were going off because one, they had to kind of like force us to go.
Rym: look at this thing too.
Rym: They put two incredibly attractive women in charge of making us like this game.
Rym: The rest of it was all just like kind of shlubby, normal gamer dudes teaching you how to play.
Rym: But they had these two women who obviously were kind of, they were booth babes.
Scott: I don't think they were booth babes.
Scott: I think one of them was actually the PR person.
Rym: But they were, they were so like, it was so transparent.
Rym: what they were trying to do to us.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: It was pretty odd.
Scott: I think that's the reason they set up the booth though is, you know, it's like, we want to push our new stuff, you know, more heavily than they want to push their existing stuff.
Rym: But then warning bell number two goes off when the first thing they say is, before we go any further, look at these figures.
Rym: Look how high quality these collectible figures are.
Rym: Look at that craftsmanship.
Rym: Look at that paint, the drop rates.
Rym: And she actually said the drop rates for rares in boosters are such and such.
Scott: Wow.
Rym: Drop rates.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So we continue and I'm like, so how's the game go?
Rym: She's like, oh, we can't talk about game mechanics.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much.
Rym: And I was like, at all.
Rym: They're like, not at all.
Rym: And I was like, okay.
Rym: And we kind of stood there staring at them.
Rym: Like, well, what the fuck do you expect us to ask now?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like, we don't give a shit about anything except the game.
Scott: We don't care how high quality your miniatures are.
Scott: If I want high quality figures, I'll go over to the origin booth where they're selling the, the revolt tech, uh, you know, yotsubox.
Rym: Oh man, that yotsubox.
Scott: And the Tezuka Moderna line.
Rym: Also, I got to say there was this, uh, Makoto Kusanagi figure.
Scott: I pretty much decided that that is the only toy company that, that should be allowed to remain in existence.
Rym: There seems to be this push that's getting bigger and bigger now, at least in the kind of anime and comic fandom area where they're pushing these very, very high quality kind of like, you know, there's the tchotchkes like the $4 PVC.
Rym: There's like this cheap ass Lupin or this.
Scott: It's like a gachapon from like a, you know, a bubble.
Scott: It's, it's cheap.
Rym: But now they're pushing these like super high quality, high class.
Rym: Like I live in Manhattan.
Rym: I got a fancy apartment with like ultra modern furniture and I have this figure of Mario and this Mario figure is so high class that it fits right in next to the paintings by real artists.
Scott: And on the one hand, I kind of like it.
Scott: And the other hand, eh, I could do without it.
Rym: What I was surprised by though, they had this figure of the major from ghost in the shell and the butt was somewhat reasonably sized.
Scott: Yeah, it was, it was a, it was, I'd say it was actually somewhat flat, which lighter than it should be.
Rym: I think that's just because of the, you're, you expected so much, like I expected to look around at it and poke my eye out.
Rym: And when it wasn't there, I didn't know what to do.
Scott: I guess that's true.
Scott: Anyway, so, so the miniature game somewhere Dave Riley's crying, the miniature game, very sad for us.
Scott: They didn't tell us the rules so we couldn't, we couldn't make fun of it.
Rym: Pushed him and pushed him.
Rym: And I kept asking like more and more complexly worded questions that basically were, what are the game mechanics?
Rym: And they started kind of slipping and we learned that it's like two on two or three on three.
Rym: It's not like these big battles.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So it's like, I have my three guys and you have your three guys and it's broken up by faction.
Rym: So if I go Alliance, I can only have Alliance figures.
Rym: And they admitted that yes, some figures are just better in every way, but don't worry.
Rym: The drop rates are real low.
Rym: So Scott asked, wait a minute.
Rym: So if I have more money, I can just make the best thing.
Scott: And they were like, uh, uh, uh, uh, the kind of questions that people actually care about game mechanics as are not questions that any PR person from an American game company is prepared to answer.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But they also admitted that there's going to be a mat.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Well, they said there's going to be multiple maps.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: And the drop rates for those don't get me started.
Rym: They're special.
Rym: Actually, we learned something kind of weird on the aside.
Rym: You know, you go to like, Scott asked about.
Rym: this was a good question.
Rym: You know, you go to like a magic tournament or whatever.
Rym: And a lot of people have these like big official looking mouse pads.
Scott: Like they'll play, you know, Pokemon, right?
Scott: And you can just play Pokemon on a table, but some people have like those mats that have like little squares, like put your deck here, put your Pokemons here, you know, put your discard pile here.
Scott: And it's, you know, and then it says like Pokemon is a big exploding Pokeball.
Rym: So Scott asks, uh, Hey dude, where do you get those things?
Rym: I see them everywhere.
Scott: It's like, whenever I see, whenever I see a tournament or something that people have these mass that they, that are designed for the collectible card game to be played on.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Sort of like the board in St.
Scott: Petersburg is just a, it's just a mat designed to play St.
Rym: Petersburg card game.
Rym: Actually just a card game.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: They just comes with a board to play it on.
Scott: And I'm like, you know, I see these mats around all the time, but I'd never seen them for sale in a store.
Scott: Where do you get them?
Rym: He's like the guy looks at us.
Rym: This is the other guy from later, but he basically looks at us like the guy who was actually demoing the card game, not selling the managers game.
Rym: He looks at us for a second, like we're stupid.
Rym: And then he says, you get him if you win regional tournaments.
Scott: And I'm like, Oh yeah.
Rym: And we, and we were like, so you can't just buy them.
Rym: He was like, well, you can usually get them on eBay.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, you get anything on eBay.
Rym: But the look was like, it was that moment.
Rym: Cause that was near the end of our little interview where he was like, Oh, wait a minute.
Rym: I don't think these guys are hip to my whole card game and world.
Scott: Well, I found one Pokemon card game play mat on eBay, but searching for Pokemon card game mat it's $6.
Scott: And it's not that Japan limited number three.
Rym: Only $6.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I don't think that's a, uh, I think that's Japan where you might be able to just buy them on the shelf.
Rym: But it's a limited number three.
Scott: I know.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Anyway, so the world of core craft card game, right?
Scott: We start playing it.
Scott: And it's funny because I didn't want to compare it or associate it to world of Warcraft in any way.
Scott: I wanted to sort of separate it in my mind from my opinion of world of Warcraft and examine the card game on its own as a card game.
Rym: We were really trying to be objective.
Scott: If anything, I was going to compare it to magic.
Rym: And furthermore, we were trying to kind of get a feel for it.
Rym: Not necessarily from the, is it a good straight up game, but also the, could you have fun with it if you're role played or didn't take it seriously.
Scott: And I still get the feeling even after playing it, that while I don't think it's, it's that great, which we'll talk about a second.
Scott: I do think that if you had a bunch of friends and you played those raids that you could get some role-playing on, I don't know.
Scott: And I wouldn't be, it was.
Rym: the thing is really leery because of something the guy said near the end where we basically, by the end of this interview, we're sitting there and we're like, so this game is basically 80% debt construction and like 15% luck and 5% tactics.
Rym: And the guy was like, yeah, it's all debt construction to which we say.
Rym: So then playing doesn't matter at all, does it?
Rym: It's just debt construction.
Rym: That's the game.
Rym: Why bother playing?
Scott: Just make a deck, then show your deck to the other person.
Scott: They show their deck to you.
Rym: And his response was no, no, no, no, no.
Rym: That's not true.
Rym: And we were like, all right, dude.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But then we were like, well, what about the rage?
Rym: The rage is where the game shines.
Rym: And he talked a bit, but the sentence he said was, I forget what raid about which he was talking, but he said, yeah, it's all about just the memorization.
Rym: Right?
Rym: So I played, what's it?
Rym: raid like 40 times before I finally figured out how to beat it.
Rym: And then I just made a deck that beat it like that.
Rym: And it was awesome.
Scott: I'm like, okay, so I can just buy the raid deck, look at all the cards in it, then look at all the cards I have, figure out exactly which cards I need to beat the raid deck.
Scott: Then what's the point of playing?
Scott: It's like, it's like just buying a jigsaw puzzle almost, and then solving it.
Scott: only I need to buy.
Scott: I can't just, I don't get all the pieces.
Scott: I have to keep buying more pieces until I have all the pieces I need to solve the jigsaw puzzle.
Rym: Now, at the same time, we went into this and I was trying not to compare it to magic.
Rym: I mean, I've played a bunch of card games over the years, a little bit, mostly by borrowing decks.
Rym: So I played the Harry Potter game, which was garbage.
Rym: I played Yu-Gi-Oh, which is garbage.
Scott: Yeah, I played, I played, I played magic for a while.
Rym: Pokemon was slightly less garbage.
Scott: Pokemon I definitely say is slightly less garbage.
Scott: At least I played the original one and I still have maybe a couple hundred cards.
Scott: That's about it.
Scott: Maybe not even that.
Scott: And that was definitely, it still has all the fundamental problems of a CCG, but in all honesty, it is the best one that I've played.
Scott: I'm sure there might be others out there.
Rym: But I'm trying not to compare it to magic, especially old, old, old magic.
Rym: Because remember, I remember when magic almost died and when like buying of magic cards dropped off and all the game stores stopped carrying it for a while.
Rym: And that was when I said, wow, magic is dead.
Rym: And it wasn't just me like a lot of players at the time agreed.
Rym: Magic is dead.
Rym: And the Fallen Empires expansion is what killed it.
Scott: I started playing magic when the Fallen Empires was just like, just about to come out.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: There was like this decay.
Scott: Like I bought like a revised and then a Fallen Empires booster.
Rym: And then the game kind of faltered.
Rym: Then it was like Ice Age and new players started coming in and the game changed.
Rym: And then the last game of magic I ever played was actually at a regional tournament.
Rym: And it was like three days after alliances.
Scott: That's when I stopped playing as I played a tournament in like Jersey at some hotel and alliances was brand new.
Rym: I remember I walked in and I forgot that alliances had come out.
Rym: So I walk in and a kid walks up to me.
Rym: He's like, you want to buy an alliance booster?
Rym: And I was like, no fucking way.
Rym: No, God damn it.
Rym: How much?
Rym: He's like 20 bucks.
Scott: No, it wasn't 20 bucks.
Rym: No, he said 20 bucks because it was a regional tournament, right?
Rym: Where else are you going to get them?
Scott: See, the thing is, I was at the tournament and alliances just came out.
Scott: I went into the dealer's room and they had plenty and they were $2.
Scott: They didn't.
Rym: So this kid was trying to scalp them.
Rym: So I was like, man, I can't win the tournament now because people are going to buy all the good alliance cards and win.
Rym: And then I walk into the tournament room and there's the biggest hand drawn poster I've ever seen.
Rym: It was like a big piece of poster with electrical tape forming the letters.
Rym: And it said, no alliances allowed.
Rym: Type one a only.
Rym: And I remember that was like the best.
Rym: I still fucking lost the tournament.
Rym: Like you wouldn't believe.
Scott: Oh, I got completely hosed because I'd only ever played against my loser friends.
Scott: And you know, we didn't know the strategies or anything.
Scott: Despite buying books and magazines.
Rym: I knew the perfect deck and I probably could have won.
Rym: I couldn't afford it.
Rym: So I made some poison deck that relied heavily on getting certain cards early on.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Anyway, so the World of Warcraft card game, right?
Scott: We didn't want to compare it to magic, but it's a game where you put down resource cards and then you summon monsters and then you attack.
Rym: It's every round.
Rym: You drop your resource cards.
Rym: You can put one down per turn.
Rym: You tap, I'm sorry, exhaust by rotating 90 degrees to the right.
Rym: And you then it's just colorless mana.
Rym: And creatures.
Rym: And the best part is the guy's like, it's not magic.
Rym: It's not magic.
Rym: But I'm like, all right, so I tapped this.
Rym: He's like, yeah, no, no, no.
Rym: You exhausted.
Rym: He catch himself.
Rym: And then finally I decided, all right, I'm going to get him.
Rym: I was like, all right.
Rym: So I played a creature and I was like, so I can't attack on the first round, right?
Rym: He's like, yeah, summoning sickness.
Rym: And I was like, what's it called in this game?
Rym: He's like, oh, so I forget what he said.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: He was like, yeah, it's just magic.
Scott: But basically, all right.
Scott: The thing is, despite the game largely being the same as magic, like the World of Warcraft MMO, World of Warcraft is fundamentally the same as the muds that preceded it.
Scott: Yet it was polished heavily.
Scott: All the annoyances that were on top of the fundamental flaws were washed away in the World of Warcraft.
Scott: Now, the World of Warcraft card card game has all the fundamental flaws of Magic the Gathering and other similar collectible card games.
Scott: But all of the annoyances on top of those have been washed away.
Rym: Now, I don't want to get into the long discussion of exactly why.
Rym: But, you know, people would argue like, oh, but magic is this magic is this.
Rym: And I guess we can take that to the forums.
Rym: I don't want to get into it, especially since this is our news bit.
Rym: Yeah, but playing the game, it was just magic, but they removed like some of the more annoying mechanics of magic.
Rym: Like the best example is resources.
Rym: Any round you can play a land.
Rym: Well, I guess they're quests and they have an extra little carrot dangle.
Scott: I was thinking, why don't you just make a deck with no quest?
Scott: The quests are not as good as cards as non quest cards.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So just make a deck of all non quests and you can use any card as a land in quotes.
Rym: Well, the quest do get you things they do.
Scott: But I think the quests were not nearly as useful as actual cards.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, I mean, I guess we'd have to see more of the guy.
Scott: I don't know enough about all the cards available.
Rym: The game is pretty much one hundred percent deck building.
Rym: And the guy was like, no, it isn't.
Rym: And he showed us a strategy.
Rym: He's like, no, what if you want to any.
Scott: What if you bluffed?
Scott: And I'm like, oh, that would.
Rym: it's like, you know, he was like, I can attack him now for five damage or I could wait until I have a whole bunch of attacks and then attack him all at once for the one round kill.
Rym: And it's totally awesome.
Scott: And I was like, but wait, I can attack every turn and then the guy can defend even if he just attacked.
Scott: Why?
Scott: Why would I ever not attack unless I was going to die from attacking?
Rym: And it just basically playing the game.
Rym: It was just this kind of simplified magic game.
Rym: It comes down to one hundred percent.
Rym: Well, I guess maybe 90 percent deck building and knowing what cards and knowing what cards the other person is going to play and kind of like a magic tournaments.
Rym: It was all about sideboard management and pregame tactics.
Rym: Well, pregame strategy.
Rym: Once you played, there were no tactical decisions at all.
Rym: There were only strategic decisions.
Rym: But you just made all those decisions before you played.
Scott: It's basically right.
Scott: instead of rock, paper, scissors.
Scott: Imagine rock, paper, scissors.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But instead of just rock, paper and scissor, you have like a thousand different things you can choose from.
Scott: Nuclear missile, nuclear missile defender.
Rym: So what you do, though, is you pick, you and your friend each pick a hundred of these secretly.
Rym: And then you pick another ten that you can swap in and out with.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And then you play a game and then you're both allowed to swap in and out.
Rym: And then you play another game and then you're both allowed to swap in and out.
Rym: Then you play a third game and whoever wins two out of three wins.
Scott: It's just complicated rock, paper, scissor.
Scott: There was nothing to it.
Rym: We said we didn't want to compare this game to WOW either.
Rym: And same with the collectible game.
Rym: But in both instances, the people who are demoing these games for us would basically every other sentence say it's exactly like WOW.
Rym: We have tried to recreate the WOW experience a hundred percent.
Rym: It is just.
Rym: it is WOW in cards.
Rym: It is WOW.
Rym: We are targeting WOW players.
Scott: Pretty much.
Scott: I mean, WOW has a lot of people and they're targeting collectors like specifically with the collectible game.
Rym: They were giving us straight up percentages of drop rates.
Rym: And they were like, yes, we really want it.
Rym: We expect people to collect every version and everything and collect, collect, collect.
Rym: And the primary focus is collecting.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So screw that shit.
Rym: And they pretty much even said that they're going after the sunk cost.
Rym: I eventually got the miniatures people to say something to the effect of, well, yeah, the more they have, the more likely they are to keep buying more.
Rym: You're not going to just give up if you already own all these figures, right?
Rym: And I was like, wow, I couldn't have said it better myself.
Scott: Wow.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So speaking of WOW, I have talked about this before.
Rym: I'm going to make it my thing of the day only because I'm possibly going to do something epic.
Rym: But at the same time, I'm kind of afraid of doing this.
Rym: But you see, the first MMO was Sierra's The Realm Online.
Rym: And I've talked about it a few times.
Rym: How I played this game for longer than WOW it existed, though that is no longer true because WOW has been around a while now.
Rym: But let me put it, I'll put it to you straight.
Rym: Not only is The Realm still online, not only is the website still up, not only are the forums still active, not only are people still playing, but it's $70 a year and there's still a free trial.
Scott: That's $70 a year.
Scott: isn't too bad compared to some other MMOs.
Rym: But what I'm thinking I want to do is remember this game had like 30,000 people in it.
Scott: See if your account is still in there.
Rym: Well, theoretically, I was given an account in perpetuity, but I'm sure it's not there anymore.
Rym: But what I could be, I think I don't even remember my password.
Scott: Fuck, if I saw the old email addresses.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Elsendar@geocities.com.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: It could have been merged with the yahoo account.
Rym: A yahoo account that I don't have the password for anymore.
Scott: You get it recovered.
Rym: How?
Rym: It doesn't, I don't have an alternate email address in there.
Rym: My alternate email address was the geos80s one.
Scott: Because I didn't want, I hate yahoo.
Scott: There has to be a way.
Rym: I don't think there's a way.
Scott: Well, anyway.
Rym: Anyway, I think I'm going to make a free account and go in and see just what the fuck it's like in there.
Scott: Are you sure it's actually like, you know, still going or is it just like a website to the port just now?
Rym: And it was there.
Rym: All right.
Rym: It gave the same response that it gave when I was a kid.
Rym: So I'm going to find out.
Rym: I'm kind of afraid.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: I'm just going to link to the realm.
Rym: You can look at some pictures.
Scott: Remember, this was the first MMO and didn't meridian 59 come a little earlier?
Rym: No, this game's a little bit later.
Rym: A little bit later.
Scott: They were similar in time because meridian 59, I didn't even hear know about the realm until you talked about it too.
Rym: It was garbage.
Scott: It was total trash garbage, like times a thousand.
Scott: Like when those games are coming out, basically all those games did was popularize muds because people are like, oh man, I'd like to play that kind of game.
Scott: Oh wait, they're charging a lot of money.
Scott: Oh, but wait, there's these text-based ones that are the same game, but they're free.
Scott: I'll do those.
Rym: See, but I remember at the same time there was one other game.
Rym: I actually, I think for Katie of all things was based on the same engine, but it was basically a text mud, but they kind of skinned it kind of like how there's that skin for dwarf or some people made like text muds, right?
Scott: But then they would clear a client application that would, you know, basically it was just a telnet, you know, program, but instead of showing you the actual text in the terminal, it would read the text.
Scott: The client would read the text and then render graphics based upon it.
Scott: And then you would click buttons in the interface and it would send the text.
Scott: So it was just like a GUI on top of, you know, the existing telnet muds.
Scott: You can play the mud with the GUI or play the mud with the typing.
Rym: So the realm exists.
Rym: And I really, apparently according to Wikipedia, which I just looked up now, there's still like 200 people in there.
Rym: Oh, wow.
Rym: What are those people like?
Scott: I watch one of those people is someone who remembers you.
Rym: That would be kind of frightening.
Rym: I mean, if elemental flame or Lorianna or L minister are in there, because Elminster was taken by some other guy.
Rym: I still remember the night.
Rym: it was sad, but when princess Diana died and I had a friend in the game whose name was princess die and he'd had that name for forever long before princess Diana died.
Rym: And I remember him saying in the public channel, man, I'm going to get so much undeserved shit for this.
Scott: That's like the guy who's playing Counter-Strike and his name was Osama bin Laden on September 10th.
Rym: And then, you know, having the name Osama bin Laden wasn't making any friends before that.
Scott: No, it wasn't.
Scott: But it was still.
Rym: besides you can change your name in Counter-Strike.
Scott: You can.
Rym: I used to play Counter-Strike with the troll in his names sometimes, but depends on the server.
Rym: It's not.
Rym: I mean, the realm, if I had my millions, it wasn't that easy to transfer my millions to someone else.
Rym: I basically have to go to like another account's house and dump it in the front yard and then change and hope that no one goes to the house and grabs it.
Rym: But anyway.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Now that we have new computers, you want to, you know, I remember a long time ago we said we're going to do the the wow free trial.
Scott: It's moving up in the queue, I guess.
Rym: Yeah, I guess it is.
Scott: But at the same time, I don't imagine it taking more than like four hours.
Rym: I think we should play every modern deathmatch because there aren't many deathmatches left in the world.
Scott: Oh, definitely.
Rym: Even though I contend now I'm not going to back this up because I haven't played any deathmatch since Quake three.
Rym: And when I say deathmatch, I mean hardcore old school frags and Gibbs.
Rym: And that's it.
Scott: I played a quick for deathmatch once for a little bit.
Scott: It was all right.
Rym: I'm also talking PC only.
Rym: None of that.
Scott: Halo is PC.
Rym: Yeah, but like Halo ones on the PC only on the PC because it's kind of a different game.
Rym: otherwise for a lot of reasons.
Rym: But I contend I think I postulate.
Rym: I guess that lithium to deathmatch for the quick for Quake two was probably the most skill based and best overall FPS deathmatch ever made.
Scott: I think that's mostly your sentimental values.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I think in terms of the cap on the skill, I think it had the highest cap, as in I don't think any human ever achieved the cap.
Rym: Maybe I know people achieve the the cap in Quake three.
Scott: And so my thing of the day here, right?
Scott: This is something everyone on the air has priority seen.
Scott: It's not really that new.
Scott: There's just a new YouTube video of it that got the links got passed around.
Scott: But this is like I hadn't seen it before, despite knowing it was old.
Scott: And this is like right up my alley of things that I think are awesome.
Scott: It's a robot.
Scott: The robot is inside the box.
Scott: The box is actually, you could say, is part of the robot.
Scott: There's a switch on the outside of the box.
Scott: You flick the switch.
Scott: The box opens and the robot will.
Scott: Well, the robot is the box, but the robot will flick the switch in the other direction and then it will close itself.
Rym: I will point out, I remember very clearly that in it not gotten not in the realm in Quest for Glory, you go into this bad place at one point with dangerous wizard stuff all around.
Rym: And there's a box with a big lever and you pull the lever and this hairy ass arm comes out and pulls the lever to make the door close.
Rym: It's exactly like your little box.
Scott: Awesome.
Scott: I like this box.
Rym: So this won't take long tonight.
Rym: talking about Risk.
Scott: Yes, it is a game that is very famous.
Scott: It's like a war game.
Scott: I guess it is a war game, even though I sort of don't want to dignify it in any way.
Rym: Risk is a almost completely random game that for some reason Americans have this fixation on kind of like monopoly or sorry or like headache.
Scott: Yeah, it has like this place, problematic trouble.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It has like this place in people's mind.
Scott: Like people know what Risk is.
Scott: Like a lot of people have played it.
Scott: It's popular.
Scott: It's on the shelves in anywhere that board games are sold, unlike, say, Settlers of Catan, which is not on the shelves.
Scott: anywhere board games are sold.
Scott: And, you know, it's taken.
Scott: Uh, it is a place in pop culture.
Scott: Had the Seinfeld episode where the Ukraine is weak, very famous, very funny.
Scott: All right.
Scott: But Risk as a game is really not good at all.
Scott: It's a complete waste of time.
Rym: I mean, it can be fun if you have like a Risk party or everyone's really into it.
Scott: Even when we had a Risk party, that's sort of like when I finally realized that wasn't fun.
Rym: See, the Risk party was fun.
Rym: The main reason it was fun is there was like the full on extended front row crew.
Rym: And we had three simultaneous games of Risk going in the same room, and it was pretty much just a giant, crazy loud socializing party that happened to have a Risk in the center of it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The Risk.
Scott: And it's a funny thing.
Scott: It's like when I was a kid, right?
Scott: Like I didn't know about the real quality game.
Scott: So I was like, Risk.
Scott: Oh yeah.
Scott: Real game.
Rym: All right.
Rym: See, I guess as a kid, I knew better because even I'd play Risk with my family and I, the whole time it'd be like, this is random bullshit.
Rym: That was bullshit.
Rym: This game's just random bullshit.
Rym: We might as well just flip a coin.
Scott: So my family wouldn't play with me.
Scott: I had to play, I could play with my brother and sometimes I could play with friends coming over.
Scott: But, you know, basically it's like the game, like I liked it as a kid because I liked moving things around.
Scott: I like playing with little soldiers and moving around a map.
Scott: And, you know, I liked rolling dice, you know?
Scott: But the game itself like didn't bother me at that young age.
Scott: And later on, you know, it's like every time we would play, like someone would just give up and quit or someone would like flip the board over, you know, it was getting really stupid and annoying.
Scott: And I felt like it was sort of weird because I didn't get, I didn't, I like, I blamed the people I was playing with.
Scott: instead of blaming the game, you know, because like I was sort of having fun moving the pieces around.
Scott: It's like when the game was sort of crumble apart before actually finishing, I'd be like, ah, it's you.
Scott: Why didn't you go through on the game?
Scott: You suck.
Scott: Blah.
Scott: And it was, you know, but it took a while to realize, oh, the game sucks.
Scott: That's why.
Rym: So if you like Risk and you don't play German board games, play German board games, at least play Axes and Allies, which is marginally better.
Rym: At least play.
Scott: I mean, you're even better off playing an actual miniatures game like Warhammer or Battle Tech or one of those.
Rym: Or even Castle Risk.
Scott: Castle Risk is bad.
Rym: Wasn't that bad.
Rym: It's better than Risk.
Scott: It is better than Risk, but that's not saying much.
Rym: It's like saying it smells better than poop, but God risk is just, I can say one thing.
Rym: Australia guarantees you the solid second place.
Scott: I guess it does.
Rym: Yes, it does.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Just playing Risk is just not fun.
Rym: And I'll tell you all one thing.
Rym: And I think I said this before and some people in the forums, one guy emailed me and he was like, Rym, I did what you said and I went at risk a lot now and pretty much always be on the offensive.
Rym: If you're on the offensive and you outnumber your opponent about three to two, you will always win in aggregates.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And you might lose a battle here and there, but you're going to win most of the time.
Scott: And if you just keep battling everywhere, you know, if you start 10 battles a turn and you win six of them, you know, you're going to pretty much be equally powerful as the other guy.
Scott: And you're going to gain six territories and, you know, lose three.
Scott: You're going to be up and you do it again the next turn to be up again and you'll get more than him.
Scott: And then momentum sets in and you win.
Scott: And that's the game.
Scott: It just.
Scott: I think the problems with risk are this.
Rym: Number one, there's a lot of randomness going on, but that seems to be a trend in almost every American style board game ever made.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Number two, the cards really kind of dumb, really.
Rym: I remember playing a problematic trouble, which was I don't know how popular it is among families nowadays.
Rym: But when I was a kid, I saw some people playing travel trouble at the laundromat.
Rym: Uh, that game was like the.
Rym: I mean, I played a lot of board games as a kid with my family and I'd always get into arguments because I would always contend that every game we owned was completely random and there was no point in playing them.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, trouble.
Rym: And they'd always say, no, you're just a sore loser.
Scott: Trouble was fun because of the problematic part.
Scott: Other than that, it was just roll, move, roll, move, roll, move.
Rym: It was just Candyland, basically, basically.
Scott: It's saying Uncle Wiggly even.
Rym: Oh God, Uncle Wiggly.
Scott: Even worse than Candyland.
Rym: We have like an old 1930 something version of Uncle Wiggly.
Scott: That's pretty good.
Scott: I like Uncle Wiggly.
Scott: I like Candyland.
Scott: I just don't like the games.
Scott: I like the theme.
Rym: Chutes and Ladders.
Scott: Chutes and Ladders, same game.
Rym: Actually, there was one good game.
Rym: It was called Payday and it was kind of manager money.
Scott: Other people had that game.
Scott: I didn't, but I seen it around.
Rym: It was better than most of those games.
Scott: Careers was a better version.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: The worst game was Life.
Scott: Life, yeah.
Scott: Careers is basically life, but sucks less.
Scott: I have careers in the closet.
Scott: We could play it.
Rym: I would recommend that if you ever have the urge to play Risk ever again, just hit yourself on the arm with a newspaper and say nope, and then go buy like Illuminati or something and play that.
Rym: It's just as tedious, but at least it's more fun.
Scott: The thing that I think is the biggest problem with Risk is that it takes too long for what you get.
Scott: I mean, look at a game like Shogun, say, or Samurai Sword.
Scott: That game is awesome.
Rym: And no, if you want to play Risk, play Shogun instead.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Well, Samurai Sword is formerly known as Shogun, right?
Scott: Because there's other games named Shogun that are not Samurai Sword.
Rym: In fact, there's two other games named Shogun that I know of.
Scott: We're talking Milton Bradley's Game Master series, Shogun/Samurai Sword.
Rym: The one for your old D12.
Scott: It comes in a box that looks a lot like the Axis and Allies boxes in the same set.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So in that game, there's a lot of different stuff going on.
Scott: You got the, you got the, the Goku management.
Scott: You got the Ninja.
Scott: You got the Ronin.
Scott: You got the castles, right?
Scott: There's all sorts of different things that spice the game up.
Scott: In Risk, it's just how many units do you have?
Scott: Where are they?
Scott: That's it.
Scott: It's a number and a spot.
Scott: It couldn't be more bland with just nothing to think about, nothing to do.
Scott: It's just my number is bigger than yours and it's next to yours.
Scott: Attack.
Scott: And like, you can just move all your guys through your own territory infinitely, right?
Scott: If I remember.
Rym: Not fully.
Scott: I pretty much.
Scott: And basically I remember I would just have you basically move all your guys to the border territories and all your inner territories would be pretty much empty.
Scott: That was just like, so all it was was just, okay, I put all most my guys next to most of your guys.
Scott: Then we roll the dice a whole bunch and see who wins.
Scott: And maybe once in a blue moon, the guy with less guys would hold out.
Scott: One unit would somehow destroy like Dan and it would be crazy.
Rym: When a player has finished attacking, he or she has the option to move any number of armies from one and only one of their territories in adjacent territory that occupy.
Rym: And then there's the whole fortifying after the fact stuff too.
Rym: Doesn't matter.
Rym: Risk is not worth playing ever again.
Rym: Pretty much.
Rym: Don't bother with it.
Scott: And it's famous.
Scott: I don't know why it's famous.
Scott: It just is.
Scott: I get the feeling it's weird because in other mediums of, you know, art creation, right, things which have become famous, you know, it might not always be the most, you know, artistically wonderful and perfect things that get the most famous, you know, but the things that do get famous have some sort of merit, you know, like really famous movies.
Scott: You don't see really terrible movies becoming really popular.
Scott: I mean, you might see like a summer blockbuster getting really popular, but it's not going to be like some horrendously bad one that like people are like barfing when they watch or like it's so painful, you know, they just, you know, they might be average.
Scott: or, you know, the really popular video games, you know, the halos, the maddens, the GTAs, right?
Scott: They're not that bad.
Scott: I mean, they're no, they're no
Scott: E.T.,
Scott: right?
Scott: But in board games, at least in the
Scott: U.S.,
Scott: the really popular ones are the really terrible ones.
Scott: They're just so bad.
Rym: I don't know what it is, but what is the mac and the ridiculous obsession with bad games?
Scott: Monopoly, so bad.
Scott: Risk, so bad.
Rym: I guess, you know, here's this might be the illuminating point.
Scott: Scrabble is not so bad.
Rym: Scrabble is pretty bad.
Scott: No, it's not that bad.
Scott: It's not.
Rym: Their worst game.
Scott: Stratego is not so bad either.
Rym: But I want to, I point out that if you play Monopoly according to the rules, it's not nearly as bad of a game.
Rym: It's just incredibly unfun.
Rym: It's not that unfun.
Rym: It's pretty unfun.
Rym: What I'm saying, though, you're missing the point.
Rym: The default game, Monopoly, as it is in the rule book originally is not that bad of a game.
Scott: It's not that bad.
Rym: Let me finish.
Rym: Good guy.
Rym: But every American I've ever met who plays Monopoly, they all play with the same set of house rules to the point that everyone in America thinks these are the rules, even though they're not written in any rule book ever.
Rym: And all these rules serve to do is make the game like four times more random.
Rym: It's like they try to remove skill from games and make it more fair.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much.
Scott: I think the reason, though, people do that in Monopoly is because if you play Monopoly by the rules, the real way it's supposed to be played, it's very painful and unfun.
Rym: because really, it's not any less painful.
Rym: It does.
Scott: If you suck because you basically have not so much money, you can't just buy everything you land on.
Scott: You know, you have to actually think about things and do things like what are the original rules?
Scott: Well, it's different.
Scott: Someone lands on a property like you auction it off.
Scott: No, no, no.
Rym: If you land on a property, you have the right to buy it.
Rym: If you don't buy it, then it is auctioned.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Rym: You have the right to buy it, though.
Rym: It doesn't just automatically go to auction.
Scott: Yeah, but you like.
Scott: I remember I played a DOS version that sort of had the auctioning, but you could actually opt not to auction, which is not an option in the real rules.
Scott: You have to auction it if you don't buy it anyway.
Scott: The point is, if you play Monopoly by the real rules, it's it's not.
Scott: you know, people like to have lots of money and they like to just buy everything they land on.
Scott: I'd like to collect the little properties and move the guy around the board.
Scott: And by modifying the rules, by putting lots of money in the middle and getting it when you land on free parking and stuff like that, it makes the game like you're getting more stuff and you go.
Rym: Well, that's just it.
Rym: Seems like a lot of people really don't like games of skill and they want to play games that are effectively just pretty colors.
Scott: They just want to collect lots of thingies and feel good about collecting lots of thingies.
Rym: Oh, well, we might get some hate from the fact that we're hating on risk.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: Risk is a terrible game.
Scott: And you know what?
Scott: I feel like this whole show.
Scott: really.
Scott: I mean, it could it's it's it's technically the risk show, but really it's just the bitch about bad games.
Scott: I mean, they bitched about the world card game sucking some more.
Scott: They bitched about, you know, the sucky risk.
Scott: I sort of Rondo of Swords wasn't that bad.
Scott: It's a good it's OK.
Scott: Puzzle game.
Rym: I mentioned Advanced Wars and I like it a lot.
Rym: I guess.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Man, want to play Advanced Wars right now?
Scott: No, we got to play other games.
Rym: Now we don't.
Scott: We got Mario Kart and such.
Rym: Yeah, we played.
Rym: we played a few races in Mario Kart.
Rym: All I have to say, it's really fun, except when the A.I.
Rym: is around because there's so many items that it's just it's not worth playing to figure out how to turn the A.I.
Scott: off.
Scott: And if that's not possible, it's gonna be very annoying.
Rym: if I'm sure there's a way we played the game for like 10 minutes.
Rym: But if there is no way to turn off all those extra A.I.
Rym: players, I'm done with Mario Kart already.
Scott: I know that's not the case, but yeah, we'll probably play it when people come over.
Scott: But it's, you know, yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Plus, people said, oh, they took out snaking completely.
Rym: But I discovered already that if I pick a car with the worst handling I can, I can totally gold spark on straight away.
Scott: You can, but it's not snaking because you're not like having to hurt your hand by wiggling back and forth.
Rym: Yeah, but it's the same kind of gaming.
Rym: It's just not quite as bad.
Scott: But you can tell the problem I had with the snaking was not the boosting on the straight away, but the fact that you had to.
Scott: basically the way to win the game was by shaking your hand furiously back and forth.
Rym: Well, all you had to do really was don't shake your hand.
Scott: Shake the D.S Well, so a game that you win, that's basically the shaking game, not fun.
Scott: Yeah, if it's if it's, you know, sort of a slow, actual doable control, then it's that is acceptable.
Rym: You know, it's funny.
Rym: I thought, oh, I have a bunch of risk anecdotes.
Rym: But when I think back, I have a couple of castle risk anecdotes, but I don't want to talk about castle risk.
Rym: Yeah, that game.
Scott: You probably I barely remember castle.
Rym: I owned it.
Scott: Yeah, you did.
Rym: The only anecdotes I have are either.
Rym: Yeah, we had this risk party one time and every other one ends with, yeah, everyone got pissed at each other and quit playing after about an hour.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty much all my risk things where you cheated or the game is bullshit.
Scott: I give up.
Scott: There's nothing I can do.
Scott: or this isn't fun anymore.
Scott: It's been going on too long or, you know, no one.
Scott: You know, it's like no one ever finishes that game or finishes Monopoly either.
Scott: What does that tell you?
Rym: You know, I'm liking more and more because we bought a couple of games over the weekend and well, last weekend.
Scott: Yeah, we'll talk.
Scott: We bought diplomacy and I bought through the ages.
Rym: Both of these games have something that other games don't have.
Rym: They have a way for a player to quit that doesn't just end the game and break everything, Like, because, you know, let's say you're playing Monopoly and you say, I quit.
Scott: Well, there's no rules in the game for quitting and it sort of ruins the game if someone quits.
Scott: because now what do you do with their money?
Scott: What do you do with their property?
Rym: It doesn't so much in Monopoly, but there are other games where it totally ruined like settlers.
Rym: What now?
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: If someone quits in the middle of the game, it just ruins the game.
Scott: But these games actually have built in rules diplomacy and through the ages and say, if someone wants to quit, this is what you do.
Scott: And it's actually, oh, now, you know, that's that's really good.
Scott: I like that.
Scott: I like especially for long games, you know, a way for someone to quit that doesn't break the game for the remaining players.
Scott: That's awesome.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our crapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology.
Rym: Tuesdays we have video games, board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights and Thursdays are the catchalls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Scott: Just click the link that says "send me an Odeo" on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: For the complete archives, visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution Non-Commercial ShareAlike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit, don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.