Rym: It's Monday, April 14th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is gig knives.
Rym: tonight We end up just kind of going off on this nostalgia trip about the 90s Internet.
Rym: Let's do this.
Scott: video is Difficult much more difficult than audio.
Rym: Let me tell you I've noticed two frightening things However, frightening thing.
Rym: the first in the day's worth of filming I've learned that we're already better than pretty much 99% of YouTube.
Scott: Well, I think we got better than 99% of YouTube videos because we tried and thought about it.
Scott: It just doing that alone.
Rym: It makes you better because most of the people just turn on a camera and go Yep, but beyond that we've learned that pretty much there is nothing that edits audio video Well without spending a lot of money nothing.
Scott: Yeah, we pretty much either have to get the Apple Final cut thingy or the Adobe Premiere After Effects thingy.
Rym: Yeah, there's really.
Scott: they're both a Bajillion dollars and there's nothing else.
Rym: Everything else is so Absolutely awful.
Scott: Well, there's that Sony Vegas people talk about.
Scott: I wonder if it's actually any good though.
Scott: Yeah, but like Sony I mean how good get Sony board.
Rym: It's just awful.
Scott: The open-source free stuff is no good, but So anyway, not only do we need the software to edit video and such.
Scott: but we actually need a computer because You know, my computer is bleh.
Scott: I'm not really using my desktop much anymore.
Rym: I'm also using my laptop and Scott and I have kind of taken turns leapfrogging each other with computers.
Rym: So I currently have the badass computer and Scott has the marginally useful computer.
Scott: His computer is not ready for video editing.
Rym: really I don't have the software and and as we agreed you are captain video because I got this audio thing down.
Scott: Yeah, I'm captain video apparently.
Scott: so I'm gonna have to learn movie making but or at least amateur movie making.
Scott: But yeah, I realized that making video and editing video is hard.
Scott: being on video is a thousand times harder.
Rym: You were staring at the camera like a serial killer.
Scott: Well, I I do not look good on a camera.
Scott: I Remember looks kind of okay, but I don't know I look not so good.
Rym: Well, I can say one thing.
Rym: I don't wanna make fun of you, but that's how you look when we do most of our panels.
Scott: Maybe I should.
Scott: I don't know what I'm gonna do about that.
Scott: Yeah, I don't really care.
Scott: The thing is stands like straight.
Rym: The thing is it's weird to do is stand up straight.
Scott: I can't smile.
Scott: I have a hunch on the hunch.
Rym: How do I unhunch go to a doctor?
Scott: How was the doctor gonna do?
Rym: They're gonna unhunch you how?
Rym: Chiropractic no, no, no.
Rym: Thank you.
Rym: We're a brace.
Scott: They're not wearing a brace.
Rym: I get that he could make you lay on a posture correcting bed every night.
Scott: What's the posture correcting bed?
Rym: Like probably not very comfortable like that.
Scott: What other options?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: don't have a hunch.
Scott: It's not really an option.
Rym: I don't have.
Scott: that's like saying Hey, I don't have a penis.
Rym: If you My penis is a positive impact on my life.
Rym: your hunch not so much.
Scott: my hunch is not negative either.
Rym: You're gonna be a humpback.
Rym: So Are you?
Scott: are you a humpback ist?
Scott: Yes a quasi modist.
Rym: I do not like quasi moto.
Rym: I'm not a fan of that, dude What's wrong with him?
Rym: face Do you ever read that book?
Rym: No, did you ever see the Disney movie?
Scott: No, I saw pictures of it.
Rym: Do you even know what it's about a guy?
Scott: He's a hunchback.
Scott: He lives in the church.
Scott: He rings the bell, but not easy.
Scott: sad because he has no friends except the cute little animals Yes, the cute little and he falls in love with some hot chick and then in the end He kills the bad dude and the hot chick loves him because he's good on the inside.
Rym: That's not quite how it goes.
Rym: No, not so much okay kind of like how in the original Little Mermaid it doesn't end happily.
Scott: no No, it doesn't.
Rym: but anyway, I think the biggest trouble with video editing we found is that well one We don't know anything about it.
Rym: Like we're in the other room and we're we're debating like basically we spend an hour independently driving Like a basic thing of filmmaking that Emily after we spent an hour driving it walked in and basically said yeah That's what you're supposed to do.
Scott: She basically came in and said why don't you guys do this?
Scott: We just spent the last hour figuring out that we had to do just that.
Rym: It's uh, it's not so easy.
Rym: Yeah, also lighting is a lot.
Scott: It's hard, especially in a house That's like this with normal, you know living lights as opposed to movie lights.
Rym: and the worst thing is everything is yellow.
Rym: the reason all the video on the internet is awful is Partly because the amount of I mean to make audio sound good.
Rym: GeekNights sounds better than like every goddamn Podcast out there and it took that the professional ones, but even then it's close.
Scott: It's pretty good.
Rym: It took a couple hundred dollars worth of equipment.
Rym: We're gonna have to like.
Rym: we need lavaliers now.
Rym: We need all this equipment to make video look good and sound good.
Scott: All right, the other thing right.
Scott: is that okay?
Scott: First of all, right?
Scott: It's like okay.
Scott: I have a choice between the here's my choices, right?
Scott: We need another powerful computer to do the video editing.
Scott: choice number one.
Scott: Don't buy a computer.
Scott: Well, no video.
Scott: So that's out.
Rym: Well, the other option is Rym does the editing.
Rym: but if I do the video editing I'm fine with that.
Rym: I'm gonna offload a lot of the other GeekNights work to you.
Rym: Yeah, like post making.
Scott: Anyway, option number two, right?
Scott: I buy a build a computer.
Scott: I put Linux on it.
Scott: Well, there's no video editing software for Linux.
Scott: So there was.
Scott: we would have this problem.
Scott: Option number three I buy I build a computer and I put Windows on it.
Scott: That's an okay Option.
Rym: you'll get Windows Movie Maker.
Rym: Yeah, that's a start.
Rym: actually You know what?
Rym: That's better than every open-source video editing program ever written.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is is it's still kind of shitty and it's not perfect.
Rym: You know, it's better than nothing.
Rym: I'm thinking about editing our first video on my laptop because I have Windows Movie Maker over there.
Rym: Yeah, and I have a hundred gigs free.
Scott: Another option is to buy the Mac and you know the.
Scott: the advantage of that is it's really easy But it costs so much more money.
Rym: The worst thing is the Mac cost a lot of money.
Rym: the software cost almost as much.
Scott: Yeah, well the thing is right.
Scott: we can get after effects which is Mac only which is like $1,300.
Scott: All right, we can get the Adobe Production Suite, which has flash Photoshop premiere and after effects and a bunch of other things right which is pretty much everything we need and more right and that's $1,800.
Scott: but the Educational version is $600 now.
Scott: We're not in school.
Scott: So we don't check legally qualify for the educational version, but Because we know people in school.
Scott: We could easily get the educational version.
Rym: I still have my RIT ID though I heard they changed the RIT ID.
Scott: I'm sure when you go to RIT in a couple weeks someone there will gladly go to the store and you know buy you the Educational version.
Rym: if you give them the money, I'm sure I could talk my way into getting it just by going into the store myself.
Rym: Yeah, probably all I have to do is dress all scruffily, right?
Rym: I gotta wear like pajamas and flannel gonna not shave for a couple days.
Rym: I kind of stagger in and I go Adobe Yeah, but it's really I'm at like it.
Scott: I'm at a troublesome point here cuz I sort of I think the trouble here Right.
Scott: is that back in the day?
Scott: It was so clear like you got a computer with DOS.
Scott: then it was so clear.
Scott: you got Windows 3.1 there was all the other options, you know, there were Macs, but it was so clear that that was not a good option.
Scott: It was obvious.
Scott: Windows 95 still obvious 98 still obvious.
Scott: then when you got me very obvious Yeah, it's very obvious.
Scott: But then as we started to got into like the earlier 2000s like 2003 it was like well XP, you know, I have it for games.
Scott: But Linux so obvious right and it's been Linux so obvious at least for the things that I've been doing.
Scott: You know coding and such and just web browsing and IMing and less and less gaming.
Scott: Linux has been so obvious.
Scott: but now we're at a point actually where we I want to do a lot more things and I sort of need all three OS's and that's the temptation of the Mac Is that the Mac can run all three because then
Rym: actually we only need two if you stop gaming
Scott: I know I mean.
Scott: and the thing is if I buy Windows I can actually probably get by because the Mac doesn't do.
Scott: I mean I can have iTunes on Windows and I can use VMware on Windows to run Linux and The OS X doesn't do that much that I really need, you know, but each OS really, you know really good parts and really bad parts and I really I'm starting to feel that they're all sort of equal in ways at this point in time and it's very very difficult because it's making Computing very expensive.
Rym: Well, the other thing is that just in terms of what we want to do We knew enough about audio like it cost us less.
Rym: it cost a couple hundred dollars to get into podcasting.
Rym: Yeah to get into video at the same Equivalent level like to get into video at the level that we got into podcasting is going to cost many thousands of dollars.
Rym: Yep, many thousands.
Rym: Yeah, not to mention the Inordinate amount of time it takes to do all this.
Rym: I mean God we spent hours and hours and what we got out of it were 14 flawed takes of something That is in the end gonna be like four minutes long.
Scott: I mean it used to be.
Scott: I would go build a computer and I'd be like, this is perfect.
Scott: This is the best computer that I could afford given a you know price performance ratio.
Scott: This is everything I wanted.
Scott: But now I feel like no matter what computer I buy no matter how much money I spend unless I go and buy a Mac Pro and a new Windows computer and
Rym: Add all the Adobe and
Scott: all and the Adobe master suite and everything unless I spend like $20,000 I feel like I'll be not having the perfect thing.
Scott: There is no there is nothing that will satisfy.
Rym: You know, what everything has There's plenty that will satisfy if we give up on this wild notion of creating content.
Scott: Yeah, that's true.
Rym: If I give up on creating I wasn't doing GeekNights I would just have a Windows Vista computer with the baddest ass video card in the world for playing games at a VMware for writing code and that'd be it.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much I could do that.
Scott: if that's all.
Scott: no No, I got without without making it without making content.
Scott: I would just need a Linux on my laptop.
Scott: I wouldn't even need a desktop.
Rym: actually once I finish my I'm starting to write a Python program that will do Everything I need audio wise because resound is really crappy.
Rym: It's just.
Rym: it's just the best thing out there.
Scott: So I'm trying to write a command line, you know that Adobe production see comes with a sound booth.
Rym: I know and I know it's really good.
Scott: I don't know if it's really good or not.
Rym: Who knows it has some good points.
Rym: The thing is if I write this program cuz Python works just fine on Windows.
Rym: That's it.
Rym: I will never need to boot back into Linux again ever.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, look at that.
Rym: Yeah Python is allowing me to get out of this.
Scott: maybe yeah, it seems like also nowadays a lot more stuff is cross-platform.
Scott: I mean really more than the.
Scott: oh it used to be.
Scott: the OS is really important.
Scott: But now as long as I have Firefox The like other stuff matters a lot less a whole lot less.
Scott: I mean like you can tell too cuz back in the day I would customize my desktop heavily super heavily because it mattered.
Scott: now Everything's in the web browser.
Scott: So my desktop I just leave it as the default because I'm lazy and it doesn't matter because everything is in Firefox.
Rym: I used to make all these icons to click on but if I look at the icons I've got here I've got two.
Rym: I never click on.
Rym: one spawns a terminal one opens a folder of my music the third icon Firefox.
Rym: I don't even click on that.
Scott: Yeah, it's like outside of You know the web browser.
Scott: the only really things we need applications for anymore are content creation Mostly and then and get so.
Scott: so it's like running a web browser is incredibly easy and cheap Everything.
Scott: and then as soon as you step beyond that and you say I actually need an application again Everything suddenly becomes a bajillion dollars and it seems like a crime Because you've been paying nothing for so long because you've only needed a web browsing course.
Rym: the other problem It's not really a problem.
Rym: I can't blame people who do things for free, but the people developing the open source content creation software Obviously do not actually create content with said software.
Scott: Well, some of them do not good kinds like Pavre actually You know, but that's mostly a rendering kind of thing.
Rym: Yeah, but like most I mean the gimp.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, the gimp was not made by artists and even Audacity is pretty awful.
Rym: If you want to do anything serious with it.
Rym: I mean I guess for music it's okay But I'm really asking.
Scott: I have frequently come really close to just you know, I mean I said well the Mac Pro is done.
Scott: I'm not considering it anymore because the VMware doesn't do dual screen black But it would just be so easy to just go to the Apple Store tomorrow.
Scott: Like fucking give it to me I don't give a shit anymore would really clinch.
Rym: it is if and when we get a house.
Rym: Yeah, what we would do is we'd have the recording studio and in that room would be the Mac Pro and the big screen For it and the sound isolation, but
Scott: if people want to share it the Mac Pro with me That would much encourage me to meet even if you just shared it with me.
Scott: It would be $1,500 instead of 3,000.
Scott: I would just go out and get it tomorrow.
Scott: Yeah, but as much as there are problems with it.
Rym: Yeah, it's tricky though It is tricky.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: I mean, I'm in a computing dilemma, please offer me your advices.
Rym: Yeah, especially if you have a video editing experience you out there actually make video for the internet.
Scott: Yeah, like good video for the Internet's.
Rym: if you're not sure if you make good video the answer is probably no.
Scott: Yeah, like we need we should call the ask a ninja guy.
Scott: He'd probably know.
Scott: Yeah, we can ask him and he would say.
Scott: he would say buy the blank any blank, you know Like buy this and then I'll kill you.
Rym: here's the other problem.
Rym: a lot of people make content now There's a lot of podcasts and a lot of YouTube whatevers, but and a lot of that content is good.
Rym: But I talked to some of these people who do make the content and their answers are always yeah It takes me like four weeks to put each one of these things together Even podcasters a lot of the podcasters.
Rym: We know it takes them four eight twelve hours to edit One hour long episode of their show.
Rym: it takes us 30 seconds to edit GeekNights because we wrote scripts to do it all for us.
Scott: Yeah, like most people they I don't think there's any way to make video.
Scott: go that quickly.
Scott: The thing is right.
Scott: boing boing t boing boing is making those boing boing TV things, right?
Rym: What do they use?
Scott: I don't know what they use but they've been around for six months say they've done 150 episodes.
Rym: Let's just ask him what software they use and what hardware they use and buy whatever they say whatever they say.
Scott: So if they say Mac Pro with the After Effects we're not with the Final Cut we're just gonna go buy that.
Rym: I don't think I would ship in 50% yet because it would also be your primary computer.
Scott: Yeah, well the thing is but I would in all honesty right.
Scott: what if we do buy?
Scott: let's say we go and buy a Mac Pro We just go to the apples you come downtown.
Scott: We going to buy right?
Scott: Really?
Scott: My laptop would still be my primary computer.
Scott: I would use the the Mac pretty much or the or the windows.
Scott: if we buy that.
Scott: I pretty much use it for video editing gaming and Music and I wouldn't use it for my normal computing at all Because my laptop does all that.
Rym: Yeah, of course.
Rym: I really need some Google gears for my Google Docs.
Scott: We really Google came out with the Google gears and it works at the reader kind of.
Rym: but thing is I don't trust half the Little apps that people are making with the Google gears.
Rym: I'm just waiting for something.
Scott: I only want Google to use the Google gears, but they're not.
Scott: they made it and they're not using it enough.
Scott: Yeah, eventually maybe That's the one problem with web applications.
Scott: is you know, we can't push ourselves forward.
Scott: We're sort of at Google's mercy and they're going.
Rym: we could we could use the Google gears and do stuff.
Scott: We just yeah, we could.
Scott: we would have to write basically web applications that do everything that Google does.
Rym: from what I can see I could write Google apps in Django in like 20 minutes.
Rym: No, no, I couldn't.
Rym: but anyway, I got some news.
Scott: Well, it's a long opening bit.
Scott: Let's do news.
Rym: That's fine.
Rym: What do you got?
Scott: Oh, okay So, you know flash memory, right?
Scott: It's pretty much in everything.
Scott: Yeah, good the the advantages of flash memory or that you can get a lot of space.
Scott: a lot of you know Digital data in a small amount of physical space.
Scott: It's pretty fast kind of fast And you know, he doesn't need electricity.
Scott: So you it'll just sit there and store whatever it's storing for a long time and there's no moving parts.
Scott: That's that's pretty great problem with flash memory.
Scott: it's fast, but it's not that fast.
Scott: I mean, it's not stupid fast.
Rym: It's kind of fast and it's also, you know, eventually it wears out exactly It doesn't wear out.
Scott: Yeah, if you look at Scott Johnson, yeah, if you look at one bit in the flash memory Let's say I have one bit of flash memory.
Scott: I know that's impossible Technologically speaking, but let's pretend I guess it's not technically impossible.
Scott: But yeah pretend you have one bit of flash memory Zero.
Scott: I make it want to make it zero.
Scott: make it want to make it zero.
Scott: make it want to make it.
Rym: make it What.
Rym: well, you can turn it to zero a limited number of times exactly the ten thousandth or so time I turn it to zero.
Scott: It will never turn back to one again.
Scott: It's it's dead It'll did.
Scott: flash memory if you keep using it eventually dies.
Rym: That's why if you and a lot of people don't realize this if you install Software from a flash drive like a Firefox or all - you or whatever.
Rym: Make sure you get the versions people have made that are designed for a flash drive.
Rym: Otherwise programs like audacity are just gonna write a ton of data that I think it ruin it real quick.
Scott: This is why on my laptop, right?
Scott: I'm running Linux on my laptop and I got a solid-state drive, but I turned off all log files.
Scott: that way I'm not writing data to the.
Scott: the solid-state drive slowly kill killing it faster than it's normally gonna kill me softly.
Rym: I Inject a little Dave and Joel there.
Rym: He always sings.
Scott: All right, so IBM right a rims.
Scott: former rims.
Rym: former employer IBM was In all the jobs I've had in my life.
Rym: That was one of the more fun jobs.
Scott: anyway They've came up invented a new kind of memory called racetrack memory.
Scott: racetrack is the marketing name.
Scott: I'm sure there's a sciency name.
Scott: There's probably a really cool internal name - probably but basically the way it works is a video that Explains it really simply and the video is sort of my news, but basically there's a nano wire.
Scott: So it's a wire but it's really fucking small like Thousand of these wires together would look like a hair.
Rym: I'm sure you're all familiar with it from every cyberpunk thing ever.
Rym: It's the coolest weapon anyone can ever wheel.
Scott: pretty much so you have a nano wire and on one end you have some zeros the other end you have ones right and In the middle you have zeros and one sort of mixed up and you can push from either side.
Scott: So if I push on the one end Right all the sort of zeros and ones in the middle get pushed closer to the zero end.
Scott: It's sort of like having a bunch of beads on an abacus and sliding all of them together while keeping the space in between them the same right and then basically whichever, you know at the spot in the middle you can switch it between zero and one and You can do this really really quickly.
Scott: you can just you know, like push, you know, switch push switch push switch push push the other direction switch and It.
Scott: in theory and in practice.
Scott: I guess this is gonna make basically eventually if they can come through on the manufacturing end Which are they probably will I would if IBM, you know, I don't think they're going out of business soon.
Scott: Right if they hold out You know the however many years it takes them to get this into production and they get it into production into a feasible product.
Scott: Investing in IBM.
Scott: good idea.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I just thought of something crazy.
Rym: Yeah I'm totally gonna ask my old manager my friends at IBM if they can hook me up with the press contacts and see if I Get an interview with like an engineer or something.
Scott: Yeah, I think these.
Scott: this wasn't at your IBM.
Scott: This is in California in Silicon Valley the IBM.
Rym: But at the same time The way IBM is I'm pretty sure I could get talk to someone who could say something cool to us.
Scott: Maybe maybe the shot say some.
Scott: you say exactly what the video says with more sciency words Yes, but then you get the voice of an engineer Especially if it's a cool and we could just have one of our friends pretend they're an engineer and read the.
Scott: they could read the Documentation and then well, we have our resident scientist.
Rym: We actually haven't had him on the show in a long time.
Scott: He's mostly with the biology's.
Rym: Yeah, we haven't talked about that in a long time.
Scott: There hasn't been much.
Scott: Well, I'm sure there's been something to say.
Rym: when was the last time we had him on the show with that pseudoscience episode?
Scott: I think I was forever again.
Rym: Maybe we should huh?
Rym: This is a total aside.
Rym: But for Mondays Would you guys be cool if we added like a bit some sort of.
Rym: we get our couple of our scientist friends to record some?
Rym: Like I don't know two or three minute quickies like I think you just Skype them up and do an episode about something about what?
Rym: Bacteria.
Scott: No, I think we should an episode about like organic stuff going food because he likes talking, you know, that's what his job is
Rym: Alright, so instead of skyping him up Why don't we just buy him a train ticket down here so I can record his majestic voice
Scott: because We could just wait till he's down here.
Rym: Normally he'll come down.
Rym: Yeah, we'll get him down here.
Rym: Plus we got to play some teeny anyway.
Rym: So this stuff's pretty cool.
Rym: But here's something not cool.
Rym: But at the same time you're gonna.
Rym: any of you who are not in the IT world yet might wonder how something like this could Happen but I can tell you that with rare exceptions.
Rym: This is the way every big company is.
Rym: There's an article on slashdot entitled the Dead Sea effect in the IT workplace.
Scott: I was in the Dead Sea.
Scott: Were you in the Dead Sea?
Scott: I was in a Dead Sea a Dead Sea or the Dead Sea.
Rym: I was in a Dead Sea.
Scott: I was in the Dead Sea so that I avoid talking about places.
Rym: I've worked.
Rym: I mean I talk about IBM a lot cuz I was kind of my first job and I that's when I kind of learned how this whole IT Computer enterprise world worked.
Rym: and then I worked for a company.
Rym: It was pretty crappy and now I work for like the most awesome company ever.
Rym: but The second company there was a Dead Sea.
Rym: in terms of IT and there are a lot of Dead Seas out there The Dead Sea idea is that if you have a large company for those you don't know The Dead Sea is like the lowest place on earth.
Scott: I mean, we're not counting.
Scott: What is that?
Rym: be the center of the earth?
Scott: I know.
Scott: but you know, we're counting like, you know the lowest sea level that you wouldn't that be the Marianas Trench?
Scott: No, because that's under the sea.
Rym: but isn't is this lower sea level?
Rym: technically under the sea There's just no sea level.
Scott: but the sea, you know, you're still up.
Scott: It's where you can stand on Dirt, but be the lowest above sea level that you can be.
Rym: but I could stand on dirt at the bottom of the ocean.
Rym: I would just be very small.
Scott: Well not and not be wet Like you see in a suit.
Scott: you understand what I'm saying.
Scott: I could be in a suit now and I could have holes in the bottom as a result of being so low.
Scott: Right the all the rainwater and such goes down into the Dead Sea and brings a lot of salt and other minerals down there.
Scott: So it's basically it's water that has so much salt and minerals into it Like you literally see big rocks of salt like just you know, popping up like little it's out of the sea.
Rym: You can make a very small one by dumping salt into a bathtub.
Scott: Yeah And like if you go into the Dead Sea like it's hard to put your body parts underwater like it forces you to float And of course is also.
Scott: people are like there's a little company there and they make all sorts of lotions and other bullshit.
Scott: You know that's like oh the Dead Sea will heal you because it's special sodium chloride.
Scott: Yeah But I can tell you that if you if you do take Dead Sea mud and put it all over you and then rinse It off and little showers they have it does feel good.
Rym: Anyway, yeah, so the Dead Sea idea in the IT workplace is that you know, maybe I'll just quote here.
Rym: This will make it easy quote.
Rym: many large IT shops work like the Dead Sea.
Scott: You float in them really easily and it's hard to sink.
Rym: new hires are brought in as management deems it necessary.
Rym: the qualifications So they the salt will vary depending on curtain.
Scott: you're there the water employee departure personnel budget etc.
Rym: It's a blah blah blah blah blah.
Rym: all things being equal The general competency of the IT department should have a roughly the same distribution as the incoming hires.
Rym: instead What happens is that the most talented and most effective IT?
Rym: Engineers are the ones most likely to leave you Evaporate if you will.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: They're the ones least likely.
Rym: I'm gonna.
Rym: I'm gonna Translate the rest of this sentence into what it's actually trying to say.
Scott: smart people don't stick around.
Rym: They're the ones least likely to put up with the bullshit.
Rym: Yep That plagues large organizations and they're the ones most likely to have other Opportunities lined up that they can readily and easily move to.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: What tends to remain is the residue.
Scott: This is why if you go to any IT shop Right, you'll basically either find a place like where there's all smart people working together And they're all happy because there's no bullshit at their work and it's all smart people they go.
Scott: Yay All right, or you go to another place where you know, there's a bunch of dumb people and maybe there's some smart people But the smart people are not happy because they have to deal with the dumb people's bullshit.
Scott: Now dumb people might also be upset with the bullshit But they can't leave because they're dumb and they can't get new jobs.
Scott: the smart people can get new jobs.
Rym: Now they get the hell out.
Rym: There are other situations like IBM kept coming up but there are a lot of like.
Rym: if you get beyond the normal idea of a large company and into the idea of a Stupidly large company IBM is a good example of that.
Rym: just a company that is just massive.
Rym: Yeah, then you get in.
Scott: every situation really is different when you get down to the details.
Rym: There's the third case where you'll have like a pocket of smart people Surrounded by the bullshit of the large organization.
Rym: That's true.
Scott: Cuz when you get to such a big company like that, it's really operates like a bunch of smaller companies with loose ties between.
Rym: but I worked in a place between working where I work now, which Illustrated this perfectly.
Rym: I got to this company and I was excited about it.
Rym: It was it looked like a fun job.
Rym: I was being paid pretty well for what I was gonna be doing and it just seemed awesome.
Rym: all the way and As time went on the guy who I was working under my first manager Quit within a month because he took a high-paying job elsewhere in the financial district Mmm, so they hired a replacement and in that time I worked for some other guy.
Rym: The guy I worked for quit and got a much higher playing job in the financial district.
Scott: One of my co-workers were these guys smart guys who were leaving.
Rym: they were smart guys.
Rym: I worked for someone else my new manager.
Rym: They quit within two weeks Whoa to get a job and this guy was freshly hired.
Rym: He was hired I worked for him quit immediately got a high-paying job in the financial.
Scott: So eventually I quit and got a high-paying job in the financial.
Rym: Yes, and I can say this.
Rym: I can say this honestly I mean I left for a number of reasons.
Rym: Actually, the main reason I left was because the environment was making me kind of sick in a physical way because of where I was Working, you know hospitals.
Rym: Yeah in bad parts of New York City every day.
Rym: but I don't think I left ain't a single competent IT person behind.
Rym: and there was this kind of environment where if you were smart, you were desperately looking for a job elsewhere.
Rym: and Everyone I talked to with the company who was smart when I said, yeah, I'm quitting said, where are you going?
Rym: Take me with you Oh my god.
Rym: And meanwhile I the company I work for now Everyone's smart.
Rym: Yeah, and no one's trying to leave.
Rym: In fact, people are trying to get in see.
Scott: I recognize this phenomena.
Scott: Add other companies, but I've only ever worked for places that had like four or five tech people.
Scott: So it's like I don't really.
Scott: I can't really see it my own jobs because I don't work anywhere But there's too many people.
Rym: the way around.
Rym: this is pretty simple.
Rym: All you have to do if you're a company no matter how big you are is make sure That you've whoever you hire.
Rym: you always give them opportunities to advance Even knowing that that training that you're paying for could very easily get them a job elsewhere for a lot more money.
Scott: Also, make sure that you have more smart IT people than dumb IT.
Rym: Yeah but that's not easy to do.
Rym: the way to get it that way is to get people and offer them all this training and and Constantly, like what do you want to learn?
Rym: What do you want to do and pay for that training?
Rym: and By doing so you'll have a lot of smart people who while they could leave with that knowledge and work somewhere else they're more inclined to stick around because they kind of got this sunk cost.
Rym: and also they'll continue to get this training and everyone else is getting this training and everyone else is getting smarter alongside them and Eventually, you'll have only smart people.
Scott: In other words, you have to spoil the IT people who are doing this podcast.
Scott: us too are saying you must spoil us Or we will give you the finger.
Rym: Yes, but that's kind of true.
Scott: That's it is true.
Rym: Plus it works out really well because there's another thing a side factor to this people who don't take advantage of that free training.
Rym: You probably don't want to keep them around.
Rym: Oh Snap, especially you make the training during work hours like you.
Rym: let people go on trips like go to this training in Boston for a week and then come back and then do a lecture on what you did.
Rym: and if people won't do that like if You have IT people who seriously won't accept training They're probably not going to be useful in the future.
Rym: Nope Anyway, this is an interesting article.
Rym: I'd recommend you read it and What I think you should take from it is not so much that oh It's all stupid people and everything's gonna suck.
Rym: take it as smart people can always find their way out.
Rym: Anyway things of the day now, I've brought this up several times.
Rym: I Talk about this.
Rym: I've been talking about this on a regular basis since I was in high school.
Scott: We've been talking about this for a long time.
Rym: This has been an issue in my life for years.
Rym: This has been discussing this I personally been an activist against since I was 14.
Rym: Oh, man, because that's when I started driving.
Rym: Okay, partly because I lived in Michigan, which is it's awesome to live in Michigan if you like driving.
Rym: But anyway Not so awesome.
Rym: If you like mass transit, but there's a problem in this country.
Rym: We make traffic laws Nominally to make driving safer.
Rym: a speed limit should be set Next to a school because there's little kids running out into traffic.
Scott: Yeah, and when people you know, if I make an argument saying as speed limits are bullshit Well the thing people always say well, it makes the road safer.
Scott: anything that makes the road safer It's it's hard to argue against if it does indeed make the road safer.
Scott: So every traffic law in theory should be a law that increases safety.
Rym: Now, of course the problem with that argument is that all right The speed limit should be five miles an hour everywhere because then no one can get hurt.
Scott: Well, this is a line you have to draw between safety and visibility.
Rym: But the problem I have on a fundamental level is that the what traffic laws are actually used for in the most places in the United States is Revenue generation and not even on the large scale not by states not by the feds but by crappy little towns and local police and There's no better evidence of this than in Texas though.
Rym: Texas has done some good things to stop this, Ohio I could tell some stories about Ohio where you can pay tickets with a credit card at the cop and continue on your way at The cop as if the cop is a place.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: The cop is a place.
Rym: I've stopped there.
Rym: It's a drive-thru.
Scott: Good burgers, I Hear the donuts are a little stale and half-eaten.
Rym: but In in Fishkill, there's this little town next to us.
Rym: And this town is actually really small and it has a lot of problems partly because it only has one road.
Rym: But the town is set up to where the whole town's in one place.
Rym: and then there's a major road.
Rym: The only north-south road in this area is the only way to go north without going to the throughway.
Rym: And on this road this town of Fishkill goes across it and the number of police officers that they put on the tiny stretch of this road that they control and the number of tickets that they ride on a daily basis is Frightening.
Rym: and as a result this tiny town of Fishkill has the biggest most opulent police station and courthouse You would ever believe.
Scott: the town hall is also pretty extravagant.
Rym: They have so many cops.
Scott: meanwhile here in Beacon a city compared to their town It's not quite as opulent.
Rym: Of course, the police in Beacon are very prudent.
Rym: I've noticed that I've never seen them doing speed traps and the only time I've ever seen them pull someone over is when someone was Doing something really really stupid like going 60 or 70 miles an hour through the nuns.
Scott: Oh, yeah, the Beacon cops seem pretty reasonable.
Rym: Yeah The one time ever got pulled over in Beacon was cuz my headlight was out.
Rym: and you know what?
Rym: My headlight was out and I fixed it the next day cuz my headlight was out.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But anyway, I digress.
Rym: Red light cameras in theory are a cool idea.
Rym: I have no problem with automated enforcement of intelligent traffic law as long as it works now.
Rym: The problem here is that red light cameras as far as I've ever been able to tell are put in Never to increase safety never to decrease accidents or deaths never to make traffic flow better But always to generate revenue.
Rym: and a lot of people say oh Rym You're just paranoid.
Rym: and I point to evidence.
Rym: They know you're just paranoid.
Rym: more evidence.
Rym: Are you just paranoid?
Rym: What I'm linking to is yet more evidence that whenever these lights are put in cities and municipalities time and time again always Decrease the time of yellow lights in order to increase the revenue.
Rym: They make the intersections less safe.
Rym: fatalities and accidents increase dramatically.
Rym: That doesn't make the road safer.
Rym: it generates money and I don't I can't.
Scott: The real issue here in other words the town wants your money Because the other only other way to get your money is to raise taxes and piss you off.
Scott: So you won't vote for them.
Scott: So in order to get your money they make it so that you die driving your car to get your money now.
Rym: The worst thing is that it's not even just this.
Rym: there's actually far more civil liberties implications to all this because speed limits are the same Way.
Rym: a speed limit should be a speed limit as in on a straight freeway The speed limit should be fairly high because the odds of an accident are low.
Rym: But if the freeway is curvy or you know, it's dangerous like say there's a curve that doesn't appear dangerous But studies show it is dangerous and maybe it's safe.
Rym: If you go 35, then I'm all cool with having engineers say this turn you got to go 35.
Rym: I'm gonna make a law gonna put up a sign.
Rym: But there's also evidence that a lot of places put the speed limit well below the median speed well below the safe speed in order to generate revenue and This is never been it been put in more stark relief than this video.
Scott: This video is the video is a thing of the day.
Scott: a long time ago.
Rym: This video was a thing of the day when I still worked at IBM.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Some kids got together in Georgia and the speed limit on this freeway is 55 miles an hour.
Scott: That's what it is here in 84.
Rym: It's four lanes wide.
Rym: They got four cars.
Rym: They got in a line.
Rym: They went 55 miles an hour and The chaos that ensues.
Rym: there is no Conscionable way to have the speed limit be 55 on this road and a lot of people got really mad about this video.
Rym: a lot Of people were saying what they did was illegal and dangerous and blog and to me No, it illustrates that the speed limit of 55 on that road is bullshit.
Scott: Now I want to.
Scott: I mean it's obvious to me looking at that road It is probably safe to drive about 80 on that road and if your car can't go 80 and if you can't handle the car Going 80 you
Rym: shouldn't be driving or at least not beyond the
Scott: highway at least
Rym: but it's tricky.
Rym: But I don't want to get into the specifics of that but a lot of people said oh what they did was illegal.
Rym: and I have Here a quote from David Speer a spokesman for the State Department of Transportation in Georgia, and he said the following They didn't do a thing wrong in Atlanta.
Rym: The actual effect of it is we expect the people going 75 to move over so that people going 95 can have their way.
Rym: and he goes on and on about what was like the whole gist of all this.
Rym: but To all the people who were saying that this is horrible what these kids did and dangerous the cops themselves to it no problem with it.
Rym: and The moral of everything I have to say civil liberties wise is this We've gotten to the point with traffic laws to where the police can effectively pull Anyone over at any time for and they'll always be able to after the fact post-hoc Come up with a legitimate reason for pulling the person over Which opens the door for pulling
Scott: over
Rym: anyone that you have anything against?
Rym: Profiling anything and then kind of just going on a fishing expedition.
Rym: Oh, hey, I pulled you over Cuz you were going four miles an hour over the speed limit.
Rym: Never mind the fact that the speed limit is 40 miles an hour lower than what people normally drive.
Rym: Never mind the fact that the actual average speed of drivers on the road is 80 instead of 40.
Rym: But I see there's something that might be a marijuana cigarette mashed up in your cigarette tray up jail for you.
Rym: Yeah So check out this video.
Rym: I know it's an old thing of the day, but everyone should see this.
Scott: check out this article Your articles your actual new thing of the day.
Rym: Yes, it is.
Rym: They're both my thing of the day.
Rym: That's all I got to say.
Rym: This is this is something that bothers me on a lot of levels.
Rym: I'd love anyone to have any legitimate argument against me.
Scott: Yeah Alright, so this would normally be like a Tuesday thing of the day cuz it's all video gaming.
Scott: But actually I'm gonna it's all teching.
Scott: You just don't realize that.
Rym: Oh, I know what you're gonna do.
Scott: Yeah It's.
Rym: uh, you know before the show but I would know even if I did not know because I would have known Would you?
Scott: oh I would have anyway some dude.
Scott: He wrote the first level of Super Mario Brothers one But he wrote it in JavaScript.
Scott: now the reason this is sort of amazing from a tech perspective because JavaScript is not like a programming language.
Scott: you write programs in.
Scott: JavaScript is pretty much a language that sort of it's.
Scott: it's a thing that what it's pretty much just for web browsers and what you do is JavaScript is you send the JavaScript code itself from the web server to the web browser.
Scott: So your web browser when you visit a website with JavaScript actually downloads the source code of the JavaScript, right?
Scott: and then it actually you know reads all that JavaScript and runs it on its own.
Scott: and JavaScript is really only designed to sort of manipulate web pages.
Scott: so you can sort of make things Happen on web pages locally, you know, and for example, you know making you know pull down menus or you know JavaScript, you know did they use it nowadays for a lot of those things where you can you know Make a post on a make a comment post without reloading the page, you know that it's gotten pretty advanced lately.
Scott: Actually, you know, I mean I remember back in the day where it was like they made JavaScript.
Scott: It was like oh if you want to do cool stuff use JavaScript.
Scott: and then it was like JavaScript is bad don't use it.
Scott: and it was kind of bad and you shouldn't have used it.
Scott: But now it's gotten to the point where people worked so hard on JavaScript.
Scott: They're like, all right, it sucks but we've Sort of beaten the shit out of it and now we can do things with it.
Scott: and this guy made all of the first level of Mario Super Mario Brothers in JavaScript not only in JavaScript in only 14 K of JavaScript an incredibly small amount of memory.
Rym: That's pretty impressive.
Scott: it is pretty impressive.
Scott: now the thing about this is first of all, it's not a perfect implementation.
Scott: I mean you can walk left Which is not correct, right?
Scott: You can walk left off the board at the beginning of the game and then you have to reload because you broke it All.
Scott: the question blocks only have coins, right?
Scott: There's no turtles only goombas.
Scott: really there's no stars.
Scott: It's you know, you can't.
Scott: really you don't get big.
Scott: There's no fire flowers.
Scott: It's pretty much just walk right don't touch a goon, but don't fall in a hole.
Scott: There's no flag.
Scott: even you just sort of walk off the map at the end and that's it.
Rym: I'll be more impressed if he implements it in reloading cascading style sheets.
Scott: Yeah, that's not so good.
Scott: But I got another link in addition to the Mario one in JavaScript link That is a it's.
Scott: basically this is dude John Resig, right and I don't know him.
Scott: He probably doesn't know me but like I met him once or twice because he was at RIT I think in my class.
Scott: I'm not sure if he's in my class But and he was pretty famous at RIT at least semi-famous because he made the sort of schedule maker program Which was a boon to many a student in those days.
Scott: if you knew what the scheduling situation was like at RIT Yeah, it was pretty high quality.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And now he basically he invented jQuery which is like one of the most premier JavaScript libraries in the world.
Scott: he wrote a book about JavaScript and He I think I think his job is still.
Scott: I think he's the JavaScript evangelist at Mozilla.
Scott: still I think that's his job.
Scott: So he's a pretty pretty much like the king of JavaScript in a way and On his website here.
Scott: He has a breakdown of exactly how this 14k Super Mario Brothers JavaScript was made like he shows you.
Scott: Oh, here's how he programmed it.
Scott: Here's how he did the images and ASCII.
Scott: Here's how he did the whole thing and it's pretty interesting stuff.
Scott: if you care about programming or JavaScript or anything like that.
Scott: I think it makes a good thing a day.
Rym: So what are we gonna talk about?
Rym: We're holding off on the ITCs alternating for a while.
Rym: give that a little bit of rest.
Rym: We'll bring it back.
Rym: Don't worry.
Scott: Yep Well, I don't know.
Scott: I want you to narrow down exactly what this topic is gonna be because it's sort of and feel like we've got sort of like three like Intermingling show ideas sort of like a Venn diagram and I sort of want to pick just one of those circles and sort of Concentrate on that.
Rym: only because a lot of there's a lot of things about the internet.
Rym: they're a lot of very different now from the way they used to be.
Rym: and we thought of this when people found like my old website and then Scott was talking about his old website and The things that people do on the internet and then over time those things are still hanging around and on one end I think about how People like us used the internet back in the day like in the 90s as opposed to now now come.
Rym: it was completely a different idea, but there's also talk about where are we going with the future where we're kind of the first generation that's going to be dealing with the fact that Everything we do from the beginning on is online forever.
Rym: So politicians coming up from our generation Are gonna have to deal with the fact that their Facebook from when they were in college with the solo cups is out there And no one can make it go away.
Scott: And you're already seeing stuff like this happening already.
Scott: like when people like meet new people they go and they google them right away.
Scott: You know you're seeing people.
Scott: When they go and apply for a job someone googles them and digs up all their internet Bones out of their closet as much as they can.
Rym: Yep, and it's only gonna get worse.
Rym: I mean, I eventually I'm curious how society is gonna deal with it.
Rym: because think about this on a fundamental level What are politicians from this generation gonna do?
Rym: because the only way to not have anything?
Rym: embarrassing or strange from your internet history would be to not be on the internet or to be groomed from birth to be a politician
Scott: and those are not the kind of people I think we want being politicians
Rym: now unless we make some sort of Political case and
Scott: That's not good.
Rym: So, I don't know what direction should we go with this?
Rym: Or maybe we'll just talk about the directions we could go and cop out and then do one of those shows next week.
Scott: Now let's talk about.
Scott: I want to talk about mostly like the things that we did when the internet was really new.
Scott: Like what was the first time you know?
Scott: That way I want to sort of because that seemed to be the interesting and entertaining Thing was like what was the internet like for us back in like the mid to late 90s?
Scott: Like what was the crazy shit going on?
Rym: I can say one thing most of these Facebook kids never heard of the first time I ever got one Back, then a lot of people myself included and Scott too early on Weren't quite sure what the internet was as opposed to what we had.
Scott: Yeah I mean I had heard that there was this information superhighway thing and I was like, ooh Actually, I had a computer with os2 and there was an icon that said info highway or information superhighway.
Scott: But like it didn't work the computer had a 14-4 modem but it wasn't plugged in and we had to pay.
Scott: I somehow knew we had to pay for something and I got.
Scott: we didn't pay for it and we didn't plug the modem in and there's no phone lines.
Scott: So like it didn't happen for quite a while, you know, but at other places I had used things like, you know I'd gone to one person's house made compi serve and I went to another person's house at AOL and I went to the comp USA and they had
Rym: AOL and I remember I dial into like local wares boards and things.
Scott: but yeah I remember like some people were like Like dialing into the local library or like people are connecting to work.
Scott: and then you know It was sort of like, you know I slowly realized the idea was that computers would connect over the phone lines somehow.
Rym: Regardless eventually we got on the internet because all that other stuff is a whole other show.
Rym: I had to a wells My first time quite a while.
Rym: I had prodigy classic and then when I first got on the internet, I used prodigy internet.
Scott: Yeah, but I was smart and I would actually run AOL to connect minimize it then open up Netscape navigate.
Rym: I never had AOL I used AOL.
Rym: I used a million free accounts when I was trying to hack things I also would use.
Rym: there used to be a bug with AOL.
Rym: Or if you sent like if you went to the logon thing and you did a certain thing You could crash the AOL login server for your area.
Rym: Yeah, and I we would do that periodically.
Scott: the main problem with AOL back in those days Right is?
Scott: they provided you with an internet connection.
Scott: They were your ISP, right, which is fine.
Scott: But what they would also do that was problematic is in order to connect you couldn't just dial up.
Scott: You had to run this AOL application, which is big monstrous and slow application Especially on old shitty computers at the time, which had almost no memory, you know.
Scott: Anyway, basically take up all the memory on your computer and make it really slow just to connect.
Scott: And it wasn't till later when I got my second computer that Pentium 3 that I brought to RIT That I I my parents leaves AOL.
Scott: But I switched to using the local phone company is the ISP and I just use Windows dial-up networking And so I didn't have to basically run my computer into the ground just to connect to the internet.
Rym: But again, that's all kind of a separate show.
Rym: I really want to talk about using the internet.
Rym: So we'll skip ahead to the first time I ever got on the internet.
Rym: I used Wow actually after prodigy internet because why was amazing?
Rym: It was the first like 20 bucks a month all you can use.
Scott: Hey, well, I was 20 bucks a month.
Scott: I can use.
Rym: I Was a lot faster - I didn't say wasn't plus I think.
Rym: anyway I don't think I didn't.
Rym: could you pay for all?
Rym: you can use AOL that early?
Rym: I don't remember exactly when that came later.
Scott: It did come at some point later But I was way.
Scott: I don't think we got AOL until it was unlimited.
Rym: remember I had a cable modem when I was in like a freshman in high school.
Scott: Yeah, we didn't cuz they weren't offered in our area for a while.
Rym: Yeah, I was.
Scott: I was using my parents Using a pretty slow DSL.
Rym: I use my cable modem to play quick one online.
Rym: Wow, but anyway.
Rym: So the first thing I ever did when I got on the internet was I clicked on the search button and this big search thing Came up and I typed bomb making instructions.
Rym: Wow, you're right because I'd heard yeah, everything's on the internet.
Rym: people make bombs and oh my god I was like, oh man, I'm gonna make me some fireworks.
Rym: I'm gonna blow up a trash can in the woods.
Rym: I'm gonna.
Rym: I'm gonna do all the cool things from cuz I saw war games.
Rym: I assumed that I could become Awesome, as long as I could go on the Internet.
Rym: Mmm, and I remember I found a bunch of bomb making things and my whole family was standing around me Like we're not gonna be on the internet and I was the tech guy.
Rym: No one else knew anything.
Rym: so the whole family and like the friends of my parents and like the kids from the neighborhood were all standing around as We get it online and they all look.
Rym: and as soon as I type bomb My mom goes.
Rym: I knew it.
Rym: My dad goes, let's see how long it takes for the FBI to come.
Rym: And we looked at bomb making instructions determined that they were all fake and I don't know what I did after that.
Scott: I Remember doing the chat room thing a lot because it was just something about chat rooms.
Rym: I did that on prodigy.
Rym: I was the head of that magic the gathering role-playing group I remember.
Scott: on AOL you could search for like games and there was this one part of AOL Where there's like some games you could download for free.
Scott: They were all really bad games, but they were like made in Visual Basic.
Scott: that just so my kids had put up there.
Scott: But I just went in there.
Scott: It was like AOL was weird because it felt like you were sort of crawling around and like this Untamed sort of weird dungeon of weird Unorganized shit.
Scott: and it was sort of like, you know They're just.
Scott: you really got the feeling even when you were just walking around looking at crap that you were sort of like Actually in a dank dungeon exploring and finding buried treasures, even if the treasures are crappy.
Scott: Yeah, I felt really good.
Rym: That's what the web was like.
Rym: I mean even let's go one step further.
Rym: forget the internet.
Rym: Let's just talk about the web because the web was a new thing and being on it back then There weren't search engines.
Rym: You couldn't search for things because they didn't work and they wouldn't ever find anything.
Scott: Yeah, there were some bastions of like sanity like Yahoo or Alta Vista or web crawler.
Scott: pretty much They didn't really help you.
Scott: and whenever you found something outside of like, you know, the obvious it was like.
Rym: Oh, I found a thing.
Rym: I remember that this is brother because thing no one does this anymore.
Rym: This is a term that was big in the 90s.
Rym: Surfing the web.
Rym: Yeah, people would web surf.
Rym: they would go on the internet.
Rym: They'd go to a website from there.
Rym: They go to the links page.
Rym: They click on another site from there.
Rym: They'd look at the bottom.
Rym: Oh, there's a web ring.
Rym: They'd go through the web ring till they found a site.
Rym: They like there.
Rym: then they'd click on another link.
Scott: Yeah it's like because of the way the net was structured like if you Knew what you wanted like you kind of like a cat kind of want video games and that's how general you had to be right.
Scott: you would sort of reach in that direction and you would end up in a lot of the same places over and over and Like when something spawned out in the distance, it would be really hard to get to but occasionally You would sort of find these things.
Rym: website that was like this website lists like all the ROM sites and Maybe a third of the links worked.
Rym: but that website was like the best website ever I know right and the dead links are all over the place like you'd expect dead links.
Rym: That was also remembered.
Rym: there were no tabs back then and I remember back in those days I would have like eight web browser windows open and I'd be surfing like eight different threads Simultaneous like in one web browser, I'd be like looking for Rob's the other web server where the other like web browser window.
Rym: I'd be going through all the art sites looking for like cool arts or It was crazy.
Rym: And then of course computers crashed all the time because you couldn't have all those windows open.
Rym: you had eight megabytes of RAM.
Scott: Yeah, I had 16 at that point.
Rym: at that point I'm trying to remember when I got the Pentium Pro.
Scott: I had 16 then but then later I had more.
Scott: Yeah, oh Yeah, those are those are great.
Scott: I remember playing Mudd's in those days.
Rym: That was back when there were ads on the internet.
Scott: Like I remember they wait because before there were ads but the ads were sort of like link share things like link exchange.
Scott: You know stuff like that link exchange, you know web rings link exchange was like.
Rym: I remember even back then Seeing link exchange on a website was like the sign that this website is crap Anything like that, there are all these things.
Rym: and I remember like GeoCities is where it's at Angelfire.
Rym: Those are where the bad kids are.
Scott: Yeah, that's right.
Rym: Angelfire was where like people would make porn sites but a porn site was something that had one picture on it.
Scott: It's like no one had actually the knowledge or the resources to have Actual web hosting or pay for it because it was mostly punk kids.
Rym: and remember GeoCities gave you two megabytes.
Rym: That was a big fucking deal.
Scott: and it wasn't like today where you go to like blog spot and they give you a blog.
Scott: It was GeoCities and you have to write static HTML and put it up there and take images and put them up there.
Scott: I know you've all found.
Scott: You can't do any PHP's.
Scott: You can't do it.
Scott: All you can do is write HTML's.
Rym: I know you've all found my old one of my old GeoCities sites.
Scott: I can't find my old GeoCities.
Scott: It was in Times Square Castle like 1876 or something like that.
Rym: My original GeoCities site, I had several.
Rym: I had two.
Rym: that were the clan websites for the various MMO and/or mud clans that I was a member of.
Rym: One of them was for the Magic the Gathering Role-playing circle that I was a member of and one of them was Mephistopheles Realm which included Doom modding and Japanese roms of games.
Scott: See I had one website One GeoCities, but like I actually I remember at one point I moved it to crosswinds.net because crosswinds was awesome because they gave you infinite space, but they were mad slow Mad slow.
Rym: Well, no what I did Everyone did is we'd put all our big files on crosswinds, but our real site was on GeoCities.
Scott: Oh, man, that's a good move.
Scott: I should have thought of that back in the day and then they started blocking referrers.
Rym: So we'd go we'd link like through anonymizers because back then those things worked.
Scott: But yeah, basically like the first the website I made I basically would like Because it wasn't like a blog right?
Scott: What I do is I had like a news section and I didn't have any news.
Scott: and then I had When I still believed that there are aliens, I'd made like a UFO section.
Scott: I didn't put anything in there either.
Rym: Mephistopheles Realm was all dark and because it was a Doom modding site nominally I had PaintShop Pro.
Scott: I bought it for 80 bucks and I would like try to draw graphics and things and I did it really poorly.
Scott: I would go on the internet and I found like one tutorial that was like do apply these filters in this order to make It look cool.
Scott: and I did that and I made like plastic text.
Rym: I had that animated gif of that fire.
Scott: Yeah, I made some image maps and oh man image maps.
Scott: I had repeating backgrounds that made it impossible to see back when there's the debate.
Rym: frames are good frames are evil.
Scott: The thing is like my first one or two.
Scott: does I?
Scott: basically I wouldn't actually Other than like writing some.
Scott: you know opinions of highest punk high school kid On there Occasionally and you know eventually I think my old site eventually evolved.
Scott: It's like this video game NES site that I think is still up somewhere.
Scott: You know, it was mostly crap in terms of content, but I basically learned HTMLs from.
Scott: you know, myspace level all the way up through.
Scott: not so bad.
Rym: I remember eighth or ninth grade.
Rym: Maybe it was earlier.
Rym: I don't remember when I was like man.
Rym: I want to make a wet an internet site a website and some guy who was all cool that I knew was like you got to Use the HTMLs.
Rym: I was like, what's that?
Rym: He's like, well say you want something to be bold, right?
Rym: You put a B in front of it And then you put like a slash B after and everything between those two things is bold.
Rym: I was like, that's it.
Rym: He was like, yeah, that's it.
Rym: Yeah, I'm making an internet site.
Rym: Oh, man.
Scott: So here I found the the final Incarnation of my original website.
Scott: Let's see.
Scott: How well is it working?
Scott: It's kind of working.
Scott: Okay, let me make let me just check out.
Scott: Okay, I think the screenshots are all gone.
Scott: Some of them are there.
Scott: hold on some of the screenshots are there.
Scott: Yeah, it's looking pretty good.
Scott: if you go to APRECHE.net Slash old hyphen site SITE slash index dot HTML You will find the sort of final incarnation of the website.
Scott: I made that and it was last updated in September 23rd of 2000.
Rym: man I will.
Rym: I would give anyone a t-shirt or something if you can find my original GeoCities website Mephistopheles around them.
Scott: Well on the links page.
Scott: There's a link to MU infinity.com Which is an emulator site that's been gone for 100 years and there's a link to classic gaming.com slash Metroid database Which still exists actually, I think it's part of game spy now or something.
Scott: Oh Let's see mp3s, I don't I have an mp3s link but there's no mp3s.
Rym: Oh, man, remember mp3s links mp3s sites sites.
Scott: Oh, yeah I got a whole bunch of like screenshots right that I took from Games in playing in the emulator and then I have little reviews I wrote of the different NES games and as any as games.
Rym: the weirdest thing to me still thinking back is that there were ads.
Rym: Yeah, like the fact that I there used to be ads on the internet that I would see and they'd be there Right away I was like, wait a minute until the pop-up ads came right before the pop-up ad times.
Scott: the ads were actually Less intrusive than they are now if you don't have the ad blocking?
Rym: Yeah, but at the same time even back then I remember immediately thinking how can I not see these?
Rym: Oh, definitely and Hosts file was where it was at back then house files.
Rym: a good way to route every bad thing I ever saw to one twenty seven dot o dot o dot one.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, it's a good move good move Any other nostalgia things to say they're not really?
Rym: Frames No frames.
Rym: remember.
Rym: I had oh remember every website had a million banners at the bottom.
Rym: You'd have the EFF banner.
Rym: You'd have the IE sucks banner or the Netscape sucks ban.
Scott: Yeah The blue ribbon free speech on the internet campaign were basically people were fighting for a free speech on the internet even though There wasn't really anyone fighting against free speech on the internet.
Scott: Well, there were.
Scott: it's like they saw it coming and there was like a preemptive defense and it was good.
Rym: Yeah, and all these banners and frames are good.
Rym: frames are evil.
Rym: I use frames.
Scott: I used frames that I didn't use.
Scott: it's like I. you know It changed daily like one day to be man.
Scott: if you use frames you can make a website where you know Your links sort of stay on the side for navigation, but then people thought well since my links are so awesome Why don't I make it?
Rym: So if you surf away from my site, my frame is still there.
Rym: and then everyone did that.
Scott: Yeah, so then it was like alright frames are bad now.
Scott: So everyone got.
Scott: I got rid of my frame So I made an image map.
Scott: then it's like image maps.
Scott: I had an image map in a frame at one point as my navigation.
Rym: Wow image maps are great.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, remember I wanted to make animated gifs, but I couldn't figure out how I had jazz paint shop pro.
Scott: So I was alright sad didn't have that though.
Rym: I eventually got a pirated copy of Autodesk animator and I spent months trying to make animations and none of them looked good.
Scott: Yeah, my at most of the stuff I did though was all text, you know Like I'd make some text fly across or I choose a different font and a different color and a different filter.
Rym: Yeah, I'd use a lot of word art and then I'd take a screenshot of that and then make a gif out of that.
Scott: Wow Wow, that was way early thing is that was that was this yet?
Scott: I didn't have the paint shop pro really until Like maybe sophomore year of high school.
Rym: The thing is you always kind of underestimate.
Rym: I think I bought it with some money I made like In all things considered how recently a lot of this was.
Rym: like you think wow, I made a website called Mephistopheles realm.
Rym: Yeah, I was in like eighth or ninth grade.
Rym: I wasn't that long ago.
Scott: Yeah, it's kind of.
Scott: it's kind of scary.
Scott: Like it feels like the ancient times, but really Maybe I thought it was cool.
Scott: I'm not even twice as old as I was as then.
Rym: I thought it was cool to turn the tea in Mephistopheles Mid to late 90s like 97 98 here.
Rym: also the fact that the internet was so different back then is to be unrecognizable.
Rym: However, the other thing I want to point out the the internet in places like Japan Now is pretty much exactly like the internet was here in the 90s.
Rym: Like it's frightening to go to a lot of Japanese websites.
Scott: Well some of them also myspace a lot of the bad myspace sites look a lot like myspace Looks like the kind of website that if you didn't know HTML you could use that JavaScript.
Rym: make my HTML thing.
Rym: Yeah on Geo cities I remember.
Scott: actually, you know shockwave flash is everywhere now, right?
Scott: It's all over the net but I remember the first flash.
Scott: there was the first flash I ever saw.
Scott: there was some website and they had some flash games.
Scott: It was like play games in the web browser like games that actually played like for real and I was like no fucking way.
Rym: I remember after Columbine a lot in like College Humor They made.
Rym: they made like Pico's world.
Rym: we're like in a high school and it was like all this.
Scott: people were trying to make games That were social commentary before that but I instead they're like it's all this plug-in.
Scott: So I knew a plugins work as I had them to play video files.
Scott: I remember real player and all that shit.
Scott: Yeah So I installed this plug-in right and then suddenly there's this game.
Scott: I was like Lenny lose jocks or something and they're like, I remember the website had a fish on it.
Scott: I could try to look it up But there were basically the earliest flash games and now it was ezone.com.
Scott: ezone.com still exists.
Scott: Holy crap It's a flash game site.
Rym: I just remember going to Newgrounds and all that business and people would make these Animations that by today's standards aren't even like.
Rym: I don't even know.
Rym: there's no radar that they would appear on like.
Rym: they're not.
Rym: They're nothing.
Rym: They're below the level of anything.
Rym: and yet people would huddle around a computer and watch these in their 200 by 200 pixel goodness.
Scott: Well, that was like, you know people have finally had CD encyclopedias.
Rym: They would watch, you know, we all watch that video of the first 10 seconds of Martin Luther King's speech Really?
Scott: I watched the video the 10 second really incredibly grainy low-resolution clip from Star Wars in Microsoft and Carta.
Scott: and then You know for some reason watching that tiny grainy clip of Star Wars in in Carta was better than watching actual Star Wars VHS yeah Computers internet.
Rym: that was just an nostalgia fest.
Rym: I think we should end there cuz I'm hungry and we didn't really go anywhere.
Rym: I'm so fucking hungry.
Scott: This episode didn't go anywhere.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our crapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew calm.
Scott: Or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an Odeo on the right side of our website.
Rym: if you like what you hear.
Rym: you Can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.