Scott: It's Monday, May 5th.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: Sneezy.
Scott: And this is GeekNights!
Scott: Tonight, the amazing, world-changing, memory store.
Scott: Let's do this!
Rym: So, uh, it being another Visigothic weekend, we had to go out for dinner as we do, and we always kind of go to the same places.
Rym: Like up, we go to the Cafe Maya, we go to the whatever, and we wanted to eat something different.
Scott: What can we eat different here?
Rym: Well, the thing is, there's fancy expensive places, but we don't want to go get like a $40 dinner every weekend.
Rym: That really doesn't work so well.
Scott: No, not really.
Rym: And there's one restaurant, one kind of food, that we ate a lot in Rochester, but we don't eat so much in Beacon, because while there is a restaurant that serves it, we have had a somewhat colored history with this restaurant.
Scott: Oh, oh, I know what you're going to talk about.
Rym: The Sukhothai in Beacon.
Rym: It's Thai food.
Rym: It's pretty good Thai food.
Scott: It's okay.
Scott: It's not as good as the King and I in Rochester.
Scott: Get that garlic pepper beef, oh man.
Rym: And it doesn't really hold a candle to anything in the city.
Scott: And then you would get the garlic pepper chicken, and then we would both basically get garlic pepper beef chicken.
Rym: We'd also get like four or five meats on sticks.
Rym: But that was just a given.
Scott: You mean satay?
Rym: Meat on stick for the uninitiated.
Scott: Correct.
Rym: It's meat on a stick.
Scott: I love meat on a stick, let me tell you.
Scott: If there is any way to eat meat, on a stick is probably the second best way to eat meat.
Rym: But you see, a while ago, we'd sworn off the Sukhothai because we'd gone one time with a group of like six or seven people, and I walked in and I said, "Hey, how long is the wait for
Rym: seven?".
Rym: And the guy said, "Just a
Rym: minute.".
Rym: And like 10 minutes go by.
Rym: So I go back up and say, "Hey, how long is the wait going to be?
Rym: I've already been here like 10
Rym: minutes.".
Rym: He says, "Just a
Rym: minute.".
Rym: "All
Rym: right.".
Rym: This repeats for a while.
Rym: Finally, we say, "Screw it," and just walk out and eat at the place across the street.
Rym: We go back like a month later and the same thing happens.
Rym: So we swore the place off, just terrible service, and the price was not-.
Scott: We've eaten there successfully a few times, but not recently.
Rym: Yeah, and I don't know if it's under new management or I don't know what the deal is, but we've been getting our Thai food in the city instead, where it's much better anyway.
Rym: But this weekend, we decided, "You know what?
Rym: We all really want Thai food.
Rym: Let's chance
Rym: it.".
Rym: And if we fail, there's that good Italian place right across the street.
Rym: So Emily and I went ahead to try to get a table.
Rym: And as we're walking in, there was a portent, you see, or a car slowed and it was full of punk kids, like punkology kids.
Rym: Window rolls down and they yell, "Fuck you, Sukhothai!
Rym: Fuck you!
Rym: Fuck you,
Rym: Sukhothai!".
Rym: And then they speed off.
Scott: See, now the question is, were they just in general saying, "Fuck you" to everything they passed?
Scott: Or were they specifically targeting the Sukhothai?
Rym: It was definitely a specific Sukhothai target, because they drove up, slowed down to a stop pretty much outside of the Sukhothai, called it out by name, then rolled up the window and continued.
Scott: There's a story there somewhere.
Rym: I'm sure there is, so whatever.
Rym: Emily and I go in, I say, "How long's the wait for
Rym: 9?".
Rym: And the woman says, "Just a
Rym: minute.".
Rym: And I say, "Well, just a minute before I get a table, or just a minute before you tell me along the way it
Rym: is.".
Rym: And she says, "Just a
Rym: minute.".
Rym: "It's all
Rym: right.".
Rym: I say, "All right, I'll be standing outside.
Rym: Will you come get me when you
Rym: know?".
Rym: And she said,
Rym: "Yeah.".
Rym: So I go outside, we wait a while, I walk back in.
Rym: "Hey, so can I get a table?
Rym: Just a
Rym: minute.".
Rym: "All right, are you going to give us a table or
Rym: not?".
Rym: "Let me talk to the
Rym: manager.".
Rym: Manager comes over and I'm like, "Hey, how long's the
Rym: wait?".
Rym: No one seems to be able to tell me.
Rym: I got 9 people, we're hungry.
Rym: And he says, "Oh, whoa, whoa, just a
Rym: minute.".
Rym: And then he walks away.
Rym: To which I say, "All right, screw
Rym: this.".
Rym: We went across the street and I got some lobster ravioli instead.
Scott: "Sukotai in Beacon, New York.
Scott: Do not eat there.
Scott: Ever.".
Rym: I don't know if it's that they don't like large parties, but that's not it.
Rym: Because there was a party of 11 already in there.
Scott: It looked like that was a reserved party that had a reservation.
Scott: But, you know, still, they definitely don't mind a large party.
Rym: But I think maybe they just don't like young people because there were, I realized, there were no parties of young people in that place.
Rym: But it has been a coincidence.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: It's not like that time.
Rym: Scott and I went to the Italian place in Fishkill where I was dressed like a hobo and we looked like people who could not afford to be eating there.
Scott: Yeah, but they let us in.
Scott: They fed us.
Scott: We went to this fancy $40 steak place not dressed up at all and they fed us.
Rym: I was wearing shorts and a scuzzy old webcomic t-shirt.
Scott: I was wearing shorts and a t-shirt and they totally fed us and they filled my water far too often.
Rym: Though when we went to that place when I was dressed like a hobo, they let us in and they served us.
Rym: But I remember they looked at me a little bit odd when I ordered wine.
Scott: Yeah, "How much for the
Scott: girls?".
Rym: "Ha, you're weaving.
Scott: How much for the
Scott: women?".
Scott: "How much for the
Rym: "I want to buy your women.
Rym: Your wife, your little
Rym: girl.".
Scott: Alright.
Rym: So yeah, we'll talk about the Visigoth thing on Tuesday where it's more relevant.
Scott: So I bought my new computer.
Rym: Yes, you did.
Scott: And we had that old, we had a server that died, right?
Scott: And I had my old computer which still worked, right?
Scott: So I said, "You know, I'll combine the server that died and my old computer that still works and make a working computer and that will be the new server because I really need a DNS server.
Scott: It's really hard to do web development without some sort of
Scott: DNS.".
Rym: Now something must have happened because the equation, I think what you intended was broken computer plus working computer equals better computer.
Rym: But instead, you got working computer times.
Rym: broken computer equals all broken computers.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much.
Scott: I mean, it's sort of one of those situations where the parts, I'm pretty sure, still work.
Scott: But like if you screw the motherboard into the case, then the case sort of touches the motherboard in a bad way.
Scott: It's a bad touch, if you will.
Rym: I need an adult.
Scott: It's a bad touch.
Scott: The motherboard is, "Where did he touch you,
Scott: motherboard?".
Rym: It was Scott Johnson and he had this sweater on.
Scott: Because if I take the motherboard out of the case and I rest it on a static bag and boot it, it works.
Scott: So I just got to screw it into the case in a very careful way where everything's lined up nicely, only touching the good places, and then it will boot properly.
Scott: If I don't, it goes, "Dee doo doo," which is very annoying.
Rym: Of course, you know, my old computer, Shazar, did that whenever it overheated.
Rym: And I think you remember that I solved that pretty handily by unplugging the PC speaker.
Scott: Yeah, no, but I've got, the thing is, right, I'm going to get this computer working somehow.
Scott: Alex also has some parts, so we can combine those two.
Scott: But I've got a lot of extra parts for computers.
Scott: And some of them, I like to have extra parts, so I don't want to get rid of all of them.
Scott: But some of them are working, but just not necessary.
Scott: Like, I do not need three 300-watt power supplies when I only have, like, two computers that could possibly use them.
Rym: We're going to have more.
Rym: I have that other power supply that wouldn't work with my motherboard, but it's otherwise fine, and I'm buying a new power supply just because the one I have now is loud.
Scott: I still have my first computer that was mine personally, my 8-bit BX6 R2 motherboard with the Pentium 3450 Slot 1 CPU in it, and I have RAM for it, and that is the most reliable computer in the known universe.
Scott: And it still works, I'm sure.
Scott: But I have no use for it unless I really want to make a DOS computer, but we have DOSBox now, the piece of software DOSBox, so it's really not necessary.
Rym: Yeah, there was a time when anyone who would really consider themselves a PC gamer kept around an old Pentium box to play DOS games.
Rym: But that technology, we have averted that.
Rym: We no longer need these old, archaic devices.
Scott: Yeah, if you don't know what DOSBox is, if you install old DOS games in Steam, like, say, Doom, it uses DOSBox to make those games work.
Rym: Yeah, or if you're hardcore, DOS EMU.
Scott: That's stupid hardcore.
Scott: Unnecessarily hardcore, in fact.
Scott: But yeah, so I'm just having a little trouble putting some computers together.
Scott: We'll see how this goes.
Scott: But I'm going to try to find, because I know there's those places that just take donations of old computer parts and then sort of do what I'm doing and make working computers and give them to people who don't have computers and teach them how to use them.
Rym: You should just give them all to Scott Johnson, because he has a collection of networking computers that would rival many museums.
Scott: But he doesn't do anything with them.
Rym: Well, he slowly builds computers.
Scott: He should open up one of those places that takes donations and builds computers and gives them to people.
Scott: Those places are actually really cool.
Scott: I don't know if there's one nearby us, but I know there's one in California.
Scott: I saw a video about it.
Scott: And basically, they take you in, right, and they collect parts from donations.
Scott: They take people in.
Scott: The people test parts to see if they work or not.
Scott: And the people learn how to build a computer.
Scott: And the deal is, you come in, you build X number of computers, and you get to keep one.
Scott: And then the other computers go to people who need computers who don't have them.
Scott: And they just build really crappy but working computers.
Rym: Which is fine for grandma.
Scott: Yeah, it's great for grandma.
Scott: It's also great for homeless guy and also great for crazy guy.
Rym: Oh man, speaking of fine for grandma, I got to burn a nice Ubuntu CD because Red Hat workstation, not cutting it.
Scott: No, not at all.
Rym: Oh, well, I had the pleasure of talking to Red Hat Enterprise Support.
Scott: Wow, you have to pay for that.
Rym: Well, back when I worked at IBM, we had Red Hat Support, and I never got anything out of them.
Rym: And sure enough, I can't get any useful information.
Rym: They don't really offer support, as far as I can tell.
Scott: What are you paying for?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: This is an experiment, so I think my next test is going to be, "Will Ubuntu
Rym: boot?"
Rym: Followed by, "Look everybody, Ubuntu is
Rym: better.".
Scott: And another thing, right, is I have two 17-inch monitors on my desk that I'm using with the new computer.
Rym: Scott bought those things back when you could not use LCDs for gaming, unless you bought the one that Scott had.
Scott: Way back in the day, right, if you wanted an LCD monitor and you wanted to play games, it was impossible.
Scott: I mean, it worked, but you would get this ghosting effect because the refresh rates of the monitor were so slow that, like, it would draw, like, if you were moving left and right in an FPS, just like aim to the left, aim to the right, it wouldn't erase fully the gun on the left before it drew it on the right.
Rym: It was awful.
Scott: So everything was, like, had this ghost.
Scott: It was, like, you could see the ghost of your former self.
Scott: Like, if a bad guy moved, you could see where he just was and where he was now, and it really sucked.
Scott: And then eventually they got the monitors to a point where they had a 12-millisecond refresh rate.
Rym: That's pretty much the line.
Scott: That's the line.
Scott: It's, like, 12 milliseconds.
Scott: Now there's no ghosting when you play an FPS at 75 frames per second, right?
Scott: So I was, like, hot shit.
Scott: And so I went, and it was also, it's a really nice monitor.
Scott: Like, it can adjust in all different directions, and it would, like, there's barely any plastic around the screen itself.
Scott: I hate that when there's, like, a monitor, and then around the monitor there's all this plastic or speakers or any other shit like that.
Rym: That's why I'm really liking these.
Rym: Dell is rocking with the wide screens.
Scott: Dell has conquered the monitor world.
Scott: Like, ViewSonic is down the shitter.
Scott: But anyway, so I have two.
Scott: I bought the first one when it was $500.
Scott: I think it might have been $550.
Scott: So that was poor at RIT, relatively poor anyway.
Scott: I got a Samsung 17-inch LCD, the 172X, famous monitor.
Scott: In those days, everyone, if you said what monitor do I buy, everyone said 172X.
Scott: And then later on, I bought another 172X, like, right before they were discontinued.
Rym: Now this presented a problem, because then Scott realized that his one he'd had for so long had a little bit of a problem with the backlight.
Scott: Yeah, I know.
Scott: It's like I turned the new one on, and the old one I thought was just fine.
Scott: But turning the new one on, it was, like, twice as bright as the old one.
Scott: Now I don't know if they maybe made changes to it along the production process, or if I damaged the backlight or something.
Scott: Because it has even lighting, it's just as dim lighting compared to the newer one.
Scott: So now I have a bright 17-inch LCD and a dim 17-inch LCD, but they both work.
Scott: They both work well enough to see.
Scott: One just has unreliable color, and is only good for a side monitor, not a primary monitor.
Scott: And I've had these two monitors for a while, and I feel really bad replacing them, because they cost so much money.
Scott: But a Dell UltraSharp 20-inch widescreen is $250, which makes me feel terrible.
Rym: You know, you could just use three monitors.
Scott: No, I don't have room on my desk, or I would.
Rym: You could have two monitors, have the widescreen, and then the other one.
Scott: That's what I'm gonna do, probably.
Scott: That's a good idea.
Scott: But I went to the Dell website, right?
Scott: Now here's a few things I gotta say about this.
Scott: Number one, widescreen monitors, right?
Scott: They are a good deal, and they're just fine.
Scott: I mean, buy one, I recommend it.
Scott: But they're not as good a deal as you think.
Scott: Because, think about this, right?
Rym: Well, just look at a square, and then look at a rectangle, and do some geometry, knowing that they measure diagonally.
Rym: And I think it's self-evident.
Scott: Well, think about this, okay?
Scott: 20-inch widescreen, resolution, 1680x1050.
Scott: 22-inch widescreen, same resolution.
Scott: You're not getting any more screen real estate.
Scott: All you're doing by buying the 22-inch is you can sit farther away.
Scott: That's the only difference.
Rym: Well, no, the thing is, I prefer, to a degree, a larger one.
Scott: Well, besides sitting farther away, what advantage is there?
Scott: It's bigger.
Scott: What's the advantage, besides being able to sit farther away, what's the advantage of it being bigger?
Rym: It's bigger.
Rym: You can see it more easily.
Scott: So you can sit slightly farther away?
Rym: Or sit closer, and it's even clearer.
Scott: I don't see any other advantage to it being bigger.
Rym: A resolution is all that matters.
Rym: Then get a 12-inch monitor with a 1900 by whatever crazy resolution.
Scott: There's a point at which it becomes silly.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, yeah, whatever.
Scott: It's not true to the extreme, but it's true for two inches.
Rym: No, I very much, because I had, at work, I had a 20-inch, 16, whatever, 1600x1050, or 1680x1050.
Rym: And then at home, I got the 22-inch, 1680x1050.
Rym: I much prefer the 22-inch.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Scott: Anyway, I prefer the 1680x1050.
Rym: So then at work, I got another 1680x1050, 22-inch.
Rym: And then I got another one.
Scott: At work, I have a 22-inch.
Scott: I'm not a fan.
Scott: But anyway, if you look, a 20-inch square non-widescreen monitor is 1600x1200.
Scott: 1600x1200 is a lot more than 1680x1050.
Scott: That's why the square monitor is $500 and the widescreen is $250.
Rym: I still think you're better off with the widescreen.
Scott: Yeah, that's why every laptop today is widescreen, because they can advertise more inches, right?
Scott: Because that's what people look at, the inches.
Scott: But they're actually, you have less overall space.
Scott: And they save money.
Scott: And that's why it seems like such a deal.
Scott: Like, oh my God, 20-inch monitor for almost nothing.
Scott: Well, actually, a 19-inch square monitor is bigger than that 20-inch.
Scott: You know, in terms of square inches and pixels and things.
Rym: Yeah, of course, pretty much every usability study shows that except for very specific applications, you're usually better off having more horizontal screen space.
Scott: Well, the reason you're better off with horizontal space is because horizontal scrolling is a million times worse than vertical scrolling.
Rym: But also, the side-by-side and toolbars and docking and everything.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Scott: I still like having separate monitors as well.
Rym: Well, but that's not for, like, viewing.
Rym: That's for, like, workflow.
Scott: Right, right, right, no.
Rym: Which is a totally different issue.
Scott: So, anyway, I think I'm going to buy the 20-inch Dell widescreen because it can rotate sideways and be tall.
Rym: Be warned.
Rym: Because I did that at work just to see because, like, hee-hee.
Rym: And I realized something.
Rym: Pretty much every LCD monitor, you know, they have the viewing angle.
Rym: And they've really gotten the horizontal viewing angles to be a lot better than they used to be.
Scott: The vertical viewing angle not so much.
Rym: Yeah, so if you turn it vertically, your viewing angle goes to shit.
Scott: The thing is, that's okay because I would only turn it vertically when I'm coding, which is pretty much just text.
Scott: And I'll be able to see anyway.
Scott: And that's when I can get a really tall VI and see lots of code at once.
Rym: Honestly, if I were coding more than I do now, I would have two widescreens.
Rym: One vertical, one horizontal.
Scott: Oh, that's not bad, but yeah.
Scott: That's what I would do.
Scott: I don't have room on my desk for that.
Scott: Otherwise, I might buy that.
Scott: But the thing is, I went to the Dell website, and I'm pretty sure I did actually buy the monitor, but I didn't get an email.
Scott: So I'm not sure if it went through or not.
Scott: And I'm like, I could just go buy it again, but...
Rym: Just buy it again.
Scott: The thing is, is two gonna show up?
Scott: I gotta go check to see if they charge my credit card to figure out if I bought it or not.
Rym: You should get on that.
Scott: Yeah, I'm gonna check after the show, and then if it wasn't charged to my credit card, I'll buy it.
Scott: And if they send me two, I just won't open one, and I'll return it.
Rym: But before we get on to the news, if I sound a little bit weird, probably for the rest of this week... You have horrible allergies.
Rym: I'm allergic to a degree.
Scott: Do you wanna talk about the Chromelim sodium fiasco?
Rym: I'm gonna save that, but suffice to say, no one sells Chromelim sodium around here.
Rym: And every pharmacist I've talked to has pretty much said, "Yeah, no one wants real medicine.
Rym: They'd rather use that Zicam
Rym: crap.".
Scott: Yeah, that doesn't work and actually destroys your sense of smell?
Rym: Yeah, one pharmacist was like, "Yeah, that stuff doesn't
Rym: work.".
Scott: Zicam, if you use it, it will destroy your sense of smell.
Scott: As in, you use it, you use it again, you use it again.
Scott: Not only will it not do anything that it's supposed to do, or is, yeah, it says it will do, but you eventually won't be able to smell things.
Scott: Isn't that wonderful?
Rym: You know what, though?
Rym: Even worse, a lot of people...
Scott: I guess if there's a lot of poop around, or if you're like, you know, a septic tank guy, Zicam is great.
Rym: And other than the Zicam, they sell, like, there's a million nose sprays, but they're all actually the same thing as Afrin.
Scott: Well, they're oxy-whatnot.
Scott: There's actually another kind.
Rym: I'm not talking about that crap, but I'm talking about one that works.
Rym: Afrin.
Rym: It's something hydrochloride.
Scott: Yeah, that's the one I was talking about.
Rym: Might be because there's another oxy-something.
Scott: I was in the store and I looked at the nose sprays and I saw four kinds.
Scott: Saline, Afrin, Oxy-whatever, something else that was like phospho-something-something, and bullshit Zicam.
Rym: But the thing is, the Afrin one, don't take that either because, yeah, that'll decongest someone.
Rym: But then, if you don't take it again, you'll double congest.
Rym: It's this known rebound problem.
Scott: There was actually a Mucinex brand nose spray, but it was just the Afrin.
Rym: Yeah, it was.
Scott: And they had another one that was just the other kind.
Rym: See, the thing is, I like Mucinex, but now that I know all about it, I just buy the three different ingredients that make up the different Mucinexes and just make the same dosage.
Scott: Yeah, I bought the-.
Scott: Yeah, I bought the Sudafedrin Mucinex.
Scott: That'll last me forever.
Rym: Yeah, well, we've got all different three kinds.
Rym: We've got every combination for every sickness.
Scott: For our meth lab.
Rym: So, I don't have a lot to say about this, but in the news, people are talking about how there might be, this is purely speculation.
Scott: Speculation.
Rym: But MacGyver movie, to which I said, "But there was already a MacGyver
Rym: movie.".
Scott: I did not know this.
Scott: I saw it.
Rym: When I was a kid- It was causing lead poisoning, and they found the woman's skull.
Scott: See, when I was a kid, MacGyver, my cartoons would be over, and then I would see the MacGyver opener, and they would have commercials like, "Up next, MacGyver," and then I would turn it off and eat dinner.
Rym: I would skip the commercials and skip the cartoons and then sit down to watch me some MacGyver, because I gotta tell you what, Richard Dean Anderson is awesome.
Scott: You know, I watched MacGyver a few times.
Scott: It was okay.
Rym: I liked it.
Scott: I liked the fact that- It's better for making funny jokes about blowing up buildings with paperclips.
Rym: It was a pretty good show, all things considered.
Rym: The science, not always quite on the spot.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, there were better shows.
Scott: I mean, Mission Impossible is a better show.
Rym: Eh, I preferred MacGyver.
Scott: Nah, anyway.
Rym: Plus, Richard Dean Anderson.
Scott: Yeah, MacGyver, like, you know it was in that time slot before MacGyver when I was a kid?
Rym: For me, it was the A-Team.
Scott: For me, it was 21 Jump Street was on that time slot.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I never actually watched 21 Jump Street.
Scott: Me either, but I saw the opener, and then I turned it off and went to eat dinner.
Rym: I turned on the TV, and it'd be like the end of 21 Jump Street.
Rym: And I always wondered what it was about.
Rym: Yeah, basically it was like- I assumed it was like kids in a drug-invested school.
Scott: I watched my cartoons, and then this live-action show opener would start, and I would turn it off and eat dinner.
Scott: Oh, those are the days.
Scott: Alright.
Rym: I'm looking up what 21 Jump Street was.
Scott: Oh, shit.
Scott: You want me to do my news?
Rym: Alright, do your news.
Scott: So, Blu-Ray beat the shit out of HD DVD.
Scott: That was a few months ago, right?
Scott: Well, that's kind of like saying that, yeah- I beat the shit out of that baby.
Rym: That one baby beat up that other baby.
Scott: The news now, which isn't really news, because they've sort of just been saying the same thing, and it's sort of been true for a long time.
Scott: It's just suddenly all the news organizations have decided to talk to, you know, put the story up.
Scott: Blu-Ray sales stagnant, unlikely to improve this year.
Scott: Pretty much, they're saying exactly what everyone said before.
Scott: Regardless of who wins this war, right, which has already won, the war is over.
Scott: People are happy with DVDs, Blu-Ray or HDVD, but basically Blu-Ray has no significant advantage over DVD.
Scott: that makes people want to switch to it.
Scott: You know, I mean, most people don't even have HDTVs.
Scott: If they did, most people don't even hook them up right.
Scott: Blu-Ray players are really expensive, the discs are really expensive.
Scott: There's a rumor going around- There's a rumor going around.
Scott: There's a rumor that started with the guy who's the head of Netflix that they're going to charge more for renting a Blu-Ray.
Scott: And people already have large DVD collections, they're happy with their DVDs.
Scott: And Blu-Ray is really not selling, except for in the PS3.
Scott: And the PS3 isn't really selling, at least not until the Metal Gear comes.
Scott: Honestly, I think part of what's doing it- The GTA will sell a few PS3s, but it's selling 360s as well.
Rym: There's kind of been a general economic slowdown, and Blu-Ray is very expensive.
Scott: Yeah, in an economic slowdown, people are not going to go and switch up their cheap DVD players for the Blu-Rays and HDTVs.
Scott: That's not at the top of the list.
Rym: The standalone players are hella expensive.
Scott: People can't even afford gas and food.
Scott: They are hella expensive.
Scott: Yeah, and gas- You know what's even more hella expensive?
Scott: A drive for your computer.
Rym: I actually know Blu-Ray drives are stupidly cheap.
Rym: Really?
Rym: Yeah, they're like ludicrously cheap.
Scott: Maybe I should go.
Rym: In fact, they come with all the laptops now.
Scott: All the Dell laptops come with them, which is sort of like supposed to be the deal.
Scott: Like everyone's like, "Hey, don't buy a Blu-Ray player.
Scott: Just buy a Dell laptop and then use the TV out and you'll be all
Scott: set.".
Scott: Which is not a bad idea, really.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is- If you need a laptop, at least.
Scott: Don't buy that instead of a player.
Scott: I'm sure the player's cheaper than a laptop.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I'll be honest.
Rym: You're probably, if you want a Blu-Ray player, you're best off getting a PS3.
Scott: The PS3 really is the best bet for the Blu-Ray player, but- From what I read, it's better than all the real Blu-Ray players.
Rym: It's cheaper and better.
Scott: Yeah, and the PS3, you know, it has some good stuff going on.
Rym: It has Gran Turismo.
Scott: Well, it has Gran Turismo.
Rym: So, 21 Jump Street, 1987.
Scott: Good God, my brother was one.
Rym: That was more than a decade ago.
Scott: I was five.
Scott: All the old people who are older than me feel old.
Scott: All the young people weren't born yet, punk kids.
Rym: Quote, "21 Jump Street is the headquarters for a squad of police officers who specialize in investigations relating to young
Rym: people.".
Rym: "Each of the Jump Street personnel was selected for their ability to pass for high school
Rym: students.".
Rym: "Allowing them to operate undercover in areas where it is difficult for regular police officers to blend in
Rym: unnoticed.".
Rym: I guess I was right.
Rym: I thought it was about kids in high school with drugs.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much.
Scott: Alright.
Scott: Is that your news or what?
Rym: Well, you just did your news.
Scott: Yeah, what's your news?
Rym: I said there's gonna be maybe another MacGyver movie.
Scott: Oh, that was your news?
Rym: That's all I got.
Scott: On Monday?
Rym: Yeah, MacGyver, Science and Tech.
Scott: Alrighty, let's go to things of the day.
Rym: So, things of the day.
Rym: This isn't related at all to Monday, so forget it, whatever.
Rym: I found this guy really random.
Scott: You really phoned it in.
Rym: Yeah, I'm full of allergies and it's kinda late.
Scott: You've been constantly sneezing for like hours.
Rym: Yeah, I keep hitting the mute button and blowing my nose for five minutes.
Scott: It's awful.
Scott: Did you order the stuff online?
Rym: Yeah, but it won't be here for a while.
Scott: How much did you order?
Scott: A lot, hopefully?
Rym: I bought a case of it.
Rym: There you go.
Rym: Enough to last you a few years?
Rym: It takes about a week for it to take effect.
Scott: That's fine.
Rym: But anyway.
Scott: You're the one suffering.
Scott: I'm only suffering partially.
Rym: This is from some TV show.
Rym: I'll admit.
Scott: 21 Jump Street?
Rym: I wish.
Scott: I have no idea.
Scott: People are gonna be talking about 21 Jump Street and The Forbes.
Rym: I think we're gonna have to do a show about 21 Jump Street.
Rym: I've never seen it.
Scott: Me either.
Rym: Thursday, we'll Skype someone in who liked it.
Scott: That's not a show.
Rym: So, I think the guy on the left is Doogie Howser.
Scott: What's with the old TV shows today?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: The actor who played Doogie Howser.
Scott: Alright, alright.
Rym: Not the real Doogie Howser.
Scott: He's supposed to be like, he's an infamous dude.
Rym: Well, you learn that from Harold and Kumar.
Rym: Go to White Castle.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Oh god, we should do a show on that.
Scott: It's not worthy of a show.
Rym: Half of it was worthy of a show.
Scott: Anyway, go down with your thing of the day.
Rym: Get on with it?
Scott: Get on with it.
Rym: Alright.
Rym: I don't know what this show is.
Rym: Some kind of talk show.
Rym: But they're talking.
Rym: And these two guys are talking about how with their friends like, yeah, they would like sing the confrontation song from Les Miserables at each other.
Rym: And I found that funny because when I was in high school, we totally did that with Dr.
Rym: Jekyll and Mr.
Rym: Hyde, the gothic musical thriller.
Rym: But not well.
Rym: Oh, no, no.
Rym: I'll get to that.
Rym: The only difference between what me and my friends did in high school and what these people are doing on this video is that they can sing.
Rym: and good god, am I never going to sing anything from Dr.
Rym: Jekyll and Mr.
Rym: Hyde, the gothic musical thriller again.
Scott: I mean, listen to these guys.
Scott: I thought they were just playing the album, the CD of Les Miserables that you can buy in the store.
Scott: It sounds a lot like it.
Rym: Well, they definitely used the phrasing of the original British cast as opposed to some of the later casts.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, that's the one that I know because, I mean, I saw it once live, you know, on Broadway, but mostly I've heard the CD or, I guess, the cassette tape.
Rym: I'm not going to sing, but there are two different, like, styles for doing Les Mis.
Rym: And in the opening scene, like one guy, one way where they're like, "Now I bring me prisoner two, four, six," so like they kind of drag it out.
Rym: And the other styles are like, "Now I bring me prisoner two, four, six,".
Rym: so one and then all this pause with the music.
Scott: Yeah, that's the one that I hear.
Scott: That's the one that you heard?
Scott: That's the one I've always heard.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I never heard that other one.
Rym: When I saw it, I saw the other one.
Scott: I think that's even the one that I saw on Broadway.
Scott: did it the second way.
Rym: I saw both on Broadway.
Rym: Huh.
Rym: I saw Les Mis like four times, though, because it was high school.
Scott: The greatest part about seeing that play is the turning stage.
Scott: It's just this big circle, and it turns around.
Scott: I go,
Scott: "Whoo.".
Rym: I remember talking to the cast after.
Scott: And then like those guys, like when they got like the chain gang, and they're walking.
Scott: Look down.
Scott: They're staying still, but they're walking because it's a spinning circle.
Scott: I learned one thing.
Scott: The guys practice walking at the same speed as the circle.
Rym: I talked to the cast afterward because it was like this high school trip, so I got this big poster actually with like the cast signing it.
Rym: But, oh man, high school.
Scott: All right, so when you went to see Les Mis, right, which guy got the most applause of anybody?
Rym: Obviously, it was the Eternadiers.
Scott: Ah, yes.
Scott: That is correct.
Scott: I saw like the best guy who was in that part ever.
Rym: It's always the best guy in that part.
Rym: And the guy who played the sad guy looked exactly like Stephen Wright and sounded exactly like Stephen Wright.
Rym: I don't remember.
Rym: It was Stephen Wright.
Scott: No, no, no.
Scott: It's all about-- What do you mean?
Rym: you don't remember?
Rym: You didn't see it at like the Pantages.
Scott: No.
Rym: But anyway, I'll skip all that.
Rym: All I learned is that it's really, really hard to walk on that stage.
Scott: Yeah, it really is.
Rym: Okay, so check-- But this video, they're like, "Yeah, we used to do this to each other when we were friends way
Rym: back.".
Rym: And they're like, "Well, now you have to do
Rym: it.".
Rym: So they do it, and it's great.
Scott: Yep, I just said it was great before.
Rym: Yeah, but now I'm saying it's great, thus concluding my thing of the day and now I can blow my nose while you do yours.
Scott: All right, so me and Emily, we're talking before a week or so ago, and I was actually thinking about this even before then.
Scott: And basically, we live in a house that doesn't have a basement, doesn't have a garage, right?
Scott: But we're nerdy type people, and we want to do workshop kind of things.
Scott: Like I want to cut some wood to make woodworking projects.
Rym: Or like when I made that DDR pad back in the day.
Scott: I want to do some metalworking, maybe machine some parts to--.
Scott: Maybe if I want to do one of those cool how-to-do-it-yourself hack things, like a portable SNES, I need to machine some parts, right?
Scott: And I need a metalworking shop or something.
Scott: Or maybe I want to weld something.
Scott: I don't have a welder, I'm not going to buy a welder, but I might need to weld something once in a while.
Rym: And unless you have the resources and the space and the time to set all this up, you either have to give up, find someone else who has the stuff, or go the half-assed way.
Rym: And the half-assed way resulted in me burning myself a lot.
Scott: Right, so it's like at RIT, I found out too late that there were actually metalworking labs that I could just use.
Scott: It was sort of like I was almost graduated, and I was like, "Wait a minute, I could just come to this lab and make
Scott: stuff?".
Scott: They're like, "Yeah, you're a student here, what is your tuition paying
Scott: for?".
Scott: I'm like, "Nobody tells
Scott: me!".
Scott: And it was too late to get all Make Magazine up in that business, so it never happened.
Scott: But lately I kind of want to be all Make Magazine up in this business, but it's not easy.
Scott: Well, somebody solved this problem before I did, and I just had to find out about them too late.
Scott: It's called Tech Shop, Build Your Dreams Here.
Scott: And what they do is it's sort of like, you know how you have a workout gym, like a sports club where they have all these big expensive machines you can't afford, but you go and you pay a membership fee and then you can go and use their machines whenever you want?
Scott: This is the same thing only for tools and tech things and metalworking.
Scott: And the best thing is they know that most people-- because there's a lot more tools than there are workout machines, right?
Scott: They know that most people only know how to use a few of the tools, so they have all these classes where you know how to use these three machines and he knows how to use those three machines and you sort of teach each other, so everyone learns how to use all the machines they need to use.
Rym: That's a really good idea because you get out of your element really quick.
Rym: It's like, "All right, I got this jigsaw down.
Rym: I can
Rym: jig.".
Rym: And then you go over to the band saw and it's like, "All
Rym: right.".
Rym: This may look like a jigsaw, but it does not act like a jigsaw.
Scott: Here's what it says on the side of their website.
Scott: "Open classes as of Monday the 5th at 5.41 p.m "Introduction to soldering basics, CNC vinyl cutter SBU, "English wheel and cold form metal shaping, introductions to carbon fiber, "CNC plasma cutter
Scott: SBU.".
Scott: I want to take the plasma cutter class.
Scott: Sweet.
Scott: But basically, there's like one, two, three, four, five, six of these things in fucking California.
Scott: There's like two, one in Seattle, one in Portland, one in Texas, one in Florida, and one in North Carolina.
Scott: New York City, come on, step it up.
Scott: I need a lab here.
Rym: Someone out there, you want a business opportunity in Manhattan?
Scott: Yeah, the thing is, the way these things work, the way they're funded, see, most people don't realize this.
Scott: The way a workout gym makes its money, like a New York sports club or a Gold's Gym or any of those places, the way they make their money is this.
Scott: They have big membership drives.
Scott: They say, "Join, join, join, join, join," right?
Scott: And they charge like 30 bucks a month or something like that.
Scott: And people join, join, join, join, join, but hardly anyone actually goes.
Scott: Such a small percentage of the people actually show up.
Rym: Well, it depends.
Rym: If you go to a gym between January 2nd and January 8th, it'll be packed.
Rym: Right, right, right.
Rym: But they don't go back.
Scott: No, no.
Scott: People will go once and they usually won't come back.
Scott: If everyone who actually had a membership went regularly, they'd be out of business because they would have to buy so many machines to keep up with it that they would be screwed.
Scott: So they buy a very small amount of machines of a very large membership that they can't realistically accommodate.
Scott: So like ISPs, they have very little bandwidth and all these people pay for the bandwidth, but only a few people actually use it a lot.
Scott: And thus they get away with not having enough bandwidth to support everyone using all of the bandwidth they pay for at once.
Scott: So that's how gyms make their money.
Scott: This place can't do that because you'd be damn sure anyone who pays is showing up, right?
Scott: So what do they do?
Scott: What they do is they get loans, but they don't get loans from the bank.
Scott: They get loans from people in the community who want to be members.
Scott: If a place like this wanted to open up, I, Scott Rubin, would give them a $25,000 loan.
Scott: They would pay me back and I would be a member and I'd be able to vote and maybe I'd even own part of the place.
Rym: Yeah, it's called a business.
Scott: Right, right, right.
Scott: But that's how they do it, these community loan deals.
Scott: I think that's a pretty cool idea and I think that's probably the only way that something like this would ever be able to exist short of Bill Gates just giving them the money or something like that.
Scott: So yeah, come on.
Scott: We need this in New York.
Scott: I need to make things.
Scott: Come on.
Rym: Alright, so we were thinking about talking about the memristor for the main kind of show.
Scott: We probably should.
Scott: You got a better idea?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: It's already 9.30.
Rym: I'm feeling tired and allergy.
Scott: You can talk about anything.
Scott: Talk about something.
Rym: I could just cop.
Rym: I could bail.
Scott: Don't bail.
Rym: Alright, Scott, so how does a memristor work?
Scott: Forget the chemical.
Rym: No, no, but like what are the inputs and outputs?
Rym: How stateful is it?
Scott: It's analog stateful.
Rym: But no, no, I mean how stateful as in does it keep its state forever?
Rym: Does it need to be refreshed at all?
Scott: No, it doesn't need to be refreshed.
Scott: Ever?
Scott: It might in a very, very long time, but not in a short time.
Scott: Alright.
Rym: Alright.
Rym: Off to a good start here.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Okay, let's go back a little bit, right?
Scott: In electronics, right, there are three things that make pretty much every electronic device is made up of three things.
Scott: It's made up of resistors, inductors, and capacitors.
Rym: Now, why are those the three fundamental components as opposed to say diodes or other things?
Scott: Well, a diode is actually a combination of resistors, capacitors, and inductors.
Scott: I'm pretty sure.
Scott: Is it?
Scott: I might be wrong.
Scott: I don't have an electronics degree.
Scott: I don't know that much about it.
Scott: I know PV equals an RT.
Rym: What does a diode do?
Scott: It has three prongs on it.
Rym: No, it has two.
Scott: No, I don't know.
Scott: I've used ones with three prongs.
Rym: Are you sure those weren't transistors?
Scott: Yeah, I'm pretty sure.
Scott: Anyway, I know a transistor also has three prongs.
Scott: Anyway, we suck at electronics.
Rym: What are the inputs and outputs on a transistor?
Scott: Oh, a transistor.
Scott: Okay, I know how a transistor works because that's my...
Rym: PNP or NPN?
Scott: A transistor has one in and one out, and then there's the toggle on the top where you sort of... If there's electricity going in the top, then it's a pass-through.
Scott: If it's not going in the top, then it doesn't pass through, and that's how it works.
Scott: Anyway...
Rym: All right, so continue.
Scott: So recently, there was a theoretical... Since the '70s, since a long time ago, there was a theoretical fourth component of electronics.
Scott: There was the memristor, and it was only on paper.
Scott: Like, no one actually had one of these things, but if you did the math, you said, "Aha!
Scott: There could be this other fourth thing, but it doesn't
Scott: exist.".
Scott: And people from time to time tried to make it, and it never really worked out.
Scott: Until very recently, HP actually made it, and that's crazy.
Scott: Like, holy shit crazy, but people don't realize how crazy it is because, like me, they don't understand electronics, and I'm sure that... I already know some of our friends are like, "Uh, Scott, you know what I think about
Scott: electronics?".
Scott: And they're going to start emailing and forming, saying how moron I am.
Scott: But that's what I get for not reading the Wikipedia before doing this episode, and Rym not saying much and helping me out, mostly challenging me and exposing my lack of electronics knowledge, which is fine, because I admit I lack electronics knowledge.
Rym: Well, you see, I don't know a lot, but I know that a diode does not have three terminals.
Scott: I remember making a little project, it was like a little burglar alarm, and they said, "Yeah, put the diode there," and it had three prongies on the bottom.
Scott: It was like a little black square.
Rym: Are you sure that wasn't a transistor?
Scott: I don't know anymore.
Rym: I think it was a transistor.
Scott: Anyway, it could have been.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I'm lost.
Scott: Regardless, the memristor is crazy.
Rym: I mean, I guess it could have been like a rectifier diode.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I don't know anything.
Scott: So, a memristor.
Scott: A memristor is crazy, because what it does is this, right?
Scott: Right now, if you want to store a bit, you want to remember a bit, the ways we have to do that are a few.
Scott: We can do a flip-flop, but a flip-flop, you lose the electricity, it's not flip-flopped anymore, really.
Scott: We can do a capacitor, which is what RAM does, but RAM also loses when you turn the electricity off.
Scott: Not immediately, but eventually.
Scott: We can do a circuit breaker kind of thing, which is like what your BIOS does, or your CMOS, which is incredibly slow, and it's like a bunch of switches moving back, it's terrible.
Scott: We can do a magnet thing, which is what your hard drive does, also horrendously slow.
Scott: And we can do flash, also.
Scott: And those are pretty much the big ones.
Scott: Oh, we can do a register, but a register is flip-flops, right?
Scott: So, what else, you know, do you really, what are we going to do?
Scott: The memristor is pretty much like the ultimate answer to this problem.
Scott: What you have is they have this special chemical, I forget what chemical they used, I didn't read it.
Scott: It was like lead, or I forget.
Scott: Anyway, you send a current across the memristor in one direction, right?
Scott: And as you send the current across, right, you send a direct current, DC.
Scott: DC current across in one direction, across the memristor, and the resistance increases.
Scott: And you send the direct current across in the other direction, and the resistance decreases.
Rym: Now, the common thing that people mistake right away is that somehow you have to keep having this current there.
Rym: It's like it's just you control it with the current.
Scott: No, because the way it's made, the chemical that's in there, you apply the current, and the chemical sort of moves and changes, and now is more resistant.
Scott: And it's not going to move again unless you send some more direct current at it from one of the directions.
Scott: And then, what you do is you send an alternating current into the memristor.
Scott: Now, the alternating current won't move it, so its resistance level will not change when sending an alternating current.
Scott: But what you can do is you send the alternating current in one side, and on the other side, you can figure out, by looking at the alternating current that comes out, how much it resisted you.
Scott: Thus, you use direct current to change the data that's in there, and use alternating current to read.
Scott: So it's this little thing, it's a circuit, and you can read, and you can write.
Scott: And not only can you read and you write one and zero, like you could say if the resistance is below one, it's zero, and if it's above one, it's one, right?
Scott: And now you have basically what amounts to storing one bit of data, and it will store that one bit of data even if you turn all the electricity off, and it's wicked fast.
Scott: But you could say, well, since I can basically change the resistance between the minimum resistance it can handle and the maximum, I could make sort of an analog thing.
Scott: It could store any number from zero to 100 maybe.
Scott: I could divide it into 32 sections and say, look, I can store 32 possible values on this one memristor.
Scott: And since it's really small, and it's a fundamental component, we could get a whole zillion of these things in there.
Scott: And that's crazy.
Scott: In terms of what it means for consumer electronics, it's probably going to start out with crazy fast RAM.
Rym: It's non-volatile storage, but you can also use it for control.
Scott: It's going to start out with maybe replacing flash.
Scott: That IBM racetrack memory we talked about might be basically screwed.
Scott: You might see CPUs that have a lot of actual storage space in them, like a CPU.
Rym: Well, remember, in its current implementations, it's not that fast yet.
Scott: No, but it's going to be.
Rym: It's one order of magnitude slower than dynamic RAM.
Rym: Right.
Scott: But I mean, we're talking like a CPU where you could turn the electricity off on the computer, turn it back on, and the RAM and the CPU, if they're both just memristors, will pick up right where they left off.
Scott: So you could turn your computer off, off, off, off, completely off, and then turn it back on and it won't even boot.
Scott: It'll just be immediately back on where it was when you turned it off.
Scott: That's like the beginning.
Scott: That is like the first most obvious thing you can do with this amazing technology.
Rym: I'm imagining more that with this sort of analog control, you could make very large branching networks and do really crazy kind of neural style things.
Scott: That's what the scientists type people are hoping.
Scott: is that because it's not just one or zero, you can sort of get this levels of resistance that you can sort of get a few memristors together and sort of simulate something like a neuron.
Scott: Or even if you can't make a brain, you can make a computer that works more like a brain than like a core two duo.
Scott: Anything else to say about the memristor except about how amazing this is.
Scott: an amazing discovery of holy shit?
Rym: As amazing as it is, I'm full of allergies and I'm just kind of waiting to bail tonight.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: HP is the people who invented this.
Scott: So invest in them when the stock price already went up a little too late.
Rym: Do not take anything that I said today to be investment advice of any kind.
Scott: No, it's not allowed to give investment advice.
Scott: And I know nothing about the stock market except I won the stock market game when I was in like 10th grade.
Scott: Oh, no, seventh grade.
Scott: But yeah, if I would have known this news story a day before it hit the news, I would have bought HP that day.
Rym: Well, actually, the thing is, despite all the news about HP, there's at least one other company that has a patent for a very, very similar thing.
Rym: They'll do the same thing.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I would say, since it's already sort of too late to get the HP before it jumps up, I say wait for the, like, pay attention to the patent story on this.
Scott: Because there might be like, you know, all sorts of stuff like.
Scott: this is a fundamental thing.
Scott: You can't patent it.
Scott: There might be things like, well, this guy actually came up with it.
Scott: You just made it.
Scott: And this, you know, all the different specific parts of it are patented by different people.
Rym: No, the idea is not, that has nothing to do with it.
Rym: If you're going to talk about patents, what is patented is the process.
Scott: That is true.
Rym: And as manufacturing goes, I mean, remember, I worked in a manufacturing environment at IBM where we made like the cell chips, among other things.
Rym: And the art and the science of making the things counts for a billion times more than the theoretical or even the proof of concept.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: But I would keep an eye on how this patent war is going to play out and whoever wins, I would get your monies ready if you're that kind of person who likes to, you know, invest in the stocks and not just your safe old 401k.
Rym: Again, I have no opinion whatsoever.
Scott: Ram has no opinion.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But it's funny how like these amazing discoveries happen.
Scott: But like most people, either because they can't understand them or because I don't know the way the world is, like you don't sort of fully grasp it.
Scott: You know, I don't know.
Scott: It doesn't seem like this thing happens.
Scott: This kind of amazing discovery happens too often anymore.
Scott: You know what happened when he said everything that can be invented has been invented.
Rym: There's a layman's way to understand why this is so revolutionary.
Rym: Like here's the proof.
Rym: There are now two terms that you will need to know in electronics, memristance and memductance.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, pretty much they have to rewrite every electronics textbook, all of them.
Scott: It's that crazy.
Scott: Like, you know, there's advances now and then, you know, and this advances all the time in electronics, actually.
Scott: But none of them are like, OK, we have to rewrite the whole textbook right now.
Scott: They're usually, OK, we'll revise the textbook and we'll make a few corrections here and there for new things we learned.
Scott: This is throw your textbook out the window material here.
Scott: This is like you might not see this again in your life, this kind of advancement.
Rym: I mean, it's kind of like, you know, we have logic, it's like and and or nor.
Rym: It's not possible with just, you know, with straight logic.
Rym: But imagine if someone came up with a new gate that did something else.
Scott: I can't even think because there's no discrete math to go with the gate.
Scott: It's not like.
Scott: this is discrete math.
Scott: We don't have a gate to go with it.
Rym: That's because like saying, well, in the two dimensional world, I know what's the third dimension like.
Rym: now there isn't one.
Scott: I know it's like there is no logical syllogism that we cannot make with Gates.
Scott: So it's like I couldn't even.
Scott: this is where basically the memristor is where he had the syllogism, but we didn't have the actual component to make it happen.
Scott: But now we have it, which is why it's crazy.
Scott: All right.
Scott: It's like as if we knew we could do Nand on paper, but we didn't actually have a Nand gate.
Rym: So we had to get around suddenly, you know, that would have been the worst case because Nand is the simplest gate.
Scott: I know that you can pretty much make everything that you can make with Gates with Nand Gates only.
Rym: Well, what do you mean?
Rym: Pretty much you can.
Scott: I know.
Rym: That's why if you go to Radio Shack, you can buy a chip that's just like 40 Nand Gates.
Scott: Those are the best chips.
Scott: It's just a big long bug.
Scott: And it's like, you know, these two and then that one and these two goes to that one and these two goes to that one.
Scott: And they're all just Nand Gates lined up.
Rym: And on that note, I was muted and sneezing for a while, so I'm totally bailing.
Scott: Yeah, let's bail.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com, where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our Frapper map, and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology.
Rym: Tuesdays we have video games, board games, and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights, and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com, or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Scott: Just click the link that says "Send me an Odeo" on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: For the complete archives, visit the website, which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution Non-Commercial Share-A-Like 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it, as long as you give us credit, don't make money, and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.