Rym: It's Monday March 10th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We answer the question somewhat what is information technology?
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: What a day I get on my train.
Rym: I had lost my hour, so it's dark again.
Rym: But that's fine because now it's light out sun is out.
Scott: It's amazing.
Scott: Yeah I don't know if we should use all the things that happen today as the opening bit because let's never want to have opening bits For the rest of the day.
Rym: Let's just rush right through him cuz tomorrow is gonna be the all smash brothers Alright, so let's see I wake up.
Scott: I missed the train.
Rym: Wow I've owned by one minute.
Scott: I pulled into the train station as the train was pulling out.
Scott: if I hadn't brought back the trash cans I would have made it.
Rym: You know I've now.
Rym: I've only once missed a train.
Scott: Yeah, at least for work, so I just hung out at the train station listen to my iPod whatever.
Rym: Yeah, see I got on my train and on my laptop, and I was laying there.
Rym: There's this big fat guy Behind the seat.
Rym: I was gonna sit in like he was big enough.
Rym: I'm curious how he got in the door because he took up two whole seats like fully.
Rym: He might have taken the double doors he might have and uh alright bad guy.
Rym: No big deal There's a seat in front of him, so I'll just sit there and and then about 20 minutes in the train ride I hear a choking sound followed by.
Scott: That's just wonderful.
Scott: All right, you can stop that.
Scott: now You're wasting time in the back got worse and worse and any like fun.
Scott: She's moved to another car.
Rym: Oh, I left.
Rym: I left the car.
Rym: okay, so did a bunch of other people.
Rym: yeah But I tell you what if I were a conductor I would have woken that guy up every time I walked by him on the way home.
Scott: the guy sitting next to me.
Scott: He wasn't a bad guy, but he smelled like fast-food grease something fierce.
Scott: I couldn't tell if he worked in a fast food, or if he just had just eaten it and gotten all over himself.
Rym: I could not tell the economy is definitely not bad enough to where McDonald's workers are commuting in.
Scott: no But I smelled man.
Scott: the economy could never be good enough.
Scott: then McDonald's commute in but Yeah, he smelled like fast food all the whole way, and it was kind of sickening.
Rym: well I think the economy either has to be really really good or really really bad for the fast-food workers to commute in.
Rym: there's no middle ground there.
Scott: I Guess yeah Cuz if it was really bad their meager Fast-food incomes would be enough to pay for a commute because the commute price would be so low and money be so valuable.
Rym: yeah At the same time if real estate is still so bad in the city which even when the city turns to shit real estate still Crazy there, or if the economy was so great then fast-food workers are making a bajillion dollars And they could afford to commute.
Rym: or we have Monaco or Monica could have.
Scott: Monica could have Monica.
Rym: I'll tell you what if we have Monaco.
Rym: if I'm not in New York.
Rym: I'm out of here.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: Anyway, oh, so what other crazy should have?
Scott: Smash Brothers came in the mail today.
Rym: Yeah, just kidding as much as we want to play We're gonna hold out at least until we finish.
Scott: yeah Yeah, you probably thought you were clever fooling everyone like that.
Scott: But they're.
Scott: they can all look at their iPods and see this podcast is plenty of time left.
Rym: You know most people don't.
Rym: I know how people listen to their iPods, and I know I listen to my iPod.
Rym: I just hit play on a playlist, and I'm just sitting there, and I'm just listening And I don't look.
Rym: I don't see my iPod.
Rym: my iPod is away and possibly locked.
Scott: See I actually when it is away and locked But if I hear the end of a podcast I get my iPod out and to switch it up.
Scott: and Usually a lot of podcast the ending shit I don't want to listen to.
Scott: so I'll get ready.
Rym: so but what about the stinger?
Scott: no But if a podcast ended like started sounded like it was ending prematurely I would take a look to see if it was a broken mp3 where they fuck yeah, but you
Rym: forget that there's that that moment that split second where they hear that music and they go ah Those bastards.
Scott: and then they hear me say just kidding before they could look and they go ah right also today at work Like my co-workers weren't there, so it was like there's only four tech workers.
Scott: So it was me and the boss and that was it and we're just kind of sitting there like yep.
Rym: A few people didn't handle the DST transition so well no Lot of.
Rym: I called a lot of customers and people to say hey You're gonna connect an hour from now I'm guessing like oh, yeah Oops yeah, also a lot of people just didn't seem to have enough sleep today and TP And it doesn't cut solve that.
Rym: NTP just sets the clock.
Rym: your computer had better handle the time zone.
Scott: Yeah, that's right.
Scott: You got to set Etsy local time.
Rym: Yeah Symbolic link yes you do.
Rym: and also what if you have some demons or systems that think in GMT which a lot of people do?
Scott: You gotta have Etsy local time set to the right thing.
Scott: so it's a no.
Rym: No, what if everything is in GMT straight up where there is no daylight savings time?
Rym: You need to be aware of that and right around that in your software, which a lot of people don't anyway.
Rym: Everything should be in GMT.
Rym: computers shouldn't have to care what time it is, but I digress.
Scott: well That's the way.
Scott: every that all my computers are is that?
Scott: well I guess except for my desktop because it has to reboot to Windows and Windows is stupid as shit.
Scott: But all my Linux only computers.
Scott: the hardware clock is in GMT and the operating system knows what time zone I'm in and it interpolates for any clock Like logs and everything.
Rym: I like to have everything as possible in GMT.
Scott: Oh, yeah, definitely But no for any time.
Scott: the only time it should translate to a time zone is when someone has to look at the time in Say, you know the clock applet in the yeah only when a human needs to see the exactly Yeah, oh and the governor is in trouble.
Rym: Oh, yeah our man Spitzer You know It amazes me.
Rym: Just how Many people can be so corrupt in our government.
Scott: I mean, I mean the governor I lived in Connecticut governor corrupt Governor Roland was corrupt and he got went to jail, right?
Scott: Let's see in New Jersey He was gay.
Scott: So he resigned.
Scott: But it's it's still the governor got in trouble.
Scott: New York governor Prostitution.
Scott: and we should do a Thursday on prostitution.
Scott: We should do a Thursday on governors that too, but governor in trouble I don't think a lot of you know, are you connecting states governor's in trouble?
Rym: I'm gonna put forth a statement.
Rym: I don't think a lot of our listeners in the US actually know what the governor's duties are.
Scott: I don't think they know either.
Scott: and you know what I'm thinking about this.
Rym: I'm curious.
Rym: Answer this in the forum.
Rym: How many of you who live in the United States without looking it up know who your governor is?
Rym: That's all I want to ask.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Here's the thing.
Scott: I really want to know as I was trying to think right?
Scott: We have listeners that are international right and international listeners probably know about the president of the United States and whatever They may even know about the Congress.
Scott: They might know states have governors But like, you know, like Germany has states right and there must be local, you know Governance for the the states of Germany or the states of France.
Rym: If you're asking the providences of Canada, if you're asking people to tell us about their local or federalized government structure There's something called Wikipedia.
Scott: No, no, no.
Scott: No, I'm wondering right.
Scott: It's like I have.
Scott: I could not name a single like Like.
Scott: who's the the person in charge of Alberta?
Scott: I couldn't I have no clue.
Scott: The person in charge of Ontario.
Rym: No, I think it's obvious Scott You really don't know the person in charge of Alberta You're?
Rym: you honestly don't What?
Scott: there's someone who's like the who's the guess the equivalent of governor of?
Rym: obviously it's Prince Albert.
Scott: No It's not funny.
Scott: This is stupid.
Rym: No, it's not.
Scott: but you know They probably don't.
Scott: Albert and people in other countries probably have no fucking clue unless they're really smart or they pay really close attention About like the you know, the lower levels of the state and town.
Scott: Honest no, but I think it's really interesting.
Scott: and now I kind of want to know how local and state governments who work in other countries Yeah, and I want them to know about ours Wikipedia.
Scott: Yeah Won't be that complete.
Scott: Wikipedia is u.s.
Rym: Central more so go read the Wikipedia on Germany.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, but to get the to get the really detailed information.
Scott: I'd have to read the Wikipedia that's written in German.
Scott: Really there'd be a lot more information in that one than there would be.
Rym: I suggest you go because most Wikipedia is for countries that people care enough about to write an article about Tend to have an entirely separate page dedicated solely to the minutiae of their governmental structures.
Rym: Yeah, I'm just saying I think all the information is there.
Scott: I think that in that level of information will be there.
Scott: But if I were to say look up Information about like a specific state in a specific town and like what's the situation is there right now?
Rym: I think that would be worse now because that shouldn't even be in Wikipedia.
Scott: Well, a lot of this stuff's in there for the US and Wikipedia.
Scott: They're like not really pages for like every town in the United States and who's the mayor?
Rym: and you realize there's pages for most of The places in France and Britain to to go.
Scott: take a look then.
Scott: that'd be interesting.
Rym: Anyway But yeah, there's there's a bunch of news and I'll talk about this real briefly because I so little needs to be said.
Rym: but apparently a Lawmaker Tim couch in a state somewhere some state that doesn't matter at all has Decided that the best way to fix the problems that he is facing In the world today and the people are facing is to ban Anonymity on the internet.
Rym: and all I want to say is good luck, sir with that.
Rym: Good luck to you, sir.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know where to begin on that one like I it's very rare that statement by a person Will is able to so succinctly and so clearly convey unto me the fact that they have no Concept of what the internet is.
Scott: you should probably ban steering wheels on cars.
Scott: No steering wheels on the car.
Rym: never use the computer in their lives.
Scott: We should we should ban we should ban wings on airplanes.
Scott: The wings are causing all the trouble there.
Rym: Of course, he says enforcing this bill if it becomes law would be a challenge.
Scott: Well, okay, so he's not a hundred percent moron he's just 99.9 percent moron.
Rym: This is just like.
Rym: this is crazy.
Rym: quote if the bill becomes law the website operator.
Rym: So I guess this only affects website operators in Kentucky.
Rym: Okay Would have to pay if someone was allowed to post information anonymously on their site.
Rym: The fine would be five hundred dollars for a first offense and one thousand dollars for each offense after that.
Scott: So basically all that.
Scott: why doesn't he?
Scott: that's the same thing as writing a law saying we don't want anyone to host websites in Kentucky.
Rym: Yeah, pretty much.
Rym: but it's also illegal to post anything online.
Rym: So if you live in Kentucky and you post on slash dot you're breaking the law.
Scott: Wait a minute.
Scott: But if you're anonymous and you're in Kentucky, how the fuck will they know?
Rym: Well, they'll probably try to subpoena slashed out for IP addresses.
Scott: So wait, they're gonna subpoena slash time.
Scott: say give us the IP addresses of every anonymous poster And we're gonna look and see if any of them are in Kentucky.
Scott: Well, no, that's not gonna fly.
Rym: what they'd be tricky.
Rym: What they probably do is just ban any sort of business interactions with slash dot Which is fine because I don't think there's any company in Kentucky that would bother advertising on slash dot.
Scott: man.
Scott: I hope they do this because it'd be so cool to drive through Kentucky in the future.
Scott: It'd be like Jetson's house Jetson's house caveman log cabin.
Scott: caveman log cabin.
Scott: Jetson's house.
Scott: when you come back out on the other side.
Rym: This is so ludicrous that it's not even worth discussing.
Rym: Banning anonymity on the internet is like banning spitting in a dark room.
Rym: Okay, anyway, so what do you got?
Scott: so, you know, I hate the fake medicines a lot.
Scott: you hate the fake medicines.
Rym: Yeah, the only difference between the two of us is that Scott will not shop at the local Hippie market because while the local hippie market is the only store in the area that has a lot of really good stuff It also sells made-up fake dangerous medicine pretty much.
Scott: Well, it's not.
Scott: it's the opposite of dangerous.
Scott: It does nothing That's.
Rym: that's a problem from other perspectives.
Scott: Yeah, it is.
Rym: But the only difference is that I will go there But I will get into arguments with people and generally be a cock while I'm there and I'll feel dirty the whole time.
Rym: But it's the only place I can buy my guava juice.
Scott: You can buy guava juice across the river at the other place.
Rym: Yes across the river.
Scott: Can you buy guava juice in the city and then carry it home?
Scott: Yeah, why not?
Scott: I carry stuff to the city.
Scott: I might as well carry it home.
Rym: That's not worth it.
Rym: Anyway, so You know how I get away with it.
Rym: I buy small amounts with my credit card Something I hate.
Scott: worse.
Scott: Oh, I don't know.
Scott: hate equally to fake medicine is when people are putting down real medicine Like those people who say don't take vaccines, they'll give you autism.
Scott: All right complete bullshit.
Rym: I think we can sum this up real quick in case anyone.
Rym: we have a lot of new listeners So in case you're not up to speed One the Marisol isn't even used in fucking vaccines anymore in the u.s.
Rym: So it doesn't even matter - it doesn't cause autism.
Rym: three Vaccines in general do not cause autism period.
Scott: Yeah, I mean if you don't notice right, I mean I had a biology teacher once in 11th grade and he was like Oh, you don't need vaccines.
Scott: It'd be alright.
Rym: Right and wow that guy shouldn't be a biology teacher.
Scott: Yeah, and at the time it kind of made a little bit of sense, you know Cuz from what I learned in biology class, you know, like, you know, if a virus comes in your body will make antibodies.
Scott: You know, whatever right?
Scott: He was like, oh you don't need to take a flu vaccine Just take some you know Nearly dead flu and just kind of swab them on the back of your throat and then your body will build up vaccine exactly What.
Scott: So and it was only you know a couple years later that I realized huh?
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Anyway, so yeah if you don't notice Right.
Scott: Oh and also the other argument that biology teacher used to make was you know Oh back in my day when the polio vaccine was coming out kids would get the vaccine and then they would still get polio.
Rym: but So anyway, I have a hyphenated word to respond to that that is herd immunity, right.
Scott: so If you don't realize right, um way back before the polio vaccine There was a lot of polio and now after the polio vaccine Where's the polio?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: maybe we should look for it, you know before MMR kids used to get measles.
Scott: You know what.
Scott: and mumps and rubella.
Rym: I'll tell you this measles sucks mumps sucks rubella not cool.
Scott: But you know what?
Scott: now?
Scott: who gets measles?
Scott: who gets mumps?
Scott: who gets rubella?
Scott: at least the United States Almost nobody, you know what you would get it like.
Scott: you would get the flu or the cold all the fucking time.
Scott: But now no, it's gone.
Rym: tetanus shots.
Rym: What about diptheria?
Rym: diptheria is actually really dangerous to a lot of kids.
Rym: But now you don't get to theory because you get your tetanus diptheria shot.
Scott: That's right But you know what?
Scott: now for anyone who doesn't believe in fucking vaccines and their awesomeness, right?
Rym: I'm sure we don't need.
Rym: I mean, I guess we're preaching to the choir now.
Scott: Yes Because anyone who disagrees right stop listening cuz they're more.
Rym: I don't want those people listening to my show.
Scott: Yeah, if you don't believe something like that that's in the past that you know, maybe it was something else.
Scott: You don't know cuz you're a moron.
Scott: Here's an Inarguable proof.
Scott: the vaccines are the real deal.
Scott: Uganda right people were kids were getting meningitis left and right.
Scott: like 5,000 kids a year would die from this horrible meningitis.
Scott: and if you don't know about meningitis Meningitis is like the worst thing ever.
Rym: There are two forms of meningitis effectively in terms of how they like what they can do to you.
Rym: There's viral meningitis.
Scott: I really quick and die even quicker.
Rym: Well, actually the viral meningitis and bacterial meningitis and actually my stepdad had viral meningitis.
Rym: Uh, it's not At that bad, it's pretty bad.
Rym: Most forms of bacterial cuz remember it's an infection of the meninges.
Rym: if you don't know what meninges are I suggest get the learn To John Wikipedia.
Rym: if you if there's bacteria growing in your meninges.
Scott: you're serious shit You're going to die.
Scott: You need those meninges.
Scott: but anyway, I Think the things that are in anyway or anyway, so there was mad mad meningitis going down in Uganda, right?
Scott: So they got this vaccine.
Scott: this vaccine has existed since 1991, right?
Scott: But it cost seven dollars at the price.
Scott: to you know The poor country price was seven dollars which is seven times as much as some other vaccines that they could get.
Scott: so they You know through their magic works the kind of works that Bill Clinton are doing.
Scott: people like Bill Clinton are doing.
Scott: they got the price down to one dollar and they helped prevent 2.3 million deaths since the year 2000.
Rym: That's uh, that's closing in on Norman Norman Borlaug right there.
Scott: I know what Uganda.
Scott: people dying of meningitis insert vaccine.
Scott: No more Meningitis, huh?
Scott: No, does it maybe work?
Rym: now to the crazy?
Rym: Who argue that?
Rym: Yeah, it protects you from those diseases, but it also causes autism.
Rym: I would wager that autism rates in Uganda are not gonna change.
Scott: No.
Rym: No, I don't think so except perhaps that maybe a percentage of children who might have died of meningitis before they had the chance to even Manifest their autism will now manifest their autism, but that's not.
Scott: Anyway, so here's the thing, right?
Scott: I'm sure that in Uganda.
Scott: They had plenty of witch doctoring maybe homeopathies maybe Acupuncture's.
Scott: who knows they probably had some bullshit medicine.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: They had that.
Scott: they've had that because that's the argument people always make right.
Scott: this Acupuncture has been around for millions of years.
Scott: Therefore.
Scott: It's so old and ancient.
Scott: It must be right because anything old is right something new is wrong.
Rym: speaking of which acupuncture reflex ology and Chiropractic are bullshit and homeopathy.
Rym: Yes, but I'm assuming you know that.
Rym: yeah.
Scott: Anyway in Uganda, they've had some sort of fake medicine probably for a very long time And you know what the meningitis didn't stop until the real medicine came.
Scott: Real medicine is real fake medicine is fake.
Scott: shut the fuck.
Rym: The Problem is I don't think anyone who needs to hear that message is listening to GeekNights let alone on the internet.
Scott: No, I don't think so.
Scott: But even if one person has learned it'll be enough.
Rym: so Right along with that since my news was such a cop-out.
Rym: I just I couldn't Ignore this to get to the Facebook news or what?
Rym: I got a news here that it's kind of interesting.
Rym: actually now the article to which this links includes a video.
Rym: do not Okay, watch this video.
Rym: the video is absolutely Stupid.
Scott: I didn't watch the video.
Scott: I just read the article which is disappointingly short.
Rym: Yes, the articles dumb the videos dumb, but it's one of those.
Rym: the article doesn't matter.
Rym: What matters is the discussion that is generated?
Scott: I think you'll make a good Thursday episode and we should hang on to it.
Rym: Oh, maybe we will but I'll introduce it.
Rym: then I'll do two half news's.
Rym: I think that works.
Rym: So the question raised is should scientists date people who believe in astrology?
Scott: The short answer right?
Scott: No Here's my short answer, right?
Scott: Every individual human being can date whoever the fuck they want.
Scott: And here's my other answer.
Scott: I wouldn't.
Rym: Well, you see it's actually I don't know how complicated of an issue it is because the way I look at it I mean you I mean there's arguments for I'll read the rest of this here.
Rym: wired science asks should Scientists date people who believe in astrology?
Rym: Apparently the argument is quite complex.
Rym: Astrology is a complex flawed mental shortcut for understanding the world.
Rym: That's an understatement.
Scott: It's quite an understatement.
Rym: So is Disregarding someone because of their spiritual beliefs.
Rym: That's that does not follow.
Rym: That's not quite a anyway false premise.
Rym: possibly anyway, women are inundated with astrological nonsense from fashion magazines So so it is normative for them to believe it even if they otherwise are highly logical.
Rym: That's excellent.
Rym: that that's that takes sexism to a new level that I don't know.
Scott: I think that's about on the same level.
Scott: I've seen it everywhere else.
Rym: and the last thing smart people can convince themselves of silly things.
Rym: now, there is an interesting phenomenon whereby Certain sometimes people who are very smart will defend a wrong idea long after they would have in a vacuum already been convinced that the idea was wrong because of misplaced pride and because a lot of times smart people are able to find evidence and Put forth their arguments eloquently in order to kind of hold out longer like you might be wrong But you might be smart enough to convince people who are dumber than you that you're right anyway longer until someone smart such a right.
Scott: There's also the problem of this is where we're gonna start doing the whole episode on it and that there are people who are very Intelligent.
Scott: they're very knowledgeable about the world and they're very good at you know Math and or other things right or writing or whatever and they're very intelligent smart people, but they don't have the the skeptical Scientific evidence is required or I will believe nothing viewpoint of the world Which is the only correct sort of viewpoint to have to be completely rational and thus they can convince themselves Of irrational things.
Rym: now, I mean that I take issue with almost every sentence in this little summary here.
Rym: I mean Astrology is a flawed mental shortcut for understanding the world.
Rym: astrology saying it's a flawed mental shortcut goes a step.
Rym: Yeah, it's just outright sham.
Rym: It's nothing.
Rym: It was anything.
Rym: It's just astrology is fantasy.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: It's that's just all there is to it.
Scott: It's completely made up nothing.
Rym: and the whole women thing.
Rym: I don't even want to touch that because that's just.
Scott: Yeah, I hope I clicked on the link because the link was just like should scientists date an astrologer?
Scott: and I was like Oh, that's not a bad.
Scott: I you know article.
Scott: I'll read that but the article is so bad and disappointing.
Rym: in short I was like, ah, but the whole but so is disregarding someone because of their spiritual beliefs.
Rym: now there's a real issue here with conflating ideas and spirituality and philosophy and religion are three very different things and people
Scott: You know have different definitions of them and such and you sort of have to before you discuss them with someone Decide what the definitions are going to do something.
Rym: There are a lot of people who are very spiritual but at the same time do not hold any irrational beliefs at all.
Rym: and there are a lot of people who when confronted with an atheist or someone who believes in science will Make an argument along the lines of oh you say there's no and nothing out there There can't be anything out there.
Rym: But this on earth for what we've seen that nothing could possibly exist because that it added up.
Rym: But that's just because they're conflating the terms.
Rym: just because I haven't observed something doesn't mean it's not out there or something like that.
Rym: It just means I haven't observed it there and no one I've ever met or ever read of or ever Experienced has ever observed it.
Rym: There's no record of observing it.
Rym: Logically, I cannot believe that it exists and I can logically assume that it probably does not exist.
Rym: But that does not discount outright that it does not exist.
Rym: But a rational person will assume that it does not exist unless presented with other evidence.
Scott: Yes, this is why we should do a whole episode on this.
Rym: I think we should you know Yeah, just kind of the idea that denouncing religion in and of itself is not denouncing philosophy.
Rym: I think it is spirituality.
Scott: I think basically it goes back to our old point of you know While discriminating against anyone seems wrong and in many cases is wrong But it depends on why you discriminate against the person.
Scott: if I discriminate against someone because they're a psycho killer That's okay.
Scott: If I discriminated against someone because they believe the tooth fairy is real that's okay.
Rym: If I discriminate against someone because they're black whoa now that trouble.
Rym: Yeah, that's not okay You know, but I mean it's kind of like.
Scott: I mean if I discriminate against someone Who's a Jew because they were born of Jewish parents and they have a Jewish culture That's not okay.
Scott: If I discriminated against someone because they believe in a magical Skyman and they treat their wife poorly that is okay.
Scott: those, you know, the thing is they both, you know You could put you on both of those things, but they're two different.
Scott: This is where you run into trouble.
Rym: you say we need a word for secular Jew as opposed to religious.
Scott: We need we need a word in general for secular kinds of thing, you know Yeah, like a Muslim religious Muslim cultural Muslim big difference.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, yeah, there are people who are just Irish You know, they just love Ireland and they like to drink and they like leprechauns.
Scott: Wow way to go Yeah, I know right and I'm throwing to my little funniness there, but they're not like super Catholics like You know could be off.
Scott: most Irish type peoples are because it's also the Protestant Irish and that is why they have wars and things.
Scott: But not getting into that because I don't know enough about it.
Rym: to say more I could speak volumes.
Scott: I just get into trouble for For many reasons.
Rym: It was actually a hot issue in Detroit and I'm well versed in the.
Scott: the Irish trouble I'm only slightly versed.
Scott: So let us pass that on and continue to things of the day.
Rym: Well, I'll end on this because this is this is the important thing.
Rym: I want to get out of this here.
Rym: When it comes to disregard it people seem to try to make spiritual or religious beliefs somehow different from other kinds of beliefs or other kinds of assertions and I can't go there.
Rym: I'm of the mind that Any idea once an idea is put forth into the world into the marketplace of ideas If someone states an idea that idea is now no matter who said it no matter what backing it has subject to the scrutiny of the world and subject to all the verbal or written criticism that any human being can muster and If someone is not willing to deal with that sort of criticism or that sort of critique Then they really shouldn't be putting forth the idea and then getting in a huff when people Possibly disrespect or shoot down or otherwise criticize the idea.
Scott: Yep, all ideas are created equal.
Scott: if your idea can't stand up on its own then it can't stand up.
Scott: Idea is sacred.
Rym: but to get to the I'm done now, this is it.
Rym: This is the easy way.
Rym: It's real easy to get into the whole.
Rym: Well, what about philosophical?
Rym: What about blah?
Rym: It's very very very simple to answer this question.
Rym: if you get into these specific Questions instead of the general questions would I ever date or even associate with someone who actually believed in astrology?
Rym: No, hell no, I wouldn't even respect you exactly.
Rym: astrology is BS if you believe in it.
Rym: I hate you.
Scott: We're gonna get nasty lettuce and astrology listeners anyway.
Rym: things of the day This.
Rym: I'd really like to talk about this as a whole show.
Scott: It's almost I love The whole shows isn't it?
Rym: But I'll just briefly in case anyone missed this on slashdot I want to direct your attention to the Cuban memory stick underground.
Rym: very simply the idea here.
Rym: Is that Cuba kind of repressed?
Rym: difficult to get information Censorship abroad, you know, a lot of people try to make Cuba out to be this socialist paradise and Regardless of the reasons for Cuba being the way it is because they're largely the United States fault It remains that Cuba is not a very nice place to live and Cuba has serious problems.
Scott: Then the only the nicest thing about Cuba is the weather pretty much.
Rym: Yeah, and the health system is okay But don't pretend it's this wonderful like.
Scott: anyway He was actually a lot nicer for tourists than it is for people living there.
Scott: And the problem is tourists come there and it's kind of nice But they don't realize.
Rym: a lot of the things tourists get are like, you know, not allowed for normal citizens Yep, but anyway, so the Cuban memory stick underground refers to the fact that there is now a trade.
Rym: This is like sneaker.
Rym: net times a million in USB sticks filled with websites Information and pretty much anything they can get from the outside world.
Rym: people smuggle them in and ship them in.
Rym: they copy them and pass them around and This is utterly utterly fascinating to me.
Rym: That's so awesome.
Scott: They can't get the internet So someone copies a bunch of websites on to like flash memories takes and then they share them all.
Scott: that's so cool.
Rym: It gives me an idea.
Scott: what computers are they using?
Scott: because no one's sending them computers, right?
Rym: You can get a hold of computers.
Scott: Yeah, they got like computers with USB.
Scott: I mean, yeah, how long is it?
Scott: but the embargoes been going on?
Scott: how long how you know?
Scott: What kind of things get smuggled in?
Rym: and there are nations that are not embargo in Cuba?
Scott: No, I guess.
Rym: but yeah The thing is it's easier to get crappy old computers than it is to get internet access.
Rym: I want to is to get around the sensor.
Scott: I want to know what the gaming scene is.
Scott: the video gaming scene is liking cute.
Rym: I'll bet there's a lot of old.
Rym: Sega Genesis is down.
Scott: I bet there's something going on there and I want in on that action because it's probably people who are like Rockin a Street Fighter 2 machine somewhere in Cuba.
Rym: It's gives me an idea.
Rym: I'd kind of like to set up some sort of charitable gray market charity organization where we basically put information on memory sticks and Airdrop them in places like Afghanistan and China.
Scott: Oh, we do better with hard drives.
Scott: I think make no yes hard drives coming from the sky A little tight, you know those little parachutes at the army man, you'd buy them in like the 25 cent, you know machine They come a little bubble.
Scott: Yes, we could just tie the USB stick to that with a little parachute.
Rym: I used to put those on model rockets.
Rym: I never saw those army men again.
Scott: I used to just throw them off like out of my window or whatever and anyway I think they would be stuck in a bush and I'd get them out.
Scott: and they don't be one-time use.
Rym: now You got to wrap that thing.
Scott: Anyway, yeah, it's a pain.
Rym: What do you got?
Scott: Oh Right things a day.
Scott: So when I was a kid, I played Legos.
Scott: you play Legos.
Rym: Legos were like the best thing ever.
Rym: In fact, the only reason I'm still doing gig nights is because my mom has never shipped me all my Legos.
Scott: Anyway, so when I was a kid, I thought I was so cool in the days before the internet You know I wrote a letter to Lego because I was mostly playing with my castle Legos.
Scott: cuz I like the castles which is still the best Legos, right?
Scott: I had my Robin Hood's and I had the black Knights and they go haha.
Scott: Anyway, I went I was playing my Legos and I said, you know, what would be cool if they had like race car Legos?
Scott: And of course they didn't have race car Legos.
Scott: But I was stupid and I was a little punk kid like elementary school and I said, you know, let's be cool They'd army man Legos, which they did not have and they still do not have army man Legos.
Rym: that kind of makes sense.
Rym: Yeah, because they don't like the violence and such right unless the violence is directed at pirates or spacemen.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So I wrote a letter to Lego and I was like you should make race car Legos and army man Legos.
Scott: And they just sent me back and they were like, thanks for your ideas But we can't use your ideas blah.
Scott: and that was like.
Scott: as a punk kid I was like, yeah, fuck you and There still are no army man Legos and there always were race car Legos.
Scott: like one of the first Lego I was dumb plus.
Rym: I mean no violence in Legos I'm sure all of you out there whenever you needed to deal with dissidents you made the gallows out of that whip.
Scott: Yeah, I know right.
Scott: Anyway, this is a website.
Scott: brick arms calm and you know what they sell Illegal arms for Lego man.
Scott: pretty much it is like the black market of Lego pieces.
Scott: They got like you can make terrorists.
Scott: They got like every all different kinds of guns like.
Scott: they got mp5s.
Scott: They got TMPs.
Scott: They got p90s.
Scott: They got FAMAS.
Scott: They got you know sniper rifles.
Scott: They got grenades.
Scott: They got like bunches of grenades that you can like bunch up on the front of a Lego guy.
Scott: They got like scary German Nazi soldiers with dogs.
Rym: Do they have bandoliers?
Scott: I don't know if they have bit those guys with band.
Scott: Yeah, they have.
Scott: the guys have bandoliers like painted on their body.
Rym: I want like a bandolier much like that arrow sheet that I can put on a Lego man.
Scott: But if you're looking for like some military Lego action brick arms calm as like the full loadout.
Scott: Let me let me read some of these to you brick arms bandit.
Scott: He looks like a terrorist Colonel marine.
Scott: Oh, it's some girl who's like a marine spy bio.
Scott: James Bond.
Scott: World War two.
Scott: German SS.
Scott: major World War two.
Scott: German colonel.
Scott: World War two.
Scott: German soldier panzer green.
Scott: There's a lot of Legos going on here and if you like the militaries This is a. this is where your Legos are at and you could buy it up.
Scott: And I think they have a deal like where every time you buy something you get a free gun.
Scott: It would hurt RPGs not bad Do they shoot know that of course just plastic RPGs that a Lego guy can hold in his hand and they come in dark blue gray medium gray silver metallic and I see some gold in there but Metallic not bad.
Scott: Yeah, but there's also I think that might be some miss painted ones that look gold.
Scott: Who knows?
Rym: So anyway, this won't be super long because a lot of the topics I have to bring up in this series are very very detailed.
Rym: For Scott to relax I kind of just want to give a basic overview.
Rym: But as we said last week Scott and I are going to for a while now alternate between talking about our respective majors computer science and information technology and Scott spent much of last week Describing well last Monday at least talking about what computer science and programming and all those things really were.
Rym: so to dispel the myths The legends and everything that you thought you knew about information technology.
Rym: Here we go because you see IT is Actually a super new degree a super new program.
Rym: IT did not exist as it does today in this world until very recently.
Rym: in fact the first Information technology program at a real university with a bachelor's that was accredited was formed in 1991 by of all places the Rochester Institute of Technology my alma mater.
Rym: It turns out you know I think I've mentioned this before that I actually studied IT at the first and foremost IT school in the world.
Scott: I studied CS at the first and foremost IT school in the world.
Rym: ha but actually up there that for computer science RIT was in the first I think five Universities to have a computer science bachelor's something like that back in the 70s something like that.
Rym: So yeah, RIT is I mean, it's not super known outside of its circles.
Rym: But if you're a young punk kid and you're thinking about information technology And you got a lot of money you pretty much or you can get a scholarship.
Rym: if you're a national marriage scholar you realize They'll give you a full ride.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: But anyway RIT is the IT school.
Rym: IT began there and IT is on the bleeding edge there.
Rym: So what is Information technology?
Rym: because it's actually kind of complicated and since it's a new degree How we've had computers and we've had IT relatively new for a long time.
Rym: So how come there were no what?
Rym: where were people getting these jobs?
Rym: How are people doing these jobs?
Scott: If there were no idea learning on the job, they were learning at home.
Rym: well the answer is that the majority of computer workers pretty much from the beginning of computing until Now and even now it's really hasn't changed much yet We're untrained people who learned as they went had no actual formal training in computers or IT or anything like that.
Rym: And that is the cause behind the majority of the kind of clusterfucks of computing that exists today.
Rym: You see when computers were they first existed there wasn't that much to know about computers.
Rym: so computer science kind of encompassed everything that computers were.
Rym: and then as time went on Computers got too complicated.
Rym: I mean Computers as a physical thing became so complex that you could devote your entire bachelor's or even master's study to just how computers worked physically how they were put together electronics and that is computer engineering.
Rym: and Then there were people.
Rym: and so that kind of split off.
Rym: and then you had computer science, which is everything else.
Rym: but as time went on I'm gonna skip over a lot of this.
Rym: but bit by bit every sort of Major every sort of discipline everything that could be split off has been bit by bit being split off from computer science Computer science itself split off.
Rym: computer science is now effectively the art of programming But even that is split into computer science and software engineering and all these kind of specialties are brancing out from the core.
Rym: And it's come to the point that Information technology is the glue that connects everything together.
Rym: IT is in one hand the catch-all for anything and everything related to computers that does not have its own specialist discipline.
Rym: and more importantly Information technology is the degree the program the idea the study the field of practice that Kind of has the overview that knows enough about every single discipline to be able to manage computer environments.
Rym: I mean say you've got a company and you want to write some software you want to do something cool All right, you got to hire some CS guys to actually write your software Maybe some software engineering guys to kind of manage the software projects, but what about your infrastructure?
Rym: You don't want the same people writing your code Managing your routers, I mean most people actually a lot of companies.
Scott: That's exactly what happens.
Rym: and that is not.
Scott: They can only hire one or two computer guys and they need both.
Scott: so they get someone who has more than one skill set.
Rym: Yes, the problem is that usually does not work very well except in very very small environment.
Scott: Well, even if it works Well the person, you know that usually means that the person who is doing.
Rym: all that work is overworked and a lot of companies even have a lot of Misunderstandings as to what information technology is.
Rym: a lot of big companies.
Rym: Look at it as almost a buzzword.
Rym: Yep, we leverage RIT synergy to utilize our efficiency and that sort of bullshit.
Rym: or even worse A lot of companies seem to think that you know, they have problems in their company and it's easy to say Oh those problems can be solved by technology, which is usually true.
Rym: Let's just get an IT department and everything will go away.
Rym: and that doesn't work at all.
Rym: because IT Basically all IT does in a company in any sort of real working environment is Make sure that all of the technology that is being used by a company or by an organization is used Effectively and as to the fullness that it can be used.
Rym: that is in a nutshell all that IT is all to IT exists.
Rym: to do is make sure that you're using the technology you have as Best you can and also to recommend new technology and then once that is implemented to use it effectively.
Rym: That seems really simple Doesn't doesn't that seem simple?
Scott: No, actually, I know it's not simple because Unless your company is one dude with one computer.
Scott: It's gonna be there's a lot of crazy stuff going on.
Rym: Well, see this is where the problem is.
Rym: Most of the workforce in the world today in the information technology industry do not have information technology degrees.
Rym: people like me are the vast vast minority in the workforce and As a result, we have a lot of these sort of IT Organizations that aren't really doing what IT should be doing a lot of times.
Rym: They'll call it the IT department but then the IT department is full of people writing code and full of people writing the software that runs the business or full of people just doing all the sort of Computer geeky stuff that the CFO and the CEO don't really understand.
Rym: They lump it over into the IT department and Really?
Rym: You've kind of got to have a an idea of what IT is and then you've got to actually organize your your stuff.
Rym: I mean, I'm trying to not get into the details here.
Rym: That's why it might sound like I'm dancing around a lot of issues.
Rym: That's because I'm very purposely dancing around a lot of dance dance for me.
Rym: But you've got to understand that IT is not a revenue generating center.
Rym: Computer science in a company should be a revenue generating center.
Scott: It could be.
Scott: it
Rym: should be
Scott: unless you're selling the software if you're just using the software for yourself Maybe not
Rym: but even then if you're writing software for yourself Most likely you would have been better served by having an IT department that seeks out pre-existing solutions and then implements them for you
Scott: unless there is no pre-existing solution and
Rym: in which case then you would probably have an IT department that would hire people in a small CS development environment to write that software.
Rym: But technically the IT department would manage it.
Rym: The IT department would put in the feature requests the bug fixes all that and the CS department should primarily be implementation May be headed up by a software engineer who manages all of that and provides the interface for the IT department.
Rym: but there's a lot of companies that end up having this sort of cross relationship where IT people talk directly to CS people who then go over the software engineer's head and all these interconnections kind of really make things difficult to manage.
Rym: and Thus I'm going to get into what IT is directly because here are all the things that IT is.
Rym: IT is Network monitoring.
Rym: IT is managing the development of the software that you use But not the software that makes your business go necessarily or that you were selling.
Rym: IT is security all security computer security software security network security.
Rym: IT is technology workflow management.
Rym: You know, I said you don't want all these connections people talking to people especially once you get into a larger organization.
Rym: what IT does is it sets up the workflows and Manages the workflows using technology so that like say you have people who write software for your company Right, and then you have people who use that software and then you have people who manage both sides of those people.
Rym: the IT person's job is to set up technology like wiki's or knowledge bases or ticketing systems or workflow systems or Like purchase asset management change tracking systems to kind of control all of these workflows and track all of these workflows So that everyone can get their job done and people aren't forced to do work that could be done better by someone else.
Rym: Like I'm a CS guy and I'm writing my code I shouldn't need to prioritize Which bug fixes are important in which bug fixes aren't.
Rym: that's the software engineer's job.
Rym: The software engineer shouldn't have to guess at what's important and what's not important to the business the IT department and through them all the other departments of the company.
Rym: there should be some sort of process for managing that and As you can see.
Rym: I could go on and on.
Rym: IT is everything.
Rym: IT is both the simplest and the most complex part of an organization.
Rym: IT is the most misunderstood part of any organization and Almost no one in the world is trained in what IT actually is.
Rym: so you can see where there might be problems Maybe maybe.
Rym: so what I want to do in you know My coming shows is I'm gonna break IT up into as tiny chunks as I can and talk about them in as much detail As I think you can handle.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights' at Frontrowcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.