Rym: It's Monday April 21st.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We talk a bit about the fears and misconceptions surrounding RFID and privacy.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: I know we've been saying this sort of thing a lot lately But I got to say once again welcome to all the new listeners.
Scott: Hopefully there are some.
Rym: I can already see a couple.
Rym: someone was in the forum.
Rym: We got some emails and someone already sent me a picture They'd taken.
Rym: but Yeah, for those of you who are at the event at Kinokuniya by Bryant Park on Sunday We were there with a TM revolution.
Rym: We did something fun.
Rym: But we're actually not going to talk about that until Wednesday because GeekNights is actually four nights a week and you know Mondays are science and tech and Tuesdays are gaming and Wednesdays are the anime manga comic show that you're interested in.
Scott: yep, so today.
Scott: We're just gonna talk about computers and shit You're probably not interested in.
Rym: yeah, but if you're a geek you might have some overlap.
Rym: I know a lot of people in that line waiting to see TMR.
Rym: I saw some DS's Action in there.
Scott: It still shocks and amazes me like like how many people are like geeks like they are geeky peoples.
Scott: They're in the same culture as us yet.
Scott: They do not have the technology knowledges.
Scott: It's like I feel well because well hand in hand, but I would they.
Rym: why would someone be an anime geek and be a computer?
Rym: I am yeah, but that doesn't mean everyone else is.
Scott: I know it's like it goes one.
Scott: It feels like it's one direction, but not the other.
Scott: like if someone's a computer geek They probably seen and enjoyed some animes.
Rym: how many people on slash job complain about how much they hate anime all the time?
Rym: There's a lot of them.
Scott: I know, but it's it.
Scott: They've seen it.
Scott: They know of it.
Rym: You know yeah, they know about it.
Rym: They don't like it.
Rym: They don't care about it.
Rym: They know that it exists, and that's it.
Rym: much like someone might know that computer technology exists But they don't care.
Scott: they gotta.
Scott: you gotta cross it over people.
Scott: you can't be just like doing one part not the other.
Scott: Okay, yeah.
Rym: Anyway before this event.
Rym: This is somewhat more relevant to Monday We were hanging out in Brian Park since we Despite being press at the New York Comic Con we avoided most of our Presley duties because there wasn't that much of interest to cover And the only people I wanted interviews with declined interviews with anyone.
Rym: So that was the end of that.
Rym: But we left and we're waiting by Brian Park before our call up to go.
Rym: do the TMR thing.
Rym: in Kinokuniya We see some punk kids who were obviously Anonymous.
Scott: yeah, it was pretty much like oh, hey There's anonymous people who happen to be here like.
Scott: I recognize some of them from pictures on the internet like I've seen you before.
Rym: Also, they had a little sign that pretty much said we're anonymous and they had their cards.
Rym: and who else?
Scott: where else would you see?
Scott: Multiple v-masks a laughing man hat and other such things all on Young punk kids together in a group in the city, so I'm still dressed like press and I'm ready for this TMR event.
Rym: So as a result, I'm dressed up really nice, and I look like a businessman.
Rym: I got my little thing and I walk over and like excuse me and they all shut up and they stared me with this dubious look of what's this guy want a Scientologist oh, man, and I was like I'm a member of the press.
Rym: and then there's this double look of oh oh oh oh It's like.
Rym: and then I stopped and I realized they're all kind of afraid like wait right now I'm cool with you guys, and then they get they raise the eyebrow like no seriously.
Rym: I just I want to talk a little bit.
Rym: Hey, they're like hey, and then we start talking and I can say one thing they were pretty much anime manga Geeky people like everyone else like that seemed to be their primary thing.
Scott: no shit You really you think so?
Scott: 4chan people's.
Rym: well the fun like in the anime gasp the funniest thing was so Alright, and they're telling me.
Rym: I'm like.
Rym: so what's going on?
Rym: you guys doing one of your anonymous protests Is there a special occasion?
Rym: it turned out that they said that weekend was like Dianetics push weekend And they were gonna be there kind of pointing out to people that Dianetics is just Scientology and everything that means.
Rym: alright Which you know.
Rym: I'm cool with that.
Rym: Yeah, but then they're like hey Why don't you come cover it?
Rym: and I was like well?
Rym: I'd love to but actually in about an hour TM revolution and a hair squeak from this little crowd of people but I keep talking is gonna be in the Kinokuniya, and we're gonna be interviewing them for Japanese radio and The squeak happens again, and there's this one girl who bore a remarkable resemblance to knives.
Rym: chow Basically said that's trouble.
Rym: Oh, no.
Rym: I'm like the biggest TMR fan ever I can't.
Rym: He's really gonna be there, and I was like yeah.
Rym: He's gonna be there.
Rym: He's really gonna be the.
Rym: yeah He's really gonna be there.
Rym: and she was obviously torn 50/50 between continuing in her anonymous duties and Going to squeak at TMR.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: There are plenty of people squeaking.
Rym: It was quite an event that I've never seen that many people in such a small space before.
Scott: all I have to say about it Now I mean I'm probably gonna say this every time we talk about this that guy is really small But at the same time there's so much energy.
Rym: It's like the per pound energy in.
Rym: that guy is probably the most energy any human has ever had.
Scott: I'm not saying anything.
Rym: It's good or bad, or I'm just saying he is a small Dude, I'm just saying that it's so like the smile never wore off.
Rym: that guy is like concentrated like let's go.
Rym: Let's go Let's go.
Rym: But we'll talk about that more on Wednesday because we we got some interesting answers out of him to some of the questions.
Rym: Yeah, the least yeah, it was a lot unlike what I expected.
Rym: You know usually when you interview Japanese celebrities It's like well.
Rym: What is your inspiration?
Rym: Oh generic answer about my inspiration?
Rym: What do you think about your fans?
Scott: Serious and flat answer that I've been told to say.
Rym: and when he said Something about if I had known that I would have my own Gundam when I was a kid I probably would have peed myself.
Rym: Yeah, it was.
Rym: it was pretty fun.
Rym: Yeah, but I don't know how the anonymous protests went out.
Rym: I didn't see any mass media coverage, so I don't know.
Scott: it wasn't a big anonymous protest obviously but really what they should just do is they just hold hands and make a little wall around the Stress testing booth, that's all they should do.
Scott: that might be illegal is it?
Rym: But what I will say I have a little bit of advice for anonymous But let people through if they ask because you know no you can't really do it that way.
Rym: Yeah, but you know we talked and they actually wanted GeekNights fliers.
Rym: I gave him a whole handful of them, and they seem pretty cool.
Rym: But I know a lot of you were probably listening now anonymous, and I have.
Rym: I have a little bit of advice.
Rym: I Look at the way for those of you who were there that I was dressed and you guys I mean the the whole anonymous V laughing man thing works in his cool, but if you dressed like me And you were standing there looking very professional as opposed to
Scott: Look at the Scientologists right they're wearing like really nice pants and tucked in like button-down shirts like all the girls are wearing like dresses and whatnot.
Scott: and So when someone goes up to them they you know they are crazy And you're not but you look crazy, and they don't.
Scott: so someone who knows nothing about this whole situation Are they gonna trust the crazy punk kid?
Scott: or they get it.
Scott: it's like the socialists at all in college.
Scott: They would always protest like you know out by the library.
Rym: is there were always three of them?
Rym: They're always like shirtless with dreadlocks yelling and screaming They smell bad that you know.
Scott: and they they had like you know hemp hats and whatever.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know, but it's like even if what they're saying is true or has merit they basically discredit themselves by acting hobos, so if you guys anonymous guys You know you have that little logo of like that little you know tuxedo that has no hands or a head or feet You should go where like you know your best Sunday clothes or whatever.
Scott: and you know act very serious and Polite and businesslike and friendly and then people will take you way more Seriously, and you'll be much more effective.
Rym: because I will say watching that as the group grew And they're all these anonymous kids kind of hanging out in Brian Park getting ready to do their thing They were acting pretty much identically to the crowd at any anime convention.
Rym: Yeah, pretty anywhere It was I could have been in anime convention.
Scott: They were having fun.
Scott: They're having fun, but yeah, and they were probably somewhat effective But they could be.
Scott: they could have fun and then also be more effective at the same time Seriously rock the blazer, and you'll get a lot more people.
Rym: yeah ties work - ties do work not bow ties though.
Rym: No bow ties the mark of a crazy man.
Scott: Yeah, it's quite crazy.
Scott: All right, you want to hit news all right?
Rym: Scott will groan and moan about this, but I think this is grown so Zombie.
Rym: I have to say very much that tomorrow is the Pennsylvania primary Democrats in America.
Rym: this is critical.
Rym: I cannot stress to you how much I support Barack Obama.
Rym: It's not critical.
Scott: He's already mathematically won.
Scott: It doesn't matter.
Rym: No, he hasn't because the super delegates could just vote for Hillary, but then the primary doesn't matter.
Rym: yes the primary doesn't matter.
Scott: So why was this critical part?
Rym: No, no the whole primaries as a whole.
Rym: the problem is if he wins this then pretty much the super delegates would have to stab Themselves it politically in order to actually vote.
Scott: if you're a super delegate You're not also a pot like they're we.
Scott: no one knows who those people are.
Rym: you mean most of them are high-ranking Democrats.
Rym: You can go look at the list of all of them.
Rym: a lot of them are people who are well-known.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean no one's gonna be like oh, you're a super delegate, and you voted for Hillary, but now I'm not voting for you.
Rym: well actually that will happen but more beyond that.
Rym: the problem Is that it's as a group if as a group they vote for a candidate that otherwise in terms of the media perspective lost the primary.
Rym: Then a lot of people who voted in the primaries to suddenly feel betrayed, it's kind of like the Democratic Party falling.
Scott: Yes, I don't think the super delegates themselves will take a hit.
Scott: I think the Democratic Party will lose a lot of credibility.
Rym: Individual super delegates will also take big hits.
Rym: Maybe that's happened in the past.
Scott: maybe if the media brings enough attention to specific ones then yes You realize that it's also within the party that.
Rym: and what are you?
Rym: you don't even know anything about politics.
Scott: I know plenty.
Rym: Yeah, anyway if you live in Pennsylvania I encourage you to vote and you're a Democrat, and you had.
Rym: you didn't miss the deadline to be a Democrat temporarily.
Rym: I highly recommend you vote for Barack Obama.
Rym: but that aside The debate that happened right ABC had a big debate and they'd so many debates that they had already 11.
Scott: I think yeah, that's a lot.
Rym: yeah, I've watched most of them on YouTube yeah, but anyway I didn't watch the most recent one, but ABC because they staged the debate set down some guidelines Because the debate happened on the East Coast and live, but they had obligations to their West Coast affiliates.
Rym: So what they said?
Rym: this I'm gonna quote the New York Times here quote ABC's guidelines said that news organizations could select one 30-second sound bite to use on television radio or the web Between 11 p.m.. Wednesday and 5 a.m.. Thursday mm-hmm.
Rym: So they basically said you can't show the debate you can't show any big clips from it You can't really do anything with it until we've been able to show it on the West Coast.
Rym: Uh-huh luckily now.
Rym: I have a lot to say about that.
Rym: I mean yeah.
Rym: Why don't they show at the same time on both coasts because then it it's at a time when no one's gonna watch it on The West Coast.
Scott: have shit for living on the West Coast.
Scott: you'll there'll be a West Coast debate later And you'll see that one, and we'll see.
Scott: well Late to watch there won't be any more West Coast debates.
Scott: well there were.
Rym: Those didn't matter.
Rym: well you had your chance and actually the debates were mostly out here.
Rym: Anyway that they deal is that one.
Rym: this smacks of media not understanding the world in that It's a global medium now.
Rym: I can get information from anywhere in the world at the same time.
Rym: so It'd be like if there was a hockey game in New York and there were fans of that hockey game in, Arizona.
Rym: So they weren't allowed to broadcast the hockey game live.
Rym: Instead they filmed the hockey game and wouldn't let anyone talk about their results Until it was prime time later, and then they showed it.
Rym: Yeah, or they showed it on the East Coast But no one was allowed to talk about.
Scott: of course people on the Internet people who are at the event live just go on the Internet and say what happened.
Rym: yeah, but they can't show clips from it.
Rym: They can't show highlights.
Rym: They can't show a long like.
Rym: well This is what Barack said blah blah blah blah, but it turns out that pretty much every news organization other than ABC Completely ignored this rule and showed very long Segments from the debate basically told ABC to piss off and cited fair use.
Scott: yeah I say fair use.
Rym: I'm so happy about that.
Rym: the way this has been handled.
Scott: Yeah, I mean the timezone thing is gonna be an issue nowadays.
Scott: You know the information travels so quickly.
Scott: You know is you're gonna have events happening at times that are inconvenient for you.
Scott: I mean just look there were a bunch of basketball and hockey games over the weekend right some of which I watched.
Scott: But like there was some West Coast basketball games.
Scott: They were late at night for me, and I didn't watch him.
Scott: You know I just went to bed.
Rym: Oh, I guess I only paid attention to the debates that were near me because they're actually 21. the rest of those must have been Out on the West Coast or something.
Scott: yeah, when they would have been late at night for you.
Scott: And at the same way when some you know some things will be.
Scott: you know while West Coast people are still at work But they're prime time for us, and that's just.
Scott: it's gonna be in the end.
Scott: You know New York is on this side of country and LA is on that side of the country.
Scott: It's gonna even out.
Scott: people just have to deal with it.
Scott: time shift get your TiVo's get your internets and everything will be cool.
Scott: Whatever the thing
Rym: is part of the problem is that like these West Coast affiliates or whoever it is who isn't in the prime time zone Have a problem in that There's no point in them showing the debate because when it happens no one will watch it and no one's gonna watch it after the Fact because I
Scott: don't show it just talk about it on the evening news,
Rym: but then they lose a lot of the ad revenue They could have gotten by show it like having the right.
Scott: But then there'll be another event that happens on the West Coast of the East Coast affiliate won't get.
Rym: yeah That's.
Rym: the problem is that in the global world people are trying to have it both ways where these West Coast affiliates want the benefits The global media and the fact that they can cover everything in the world.
Rym: But they also don't want to have to compete with the media all around the world.
Rym: Well,
Scott: I think the real problem is that we still have you know these this idea of the local affiliate And I mean that was the reason that there are local affiliates is from a time where you needed an antenna to broadcast television into a local area and Now really the only reason you need a local affiliate is to make the local news everything
Rym: else.
Rym: Yeah, that's the primary reason why we still have local affiliates.
Scott: Yeah They should really just have Like places around the country that make the local news and then everything else is just nationally controlled And they just say okay put all the local news is on at the right time.
Scott: Because why do we need these?
Scott: you know local affiliate that actually programs a whole thing?
Scott: It's really just a waste.
Scott: I mean, that's why cable TV has been rocking so much because cable TV is just same thing in the whole country.
Scott: It's interesting thing in the whole world.
Rym: It's interesting because all the cable debates We're pretty much broadcast live across all time zones and no one cares.
Scott: Yeah I mean tell you the Fox News the CNN news is all those channel.
Scott: the cable news channels are kicking the ass of the local Newses.
Scott: all right, so yeah, it shows you
Rym: but it was just I find that really interesting that it seems like ABC and actually multiple of the news stories that I read about this pointed out that ABC in all of their coverage and all of the ways they dealt with this tried to treat it like it was a TV show Like a television event as opposed to news.
Rym: Yeah, and then all the cable networks treated these as news as a real-world thing.
Rym: that matters at ABC like even though in The end they were all just trying to make money.
Rym: ABC.
Rym: it was like if ABC was like yeah, we're trying to make money and everyone else was like yeah We're trying to cover the news and make money and as a result ABC just looks really really bad.
Scott: No, ABC is Disney whatever.
Scott: They're all bad.
Scott: I Don't think any of them are good, okay, which one's good?
Rym: Anyway, what do you got in the news?
Rym: since you obviously don't care about this at all?
Scott: no not really all right.
Rym: So I still don't get how you cannot be so activist about everything yet not care about politics on any level local national state anything cuz like That.
Scott: better things to do.
Scott: the point of politics is in the perfect political world right?
Scott: imagine if all politics is perfect.
Scott: every Representative was was perfectly in line with what I wanted right.
Scott: the goal the goal The perfect world would be.
Scott: I just mind my own business and everything's great.
Scott: And I realize hey I can just pretend mind my own business and pretend everything's great, and it'll be just like that.
Scott: I just have to ignore all the bullshit, and it's like the bullshit uses in there uh-huh, and it's much better that way.
Rym: Okay, I can't I couldn't disagree with you enough, but anyway go on.
Scott: if I just turned off the news I would think the world was perfect, so I turn off the news, and I think the world is perfect.
Rym: all right You're willing to go with the whole ignorance is bliss thing then go nuts.
Scott: it works pretty well.
Scott: Yeah, anyway anyway, so Speaking of some bullshits.
Scott: right we've been complaining about patents for 10 years 20 years 100 years I don't know.
Scott: Patents are sucking especially the software patents.
Scott: You know every day There's another story some company that doesn't actually make anything has a patent on some bullshit That shouldn't have been patentable in the first place.
Scott: Then some other company that actually makes something like I don't know Rym the blackberry company not Rym the person over there or You know someone else has to pay a bajillion dollars or SEO.
Scott: How long did that thing go on?
Scott: remember rambas?
Scott: Yeah, rambas all right.
Scott: It's just a bunch of bullshit, right?
Scott: well the head of the US patent office John Dudas the same guy apparently who was recently Trying to promote like an educate a patent educational curriculum for children.
Scott: those things are always great, right.
Scott: That was telling children that every inventor needs a patent.
Scott: that yet, which is not true.
Scott: This guy recently said that Yeah, the patent office is getting a bunch of really really shitty patents, and they're getting shittier by the day.
Scott: That's a paraphrase, but he's basically saying the quality of patent applications is decreasing.
Scott: huh He's just realizing this now.
Rym: Well, I think the reason that patents are getting the way they are is that the reward for like.
Rym: the reward for me.
Rym: Oh, it's obvious why no, but the specific reward for making a broad patent is very very high.
Rym: But the cost of making that patent is very very low.
Rym: so all you have to do is Think about or look at what anyone else in any competitive arena is doing.
Rym: and then?
Rym: Try to patent as many things as you can because you don't need to prove that something works to patent it.
Rym: patent everything related To all the technology in the realm you compete and then just hope that something one of your competitors does in some vague way Overlaps that patent and then sue them for licensing fees.
Scott: yeah And it's in.
Scott: judges have been constantly deciding on the side of patent holders Which you know really?
Scott: you know it used to be you didn't patent something so you actually had it.
Scott: like you know Alexander Graham Bell He had a working phone, and then he ran to the patent office.
Scott: You know Thomas Edison had a working light bulb And then he beat the other guy up on his way to the patent office, and he ended his in first.
Scott: You know you they don't go.
Scott: aha I have you know I've thought maybe we could have a light bulb and then patent it.
Scott: that wasn't how it was done.
Scott: and now Suddenly nowadays people are patenting things.
Scott: I just thought of like yeah, I'm patenting the idea of a light bulb.
Scott: I Don't even know how it's gonna work yet, but the real can't?
Scott: anyone makes the one.
Scott: I get the money.
Rym: There's no simple solution.
Rym: I mean some people have said oh, we'll make the fee to apply for a patent hire But then that just prevents anyone who isn't a major corporation from ever getting a pen.
Scott: Well, I actually think patent applications should be free like it shouldn't cost anything to apply But you should actually you should have to submit the working Invent.
Rym: you know what I was about to say if you hadn't interrupted me was that Forcing someone to present the working invention is equally bad because a lot of times you can design something that will work.
Rym: you can engineer Something and that's most of the effort, but the cost to actually build the thing you have engineered is Extremely prohibitive.
Rym: so someone who's very intelligent who makes something good like a chip There's no way if I designed a chip that I could get someone to fabricate it Quickly and probably in a way that I could afford.
Scott: Hmm that is a tough situation there.
Scott: I think maybe you just had to either if you could prove that the cost of developing the Invention you know producing one was too high.
Rym: How do you prove that proving that would cost a lot of money?
Scott: No, if you could you would have to somehow prove that it was possible that it would actually work.
Scott: how though?
Scott: well If you can't prove that it works, then you know what.
Scott: how difficult was it to come up with it?
Rym: How can you?
Rym: but what do you mean?
Rym: How do you prove that engineering design works without building it?
Rym: With math that doesn't prove anything actually?
Scott: Uh-huh not really well then what is?
Scott: how good is your invention if we can't even prove that?
Scott: was it?
Scott: Why should we give you a patent?
Scott: We can't even prove this thing you came up with actually works.
Scott: What's it worth?
Rym: Okay, so what do you propose?
Scott: I do exactly what I just said.
Rym: I just think it's a terrible idea.
Scott: What's your great idea?
Scott: genius.
Rym: there is no great idea?
Rym: That's what I was saying.
Rym: We need a more fundamental reform than simply changing the patent application process.
Rym: I think we need a clearer definition of The exact social and economic purpose that patents are intended to enact and then from there Go on to come up with policies that enact that idea as best as we can.
Rym: I think opposed to trying to reform kind of the interface with the system.
Scott: I think another problem that's been happening more recently.
Scott: Is that it's a very it's tough to tell like where invention stops and where Innovation the Microsoft Word begins.
Scott: like if if you know if I invent an improvement to something that already exists like, you know Is that really a new invention?
Scott: Well, how obvious was it?
Scott: What if it was a little bit obvious?
Scott: What if it was really, you know?
Scott: Is this sliding scale and we have to sort of figure out?
Scott: where do we draw the line as to okay your?
Scott: Contribution was significant enough to where you deserve some sort of rights to money or or you know, monopoly or something.
Scott: Your contribution was not significant.
Scott: You don't get anything.
Rym: Well, frankly, I think the best way to go about it would be to reform the system So that the limited monopoly is reduced sharply to a very small span.
Rym: Like maybe you apply for a patent and you don't have to submit a working model but the patent guy takes effect and starts working when you produce the thing and then from that point and obviously a time delay whereby if you don't get it produced between when you submit the patent and This arbitrary deadline say
Scott: I'll see that.
Scott: Yeah, those are those it first.
Scott: Yeah, that's a good one.
Scott: If you don't if you don't make it then you lose the patent.
Rym: Well, if you let me finish there's a lot more to it than that.
Rym: So first you submit the patent and then if the patent is accepted then from that point You have an arbitrary span of say up to a year to get someone to produce whatever it is.
Rym: And if you do then from the time it is produced you have a temporary monopoly of say another short term like two years Maybe at most.
Rym: but going along with this we add much stronger protections on trademarks of branding and that sort of thing so that you get the actual monopoly for a short term.
Rym: you get the buffer time to prove that it was viable.
Rym: because if it was viable you patent it.
Rym: Someone will decide that it's worth investing in.
Rym: if no one decides it's worth investing in then Obviously your patent was either ahead of its time or in other ways wouldn't work.
Rym: and then obviously the patent expires Maybe with a clause that it can be reapplied for again in the future.
Rym: doesn't some sort of delay?
Rym: So, alright so now after you build it you that company that built it and you get a temporary monopoly of a couple of years to milk It for money and to establish your brand.
Rym: but then after that short monopoly the monopolies gone.
Rym: anyone else can compete.
Rym: but you still have the soft monopoly that you were there.
Rym: first you have the branding and It'll kind of it caused this long trail off of your monopoly instead of the hard long term.
Scott: I think I think that's a good idea for consumer type products.
Scott: But actually I see a problem in that There are things in this world which take a very long time to make.
Scott: if I patent some sort of new Like, you know equivalent of you know, the Hadron Collider It's gonna take a lot like ten years to build it.
Scott: if we do build it, right?
Rym: Like that should really be patented.
Scott: maybe maybe but you know There are some things which take an incredibly long time to actually make.
Scott: or you know Maybe we make one.
Rym: you want me to go into more detail.
Rym: I think not so simple as just it came off the production line But you set up a stipulation whereby the infrastructure is being built to put it in place.
Scott: I think what you need to do actually is the pat.
Scott: I think you need to actually give the patent examiners more, you know leeway you don't set.
Scott: you know this long It's.
Scott: they look at the patent and they say this should take, you know, no more than X years.
Rym: I hate to say it but I think that's an almost ludicrous idea because that implies that you have to have the patent examiners be experts in every possible field.
Scott: Well, there are.
Scott: they have a zillion patent examiners and they're each.
Scott: they have whatever you're submitting a patent for They should have at least one expert in that field, but that's prohibitively expensive.
Scott: That's what.
Scott: that's how that?
Rym: I don't think that's a good idea.
Rym: I think that the patent office should be fairly liberal with this kind of system in awarding patents because a patent that is to blur Fluous will either be ignored by investors or will not be enacted.
Rym: But
Scott: I don't think if there's a pet if they're no matter what the system is if you have some sort of Patenting if the person who approves or denies the patent isn't incredibly knowledgeable in the topic at hand I don't think they're qualified to make a judgment as a yes
Rym: or no about the way My system was put in the way it is set up.
Rym: Even if a bad patent gets in it's a very short span and With the trademark protection and all that it I think it would work out really well.
Scott: I also think that you know some like if the patent office doesn't have someone who's an expert right there should be some sort You know like they already have sort of a system where you know citizens can go and look at patents and make comments on them.
Scott: I really think that should be expanded like huh?
Scott: I'm not a hundred percent sure on this.
Scott: I'm going to mail it to an incredibly smart college professor who's an expert in this area And then he will mail it back.
Rym: a big problem with that is once you give people that sort of Scientific or knowledge based control over the system you have those people are often engaged in the industry anyway.
Scott: That's why you don't do just one person.
Scott: you do like a. you know a bunch of Review action.
Rym: all of those people are engaged in the industry and unlike the side the hard sciences when you're getting into consumer technology Finding even a quorum of people who are not biased is pretty much impossible.
Scott: It's very difficult.
Rym: I think the easiest way to fix it for the least amount of reform and effort and problems is simply to have the very short Monopoly coupled with the buffer period before going building a proof of concept.
Scott: I don't think if nothing else we agree that the time and the amount of monopoly the patents give you has to be much shorter Especially considering the speed at which you know technology is advancing compared to say you know the the early 1900s.
Rym: well honestly I'm also of the mind more and more that Only physical things should be able to be patented.
Rym: absolutely not just not just like oh software patents are bad.
Rym: But I don't think you should even be able to patent a business process or a business plan.
Rym: I know only Physical engineered objects.
Scott: yes absolutely.
Scott: if something is an idea I mean all software is a number.
Scott: so saying you can patent that no good.
Scott: now see here's the end.
Scott: You should also not be able to.
Scott: it should only be man-made objects.
Scott: I don't like this patenting jeans stuff, right, but what if I made the gene?
Rym: if you chemically that which is that's how we do.
Scott: We make you chemically engineer something in a chemical plant right you make it then that's a man-made chemical.
Scott: But if you just take it out of my arm and look at it in a microscope you didn't make it.
Scott: So it doesn't count.
Scott: yeah, that's how I say it should be.
Rym: well even then you don't patent the end result.
Rym: you patent the process.
Scott: That's fine.
Scott: as long as there's a process involving the business process the engineering process As long as you're making a physical thing like if you figure out how to make you know the same Gene that comes out of my arm right and you make it.
Scott: you can patent though the you know chemical process of how you made It.
Scott: that's fine.
Rym: plus regardless the short-term monopoly with the buffer period and all that Basically makes it so that no matter how bad.
Rym: the mistakes are in the patent office.
Rym: they get resolved relatively quickly And a cycle of two years is the longest.
Rym: well even with the buffer period alright.
Rym: So a bad patent gets through worst-case scenario three years of misery, and then everything's fine.
Rym: I'm cool with that.
Scott: Yeah, it's fun.
Rym: Anyway things of the day nothing is funnier to me than cats confronted with obstacles They cannot understand.
Scott: did you see that one a couple weeks ago?
Scott: That was like the guy had a glass door in front of you know at his front door You know we have a screen door beat a glass screen door, and he took the glass out But the dog like wouldn't go through unless he actually opened the door.
Rym: cuz think about that.
Rym: the dog knows better if he just runs At.
Scott: that thing hit something, but then the guy himself walked through the hole and the dog still didn't get it.
Rym: Well, that was just a dumb dog.
Scott: I know, but you know what I'm saying, but that's funny.
Rym: basically This is.
Rym: I don't know the exact story, but you know those.
Rym: Uh I'm gonna call this is an inside joke for those archangel dark angel cakes the ones you get it like a grocery store.
Rym: It's like a big.
Scott: you go to the grocery store, and you say hey I see that blank cake there.
Scott: write this on the right archangel dark angel.
Rym: Lend me thy ear on it.
Rym: no That's a story from the guy kind of the golden age of the front row crew something like that.
Rym: well Maybe the Silver Age.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: Definitely.
Scott: that was definitely like pre goes the ancient times.
Rym: But uh by the way just so you know those cakes in the grocery store are full of trans fat.
Scott: Don't eat those cakes don't want to get.
Rym: those aren't good cakes cuz we One of the FRC people had a birthday a few months ago, and I was like we should buy a cake.
Rym: We used to do that.
Rym: We used to always get one of those cakes.
Rym: It was like a big deal when I remember to Which what we get them all the time at RIT because ice cream cake is a good way to go.
Scott: a little carvel get The whale.
Scott: I like the whale.
Rym: I think those have trans fat - I also like the watermelon.
Rym: But anyway those things as we discovered recently are like loaded with trans fat.
Scott: Yeah I'm no fan of you know.
Scott: you know I'm not.
Scott: I'm not big on the nutrition, but trans fat.
Rym: I mean it's pretty much poison Followed closely by high fructose corn, but anyway those trans fat cakes always come with this big plastic Shell to keep them fresh even though if you take that shell off that thing is never gonna rot.
Scott: nope But so much preservatives in there.
Scott: I mean the frosting will get hard and crusty, but that's about it.
Rym: now cats love these things.
Rym: I've experienced this firsthand.
Rym: cats like a lot of things, but particularly those archangel dark angel cakes cats.
Rym: We'll just go nuts over these things.
Rym: if you leave one out, and you have a cat that cake is forfeit.
Rym: But uh if you leave the shell on it the cat can't get to the cake.
Rym: But that doesn't mean he isn't gonna try.
Rym: and that's my thing of the day.
Rym: This is hilarious because he's just like Homer when he's trying to get to that almost there almost there.
Scott: All right my thing of the day my thing of the day is going to be a a Shakespearean performance by me and Rym here Rym and I and If you don't know which actually Scott it would be by me and Rym.
Rym: Yeah, by Rym and me because you know you said two.
Scott: so it would be by Rym and myself.
Scott: Yeah, there we go.
Scott: so If you don't know which Shakespearean play we are performing.
Scott: you're a moron.
Rym: well I'll be more to the point if you don't get the joke from the very first line.
Rym: you obviously Didn't get it.
Scott: Yeah, um and Then we're gonna link you to the the script for this.
Scott: this year We're just gonna do a very small part like not even like a scene.
Scott: It's gonna be like a piece of a scene.
Rym: I uh I'll admit I laughed out loud Before I finish reading the first line because suddenly I realized what this was.
Scott: I don't screw up the lines like you did last time.
Rym: What last time?
Scott: but the first time.
Scott: okay, yeah, all right all right, so I'll begin and Knowest thou what the French name cottage pie say.
Rym: they not cottage pie in their own tongue.
Scott: But nay their tongues for speech and taste alike are strange to ours with their own history.
Scott: Gall knoweth not a cottage from a house.
Rym: What say they then?
Rym: pray hatches permentier hatches permentier.
Scott: What name thy cream cream is but cream only.
Scott: they say la creme.
Rym: What do they name black pudding?
Scott: I know not.
Scott: I visited no in.
Scott: it could be bought.
Scott: Do you want to keep going?
Rym: I think we can do the second one.
Scott: We're gonna do the second scene.
Scott: We might mess this one up though.
Scott: We didn't practice this one.
Rym: Do you want to be the awesome part or the get shot part?
Scott: I will do.
Scott: I was doing the awesome part.
Scott: I could keep doing the awesome.
Rym: Okay, you'd better do it.
Rym: Well, all right do it.
Scott: Well young My Pardon, did I break thy concentration?
Scott: Continue.
Scott: Ah, but now thy tongue is still.
Scott: allow me then to offer a response.
Scott: describe Marcellus Wallace to me.
Scott: Pray what.
Scott: what country dost thou hail from?
Scott: What.
Scott: how passing.
Scott: strange for I have traveled far and never have I heard tell of this.
Scott: what?
Scott: What language speak they in the land of what?
Scott: what the Queen's own English-based knave dost thou speak it?
Scott: I Then harken to my words and answer them.
Scott: describe to me Marcellus Wallace what?
Scott: Speak what again thou cur cry.
Scott: what again?
Scott: I dare the utter what again but once I dare thee twice and spit upon thy name.
Scott: Now paint for me a portraiture in words if thou hast any in thy head, but what of Marcellus Wallace?
Rym: He is dark.
Rym: I and what more his head is shaven bald.
Scott: Has he the semblance of a harlot?
Scott: What?
Scott: ah Has he the semblance of a harlot?
Scott: Hey, then why did thou attempts to bed him thus?
Scott: I did not I thou didst.
Scott: Oh, I thou didst thou hope to rape him like a chattel whore and south Lord Wallace is displeased to bed with anyone but she to whom he wed This?
Scott: I I don't know.
Scott: I think that's all there is.
Rym: I love this sort of thing.
Scott: I We're gonna link to it anyway to give credit where credit is due.
Rym: credit is indeed to mr.
Scott: Cerulean st.
Scott: On the live journals or perhaps Darth Paradox.
Scott: I can't tell I don't get live journal No, whatever.
Rym: All I know is that it bothers me that now it asks me if I am if I am 14 before I'm allowed to view certain live journals whatever.
Rym: So, uh, what shall we talk about?
Scott: I do want to talk about the RF IDs.
Rym: I think we should because there was a. this will be a kind of short show.
Scott: I won't be that short.
Scott: Well, I think you could go as long as you wanted to.
Rym: actually I'm kind of hungry and I am hungry.
Rym: I actually want to skip all the technology I want to.
Scott: I want to talk about you guys.
Scott: only cover the basic.
Scott: that way they understand All right.
Rym: So an RF ID is very simply a small it will.
Rym: there are common misconceptions about RF IDs.
Rym: one Is that they broadcast information about you?
Scott: They do not broadcast information about you.
Scott: what they do?
Rym: They're a little inert piece of metal and a chip Yeah and a little antenna and all they do.
Rym: it's called RF ID.
Rym: if an RF signal is present it has to be a fairly strong one because Remember RF will if there's a wire a conductor cause a small amount of current to go across it.
Rym: exactly kind of like if you take a magnet and you move it back and forth or spin it in the presence of a wire a Charge will appear on that one.
Scott: You take an extension cord need to play jump rope with it.
Scott: You can actually I get a light bulb to light up Standing if you're standing in the right orientation to the the gravitation the magnetic field of the earth.
Rym: Yes, not gravitation.
Scott: Yeah, if you had somehow linked you have to be standing what east-west or north-south?
Scott: I forget.
Rym: if you had somehow linked the gravitational forces with the electromagnetic forces You would have just achieved the holy grail of all sighs.
Rym: Better than Einstein would have solved the most fundamental problem physics has ever offered unto man.
Scott: But anyway, but anyway, so RF ID.
Rym: you basically have this Simple in the presence of an RF field a Current will go through this chip which will cause it to broadcast in a very small span through its little antenna Powered by the RF signal a small series of bits.
Scott: in other words radio goes into the chip onto across an antenna powers it at each the chip powers up and then radio comes out.
Scott: and Actually if you put more radio in you can get more radio out.
Scott: so theoretically, you know, it's the same radio.
Scott: It's not gonna change what it's broadcast It's just gonna.
Rym: it's like if I'm the brought the thing and Scott is the RF ID.
Rym: I go Hey, and Scott goes what.
Rym: and I go hey, he goes what?
Scott: Exactly the louder you yell at it the louder it yells back But it's always gonna yell back less than you yelled at it because it's a tiny little thing that's powered only by the RF.
Scott: That's why RF IDs don't have batteries in them.
Scott: They don't need batteries.
Scott: all the the the radio waves coming at it provide all the power that is needed.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: The nicest thing is about farting in an air on chair.
Scott: It goes right through.
Rym: Anyway, I'm sorry about that.
Scott: So our FID technology has been used in many places.
Scott: in many places is replace the barcode Right because now instead of having to turn something over and finding the barcode or whatever, right?
Scott: All you do is you zap an RF radio wave at it and then wherever the RF ID is, you know It's in there somewhere.
Scott: It'll broadcast back.
Scott: Hey, here's my ID number and then you say, okay and then you know what it is and you look it up in the database and you charge them the right amount of money or It's great.
Rym: Like my badge for work has an RF ID, right?
Scott: So Rym goes up to his office and the thing near his office says, you know, it's always going.
Scott: Hey RF ID.
Scott: Hey, hey and Rym waves his RF ID near it and then he's I don't even do that There's multiple of them.
Rym: Actually, there's there's turnstiles to even get to the elevator to get to my part of the building.
Rym: Oh, wow, and when I walk up the turnstile says oh, it's Rym and it opens and I walk in and it closes behind.
Scott: No, that's a more powerful one than what we got.
Rym: It's actually really cool because it's timed so perfectly that only One dude is getting through that thing and I see people try to get through it and it just hits them right in the mean Mean machine.
Scott: Oh, it's so excellent.
Rym: Yeah people get hit by that thing.
Scott: Yes, so it's it's Rym has a little RF ID that he carries to work, you know, and they have.
Scott: they have a database.
Scott: Yep, they have a database that says this number is allowed in this number is not allowed in and then Rym walks up.
Scott: the RF ID is somewhere on rims body.
Scott: He doesn't have to whip it out because it's really powerful and it says hey Hey, and then rims RF ID goes I'm Rym and their database says rims allowed into the door opens the Rym walks into the door closed and then
Rym: I go upstairs and I stand outside the door of my office and then the Door unlocks because it knows it's me now depending on the employee.
Rym: It looks up and says, oh, it's Rym He's allowed to come in 24/7.
Rym: Oh, it's so-and-so the janitor He's not allowed to come in except between these hours and these hours.
Scott: or yeah Oh, that's all in the database.
Scott: You know the RF ID just has an ID number and that's the primary Misconception.
Rym: that why so many people are afraid of RF IDs that it'd be broadcast in my business.
Rym: Oh, no, it's my business.
Scott: Now there is that.
Scott: that's not to say the RF ID is perfect.
Scott: there are problems.
Rym: I mean, we'll cover this first.
Rym: Remember the key here is that in General the way an RF ID works is that it'll be a number like a serial number like I have my number two four six Oh one and great number.
Rym: That's one of my favorite numbers Other than e to the XC anyway.
Rym: So this number doesn't tell you anything about me.
Scott: It's just my silver plate asshole.
Rym: It's just and candelabra.
Rym: Yeah, it's just my number.
Rym: and Knowing that number doesn't help you on a Getting my business information unless you also have access to the back-end database system.
Scott: Yeah, which is why RF ID security is really just database security.
Scott: I mean if you know different than a key.
Rym: It's no different than because a key is just a look-up except the database is physical and local and trivially broken.
Rym: Yeah, but I mean are it has one it is a key.
Scott: All of the Most of the privacy concerns with RF ID are really just database privacy concerns.
Rym: They're really not any different, you know, yeah, I mean say alright So I've got the number and I'm walking around the anime con that's using the numbers.
Rym: someone snooping Well just could say, huh?
Rym: Well, like we can see that this RF ID went into this room and went into this room or this RF ID was standing here Or if they were snooping on the con goer level like they walk around.
Rym: they're like well rims numbers 2 4 6 0 1 and Scott's number is negative 8 and and that girl's number is 4009 but that number doesn't tell them anything now here.
Scott: Here are some situations where it could get a little tricky, right?
Scott: Let's say someone at rims work the person who say managed this RF ID system.
Scott: They know what rims number is, right?
Scott: So they go to some say I don't know Political event and they just walk around to the little radio looking for RF IDs and they're picking up numbers and suddenly they pick up a number and it's rims number and they can sort of figure out which direction is coming from kind of.
Scott: so They yeah, and then sure enough there's Rym, right?
Scott: So now they they sort of know rims.
Scott: rims at this event rims a Barack Obama supporter, right?
Scott: So they go.
Rym: he's at an ACLU meeting Expected that what it does.
Scott: the the the real thing to worry about.
Scott: it's not really anything to worry about but the the theoretical dangers of RF ID are that someone who gave you an RF ID someone who already has a match of Your RF ID to their database can then if they are physically near enough to you Right sort of track your general location, you know and add that location Data to their existing database of information about you.
Rym: now In terms of I think the way this show is going now that we've talked a bit is we're only gonna talk about Not the technology and not even the good uses of it so much.
Rym: I think I just want to talk about all the security concerns.
Scott: pretty much Yeah, I could do.
Rym: we could do a whole show on the awesome and privacy also Yeah, but just in terms of security and privacy I mean the.
Rym: here's the biggest real concern you could have.
Rym: but I think I want to point out at the end Why I don't think it's as big a concern as people are making it out to be.
Rym: so let's say RF IDs eventually and this will happen will be in everything.
Rym: every article of clothing I mean tires for cars already have RF IDs in them.
Rym: Yep, but products will start to have RF IDs.
Rym: now It won't be linked like I buy a shirt and it has a number that says this is rimmed shirt in it.
Rym: every Hanes Whatever shirt will probably have the exact same number.
Rym: So even if you try to cross-link database is like alright.
Rym: Rym bought a Hanes t-shirt.
Rym: Oh, look a Hanes t-shirt walked by my RF day ID reader.
Rym: So did a thousand other Hanes t-shirts.
Scott: Yeah, and even if they did have different numbers, right?
Scott: Let's say each Hanes t-shirt had a unique number, right?
Scott: It was like IPv6, right?
Scott: Okay, so, you know that a Hanes t-shirt went by.
Scott: unless you have access to the Hanes t-shirt database or perhaps the retail store Database Rym bought the t-shirt.
Rym: even I could have paid cash.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: So unless Rym work it Rym paid with a credit card and you either have the Kohl's database or the Hanes database.
Scott: You're not gonna know that the Hanes t-shirt that just walked by was Rym.
Scott: You know to have access to the databases, which means you really only have to worry about Hanes or Kohl's Following you around or something or being you know Broadcasting RF IDs in areas where you go and
Rym: also the people who are so afraid about the stores finding out what you buy if You use credit cards at all Then all those concerns are out the window because they already know everything about you And you know what they do track that data stores constantly track what credit.
Scott: Yeah, are you are using a little fun saver card at the grocery store?
Scott: Cuz even if you pay with cash use that little, you know Club Savings Card Guess what?
Rym: Of course, I use one that I found on the ground a number of years ago.
Scott: So does Scott and so does Emily and so does Alex sometimes Yeah, and you can just you if you want one of those things at the grocery store You can just fill out false information.
Scott: They'll hand you one right.
Rym: then depends on the groceries.
Scott: It does depend on the grocery store, but in my experience you can just go up and be like, I'm Joey Jojo Shabdo I live on five Pine Street in this town that this grocery store It's now.
Rym: they'll only give you a temporary one and then they'll mail you the real one.
Rym: That's fine.
Scott: Yeah, I'll use the temporary one and every time I come to the store I get a new temporary one.
Rym: that but you were gonna go for all that trouble.
Rym: I'll just get the thing cuz I don't care if the food line knows that I buy hams every Thursday.
Scott: actually It's really yet to decide, you know, do you care more about them?
Scott: you know look using your information against you as a way to sell you more shit or The other way to look at it.
Scott: is you know, are they gonna make your shopping experience better?
Scott: I kind of want them to know that I buy this bread every week because then they'll keep that bread in stock and it won't Sell out of it.
Rym: Yeah or this group of people always buy all this Asian food and They also tend to buy the very expensive things in the other part of the and they come on Friday.
Rym: so what if we stock more of these ramens that they're always buying and we make sure they're in stock on Friday?
Rym: and They'll?
Rym: because we know that they're big spenders.
Rym: Anyway, they're more likely to buy that stuff.
Rym: Yep but here's the more paranoid.
Rym: can security concern and this is the.
Rym: if I were doing the evil nefarious things how I Would use RF IDs so I can't easily track someone without knowing their database, whatever.
Rym: So let's say the databases are secure.
Rym: What if I spend a lot of time around you and I grab RF IDs whenever I can near you And I get my agents to grab them near you.
Rym: I know where you work I know the things you walk by.
Rym: so, you know, I'm already spying on you.
Rym: So I try to gather over a long period of time your RF ID profile.
Rym: You tend to wear these brands of clothes.
Rym: you tend to wear these kinds of shoes Most people only hit.
Rym: well most guys who work in the business world only have one or two pairs of shoes at most and they Wear them every day and they don't change them often.
Rym: So over time I can build an RF ID profile Whereby I could figure out where you are by having RF ID sensors in key places.
Rym: based on the likelihood of well The it's 80% likely that this is Rym because it is wearing.
Scott: it has 90% match ratio with as you Rym shoes and Rym Cellphone in the same place.
Rym: Well, I see the brand of shoes rimmed wares and the brand of cell phone Rym wears and 70% of these general articles of clothing that he wear matches.
Rym: profile odds are it's Rym And that sort of tracking is very interesting.
Rym: But I am personally not afraid of that kind of tracking because there are many many non Technological ways to do that kind of tracking.
Scott: and if someone is spending that amount of time tracking you That's the least of your concerns, yeah, I know right and really all the data they can get about you is you where you are Now beyond that the the and if you're going to nefarious places, right?
Scott: Let's say you're going to some embarrassing places like say a strip club, right?
Scott: You know the real interesting and you know, you don't want your wife to know right?
Scott: I don't imagine you know strip clubs will be looking at everyone's RF IDs.
Scott: They'll probably be in fact blocking, you know, just to be like, ah, we protect you.
Rym: Well, it's like the scary porno shop on West Henrietta Road that we don't Right, you know every porn stop has parking in the back where people can hide their cars.
Scott: yep, also what you could worry about though is the porn store could are could get all the RF IDs of people coming into their store and then blackmail you.
Rym: it's like that Futurama where he's like.
Rym: Respect the privacy of my customers.
Rym: Lila's like I'll beat you up.
Rym: He's like fine.
Rym: I videotape all my customers and blackmail them later.
Rym: Who do you want to see?
Rym: That's horrible, what do you expect?
Rym: I'm some horrible space monster Who runs a porno star?
Rym: but the other thing is RFID is RF.
Rym: It is so trivial to block RFID.
Scott: Yeah, you know tinfoil a little one of those little, you know, those little baggies.
Scott: They go around your easy pass.
Scott: that works.
Rym: Not even that the range is not so great.
Scott: Well, you can pump up the range with more power.
Rym: No But upping the power one makes you more noticeable by people who might not want you to be doing what you're doing.
Rym: Yeah, like in the FCC.
Rym: Well, no like in a snow crash where that gargoyle guy gets totally fucked by the fact that because he's spying on everyone with his High-powered equipment, he's kind of broadcasting the fact that he's spying on everyone with his high-powered equipment.
Scott: And they yeah, it's like, you know, they have a high-powered thing.
Scott: You're gonna need like to carry a car bat around you, huh?
Scott: Who's that guy with a car?
Rym: Battery and a ghostbuster device just like in silent service, you know sonar Active sonar lets you see the enemy sub But it also tells the enemy sub exactly where you are.
Rym: And now you both have a firing solution and only Sean Connery can save the day by going full speed ahead Before the torpedo arms, but yeah passive sonar for the win.
Rym: that the thing is it it's difficult because alright So you up the power now, especially as RF IDs get more widespread you get so many responses from all the Hanes t-shirts.
Scott: Yeah I mean like if you're in Times Square and you turn this thing on you don't really.
Scott: you might be able to tell Generally, which direction they came from.
Scott: but you don't you don't really know.
Scott: All you know is that they're within range.
Scott: That's all you really know.
Scott: is that this RFID is within range of where I am right now?
Rym: Not even that because they respond in the same signal space and because they're the same.
Rym: all the Hanes t-shirts that are gray of the same response.
Rym: They overlap they collide.
Rym: you might not even be able to read any of the data.
Scott: Yeah, you also might not eat.
Scott: you might know.
Scott: there are Hanes t-shirts.
Scott: You don't know how many you know, you could be one it could be a hundred and you just you just get this number back.
Scott: Maybe one RFID broadcasted ten times or maybe ten of them broadcasted once you don't know and doing it directionally is Theoretically possible but difficult and of dubious.
Scott: It is much more difficult to get any sort of direction But I think it is theoretically possible with triangulation.
Rym: I think I mean to sum this up in my estimation Scott and I are fairly well versed in technology and the two of us despite being very Protective of certain kinds of privacy and also look at other people are in the know.
Rym: None of us are really afraid of RFID.
Scott: Well, there are a few situations in which it is a good.
Scott: there are some reasons to be afraid of RFID.
Scott: For example, if they were they were talking about putting RFID in US passports, right?
Rym: I just have a Mesh bag.
Rym: I keep it right.
Scott: if you keep it in a little bag with a little you know That filters out RF which is what I would do anyway, which is what you would do.
Scott: You're fine.
Scott: Perfect.
Scott: But if someone's dumb and they don't let's say you're in a place that's not so friendly to the US say Quebec.
Scott: All right, you go to Quebec Right and you have your US passport in your pocket But you're pretending to be Canadian because you don't have to be pissed off at you.
Scott: All right, someone's got a little RFID reader and they go haha.
Scott: This is a stupid American.
Scott: I will go beat him up now.
Scott: then this is a slight cause for worry.
Scott: But you put your passport in a little protect II thing.
Scott: good.
Scott: You're done.
Scott: Whatever.
Scott: No, it doesn't matter.
Scott: now They can have the biggest radio in the world.
Scott: It won't mean shit.
Rym: plus I'm not afraid in a more general sense because like people think oh they can track me.
Rym: But then if this technology gets widespread enough to where that'll happen RFID will be everywhere It'll be ubiquitous.
Rym: and then the value of tracking you goes down as opposed to the value of trying to track anyone.
Rym: It's no different than it's just technology advancing and it's kind of the idea that you really can't expect privacy in public places.
Scott: Yeah, especially as information becomes, you know so much more easier to collect and transmit more information is gonna be out there.
Rym: Just I guess don't do anything Nothing else.
Rym: my opinion if you trust my opinion personally as a as a person who understands technology I am not in the least afraid of RFID technology.
Rym: I welcome its inception and in the future I think we'll do a show on the like billion awesome things we could do if RFID became widespread.
Scott: Yeah, I'm not afraid of it for myself because in any of the few situations in which it might prove, you know somewhat troubling I know I would be smart I would just you know, I'd put my passport a little baggie and I'd be safe.
Scott: But I do slightly worry for some of the unawares.
Scott: less, you know I don't want to say inept more inept peoples or more ignorant.
Rym: But at the same time, you know the US like if travelers were going overseas and this is an issue in the future They would issue the standard warning like got to get your malaria shot got to get you whatever.
Rym: don't watch out for terrorists and Don't forget to use your handy-dandy Special protect me from the terrorists mesh bag for your passport.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Yeah be fun.
Scott: Yeah, the only thing you really had to.
Scott: the thing about RFID is that because you know RFID sort of has people spooked, right?
Scott: And they sort of come up with all these, you know This and this and this that all the this is and this is that they're worried about are really database, you know Aggregation privacy and security issues, which is actually a separate issue.
Scott: It's just because of the fear of RFID.
Scott: light is being shined on this separate database issue and being attached to RFID and there is some stuff to worry about when you know people with big databases put them together, but Not right now.
Scott: We'll talk about that some other day.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology.
Rym: Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback Via audio.
Scott: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Scott: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.