Rym: It's Monday, December 1st, I'm Rym, I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights!
Rym: Tonight, after a lot of other discussions, we talk briefly about how to interview tech people.
Scott: Let's do this!
Rym: So it was a Monday, and I had done laundry, as I often do on the weekends, so I could choose from any of the shirts that I own, I own many shirts, I could choose any one of them.
Rym: So of all the shirts that I own, I chose to wear a blue dress shirt to work today.
Rym: I get to work, and it just so happens that every single person in the entire tech department wore a blue collared shirt today.
Rym: Every single one of us.
Scott: But, so, I mean, how many colors are there?
Scott: I mean, white, blue, darker blue, black, red, yeah, I mean, you know, it's not like some freak of nature that everyone wears blue, one of the most common shirt colors.
Rym: But the fact, the thing is, people don't wear blue that often.
Rym: I wear blue more than anyone.
Rym: Most people wear green or black or something, or they wear, like, a sweater.
Rym: But the fact that everyone was wearing blue was kind of, it was kind of surprising.
Rym: We declared that we won some sort of arbitrary prize.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Is that all you got there?
Rym: That's all I got.
Scott: All right, so check this out.
Scott: I don't want to tell this whole story because, you know, the person who told me the story, because it's about them, you know, if you're going to hear it, it's going to be from them and not a secondhand story.
Scott: But basically, I don't know if I said this on the show yet.
Scott: I don't think I have.
Scott: is that my the person who was until very recently, my boss.
Rym: Oh, oh, you're going to tell a story that you told me a while ago and you were probably saving for a Monday.
Scott: Yeah, he was the.
Rym: I went with the topical, the reason the the actual thing from I got more going on.
Scott: He I'm not going to tell the whole story of it.
Scott: You'll have to wait maybe to hear that.
Scott: But he is the.
Scott: he tells me and I'm pretty sure he's correct.
Scott: He's not lying.
Scott: He was the youngest, perhaps the youngest victim of Operation Sun Devil.
Scott: You can go look up what Operation Sun Devil is.
Rym: Operation Sun Devil is infamous among tech people.
Rym: It has a lot to do with the 70s.
Scott: It has a lot to do with Apple twos in the early 80s and, you know, and pirating and BBS's and dial up modem BBS's.
Rym: I mean, we grew up on the Secret Service.
Rym: We grew up on the tail end of the BBS days.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So he apparently has a flaw.
Scott: He tells me as a floppy disk that has the BBS he wrote in like some language that was only ever used to write BBS's for the Apple two.
Scott: And he's got this one floppy disk, but he's got nothing to do with it.
Scott: And I have an Apple to G.S.
Scott: So I went out and I got a USB to serial cable and I got a serial to Apple to modem cable.
Scott: And I got a program called ADT Pro.
Scott: And I'm talking to people on the Internet's.
Scott: and all we need now is basically I need.
Scott: I ordered on eBay 10 brand new, never opened 3M dual sided double density five and a quarter inch floppy disk.
Rym: The saddest thing is that at RIT, we used to when we were freshmen, wander around in the tunnels under RIT.
Rym: And one day we were somewhere we shouldn't be.
Rym: And I remember we found a box full of five and a quarter floppies.
Rym: Yeah, we played with them like Frisbees for an hour and then we threw them all away.
Scott: If only we would have known that they were rare and no longer made.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Much like the box of 80 keyboards.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But I won the auction for a dollar and the shipping was five dollars.
Scott: We'll see when it shows up.
Scott: The person's lesson emailed me.
Rym: And I remember when I bought a box of one hundred high density, three and a half inch floppies.
Rym: Well, it is forty five dollars.
Scott: is the thing is I tested it out the Apple two, you know, and it totally works.
Scott: And the cable works great and everything's awesome.
Scott: Apparently there is.
Scott: there is a three and a half inch drive for the Apple to G.S.
Scott: I just if I could get one of those, then I could get a bunch of three and a half inch disks and I could download all sorts of Apple to software from the Web and put it on those floppies and rock the house.
Scott: But I need to get the drive.
Scott: And I so far I found one of those drives and it was on eBay for 40 bucks.
Scott: And I'm like, screw that.
Scott: It's not worth it.
Scott: So Apple to G.S.
Scott: is awoken in my room.
Scott: The second thing I all of most of our computers.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Oh, the twenty dollar motherboard.
Scott: Well, the second one.
Scott: Basically, originally we all had Pentiums, right?
Scott: Like the late 90s.
Scott: I had a Pentium three.
Rym: I had a Pentium Pro Pro.
Rym: Oh, man, I missed that.
Rym: I don't miss that thing.
Scott: And these are all.
Scott: you know, most of these were like slot based things.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I mean, Rym had slot A, which is the like the first Athlons.
Rym: I remember I was so proud.
Rym: I bought the AMD K seven eight hundred megahertz.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So I overclocked.
Scott: that was sort of hell when we got to RIT.
Scott: Those are the computers that most of the people brought with them.
Scott: I think Alex brought an old pre OS X Mac and someone else.
Scott: I think Greg had a K six to whatever.
Scott: You know, that was the first generation of the computers he brought to college.
Scott: We obviously had computers before that.
Scott: Fourty sixes and whatnot.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: We all kind of took turns leapfrogging each other in terms of who had the best as a computer after that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: After those computers went away, pretty much everyone, me, Ram, Alex, Greg, Pete, everybody bought socket a machines with Athlon CPUs, Athlon XPs across the board.
Scott: Everyone had socket a computers.
Scott: In fact, with AGP slots, everybody upgrade my computer.
Scott: The only reason we all had DDR four hundred or DDR three thirty three or DDR two sixty six, you know, that was the brand.
Scott: Everyone had DDR, Ram, socket, a motherboards, Athlon, CPUs and AGP.
Rym: That's if I were every computer had that, if I recall, there was.
Rym: that was right around the era where Ram got ludicrously cheap for like four or five months.
Rym: Like Ram was so cheap.
Rym: It was like Ram is so cheap now.
Rym: It's loud.
Rym: I know.
Rym: But back then, for what you got compared to what Ram had cost just a little bit before and what it cost a little bit after.
Rym: Because remember, there was that earthquake and that Ram prices sky.
Scott: Yeah, that earthquake was in the news for like a week.
Scott: And then we forgot about it anyway.
Rym: But then Ram prices were up for a while.
Scott: And, you know, I was using that NF seven as socket, a motherboard with the XP.
Scott: twenty five hundred up until like less than a year ago.
Scott: And I bought my current, you know, Kortu duo.
Rym: Hey, I was doing GeekNights this show on that old Athlon slot or socket that I bought when the slot blew up.
Rym: Yeah, until when I bought that Mac.
Scott: So as a result, you know, we all bought these new computers that have core two duos and LGA seven, seven, five.
Scott: But we have a lot.
Scott: All the computer equipment lying around the house, besides, you know, the Apple to G.S.
Scott: and the Mac 512 K and the I guess the Mac mini is all socket equipment.
Scott: We got lots of socket, a motherboards, lots of socket, a ram, lots of socket, a CPUs.
Scott: I've got like four or five of them.
Rym: We've got nine power supplies to go.
Scott: I've got nine power supplies that are compatible with this.
Scott: You know, we have a lot of socket, a computer equipment.
Scott: And the thing is, if you go a new egg, there are exactly two socket, a motherboards you can buy.
Scott: One of them is like a zillion dollar.
Scott: It's not a zillion dollars, but it's very expensive because it's a micro.
Scott: It's a mini ITX.
Scott: It's one of the ones that's meant for, you know, very tiny computers.
Scott: So that's really not useful.
Scott: The other one is a twenty dollar piece of crap.
Scott: Now, I had a lot of socket equipment and I've only got one working socket, a computer.
Scott: I've got like five or six motherboards, five or six CPUs, a pile of RAM sticks.
Rym: Who knows which are good, which are three perfectly good ATX cases.
Scott: I've got cases.
Scott: I've got power.
Scott: They got everything right.
Scott: And a while back, I tried to buy a twenty dollar motherboard, a new egg, and it worked for a while and then it stopped working.
Scott: So I was like, ah, fuck it.
Scott: But that was I think that was a micro ATX job.
Rym: That was because I had a micro ATX case point out that was also in that one case that always seemed to break.
Scott: because that's the thing is the micro ATX case comes with the power supply because the regular power supply isn't going to fit in there.
Scott: And I think that power supply was a killer anyway.
Scott: So I said, you know what, let me try again.
Scott: We've got one working socket, a computer.
Scott: It's in the hallway.
Scott: It's like the house server for doing DNS and whatnot.
Scott: Let me try to make.
Scott: this is my last shot at a socket, a computer that works.
Scott: So I pay 20 bucks.
Scott: I say, you know, even if it doesn't work, 20 bucks, big deal.
Scott: I won't even bother returning it.
Scott: It kind of works, but not really doesn't work, you know, it's an it's amazing to me, and it's just too much trouble to actually make it work all the way, if such a thing is possible.
Rym: I remember when I was a kid in high school, before I even went to RIT and I was like I'd saved up all this money and I cashed in a bunch of bonds and I was building my first computer from scratch.
Scott: I built your first computer from scratch with money from bonds.
Scott: I worked for an entire summer.
Rym: No, I worked for that summer, too.
Rym: I also cashed bonds.
Scott: I actually I didn't need to get.
Rym: I made more money.
Rym: From that job than the computer cost.
Rym: The computer was four thousand dollars.
Rym: Yeah, but that didn't.
Scott: when I got my first part time job, I spent basically I bought it from.
Scott: I bought a game boy and GB.
Scott: I think it was a Game Boy Color and a bunch of games.
Scott: But then I didn't buy anything until I had like a thousand dollars.
Scott: And I bought Pentium.
Rym: But I point out this four thousand dollars got me, among other things, a SCSI controller thousand.
Scott: I said one thousand.
Rym: Well, that included every single accessory, everything.
Scott: See, I kept the job and over I got basically got the base computer and over time bought up the accessories.
Rym: Remember, I bought everything all at once, like right before I went to RIT.
Scott: But even then, not all of it together cost four thousand.
Scott: It might have been two thousand.
Rym: That included the SCSI card, the TV tuner card.
Scott: Oh, man, I used to buy stuff from buy dot com and then mail them checks.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But remember, I had that Aver TV, USB.
Scott: Oh, that was pretty funny.
Rym: That thing was like one hundred and forty bucks.
Rym: The thing was not worth one hundred and forty dollars.
Scott: So the result is I sort of gave up on trying to get the twenty dollar motherboard to work.
Scott: I was just like after a couple of hours, I'm like, I just fuck it.
Rym: But this is a deal made me realize, you know, I spent all this time and I built a computer.
Rym: And then I remember thinking I have attained the skill.
Rym: I will every few years build new computers forever.
Rym: And like I was excited about it.
Rym: And I've built a few computers since then, but far fewer than I expected to have built.
Scott: I built one for myself about every five years.
Scott: But in general, I built a lot or, you know, it's weird.
Scott: It's like I look around at how many computer parts are there.
Scott: And I'm like, damn, I did a lot of computer building.
Scott: When the hell did that happen?
Scott: I only this is only my third computer I'm using that I've built.
Rym: Of course, a lot of this stuff we got from side projects like Pete would upgrade and we'd have his old processor and we try to make it work.
Rym: And yeah, the thing is, all the equipment we have that isn't in a working computer was something that didn't work immediately in some other project and thus was just discarded.
Rym: because if you have three socket, a processors and one doesn't work immediately with no effort, you just toss it and grab the next one.
Rym: You don't think about it.
Scott: So so I've got all this socket, a computer equipment, and I can't seem to construct a working computer out of it, even though I have theoretically enough parts to do so, assuming that one of each part is working properly.
Scott: So I just want to get it out of the house now.
Scott: I'm done with it.
Scott: You know, keep the socket, a computer in the hallway that's working.
Scott: And the rest of it, I either want to sell or recycle or just get it out of the house.
Rym: Well, I think what would push Scout over the edge was the fact that you spend what I think two hours total working on that thing and it didn't work at the end of that two hours.
Scott: Yeah, it didn't work perfectly.
Scott: It didn't work enough to actually be a computer that would turn on and function.
Rym: Yes, because the goal, actually, we want to we you know, we want to use one of these computers to make a Windows gaming box to run.
Scott: And yes, that's the thing is like I most of the a lot of the parts I have, it's like if the part goes to waste, I don't care.
Scott: Like I had to do on nine hundreds.
Scott: Who gives a shit if those don't get used?
Scott: You know, they're pretty useless.
Scott: But I've got this Geforce like 7000 series AGP eight X card.
Scott: now it's AGP, so it can't work in any modern computer.
Scott: No computer has AGP anymore, but it's a working perfectly good card that could actually play like Half-Life two games.
Scott: I just need a computer that has an AGP slot for it to go in.
Scott: But I don't have such a, you know, computer.
Scott: So it's like I have this good part going to waste because I don't have other good parts for it to function with.
Scott: And I don't want to.
Scott: if I'm going to buy a whole bunch of parts, I can, you know, go on the forum.
Scott: I posted like an amazing machine for seven hundred dollars.
Rym: So well, that's the thing for you know, it takes two hours of your life to get this thing working barely for seven hundred dollars.
Scott: I can get like a work of art for seven hundred dollars.
Rym: You can get a computer that's like four times faster than anything.
Scott: We could get a computer faster than the ones on my desk, which is really sad.
Rym: Yes, it's moving so quickly for less than a thousand dollars.
Rym: I could build a computer that's almost all told twice as fast as the one I use now as my primary PC.
Rym: And I'm really tempted periodically.
Rym: I play I play a game like Left 4 Dead.
Rym: And my FPS is only 40.
Rym: Maybe I should upgrade.
Scott: So if anyone wants some socket, a computer equipment, if you want the small stuff like some CPUs or some ram or something like that, or if you have a use for that video card, let me know and I can mail it to you.
Scott: If you want cases, motherboards, power supplies, you know, the big stuff, you got to come here and get it because I'm not going to mail it.
Scott: It's too big.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So anyway, enough of that, because if you if no one wants it, we're going to donate it to some place in the Bronx or maybe we're going to find someone just to get it the hell out of the house.
Scott: Also, if anyone wants a 12 inch VGA CRT, oh, hell, if you want a 17 inch LCD, that's perfectly fine.
Scott: We have extras.
Rym: It's where I remember we bought this LCD for GeekNights to bring to conventions for, you know, like when we take the Mac and set it up on a table and record stuff.
Rym: And I remember like it was a big deal.
Rym: Like, yes, we should buy this.
Rym: Let's just spend the money.
Rym: Let's do it.
Rym: Now we have like three LCDs we're not even using.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Times are changing.
Rym: anyway in actual tech news, because we talked about that for a while.
Rym: There was an article on Slashdot.
Rym: Basically, HP decided to go after this open source vendor because the open source vendor was revealing HP's, quote, confidential pricing, confidential pricing.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: You see, HP, like pretty much every enterprise vendor out there for enterprise stuff, does not actually advertise their prices for any of their enterprise products.
Scott: Well, yeah, it's one of those situations where, you know, I mean, an enterprise thing, you know, it's understandable because there isn't really a price.
Scott: It's not like, you know, you know, this gigantic server set up costs X. It's you go and you negotiate a contract with the salespeople and they customize it to what you need.
Rym: You think that, but we're even talking about just software, like just a ticketing system, let's say anything like that.
Rym: It's not that there isn't a price because there is.
Rym: there is actually just a price.
Rym: The thing is, they'll always originally always, always, always if you just ask for a price or you find a listed price, it'll be like four times what the actual secret price is.
Rym: And what they'll do is they'll publish that.
Rym: And I didn't realize this at first.
Rym: When I got into the IT industry, I was young and green and I went to this company and I was like, not the company I'm talking about in the article, but some other company.
Rym: And I was like, yeah, I'd like your software.
Rym: Can you give me a quote?
Rym: And they were like, two hundred thousand dollars.
Rym: I'm like, all right, fine.
Rym: And I take that quote to my boss and my boss looks at it and he's like, demand a 70 percent discount or tell him we won't buy it.
Rym: And I was like, that's kind of ballsy.
Rym: And he was like, no, that's the way it works.
Rym: Trust me.
Rym: So I call the guy back and I'm like, listen, I need at least 70 percent off.
Rym: And he was like, all right.
Rym: When it comes to this stuff, it's not that there's no price and they like fiddle it to make sure that they make the most money out of you is basically there is a price.
Scott: But by saying this higher price first, idiots who don't know better will pay this ludicrous extra amount of money.
Scott: I guess an idiot tax.
Rym: It's an idiot tax.
Rym: And more importantly, it's for the bean counters because I'm the tech guy.
Rym: I know I need this software.
Rym: It's the only software in the world that does the specific ludicrous enterprise thing that I need.
Rym: So I go to the company and they give me a quote and then I say, all right, I'll give me the other quote with the discount.
Rym: And then I take the two quotes to my bean counter and I say, look, I saved the company seven hundred thousand dollars by negotiating this discount.
Scott: because everything that's one thing is that at any company, IT is nothing but cost.
Scott: IT doesn't.
Scott: unless you're a tech company, IT doesn't make you any money whatsoever.
Scott: It's just the cost of doing business.
Scott: So thus any company that does something for reals and just has IT supporting that something for reals wants to minimize ID costs as much as possible.
Scott: So as
Rym: an aside, I will point out that if you want to know if the company you work for is smart or not, the simplest way to find out in a hurry is to see how the management that is not technical, regards the IT, you know, computer science, whatever department, because if they regard it with disdain or they're constantly trying to cut its budget, that means that they don't understand the value it provides.
Scott: They've kind of fallen into that trap that if you are it's a shitty IT department that's not providing the value.
Rym: But if that's the case, just get rid of it and outsource.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: But a lot of times companies, you get into this problem where if an IT department works very well, like everyone is very skilled, you will never even notice that they're there.
Rym: Like you won't even realize they're working like no one.
Rym: Nothing ever goes wrong.
Rym: No one thinks you're doing any work.
Rym: So bad bean counters will look at this and say, well, if nothing's ever breaking and we never see them doing any work, we should fire half of them and lower their salaries and take away those servers they're using.
Scott: No.
Scott: What do you know?
Scott: Everything's breaking.
Scott: It just breaks all the time.
Rym: And even when no one does anything, they always say you can tell the worth of a society by the way it treats its prisoners.
Rym: You can tell the worth of a company by the way they treat their prisoners, a.k.a.
Rym: the IT department.
Rym: Yeah, but all enterprise stuff is like this.
Rym: And this open source company, what happened here was they they got the prices, the, you know, quote unquote prices.
Scott: So they basically said they got the fake prices and said, look, this is the fake price of HP's solution.
Scott: Our solution is open source free.
Rym: Well, it's not open source free because they provide a solution.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Scott: Well, the program is free and we provide the support for this incredibly tiny cost compared to the fake cost.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: According to the article, what they charge is eighty two percent less than what the HP is charging.
Scott: But HP probably charges eighty two percent less than what they charge.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: But the thing is the HP and the enterprise industry in general realize that if people could compare prices legitimately, if there was just a quote like I could see what another company paid, their whole house of cards comes tumbling down because this stuff does not cost that much.
Rym: And a lot of this is markup and a lot of it's the B.S.
Rym: So I can say to my bean counter that I did good.
Scott: Well, really, the big problem is that, you know, an enterprise application is something that companies desperately need.
Scott: And but even then, you don't sell that many copies.
Scott: It's not like Photoshop where you sell a bajillion copies of people.
Scott: You sell a bajillion copies.
Scott: Right.
Rym: How many companies in the world will ever need software like Remedy?
Scott: So but, you know, it's.
Scott: there are companies that desperately need remedy.
Scott: It needs to be made.
Scott: There's a demand.
Scott: It can be filled.
Scott: There's money to be made.
Rym: Now, granted, I have my opinions.
Scott: The demand is only maybe like a hundred or a few hundred companies, maybe a few thousand.
Scott: If you're lucky, if you sell for 50 bucks, you get fifty thousand dollars.
Scott: So I hope that you made remedy with one developer in one year that you're fifty thousand dollars paid him and you broke even.
Scott: So more and more I'm of the mind that you need to sell enterprise software for a lot more money in order to make a profit because you're not selling that many copies.
Rym: I'm feeling more and more, though, that in many cases, the cost of enterprise software is not justified compared to what it would cost to hire in-house developers to make a specific problem for you.
Scott: The problem is finding developers who are good enough because they, you know.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: And have the knowledge in the appropriate subject area.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: I mean, the example is always like hospital software or like financial software.
Rym: The subset of people who know programming and the subset of people who know complex like debt instruments or hospital stuff, there's not a lot of overlap there.
Rym: And you're not going to find some open source guy who's like, man, you know, it's totally awesome writing accounting software for car dealerships.
Rym: Yeah, I'm totally going to do that in my free time.
Scott: And, you know, they if you do find someone who has that overlap, say they really know how to manage hospitals and they know how to write software really well.
Scott: Guess what?
Scott: That person is probably just going to write that software on their own and sell it to every hospital instead of letting themselves be hired by one hospital on a salary and writing the software for one hospital and one hospital only.
Rym: But anyway, this reveals a more a wider problem in the technology world and even just the commercial world, in that there are more and more people relying on obscurity of their prices for their business models.
Rym: I mean, how many websites or retailers have rules where they don't let other people advertise their price?
Scott: I mean, how many times do you go on Amazon and it says price hidden, click here to see the actual price because they don't want like the super discounted price to be indexed anywhere on Google or anything?
Rym: Yes.
Rym: And I'm starting to feel like in the end there needs to be some sort of regulation or some sort of consumer rights that pricing information is public domain and cannot be in any way restricted.
Scott: I think that's, you know, that I think this shows just, you know, how the free flow of information and the free market are sort of inseparable.
Scott: And, you know, many people try to, you know, have one without the other or vice versa.
Rym: There's a lot of this.
Scott: And it really it really I mean, look at your company is all about keeping some information secret and keeping some other information, not secret.
Rym: Well, the thing is, that actually saves people as opposed to harming them.
Rym: It makes the market flow better.
Scott: Yeah, that's true.
Scott: But the thing is, it's like, well, you know, this keeping this information secret saves people at HP and helps them go better.
Rym: Yes, but there's a different I don't know.
Rym: I feel like pricing at least to get it because I could go to the very deep specifics of what my company does.
Scott: And, you know, that is true is that at least, you know, with the stocks that, you know, your company trades stocks and whatnot, you can look up the prices of a stock just like a Google finance or whatever.
Scott: It's not secret.
Rym: Yeah, but I feel every industry is different.
Rym: Everything is different.
Rym: But in general, if someone publishes a price or someone is willing to sell something for some price and I find out what that price is, I should not be restricted in telling someone else what that price is.
Scott: Yeah, unless you sign some sort of thing.
Scott: Yes,
Rym: but if I didn't and I find out a price or if a price is publicly available or in fact, if any information is publicly available and I am not bound by any sort of NDA that I have agreed to before seeing said information, then that information, it should not be illegal or against various contract laws or whatever to redistribute.
Scott: Yeah, you can't copyright.
Scott: It's not a work.
Scott: It's not copyrighted.
Scott: It's not a logo or anything.
Scott: It's not a trademark, right?
Scott: It's not unless the product is not yet available or something.
Scott: It's not insider information.
Scott: And unless it's, you know, and it's not like the codes of the nuclear weapons, it's not a security issue.
Rym: And it's not a heavy, heavily regulated industry.
Rym: Like part of the reason why stocks are so different is that there is a very heavy handed government presence in stock.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So if there's none of those things that we just listed, then any piece of information should be allowed to be freely disseminated.
Scott: It's freedom of the press.
Scott: That's how it works.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: So that's all I really have to say about that.
Rym: It's one of those situations where I brought up the article just to discuss the topic.
Rym: But all I have to say is I went to my boss and I was like, I got a 70 percent discount.
Rym: He was like, good job, because he knows that it's so great working for a company where everyone knows better.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Other bosses might be like, really?
Scott: So we should.
Rym: Of course, I didn't realize until later.
Rym: But when I worked at the hospital, I was on the opposite side of that.
Rym: I just never did the negotiating.
Rym: So I never knew.
Rym: I never realized.
Scott: Anyway, so check that.
Scott: This is a really interesting story.
Scott: I thought people, when they think of robots, you know, fighting in wars or anything like that, they think of, you know, science fiction, doomsday robots killing everyone with laser beams.
Scott: You know, I think all the humans.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: I think about the Matrix.
Scott: They think about all that sort of stuff.
Scott: And with very good reason, they think about those things.
Rym: However, because robots have such a long, colorful history of killing us.
Scott: Of course, you know, even Astro voice talking about this kind of action.
Scott: But there's actually, you know, people are, of course, you know, that military is researching everything.
Scott: And of course, they're researching autonomous battlefield robots.
Scott: It's not, you know, we have the technology to do something in this area.
Rym: As far as I am aware, no doctrine of U.S.
Rym: military strategy has changed.
Rym: I believe now I'm talking based largely on things I read a long time ago.
Rym: But as far as I'm aware, the doctrine of our military is that regardless of what electronic systems are in place, a human must always make the kill decision.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I think that's how it is now.
Rym: Well, that's kind of like currently the universal doctrine of automatic killing.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: We've got, you know, we've got robot drones that fly, but they don't drop bombs or anything.
Scott: And if they do, someone else is is looking at like a camera and pushing a button that drops the bomb, you know, whatever like that.
Rym: A human always makes the decision to engage a lethal device.
Scott: But what's interesting here is that normally people would go, ah, it's give you the matrix.
Scott: Don't do that.
Scott: Don't make killing robots.
Scott: But actually, there are some things that are actually better about robots being in wars than people.
Scott: You know, take, for example, a person, you know, in, you know, a battlefield situation.
Scott: They're afraid.
Scott: They're you know, they're.
Scott: they're very paranoid that, you know, every person they see, especially like an Iraq kind of situation, you know, is is actually like a crazy suicide bomber.
Rym: It's a concept I actually was unaware of.
Rym: And I read a fascinating couple of articles about it, but it was situational.
Rym: I forgot what the term was.
Rym: I feel like it says here, scenario fulfillment, scenario fulfillment.
Rym: That's the one.
Rym: It's this whole idea that if someone expects a certain outcome based on their training or their life experience, even if the situation they're in will not necessarily lead to that outcome, they will take action subconsciously to cause that outcome to occur anyway.
Scott: Well, actually, what it is, is that if you let's say you think that, you know, a suicide bombing is going to happen, right, as you expect.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So you look around you and you know, you basically anything around you that may hint at a suicide bombing, perhaps a guy with a trench coat or, you know, those pieces of information, you know, the guy with the trench coat, a guy, you know, winking at some people, you know, stuff like that, that information, those things.
Scott: you will observe those things and they will stick in your mind and you will notice the more and you will notice other things less.
Scott: And that's now, you know, you expect a thing to happen.
Scott: And now everything you see makes it look like that's going to happen.
Scott: It's like, oh, my God, it is going to happen.
Scott: You know, because you expected it to happen, your your brain sort of sees it coming and turns everything around you into hints of it coming and ignores everything else is going on.
Scott: And thus, you know, people are very likely to get panicky and make all sorts of mistakes.
Scott: Whereas
Rym: a robot, while
Scott: it if you had some evil Terminator style,
Rym: I, you know, or if you run into the as a mob problem where, you know, you make the very specific rules, but then there's the one condition that doesn't really jive with the rules and then horrible things happen.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But the robot doesn't have these.
Scott: robot isn't going to like panic and, you know, just start shooting like crazy unless it's broken and it's got a bug in it.
Scott: You know, it doesn't.
Scott: it's not afraid of things it does.
Scott: It doesn't.
Scott: Well, I guess the theoretical idea is that simply it doesn't have all sorts of nasty, like, you know, human problems of like going crazy in Vietnam and becoming a human can be programmed by training.
Rym: But at the same time, humans, all humans, ourselves included, believe it or not, are fallible.
Rym: And you can't program a human to behave in a specific way 100 percent because we're human.
Rym: If you could program a human that way, then that kind of belies our ability to choose and think and all sorts of things.
Rym: But humans can react in irrational ways.
Rym: They can be frightened.
Rym: And theoretically, you can program a robot so long as you have a sufficient means to program it effectively to always behave in a specific way.
Rym: So a robot, if you train it and you train it properly, will always behave exactly the way you trained it.
Rym: It will never deviate from this course.
Rym: So say you had a century robot that's guarding a checkpoint and it is instructed to, you know, give five warnings if someone approaches without identifying themselves and it gives those warnings in various different languages.
Rym: And it only shoots if the specific final threshold is reached and the specific number of warnings has been given, as opposed to a human who, if they see a jeep driving at them quickly, might fire on it before they realize that behind that jeep, there's something else going on or the jeep is trying to slow down.
Scott: Or maybe their friends are driving the jeep and they stole it, you know, and even though it's a disguised jeep, you know, who know, you know, it makes all sorts of mistakes and they properly.
Scott: But there's other advantages to a robot as well.
Scott: For example, you know, there's a robot.
Scott: You can't really capture it and make it a prisoner of war, it doesn't really work, you can't interrogate it and someone can always self-destruct it, you know, from far away.
Rym: Of course, there is still the.
Rym: the primary ethical concern I've always found with autonomous killing machines or even remote killing machines is that it removes all of the kind of danger or immediacy of warfare from the person engaging in it.
Scott: so that also if we ever reach a point where it's robots fighting robots, it really becomes like, why?
Scott: Yeah, just if you're basically having a fight of money and science, you might as well just play a game at that point.
Scott: Well, we should do anyway.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Well, Europe turned to soccer a long time ago.
Rym: I know.
Rym: They're well for them.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: I need robot soccer.
Rym: But there's also the problem that I mean, imagine, you know, occupying Iraq or occupying a country, a war, an aggressive war against an enemy state.
Rym: Currently, people from our side, you know, your side will die.
Rym: There'll be casualties.
Rym: There will be consequences.
Rym: But if you can, if you could eventually wage an occupying war solely with autonomous machines, then the only danger to a state that is belligerent is economic and no longer there are no longer lives on the line.
Rym: And that, in a way, if a society isn't prepared to be much more discerning in when it engages war, it kind of removes one of the natural checks and balances of the world that even if you go to war for a good reason or a bad reason, war hurts and it forces you to think about it at least a little bit.
Rym: If you remove that check, you either need a much more enlightened society or you need to just not engage in warfare at all.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Maybe at that point you shouldn't have the automatic killing machines.
Scott: Probably not.
Scott: But it's interesting, though, because usually, you know, the first thing people think of when they think of war robots is, you know, the Terminator, the Matrix or anything like that.
Scott: And for someone to come out and make a pretty decent argument for why they're probably, you know, should be, you know, robotic soldiers of, you know, some kind.
Scott: That's, you know, it's pretty interesting.
Rym: Well, I remember reading and this was a good 12 to 15 years ago, I remember reading an article about a system that had been designed and actually they've come a long way since then.
Rym: I got to see what the state is.
Rym: I'm sure there's an article about it, but it was a machine that was designed to.
Rym: it has microphones placed all over the place.
Rym: And it'll.
Rym: if a gunshot is fired, it could pinpoint in less than a second exactly where that gunshot originated from.
Rym: So in a combat zone or in a peacekeeping situation, if the technology were sufficient, like an example of one of these machines could be a robot that identifies and then, if necessary, fires upon any combatant anywhere in a zone, thus denying the ability to engage in hostilities to anyone within a certain zone, which is a very interesting peacekeeping idea.
Scott: That would be a very good idea, except that things like walls exist, which is a problem.
Rym: Well, yes, but at the same time, the gunshot could.
Rym: if the gunshot originated behind the wall, I don't need to worry about the gunshot hitting anything.
Scott: Well, no, but like, for example, this machine that has the microphones and, say, a sniper rifle in it is on the other side of the wall, I kill someone on this side of the wall.
Scott: The machine doesn't kill me.
Scott: I'm OK.
Rym: It's got all area denial devices only deny a specific area.
Rym: I mean, I have a mind, so I buried somewhere.
Rym: Someone might walk around the mine.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: OK, we shouldn't use mines anyway.
Scott: I just think that to conclude this news bit here, I think that this just demonstrates that the perfect soldier is, of course, some sort of cyborg, twisted half man, half machine, as everyone has always known, some sort of abomination.
Rym: Yes, that is a God and country that is.
Scott: that is obvious for a very long time.
Scott: This is just more more on the part.
Rym: In fact, I think it must essentially live entirely within the uncanny valley, perhaps at the deepest trough, some combination of Gogo 13 and Johnny 5.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day, I stumbled across this kind of randomly and I think it's pretty damn cool.
Rym: I don't know who this guy is.
Rym: I didn't do any research on this whatsoever other than watching this video and a couple of related videos.
Rym: But this guy has a looks like they have a research team and they've come up with a very low impact, very low technology, very efficient and very fascinating way to regreen and reclaim land that has been lost to desert, particularly in the Middle East, and turn it into useful cropland without having to divert any water from anywhere else or any substantial resources from anywhere else.
Scott: So that's pretty it because, you know, isn't the definition of desert like a place with less than X rainfall?
Rym: Yeah, but there's more to it.
Scott: Where does where does you need?
Scott: I mean, you need water and you need a certain amount of it, you know, no matter what.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I mean, you can't just suddenly if they can magically grow.
Scott: Trees with no water.
Scott: Holy crap.
Scott: Nobel prizes all around.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So they got to get the water from somewhere.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Well, the idea is that even in the harsh deserts where there is very little rainfall, there is still enough rainfall.
Rym: The problem is what little rainfall there is either evaporates immediately or hits the soil.
Rym: that won't absorb it and it washes away.
Rym: That's why.
Scott: So why?
Scott: But I mean, like I was in the desert and I spilled some water and it absorbed into the sandy dirt.
Rym: Yes, the sandy dirt.
Rym: So if you poured a ton of water, it would absorb all it could absorb at the surface and the rest of it just washes away.
Rym: And two, that's why you get these flash floods in desert places so often.
Scott: And beyond that, the soil itself, because when it actually does rain, very little of it goes into the soil and the rest of it goes whoosh.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And if only and if there's only a little bit in the soil, like you just spill your water, it's going to evaporate out of the soil like that.
Scott: And because it's very hot.
Rym: So they came up with this interesting way of kind of using the contours of the land and just like mulching and making these these troughs that will catch water.
Rym: And the very little rainfall there is, if you just catch it properly, is enough to grow a whole ton of fig trees and citrus trees and mushrooms and all sorts of neat stuff.
Rym: I suggest you all watch this video.
Rym: I'm going to try to do some more research and see the.
Rym: you know what the results of this event and how feasible it is.
Rym: But this is fascinating stuff.
Rym: I always like because, you know, people always tend to focus, especially on, you know, tech shows and podcasts in the Western world on the very high tech solutions to things.
Rym: So what's the cutting edge, the bleeding edge of, you know, every science, every technology.
Rym: But at the same time, the bleeding edge and the cutting edge often take a lot more resources and require a lot more infrastructure.
Rym: I mean, a device that could, by cranking it, purify water, even if it was very inefficient, would do a lot more good to poor parts of Africa than even the fanciest modern osmosis device.
Scott: Yeah, there are plenty of water filtering things going down there.
Rym: Yes, but that's a good example that the things that help the third world the most are often the very robust, low tech solutions.
Rym: I call this the AK-47 syndrome, that a low tech but very well constructed, very easy to use, very easy to manufacture, requiring very little preexisting knowledge solution is generally much better for helping people who don't have a lot of resources at their disposal to kind of take control of their own destiny and help themselves rather than forcing them to rely on technology they could never understand because they don't have the infrastructure or the education already to use it.
Rym: And I just I love solutions like this.
Rym: So I hope this.
Rym: I hope that we see more things like this in the future.
Rym: And I think that this is really the the the way we should be going in terms of helping the third world.
Scott: I mean, it looks like it works.
Scott: I just question whether, you know, you can't do this to all the desert.
Scott: You know, you're only going to be able to do this so much before it doesn't work anymore.
Rym: I see.
Rym: It seems like the places this is most useful are marginalized people who are living on the edges of deserts.
Rym: And I mean, there are a lot of parts of the Middle East where people are living in places that people really shouldn't be living.
Rym: But that's all they've got.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So for those people, I mean, think about it, you know, for years and years and years, all desert people like Bedouins were all nomadic.
Scott: They moved around and then they'd be.
Scott: oasis is right.
Scott: So it's like you got a desert, but you have an oasis and an oasis is like a real thing.
Scott: It's not just in the cartoons.
Scott: They exist very much, you know.
Scott: And it's like if there's an oasis, why can't the?
Scott: you know, if that can exist, why can't the oasis be bigger?
Rym: And part of I mean, why is there an oasis here?
Scott: Why can't there be an oasis two feet next to it?
Scott: What
Rym: part of the problem is that, you know, the Western world and the modern world, we advance and we go to these third world places where there's not a lot of existing infrastructure and we use our known existing solutions that while they work great in our industrialized societies, they rely so much on like petrochemical industry and, you know, steady streams, electricity and highly skilled manpower that they just they don't work in areas where that infrastructure doesn't exist and building that infrastructure out of nothing would be a gigantic catastrophe for a lot of reasons that I'm not going to get into.
Rym: So I think this is neat.
Rym: I don't want to spend more time on it now, but watch this video and it's a video is pretty yeah.
Scott: But once you sort of got to watch it for a minute before you figure out what's going on.
Rym: Yeah, the audio is good.
Scott: The slideshow is kind of the guy's a funny voice.
Scott: Yes, he does.
Rym: He's got a big chin, too.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So my thing of the day, I don't know how many people know about like RSA secure IDs.
Scott: Basically, the way they work is it's a little.
Scott: it's a little thing you put on your key chain and has an LCD screen and a battery and it generates a different random number everyone like 60 seconds, something like every minute, every.
Rym: it's like every six to 10 seconds, I think.
Scott: Anyway, you just you look at it and there's a number on it, right?
Scott: And you have a server somewhere.
Scott: you have to buy this server.
Scott: It's the expensive RSA like verification server.
Scott: And that also has numbers in it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And they're there to.
Scott: basically you have a little computer and a big computer both generating numbers.
Rym: They rely on precise timing and known seeds for random number generators so that whatever number is showing up on my completely separated key chain, the exact same number is ready for me and me alone to log into the server.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So I want to connect to my works server from home.
Scott: I look at my little key chain.
Scott: I type the number in and I push enter.
Scott: No, I also type in my name and password.
Rym: Well, now what you do is you type in a pin that is known only to you, something you know, and you type in the number on the key fob, something you have.
Rym: And then the two of those together, you know, two factor authentication.
Rym: It is incredibly secure.
Scott: Yeah, it's it's.
Scott: it's like your ATM card, you know.
Scott: Oh, someone knows my PIN number.
Scott: They don't have my card.
Scott: Someone has my card.
Scott: They don't know my PIN number.
Scott: Of course, something you have and something, you know, is like the ultimate insecurity.
Rym: I mean, well, the only thing on that is the the extension of something you have, which is something you are, you know, a.k.a.
Rym: biometrics.
Rym: Yeah, yeah.
Scott: But, you know, something you have something, you know, is fucking secure as long as the something you have isn't easily duplicated, like, say, a key like a physical key.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Or or in spy movies, you cut off the spy's finger, then you press it against the thing.
Rym: Right.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But an RSA key, unless a guy steals it from you, it even he does steal it from you.
Scott: He needs to know something he doesn't.
Rym: He has to know two things.
Scott: The key to your house.
Scott: He can open your house if he doesn't know your address.
Scott: He might know you're.
Rym: that's why people say you should never put your address on your key.
Scott: Well, definitely shouldn't do that.
Scott: That's that's just fucking stupid.
Rym: That's like putting your your PIN number.
Rym: I actually don't like your number.
Scott: You actually don't like how car keys sort of identify what kind of car they go with.
Scott: You know, it should just be a key.
Scott: It shouldn't have like, you know, a Ford logo on it.
Rym: Of course, we don't need to talk about the fact that all locks are, according to the Internet and a lot of study, trivially breakable and open by anyone who knows anything.
Scott: But anyway, there's a. there's a company called Yubico and I think they're a Swedish company.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And they made a thing called the Yubikey.
Scott: And you can just buy it.
Scott: You can buy these.
Scott: And I want to try to get 10 people to buy them.
Scott: That way I can get the price down by five bucks per key.
Scott: Basically, what this is is a lot like the RSA key.
Scott: Only better.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And how it works is it's a USB thingy.
Scott: So you put it in the USB slot and it has one button on it and you push the button instead.
Scott: And so you look at it and there's no like LCD screen on it.
Scott: So it doesn't need a battery like the RSA key does.
Scott: It's a lot smaller.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And basically you push the button and when you push the button, it's actually USB keyboard and it types in this number.
Scott: So if you open up your text editor and you push the button a few times, you'll see it type in these numbers every time you push the button.
Scott: And it's, you know, it's sort of like a one time pad, you know, sort of reading itself off.
Rym: Yes, I'll admit neither one of us has read like the white papers.
Scott: Yeah, it's not perfect.
Scott: I got to I got to read exactly how this works.
Scott: But, you know, I'm just doing it as a thing of the day for now, because we're very interested.
Rym: And believe me, once if we decide to buy these and we actually start using them or something, there will be a whole show dedicated to these.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: This is security now episode actually about it, too, where they talk to the person.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: If you want to if you want to find out our opinions on how secure they are, just listen to that security now, which we haven't listened to.
Rym: Right.
Rym: Because we'll just parrot whatever it says for the most part.
Scott: Probably.
Scott: So basically the way this works is you go to, say, you know, a website and you type in your username, you push this button and you're signed in as long as the website supports Yubikey.
Scott: Now, the thing is they somebody made a Yubikey open I.D.
Scott: thingy.
Scott: So any website you can use the Yubikey to log into open I.D.
Scott: and then use the open I.D.
Scott: to log into a site.
Scott: And they've also got it going with SSH and they've got it going with PAM, which means you can log into a Linux machine with it, you know, and it's pretty good stuff.
Scott: Now, the best part about this right is you buy these little keys, which are twenty five dollars, but it's twenty dollars if you order more.
Scott: this discount pricing for bulk orders and RSA.
Scott: If you want to buy RSA keys, you got to pay for the keys.
Scott: You got to pay for the server.
Scott: The server is like a bajillion dollars or you can't afford that.
Scott: It's got.
Scott: you know, you need to get this even with the 70 percent enterprise discount.
Scott: It's still too much money.
Rym: I'll sum this up.
Rym: Open source people will jump all over this most likely and you will be able to implement something that is very likely almost or as secure as RSA secure I.D.
Rym: on your own for very little money.
Scott: Actually, the server they've written it, the company that makes the keys wrote the server.
Scott: It's open source.
Scott: It's already.
Scott: you can just go and get it and work with it and, you know, sort of make, you know, anything you want work with Yubikey.
Scott: So it's just a matter of time for for more people to make it work with more things.
Scott: And even if it just works with open I.D.
Scott: and, you know, your Linux machines, that's enough to make it worth it, to make those things super secure.
Scott: Hells yeah, it is something to keep an eye on, especially if you're really concerned about security.
Scott: And because it's just a USB keyboard, it can work with any computer that has USB.
Scott: It doesn't freaking matter.
Scott: You don't need any special software or anything.
Rym: Scott, you got to get it to work on the Apple two GS.
Scott: It doesn't have USB.
Rym: Make a dongle.
Scott: I guess I can.
Scott: I have.
Scott: I have the USB to serial to Apple to modem port cable.
Scott: I guess maybe it would work.
Rym: Maybe you could use that analog game controller port.
Scott: I know because it wouldn't power it wouldn't.
Scott: it wouldn't work anyway.
Rym: So you might have noticed we went longer than usual for the whole show.
Rym: up to this point, because I guess it's you know, now that we have this half schedule, we had a lot of tech news and a lot of things in the day and things queued up.
Rym: So basically we got to this point where every topic we brought up was something we all have a lot to say about prior whole shows worth of stuff to say about.
Scott: So it's funny how that sort of happens unintentionally.
Rym: You know, it's good in a way, though, because it's not like the old days where we'd be scraping the bottom of the barrel for the Monday News every week.
Rym: We've been reading science articles.
Rym: We have no idea what they're about.
Rym: Like, yeah, this is awesome.
Rym: Sam a flange.
Rym: They invented a new one.
Scott: Sam a flange.
Rym: Sam a flange.
Scott: All right.
Rym: So so we were going to do this show on, you know, this whole show was supposed to be about, you know, hiring and I.T.
Rym: and CS.
Rym: Like, how do you not from the perspective of how do I get in a job in technology, even though that's what someone emailed us and asked us?
Rym: Yes, but we've done a bunch of shows about that, I'm pretty sure.
Rym: But the idea was on the other side, how do you pick out a good candidate for a technological technological job?
Scott: Because right now, you know, with the bad economies and whatnot, there are plenty of out of work tech peoples from various companies and they're looking for work, but most of them are no good.
Scott: So if you're at a company and you're hired, you know, you're looking for a tech person.
Scott: because even when the economy is bad, good tech people are hard to find and everyone needs them.
Scott: How do you know if a tech person is good or crappy?
Scott: It's very difficult.
Scott: Yes, very difficult.
Rym: And because we've been hiring people off and on and I've actually had the opportunity to be party to many interviews with potential candidates here.
Rym: And I sat in on one or two interviews at IBM and at the hospital.
Rym: And it's often very difficult to interview technological people, because on one hand, you want to vet their skills.
Rym: But on the other hand, I don't know, I've always felt awkward asking people very technical questions like, what's the command to do this?
Rym: or.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So you said, you know, this.
Rym: What are the four parts of the samoflage?
Scott: Yeah, it's like you like you either end up asking sort of like stupid like test questions for like shit in school, like, you know, what are the five aspects of blood?
Scott: It's like unless someone's just out of college, they don't know.
Scott: And whether they get the right answer or not doesn't show whether they actually know what they're doing or not.
Scott: And sort of, you know, to give someone a real test, you'd have to like put them in front of a computer and sort of watch them try to solve a problem of.
Scott: that is, you know, like the problem you want them to solve.
Rym: If you were to hire them, you really like when I ask questions like that, you always feel like you're kind of like you're implying straight up that you do not trust that the person is being forthright with their credentials.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like if the person was actually a good tech person, you ask that kind of question, they'd be stooped.
Scott: They'd be very annoyed.
Scott: Like Google asked me those kind of questions and they were like, don't look it up on Google.
Scott: So being honest, I didn't.
Scott: And they were the kind of questions you see on like a test in college, the kind of thing that nobody knows except for someone who just went to college.
Scott: And it just really it actually made me not want to work there because the questions were so insultingly annoying, stupid questions.
Rym: But what I've realized and what Scott's realized as time has gone on, that really the best way to interview tech people comes down to the simple truism of it takes one to know one.
Rym: And it seems like I found that if you're talking to someone and the best way to interview is just to try to talk to them as though you would talk to any of your technological friends, like just engage them the way you would engage anyone else you work with or anyone else, you know, who is technical and see if they reciprocate in kind or not.
Rym: I mean, and it's telling right away whether or not they know.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Like I could go up to someone and be like, yeah, have you have you ever heard of Django?
Scott: I'd be like, oh, man, it's got this, you know, great database object model.
Scott: It's pretty awesome.
Scott: And if he was just like, yep, that he's not demonstrating to me that he knows what I'm talking about.
Scott: But if I, you know, say things like that and they go, oh, yeah, you know, and it's all I've heard, you know, it's a lot like this other thing that has a whatever.
Scott: And they use also the complicated words that laymen wouldn't know.
Scott: And they use them correctly.
Scott: You know, they're demonstrating to you that they know what they're talking about.
Scott: Like I could go let's say I went to go interview for a job as like a carpenter.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And, you know, the carpenter, like, have you carpeted before?
Scott: Yes.
Scott: What carpeting have you done?
Scott: I built houses, you know, what houses did you build?
Rym: Big one.
Rym: Or consider the difference.
Rym: How many?
Rym: A hundred.
Rym: Consider the difference between these two questions.
Rym: Do you know your way around a samoflange?
Rym: Yes.
Rym: So do you prefer a samoflange or a blamoflange?
Scott: And why?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Or, you know, we use samoflanges here.
Scott: I like samoflanges because the name sounds better.
Scott: It rolls out the tongue.
Rym: But there's like.
Rym: I think like the most telling thing I ran into was that, you know, if I ask people questions that basically amount to how would you find something in a bunch of log files, you know, like a really simple question is one of those.
Rym: Do you actually know your way around the Linux command line?
Rym: or are you just saying you do because you installed Ubuntu once and it's what verbs do they use?
Rym: I mean, to many people I talk to who don't really know and, you know, further questioning proves that they don't really know will say, well, I would search through the logs and people who know would say, well, I'd grep for the unique idea in the logs.
Rym: And the fact that they use the verb grep instead of the verb search tells me more than any other.
Rym: like anything else I would have asked them.
Rym: That simple difference tells me right away if they're worth talking to.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: You basically have to ask them questions which require them to say the complicated, you know, insider words.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Like, you know, if you ask them, do you know C++, they'll be like, yes, I have 100 years experience in C++.
Scott: I'm a C++ master.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But if you're like, you know, in C++, you know, what kind of you know, what's your favorite X?
Scott: And they have to actually know what an X is.
Scott: And then, you know, name one and, you know, explain why it's their favorite.
Scott: Like, oh, I like the, you know, the the one in the STL because, you know, this reason or what, you know, they have to actually give a real answer.
Scott: that requires them to say like if you're in the carpeting, the same thing, you know, may ask someone a question where they actually are required to say something about like some sort of wooden structure, you know, as opposed to just saying, yes, I can build stairs, be like, you know, do you like to build stairs in, you know, which?
Scott: which style stairs do you like to build the most?
Scott: You know, it's like I need to know now.
Scott: I need to know different stair styles.
Scott: If I can't name a stair style, I'm fucked up like like.
Rym: So do you like to build staircases or stairwells?
Scott: Someone doesn't know the difference.
Scott: It's like a big trouble.
Rym: And like two questions in particular is like instead of saying, can you do you know your way around the Linux command line?
Rym: Can you work without a graphical environment?
Rym: Just ask.
Rym: So what text editor do you use or what shell do you prefer?
Rym: Because they might say, yeah, I know my way around Linux.
Rym: But if you ask them what shell they prefer, they've got to know the name of at least one shell.
Scott: They got to know what a shell is and they got to be able to name it.
Scott: You know, even if you ask a question like, do you like V.I.
Scott: or Emacs?
Scott: Well, they could just basically say, oh, I like Emacs or oh, I like V.I If you say what text editor to use, they need to know what a text editor is and they need to be able to name a text editor.
Rym: And yeah, and it's also very telling because if they say notepad, then I know better.
Rym: I know that they do not know.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: And if they say Pico, while Pico is silly, at least they know what a text editor is.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Sadly, that's pretty much it.
Scott: I think.
Scott: Well, I think the real problem is that if you want to hire a tech person.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But you don't already have a good tech person at your disposal.
Rym: Well, then you're screwed.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, I guess the only option there is to not go for the technical knowledge route, but to go for the.
Rym: is this person very smart route?
Rym: And it's not hard to figure out if someone is smart by interviewing them.
Rym: Just ask them difficult questions and see how they answer.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I think another good thing is if you you might not have like a tech person on staff, but, you know, there are plenty of tech people around who maybe you could like get them to help you out and, you know, be like, hey, is this person smart?
Scott: You know, here is like their resume, you know, or hey, is this person smart?
Scott: I recorded the interview with them.
Scott: Listen to this tape.
Scott: They said some complicated words there.
Scott: They bullshitting, you know, like an RIT when I said plenty of tech people on the Internet who will talk to you.
Rym: I sat in on interviews with like other people to work for the IT department and pretty much like they would always have people sit in and the hospital did the same thing, just technical people.
Rym: Or even when I interviewed at Nature magazine a long time ago, they had a tech guy just sit there.
Rym: He didn't ask any questions.
Rym: He just sat in the room while I talked to the big guy.
Rym: And the only purpose of these people is to after the person leaves, say, yeah, he knows what he's talking about.
Rym: or now he was just using buzzwords.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: And I guess it's really, really obvious to tech people.
Rym: And it's not obvious.
Rym: Well, I mean, it's obvious.
Scott: It's really, you know, we say tech because that's what we are, but it's the same in any profession.
Scott: I mean, if a graphic designer was interviewing, you know, some other graphic designer, they could tell right away if the person was saying like, you know, like, oh, man, what Photoshop filter do you use?
Rym: You know, it's like instead of tech, I guess experts, anyone who's an expert in their field can tell experts in their field from people who don't know their field at all.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Now, they can have a real problem.
Scott: if you have someone on your side who is actually a dumb ass, then a smart person comes along.
Scott: The dumb ass will think the smart person is a dumb ass.
Scott: And then you're sort of in a trap, which is, I think, another compounding reason why I.T.
Scott: and, you know, basically tech departments tend to either be all smart or all stupid.
Rym: Yeah, I very rarely run into a case because if it's all stupid, if a smart person gets hired by accident, they get the hell out.
Scott: That's right, because they get pissed off that everything is so stupid.
Scott: They get frustrated and they leave.
Rym: And if it's all smart people, well, the stupid person can't possibly get hired.
Rym: That's right.
Rym: So there's really no way to have a mixed bag I.T.
Rym: unless you have the giant bureaucracy that acts in such a capricious and random way that it hires a 50/50 balance.
Scott: Well, what you can have.
Scott: what can happen a lot of times is a company that has met is big enough as many tech departments.
Scott: So you'll get like this R&D department with all these smart people.
Scott: But then like the people who do all like, you know, the switching for the company network or complete retards, you know, stuff like that can happen.
Scott: But it's or maybe you get like a bunch of like the higher ups in the department.
Scott: You know, the department is so big.
Scott: Maybe the CTO and the developers are real smart, but the guys and help desk people are dumb, you know, stuff like that can happen.
Scott: But so honestly, the people actually work together in tech, you know, directly co-workers, you know, who see each other every day and sit next to each other or either all smart or all stupid, most likely.
Rym: The one thing I do want to bring up really quickly before I end this travesty and go to bed is that personality does count for a lot and don't sure does never pick the person who's perfect in every way.
Rym: If when you ask them what they do outside of work, don't have an answer.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Some guy comes in, you'd be like, you know, what's your favorite idea?
Scott: And he's like, oh, I like to use a clips, but real like text that, you know, he knows what he's talking about.
Scott: But then you'd be like, you know, what do you do after work?
Scott: He's like, oh, go home, watch TV, go to bed.
Scott: Don't hire that guy, because I mean, even if he's smart and maybe a work card, you know, is a really boring verse.
Rym: Well, there are two kinds of people who do not really answer when you ask them what they do outside of work.
Rym: One kind is the person who is doing something that they don't want their employer to know about, which is fine, because usually that's something really awesome.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like the guy's not going to tell you in a job interview that he runs the BDSM dungeon, even though if he does, you should probably hire him because he's totally cool.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: If I was interviewing someone for an I.T.
Rym: job and I was like, so what do you do outside of work?
Rym: And he was like, I run the BDSM dungeon down in Newport.
Scott: I'd be like, you're hired as long as you knew the tech he was talking about.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But I'm like, oh, so that's your hobby.
Rym: Anything else?
Rym: And like, yeah, I ski to, you know, people like that.
Rym: But most people I found who don't have an answer actually don't have an answer.
Rym: Like I remember back at the hospital, I was helping interview someone and they were pretty technically qualified.
Rym: But when I asked the guy what he did outside of work and he didn't really have an answer, like he didn't really do anything.
Rym: And the thing he said was, well, I don't really have any hobbies or anything.
Rym: And to which I that always just said.
Scott: that not only tells me that he's a boring person that you don't want to go on that.
Rym: I think.
Rym: So why are you getting a job like?
Rym: is work going to be your life?
Rym: What's your life?
Rym: You work because you have bills to pay to live your real life or have a job.
Rym: That's awesome.
Rym: And the job he was applying for was not awesome.
Rym: Therefore, and he didn't give off the vibe of like, I'm a Russian hacker who's escaping the law and I'm hiding my Russian hacking hobby.
Scott: I mean, if somebody doesn't have a, you know, a thing outside of work that they're working for, then either a their work is it, which means they better be, you know, they better be like the company owner or something where the work is their thing.
Rym: Or it's just that they're passionate about what they're doing.
Scott: Right.
Rym: No one's passionate about low level I.T.
Rym: Right.
Scott: Or or, you know, the question becomes, even if this person can do this job, what's their?
Scott: do they have any motivation?
Scott: Will they?
Scott: will they care that, you know, I mean, like I work because I can have money to do things outside of work.
Scott: If I didn't do anything outside of work, then why would I work?
Scott: I would just be a lazy as bum at work, not caring so much.
Scott: You know, if you have something else you care about and work supports that thing, then that caring transfers over to the work.
Rym: Plus, speaking from experience, the place I work now just is is so much more amazing in terms of just the level of intelligence at all levels compared to everywhere else I've worked and everything else I've ever done in, I guess, in official non GeekNights, you know, working in the real world capacity, which also includes most of my classes, you know, back in school.
Rym: But the one thing that really stands out is that every single person in the place I work, all the technical people, all the like H.R.
Rym: people, everyone, they have like big things they're doing outside of work, like things on the same level of GeekNights for me.
Rym: Like everyone, like they're doing their doctoral theses or they travel the world all the time or they're like a professional chef for fun on the side.
Rym: Like everyone has this full time hobby or this like really big family or something crazy outside of work.
Rym: And work is great and they love their work, but work is just one part of their lives.
Rym: And I noticed that most of the other places I've worked, work seemed to be the only thing these people had.
Rym: Yeah, people would stay late on purpose to not go home to the Y as opposed to staying late because they really want to finish that awesome piece of code they're working on for the algorithm.
Rym: Baphma dad.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: And on that note, I kind of want to go to bed.
Rym: I think we'll just stop it right there.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And if you're I guess, you know, for the people who are interviewing for jobs, just do in reverse.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: And if you have an awesome hobby, even if you think your employer might think it's bad, just let it out there because you don't hide anything.
Scott: Just answer every question completely openly and honestly.
Scott: And if they don't like your answer, you don't want to work there.
Rym: I used to hide GeekNights from employers.
Scott: I never hit anything I do.
Rym: And the fact that I now GeekNights like is I don't not like my resume, but GeekNights and like the anime convention stuff I do and even the anime club, they're all on my resume straight up.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: I mean, if you made some cool YouTube's slap that on there, you know, I mean, as well, I mean, it might, you know, don't slap on say on the video shotgunning nine beers while being tased.
Scott: Right.
Rym: But do unless you're going into a job that requires you to be able to act under pressure while being tased.
Scott: But if you made like a silly, you know, animation right of, you know, like, say, a video game character, say, mashed up with some anime you like, you know, it's like a little five second happy, cute, you know, even if it's a as long as it's a disgusting, you know, fortune kind of thing, be like, yeah, I make animations, you know, and that sounds really impressive, you know, even though they might in reality, it's fortune animations.
Scott: They will never.
Rym: I'll put it this way.
Scott: They will never check.
Rym: Pack packs is really fun.
Rym: And I'm really proud to have presented a discussion at the Penny Arcade Expo because not that many people get to do that.
Rym: But it sounds like putting on a resume or explaining it to someone who doesn't really know what conventions are like, it sounds so much more impressive than it is and things like.
Scott: things like what in reality we stood up in front of a room with one hundred, you know, peers in it and we said, hey, what's up, guys?
Scott: Check this out.
Scott: Burning wheel.
Scott: All right, let's go have fun.
Rym: Bye.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But just all the hobbies and things on this, I guess we're turning this back into the how to get hired.
Rym: All the things you do on the side always sound or actually are a lot more impressive to other people who haven't done them, because the more you do awesome things, the more you'll start to trivialize them in your own mind because they become easy for you.
Rym: I mean, if you're a juggler and you become an awesome juggler, things that are amazing to people who can't juggle, you don't even think about because you do them all the time.
Rym: So you'll start to forget how impressive they are to people who aren't kind of into that thing.
Rym: That's it.
Rym: Going to bed.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our Frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology.
Rym: Tuesdays we have video games, board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights and Thursdays are the catch alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an Odeo on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: For the complete archives, visit the website, which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution, non-commercial, share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit, don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.