Scott: It's Wednesday, October 15th.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Scott: I'm Rym.
Scott: And this is GeekNights.
Scott: Tonight, Politics in Manga.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: So if there's one thing that is a never-ending source of opening bits, it is the choo-choo train.
Rym: Oh?
Scott: Oh yes indeed.
Scott: I got on the train today.
Scott: A little earlier train than usual.
Scott: You know, the Super Express basically stops at our stop and nowhere else.
Scott: Well, it makes up after our stop, but whatever.
Scott: I got on, you know, a car and it was a hot car.
Scott: So I walked from one end of the hot car to the other and I sort of thought about maybe sitting at the other end of the hot car, but there was a bathroom at the other end of the hot car.
Rym: A hot car plus bathroom equals bad idea.
Scott: So I did not sit there.
Scott: I sat in the next car, right?
Scott: It was basically...
Rym: Wait, how could the car have been that hot?
Rym: It wasn't that hot outside.
Scott: It was a hot car.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I walked in and I was sweating my balls off and apparently everyone else was too because no one was sitting in that car.
Rym: Maybe the heat was on.
Scott: Maybe.
Rym: Maybe everyone's eye in that bathroom like a ticking time bomb.
Rym: Someone's going to open that door and people are going to die.
Scott: So I sat in the next car.
Scott: So between me and that nasty bathroom in the hot car was two vestibules.
Scott: basically, right?
Rym: Did something breach the vestibules?
Scott: Nothing breached.
Scott: Well, both vestibules.
Rym: There was a hull breach, I imagine.
Scott: There was indeed a hull breach.
Scott: You see, we were approaching Beacon Station.
Rym: Oh my God.
Scott: And I went to go wait in the vestibule, the vestibule of my car, not the vestibule of the other car.
Rym: But connected to that one.
Scott: Indeed, they were connected as train cars are connected with the big metal links.
Rym: If this was a space movie, you are in the airlock.
Rym: The cold death of space is outside, aka the hot car, possibly the aliens and lasers.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But when I got off the train or when I got really close to Beacon, it was pretty much just a flood.
Scott: It was just, it was just a straight up flood of water coming out of that bathroom.
Scott: And when the train, like when the train came in to stop, it was literally like a, like the sheet of like water just sort of came out into the vestibule and run.
Scott: And you know, it didn't come across the vestibules.
Rym: So you had that fire break between the car.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: It was just the sheet of water just came straight across and then down under the train.
Scott: Now you realize what this means because I've been in hot cars and half of the other car, you know, half of the car with the bathroom in it was just flooded with water like a centimeter deep.
Rym: Now, now see, I can see having the hot car that happened.
Rym: Surprisingly, the water looked clean, but at the same time, well, for it not to have been clean, someone had a real bad day.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I think it was just clogged and then filled up too.
Rym: Wait, but hot car is one thing.
Rym: Clogged bathroom is another thing.
Rym: Using the bathroom in the hot car has never in the history of hot car has been a good idea.
Rym: No bad idea.
Rym: Hold it in, seriously.
Rym: Go in the vestibule or something, but don't go in the hot car.
Rym: I imagine that was an Aaron Nardi situation right there.
Scott: It was, it was pretty funny just seeing this flood of water at the edge of the train, spilling out under the door.
Rym: Now here's the question.
Rym: Was anyone caught in the impact?
Scott: Well, there, you know, there was some people, was there the guy that the shell of burger going, ah, they weren't himself.
Scott: Well, there was no one holding themselves up, but there were, when the train came in for a stop, there were people who were waiting in that vestibule and they didn't seem to mind standing in this water.
Rym: I guess it didn't, you know, I would have been holding myself up by the rails and leaping out of the car without touching it.
Scott: The water looked clean and it didn't look like it was, you know, going above the sole of the shoe.
Scott: It wasn't that deep.
Scott: So I guess they just didn't mind.
Scott: And then they got off the train.
Rym: I guess if I was on a train car and suddenly the water came, all right, I could live with that, but the water out of the hot car, I don't know, the hot car bathroom, hot car bathroom, hot car bathroom, water flood.
Rym: Uh, Scott, I, there's a quest of you.
Rym: There's something that I can't believe hasn't come up yet.
Scott: Ah, it's in my raccoon wounds.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: All right.
Scott: So that was pretty funny.
Scott: I'm always laughing at things like that, like infinitely flushing toilets.
Scott: So this is funnier than that.
Rym: Even, you know, you may laugh you out there, not Scott, but if Scott sees an infinitely flushing toilet, he just starts cracking up.
Scott: It doesn't help that the one that the bathroom at work has a pro a toilet that frequently as infinite flushes.
Scott: All right.
Rym: So before we go any further, we should point out that this isn't like a quote unquote special episode of GeekNights.
Rym: Those are mostly the way the dodo, but this is a somewhat unique episode of GeekNights yet.
Scott: We don't do these things too often or hardly ever at all, but, uh, basically here's the deal, right?
Scott: People are listeners want us to talk politics, but I don't want to.
Scott: Rym does, but I don't want it.
Rym: I like to talk about some politics.
Scott: Uh, I like to talk about comics.
Scott: Comics are cool, right?
Rym: We don't do enough episodes about comics, but luckily, well, we were this week going to talk about, uh, a famous comic Scrooge McDuck.
Scott: We're going to do that next time.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But we had to put it off because of this.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So, uh, came along this opportunity to sort of do an episode.
Scott: that sort of politics sort of not.
Scott: And I said, okay, let's do this thing.
Scott: Why the hell not?
Scott: So what's going on is a whole bunch of comic podcasts, podcasts about comic books of various sorts have sort of teamed up for the month of October, you know, leading into the big election in the U S and early November to do a comics politics month.
Scott: Right?
Scott: So the idea is that all these podcasts in the month of October, we'll do an episode about politics and comics combined in some way.
Rym: And I said, you know, I just, I can't imagine there that many superhero comics that have anything non superficial to do with politics.
Scott: Well, if you want to find out, you know, plus, you know, not everyone's talking about superhero comics.
Rym: I know.
Rym: I'm just saying superhero comics.
Rym: I could talk about some V for Vendetta.
Rym: I think that's a very politically motivated coming.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: That's a good one to go for.
Scott: Um, so basically if you want to maybe the silver surfer, no, not really.
Scott: If you want to listen to a bunch of podcasts about politics and comics, uh, I'll provide you with some links that, you know, it's sort of like a tag team thing, you know, the cross promotion dealing.
Rym: Wow.
Rym: We're, we haven't done this sort of thing in a long time.
Rym: Remember the days of promos?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Forget those.
Scott: Um, but yeah, I'll link it to the cross promotion dealies.
Scott: You'll see us up there probably as soon as I give them the link to this show after he put it up and such.
Scott: And you know, if, if you're a, one of the people who's came here, not, you know, it was not a regular listener of our show, but as someone who listened to some other politic comic podcast and, you know, saw our link on this, one of these sites and came over, uh, just so you know, we're going to do news and things of the day.
Scott: And then we're going to talk about politics and manga, which is the topic that we have selected.
Rym: It's kind of our normal show format.
Scott: We've had some 600 episodes because, you know, the stuff that we're going to talk about politics and manga, we're basically going to be mostly focusing on a few politics, heavy manga series.
Scott: And our listeners have heard about those mostly already much.
Rym: anyone who saw, I don't know, the last four or five of our live appearances or anyone who's listened to the show for more than a year.
Rym: So it was probably heard everything we're about to say.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So, you know, to make up for the fact that we're doing sort of redundant show for our older existing listeners, you know, and, but even though it's a new show for these sort of cross promotion listeners, we're going to do a normal show where we do news and all that other business and then politics and manga.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So that's enough of that.
Scott: Uh, let's go to the news.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So what do you got for me?
Scott: What do I have for you?
Rym: There's pretty much nothing on the, I mean, I guess anime news network is pretty much my AP wire of anime news and I don't really pay attention to comic news unless you tell me about something.
Rym: So I basically had nothing.
Scott: Well, if you want comics news, you can go to like news around or whatever.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: If you want anime news is pretty much, uh, anime news network.
Scott: Um, so check this out.
Scott: This is sort of a video game news.
Scott: It came out of the Tokyo game show, but I think it's anime related enough to, to be said today, right?
Scott: Some people might not realize the studio Ghibli and level five are making a DS game, or it looks like to me, they've made a DS game.
Scott: Now there are two links for this.
Scott: One link is the trailer for this DS game video footage of the game.
Scott: And let me tell you, this is pretty impressive shit right here.
Scott: We're talking, you know, a whole lot of video as is to be expected, you know, animated video, sort of like professor Layton, but obviously Ghibli animation, not professor Layton animation.
Scott: Uh, and also, you know, we got Ghibli style music going on.
Scott: It's like, you hear this music and you're like, Oh, that sounds like the music for every Ghibli movie ever.
Scott: I could have told you right away.
Scott: Um, but yeah, the trailer is pretty impressive.
Scott: So that's one thing I'm linking to you for the news.
Scott: The other thing here, which is far more important than the trailer for this game, which, you know, of course you have to buy.
Scott: This is the, um, the, I don't know if it's exclusive or it's the default box the game comes in.
Scott: This is the most extravagant game box I've ever seen in my entire, the word ostentatious perhaps apply a double ostentatious, maybe, maybe epic.
Scott: It's like a spell.
Scott: First of all, this is spell book, right?
Scott: And the spell book has on each page of the spell book is some sort of, you know, you know how Castlevania had the runes that you would draw with the stylus.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: That got real old, real quick.
Scott: This has like one of these on each page of the spell book.
Scott: It's like an actual spell book.
Rym: So I can cast those spells.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Oh man.
Rym: I'm kind of down with that.
Scott: And then under the spell book is of course the game, but it comes in this big box that looks like a book and is all fancified and has, you know, like a felt fuzzy interior.
Rym: So the operative question, will the U S release of this game have the same box?
Scott: Is there going to be a U S release of this game?
Rym: I would probably buy it site on scene for anything less than a hundred dollars.
Scott: If I were you, I would just go to like, uh, NCSX or one of those, you know, video game import sites and preorder this shit from Japan for the hundreds of dollars it's going to cost you because probably should, you probably should.
Rym: It'll probably be worth it to own that thing.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, basically be buying the thing.
Rym: I can't read Japanese.
Rym: I'm not going to play the game.
Scott: I mean, when you see this thing, there's no way, if you're any sort of ghibli person, which is everybody in the world and you have a DS, how could you not go for this?
Scott: I would pay 200 bucks for it, but it's, you know, it's the trouble that I'd have to go through to pay the 200 bucks.
Scott: Then it's probably why I'm going to, I got some money.
Rym: I might just do it.
Rym: I'll let you all know how I turn out here.
Scott: All right.
Rym: But I got a little bit of news.
Rym: and this is, this comes partly after the fact that not that long ago.
Rym: Well, I guess it wasn't a while ago now, but anime Boston, the previous anime Boston had a little bit of trouble.
Scott: Well, anime Boston is sort of an infamous convention in that it's so close to us much closer than many other conventions such as, you know, uh, katsuka.
Rym: And yet not only have we never performed at anime Boston, we've never gone to anime Boston.
Rym: I've never been to Boston.
Scott: I've never been to Boston.
Scott: I've been to Boston like a hundred times, but I've never been to anime Boston.
Rym: I went north and south and north and south.
Scott: We should take an extra day off so you can see the Boston.
Rym: I actually plan to take several days off around it because I want to go see Steve.
Scott: Yeah, we can see Steve.
Scott: I haven't seen him in, uh, probably be working though.
Rym: Hi, whatever.
Rym: He'll take time off.
Scott: All right.
Rym: But, uh, anime Boston, you know, we, we talked about the news of the previous anime Boston and I don't need to get into that.
Rym: And of course, several anime Boston staff contacted us on the low down and kind of told us what the real deal was.
Rym: And we talked about that a bit, but I remember I said, Oh yeah, well, you know what, maybe we should go to anime Boston next time and, you know, do a bunch of panels and stuff.
Rym: Well, the staff is together and nothing is set in stone yet, but it is highly likely we are going to be at anime Boston most likely as guests or in the least as kind of, I don't know, built in panelists doing a whole bunch of our usual shtick.
Scott: That is a very nice, yeah.
Rym: Cause anime Boston, I don't think I don't want a table or anything.
Rym: We're pretty much just going to do live shows.
Rym: Maybe we should dust off some of the, uh, old classics just because this Con will have a lot of people who have never seen this before.
Scott: I don't know if I want to dust off any class.
Rym: Well, I don't want to dust off get geeky guy.
Rym: No, we have some other classics.
Rym: We could whip out.
Scott: There are definitely some panels that we could be running there and you know, maybe we'll just, you know, the, the conventions in what may, I think it's in may something.
Scott: we'll have panels set up by may and that'll be good practice for June, July, Otakon, right?
Scott: Otakon is going to be July this year, isn't it?
Rym: Yup.
Rym: And we're already setting that stuff up.
Rym: And of course, ConnectiCon next year.
Rym: I don't know if you talked about this yet, but there will be big, big announcements and changes in ConnectiCon.
Rym: And thus my second news, if you know anyone who you think should speak at ConnectiCon, which is not really an anime convention, it's more of a geek convention has a lot of webcomic stuff, but it has a lot of gaming and a lot of anime convention.
Rym: There's a lot of comic people there.
Rym: It's kind of a pretty much anyone who listens to GeekNights would have a good time at ConnectiCon, but it's everything but tech.
Rym: If you can think of anyone, I don't know, either professional or industry or a professor, anyone who you think could give what I would call an erudite panel.
Rym: We are putting out the kind of initial call for speakers.
Rym: So email us, email ConnectiCon, email someone, it'll get back to us.
Scott: We're not looking for the fan panels yet.
Scott: We're looking for the quarity panels.
Rym: The farrier panels, I believe is the word.
Scott: Yes, that is the word.
Rym: So is there any other anime news?
Scott: No, it's, it's really, you know, and Oh, Toonami died.
Scott: Did I talk about that before?
Rym: I don't think we did.
Scott: It's dead.
Rym: You know what?
Scott: Toonami died.
Scott: I could do a whole show on, let's do a whole show on it and then skip on it for now.
Rym: Wait, I can do the whole show right now.
Rym: Toonami died the day.
Rym: Moltar was no longer the host.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: And the body just spasmed for many years afterwards.
Rym: I'd say that I would miss it, but I missed it a long time ago.
Rym: Hey, that music played.
Rym: Now we have a lot of people listening who probably have never listened to GeekNights before.
Scott: This is sort of a waste.
Rym: Yeah, but I feel like I should at least explain a little bit things of the day.
Rym: The bit we're about to do is pretty simple.
Rym: We talk about the thing of the day, the thing that in the last 24 hours or so has somehow impressed us more so than other things we've seen.
Rym: That's the extent of our bid.
Rym: We don't do so many kind of bits on this show, despite the original plan back in like 2005.
Scott: Now, maybe we'll get around to that someday.
Rym: So Scott, what is your thing of the day?
Scott: Well, you know, the guys from Engadget, the former guys from Engadget, you know, the Peter Rojas and the Ryan Block, they're doing their new GDGT thing.
Scott: Their podcast is back up and running.
Scott: You know, used to be the Engadget podcast, now is the GDGT podcast.
Scott: And the opening music for that was pretty cool.
Scott: Maybe we'll play it right now.
Scott: Or maybe we won't.
Scott: We'll find out if Rym decides to paste it in there.
Scott: But basically it's a pretty cool song and I was grooving to it.
Scott: So I went to find out what it was and, you know, I wanted to download it, of course.
Scott: And I found a free and legal way to download it.
Scott: Wouldn't you know, there's apparently some sort of, at least it looks like a record label called Ghostly International and some sort of record label.
Scott: And they had a little partnership with Adult Swim.
Scott: So on Adult Swim dot com, there's an album called Ghostly Swim.
Scott: And you can just download this whole album for free on their website.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And it's got a whole bunch of music that I kind of like, sort of ambient, you know, sort of electronic ish, groovy music, a little Halloween vibe, a little ghostliness.
Scott: And the I really like the first track.
Scott: The first track's pretty great.
Scott: The GDGT theme song track is the final track, which is Night Court by Muxmool.
Scott: And there is also a couple exclusive videos there for, in fact, those two songs.
Scott: The first track, which is Triple Chrome Dipped by Mitchna, I think.
Scott: And there's, you know, there's two music videos and a whole album of free music.
Scott: I like it.
Scott: Why not?
Scott: Legitimately, legally free.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So it's very rare.
Rym: I mean, there was the big Webcomics boom, but it's been a very rare circumstance where I would, I guess, add a Webcomic to my repertoire.
Rym: And what have we added since the boom?
Rym: Dr.
Rym: McNinja, XKCD, Order the Stick, Anime News Nina, I guess that's pretty much it.
Rym: But it just so happens that there is a new Webcomic and a new Webcomic that I probably should have known about.
Rym: Well, there are new Webcomics every day.
Rym: Well, I should qualify that statement.
Scott: A new Webcomic we care about is this news.
Rym: Let me add another where clause to this SQL statement.
Rym: Basically, this Webcomic, Johnny Wander, is new.
Rym: And it happens to be by Yuko and Anath, two very close friends of ours and, in fact, members of the Front Row Crew.
Scott: Oh, we're biased.
Scott: You can't take us, our review, seriously.
Rym: I can say one thing.
Rym: Yuko was Internet famous in the past for her Webcomic Fallen, which was kind of frighteningly popular to the point that even after she stopped updating it for a long, long time, she still to this day has fans and still to this day.
Scott: You know that if we stopped doing GeekNights, we would have the same situation.
Rym: Except multiply that by a magnitude or two.
Rym: And that's the number of people who still email her about this comic.
Scott: Really?
Scott: Could it be that many?
Rym: Well, I don't think you understand how many people read her.
Rym: More people read her live journal than listen to us.
Rym: But anyway, she stopped doing that, you know, college and all that.
Rym: Now, the other person involved in this, Ananth, he's half of Apple Geeks.
Rym: You may have heard of it.
Rym: It's somewhat popular out here.
Scott: Yeah, more popular than us, at least.
Rym: And basically this comic, the part of the reason I bring it up is that I find it funny into it's about them.
Rym: They are characters in it.
Rym: So it's them and our friend Conrad and, you know, some other.
Scott: It's a lot like, you know, it's artistically, it's not like real life comics, but, you know, the kind of comic it is, is like real life comics where it's just funny anecdotes from their everyday lives.
Scott: And because I know them, I know a lot of these events was perhaps there for some of them and such.
Scott: So it's.
Scott: it is double hilarious for us.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: It's kind of funny to me in the same way that bad boys in computer science was funny to me because it's bad boys in computer science had shit art compared to.
Rym: Yes, it did.
Rym: That is the one I could do.
Scott: I could do art better than BBOCS.
Rym: By the way, BBOCS author still owes me.
Rym: Nick, you fuck you owe me five bucks, dude.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: Seriously, I want it back.
Scott: I do.
Scott: I want my two dollars back.
Rym: But this is my thing of the day because I'm friends with them.
Rym: But, you know, they all move to DCs.
Rym: I haven't really.
Rym: I didn't talk to them in a relatively short span.
Rym: And I find out suddenly that they're doing a webcomic.
Rym: I have to call them and ask about this webcomic.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: And also, I want to say one thing.
Rym: If you do happen to read it, the Conrad in it is exactly like that in the real world.
Scott: He's also in our forum.
Scott: You can talk to him.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: In fact, all these people are in our forum anyway, except for John.
Scott: John.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I don't know John that well.
Rym: I can't say anything about him other than that.
Rym: He's very tall.
Scott: I've only heard of this person second hand.
Rym: He is very tall.
Scott: He is very tall.
Scott: I know.
Scott: I think I met him once at a dim sum.
Rym: So that was things of the day.
Rym: I guess we can move on to this.
Rym: The main bit.
Rym: So old listeners, you've heard all this before.
Scott: Yeah, you can stop listening.
Scott: New listeners.
Scott: Hello.
Scott: We'll teach you now about politics and manga.
Scott: Now, before we're going to do is I want to talk about politics and manga a little bit generally, and then I want to talk about a few specific political mangas.
Scott: So first thing you got to know about politics when it comes to manga is that nothing is realistic.
Scott: I mean, a lot of times you'll see and say, you know, American storytelling.
Scott: more often, you know, for example, politics on TV.
Scott: A lot of times they try to pretend to be realistic.
Scott: Like look at a movie like Dave.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I like that movie a lot, but it tries to pretend or put on the air is that this could really happen.
Scott: or we're trying to make some sort of representation of how things really are.
Scott: Manga, not so much, at least not the political manga I've read.
Scott: They just go if they sort of treat politics the way Harry Turtle Dove treats history.
Rym: Well, you know, see, it depends because the I guess the skew here is that manga that are released in America are not exactly representative of, I guess, the whole of manga.
Scott: That is true.
Rym: I mean, there are manga about golf that are Kazuo Koike and there are manga about golf that are about golf in a literal probably Jack Nicklaus Tiger Woods fashion.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: I'm sure there are political manga that are just like.
Rym: there's probably something about like Barack Obama.
Scott: Well, I mean, Obama, I don't know.
Scott: I mean, technically speaking, right.
Scott: A manga is just, you know, Japanese comics.
Scott: I'm sure that there are political comics, you know, political commentary comics, just like we have, you know, political cartoons in the Japanese newspapers.
Scott: So would those not count as political manga?
Rym: Well, yes, yes, they would.
Scott: Yeah, I got to go find some now because I've never seen one of my entire life.
Scott: But it it reasons to be that they should exist now.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: It's just sadly, I mean, even well, double sadly, one, we don't see stuff like that in America.
Rym: And two, even the stuff that is good and is political that we're going to talk about is for the most part out of print and none of you will be able to read it.
Scott: Yeah, that's that is really sad.
Rym: Luckily, one of them is very easy to get, at least.
Scott: Yeah, no, but all the political manga that get translated into English, right, either a have a lot of stuff going on with sort of world politics that someone from the U.S.
Scott: can, you know, have be more involved in it, you know, relate to it better, or they have a lot of sensationalist things going on.
Scott: So you can relate to it even though the politics is foreign to you, because Japanese politics is really foreign to anyone who is in Japanese.
Scott: I mean, it's crazy.
Scott: I mean, you know, for the most part, the Japanese political system is parliamentary, only they call it the diet, not the parliament.
Scott: And it works somewhat similar to the way it does in, you know, other parliamentary countries like Canada or Britain.
Scott: But that's that's only on the most surface and basic levels.
Scott: Really, Japanese politics are crazy.
Scott: They got like all these different prefectures and American politics is crazy.
Rym: They get all these states.
Rym: I know I don't get that crap.
Rym: It's bullshit.
Scott: No, but like the laws about how you're allowed to campaign and, you know, the types of scandals and the things are gone with the types of scandals you're allowed to have.
Rym: But we're not going to talk about it.
Scott: Well, wait, that's the same is true here.
Rym: We're not going to talk about Japanese politics.
Rym: We're talking about Japanese comics, about politics.
Rym: And the other thing I'd like to say is that a lot of Japanese political comics, at least the ones we've read and like and are going to talk about, are really sensationalistic and over the top.
Rym: But one in particular is actually not.
Rym: And other than the drama that is added is incredible.
Rym: Well, it's weird.
Rym: It's incredibly realistic, like so perfectly accurate as to what actually goes on in one sense.
Rym: And yet in this other sense, completely wrong.
Rym: But the part is right about is the part I wish it was wrong about the part it was wrong about.
Rym: I wish it was right about.
Scott: No, I wish that was true for many things.
Rym: Oh, my God.
Rym: We'll talk about that.
Rym: one last, I think, because this is the most political of the political.
Rym: I keep wanting to say podcast.
Rym: The alliteration is too strong.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: The one thing I think, though, is like, you know, I'm sure they must exist.
Scott: But, you know, the political manga is actually seen to be like literal stories about politicians.
Scott: It's like a straight up drama.
Scott: But all the characters are, you know, senators or congresspeople or people running for president or people running for office or something, you know, something along those lines.
Scott: In fact, I think all three of these involve elections in some way.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: I mean, one of them is called the first president of Japan.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: They're all about, you know, elections and such.
Scott: And I don't you know, there are plenty of comics outside of Japan that deal with politics.
Scott: You know, political cartoons are in every country.
Scott: I've already discussed that, but not too many of them have straight up stories about politicians that are long running serial dramas.
Scott: I mean, there might be one out there, but I've never seen one.
Scott: You know, European comics.
Scott: Most of the ones I see are like histories or fantasies or sci fi or are those sorts of things.
Scott: You know, American comics, of course, are mostly superheroes.
Scott: Sometimes there are politicians in the superhero stories like there's always that one senator fucking with the X-Men and, you know, the president sometimes gets involved.
Rym: But but they're always like this side thing or they're there, but they're they're shallow.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like, you know, Marvel.
Scott: Civil War is not a political story.
Scott: It's just the government is involved.
Scott: The government is a character is a player in the greater story tries to have this sort of political.
Rym: It kind of pulls the V for Vendetta sort of, you know, there are the two kind of extremes and then they basically use that to make the superhero comic seem different, right?
Scott: It may have a political message, but it's not about politicians.
Scott: Politicians do not comprise the majority of the main characters.
Scott: But, you know, it's not a story about running for office or getting a bill passed or political maneuvering, you know, in a real world government.
Scott: It's it's something else.
Rym: But I will say this.
Rym: The three comics we really want to talk about tonight, the politicians in them are superheroes, but their special moves are not punch.
Rym: They are dramatic.
Rym: speech or ate that cake.
Scott: I was going to make a joke about cake, but you right then.
Scott: But you got me.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So let's get a move on.
Rym: Let's start with the simplest one to talk about.
Rym: Also, the one that's probably the most dramatically dramatic.
Rym: It's all about the first president of Japan, which is basically a fanboy masturbatory session about the way Japanese politics should be if the world was awesome.
Scott: First president of Japan is a story because, you know, Japan, like I said, is a prime minister and a parliament.
Scott: So this is a story about, you know, what if it's sort of an alternate future kind of thing where?
Scott: what if Japan had a president instead of a prime minister?
Scott: They switched up their whole government and fixed the whole thing to make it awesome.
Scott: And then even though crazy shit went down, like war between China and Taiwan and such, Japan was in there and everything was all right because that president of Japan was so awesome.
Rym: But not just him.
Rym: Everyone is awesome.
Rym: And that's what makes this.
Rym: This is basically I would almost call it a superhero comic straight up, except instead of spandex, they all wear suits.
Rym: It's just it's so it's so over the top.
Rym: And yet nothing happens.
Rym: that is in any way like metaphysical or superpowers.
Rym: It's just it's over the top.
Rym: in this way that manga is very good at doing.
Rym: And American comics aren't as well, I guess, mainstream American comics by and large are not as good at doing well.
Scott: Much like, you know, DMZ, an American comic where it sort of has like this ludicrous political situation of, you know, the majority of the United States having a giant civil war with, you know, the official United States and then having a DMZ in New York City.
Scott: Sort of a ludicrous situation.
Scott: First, President Japan is also a ludicrous situation, but in the ludicrous situation, you know, within that context, if you ignore the fact that the context is unreasonable, what happens within the context makes sense, you know, in the setting.
Scott: And it's super dramatic and super awesome.
Rym: The context is not that unreasonable.
Scott: The way that it's not as unreasonable as DMZ, but it's still unreasonable.
Rym: It's not that unreasonable.
Rym: What is unreasonable is the way the people who are the characters react to this situation.
Rym: It is the kind of thing, you know, in history, you always read.
Rym: any time you read a history book, there's always kind of the linchpin historical moment, the point where something, you know, awesome or dramatic could have happened.
Rym: But more often than not, the lame thing happens instead.
Rym: The guy surrenders, the guy makes the blunder, the king gives up.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Instead of, you know, something awesome happening, like someone going, ha ha.
Scott: And then, oh my God, everything's fixed.
Scott: You know, it's usually status quo maintained.
Scott: Nothing to see.
Scott: Nothing to see here.
Scott: Everybody go home.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I mean, of course, my favorite moment is, well, maybe not because he lost, but when the last empire emperor of Rome cast off his regalia and flung himself into the fighting to die, that was a good, he could have just totally surrendered or ran away and just disappeared in history.
Rym: But no, he had to do the thing.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But first president of Japan, basically, it's not just OMG Japan as a president.
Rym: It's all right.
Rym: Japan is going to have a president very soon.
Rym: We're in the process of doing this transition.
Rym: Oh shit.
Rym: China invades Taiwan.
Rym: North Korea goes all berserk.
Rym: Oh man, everything's going crazy.
Rym: And maybe we should give up the US Japan defense thing and section nine and have a military and, oh crap, there's a new coming.
Rym: What do we do?
Rym: I'm going to stand here.
Rym: It's a done and I know it.
Rym: And that's pretty much all that goes on.
Scott: That's something important to mention here because it's sort of central to all of Japanese politics.
Scott: is way back when Japan, after world war two, you know, Japan became, you know, good, right?
Scott: You know, in the Japanese constitution, there is, you know, a section that says you Japan cannot have a military.
Scott: They can have, you know, and, you know, over time, basically the situation is that Japan can have the Japanese self-defense force.
Rym: So even that is actually a kind of a stretch.
Scott: It is.
Scott: It's sort of as loophole.
Scott: It's sort of a, well, the thing is, it's the kind of thing a Supreme Court might interpret as being unconstitutional.
Rym: It's kind of a loophole.
Rym: It's one of those things where everyone involved says, you know what?
Rym: It's best to just keep it the way it is.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Basically, Japan has a military force, the Japanese self-defense force.
Scott: that is not allowed.
Scott: It's not allowed to project, not only by, you know, and it's not, you know, some international law that says Japan, you can't project your military force.
Scott: It's a Japanese law that says Japan cannot project its own military force.
Scott: Imagine if the US Constitution said the US is not allowed to attack anybody.
Scott: All US military forces have to stay in the United States, and they can only do anything if it means physically protecting the United States from physical attacks.
Scott: And, you know, in Japanese politics, especially if you're doing, you know, dramatic Japanese political manga, the question of whether or not to keep or get rid of, you know, this, you know, section of the constitution is pretty big deal.
Rym: It's also, remember, a lot of the people who read a lot of these comics are military fanboys or otaku of some degree.
Rym: And one of the kind of ultimate fantasies of these people is Japan gets rid of Article 9 and becomes totally awesome.
Scott: Cause the thing about Japan has wicked awesome technologies.
Scott: You know, they were one of the most advanced places technologically on earth.
Rym: That's actually one of the plot points in first president of Japan, where Japan has the, I think the, some special AWACS or the Aegis cruisers, where they know where all the Chinese nuclear subs are in the straits of Taiwan.
Rym: And the US doesn't have the capability to detect them quickly enough.
Rym: And Japan makes a secret deal with the US to totally tell them where they are.
Rym: And then there's this great scene where the Chinese military guy who was just seized power because there's a coup in China is like, OMG, nuke subs.
Rym: And then his advisor is like, ah, we haven't heard from them in a while.
Rym: I'm sure everything's okay, but, uh, uh, we don't know where they are.
Rym: Things aren't going so well.
Scott: Oh no.
Rym: I don't want to be the one to tell you this.
Scott: You can see how bring section nine into it, you know, with the technological superiority.
Rym: Article nine is something else.
Scott: Section nine, lol.
Rym: Article nine, quote, aspiring sincerely to an international peace based on justice and order, the Japanese people forever renounce war as a sovereign right of the nation and the threat or use of force as a means of settling international disputes.
Rym: in order to accomplish the aim of the proceeding paragraph, land, sea, and air forces, as well as other war potential will never be maintained.
Rym: The right of belligerency of the state will not be recognized.
Rym: That's pretty straightforward.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: There's not a real lot of interpretation there.
Scott: I was going to see how the Japanese self-defense force is unconstitutional.
Rym: I was going to quote it sooner, but, uh, I kept finding the Japanese and it was basically Kanji Kanji Kanji Kanji Kanji Kanji Kanji.
Scott: So you can see why this is a pretty easy thing to tell a dramatic story about.
Scott: Cause you know, any story about someone pushing for a constitutional management is going to be pretty high energy, pretty fantastic.
Scott: And then you throw in the high technology, you throw in, you know, the international war, you already got three pretty big aspects to lean on is going to be good stuff going on, especially for the military fan boys who want to see crazy high-tech Japanese military of awesomeness satellite lasers and shit
Rym: like that.
Rym: All three of these comics have something in common and that they basically they're character driven more than like that.
Rym: You're not going to see a lot of the fighting or the action or any of that.
Rym: You'll see those as kind of establishing shots, but all the real action scenes, like the war is not tanks fighting with tanks and fighter jets fighting with fighter jets.
Rym: It's the president watching his monitor and talking to people, the military dictator watching his monitor and talking to people, the president of Taiwan, totally talking in a secret chat room onto internet with the president of Japan.
Rym: That was a great scene.
Rym: They're just totally talking in this like political forum about what they're going to do and all the, and they read what all the other people say, but no one else knows that it's actually them.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: So first president of Japan, I think it's three volumes.
Rym: I think at least three.
Rym: It's 176 pages.
Scott: I think 176 pages is just one volume, right?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Rym: Just volume one.
Rym: I'm sorry.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I pulled up the wrong webpage.
Rym: It's written by Kadaka Yoshiki who honestly, I don't know that much about compared to the other people we're going to talk about.
Scott: Yeah, but yeah, the art is pretty standard art.
Scott: You know, they look like people.
Scott: It's not anything that's going to blow you away or anything like that.
Rym: Political people.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: It's just a bunch of it's drawings of guys in suits, drawings of boats, really, really dramatically fist out mouth open scowling.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You know, pictures of flags and missiles and that sort of thing, you know, and you, it's as out of print.
Scott: It was published by Raijin comics.
Scott: It's one of those dealies.
Scott: Um, it's these little tiny blue books.
Scott: You should be able to find them.
Scott: They're in English.
Rym: You'll find them in the dollar bid at a comic con for a dollar.
Scott: You're not going to find them on the shelf because they're out of print for quite a while, but in there, in every discount bin of manga I've ever seen, I've seen first presence of Japan.
Scott: It's an easy pickup.
Rym: I'll put it this way.
Rym: And I'm not going to try to sell it to you, but it's so cheap that even if you end up hating it, it's totally worth the money.
Rym: And you're probably not going to hate it because it's a, it's a, it's a ride to put it gently.
Rym: It is real fun.
Scott: It's not like something epic and amazing.
Rym: It's not, you know, one of the greatest comics of all time, but it's definitely the Tom Clancy slash West wing version of this sort of thing.
Rym: Absolutely.
Scott: All right.
Rym: So shall we talk about, uh, the one, well, we can talk about the one that is much more relevant, but at the same time, which cannot be obtained, I don't know.
Scott: Let's talk about sanctuary.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: So sanctuary, I'm sorry, is so out of print.
Rym: It took us a long time to get ahold of all of it.
Rym: And the sad thing is we've been talking about, we've, we've done live shows and like every con we go to about sanctuary.
Scott: We do more.
Scott: There's, I think sanctuary, we, if you take all the talking about manga we've done, I think more than 33% of the manga talk we have done is just promoting sanctuary.
Rym: And it is, it's not like it's the best manga in the world.
Rym: It's actually not even close to that.
Rym: But the thing is of this kind of manga, it's one of the only ones that's ever been released in America.
Scott: So sanctuary can best be described as a political erotic thriller, right?
Rym: If that sounds up your alley, this is up your alley in a way you can't imagine.
Scott: This is pretty much the best political erotic thriller I've ever seen.
Rym: It's, it's pretty much the story.
Rym: And again, it's similar in terms of, I guess the way it's presented to like first president of Japan, but it's much more realistic in many ways, but at the same time, it still definitely has that unrealistic, dramatic little to it.
Rym: The story is basically about Japan is a kind of corrupt, slow moving political system.
Rym: The Japanese people are complacent and these two kids were unrelated.
Rym: Their parents work in Cambodia.
Rym: One thing leads to another, their parents are murdered and they end up barely surviving the killing fields.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: They, they returned to Japan as young kids.
Rym: They're, you know, they get foster families, they're enrolled into school and they decide that because of their experiences and because of the way the people of Japan are versus the way they should be, that they are going to dedicate the rest of their lives to changing Japan in a fundamental way.
Rym: And the way they decide to do this is that they draw lots.
Rym: One of them will take the high road, will stay in school.
Rym: We'll get supported by the other one.
Rym: We'll go to college.
Rym: We'll join the political system.
Rym: We'll do whatever it takes, no matter what they have to stoop to, no matter how high, they will enter politics and they will become prime minister.
Rym: The other one is going to drop out of school, join the Yakuza, do whatever it takes, no matter how low they have to sink to become the head of the Yakuza and then use all of that money and all of that power to prop the first one out.
Scott: So it's the ultimate tag team.
Scott: You basically have the king of all the crime and then the king of all the government.
Scott: So it's like you become the king of the Yakuza.
Scott: I'll become the prime minister and we'll take over this whole country.
Scott: Let's say they both teamed up and went into politics together and didn't do the Yakuza thing, right?
Scott: Well, being prime minister, the head of the Yakuza has a lot of control over what goes on.
Scott: They can blackmail you and all these horrible things.
Scott: Just controlling the Yakuza, well, that's also not so good.
Scott: The government, the police can come cracking down on the Yakuza and take you out.
Scott: So you need to control both these things.
Scott: If you control both these things, you can control the above world and the underworld.
Scott: And no one can stop you.
Rym: And let me tell you, is this and I mean, if you read FPOJ with the first president of Japan, it's easy to get the level of style and sophistication and subtlety and just storytelling and art and everything is an order of magnitude above.
Rym: This is this is an ultimate banger.
Scott: We're looking at the writer of Sanctuary, Isho Fumimura, aka Buronsan, aka the guy who worked on Fist of the North Star.
Scott: No can.
Scott: So you take that and then take the artist, Ryuichi Ikigami, the artist of, you know, Crying Freeman and such and Samurai Crusader, Samurai Crusader is awesome.
Scott: It is.
Scott: And put them together on a team.
Scott: And Sanctuary is the ultimate genius that is produced.
Scott: Sanctuary is how many volumes is?
Scott: it's a lot of volume.
Rym: eight, I think eight or nine.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, isn't it more volumes in Japan than the US?
Rym: I always forget.
Rym: It doesn't mention that like anyone out there is going to actually be able to read it.
Scott: This is like wicked out of print.
Scott: But if you see it, pick up whatever volume you can, even if it's just ten copies of volume one, just buy all of them.
Scott: Anything it takes to get volumes of Sanctuary just hoard them and then we'll all distribute them amongst people who, you know, we know are good for it.
Scott: That's the current plan.
Rym: Anyone who is a little underhanded because it's so out of print.
Rym: There are torrents out there.
Rym: I have seen entire collections of translated or scanned Sanctuary out there.
Scott: Yeah, I would not consider it amoral to even though it might technically be illegal to go and get those.
Rym: But I mean, the kinds of scenes.
Rym: I mean, this is a manga where a cruise ship is filled with Yakuza.
Rym: You know, there's Yakuza over another part of Japan and they're causing trouble.
Rym: So what does the awesome Yakuza do?
Rym: They fill up an entire cruise ship with Yakuza and just park it off the coast.
Rym: And there's this beautiful two page spread of just a lot of very intimidating looking men standing there, looking dramatic over the edge of this cruise ship and a bunch of other very angry, imposing men looking very angry and somewhat frightened, looking up at this cruise ship going, oh, shit.
Scott: The earlier volumes concentrate a lot more on the Yakuza stuff because it takes time to move up in, you know, the actual a lot longer to move up in the actual government than it took to move up in the Yakuza.
Scott: You know, because all this time, you know, because they got one guy dropped out of school and immediately went in the Yakuza.
Scott: He's been moving up for quite some time.
Scott: The other guy was still going through school, graduating, you know, working his way up, you know, into being like an assistant of, you know, some dead men.
Scott: And, you know, it takes a lot longer to move up in that area.
Scott: So the earlier volumes concentrate a lot more on the Yakuza action.
Scott: But later on, it's they really become intertwined and the politics get pretty heavy.
Scott: You've got making coalitions, breaking coalitions, making alliances with other dead men, trying to win elections, trying to lose.
Rym: all those disenfranchised and just, you know, completely apathetic junior senators end up getting inspired and drunk and go off with those biker gang kids.
Scott: And there are so many just amazing, iconic scenes in this manga, expose people, exposing other people's scandals, you know, taking, you know, get people getting dirty money, getting clean money.
Rym: The gecky guy thing.
Rym: I mean, there there's this great scene where a big scandal is exposed.
Rym: They're like, you blah, blah, blah.
Rym: Yakuza something connection, blah, blah, blah.
Rym: And the political guy basically looks at the camera and all the press and says, Yep, what of it?
Scott: Oh, snaps.
Rym: And no one knows what to do.
Rym: And then all hell breaks loose.
Scott: I mean, like every time, you know, you know, a politician's act in the world, right?
Scott: Someone says a scandal and they go and they'll say something like either, you know, I'm deeply sorry for the blah, blah, blah.
Rym: Imagine if Bill Clinton had said, Yep, it sucks.
Rym: But you know what?
Rym: I did it.
Rym: Here's pictures.
Scott: No, even better.
Scott: What if?
Scott: what was his name?
Scott: Elliot Spitzer was like, Yeah, I had a bunch of hookers in the hotel.
Scott: It was hot.
Scott: That's basically that's what sanctuary is like.
Rym: I mean, the thing is, if you need any sort of quick impression, there there is a scene where there's a kind of a young member of the Yakuza who who's you know, he works with the main characters and he has his young wife and all this sort of thing.
Rym: You like this guy a lot, but there's a question that is asked, which is why did you become a member of the Yakuza?
Rym: Why did you choose this life?
Rym: And there's this whole scene where they look down at all the people walking in the streets, the salarymen that just the normal everyday people so apathetic, so insulated from the real world, so uninspired.
Rym: And, you know, they talked about how their eyes are dead.
Rym: And I don't want to be one of those people.
Rym: I want anything other than to be one of those people.
Rym: And there's a flashback to another point where they ask the main character, why did you become a Yakuza?
Rym: And he looks up and says, because I can do in a single day what it takes a normal man 30 years to accomplish.
Rym: Oh, that that line sums up everything that is sanctuary.
Rym: Oh, my God.
Rym: Is this an amazing comic slash manga?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Just to you know, to clarify, I guess, you know, we use the word Gekiga a few times, Gekiga was sort of this for people who don't know.
Scott: You know, there's manga, right?
Scott: Manga translates to.
Scott: it is the word for comics in Japanese, but it translates into irresponsible pictures.
Scott: So sort of the word manga inherent in the word is sort of the feeling of comedy or or, you know, non seriousness.
Scott: And Yoshihiro Tatsumi and a bunch of other guys back in the 60s and 70s, whatnot, they decided they were going to make serious manga.
Scott: You can't make serious manga because that's a serious, irresponsible picture.
Scott: That didn't make sense.
Scott: So they made Gekiga, which is dramatic.
Rym: It's very much like in America.
Rym: Suddenly we had graphic novels.
Rym: No, no, not a comic, a graphic novel.
Scott: Yeah, it's very similar to it's sort of a combination of, you know, our crime and Will Eisner, you know, our crime sort of took comics out there and tried to do things that were a little more racy, a little more extreme, a little more on the edge.
Scott: And Will Eisner tried to, you know, say, hey, you know, this is serious business here.
Scott: This isn't just all fun and games for the kiddies.
Scott: You know, comics can be, you know, serious art.
Scott: And you combine those two ideas together.
Scott: And that's sort of what the Gekiga movement was in Japan.
Scott: Now, the comics that we're talking about now, you know, are not really Gekiga.
Scott: They have many inspirations from the Gekiga movement, but they are not Gekiga.
Scott: What they are is Seinen.
Scott: Now, when you buy your mangas at the store, right, you notice that they talk about Shoujo and Shounen, right?
Rym: Shoujo marketed girls, Shounen marketed boys.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: That's how you know, it's not like in the in the U.S.
Scott: where you separate genres by like, well, they do that there, too.
Scott: But, you know, in the
Scott: U.S.,
Scott: we don't really say this is for guys.
Scott: This is for girls in the toy store.
Rym: It's also in the bookstore.
Scott: We say this is a fantasy.
Scott: This is a sci fi.
Scott: This is a mystery.
Scott: This is right.
Rym: But don't be confused too much, because while Japan like they categorize their comics based on, you know, where they're published and who the demographic is.
Rym: But that's kind of the primary demographic.
Rym: A lot of boys read Shoujo and a lot of girls read Shounen.
Scott: I read lots of Shoujo.
Rym: I do, too.
Scott: But all these are Seinen, right?
Scott: Now, Shoujo and Shounen are actually for little girls and little boys, technically, you know, show like Shounen Jump, Dragon Ball Z. That's for like, you know, elementary school, middle school, you know, boys, Naruto and stuff like that.
Rym: All you comic people out there who don't maybe not read a lot of manga or you see the kind of Tokyo pop Shoujo stuff in the manga section and you just kind of write off manga as being that sort of thing or Dragon Ball Z or whatever.
Rym: In Japan, you know, the stuff you want to read that you will like is called Seinen and Jose.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Seinen is for like college dudes and older than that.
Scott: And, you know, Jose is for college girls and older than that.
Scott: And that stuff isn't published in the U.S.
Scott: too often.
Scott: I mean, this Seinen stuff is out of print.
Scott: Now, don't be confused by the Seinen.
Scott: There's Moe Seinen and just regular Seinen.
Scott: And Moe Seinen is like, you know, lots of cheesecake type action.
Rym: Or also like Azumanga Daiya or Yotsuba.
Scott: Those are Moe Seinen's.
Scott: This is not Moe Seinen.
Scott: This is just sort of regular Seinen.
Scott: But anyway, that's just a little lesson there for you people.
Scott: So the final comic I guess we'll talk about here is perhaps it's somewhat easy to get.
Scott: It's easier to get than sanctuary, but it's not as easy to get as it once was.
Rym: I have me, us and other friends of ours have acquired between us four complete sets of two really four complete sets.
Scott: We have won.
Rym: And I know three other people who have won.
Scott: It's funny that we have four complete sets to go with the four Eisner Awards that it was nominated for.
Rym: I was going to bring up the Eisner Awards story and art were both done by Kaiji Kawaguchi.
Rym: Remember that name?
Scott: That's a very important name because see, Kaiji Kawaguchi is not only a manga writer and artist.
Scott: He actually, in researching this comic, came over to the United States and followed around the US election.
Scott: He went around on the campaign trail studying and seeing what people were doing and learning people's names and seeing everything that was going on.
Rym: You see, this comic is about straight up the 2000 presidential race in the United States from before the primaries until after the election.
Rym: But it's with a little bit of a twist because it was just following the election.
Rym: Well, we know what happened and they could dramatize it.
Rym: But that wouldn't be that interesting.
Rym: It's that election.
Rym: Now, a lot of the names are changed and they changed kind of a lot of the Republicans.
Rym: But the Republican who ends up getting the nomination is kind of an amalgamation of several prominent Republicans at the time just to make the story work.
Scott: And there are a lot of names changed to protect the innocent.
Scott: You know, the current president at the time is Bill, Bill and his wife, Ellery.
Rym: And his his vice president, who is running for the nomination for president in that election is Al Noah.
Rym: But despite all this, there's there's also one more dark horse.
Rym: There's a dark horse candidate who's in the primaries, not getting a lot of attention, not pulling that well.
Rym: And he is the half Japanese senator from Hawaii.
Rym: He's a Democrat.
Rym: He's seeking the nomination of the Democratic Party.
Scott: Now, the thing is, you know, if you're a Republican or a Democrat, it doesn't really matter.
Scott: Even though this manga is about a Democrat and you're going to be rooting for a Democrat, because sort of the issues don't come into it too much.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And even when the issues do come into it, like gun control is a pretty prominent issue that is addressed.
Rym: You'll be surprised by his stances.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: You'll be very surprised.
Scott: The guy does a lot of you know, it's all fictional.
Scott: Obviously, the character, the main character is the fictional part of the story does.
Scott: And the reason that, you know, he does so well, obviously, he does well to make it through five volumes.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Oh, oh, God.
Rym: Bill's last name is actually mentioned in the manga.
Scott: Oh, what is it?
Scott: Clyde on.
Scott: Oh, Clyde on.
Scott: He does.
Scott: He has a lot of stances.
Scott: that sort of appeal evenly across the board.
Scott: The one of my favorite scenes is where he goes into this bar in Texas.
Rym: Oh, that's one of the cowboys.
Scott: And they know he's running for president and they confront him.
Scott: And, you know, in their cowboy way, like, you know, what's your problem?
Scott: Taking away our good.
Rym: Because he is.
Rym: He's super forward slicker.
Rym: And they're like, are you for gun control?
Rym: You for taking away?
Scott: And he says, yes, I am.
Scott: But then he wins them over in a totally awesome way.
Rym: But you might be thinking, it's not just, oh, he gives a speech and they're convinced.
Rym: No, it's so much more than that.
Rym: I can't I don't even want to hint at how he does it because it would spoil so much about what makes this comic so great.
Scott: The thing is, though, right, is that this guy running for president, he's pretty central character, right?
Scott: But he's actually not the main character.
Scott: The main character is a Japanese reporter who from a Japanese newspaper who was sent to United States to follow around the campaign.
Scott: And he's pretty much like one of the only, you know, Japanese reporters who has this level of access.
Scott: He's basically embedded in the campaign.
Scott: He follows around this Yamaoka character who's running for president, you know, and is chronicling and reporting on everything that goes on.
Scott: And mostly you're paying attention to what his story is.
Scott: And of course, his story ties into Yamaoka and some other people.
Scott: And he has a love interest going on and things get sort of hairy and there's a crazy climax, you know, and you sort of get this simultaneous personal story of the main character, what his deal is and his connection, and also the story of the campaign, you know, through the primaries, through the general election.
Scott: Oh, no spoiler.
Scott: Like you didn't see that coming, right?
Scott: Who wins in the end?
Rym: But I mean, there's still a lot of drama.
Rym: I mean, obviously he's going to get to the end and then we find out, you know, does he win?
Rym: What happens?
Rym: But there is still who is going to be the vice president.
Rym: And let me tell you, a lot of people are in for the running and who actually ends up being the running mate and how that goes together.
Rym: Is more dramatic than like any action scene I've read in most comics I've ever read.
Scott: Yeah, it's at the Democratic convention.
Rym: This is a comic that makes the Democratic convention to determine who will be the nominee and all that business.
Rym: Ultra dramatic and super engaging.
Rym: Oh, my God.
Rym: Pennsylvania cast its 84 votes for Senator Yamaoka.
Rym: Oh, what's going to happen in Texas?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: And it keeps cutting to Texas for all Noah.
Scott: Oh, shit.
Scott: What's going to happen?
Scott: Yeah, no, but the here here's a quote from the back of volume three of Eagle, right?
Scott: And a lot of a lot of.
Scott: there's a lot of comparisons between these manga we've mentioned in the West Wing.
Scott: You know, that TV show that I've never watched.
Scott: But here's a quote that I think is pretty cool.
Scott: Says I was content to get my regular political fiction fix from the West Wing.
Scott: Then I discovered Eagle James Lucas Jones of savant mag dot com.
Rym: Now, one thing, you know, we've kind of gone from the most stylized and caricatured and kind of dramaticized to the least.
Rym: I mean, this is very dramaticized, but all the politics itself, all the rules, all the inside baseball is super accurate.
Rym: Like this is actually incredibly, incredibly accurate as to how the U.S.
Rym: political process works.
Scott: I mean, a lot of the campaign strategies, a lot of these people who are managing these campaigns are, you know, they're based off the actual campaign managers and campaign strategists.
Scott: And because remember, I told you, Kaiji Kawaguchi came to the U.S.
Scott: and spent a long time getting very close to the campaigns, studying how they work, studying U.S.
Scott: politics, seeing how things went.
Scott: And a lot of this campaign strategy is is pretty close to how things actually work.
Scott: You know, and if you look at how the campaigns are being run now, you know, in the 2008 election and you read this manga, you'll see, oh, yeah, if people, you know, are thinking the way that these characters in this manga are thinking, then it totally makes sense.
Scott: the things that are going, you know, that I see in the press, you know, and you can sort of surmise from what you see on the news, what the people were, you know, in McCain or Obama's campaigns.
Rym: You know, we're thinking when all these behind the scenes, because dramas like this do happen to a degree behind, you know, when the cameras are rolling, it's not quite.
Scott: it doesn't have many speed lines when people aren't moving.
Rym: It depends, but it can because, I mean, our friend Barack Obama did get one kind of get.
Rym: you got point when he pulled that he bought a half hour of primetime TV on every network on the eve of the election.
Scott: Yeah, that's kind of.
Scott: that's kind of the kind of awesome thing that happens 20 times in each of these books.
Rym: That's the kind of thing that happens on every page in these books.
Rym: But here's where this is unrealistic at all.
Rym: Everyone is awesome.
Rym: Either they're a bad guy who's misguided, but still totally awesome, or they're a good guy who's totally awesome.
Rym: And everyone always does either the smart thing or the right thing or the wrong thing.
Rym: But you know why.
Rym: And you sympathize.
Scott: And every guy who's a bad guy, right, when actually confronted by the good guys either caves in or can't beat him.
Scott: So he joins them or something along those lines.
Scott: They're like, there are no bad guys who stay standing and unopposed.
Rym: I guess when I said that this is a very realistic, very unrealistic comic, all the details are incredibly realistic.
Rym: What is unrealistic is that there are politicians with this level of moral fiber.
Scott: Now, Eagle is also out of print, but you can actually get it at a lot of discount bins.
Scott: I've seen it on the shelves and a lot of comic book store.
Rym: We've acquired several copies or several sets.
Rym: You can acquire one.
Scott: Now, the thing is, it was published in two different formats.
Scott: You see, it was published in these very small trade paperbacks.
Scott: You know, there may be like a centimeter thick.
Scott: And there are many, many volumes of that.
Scott: There's like 20 some odd, maybe 30 volumes of these little tiny trade paperbacks.
Scott: Ignore those.
Scott: You're never going to collect them all.
Scott: They cost way too much money unless they're in like the five cent bin.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's not worth it.
Scott: All of Eagle was published in five gigantic volumes.
Scott: So the first volume doesn't actually have a number on the side.
Scott: It's just solid black.
Scott: And it's about like an inch and a half thick.
Scott: Volumes two through five have the numbers two, three, four and five on them in a bit.
Scott: What single big white number?
Scott: They're solid black on the side, and they're also like an inch and a half thick.
Scott: So look for big, thick black books.
Scott: And on the front covers look like newspapers that say Eagle at the top.
Scott: And that is how you will know.
Scott: you have found the correct publishing of Eagle.
Scott: And all you need is these five volumes.
Scott: And you've got the whole thing beginning to end and you're ready to read.
Rym: It is such a good car.
Rym: I'm flipping.
Rym: I've been flipping through it this whole time.
Rym: Just kind of thinking about it because I haven't actually read.
Scott: I've got the one with the cowboy scene in a long time.
Rym: I've got the one where there's a scene where basically he gives a speech.
Scott: Do you have the cake scene over there?
Rym: I don't have the cake scene.
Scott: I'll talk about the cakes.
Rym: OK, you can talk about the cake scene.
Rym: I'm going to pull up this speech.
Scott: So the cake scene basically check.
Scott: This is the kind of awesome thing that happens in Eagle.
Scott: Yet another example, right?
Scott: So he's a politician.
Scott: He's on the campaign trail.
Scott: He's basically trying to make nice with everyone.
Scott: He sees, you know, every stop along the road.
Scott: You want to get everyone who gets close to you to vote for you.
Scott: So he stops, you know, and it turns out someone messed up his schedule.
Scott: They screwed up, right?
Scott: Because you don't manage your own schedule.
Scott: Someone else manages it and takes you around and you do all these things and you just approve it and whatnot.
Scott: So they accidentally scheduling for two dinners in one night.
Scott: Now, a dinner is not really a big deal.
Scott: You go to dinner, you eat, you chit chat.
Scott: Maybe, you know, give a little toast, et cetera, et cetera.
Scott: Everyone goes, yeah, and then you get votes.
Scott: Two dinners in one night is rough because he has to eat two dinners.
Scott: And that's not too bad.
Scott: Eating two dinners is good by me, right?
Scott: I like to eat, but it's hard to put down two dinners in your stomach.
Scott: One after the other, you might have room.
Scott: You might barf.
Scott: I know I'd get really full after just one.
Scott: And this is like a little dinner.
Scott: It's a big multi-course dinner.
Scott: You know, a fancy, you know, political fundraising type of dinner, right?
Scott: So if you don't eat the whole dinner, the people who prepared are going to be really insulted.
Scott: That's going to look pretty bad if you show up and you just sort of nibble on it and you don't like it.
Scott: The people are going to be like, yeah, we've made this big fancy dinner for you at our, you know, try to fundraise for us and you don't even eat it.
Rym: Fuck you.
Rym: The media, basically, you know, it's pretty accurate here, are always watching for any gaffe because a gaffe makes a lot more news than someone doing the right thing.
Scott: Even if it's, I mean, look at the sort of ludicrous things that the media has paid attention to in this election.
Rym: You got a flag pin on.
Scott: Did you put the wrong jersey on at the sporting event?
Scott: Your dog's hair is the wrong color.
Scott: You misspoke, you know, some word, you know, someone gets started a foreign war of aggression, right?
Scott: No matter how many, no matter who you are, if you give so many speeches, you're going to mess up a word now and then it's going to happen, but the media jumps all over it.
Scott: So of course the media is going to jump all over too full to eat dinner.
Scott: There's a question of his health.
Scott: Is there, you know, there's going to be all sorts of craziness.
Scott: So he's got to eat these two dinners.
Scott: So miraculously, he eats the two dinners and it's like, he, when he eats the final bite of the second dinner, it's like this big glow around him and every, all the, see that most of the people don't know.
Scott: he's eating two dinners.
Scott: That is the second one, you know, but all the people in his campaign are like sweating bullets.
Rym: Like it is, it is as tense as like some standoff in a gun.
Scott: Everyone who knows that it's his second dinner is sweating their brains off.
Scott: Meanwhile, he's looking cool and collected like he's supposed to.
Scott: And he puts the final bite down and they're like, oh man.
Scott: And then right as he gets up to leave, this little girl comes up to him with this piece of cake.
Scott: And I'm not going to tell you what happens then, but oh man, he's got to eat the cake, but can he eat the cake?
Scott: Oh, I don't know.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: It's supposed to be a political manga, but one of the most dramatic things that happen is someone's forced to eat cake.
Rym: But also the thing where it really gets me about this comic is that it's kind of wordy, but also the art's really good and really detailed.
Scott: There's a lot of characters, like a lot of people, you know, especially fans of, you know, superhero comics and whatever, you know, they shy away from the manga because they get that initial initial visual thing.
Scott: You know, before anything else catches your catches you, it's always going to be the visuals, you know?
Scott: And I'm guilty of this too.
Scott: If I pick up a new comic, even if that comic might be really well written or something I might care about, the visuals, you know, if the cover art or something puts me off, I'm not going to, you know, it's going to be very difficult to get me to read that or spend money on it.
Scott: But a lot of people out there, they see a manga and they see the typical anime style, big eyes, small mouth, and they're put off for whatever reason.
Scott: And, you know, I can understand someone being put off by that and they don't want to read it.
Scott: They don't like it.
Scott: They're sort of prejudiced towards it sometimes.
Scott: But, you know, there's something about that.
Scott: These manga, these three we have mentioned are not big eyes, small mouth art.
Scott: They're created, they're written and drawn by Japanese people in Japan.
Scott: These were published originally for Japanese audiences in the Japanese language, translated into English.
Scott: Yet they are not big eyes, small mouth.
Scott: It's black and white.
Scott: Well, or monochrome.
Scott: But it looks like normal people.
Scott: I mean, I guess if you looked at it, you might be able to tell that it was Japanese, you know, from the art.
Scott: But it's not big eyes, small mouth, pointy chin, giant robot action.
Scott: Far from it.
Scott: And if you're put off, you know, by the art style, the stereotypical manga anime art style, you should definitely take a look at this before you are prejudiced against it because you will be very, very surprised.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, like here's a dramatic scene.
Rym: This is one of my favorite scenes.
Rym: I mean, the reason I one of the reasons I really like this comic is the speeches because it's, you know, normal drama, normal drama.
Rym: But when a politician gives a speech, you get the whole speech.
Rym: Meanwhile, you get like all the crowd reactions, the press reactions, the reactions of people in their homes watching it on TV and the poll numbers and kind of the behind the scenes drama.
Rym: But you get the whole speech.
Rym: And one of the big plot points is that there's a lot of rumbling about his kind of foreign policy and military policy.
Rym: And a lot of people are saying he's weak and he's, you know, there's all these kind of rumors and allegations floating around.
Rym: And finally, he's at a press event.
Rym: You know, in real politics, a lot of times reporters will appear and say, hey, we've heard blah.
Rym: What's your actual stance?
Rym: And they always say something crap and totally dodge the issue.
Rym: Well, the reporters corner him and they say, what's the deal?
Rym: Are you disrespecting our military servicemen?
Rym: and blah, blah, blah, blah.
Rym: And his response is this.
Rym: I want to take this opportunity to speak for the record.
Rym: My campaign has a long term strategy for US defense.
Rym: It is for this reason in particular that I'll work hard to receive two terms from the American people.
Rym: As I anticipate, these policies will require a timeframe stretching through the first decade of the 20th century.
Rym: For the next eight years, I will order that all US bases abroad be shut down.
Scott: Oh, snaps.
Rym: And this speech goes out.
Scott: That's something I would do if I was president.
Rym: That happens all the time.
Rym: He says this and the next like eight panels, at first it shows the reporters like a GOG.
Rym: It cuts to his campaign manager going, did he just say?
Rym: And his other campaign manager is like sweating, going off shit behind him.
Rym: It cuts to all these military people.
Rym: What out of his fucking mind?
Rym: That traitor bastard.
Scott: See, it's like someone said something ludicrous, right?
Scott: And that's the sort of thing that in the real world, you just basically ruined yourself.
Scott: And of course, everyone acts as if he ruined himself.
Scott: It's it's the reactions are real.
Rym: It's the Bulworth second and parallel to this order, unless the lives of American citizens and the territory of the United States is itself under threat.
Rym: It will be the policy of my administration to forgo any future military action.
Scott: Do you see how that plays into the whole, you know, Japanese ideology with the, you know, the Article nine and whatnot?
Rym: Now, this is when it cuts to a bunch of officers at a club somewhere.
Rym: And his a guy who he wants to be his advisors at this club and forgo military action.
Rym: Asshole sounds like he's running for the president of Iraq.
Rym: That bastard.
Rym: He wants to get rid of us.
Rym: Jesus Christ.
Rym: General, you were right about him.
Rym: And he was in the core.
Rym: traitor, traitor.
Rym: And like people are just losing their shit.
Rym: And then, you know, it goes on for a while.
Rym: And then later, the Republican candidate gives a speech that's basically rah, rah, rah, military.
Rym: And everyone's thinking that the whole campaign has fallen apart.
Rym: And oh, my God, he's totally going to lose.
Rym: He's lost the American people.
Rym: He's lost the military.
Rym: It's over.
Rym: And then there's this scene where that military advisor is meeting with all these big military people and they confront him.
Rym: They're like, do you really follow on with what that guy says?
Rym: Are you with him?
Rym: Really?
Rym: Blah, blah, blah.
Rym: And he just said he looks at him and he says, if you die for a meaningless war, you died a meaningless death.
Rym: And they stand up like they're about to hit him.
Rym: And he says, I said, a meaningless death.
Rym: And that is the drama that you get in Eagle.
Rym: And that that whole thing is like one out of a thousand.
Rym: And that is actually one of the weaker ones.
Rym: This comic is so great.
Scott: Yeah, that's a that's a good mention there.
Scott: The Bulworth, though, if that's your kind of movie, these are your kind of manga.
Rym: And if these are your kind of manga, Bulworth is your kind of movie, even though, man, is that a depressing movie?
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty depressing.
Scott: You know, and I think even though all these these manga here will have you wishing that, you know, any of these fictional characters are the candidates instead of the real ones.
Rym: I would have voted for the Republican in this book.
Scott: Yeah, I would have fun the Republican in this book before Obama.
Scott: Hells yeah.
Scott: But no, it's it's not going to happen.
Scott: And that's the most.
Scott: that's why even though these are really inspirational and will have you, you know, jumping up and down and cheering and every and such and such in the end, they are depressing because you realize that this is what politics, at least in theory, could.
Scott: well, maybe not could, but what should be in a perfect world and it never will be.
Scott: And that's why it's sort of it's sort of sad at the same time.
Rym: Isn't it always kind of the cliche that I mean, how many movies do we have where the guy who doesn't care and doesn't expect to win and doesn't want to win, runs his campaign stupidly and haphazardly and as a result wins, because that's what the people really want.
Rym: And that's such a cliche.
Rym: But yet we've never seen a major political candidate do it.
Rym: No, I guess the thing is, one person did actually Ross Perot and he got real close, closer than anyone ever had.
Scott: I don't want to spend a lot of time talking about what the what's and whys and wherefores of Ross Perot and his gigantic, gigantic ears.
Rym: Well, I guess I can say this, though.
Rym: I think I want to say here's my political bit here.
Rym: I think the reason for that is Ross Perot was the least insane.
Rym: He was pretty much the least insane non-primary party person to ever, at least in history that anyone out there remembers, really to get on the national stage and get noticed for speaking his mind, because a lot of people, there are a lot of politicians who run for high office, who speak their mind.
Rym: But usually it's because they're crazy.
Rym: I mean, Ron Paul is crazy and his politics are stupid.
Rym: I'm sorry, Dig, but you're wrong.
Scott: Bob Barr, also crazy.
Scott: Pretty much every constitution party, 10,000 times crazy.
Scott: And that's not even one of the crazier parties out there.
Rym: I got to say one more thing.
Rym: You know how many people Ellery slaps or beats up or freaks out at in this book?
Rym: She is basically a tank.
Scott: Yeah, it's great.
Scott: It's super great.
Rym: She kind of reminds me of Bulma from Dragon Paul, just a little bit.
Scott: But basically, you know, everyone who runs for office in the US who isn't one of the two major parties is crazy.
Scott: And even sometimes the two major party people are crazy.
Scott: So, you know, we usually end up voting for the sane person.
Scott: And the thing is, Ross Perot was sane and there were two other sane candidates against him with three not crazy candidates.
Scott: And what happened was is the things that Ross Perot was saying that were so universally appealing, they were so agreeable, which is why he got so popular.
Scott: He said things like balance the fucking budget.
Scott: Duh.
Scott: And everyone was like, of course.
Scott: Well, I mean, no one disagree.
Rym: No one's saying that he had other policies that were crazy, but no one listened to those.
Rym: Right.
Scott: But he had a but his primary policies, his major ones were agreeable across the board.
Scott: So what happened was the Democrats, you know, Bill Clinton just said, I'll do that.
Scott: And it was a Bob Dole.
Scott: I think, yeah, Bob Dole said, yeah, I'll do that, too.
Scott: So there was no reason to vote for Ross Perot, because if you voted for one of the other guys, you got all the other issues that you actually agreed with and you got everything that Ross Perot said.
Scott: And that's what happens when there's a third party in the US.
Scott: The third party either displaces one of the two parties by taking over for it or its policies get adopted by the two major parties.
Scott: And now there's no reason to vote for that third party because it was a single issue party, something like the Green Party, which is a heavy emphasis on environmentalism and whatnot.
Scott: Both of the major parties, even though they differ on the specifics, they have both, at least in their campaign, said stuff like, you know, good for the environment.
Scott: Yeah, because it's so popular.
Scott: Wait a minute.
Scott: You're talking about politics.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I'm not talking about any specific stuff here.
Rym: Yes, you are.
Scott: Whatever.
Scott: You know, so that's that's what happened is the Green Party's policies have been adopted by the two major parties.
Scott: So there's no reason to vote for the Green Party, really, because you can just vote for one of the other parties and you're going to get some of your environmental goodness that you're looking for.
Scott: So, yeah, that's you know, and that's sort of why these manga are somewhat unrealistic is that if candidates like these came around with these sort of policies, they would either be crazy and no one would vote for them and they would be cast off or their policies would be agreeable to everyone.
Scott: And one of the other candidates would adopt those policies and there would be no reason to vote for the awesome person.
Scott: But if you're looking for a political inspiration of awesomeness, these books, you should try to find them in the bargain bins.
Rym: And I think on that note, we can wrap this up.
Rym: So I hope we have opened your eyes to three comics, two of which you'll probably never be able to read.
Scott: Well, you know, try hard.
Scott: Don't go out of your way to look for them.
Scott: You know, maybe eBay is worth looking at or Amazon or, you know, once in a while.
Scott: But whenever you happen to be at a convention, happen to be at a comic book store, look in the bargain bins, look in the, you know, discount manga, old manga, whatever, whatever, and see if you can find first president of Japan, Sanctuary or Eagle.
Scott: And if you do, just buy them.
Scott: Don't even think about it.
Scott: You know, at the very least, buy them.
Scott: And then if you don't like the mail them to us, because I'll take as many copies of these as I can get just so I can, you know, make sure they find good homes.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our Frapper map, and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology.
Rym: Tuesdays we have video games, board games, and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights, and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Scott: Just click the link that says "send me an Odeo" on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: For the complete archives, visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share-a-like 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit, don't make money, and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.