Rym: It's Wednesday October 1st.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight comics are for boys.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So today I decided that I wanted to get a holla.
Rym: But of course there's a crazy line to get holla's on the train station.
Scott: It's Rosh Hashanah.
Scott: So holla is very popular on Rosh Hashanah.
Rym: - yeah But as a result I left work early and I even said when they said why you'll even work I said I gotta get a holla.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Hey, you gotta get a holla today.
Rym: You gotta wake up to which real early to which my co-workers said you're not Jewish.
Rym: So and I was like, yeah, I want a holla.
Rym: What do you want?
Rym: So I get in line right and there's this Jewish guy Like.
Rym: he looked very like traditional possibly acidic and he's standing anyway.
Scott: He was wearing like the big hat and everything.
Scott: Okay Crazy beard and it wasn't that crazy.
Rym: He was kind of young but he's standing there, right?
Rym: So I walk, you know, there's this line and he's asking everyone who comes up like are you Jewish?
Scott: Oh He's what he's looking to.
Scott: He's asking everybody's.
Scott: he's look.
Scott: He's probably from the.
Rym: But anyway, my story gets interesting because you know me I do not shy from a challenge.
Rym: So I get up there and he seems to because the guy in front of me gets like a cupcake and he doesn't ask him.
Rym: I think he's only asking the people who buy holla's duh.
Rym: So I buy my holla and he says Excuse me.
Rym: Are you Jewish?
Rym: And I say No, I don't really believe in God.
Rym: and he says neither do I but I believe in honey and bread.
Rym: And I was like, I also believe in honey and bread.
Rym: and he was like have a good day and I was like you too.
Rym: Either he was an atheist or he has a sense of humor and I'm okay with either one of those.
Scott: That's the thing is you'd be surprised how many Jews are atheists and some of them have twisted logics and some of them don't.
Rym: Well, I think the thing is that very few people who don't who aren't Christian will say they're Christian because there's just.
Rym: there's the religion and then like culture is all Different but there's the Jewish religion and the Jewish culture and a lot of people who are one or not the other and vice versa.
Scott: No, but there are even people who are Religiously Jewish, but they don't actually like.
Scott: they'll be a guy you look at him He's a rabbi doesn't actually literally believe in any sort of deity whatsoever, but he believes in the milk and the honey.
Scott: Yeah, you know they.
Scott: they you know, they're Jewish for other reasons and they do the.
Scott: they keep kosher other reasons besides.
Scott: No, not as good will smite you know, he's psychic for his own reason exactly.
Rym: Anyway, that was the most exciting thing that happened to me today on the train.
Scott: on the way home today There was you know, the doors on the train.
Scott: It seems like wherever I sit on the train these days The door is broken.
Scott: I must have a broken.
Rym: so the vestibule is just loud and everyone's angry.
Scott: right or it won't open Right.
Scott: and today it was the weirdest situation yet.
Scott: The door right.
Scott: you would push the button and sometimes the button would do nothing, but sometimes it would work just fine.
Scott: but you know everyone just kept manipulating the door a whole bunch and it eventually would only open halfway.
Scott: and This guy sitting near me actually was a smart guy and he kept up.
Scott: He kept going to actually try to fix it.
Scott: the conductor didn't do shit.
Scott: The conductor just puts it in manual mode opens it all the way and walks away.
Scott: It doesn't care.
Rym: That's fine because then you can close it and open it right.
Scott: but you know This guy actually kept trying to fix it and he did fix it a couple of times.
Scott: But then every time someone came up to it It was broken again and you would see like a person would Manipulated a whole bunch and just they'd push the button.
Scott: It doesn't work.
Scott: push push push like ten times, you know It's like what are you doing?
Scott: Dude?
Scott: You didn't work the first time.
Scott: It's not gonna work the second time.
Scott: It's not good.
Rym: You know the best is when you see someone who walks up and they like they fiddle with it.
Rym: They finally get it open and there's someone behind them.
Scott: That person does not learn from the person To say it was like there's a line of people and every single person Kept coming up and making the same stupid mistakes and fiddling with the door for ten minutes.
Scott: Just it doors open halfway right now.
Scott: It's not gonna be fixed unless you actually stop and fix it which you obviously don't know how to do.
Scott: So it's gonna walk around it and keep going.
Rym: God It was the moral of the story that you didn't have anything to do on the train because you know
Scott: I don't pay attention to the drama
Rym: of the door I don't
Scott: need it, but I was sitting right next to the door and I was reading my book But every time someone came up to the door They were kicking it a whole bunch and made a lot of noise
Rym: and as they stormed the mountain and kicked him to death
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: So I think what it is is that I think in general we need to have you know More.
Scott: people need to learn how to fix things.
Rym: We need door training.
Scott: That's it.
Rym: We also add the use of doors as like a first-grade class.
Scott: I think we also just need.
Rym: it seems like people learn how to open the fuck out of doors.
Scott: It seems like in our culture There's a thing against just going up and fixing something that's broken if it's not yours or not your responsibility.
Scott: Almost like you're not supposed to fix something if it's not yours.
Scott: Like you might get in trouble for doing good and I think we need to get away.
Rym: No, I think mostly just people though.
Rym: It's not a matter of people are afraid.
Rym: They just really don't care.
Scott: Yeah, but there are also many situations where if you know how to fix like if someone has a problem with their computer You can't just go up and fix it.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know.
Rym: I wouldn't anyway because that's not worth my time.
Scott: I know I know but it's frustrating when something's broken.
Scott: It's like I could have gotten on my Leatherman opened up a little panel and actually fixed the door.
Rym: but now Highly doubt that you would have been able to fix that because I knew exactly what was wrong What was wrong with it?
Scott: There was a thing stuck that's got slid under the door there.
Scott: that was stuck in there keeping it from open all the way.
Scott: I could just opened it up and taking that.
Rym: you know, whatever piece of junk got in there I'm dubious of your ability to perform maintenance on the train door.
Rym: It's kind of complicated.
Scott: in there I think I can remove a piece of junk.
Scott: I can remove a paper.
Scott: Jam.
Scott: I can remove a piece of junk.
Scott: It's a. The point is is that I would have gotten.
Rym: You just talked for quite a while about the door on the train.
Rym: Yeah, that wouldn't open all the way.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: But anyway, maybe anime maybe I don't know.
Scott: there's not so much news going to hell.
Rym: There's some news.
Rym: you see the previous weekend was the New York Anime Festival 2008 in New York Went to for like the shortest amount of time.
Rym: Well, the thing is, you know We've been doing like.
Rym: we've kind of gotten to this point where there's so many panels of cons that Or our plan is actually to kind of scale back and do fewer higher quality panels.
Scott: That's a good plan.
Scott: I've also noticed just at anime conventions in general like there's less for me to do like.
Scott: I went there I literally did three panels walked and saw everything in the dealers You know exhibition room once and then I was done.
Scott: I did nothing on the schedule I wanted to go to except the MC Chris concert, which I missed.
Rym: Well, uh, we had to do the geeky guy.
Rym: Goodbye, of course But part of it said that's not.
Rym: I mean different.
Rym: every anime cons different and like Otakon is different vibe from the New York Anime Festival different vibe from Katsu Kahn and There wasn't really much of a hanging out con.
Rym: It's more of a alright You're in that you live nearby and you're into anime.
Rym: It's worth it pretty pretty much for anyone who's an anime to go there for one of the three days because there's stuff to do.
Scott: Yeah, it seemed like there was a lot of hanging out like kids are just hanging out making mischief all over the place and you Know the hallways and the lobbies and etc, etc.
Scott: but it really wasn't so exciting for me to be there other than get to give the panels and the.
Scott: You know look around the room once.
Scott: that was it.
Scott: I was done.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well then again, it's not like I mean there were events I kind of actually wanted to go to but like we literally showed up to do the three panels.
Scott: Oh, well, that's the other thing I missed that I did want to see was I wanted to see the girl who does anime news Nina Robin Savickas.
Scott: Yeah, she was there.
Rym: I wanted to see MC Chris again.
Rym: Actually, I heard sadly that not many people went to the MC Chris concert.
Rym: MC Chris is awesome.
Rym: He's no MC front a lot, but he's awesome.
Scott: No, I think they should tag team.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: They really have the same style.
Rym: MC Chris is mostly.
Rym: he stands there and yells at you on melodically but funnily.
Rym: meanwhile MC front a lot Kind of raps at you.
Rym: It's a different vibe.
Scott: Yeah, it is a different vibe, but you know, whatever It's all good.
Rym: But anyway, we did our three panels, you know, we finally we did the last time We're gonna do the gecky got panel Never again.
Rym: The thing is, you know, how many people emailed us after the con.
Rym: they were like, yeah We missed the gecky got panel.
Rym: Will you do it at insert name of con here?
Scott: I'm like, we're never doing it again and it's done.
Scott: I've done it.
Scott: I've done it that many times and you've never made it to the con.
Rym: Well, the thing is the press actually came up to like after we did and they talked to me while Scott was talking to other People.
Rym: they were like, yeah So you guys ever thought about filming a definitive version of this and putting it out there so we could just kind of link to It.
Rym: Yeah, I Feel like if we do that, we got to get Gerald involved.
Scott: Maybe alright, maybe we could do that.
Scott: We could take any panels that are dead and are never gonna be a convention again and then put those online.
Rym: I feel like that's actually a really good.
Rym: I think that's okay that every Should make kind of the round through all the conventions and then to retire it.
Rym: we do the definitive word.
Scott: Yeah, cuz then the bit the one version we put online will be so well practiced that it will be turn out really well.
Rym: It's kind of like how if you go see a band in concert, you know, they play things kind of differently.
Rym: But there's always the album version of the song like everyone knows the album version of stairway to heaven Yep, and everyone when they think of the song they think of that.
Rym: But then there's the cool people who saw him in concert who might remember the other version they heard.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Oh So anime news, it's not so it's not so strong.
Scott: That's why I got a resort to this kind of and news, but it's not the worst thing in the world.
Scott: All right, so apparently You know how Lupin and many of the Lupin movies is always seen driving that little yellow car.
Scott: I mean he's been seen driving some other cars too.
Scott: Like once he was driving that, you know, um, six-wheeled f1 car with the Don't forget ground effects.
Rym: I think that my favorite vehicle of his is the motorcycle that he rode across that clown's face in the best Lupin movie Babylon go best said with a head with.
Rym: Is that far and away the best Lupin there ever was right, right?
Scott: He also drove that car.
Scott: It was just sort of like a long car, you know has the tire on the back, you know what I'm talking about.
Scott: But mostly he's known for that little yellow Fiat kind of car and Fiat is actually going to make and people don't know.
Scott: Fiat is I think an Italian car company.
Scott: It's really.
Scott: it's owned by the say it by Ford and Ferrari and it's all.
Scott: it's all the same company really But it's not.
Scott: but they make little cars.
Scott: if you go to Europe or you know People are in Europe know this but people in Europe might not know that there are no Fiat's in the US.
Rym: We don't have those cars there are but they're in the hands of wealthy people.
Scott: Well, they're eight.
Scott: Well, they're incredibly rare, but in Europe a Fiat's like a small economic car for the average person, you know It's like a kind of car a high school kid will have you know, depending on which Fiat.
Scott: But yeah, Fiat is just a really tiny.
Scott: they make tiny efficient normal cars.
Scott: Some of them little cool some of them not so cool.
Scott: and Fiat is going to make that yellow Lupin car.
Scott: They're gonna make like five hundred of them or so.
Scott: and I guess Rym you should try to buy one you the car.
Rym: I don't need a Fiat.
Scott: We get it why it'd be really efficient.
Scott: be small like you want and it'll be a Lupin car.
Scott: Wait, wait, wait, I think you put the Otari license plate on it for the ultimate awesome.
Rym: No, I feel like if I'm getting the Otari license plate transferred to another car.
Rym: It's gotta be a red like 98 Miata.
Scott: No, I gotta get some gold Rym yellow Lupin Fiat.
Scott: We could drive it on the wall.
Rym: See it's weird because I feel like if I got like the Miata is the perfect Accio car in terms of like the feel.
Rym: But the car in the show is more like this long like there's a gigantic backseat.
Rym: It's almost like a convertible Buick.
Scott: Yeah, it's it's well you can get.
Scott: you could probably get a red like Chrysler Sebring.
Scott: It's not good.
Rym: It's the only time where the you tend.
Rym: a movie is actually worth something because in the movie that is exactly the car I can Get.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: Oh, oh the naked one in the movie.
Rym: No, not the naked one.
Rym: the naked one doesn't exist.
Scott: talking about the Accio I thought you were talking that you could get the naked car.
Scott: I know I can get the naked car.
Scott: Why can't you?
Rym: I can get the Accio car.
Rym: the naked car does not exist.
Rym: It's a pink like formula car.
Scott: No, no, I meant that the naked car just two naked girls on a stick.
Rym: Oh Well, the thing is the naked car goes through all these stages of nakedness.
Rym: It goes from partially naked to fully naked - I didn't think it could get more.
Scott: Maybe that's the cosplay.
Rym: we should make the naked car Wait, so we get two girls to be naked on a stick.
Scott: No, no, but we'd have them.
Scott: We basically have this car made out of cardboard, right and they'd be on a stick standing up But we'd put like a video of a moving street behind them.
Scott: So you're sitting in the audience and you're looking at the top of the car, but it looks like you're looking at it.
Rym: So this is a cosplay performance not just a walk around cosplay.
Scott: What what other kind of cosplay is there?
Rym: because I realize that that that's not.
Rym: No cosplay is ever gonna be good again.
Rym: until I see someone at Otakon Flip over the hood windshield until I see someone at Otakon do what they did in here is Greenwood.
Rym: I've never seen anyone do that at a con.
Scott: Oh with the whole Clock and everything.
Rym: Yeah, you see that.
Rym: Why doesn't anyone do that?
Rym: They did in Tokimeki Memorial Yes, but they didn't do it in America.
Rym: I've never seen anyone do it.
Rym: if anyone out there Knows of an anime convention where anyone did the here is Greenwood thing and if you don't know what that is.
Rym: You're way too young.
Scott: It takes a lot of manufacture.
Scott: It's a lot of set construction to make that happen.
Rym: No, see modern era you make a giant backdrop and you just throw it down.
Rym: So things of the day.
Rym: now, we're not gonna review this tonight But we're gonna review it as soon as Scott watches it again.
Scott: I haven't watched it since 2000.
Rym: you know a lot of times.
Rym: you watch it like there's an old show that you love and then you know It's like 10 years later and you decide to watch it again.
Rym: You realize it's stupid or it's not quite as good as you remember or it's completely different from you remember.
Rym: Well, KO century beast is not only exactly as good as I remember It's better than I remember for reasons that I'll get into when we finally review it.
Rym: That show is awesome.
Scott: There are a lot of shows we watched back in the days of our ITN Where we got VHS tape a digital target VHS tapes from the club library.
Rym: Christiania Christiania, whatever, you know what legend of poop bastard Bastard, that's a good show.
Scott: brought them back to the dorm rooms.
Scott: We put them in a tiny via a VCR with a tiny television.
Scott: We watched them while we were dead tired And I fell asleep often while they were on.
Rym: I think it is the Irish anime club white right.
Rym: you could check out Three VHS tapes per week.
Rym: So there were you know, like ten people in the front row crew.
Rym: We'd all each check out three tapes and then we would watch Much of that anime over the course of that weekend.
Scott: Yeah, so we saw all these crazy shows and I remember we watched like, you know, Kota Monocha, whatever Summary movie.
Scott: Yeah, I fell asleep during the whole thing.
Scott: I didn't even see the beginning or the end or the middle.
Scott: and yet we watch those sleep as it was starting Before anything happened and I woke up after the credits.
Rym: and yet we watched shows before that and after that that night.
Scott: Yeah, anyway, we see these all these shows and now that we're re-watching a few of these shows We're actually seeing what they were really like because our memories are completely wrong.
Rym: Well, actually no what I found is that our memories are right.
Rym: for example Legend of Lemnier still bad really bad But KO Century Beast.
Rym: I'm not gonna tell you my opinion of it.
Scott: So good.
Rym: My thing of the day is the second opener only because you couldn't find the first opener on YouTube.
Rym: I couldn't find the first opener on YouTube, which I actually prefer.
Rym: I just I think the song is really really cute.
Scott: this No reason about this show.
Scott: I only watch this show once in my life.
Scott: I don't know why but I have like completely memorized both opening songs in Japanese.
Rym: It was kind of scary.
Rym: Scott and I were kind of singing along.
Rym: But to this day, I still remember my thing of the day is the second opener to KO Century Beast aka Rock-and-roll bomber love missile.
Rym: three two one.
Rym: Let's go.
Scott: I think it's three two one zero.
Rym: Oh, yeah, zero.
Rym: Well and a whole no.
Rym: Oh, no rock and roll.
Rym: I think it isn't it?
Rym: Oh My god, this is open or great show.
Rym: and also I forgot the show is actually a robot show.
Rym: Yeah, partially no almost entire.
Rym: It's like 80% robot show.
Scott: There's a lot of robot going on.
Scott: It's basically not magic easy, but it's got robots.
Rym: It's a. it is a robot show.
Rym: Do not do not be fooled.
Scott: Alright seeing as it, you know Rym had to dig away back for a thing of the day Which is an opener to an old anime However, an anime that does not get enough love and as a result, I feel like many of you have not seen this.
Scott: Yeah, I also had to go back and dig for a thing of the day because the internet is devoid.
Scott: I mean I went looking for a dig.
Rym: Wait a minute as in digger on Paul.
Scott: No As in you know digging with a shovel I mean I was gonna go get some Hatsune Miku or something, but I couldn't find one that interested me.
Rym: Well, you've already said I mean the best one is still the one that did that closer to the one sergeant frog, right?
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: That's like the best house name because unless the house name who comes along is better than that I'm gonna leave her alone for a while, even though she's still awesome.
Rym: Well, if one does it's probably going to cause a macross to happen.
Scott: Yeah, but I just decided you know what?
Scott: I don't know if I've done this for a thing in the day before.
Scott: I'm pretty sure I haven't because I searched the website and didn't find it.
Scott: This is the greatest anime music video to ever exist.
Scott: It is the Mambo Leo.
Scott: If you haven't seen it, what's wrong with you?
Rym: one more thing?
Rym: I don't know if anyone out there realizes people who aren't you know in with the front row crew.
Scott: Mambo Leo has a history.
Rym: the Mambo Leo is like the official music video of the front row crew.
Scott: Well, why would he pick one?
Scott: That wasn't the best?
Rym: Well, there's more to it.
Rym: I mean at the fact that it survived to this day that there's still.
Rym: there's a video of us doing the dance even though I Think we're between all of us.
Rym: We knew the whole dance but no one of us knew all of the dance.
Rym: Yeah, but that video did not show you doing it all But it descended into chaos.
Rym: right suffice to say there's video.
Rym: There's the song.
Rym: there is the Spanish version of the song.
Rym: There is the dance that Luke created that we all learned And slightly modified.
Rym: there's a history.
Scott: Yeah, basically we saw this music video.
Scott: It was amazing.
Scott: The song is amazing.
Scott: We made up a dance to do to the song.
Scott: Then we would play the music video and do the dance multiple times.
Scott: at most recently we whipped it out at a wedding.
Rym: But I mean this goes back to RIT anime club.
Rym: like music nights The Mambo Leo would play and suddenly like the whole front of the room is filled with the eboard and the front row crew dancing.
Rym: Yep, we did it at conventions.
Rym: I danced it at the my final moment of glory at the RIT anime club before I step down.
Scott: We could do it as a cosplay at an anime convention and probably win.
Scott: The only problem is I'm not.
Scott: I'm not doing a perfect blue cosplay.
Rym: You know if the entire front row crew did the perfect blue cosplay.
Rym: I think we could win.
Scott: I'll be the director I'll be.
Scott: I'll do a Satoshi khan cosplay.
Scott: The only rule I get an icon camera and a scary beard.
Rym: the best way to do it is You have a simple rule.
Rym: No one is allowed to shave for a month before Otakon.
Rym: No legs faces anything.
Scott: No All right, so check this out.
Scott: at the New York anime festival, right?
Scott: and also At Otakon we did this panel comics for the manga fan, right?
Scott: And basically the idea of this panel was we would try to get people who are just mainly manga fans You know the kind of people at an anime convention to enjoy all comics not just comics that are from Japan And we would do this by giving them many examples of awesome comics They should go out and read that are not manga.
Rym: In fact, we also talk a lot about and or not anime manga that are good to read.
Rym: that a lot of manga fans haven't read yep,
Scott: and You know on our way to the you know, New York any festival Emily mentioned, you know that
Emily: We were in the subway car and I was like so You're gonna address any of the stuff for shoujo fans because there's probably a lot of girls here who mainly read shoujo.
Emily: And you know think of some romance comics or something.
Emily: and Scott was like the romance comics from the 60s And I was like, oh god.
Emily: No, I'll go Bargo.
Emily: I was something like, you know my faith and Frankie or Any of the other ones like that.
Scott: Alright, so, you know, we already sort of had that on our minds like, huh, huh, maybe.
Rym: hmm I have to think about it right, you know, because I mean my answer was well If they're really into that specific kind of thing manga is kind of where it's at right now.
Scott: That is that is sort of true.
Emily: There's not many be shown in.
Emily: Much American made.
Rym: yeah, there's no like shown in simple.
Scott: I'm sure there's been shown in Superman yaoi, but it's not made over here Right, so actually after the panel I'm like when I got home there was an email waiting for me Email.
Scott: so I was gonna do this as a geek back, but we decided to turn it.
Rym: What Scott did is he got this email and I could see that he was gonna respond to it.
Rym: And then he like he had to check himself be like no I'll respond to publicly in the show.
Scott: that's right because as soon as I saw this email I'm like, oh this has to be a show There's.
Scott: no it's too much to say for it You know to be wasted on a forum post or a private email.
Emily: and I finagled my way onto the show because Rym Cancelled their panel on Sunday and I was mad and I was like for punishment.
Emily: You have to have me on the show on Wednesday.
Emily: So I actually I was.
Scott: I was like if I do that if I turn this into a show, I'm gonna need Emily.
Emily: I should be like Clarissa and be like Emily the girl We were.
Rym: any other lame geek podcast we'd have made the joke that Yes, so we got an expert on the subject of being Anything is at work.
Emily: They they were gonna actually interview me about like how does being a girl affect your perspective?
Emily: You know art and I was just like well, how does your perspective of being a guy affect your marketing?
Rym: I would have said that Everything cylindrical is an oppressive phallic reference.
Scott: Yeah So anyway, we got this email about this.
Scott: You know particular topic and I wanted to reply to the email.
Scott: in a show I wanted Emily to be there and I want you know Emily You know bothered room about being on the show and the listeners bothered us about Emily being on the show.
Emily: So thank you guys.
Scott: We have planets planets aligning here.
Rym: So we've actually gotten more feedback saying get Emily on the show more than we have about any other single topic.
Scott: Yeah, it makes me blush with with planets such you know in this configuration How could we not do this show and you know, it's it's gotta be good show.
Scott: Anyway, so I'm gonna read this email and then I want to respond sort of directly to the accusation of the email and you know Sort of defend ourselves and then we can talk more generally about the topic at hand.
Scott: All right, this is the email from someone named satellite.
Scott: All right Hi, I attended your panel comics for the manga fan yesterday at the New York anime festival.
Scott: One comment about the suggestions you put forward during this presentation.
Scott: I think they're pretty much all male oriented.
Scott: Sorry, but most girls are not going to go for Watchmen parentheses.
Scott: Just look at the name parentheses Frank Miller or atomic Robo.
Scott: You should investigate what there is of non manga with more of an emphasis on females.
Scott: I have not a shell for this comic but one title that comes to mind is skeleton key by Andy Watson a Brit a Manga influenced comic from the 90s published by slave labor graphics.
Scott: The comic is widely available at Amazon and others.
Scott: Amazon link to the comic.
Scott: To me something like this would much more fall under the category Comics for the manga fan the presentation you guys did.
Scott: I would have titled some Western comics that don't suck But I did enjoy your presentation of the Western comics that don't suck.
Emily: Here's one thing I kind of want to say is that When when people hear the term Western comics for the manga reader they think of You know more of the Tokyo pop English language stuff whereas what we decided to do and what we think of when we think of Comics that would appeal to a manga reader is we don't just look at style.
Emily: We look more at You know content and I think the thing that drew at least all my friends to Manga and anime in the first place is that it had Deeper themes and it had really developed characters.
Emily: So it's less about the art style and more about about these darker darker issues and Complex characters.
Emily: Yep.
Rym: I'll leave it.
Rym: I don't even want to beat around the bush.
Rym: I feel like the accusation itself doesn't really make sense yet.
Rym: How could Watchmen I was Watchmen aimed like.
Rym: how is that a male comic exactly exactly?
Scott: Obviously someone who hasn't read Watchmen It's not watching women right now, I want to list the comics we talked about just real quick.
Scott: All right, Watchmen V for Vendetta the surrogates Scott Pilgrim black sad bone Dark Knight Returns the spirit runaways x-mock, you know wide last man fables atomic robo walking dead all the works of Jason Mouse guard and The life and times of Scrooge McDuck.
Rym: Those are the comics.
Rym: You mean McDuck McDuck, right?
Scott: So Scrooge Scrooge.
Scott: All right, so, you know, I guess you could sort of you know It's it's not hard to say I guess something like atomic robo is a little bit sort of classically male Action figury sort of stuff.
Emily: right thing about Frank Miller is I gotta say from the Frank Miller stuff I've read he does tend to have kind of dumb portrayals of female.
Rym: Yes, either he is the whore Dumb weak woman or the strong-willed hooker with the heart of gold.
Rym: That's it evil hooker.
Emily: One thing it was funny cuz I was reading Scrooge McDuck and that was the comic that everybody was like.
Emily: what the fuck why is These comics, you know people talk about shoujo and stuff being about relationships.
Emily: I mean Scrooge McDuck has a lot of comedy and it has a lot of you know adventure and daring.
Scott: But it has Goldie.
Emily: and there is this one story and I was reading this last night where it's he's a minor and maybe Maybe I'll save the description for when you guys But this is actually a Really good Relationship story like it's a cute cute love story.
Rym: Yep, plus I just I feel like what's the?
Rym: does it have to be a relationship comic in order to count as a girl?
Rym: I mean, I guess what bothers me is that I remember when I was a kid, you know young like five six seven eight years old All the guys would play with GI Joe get things, you know army stuff and all the girls would play with Barbies.
Rym: But all the girls would also play with GI Joe stuff, but the guys couldn't play with Barbies.
Scott: Yeah, see I feel sort of like what?
Scott: what we're being accused of here, right?
Scott: It's like you go to the toy store, right and you've got these sort of Barbie aisle where everything's pink, right?
Scott: You've got the aisle with all the action figures, you know Ninja Turtles and he-man and transformers, right?
Scott: That's sort of a guy I'll you know.
Rym: Also all the girls I knew totally played with he-man, right?
Scott: That's true.
Scott: But then all the other aisles like you've got the board game aisle the Lego aisle, right?
Scott: Game I was clearly aimed at man the video game Isle with just the blocks clearly and the dice and the jacks and those sorts of things, right?
Scott: and those are sort of like the everyone aisles.
Scott: and it's sort of like I feel that if we Mention either, you know action figury things or Barbie things, you know, then that is what sexist we.
Scott: basically everything we've mentioned here is a blocks I'll board game.
Scott: I'll kind of thing.
Scott: It's it's not for guys or for girls for everyone.
Scott: You know Mouse Guard is for everyone Scrooge McDuck is for everyone.
Scott: Jason's for everyone.
Scott: zombies are for everyone.
Scott: fables is for everyone.
Rym: Girl demographic that a guy doesn't run away.
Scott: spirit bone black sad watchmen V for Vendetta Those are all for everyone regardless of gender.
Scott: It's basically she's saying you didn't mention anything from the Barbie aisle and in a way that's more Sexist to mention things from the Barbie aisle, you know And I think that's partially because the sexism of Japan has sort of come over with their manga.
Scott: in a way I mean in the US we don't we have genres like science fiction.
Scott: We don't have genres like young boys.
Emily: Doesn't this relate back to remember when you had that big Big row with Clarissa over to Tara.
Rym: Is it show Joe Joe or Shonen?
Emily: No, it's hard sci-fi.
Emily: So what's the deal here, but it's it's the same sort of thing.
Emily: it's basically show Joe and Shonen has become kind of just a Term to mark what kind of magazine it was published in and whether more girls or more boys.
Emily: by it I mean, there's a there's a huge huge female readership for Shonen jump and most of the anime fans I knew who are girls were mostly fans of the the sports anime and the Shonen jump titles.
Rym: So I run into more girls who were fans of like I shield 21 then guys ever You know what?
Emily: I'd relate it to.
Emily: I like the analogy of the Barbie aisle but I always thought it was kind of like the people who only thought of show Joe or Who were very strict in their definitions of the the boys comics versus girls comics.
Emily: It's kind of like those those oxygen television networks, you know They have these television networks that are supposedly for women and these television networks for men like sport TV.
Emily: We're hardcore.
Emily: Well, actually the the programming is Is really kind of lame especially on the on the women's.
Rym: what really bothers me is I feel like Whenever something is made like this is for guys.
Rym: It's usually something that has universal appeal.
Rym: But if it's something that's for girls, it's often something really lame.
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Emily: it's like the man show.
Emily: Do you remember the man show the man show?
Scott: I like them.
Scott: I like the man show before they change the people on.
Rym: my mom like the man show a lot more than I Did.
Emily: I only saw it once.
Emily: it's like girls bouncing around and trampolines like whoo, but it was definitely tongue-in-cheek.
Rym: There's definitely that little bit of a little thing.
Emily: It's like I see all these posters in the subway.
Emily: for What the oxygen network.
Emily: and it's always like bulging.
Emily: you remember bulging fries.
Emily: Oh my god We are fat women who need to lose weight before our wedding and it was just like wrong.
Emily: It's so many levels.
Emily: It was so bad.
Rym: But then there's the also a dingo a chill baby network Which is nothing.
Rym: but I'm a wife and my husband either murdered or stole my kids and I have to get them back.
Scott: It's like I don't watch TV hardly ever but like if I'm at my parents house like sometimes like, you know The spike TV will have like a James Bond marathon and then everyone will watch.
Emily: They had by star Star Wars on there a while ago.
Scott: Yes, but it's like for everybody but the women like the lifetime channel will never have anything anyone in my house wants to watch ever.
Scott: Well, you really well actually there was when I was a kid I would watch like the the supermarket game show on there, you know, I used to watch that too cuz I was really good.
Scott: Yeah, it's like friggin go for the hams.
Scott: What's wrong with you?
Scott: You know why?
Rym: cuz?
Rym: the only people I guess in a traditional household, you know Who goes to the grocery store the wife and the kids?
Rym: So we would have known and the wife would have known but the husband's out like wrestling crocodiles.
Scott: I think the thing is is that labeling a comic for girls or for guys is more sexist than saying just Here's the freaking comic.
Scott: Great.
Rym: I said in Japan how many girls just read the comics that are labeled for guys?
Rym: How many guys read the comics labeled for girls?
Rym: Yeah, the real issue is that in America Especially we have this thing where it seems like pot like popular culture maybe outside of geekdom But like normal like the average person.
Rym: if you ask them if sci-fi like what is sci-fi aimed at?
Rym: They'll probably say it's aimed at guys.
Rym: I I get this impression that a lot of people think that like Science fiction or anything geeky or anything nerdy is a guy thing and it seems like they love to see.
Emily: I feel fantasy is actually I've always had the impression that there are both like nerdy guys and lots and lots and lots of fantasy girls.
Rym: Yeah, but I feel like they're two different camps.
Rym: like fantasy fantasy for guys is you know, like the woman Jane Melton bikini straddling that stuff is so painful.
Rym: I hate that Bristles.
Scott: Well, see that's the separate thing that is sort of plagued.
Scott: I guess Japanese and American comics is just the the high quantity of cheesecake all around.
Scott: It's just you know, I think that sort of makes it hard for you know, girls and comics in general.
Scott: I think that's sort of why there needs to be like this Almost shoujo kind of.
Scott: you know labeling.
Scott: This is for girls so that you don't you know, because everything else is horrible cheesecake and it's sort of scary Like you go into like a comic forum and it's like, you know, if people like actually have you know a discussion people be like Yeah, it's a sexist and it's you know crap and whatever.
Scott: but then it's scary how many people they're like Like my cheesecake leave alone.
Scott: Or they'll be like, you know, they'll be like every day.
Scott: They'll like put up three random comic covers.
Scott: It's like vote for which one's the best and I'll be like Oh number two is the best and someone will be like I'd vote for number two But number one has big cleavage and I'm like what the fuck is wrong with you.
Emily: Yeah, well must it must sell because they've got like these three hundred dollar figurines in the comic book store of like.
Rym: Are they?
Rym: are they busts?
Emily: But you know, I guess I think of comics.
Emily: I I always associate comics to movies, you know, because they're basically a cross-between Literature like a prose novel and a movie, you know some of my favorite comics almost read like reading a storyboard where they're very cinematic very you know the the shots from Have the same sort of pacing as a as an animated film.
Emily: but I guess it's kind of like you take the list of a hundred greatest films ever made and you look at that and Say, okay How many of these are so-called chick flicks?
Emily: or how many of these are so-called gross out cut according to the person who?
Rym: emailed us as far as I would imagine that she would rate most of them as Intended for a male audience.
Scott: exactly what the top two are like.
Scott: what the Godfather, right?
Scott: That's a guy movie.
Scott: It's a mafia movie.
Scott: It's for guys, right?
Scott: Yes, I can go.
Rym: the IMDb list didn't see more but you know, well, I'll admit I had actually never heard of the comic She suggested.
Scott: yeah me either.
Emily: Well, I've actually looked at skeleton key and I Don't know it doesn't?
Emily: it's one of those manga.
Emily: That doesn't really Strike me.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So here's the top of IMDb right now, right?
Scott: We got Shawshank Redemption and Godfather tied.
Scott: Dark Knight Godfather part two good bad and the ugly pulp fiction Schindler's List.
Rym: Well, those
Scott: who's nest
Emily: that's the.
Scott: I know I know but it's like that's like democracy.
Emily: You need to do the one.
Emily: That's all.
Scott: He's not too far off.
Scott: Some stuff is far like Dark Knight doesn't belong.
Rym: This is always half movies that deserve it and half movies that came out recently.
Rym: But the ones that come out read like Dark Knight is gonna fall off that list within a year to like halfway down.
Emily: Yeah, man, city of gods at 18 hot But obviously that's a good movie intended for guys, but like in terms of of comics that That would play well to a female audience.
Emily: I mean what exactly do these people who say, you know I want to show Joe novel.
Emily: What are they looking for?
Emily: Are they looking for a story with a lot of relationships?
Emily: Are they looking?
Emily: You know, are they looking for pretty boys?
Emily: Are they looking for?
Emily: You know hearts and sparkles.
Emily: I'm not sure what it is.
Emily: I suppose it varies from person to person But I'm not sure what it is that they want in their comics.
Emily: that I don't know.
Rym: I have a feeling that these people like her and you know I'm using the person who wrote to us as kind of an example of all of them.
Rym: But I feel like they if they go to a panel like this They're expecting to see us showing them.
Rym: so you're like super show Joey manga.
Rym: Here is the exact equivalent from other countries.
Scott: Yeah, that's not the goal of our panel It's you know, I even said that it's like our goal is not to just show you.
Scott: Hey, look, here's something that's exactly the same as I don't know What's low but no, I have one of my mind.
Emily: what's the what?
Emily: I can't read your mind Scott?
Scott: The one with the with the four guys and the one that doesn't narrow down?
Scott: no, it's like they're like the four.
Scott: It is fucking awesome, but it's like.
Scott: do you want me to just show you what the you know French honey or a dongle is?
Scott: What's the point of that?
Scott: It's you know, if they're the same thing, they're the same thing Why not?
Scott: point is to show you different things that are not like manga because it's not.
Scott: you know You like manga already.
Scott: here are non manga that are the same.
Scott: It's you like manga.
Scott: You're a comics fan.
Scott: Why are you ignoring comics from every other country?
Scott: These are good comics from other countries that you will like also if you would just read them and stop only reading things that are from Japan.
Rym: Because I can't you know black said everyone seemed really interested in black.
Rym: sad and that's the one you can't get.
Emily: Oh my god that's a good comic though people might put be put off because it's anthro and that would be such a shame.
Scott: because I hate when People look at the anthropomorphic comics and go Well, I think that's a good way to push that an anime con where there's more likeliness of acceptance of the anthro.
Scott: then Yeah, actually, I've noticed a lot of French comics tend to go for this answer.
Scott: I've been looking at a few more and it's seriously, you know, I tell everybody There's.
Emily: there's the stigma against you know, drawing anything anthro now.
Emily: It's it's been a staple of animation.
Emily: I mean funny animals have been around Mickey Mouse man Bugs bunny attractive Okay, you know, but I mean like look she's like.
Scott: I just listened to an interview with the guy who translated dungeon into English.
Scott: You did a show on dungeon, you know way back.
Scott: Yeah dungeon is an anthro right and actually from that show.
Scott: I learned about this other French comic called ordinary victories.
Scott: that's from That I've heard it's about the Algerian war and something Historical comics.
Rym: Yeah a lot of historical action as we were told by an ambassador a cultural ambassador Who happened to be set up at the New York comic-con last year?
Rym: Basically, he had this booth all by himself and there was.
Rym: he had like an assistant and no one was looking at the stuff.
Rym: There was just all these French comics and they were basically saying look France has awesome comics.
Emily: Seriously it's right cool about because I really like French comics and animation because I feel like they combine you know the serious nature of Japanese comics with a lot of the Emphasis on figure drawing and fine arts that you sometimes find in American animation.
Rym: I mean, I spent a good half hour just flipping through these books.
Emily: It's called like in France.
Emily: people call it the ninth art and they view comics more as a fine art instead of like The other eight are I don't know like music like paintings sculpt The muses.
Emily: I think it's based on the muses.
Emily: so like they have they have Calliope and all that.
Scott: but What news goes with with comics?
Emily: it's a made-up music Talks in bolded text.
Rym: Anyway what I was gonna say is um, I am big centimeter is stupid.
Rym: I know actually it's not that bad.
Rym: Yeah, as I was saying The Syrians came down like a wolf on the fold.
Rym: their cohorts were gleaming in purple.
Scott: That's enough of that.
Emily: I'm gonna kick you but It when I talked about The the comics we discussed in the beginning of this show I said, you know it we focused a lot more on the less superficial aspects of it like the art Nothing like your stereotypical manga art your your characters.
Emily: It doesn't really fit any of the.
Emily: you know The things you would see in the big-eye smallmouth role-playing guide as like sample characters.
Emily: There's no magical girl.
Rym: I wonder if even if we'd shown like a super romantic Has a magical girl we talking about Man.
Emily: I love that comic so much.
Emily: It's ridiculous I want to make a Scott Pilgrim dating game and runaways has a bunch of magical girls.
Emily: Also, that's true.
Rym: Yeah, we talked about runaways too.
Emily: I forgot about that.
Scott: Scrooge McDuck has an evil magical girl.
Emily: Yeah She's not exactly a girl.
Emily: She's more like a hag.
Scott: What a hag is female She's not.
Rym: she's more like I guess watching DuckTales like I remember as a kid.
Rym: I hated her.
Rym: She was evil and horrible, but reading the comic.
Rym: It's more like she's.
Rym: I kind of like her.
Rym: You feel kind of bad because she's always desperate That she calls them poof bombs and she throws them.
Emily: I Don't know.
Emily: I feel like What I like in my comics.
Emily: is I like good art, right?
Emily: But I'm not picky about.
Emily: it has to be a certain kind of art.
Emily: It doesn't have to have big eyes It doesn't have to have small noses.
Emily: that kind of.
Emily: well, it could be xkcd But it's one thing I'm very very set on is that it's got to have Depth, you know either that or it's got to be hella funny, you know, it could be a total space ghost.
Rym: All the comics we talked about are like important like all ages all appeal amazing kind of all ages.
Emily: Yeah, I mean, I think I wouldn't give my six-year-old The Dark Knight.
Rym: I totally remember I watched vampire hunter D in the early days of fourth grade.
Scott: Your I wouldn't give The Walking Dead to someone who wasn't in like at least middle school.
Emily: It would freak kids.
Rym: one of the first real books I ever read was Stephen King's skeleton crew followed shortly thereafter by tales of horror and the macabre a collection of Lovecraft stories.
Scott: It's alright, you know Dark Knight Returns.
Scott: You got to be at least middle of high school or something Runaways, you should be in middle or high school probably.
Emily: Yeah It's more like to really relate to this kind of story.
Emily: You've got to be above a certain age or a certain maturity level.
Scott: Yeah, even reading Scrooge McDuck in elementary school It'd be okay, but you wouldn't really fully get the deal.
Rym: Having a multi-layered thing where a kid can watch it and enjoy it.
Rym: on one level you're older you have more experience you watch it You enjoy it on this wholly different level.
Emily: That's exactly how I was with McDuck because I Collected those comics as a kid and then when Scott got the digest I was just reading it the other day and it's it's like it all comes back to me But I pick up on so many more jokes.
Scott: Are you doing Scrooge McDuck?
Scott: That's a guy's Right, he's all rough-and-tumble and mining in Alaska Because we've totally served been riffing on Someone named satellite, you know their email was kind of okay.
Scott: No, I did.
Scott: the reply I sent to them was basically, you know We were aware that you know before we did the thing that we weren't really doing any sort of.
Scott: you know Stuff that was show Joey in any sort of way, but you know now that I think about it, you know afterwards It's like hey, you know, I look at this list of comics He talked about and you know what?
Scott: I think actually more these are you know appealing to?
Scott: Both genders and you know the fact that she said really, you know, watchmen just look at the name Definitely shows that she hasn't read it and doesn't know what she's really.
Rym: Yeah, oh my god, I've read watchmen like four times I Don't know.
Scott: It's I'm gonna read it again as soon as the hardcover edition shows up.
Rym: actually, they just solicited the international edition of it and I'm like, uh, Well, I just lent it actually cuz one of my co-workers like never really read comics.
Rym: He's like a. he does doctoral stuff and he's really into I guess literature.
Scott: He's a doctor.
Scott: He'll understand it.
Rym: Well, the thing is it's fun.
Rym: He's mighty.
Rym: He gave a lecture and he was.
Rym: he exempted this whole thing about Guy Fawkes and remember remember the 5th of November.
Scott: He never read.
Scott: be a friend that it did know.
Rym: and he never said he didn't even know there was a movie.
Rym: So when everyone didn't even know there was a movie, no, he just didn't pay attention.
Rym: So all the kids in his class were like, yeah Guy Fawkes Yeah, and they all knew about it.
Rym: and he was like How do you?
Rym: and they're like there was a movie?
Rym: and he didn't see the movie.
Rym: But then he'd mentioned it to me and I was like, yeah, there's a comic - it's one of the greatest comics ever written.
Rym: And then he's like one of you know, what's the best comic ever written?
Rym: So the next day I gave him our copy of Watchmen Yeah, and he read it and he gave it back to me and he said that was interesting Interesting that she gives him civilized news.
Rym: Well, I'm gonna give him V for Vendetta because he specifically wanted it and then I got it.
Rym: I was gonna lend him your Dark Knight Returns, but it looks like someone else borrowed it.
Rym: I can't find.
Scott: Oh, is it?
Scott: I got to add to my board.
Rym: I can't find it anywhere.
Scott: Actually, I have I lent my grandma, you know, this this Will Eisner hardcover Which is sort of like the best place to start with Will Eisner and she lost it or something.
Scott: I gotta go buy it again.
Rym: She probably lent it to one of her friends.
Scott: I don't know where it is, but I got like the reading circle of all grandmas.
Scott: Yeah, I gotta go get it.
Emily: So is it?
Emily: is it one of his more?
Emily: Slice of life.
Scott: Well, all his stuff is slice of life.
Rym: Yeah, I thought slice of life was a bad word.
Rym: It's like realistic it's gritty it's it's human stories Because anime world order going on and on about oh, it's a slice of life anime.
Scott: Well, there's different.
Scott: I mean the slice of life anime.
Scott: at least the ones they're talking about and there are a bunch of them tend to be.
Scott: you Know watch someone's, you know, just everyday happenings, you know, someone goes to school la la la la.
Scott: There's a cat along the way to school.
Rym: My 10th grade English teacher literature, you know, he was like the best literature teacher ever.
Rym: He was the one who gave me the lively art of writing which is like my Bible when it comes to writing.
Rym: But I remember he went on and on about this exact thing and how yeah I think he said slice of life is more often than not a code word for no plot Couldn't think of.
Scott: one wrote the story anyway, but human interest, you know is sort of you know It sort of feels okay to call it slice of life when it because it is a slice of life.
Scott: So this is what life is like.
Scott: and here's a piece of all stories.
Rym: or human interest or no one would read them right No.
Scott: But like when someone says human interest story like especially the will Eisner stories and also like the ojihiro tatsumi stories It's like look here is you know something that is you know true?
Scott: humanity, you know people real real person in a real horrible situation like a like a homeless guy who had Cardboard blocks blown away or something, you know even worse than that That's like a wussy example because I'm not I can't come up with ones like they do.
Scott: but you know And that's that's what the spirit and all of you know Eisner stuff is all about and tatsumi also is you know.
Scott: Look here is you know a horrible horrible real human circumstance and it shows you something about.
Scott: you know Human nature and in stark contrast, it's it's rough It's not you know Just someone living their everyday life.
Emily: watch them as they go the end at some random point I feel like Well, we're back on the subject of what is a girl comic what is a guy comic?
Emily: it feels like you're talking about things people can relate to.
Emily: seems like all great media books music etc.
Emily: is That that's remembered throughout the ages?
Rym: Tends to be things that both genders can relate to to some definitely You know, I just I feel like a lot of people and not just this person will always Lump a lot of things that actually have mass appeal and say that they have male appeal.
Emily: Well, you know, there's always my feminist argument that since we live in a Patriarchal society everything is man the patriarchy and the patriarchy and it's cylindrical objects.
Scott: Oh No cylinders.
Rym: I You know someone.
Rym: I did not come up with this someone else said this but I think it rings very true.
Rym: The reason there is so much male phallic imagery in the world is that vaginas are complicated.
Scott: Yeah, I mean there's some Carcassonne tiles that look like.
Emily: I Think we've rebutted that thoroughly.
Rym: Boys and girls do you want more Emily in the show?
Emily: One more thing I want to say in case you're listening girl who wrote the email, I'm sorry We picked on you so much.
Rym: No, we're not.
Scott: But I didn't feel like we were picking on you.
Scott: I was mostly just it's sort of like I agreed in a way and that we didn't really mention any comics that are girl Specific.
Scott: you brought up a point and we're like, yes, you're right It's like we didn't mention any toys from the Barbie Isle, but I feel most of the things we mentioned You know the vast majority.
Scott: you can sort of argue maybe Dark Knight Returns of Sutton if you really wanted to right But that's the least.
Scott: again or tastic exactly the pretty much everything we mentioned is a you know Something that appeals to everyone regardless of gender and I you know, I don't think we really you know.
Scott: Pick you know picked any things that were.
Scott: this is for guys and girls won't like it, you know We did but we did a separate panel on that.
Emily: Recommendations about comics that I like that have a female perspective.
Emily: I really like Queen and Country and White out.
Emily: what's what's that author's name?
Scott: Greg Rucka.
Emily: He writes awesome female character.
Rym: Yes, white out.
Rym: Oh my god.
Emily: Oh, yeah, they're not.
Scott: he also wrote just bad.
Scott: He also wrote Gotham Central, which is focus has a police woman, right?
Scott: Yeah, it's mostly about you know There's a. it's basically about all the two different shifts of police officers the night shift in the day shift in Gotham City with a tiny Bit of Batman barely any Batman,
Emily: but it
Scott: the Renee Montoya is like the the one of the more Focused on characters that you know, there's a whole bunch of this female and male police woman.
Scott: It's like the real police people, you know, it's.
Scott: it's it's mixed up properly and such.
Scott: but then I think after that That series is over now, but I think Renee Montoya went on to be like a superhero of some kind or some shit.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I have my own recommendation.
Rym: There's the classic.
Rym: I was kidnapped by lesbian pirates from outer Before anyone thinks Scott's joking.
Rym: no that comic does rule.
Rym: it's really awesome.
Emily: I thought it was hilarious.
Rym: It's like this art and it's just awesome.
Emily: Well, it's like set in the 1950s and it's like a total takeoff of like 1950s sci-fi schlocky comic Like Velma, what are some of the?
Emily: Yeah, it's so funny.
Emily: I love it.
Emily: But Yeah stuff like that.
Emily: And of course Scott said that the mix line was canceled.
Emily: But what I've read of those they're they're decent.
Emily: They're kind of like American.
Emily: I like them New York for it's okay.
Emily: It was like, you know, all right Some of the girls are kind of they don't show a lot of self-control, but like oh well You're your college.
Scott: I also saw that the so-called plot twist coming about 20 pages New York really?
Scott: Well if you want to read The way they handled it once it happened was sort of bleh, it's like oh, why are you being all like three-year-olds?
Scott: Yeah, you could you could handle this like adults.
Emily: Yeah, just tell them off.
Emily: feel like what the fuck is your problem?
Emily: Okay, that's kind of a spoiler.
Rym: But anyway, whatever Yeah, it's not that much of a spoiler.
Rym: We've spoiled worse for less.
Emily: Okay, and Emiko superstar and stuff like that, but that lines canceled.
Emily: Bye.
Rym: Emiko superstar was also really good Okay, but then again I feel like people who thought anyone who thought that we focused on male oriented oriented comics would have read Emiko superstar and not Thought.
Rym: it was their girly comic.
Emily: Maybe who knows they want boys kissing other boys and maybe that will come someday to American comics.
Scott: But right now it's boys kissing boys and you can get quite a few of those at the mocha.
Rym: Yeah Not that I would know.
Rym: I just saw.
Rym: for some reason my brain started making this elaborate scene between Superman and Batman where Knows this?
Scott: and won't Making some Marvel DC doujins?
Rym: I'll bet that it's already out there.
Scott: Oh, there was that Batman doujin with Where Superman killed out?
Scott: No, it was like wasn't it?
Scott: like Batman and Kiki's livery services?
Scott: Batman Why or is it bad?
Scott: It was Batman and something.
Scott: I forget what it was.
Rym: I think I would have known about that.
Scott: Oh Batman and something.
Rym: Hold on and Robin Hold on.
Emily: Come on search in.
Scott: I forget what it was.
Rym: What are you gonna search for Batman?
Rym: and I Don't think that's gonna bring it up.
Rym: I think you failed.
Scott: No, hold on.
Rym: I got it was kidnapped Scott and I refuse to pause because I'm doing this complicated two-track sync thing here.
Scott: Alright, alright.
Scott: Well Scott, uh, I think I might have failed.
Rym: I think you failed.
Emily: Yes, that was also epic fail and Emily was very displeased.
Rym: yes, you do cut, okay We'll do karaoke.
Rym: We got to get to cut, okay We got to get you going off in Conrad to come up from DC to do some karaoke.
Emily: I want my friends from Queens come up and do cut.
Emily: Okay.
Rym: All right, I think this show this is over Over over it's done.
Scott: There was a doujin.
Emily: You can tell them.
Rym: next show you can link to it in the forum, okay, by the way people I'm glad you're all joining the forum people who we told you to join the forum.
Rym: The rest of you should because all the people we meet at comms always say they're not in the forum.
Rym: But at the same time if you join the forum and you can't spell or you don't capitalize well You're gonna get banned like right away just banned.
Emily: you will be punished by everyone else there.
Scott: Yes We're not.
Scott: we're not doing this to like scare you away right?
Scott: we want you to come in.
Scott: It's just we want that.
Scott: this is this is supposed to be something that you know Don't?
Scott: you shouldn't be scared away like.
Scott: oh, no people are gonna pick on me for a bad grammar.
Scott: You should be saying hooray I want to go to these forums where people are picked on for bad grammar because I know that unlike other forums Like 4chan where it's just like oh my god dick girls It's gonna be actually all the posts are forced to be Intelligent and well thought out and have effort put into them.
Scott: So it's not out me.
Scott: It's a less scary forum unless you can't write seriously.
Rym: And if you can't write I had a problem with don't.
Rym: like.
Rym: I came home and like I had this weird problem with steam and I Couldn't connect any games and I wanted to place a menace.
Rym: So I searched for you know the error to see what I found and all the links were to forums all over the internet and Like I don't think I saw a single Conversation.
Rym: I don't think I saw a single capital letter.
Rym: And I'm talking on like the official steam forums or like the official forums of some other to not be named podcast.
Rym: Good God, it's good.
Emily: God funny though, cuz we call it the ivory tower and everything.
Rym: But yeah extra life.
Emily: if you got cards the people who join there they actually enforce the rules themselves.
Rym: Yeah, I feel like I get to appoint some more moderators.
Rym: Mr.
Scott: Period really Yeah, I sort of don't.
Scott: I sort of on the one hand like that everyone is pushing.
Scott: You know the spelling but I sort of don't like that, you know, some people sort of think aha I'm spelling and they're not I'm gonna be the boss and it's sort of like they're The moderate.
Scott: yeah, there's certainly be a little jerky about.
Scott: it's like alright dude chill out It's not your you know, you don't go set you don't go, you know with the quoting and then say that dumbass go away You just edit it and move on.
Rym: that's that's how the moderators yeah, because frankly if they don't shape up I'll just ban him summarily.
Rym: Yeah, you don't need to Look court-martial that's basically I decide if I want to ban you.
Scott: being a jerk about is not necessary your big Thor.
Rym: Only I get to be a jerk about it.
Emily: That's right Hammer of doom, it's not even Scott.
Rym: It's all me.
Rym: I'm the jerk, right?
Rym: Anyway, cut we're done.
Scott: We're done.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our crapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew calm or you can send audio feedback Via audio.
Scott: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Scott: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.