Scott: It's Thursday January 24th.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Scott: I'm Rym and this is GeekNights tonight desert bus.
Rym: Let's do this This weekend just couldn't come faster.
Rym: I'm tired to put it lightly.
Scott: I got like at work.
Scott: I had some works to do right and some of the works were Works that I like to do and some were not.
Scott: and I've done all the works I like to do.
Scott: and now I'm just sitting there with these two pain in the ass works I don't want to do.
Scott: they just suck.
Rym: Well, don't do them.
Rym: Just quit.
Scott: I'm doing them incredibly slowly and mostly goofing off.
Scott: The problem is there's not enough new stuff on the internet to keep me amused all day at work And it's getting pretty painful.
Rym: You could get a job where you actually I don't know work.
Scott: I work.
Scott: I just do all the work so fast faster than they give it to me Because I'm so good at it.
Scott: And the only reason I haven't done all my work is because depending on the work They give me I either it's a it's a good work Which means I do it so fast like in a second like BAM.
Scott: that was awesome, and it's fun And I think it's really satisfying, but it takes like a minute only because I'm awesome Not because it was actually take a minute or this other work That would take a minute if I wanted to do it, and I felt like doing it.
Scott: But it doesn't because I'm a lazy slow ass and it's not pleasant.
Rym: so I take my sweet ass time And see I was in the opposite situation at the hospital where the work was all trivial But I had to rely on other people who didn't know what they were doing.
Rym: so as a result most of my time I just kind of twiddle my thumbs.
Rym: would twiddle my thumbs meant sit on YouTube.
Rym: Yeah, and now I have a job where I actually do work.
Rym: the problem is because I'm it's like the higher level like you know You call a tech support place.
Rym: There's like the level one guy level two guy like the levels going up The higher up you get like there's no more easy work.
Rym: any job that is given to you is not going to be simple.
Rym: Yeah, because if it could have been done easily or quickly someone else would have already done it.
Scott: Yeah, but I spent most of the day at work today like you know programming something for myself, but then I finished it.
Scott: I was like shit what I do now.
Rym: I got some things you could program.
Scott: What do you want?
Rym: I want a multiband dynamic range compander Written in lisp.
Scott: that's not gonna happen.
Rym: That's what I need.
Rym: well tough Yeah, I started to learn lisp, but I need some time.
Scott: I guess to actually write these things I think it's really just whether doing something for myself or for someone else.
Scott: like if I want to do it BAM it's done, but if I don't want to do it Huh people like to do things they like to do and therefore they tend to do them.
Scott: Oh gasps.
Rym: Oh well We're tired.
Rym: We'll see where the show goes.
Scott: so Yeah, I don't have a lot of confidence for the show cuz mean it's also an incredibly slow news week and thing of the day.
Rym: Hey, there was a new angry video game nerd.
Scott: It was okay.
Rym: It was pretty good.
Scott: This is average work.
Rym: Anyway, there's web comics coming out tomorrow and yesterday, but not today.
Scott: web comics.
Rym: Yeah Read a webcomic.
Scott: There's a new Perry Powell Fellowship this morning.
Rym: Oh snap.
Rym: I haven't read that.
Rym: Yeah Tell me what you got.
Rym: I'm gonna read my.
Scott: yeah, actually cuz there's no news I'm gonna do a geek back and it's a geek back about Video games, but wait a way to cross days.
Scott: Yeah, it usually do it on Tuesday, but I guess I forgot to do it.
Scott: I mean this email came in on January 8th And I guess if I don't do it now, I'm gonna forget to do it and I got nothing else to do.
Scott: So why the fuck not shrink ray?
Scott: Yeah, that's a good one.
Rym: Hahaha That is a good one.
Scott: Anyway, anyway, all right.
Scott: So let me read.
Scott: I'm gonna read this email and it's entirely.
Scott: it's from vicious Smith Which I assume is vicious, but it's vic hu s.
Rym: maybe he's a vic uis.
Scott: I've seen him around on some forums.
Scott: I think this is a longtime listener kind of guy doesn't?
Rym: isn't he one of those Dave and Joel people do or something?
Scott: He might be he might be.
Scott: anyway, let me read His emails short so I'm gonna read it in its entirety until I get to the the Just gonna read the whole thing.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: I'm a user of game fly and I've been angered with it lately.
Scott: My original intention was to play a bunch of crap games for a few days then send them back to play more crap games.
Scott: The problem is now.
Scott: I want to play better games and preview them before I decide to purchase them now.
Scott: Here are the problems.
Scott: The queue is filled with a Allegedly good games that are so popular I'll have to wait months for them to be available.
Scott: If I hold on to a game for more than a month or two I could have just bought it through eBay or some discount site.
Scott: I enjoy RPGs and RPGs are more involved than an action or RPG.
Scott: Okay Action RPG I guess.
Scott: So you have.
Rym: I haven't enjoyed an action RPG in a while.
Scott: So so have you guys used game fly and you think it's a waste of money to rent games 15 a month if you can Just wait for a good deal on games.
Rym: Well, it sounds like well, I guess you can answer this since this is your bit.
Scott: I mean ideally right if the game fly was as good as Netflix was right and you're in a situation Where you have more time to play video games than you have video games to play.
Scott: Gamefly seems like a good idea because you can buy the games that you know You're gonna play again and again and again forever.
Scott: I never want to get rid of and all those other games that are like Popular when they come out for a month or two and then they go away forever and no one ever thinks of them again.
Scott: You can just rent those from the game fly and then send them back when you're done with them.
Scott: or a lot of those games.
Scott: Do you play them once?
Scott: you never gonna play them again.
Scott: get them from the game fly send them back, right?
Scott: But I I was not aware, you know I knew game about game fly and all I knew was that it was the Netflix of video games.
Rym: It's all that used to be before that way back.
Rym: There was red octane.
Scott: red octane I don't know.
Scott: They still offer offer that service.
Scott: think so because right now they're they're making.
Rym: you know, guitar hero guitars Yeah, but back then I remember when I first got a ps1.
Rym: I paid $80 for it at Kmart and I then immediately.
Rym: then I spent like 20 bucks on a six-pin mod chip and I don't think other Than one game to test.
Rym: I never put a non Dance Dance Revolution game in there But you can't get real DDR in the u.s.
Rym: Least back then you couldn't.
Rym: there was USA makes which was possibly one of the worst contrivances ever brought up unto the world by man and I thought wait a minute.
Rym: All right, how am I gonna get these games?
Rym: I tried to pirate them and I found that every ps1 pirated game was actually just either something horrible or some sort of virus Exe like ISO exe.
Rym: Oh, wow.
Rym: I wonder what that is.
Rym: yep, but then I saw the red octane had import games and Regular games and you could rent them much like Netflix.
Rym: So I said, alright, I signed up for a one-month free trial.
Rym: I filled my queue with every DDR game that had ever been released in Japan.
Rym: When they came I immediately copied them and then sent them back.
Rym: two weeks later I canceled the account.
Rym: and I know at every game of DDR ever.
Scott: Yeah when I was in high school I had a friend who would go to Blockbuster copy the ps1 games of the CD burner then bring it back to Blockbuster essentially Effectively buying video games for $3 because he also had the mod chip.
Scott: But I don't think you can copy the ps3 in the Xbox games and the Wii game so easily.
Rym: No, you can't copy ps1 games so easily.
Rym: a lot a lot of CDs just wouldn't work.
Rym: And yeah, if you're one of those fools who bought a four-pin mod ship or one of those external mod chips half the time It didn't work.
Scott: Anyway, yeah, so I was unaware that there was actually a problem with This game fly service where if a game is popular, you can't get it right away.
Scott: That is bullshit.
Scott: I mean, I mean imagine if on Netflix if you put a movie in your queue 99.9% of the time that movies coming next.
Scott: there's never a situation where the movie is so popular.
Scott: You have to wait does any?
Scott: we never had that problem.
Rym: When was the last time we watched a Netflix?
Scott: I know but I mean even when we were super Netflix.
Rym: now even when before we Podcasted when we were both out of college had plenty of money nothing to do with ourselves We watched every Netflix the day it came and sent it back.
Scott: sometimes that day Yeah, and we never had a problem, you know waiting in a queue for something wait, and he says so Wait a minute.
Rym: if we quit doing GeekNights We can do stuff.
Rym: Yeah, we can.
Rym: we can play video games and watch movies.
Rym: Yeah, then fuck this.
Scott: Okay, but Yeah, if they're not gonna send you the games you want right away That seems like a pretty.
Scott: you know, it's not a. the service isn't living up to its usefulness.
Scott: So what's the point?
Rym: I think there's a simpler answer to his question.
Rym: He basically said well, I wanted to use product day.
Rym: So I bought product day and I wanted to do B C and D But now I wanted to do E and it turns out it doesn't do E. should I stop paying for it?
Rym: And the answer is yes.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: It's pretty simple.
Rym: You answered your own question.
Rym: You said well, it doesn't do what I wanted to do.
Rym: Should I still pay?
Scott: Yeah, I guess on paper.
Scott: It's a good idea.
Scott: if yours communism Yeah, if you're the kind of person who needs to play a lot more video games than you are able to buy I think Scott Johnson has gamefly does he and you want to?
Scott: you want to play more games than you can afford to buy and you don't have enough of them and You want to play a lot of games that you don't want to keep and you know You are you're willing to play crappier games then I guess it's a good idea.
Scott: Other than that, I guess it's you know, I guess the reality is it doesn't even do that and I'll admit I'll play.
Rym: Especially back when I had free time I would often play a subpar game.
Rym: Oh, yeah, you you get some enjoyment.
Rym: in fact if you have free time a lot of times a really bad game is almost fun in this cathartic kind of the quality of media you are willing to I guess consume goes down as Your free time increases.
Scott: the more free time you have the more willing you are to watch crappier things play crappier games and read.
Rym: Well, I think part of it's just that when you have more free time You're more willing to invest time on a risk that something may or may not be good.
Rym: Yep, I mean there are games that seem good and are good.
Rym: But after you play them for an hour They're not so fun anymore.
Rym: or games that would be good if you played them for four hours But they're not fun for an hour.
Rym: Yeah, and it's are you willing to give up that hour?
Rym: The answer is usually no nowadays.
Scott: Yeah, you have to be more discerning when you have less free time and yet you can afford to be less discerning when you have More free time.
Rym: Well, anyway, speaking of free time and things that are worthwhile.
Rym: I have a geek bite.
Scott: No, no.
Scott: now, I guess there's no news today for real.
Rym: Well, there's news and I could talk about.
Rym: I'm Legally barred from talking about the one thing I do find interesting and want to talk about.
Scott: Well, you could have just told me to talk about it.
Rym: Yeah, but what do you have to say other than whoa, how do you do that?
Rym: Oh Cuz that was the conversation we had a little while ago.
Scott: Okay, that's what you wanted to talk.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: What do you do?
Rym: Oh, how do you do it?
Rym: Oh, wow hmm, but the Scott for a long time has been meaning to read a Series of books the first of which is called Hyperion by an author named Dan Simmons.
Rym: Dan Simmons is an awesome author and Scott never got around to this Independently.
Scott: we got around to a lot of things.
Rym: independently of Alex trying to convince Scott to read Hyperion.
Rym: I have been trying to convince.
Scott: he wasn't trying to convince me.
Scott: I actually knew about the books from somewhere.
Scott: I asked him if he knew about them and he had them all.
Rym: Anyway, so I've been trying to tell Scott to read this other book called the terror and I remember when it dawned on Scott not Too long ago.
Scott: I get whenever anyone says terror.
Scott: I can't think.
Scott: I can't help but think about the stupid magic card Really?
Rym: I think about Cthulhu usually also There was.
Scott: was it an anime where it was like that terror?
Scott: Oh gassaraki.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: No, that's right.
Rym: We watched that show.
Scott: tell we watched it dubbed on VHS.
Scott: I own all the dubbed VHS's.
Rym: Wow this anyway, so it dawned upon Scott that the terror is written by the same person.
Rym: So very briefly the terror is a is a fictional book about the.
Rym: you know a novel if you will.
Rym: Well, well, I'll get to that because it is fiction But at the same time it edges very very very close to nonfiction.
Rym: You see it's about an expedition that was taken in the late or middle middling 1800s To find the Northwest Passage in the Arctic.
Rym: now This is a time when ships were mostly made out of wood and steam.
Rym: power was laughable.
Rym: So a bunch of guys got into two ships the HMS Erebus and the HMS terror and they go on Into the Northwest Passage.
Scott: What a great way to name your boat that's gonna go into the North Pole.
Rym: now I'm reading this book and I didn't.
Rym: I just read it.
Rym: I didn't do any research any backstory and oh, this book's awesome.
Rym: It's about some monster and it's kind of eerie and good and historical fiction.
Rym: But I got about three-quarters of the way through and I'm feeling okay about this book even though it's really tragic and really sad and really it.
Rym: it goes into the Procedural details of dealing with scurvy when you're alone in the Arctic and dying of frostbite You mean losing eye teeth and such.
Rym: yeah vomiting and diarrhea and blood all that Scurvy sucks.
Scott: don't get scurvy.
Rym: Even if you think you're it's gonna really help your pirate costume I think some guy at NYU got scurvy just because he didn't eat oranges For long enough.
Scott: How could you?
Scott: almost everything has vitamin C even bread some bread, you know.
Rym: I'm surprised that guy Greg's old roommate who did nothing but play Asheron's call never got scurvy.
Scott: Well, because he'd always go to Gracie's get a meal a decent meal and bring it back.
Scott: I mean as you know Gracie's wasn't the greatest food But it wasn't bad as bad as you know, you like to make fun of it for being and you know It's got to make it all the way to Gracie's.
Scott: it was nutritional.
Rym: So well barely I guess.
Rym: there there is the the the commonly known thing at RIT that freshman will have a more voluminous output of Feces than they did in their previous life do almost entirely to the composition of the food and Gracie's.
Rym: it's true.
Rym: But I got most of the way through this book and I'm digging it even though a lot of people are dying horribly and it's a really bleak depressing scary book.
Rym: and then randomly, I look on Wikipedia and I discover that this book is actually very close to what actually happened to these people and it's based on historical documents According to Wikipedia.
Rym: Well, no it actually is.
Rym: this book is Extremely well researched bit of historical fiction and is probably the thing is so the fiction is just the monster.
Rym: Well, here's the thing.
Rym: Everything that happens to these people is very realistic and is very probably very close to what actually happened to this expedition.
Rym: but There's a monster in the novel and you think alright the monster is obviously not real.
Rym: Well, once you realize what actually happened to these people the monster kind of makes sense.
Rym: Uh-huh in a realistic.
Scott: so they went insane and they all believed it was a monster possibly something like sort of a group You know Delusion.
Rym: well possibly due to the fact that there's a good chance that everyone on this expedition was suffering by lead poisoning Due to poorly canned food.
Scott: Oh in pride in lead cans.
Rym: Yeah lead solder around the seal.
Rym: Oh, so awesome, but I don't want to get in a lot of details about this book but if you like a very gritty very realistic very procedural story about the shall we say Difficulties of exploring the Arctic in a wooden ship with lead monsters in the 1800s.
Rym: And one thing you'll learn and this is this is definitely true British people exploring back then in the Arctic Didn't know shit about exploring in the Arctic and most of the problems they had were due to their own stupidity as you will learn.
Rym: Well, of course, they didn't know know what it done it before No, but they didn't even think that you'll see when you read the book.
Rym: They brought a lot of things with them that did not need to be brought with them and failed to bring things They did need to be brought.
Rym: possibly also I'd like to note that if you're going to out monster extinguisher if you're going to outfit shark into the Arctic and You're finding someone to make your food bring Batman.
Scott: I'd recommend Batman because that way he'll have always had the right tool at the right time.
Rym: They would add some canned food and then a boat shark repellent.
Rym: You know, there's no sharks up.
Scott: there Should be but polar bear repellent.
Rym: don't go with the lowest bidder.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, especially for the boat, but the the terror by Dan Simmons is a fantastic novel though It is not for the squeamish of stomach or light of heart things of the day.
Rym: It's really rare that I read a new webcomic.
Rym: I mean, I think dr.
Rym: McNinja and Wondermark are the most recent comics.
Rym: I've added to my the latest Wondermark.
Rym: It's good stuff, I don't know if that can beat stove cat.
Scott: no, it's not as good as dove cat But it's still.
Scott: it's pretty good.
Scott: I mean He's definitely doing a much more funniness lately.
Rym: and the thing is about that comic is a lot of the jokes He does or they've been done before.
Rym: it's not like.
Rym: oh, I haven't seen a joke like this before but sometimes his jokes original.
Rym: It's just the way there.
Rym: I don't know the style and the way it's done just always gets me.
Scott: It's fantastic poop jokes and top hat.
Rym: But I don't.
Rym: I didn't even look at what the rest of this comic is.
Rym: All I know is that I saw a link to it.
Rym: I guess the comic is called truck bearing kibble.
Rym: But all right it the.
Rym: the title of this comic is on executable and it's a Lego man and a Lego Pope and a Lego executioner and Lego gallows.
Rym: it is the only thing that could have made it better I guess if it had been the same Lego gallows that I always made as a kid.
Rym: you take that whip and you stick it On top of a Lego.
Scott: I made the gallows the same way with my Robin Hood's forest men playset.
Rym: I remember I got in trouble as a kid cuz my brother had his like Lego world.
Rym: I had mine and we'd fight.
Scott: See I always had all the forest men and I had these.
Scott: at first I got this one that was like these two trees.
Scott: Right, but one tree had a door and a platform, you know and the other one had a ladder.
Scott: and then there was a bridge that went from one tree to the other and all the Robin Hood guys would stay.
Scott: all the Robin Hood Lego guys would stand on it and shoot arrows, right?
Scott: Well, they wouldn't really shoot the arrows.
Rym: They'd hold it bow and arrow in one hand and smile, right?
Scott: Then I got this other.
Scott: they also had quivers on their backs.
Scott: Um, then I got it.
Scott: then I got his other Robin Hood Lego.
Scott: He playset where it was like this big tree like the whole thing opened up and it was at a door that would open and close like a like a port cutlass without spikes and it had a little Drawbridge.
Scott: and it was like a tree in the middle of the water and it was high quality.
Scott: So then I got a castle and I was big in those castles.
Rym: Yeah I remember when I got ice planet.
Rym: that was like the biggest hot shit to ever raise my press.
Scott: ice planet was wicked cool.
Scott: but all I ever had from ice planet was one guy in a snowmobile and it Orange ain't neon orange chainsaw.
Rym: See that's the thing.
Scott: The neon orange was like the most valuable so high and neon orange stuff was wicked cool with the blue and the chainsaws and Lego dudes the chainsaws to cut the ice.
Rym: Yeah, made out of the rarest substance in the world as far as those guys can tell a translucent neon orange Lego.
Rym: But I remember I got in trouble as a kid because you know My brother and I had our different Lego worlds and we were always war.
Scott: We're not doing a show about Lego.
Scott: No, you're gonna tell the story about the stupid space shuttle.
Rym: No, no, no I'm not gonna tell the whole story.
Rym: But I got in trouble when I I caught some of his spies that he'd stuck into my land.
Rym: so to make an example to the others I Had a public hanging and I left them all.
Scott: you brought it.
Scott: you brought it back Back around to the yellows, but I did.
Rym: I hung four of his Lego men as spies And I brought them on a little cart with a gallows in front of his base and left it in his room with a warning.
Rym: And then my mom yelled at me.
Scott: But I've been clever.
Rym: this joke is good on multiple levels and I'll leave it at that.
Rym: I think what helps one Everyone's smiling because they're like, oh man, yeah, of course and two it's just.
Rym: it's so perfect.
Rym: It's pretty good Alright, so what do you got for me?
Scott: Oh, it's pretty lame for things the day if Rym has to go to a webcomic.
Scott: So I'm even lamer here.
Scott: formula one starts again in like 40 some odd days right before formula one begins again the next season and You know it's now's about the time and people start to show off all the new cars and the new Ferrari is like God, I don't think I've ever seen a better car in my life.
Scott: You got to look at this thing.
Scott: It's just the odd blows you away And they even show the steering wheel is more complex than ever.
Scott: I don't know how the fuck the people drive these fucking things.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: But yeah There's a the f1 webs the official formula.
Scott: one website is actually redone and it's now no longer sucks ass.
Scott: So they actually have this really convenient Well-designed gallery where you can easily look at all the pictures the new cars.
Scott: So I'll just link you to that and you can go.
Scott: ooh and ah pictures of new cars that are awesome Speaking of which as soon as it gets warm up.
Rym: We got to do that go-kart thing.
Rym: We keep talking about never do it.
Rym: Yes, we have the money.
Rym: We can do it.
Scott: the key words when it's warm because woman it's gold.
Rym: But speaking of just going and doing things.
Rym: I don't know if you've been able to guess from the title of the episode, but We at the front row crew have a long-standing tradition of every year Like.
Rym: I guess part of it's that we we did things in college when we were poor.
Rym: So things we did had to be like.
Rym: we had to never take risks or we just lose out because we couldn't afford to make A mistake like driving to Otakon.
Rym: if we'd so much as gotten lost We might not have had enough money to buy gas to get home.
Scott: Well, maybe you I had a little buffer, but I was.
Scott: I was.
Scott: I was bad but not as bad as you were.
Scott: you were.
Scott: You had to.
Scott: you know have people feed you.
Scott: I didn't but I still would go there with a pile of money and then leave Empty-handed and then you know, yeah
Rym: Yeah but Like after Kyle we kind of got set in our ways for every year like the big trip of the front row crew would be We'd all go to Otakon every year and then we'd have a road rally to Wildwood, New Jersey Where we'd stay at Scott Johnson's Beach House for the week.
Scott: Yeah, and Wildwood is great, you know.
Scott: but the thing about Wildwood is that the reason we did that is because It was sort of like you went with Otakon So you sort of were more efficient use of your vacation time Yeah, and also it was partly that that was kind of for a long time.
Rym: That was the era where the front row crew was scattered to the wind.
Rym: Everyone got out of college and all went out and got jobs.
Rym: It was before we'd all kind of come back together in upstate.
Scott: Well upstate or downstate, New York, depending on your perspective Yeah, but it was also really cheap because we someone had a house there.
Scott: We'd had to pay for a hotel.
Scott: Transportation was by car, you know, we could carpool Yeah, and also being on vacation for a week like that was public and free.
Rym: It definitely added the aspect of you don't have to do shit.
Rym: We get there and we'd spend two days just laying in the house doing nothing.
Scott: I mean you go on a vacation somewhere like Disney World or something, you know, which can be fun.
Scott: I've done that twice.
Scott: you got to like get up and run around and do things.
Scott: You know if you go to the public beach and your friend owns the beach house, you could just be like I wake up whenever you want.
Scott: Take your sweet ass time.
Scott: Nothing cut nothing really cost you money, but food and arcade games.
Rym: Yes when you're hungry There's infinite amounts of fried things.
Scott: when you're more hungry need real food.
Scott: You got to get in the car for five minutes, but that's okay because then you go to that diner.
Rym: I love that diner.
Scott: It's a good dinner.
Rym: It's not the best honor in the world, but it's in the upper some percent.
Scott: I like the Russo's.
Rym: Other is almost as good as the de Bellas the Russo's we're.
Rym: a small sandwich is too much and a large sandwich is fucking too much Exactly.
Rym: I remember the first time I went there.
Rym: I was like, oh man that large is eight bucks.
Rym: I'm getting in Scott Johnson's like you should reconsider like those where the sides are better than the meal.
Rym: Yeah, chocolate pudding and that cheese broccoli thing she's broccoli.
Rym: Oh That guy's out of business anyway.
Rym: So part of the appeal to was that you know, the crew is somewhat scattered.
Rym: We didn't get to see each other for like we'd all get together for things.
Rym: But the week of awesome as it was called the first time we did it was kind of this chance.
Rym: It was like our Mecca our homecoming.
Rym: the whole front row crew would go to Otakon and have a crazy time But we wouldn't really hang out because Otakon you got to do stuff And then we go to the beach and we just hang out for a week and it was kind of like the annual reset of The crew but
Scott: also New Year's and that was it though.
Rym: Yeah But now we all live together and we all were all relatively successful in our in our relative domains.
Rym: And now it's to the point where I feel like we're young and I want to sew wild oats as it were.
Scott: Yeah, I mean my plan was always, you know, I like at first like it was sort of unthinkable that we would not go to.
Scott: So it was like a natural thing like of course I go to Wildwood and I was trying to make plans to do another Vacation in addition to that.
Scott: like I want to go on a real vacation, you know Europe or something to see old shit That's always scotch dick.
Rym: I want to go where the old shit is.
Scott: look at it.
Scott: That's pretty much what I want to do.
Scott: is I want to go where their castles and ruins and you know South America like Aztecs and Incas.
Rym: that is the main reason why I want to go to Turkey so much.
Scott: Well, because you want to see that specific old shit because that podcast got you interested in that.
Rym: Specifically, I just want to go to the the Mediterranean in general.
Scott: Yeah, I've been to Israel which is technically Mediterranean and part of it, you know and Mediterranean is awesome by me.
Scott: See some grease see some Italy.
Scott: I could do that.
Rym: Well, we were thinking about this and then we kind of suddenly realized.
Rym: Wait a minute.
Rym: We're young and we have no Responsibilities and we have money.
Rym: There's.
Rym: there is no reason not to go out and do the things we want to do now while we're still young enough to enjoy.
Scott: Also part of the problem is I don't have enough vacation days right - that's you yeah, but I don't have enough vacation days to do all the conventions and things and then also go to Wildwood and then also do Something else.
Scott: So the idea came and I said, you know what?
Scott: I've been to Wildwood enough times.
Scott: I'm not gonna go there for us in my life.
Scott: Let's do something besides.
Rym: that instead of that and Coincident to that was the idea that why don't we do one of those things that people always say they do but they won't one Of those things that we've always said?
Rym: we'll do that.
Rym: We won't.
Rym: let's go on our road trip.
Scott: Well, not exactly not exactly the full-on road trip.
Rym: Well, the thing is the original plan was yeah Why don't we just get a Winnebago and drive from here to California?
Rym: And we're like, yeah Yeah, and we're planning our vacation days for that.
Scott: It's a boat.
Rym: We're like, alright, let's see if we start You know here and we go up through New York and we could stop it like Cedar Point along the way Stop in Chicago,
Scott: and
Rym: then I realized that once we get to like Minneapolis
Scott: Once you pass like Mount Rushmore, there's nothing.
Rym: once you've had Milwaukee There's nothing until you hit Mount Rushmore and then there's nothing again.
Rym: Nothing.
Rym: Nothing to you.
Rym: It's Spokane, but there's nothing in Spokane.
Scott: Yeah, unless you go you got to go way south or to like Vegas to get something.
Scott: It's just the middle of nowhere.
Scott: So we
Rym: realized that all right, that's infeasible and also probably wouldn't be that fun Unlike because then it would basically be the week of awesome, but we'd all be sitting in a Winnebago Living out of it and instead of living at a beach house
Scott: and at all that and during the that time someone would have to Be driving.
Rym: Well, I think the gas yeah, that was the other thing that got me.
Rym: It's like all right, Winnebagos get what six miles to a gallon.
Rym: We're gonna drive what 2,000 miles.
Rym: how much does gas cost?
Scott: Yeah, the thing is, you know, if you spend the same amount of time in a hotel a nice hotel It's gonna you know be the same amount of money.
Scott: ish, you know, so the gas while it's expensive You got to realize that gas is instead of your hotel cost.
Scott: so it kind of works out.
Rym: Yeah But at the same time part of the reason you want to go on a road trip is not to sit in a car The whole time.
Rym: yeah with your friends you can you can sit in your house playing a DS game exactly and all and well.
Rym: Oh see the country, but I I don't want to dis South Dakota and Wyoming and Montana and Idaho But I have better things to do with my time.
Rym: I've driven through Ohio.
Rym: I know what that's like.
Scott: the people in those states are probably like.
Scott: we understand we live here.
Rym: Yeah But so then we thought wait a minute.
Rym: All right going to PAX.
Scott: Yeah We're going to PAX no matter what we will be there at PAX.
Scott: Oh wait, there's a guarantee unless we die or something We might not be guests.
Rym: We might not be doing events, but we're gonna be going.
Scott: we're gonna be going if even if we have To go as normal people and if we go as normal people We'll sit around playing games go into the concert and go into the big events.
Rym: Wow, it'll be so weird to beat a con as a civilian.
Scott: You know this year when he starts being like Omega not something something I can actually go for it.
Rym: You know what as my the odds of even having a chance to compete are so low that then why not go for it?
Rym: No, I'll go for it.
Scott: Anyway, and if I make it then I'll start training.
Rym: I would train so hardcore.
Scott: But anyway, I would go buy a 360 and train it up.
Rym: I'd take a week off work.
Scott: Maybe I wouldn't have a week.
Scott: I'm using the week to go.
Rym: I got another week.
Rym: I take the week off I would do nothing but train for a week straight.
Rym: But anyway, yeah, so alright, but people always say well go out west.
Rym: You know road trip out west.
Rym: and we thought well if you look at Google Maps all the stuff We want to see out west isn't a nice swoosh pretty much from Dallas down and all the way up to Seattle.
Rym: so Why not just fly out there?
Rym: Do all the drive all around the southwest and then drive into California and catch a train to Seattle.
Scott: Yep, I mean some plan along those lines.
Scott: I mean that the problem here is exactly how many days we have.
Scott: cuz I mean look at all the things we want to Do.
Scott: we want to go to Texas to see Texas and they got the Schlitter bond there?
Scott: Which is the best water park in the world supposedly?
Rym: Yeah, but then we got a desert bus it from Houston all the way to El Paso.
Scott: Yeah, that's that kind of.
Scott: that's pretty sucky, right?
Rym: And I really want to go to El Paso.
Rym: Yeah, my grandpa has been there a bunch of times and we could swing through San Antonio go to the basement.
Scott: Yep We go like Mexico this cool stuff that we're going to Mexico.
Rym: Anyway, speaking of which get your passport in order.
Rym: All of you all of you out there in the front row crew who may be listening to this and planning to come now My passports been in order since like 2000. my passport not so much in order.
Scott: a good job.
Rym: Yeah, I mean we got to decide.
Rym: I mean we're gonna fly into El Paso Tucson Phoenix right into Vegas.
Scott: We got to fly somewhere west probably southwest and then make our way north and we had to get to Seattle on like Thursday Perplex and then fly home from Seattle to New York.
Rym: Yep So this is turning into something awesome And I I'm kind of excited about it because yeah, this is kind of like the the baby run the test run.
Rym: We're gonna we're gonna do this crazy trip.
Rym: And while we're gonna plan we're not gonna plan so thoroughly.
Rym: We're kind of just gonna wing it after a certain point.
Scott: The thing is we do have to sort of have a schedule or else because if we don't make it to Seattle by Thursday or Friday Then it.
Scott: we just botched the whole plan.
Rym: Well, no, cuz the thing is worst case scenario.
Rym: say we get to San Francisco and we've we've screwed up and we don't have time.
Rym: Just get on a plane to see ya.
Scott: No, I'm talking like, you know, we're in Vegas on Thursday or some, you know.
Rym: Or we catch him a red-eye flight from Vegas to Seattle.
Rym: We pay out the buck for it.
Scott: But then we get there, you know saying we could be caught maybe like in between like Vegas and San Francisco.
Scott: Or you know, we could have bad timing or something.
Rym: the odds of that are pretty low.
Scott: Yeah, we could you know.
Scott: just you know.
Scott: The other thing is depending on how far away from San Francisco or Seattle we start The less time we have to spend in each thing and the more sort of interim traveling we have to do.
Rym: Yeah Like as much as I want to see Texas and also It works that we could fly out there meet two of our friends and then continue.
Rym: It's like every step closer we start we can relax more do more in that area.
Scott: Yeah It's like if we fly just to Vegas and don't go anywhere from Vegas except Seattle.
Scott: Then we can spend a whole shit a ton of time there, but you don't need to spend that much time there.
Scott: But as we fly to say Arizona, then we can spend you know half time in Arizona half time in Vegas But then we lose the hours it takes to get from Arizona to Vegas.
Scott: you see so every additional thing We want to see because everything is spread out.
Scott: I point out we lose a bunch of travel time.
Rym: There's effectively no speed limit in Arizona.
Rym: I know I know we can get there pretty quick.
Scott: It's still a few hours.
Scott: You know We're losing time each additional stop, and I'm not saying we should have the minimum number possible stops.
Scott: I'm saying we need to.
Rym: you know it's tough to calculate this business yep But the real deal is that the only time I've ever been out west was not that long ago when for the first time first Time I was ever west of Chicago.
Scott: I've never been west of Novi, Michigan.
Rym: Wow, I took Scott the furthest west he's ever been yeah, and I've been south to Florida though.
Rym: Yeah, I've also been south.
Rym: I've been all up and down the east side of the country Westside never and I've been to Israel Which is either really far east or really far west and I guess if you count the plane like flew over Italy and shit.
Rym: so But yeah, you know this is one of those things that a lot of people always talk about.
Rym: yeah I want to go on a road trip out west drive through the desert and A lot of people should talk when it comes to that sort of thing, but we for once are not shit talking.
Rym: We're gonna do this.
Rym: It's just a matter of how and exactly what the Itinerary is gonna be.
Rym: yeah I mean I'm thinking it in general.
Rym: the stuff we want to do is first My mom's ranch in Tucson.
Rym: we can stop there because there's a lot of stuff in Tucson to do in the desert Lot of stuff.
Scott: I've been to deserts, but deserts are okay.
Scott: I'd like to see some Grand Canyon action.
Rym: Yeah, well the thing is if we fly into Arizona right around there There's a lot to do and a lot to see ghost towns everywhere and those towns are cool of course.
Rym: up We want to go to Mexico pretty much the closest place to Mexico.
Rym: There is Nogales, which is See the word I would say seedy, but I don't think that really does Nogales justice.
Scott: I don't really want to go to a seedy Mexican place.
Scott: I want to sort of go to a happy Mexican place.
Rym: Yeah, I want to go somewhere like El Paso, but then we got to start in Texas Or Roswell or something.
Rym: I guess we could start in El Paso.
Scott: I don't really want to go to Roswell.
Scott: There's nutjabs.
Rym: nah Yeah But yeah, I mean from there.
Rym: We're thinking maybe we'll drive up through All that to Las Vegas and the Grand Canyon.
Rym: They're kind of near each other definitely want to go to those things.
Scott: Those are high-quality.
Rym: I want to spend a day or two in Vegas partly because I don't really want to gamble.
Rym: I mean I can gamble in Atlantic City, and I've learned that gambling is great because you win a lot of money Next time Rym gambles.
Scott: Oh, sorry guys.
Scott: I got to go back to New York.
Scott: I lost all my money.
Rym: campaign bags See I I've.
Rym: I have won for you, but 100% of the time.
Rym: I've gambled once Other times when when I went to Canada what about me gambled at the RIT casino night.
Rym: you lost big, but that wasn't real money.
Scott: Hey, well you had to pay real money to get that fake money.
Rym: I think real money to get fake money, and then we bet it all on red.
Scott: Yeah If you would have won that we would have had a ps2 on Release which we probably would have been immediately sold and then bought food.
Scott: I don't think I would have sold it.
Rym: I think oh you realize that you would have owned like 1/6 of it.
Rym: We would have been in the Bart Simpson Radioactive Man number one scenario.
Rym: You're right, and I think the rest of us would have voted to sell it.
Rym: So that's what.
Rym: there was only one game out back then that dumb robot game That wasn't fun.
Scott: zone of the enders was a good game was okay.
Scott: It is very short.
Scott: There wasn't much to it.
Scott: like I remember I would be like anime club social nights.
Scott: people do playing zone of the enders They just beat it right there, and I'd be like oh well That's not much of a game is it?
Rym: if it's so quick yeah, but in terms of Vegas I mean I feel like if you live in America you should go to Vegas at least once.
Rym: It's pretty much the pleasure capital of this country.
Scott: Yeah, I want to see some shows.
Scott: Gamble one time at least.
Rym: I just want to see shows.
Rym: I pretty much plan to get to Vegas and I want to eat and get tickets to every show that I want to see.
Scott: Yeah, can we?
Scott: because they it's you know Vegas is the one place?
Scott: I mean in New York.
Scott: right if you want to go see a show like Broadway they have Sometimes this afternoon shows like on the weekends, and I think also Wednesdays, right?
Scott: I don't remember exactly.
Rym: plus you can just pay out the button.
Rym: you know go.
Scott: And the shows at night in Vegas the shows in the morning the late morning the after Early-afternoon late afternoon the night between the late night the crack of dawn in the morning the all-you-can-eat steak buffet.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, it's like this just shows constantly.
Scott: you could just spend all day Seeing a different show every single moment.
Scott: live shows you know cuz live entertainment is a whole different category than you know.
Rym: Non live entertainment, and if you don't gamble it doesn't cost that much.
Scott: No, it doesn't because most of those you know shows and things are sort of things to attract people to where there is gambling.
Scott: and The reason those shows and things are so cheap is because the gambling subsidizes them, so if you minimize your gambling You know I'd gamble maybe once maybe twice.
Rym: I'll just go into one casino put like 400 bucks on red and walk.
Scott: yeah I mean no I wouldn't do that I'd go to like a cheap casino or like this very low minimums and I would like play every game once because the way I view a casino is like an arcade.
Scott: you know like if I Go into a video arcade I put money in these machines and fun comes out And I don't care that I lost money.
Scott: So if I go into a casino, and I play like you know poker with some guys right and it cost me You know 20 bucks.
Rym: You're not gonna find a poker table.
Rym: That's gonna cost you 20 bucks.
Scott: I'm just saying if I get 20 bucks of fun Then it was worth it.
Scott: if it cost me 500 bucks all right now I don't think I'm getting a $500 worth of fun playing poker But if I was it would be a good deal.
Rym: now How much fun would you have playing $20 worth of craps versus how much fun would you have playing $20 worth of Rampart arcade?
Rym: Yeah, that's the problem with that.
Scott: that is the problem with that, but you know I like.
Rym: I like the way We gambled in Atlantic City.
Rym: we walked in we bet all the money We brought on red or black or whatever a bunch of times And then as soon as we were ahead we walked right out of there.
Scott: Yeah, that's what you gotta do.
Rym: all right That trip is still paying for everything.
Scott: I do No, it's not.
Rym: I've contributed one cent of that gambling money to everything.
Rym: I've done since I'd gambled.
Rym: you've made a hundred transactions say Anyway So but also I really want to see Penn and tell her partly because you can just go talk to them after the show and I feel like I could talk to Penn for a little bit.
Scott: No if he doesn't just be like yeah, I'm crazy What I know blah yeah, yeah, but I could get his attention.
Scott: I think yeah, but it's like.
Scott: what would I say to him?
Scott: You can only you know he talked to him for like a minute or so.
Scott: Maybe you know.
Rym: so it's like yeah, the best angle.
Rym: I have is that I argued with Michael Godot twice nah And he actually it got to the point where he kept responding.
Rym: so yeah, I figured I ain't him a little bit.
Rym: yeah, maybe.
Rym: But yeah of course right there is the Mojave National Preserve and the Grand Canyon and Death Valley.
Scott: Yeah, Death Valley.
Scott: It feels like the best way to experience death valleys is drive through with air conditioning real fast.
Rym: So I think the plan is something along the lines if we want to fly into either like Texas or more likely, Arizona.
Rym: And then and you can do this I've been looking at I'm trying to find the best deals and everything But you can rent one-way RVs and one-way Winnebagos.
Rym: Huh, so we're thinking get an RV or Winnebago or something and then just drive through all the stuff We want to see.
Rym: you know tool around the desert hit that hit the Grand Canyon and hit Las Vegas And then from there hike all the way through Death Valley To Reno.
Scott: and you want to walk through Death Valley all the way to Reno.
Rym: well hike in the colloquial sense In drive in a Winnebago.
Scott: yeah, I'm like okay You know going for a hike in Death Valley like for a few hours like you know look at some cactuses.
Scott: Avoid some scorpions.
Scott: that could be cool You know.
Scott: but hike across Death Valley first of all.
Scott: that would take our entire vacation in terms of days And I know the much more important.
Rym: We would die Would die.
Scott: I wouldn't die me.
Rym: I walked for two days in the desert in Israel Two days in the desert in Israel, I don't think you understand how hot Death Valley is.
Scott: I don't know Desert near the equator.
Scott: I did.
Scott: can it really get worse than that.
Rym: Death Valley is pretty bad.
Scott: Also, I point out as long as you have enough water with you.
Scott: It's all good.
Scott: and equipment yeah Yeah, I I.
Rym: here's the thing with our level of expertise and the amount of strength We have to carry water.
Rym: We would die if we tried to.
Rym: well.
Scott: We had camels carrying the water.
Scott: ah See the camel is very necessary.
Scott: so yeah in Death Valley.
Scott: I would have some sort of horse Carrying the water.
Rym: I think we sort of a camel motorized horse with wheels perhaps with several hundred horses.
Rym: hundred horses yes Ours is a fire and steel, but we're also thinking I mean there's a lot to do out there.
Rym: But pretty much after we had Vegas and all that and drive through Death Valley and go on the final road trip bit Instead of driving all the way up, California because I don't really want to drive all the way up, California We could hook up with one of the penny arcade pegs.
Scott: super trips Maybe maybe but we have to I think those super trips.
Scott: You know they they start pretty early.
Scott: We'd have to get like on a train somewhere.
Scott: I know this.
Scott: there's got to be a train from San Francisco to Seattle But I don't know how long would it take to drive from say Reno to San Francisco or something like ways?
Scott: Yeah, it might take like a whole day.
Scott: So it's like.
Scott: you know.
Rym: I don't know if it's gonna be the most efficient use of the time But at the same time it might be fun because we can stop at all those weird places along the way.
Scott: Maybe it would be Springs, Tonopah Gibbs maybe you know.
Scott: Usually I'm sort of against like travel agents because travel agents tend to you know.
Scott: It's sort of like you're paying for something that you could do yourself You know with like AAA, or you know just Google Maps, and it's like what do they really do for you?
Scott: But then again you know it's like They know exactly.
Scott: you know they have tools that we don't have access to like proprietary travel agent software.
Scott: That could be like this is exactly how long it will take.
Rym: or I can just ask my grandpa Who knows the Old West like the back of his hand that works, too?
Rym: You know and and my mom knows where all these like crazy ghost towns are and just things all over, Arizona.
Scott: It's like you know.
Scott: the point is to ask someone else who knows more than we do.
Scott: Yeah, but not a trap I feel like if we just try to plan it ourselves on Google Maps that we will mess up and not make it in time.
Rym: I'm definitely pursuing other angles than Google Maps.
Scott: Yeah Yes, I'm also pursuing the the paper map And the the map quest.
Rym: come on we can go to gabs and Tonopah.
Scott: Yeah, yante Yes, sir.
Scott: I want to go.
Rym: Yeah, that's pretty.
Rym: You know those things like you.
Scott: You see him for the sky, and it's like they'd like arrange the rocks to look like something.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, where is that?
Scott: South America, okay, not, Nevada, okay, I thought maybe go see that.
Rym: no unless we go to South America.
Rym: So I guess I think the real issue the real thing we have to consider is not so much What are we going to do?
Rym: because that's gonna work itself out.
Rym: not are we gonna?
Rym: Do it?
Rym: because obviously we're doing this.
Scott: we're doing it.
Scott: It's a lock.
Rym: the question is who among the front row crew has enough balls to come on a week-long Excursion into the wilds of the Southwest?
Scott: yeah, I think also for some people It's not just the balls, but it's also the money in the vacation days.
Scott: like I know There's some people if they had the vacation days they would do it But they don't and some people they have the days or they don't have the money.
Rym: So Emily's the only one with a good excuse because instead of doing this she's going to Finland.
Scott: That's fine You know it's all you know, but you know it's not a lot for not.
Scott: It's not a lack of some people It's also a lack of.
Scott: it's a lack of balls, but forever.
Scott: It's It's not a lack of balls for everybody there.
Scott: people have the balls that aren't going despite.
Rym: Well we don't know who's going yet, or not.
Rym: all I know is that some people are particularly excited and some people seem really Reluctant.
Rym: yeah, and I wonder how many people we'd have along with us if we were going to Turkey instead of this.
Scott: Yeah, well what if we had?
Scott: you know well?
Scott: You know if we had a zillion dollars right everyone had a zillion dollars and infinite vacation and no jobs.
Scott: How many people would be up for?
Scott: probably everybody.
Rym: well, then I would try I wouldn't go to the Southwest I'd be in Europe pretty much to be living in the Mediterranean.
Scott: I'd be in the Southwest at some point Everywhere.
Rym: oh yeah, but I'd spend a lot of time in Monaco.
Scott: Oh Monica Yeah, I might spend like a month there Living in the hotel that is also a casino Playing baccarat watching Formula One races Which is once a year.
Rym: if you had that much money you could buy your way into racing in Formula One races.
Scott: No formula one team is like five hundred million dollars.
Rym: if I use that zillions, okay?
Scott: If I have zillion I didn't know a zillion was bigger than five I can buy.
Rym: if I have Effectively Monte Cristo money I can buy an f1 team and then pay them to put me in the car until I die which won't Take long, so you'll die.
Rym: practice one Maybe not practice one cuz I'd probably go.
Scott: you're right.
Scott: You're right.
Scott: You died.
Rym: go so I would drive So slowly that the engine would catch fire.
Scott: That's not well.
Scott: first of all if you drove that slowly the brakes would catch fire first right and second It's not even worth discussing this.
Rym: Maybe we should just do our go-karts.
Rym: Yes, let's stick to the go-karts, but yes We'll probably talk about this more as time goes on.
Rym: But we are going west and good or bad may come of it.
Scott: We're going to PAX no matter what PAX people at the if all else fails.
Scott: We'll just fly to Seattle and fly home.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights' at front row.
Scott: crew calm.
Scott: Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: if you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the Website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license, this means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.
Scott: Moscow See the Kremlin's you know, you want to see the Kremlin's and the chairs.
Rym: don't forget the chair.
Rym: see Lenin.