Rym: It's Thursday, May 1st.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And tonight, Geeknight Thursdays is changing it up and we bring you the lounge.
Rym: Or whatever we're going to call it.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: Tonight might be a little weird.
Scott: A little, it's going to be half weird, half cop out.
Rym: Half assed.
Scott: I didn't even see that one coming, that was good.
Rym: I'm proud of that.
Rym: You see, don't get us wrong, don't read into this a lot, but we're not getting tired of Geeknights.
Rym: Geeknights isn't changing.
Rym: The Geeknights you know and love is going to be the same as you've always known and loved it.
Scott: Actually, this is the last Geeknights.
Rym: I'm going to start writing a wow blog.
Rym: I think I should really focus on my wow blog.
Rym: I think that's where my life is going right now.
Rym: You know, the fact that Dave had to point out like four days after they'd start, like four shows after the joke.
Rym: Like, you know, it was a joke.
Scott: We're still podcasting.
Scott: Didn't you notice that there were other episodes there after the watch?
Rym: Because you know, like 50 of their listeners were probably just like, "What?
Rym: It's over.
Rym: Unsubscribed in the feed.
Rym: Took the bookmark out of their bookmarks.
Rym: Has no idea that Dave Riley is still podcasting out
Rym: there.".
Scott: And Joel White.
Rym: It's weird how, it's kind of like how Anime World Order.
Rym: There's three people.
Rym: There's Daryl, Clarissa, and Gerald, but I always just kind of mention Daryl Surratt and leave it at that.
Rym: I kind of only mention Dave Riley.
Rym: And I say his whole name too.
Rym: What's up with that?
Scott: Because there's a lot of Daves.
Scott: If you just say Dave, it's like which one?
Rym: Just Dave Riley kind of rolls off the tongue.
Scott: It's not like Scott where there's only one person named Scott, so you don't have to say any last name.
Rym: Yes, there's only one person named Scott.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: Scott Johnson.
Rym: Because I do recall back at RIT.
Scott: Now his name is Scott Johnson.
Scott: You see, my name is Scott.
Scott: His name is Scott Johnson.
Rym: Well, I remember there were a bunch of ways we tried to deal with that problem.
Rym: First, we called you Scott Prime.
Scott: That didn't last very long.
Rym: Yeah, but I remember you tried to spin it like, "Yeah, but it's like Optimus
Rym: Prime.".
Scott: Right, because if I'm Prime, that's like one.
Rym: So the other one had to be like Scott Squared, which is like-- No, Prime is the alternate, the one that came after.
Rym: That means that Scott Johnson was the one who came before, and you're just a weeper.
Scott: So before Optimus Prime, that was just Optimus?
Rym: Yes.
Scott: Where was Optimus?
Rym: Doing geometry somewhere.
Scott: No.
Scott: It was Optimus Prime.
Rym: You know where he wasn't?
Rym: Teaching Starscream how to shoot.
Rym: Or, you know, I could say that for any Decepticon.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much.
Scott: You can't aim for shit, Shockwave.
Rym: I think Shockwave was the worst of them, but Starscream was no good.
Rym: He never hit anything.
Scott: No.
Rym: Anyway.
Scott: And he didn't do enough damage.
Rym: If you couldn't tell, we're changing up the Thursday format a little bit here.
Scott: Yeah, Thursday was always hard to come up with episodes, and in the calendar right now, we sort of filled it in, but all the episodes are like cornball.
Scott: It was sort of like stupid versus arguments, like this or that.
Rym: Or what if I was a spaceship?
Scott: What if I was a spaceship?
Rym: I don't know why I put it in that calendar.
Rym: Every week I'd look at it and go, "What the fuck is
Rym: that?".
Rym: And I'd push it back like a month, and then a month would go by and I'd see it there again.
Rym: I'd be like, "Why did I even put that in the
Rym: calendar?".
Scott: Yeah, the Thursday calendar is pretty much filled up with who would win in a fight episodes and what if episodes.
Scott: And while those could be occasionally fun, Thursday is not going to become what if day.
Rym: Plus, more to the point, there's kind of two driving factors here.
Rym: One, we've been doing gig nights for a long time now.
Rym: We're pushing some 500 episodes.
Scott: We started in '05.
Scott: It's '08.
Rym: We've got like 500 episodes now.
Rym: It's crazy.
Rym: And on one hand, I'm not getting tired of it, but I feel like we should switch it up a little bit.
Rym: Like, it always, I don't know, Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday are like these solid shows where it's topical all the way through.
Rym: And Thursday, it's kind of like the catch-all, you know, for various rents and tomfoolery and whatever.
Rym: But I feel like if we made the format more conducive to more laid-back talk, we'd probably end up covering a lot more interesting things.
Scott: Well, I think really what we need to do is, on the one hand, we need sort of less structure on the Thursday, to separate it from the other days.
Scott: But on the other hand, we need a little bit more structure to enhance the creativity of what the hell are we going to talk about.
Scott: Because, you know, when you have, we always talk about this, but when you have limitations, that's when you can be more creative.
Scott: When it's just anything goes, it's very difficult.
Scott: So I think by narrowing the thought process for Thursday, we can come up with better ideas of what to do the show on.
Rym: Well, part of it, too, is that we're still going to do Thursday shows, same as always.
Rym: I think it's just more that the format for Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday is really coalesced.
Rym: Like, we used to debate about whether or not the news should be germane to the topic.
Rym: We had long debates about whether or not, like, on a Wednesday, we would always only talk about anime news.
Rym: And we even, for a while, considered only anime, manga, or comic-related things of the day.
Rym: And we still aren't, I mean, now it seems like we keep the news topical.
Rym: Things of the day are only topical if there's something great, but I feel like we kind of tried to sneak in the cross-pollination a little bit, because, you know, our whole shtick is pan-geekism and how you can always get into another geekery.
Scott: Yeah, but I think generally what we try to do is we lean towards using a relevant news and thing of the day, but if we can't find one, just fuck it and just do whatever.
Rym: Our long-term goal is I feel like if we alter the format of all the different shows a little bit based on the topic, so, like, if we kind of change Wednesdays into, instead of, you know, the rigid format of "open-y bit" where we talk about nothing, "news" where we, like, read Anime News Network.
Scott: People know the format of the show.
Rym: Yeah, but, like, it's so rigid.
Rym: Like, we do this, and we do the news, thing of the day, and then the main bit.
Rym: Then we kind of trail off.
Scott: I think what we need to do is we need to tweak the format of each day such that it's still GeekNights, but, you know, we change the Wednesday format to be more conducive to Anime, Manga, Comic Talk, and we can tweak the format of Tuesday so that maybe all the days won't have the same format.
Scott: They will just have formats that are accustomed to the topic at hand.
Rym: Now, I mean, we started this.
Rym: Scott's box was kind of an experiment along those lines because the original concept for GeekNights, I mean, we're talking many years ago.
Scott: Was pillow talk with Rym and Scott?
Rym: Well, after that, after that initial, wow, yeah.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: If we'd had money, we probably would have started doing a radio show in, like, 2002.
Rym: It would have been about January 2002.
Rym: We would have started podcasting.
Scott: Something like that.
Rym: But, no, luckily for all of you, we didn't have any money.
Scott: We would have been the first podcasters before podcasting existed, before everyone had iPods.
Rym: We would have just had this radio show.
Scott: We would have just had this blog, basically, running on, like, Perl.
Scott: that was just links to MP3s.
Scott: We would have hosted-- And RIT's bandwidth would have been like, hey, and they would have shut us down, and they wouldn't have been able to afford any other bandwidth.
Rym: Actually, knowing RIT, Al Biles or someone probably would have, like, gotten us official RIT business.
Scott: Yeah, maybe.
Rym: But in return, we would have had to probably give up the show when we graduated.
Scott: Something like that.
Rym: But the original concept after pillow talk with Rym and Scott was that we would have a show that's like a late show, and we'd have, like, 15 different bits.
Rym: Like, there's the opening bit.
Rym: There's the news bit.
Rym: There's the, like, review bit.
Rym: There's the topical, like, op-ed bit.
Rym: There's the bring a guest in for five minutes bit.
Rym: And every show would be, like, a different collection of these bits, depending on what we had put together.
Rym: A Monday show might have been the opening bit, and then we do the science news bit, and then we do, like, the things of the day, which is like this aside.
Rym: Like, we break in and do the things of the day, and then we come back with the science minute that we do every Monday, and then we do, like, the main show, and then we end with the reader feedback thing.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: That would have been great, and we probably would have done that if GeekNights was one night a week, because changing up like that would have required a lot of work, and there's no way we could have pulled that off early on.
Scott: Yeah, we would have had to come up with all those different bits, and then each and every episode, we would have had to select which bits we were going to do and figure out exactly what we were going to do in them, and then ordered them and figure out how much long they were going to take.
Rym: Now, we could have done that.
Rym: What really stopped us was the fact that way back then, early on, it took a long time to do post-production, and it took us a long time to do pre-production for what little we were doing.
Rym: So we knew that that sort of complex format was way out of our league, and we didn't even try it.
Rym: But now, post-production, it takes me longer to type the post that you see in our WordPress than it does to edit, upload -- well, maybe not upload, because Libsyn's slow -- but to edit, to put together, to filter, to process, to make the MP3, to make the ID3 and all that.
Rym: It's faster to do all that than it is to type the WordPress.
Rym: GeekNights does not take us very long to do.
Rym: All right.
Rym: But at the same time, I don't know if I want to go back to the days of GeekNights taking three hours every night.
Scott: So here's what I'm thinking.
Scott: I'm thinking that we should have sort of different types of Thursdays, and then we could cycle through them.
Scott: That way, each individual Thursday episode, we can sort of focus and come up with something to do the show on more easily, but it won't be the same thing every week.
Scott: So we could do, like, maybe talk to someone on Skype Thursdays, or what else can we do?
Scott: We had these ideas before.
Rym: That's it.
Rym: We'll just Skype people in.
Rym: But we'll do the listener feedback thing, or we'll do the --.
Rym: we had an episode a long time ago, something about, you know, on the way to the forum, something funny happened on the way to the forum, and that actually was a really popular episode.
Scott: So, like, that could be a bit where we -- It was popular among people in the forum.
Scott: I don't know how much people outside the forum.
Rym: That episode was pretty well -- kind of like those Questions episodes.
Rym: They were way downloaded, more so than other episodes at the same kind of era.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: My only hesitation with that kind of episode is that I really want to make sure that all the episodes of GeekNights, like, anyone coming in can get it.
Scott: I don't want to be, you know, sort of, like, inside baseball at all.
Rym: Oh, no, but it's very trivial to make that not inside baseball.
Rym: You just -- you go through the virtual world.
Rym: We're going to try it in the second half of the show again, and I think you'll see it'll work pretty well, even if you don't even know what GeekNights is.
Rym: But the long-term goal is that.
Rym: But I think the short-term goal is all we're going to do to have the most impact and to learn the most.
Rym: the quickest is to kind of, you know -- GeekNights Mondays will be science and technology, and GeekNights Tuesdays will be gaming, and Wednesdays will be anime, manga, comics.
Rym: People know.
Scott: Why are you repeating all this stuff?
Rym: Because that's what you do.
Rym: But GeekNights Thursdays are not going to be GeekNights Thursdays, blah, you know, because it's kind of this nothing thing.
Rym: It's going to be GeekNights Thursdays or GeekNights The Lounge.
Rym: I think that's going to be the title.
Scott: You really like that lounge idea.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I like the idea for now of just making Thursday.
Rym: There's no format in terms of we do the news, and then we do the main bit.
Rym: Instead, we might do bits.
Rym: We might just talk.
Rym: It'll be kind of the laid-back, relaxed show, because the Friday Night Party line was really fun when we're on it.
Rym: We rarely have time to be on it anymore, but that sort of laid-back kind of just talking.
Rym: You're not quite -- like, you got a vague idea where you're going, but you don't plan everything out.
Rym: You don't have this rigid news thing-of-the-day thing set up, ready to go.
Rym: And I feel like it'll be more natural.
Rym: It'll be more fun for us.
Rym: It'll make Thursdays this kind of easy thing to just sit down and talk.
Rym: And I don't know.
Rym: People seem to like the conversational style.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I just think what you should do is you should have, like, you know, four or five different -- you know, because if it's just talk about whatever, then it's just the lounge.
Scott: That's sort of we're stuck in the same place.
Rym: We got to be like -- Well, see, not so much, because talk about whatever.
Rym: No, when I say the lounge, I mean it's more that we don't follow the format of news and then a main bit.
Scott: No, no, no.
Rym: We might still have a topic, but we might just talk about the topic the whole time.
Rym: Or we might talk about the topic for the first half, and then for the second half, we Skype someone in, and then all of us talk about the topic.
Scott: We could do that.
Scott: I'm thinking, though, if we sort of, like, had -- you know, we could do, like, GeekNights Thursday movies, or GeekNights Thursday, right?
Scott: Or GeekNights Thursday book club, right?
Scott: Like, people have always wanted us to do regular old book club of normal non-comic books.
Rym: You want a book club?
Rym: Read The Darkness That Comes Before.
Scott: Yeah, that should be our first one.
Rym: Good God, read those books.
Rym: The Prince of Nothing, R. Scott Bakker.
Scott: We could sort of, like, you know, we could do each one of them, like, once a month or every other month.
Rym: So it's like Thursday would actually be, like, a bunch of different -- See, at the same time, my only problem with doing them all, like, once a month like that is, now we're suddenly back into the, "Well, it's the third week of the month.
Rym: We got to do the book
Rym: bit.".
Scott: Well, no, we could just do is we could have, you know, we come up with, you know, we have Thursday books, we have Thursday Skype someone, we have Thursday, you know, movie, we have Thursday something else, right?
Scott: And then we just sort of come in on Thursday and pick one of them.
Rym: Yeah, and we can also get to the point where some Thursdays, we just choose four bits.
Scott: We could do that, too.
Rym: But I think that's all still long-term.
Rym: Right now, all we're going to do is change the style of Thursday, so we're still going to have a topic.
Rym: Like, every show will have a topic, but basically, cosmetically, all we're doing is getting rid of the news.
Scott: I guess for now.
Rym: But it's more that I think we'll have a more conversational style, and I think GeekNights' Thursdays, over the next few months, is going to evolve rapidly.
Rym: And I think you and us will both all kind of know when we hit the sweet spot.
Scott: Yeah, probably.
Rym: Like, we'll know when it's good, we'll know what works and what doesn't.
Scott: You can tell, we can tell when we make a show whether it's a good show or not.
Scott: Like, Monday and Tuesday this week, we're a little eh, but yesterday was really good.
Rym: Even though yesterday was, "Oh, my God.
Rym: "Escaflowne is so awesome, Scott.
Rym: "Yeah, Rym, Escaflowne is so awesome.
Rym: "You know why it's so awesome?
Rym: Maybe because it's
Rym: awesome.".
Scott: But you could tell, we could tell when we make a show, whether it's good or not.
Rym: Sometimes.
Rym: Every now and then, we think, like, "Wow, that was a crap
Rym: show.".
Rym: And then people in the forum are like, "Man, that was, like, the best show you guys have done in a
Rym: while.".
Scott: Yeah, I don't know what's up with that.
Rym: I think you're all lying.
Rym: I think it's some sort of, "You're trying to bring us
Rym: down.".
Scott: I don't trust the people in the forum, say.
Rym: It is kind of scary how crazy the forums are, but we'll get to that.
Rym: But seriously, I think Thursdays are just going to become this kind of evolving thing, and we debated whether or not we should do this kind of experimentation in the experimental feed, but the decision, and you'll probably see...
Scott: There's still going to be experimentation in the experimental feed, but it's going to be more crazy experimentation.
Rym: There hasn't been a lot in that feed.
Rym: There's been almost nothing in there, because we have been very busy, but we've actually recorded a lot that's going to go in there.
Rym: I just have to kind of parse through it and figure out what's worthwhile, and some things we recorded...
Scott: Stuff doesn't have to be worthwhile.
Scott: It just has to be worth the Libsyn quota.
Rym: Yeah, some of them aren't even worth that yet.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Like, we recorded a commentary on some Penn and Teller bullshit episodes, but now I know a lot more about the logistics of doing that, so...
Scott: Yeah, plus now that I got the video editing, we can actually maybe put those on YouTube instead of...
Rym: Yeah, maybe not the Penn and Teller bullshits.
Scott: No, no, no, no, no.
Rym: But for now, experimentation with the format is going to be in Thursday.
Rym: Experimentation with, you know, "What if Rym and Scott just yell into a microphone for ten
Rym: minutes?"
Rym: is going to be in the experimental feed.
Scott: Pretty much.
Rym: And also, you might have seen in the forums, there's the GeekNights select feed.
Rym: That's not going to be public for, like, a month, because I've got to figure out how I'm going to do that.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know exactly.
Scott: You're basically just, you know, trying to aggregate multiple RSS feeds into one and sort of select episodes and...
Rym: Well, my idea, my main idea, let's look at anime for an example.
Rym: GeekNights Wednesdays is anime/manga comics.
Rym: What if we made a feed that was out there, that was just the anime episodes only of GeekNights...
Scott: Yeah, see, we could do that really easily.
Rym: Yeah, and the anime episodes of Dave and Joel, which I could parse out pretty easily and automatically, and Anime World Order, because they're anime.
Rym: And then you've got this feed for people who just care about the anime, because, I mean, we broke up early on, we decided to have these four different feeds for GeekNights, and then, you know, the fifth kind of omnibus feed, and I'm still working on archival feeds, and once we get the new, new, new GeekNights website, which is still a ways out, there's going to be a ton of different feeds.
Rym: You can pretty much pick and choose exactly what GeekNights you want here.
Scott: Yeah, when the new website is up, there's going to be like a zillion feeds going on, because right now we've got five, but there'll be just like a whole bunch to be able to, like, sort of subscribe to exactly what you want, and not anything else.
Rym: And I feel like some of those feeds are going to, like, this kind of GeekNights Select is just testing for what works and what doesn't, so when we have that new website, I'll know what works and what doesn't, and we can include non-GeekNights content in some of those feeds.
Scott: Very possibly.
Rym: Because I think a lot of people would like that.
Rym: Maybe.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I mean, the interest I've gotten...
Scott: It's hard to tell, like, how podcast subscriber people work, you know?
Scott: Do they like to subscribe to the thing separately?
Rym: Well, considering more than half our downloads are still from people clicking directly on the website...
Scott: Yeah, I know, right?
Scott: So really, how much is it going to matter?
Rym: Well, it might, because with the new website, it might be a lot easier to push people into understanding how subscribing works, and also, a lot of those clicks are because a lot of people go through our archives.
Rym: But at most, if you pick the individual feeds, you'll get 100 episodes back per night, so you'll get about 400 episodes back, which already doesn't cover all of GeekNights.
Scott: No, it does not.
Scott: No, it does not, sadly.
Scott: Yeah, it's just impossible to make an RSS feed sort of big enough to... I guess it's not technically impossible, but, you know, a lot of... A lot of it sucks to put too many episodes in the feed, so... But yeah.
Scott: You gotta work around that somehow.
Rym: But also, kind of the drive, just so you all get kind of a perspective here, the drive behind all this is that in the last, I don't know, three or four months, we've kind of hit a threshold.
Rym: Not a plateau, I don't think, but more a threshold.
Rym: in terms of we've gotten as good as we can be technically, pretty much.
Rym: There's no reason to get better technically at this time, other than website changes and cosmetic things.
Rym: And content-wise, I feel like we need to switch it up and kind of kick it up to the next level, because we're scarily edging toward becoming professionals in the actual definition sense of the word.
Scott: I think we just really need to make some changes to keep it more interesting, because it's been sort of getting a little... You know, it's not bad, but it's sort of like the same thing over and over.
Scott: We gotta do something a little different to get the spice action going on.
Rym: Yeah, and I feel like there's gonna be a lot of changes in the coming couple of years, because, I mean, I really can't talk about the details, but we've got some kind of professional things very, very closer on the horizon than they were, say, a year ago.
Scott: Yeah, we'll see what comes then.
Rym: Yeah, I'm kind of excited about some of these things, but we seriously can't talk about it.
Scott: I don't get excited till shit happens.
Rym: You don't get excited about anything ever.
Scott: I just don't set myself up for disappointment.
Rym: See, the thing is, I don't either, because, you know, people always talk about the key to happiness is low expectations, but I think the key to happiness is having very, very rational expectations, because you're not underestimating all the time, you're not just pessimistic and blah, but you're not overestimating and being constantly disappointed, and I think my expectations of where GeekNights is gonna be a year from now are very spot on, and I would be quite surprised if we don't hit at least what I expect.
Scott: Alright, so we're still gonna do Things of the Day in every show no matter what.
Rym: Yeah, I was 50/50.
Rym: I wasn't sure.
Rym: I was like, "Alright, should we keep Things of the Day or
Rym: not?".
Scott: I think we should keep Things of the Day, because that's, like, the thing.
Scott: You know, it's like GeekNights, every episode is a Thing of the Day, so it's something to latch onto in every GeekNights show.
Scott: It's like, "Thing of the Day time,
Scott: omens!".
Rym: Plus, people seem to really like that music we use.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I guess.
Scott: The music's not that great.
Rym: Way back when we had guest hosts, we had Movies You Should See guest hosting.
Rym: Actually, there's gonna be a lot more guest hosting this summer.
Scott: Yeah, we're gonna start Skyping it up more and more and interviewing and all that.
Rym: The month of August is going to be GeekNights guest hosts, because we're going to conventions, like, three out of the five weekends.
Scott: Something like that.
Rym: But when Movies You Should See, which you should listen to, they guest hosted, and that was super awesome, and we want to do that more.
Rym: But I remember Richard went on and on about that music.
Rym: I just love it.
Rym: I can't do a British accent, but he really liked it.
Scott: Yeah, I guess.
Rym: He emailed me twice.
Rym: He was like, "So what was that music, and where can I get
Rym: it?".
Rym: And I was like, "Oh, I'll totally send you the
Rym: song.".
Rym: I don't know if I actually sent it to him, or if I just said I would, and then I didn't.
Scott: It's a secret anyway.
Scott: A secret to everybody.
Rym: It's dangerous to go alone and use this.
Scott: It's dangerous to go alone and use the secret to everybody.
Rym: So anyway, I guess that music was good, but things of the day.
Rym: Now, this is all from Michigan, and Scott even asked me when I showed it to him, "Is this some Michigan
Rym: thing?".
Rym: I don't think so, but the fact that there's more than one of these in Michigan, I don't know if I just was out of the loop.
Rym: Maybe this is from the other parts of the hand that I never went to so much, but the idea behind this video is great, and the video itself is great, so I feel like this is good thing-of-the-day quality.
Rym: Also, it is from neither Dig nor Kaleghumor.
Scott: Kaleghumor?
Rym: Kaleghumor.
Scott: Kaleghumor.
Rym: I feel like that's a boon, a plus.
Rym: So there's this shoe tree in northern Michigan.
Rym: Basically, this guy was driving on M33.
Rym: Now, a little aside.
Rym: When I moved to New York, I was always confused, because when people said the name of a freeway or a highway or whatever, when they said the name of a highway, they'd use a word name.
Rym: Like, they'd call highways names.
Rym: Like, it's the blah-blah-blah highway or blah-blah-blah street.
Scott: The Taconic.
Scott: The Van Wyk.
Rym: Well, those are parkways.
Rym: That's special.
Scott: You know, the Merritt.
Rym: But there are no park--.
Rym: Well, I guess there's the Metro Parkway, but that's a different kind of thing in Michigan.
Rym: But when people referred to Interstate 90 in New York, and in most of America, they said 90.
Rym: And that always confused me.
Rym: And I realize why now, because outside of the Midwest, the majority of roads that you use with a number are either windy roads, where they often have local names, or they're not super useful or referred to like that, or they're freeways.
Rym: And there aren't a lot of these state and county roads that are major enough to warrant that kind of nomenclature.
Rym: But in Michigan, and in Ohio, and in Indiana, there's interstates.
Scott: You know, like I-- 90 is an interstate.
Rym: I know.
Rym: I'm getting to that.
Rym: But there's interstates, right?
Rym: Like everywhere else.
Rym: There's Interstate 75, I-75.
Rym: There's I-96, I-696, and I-94.
Rym: But whenever you refer to a freeway in the Midwest, you always prefix it with the I. And the reason is because there's also M's or the other letters, because like M-33 or M-59 are super major roads.
Rym: They're gigantic freeways.
Rym: They just happen to be state roads instead of interstates.
Rym: So M-33 is distinct from if there were an I-33.
Rym: So if you go to Michigan, people always say I-95, I-94, M-33.
Rym: They say the letter and the number.
Scott: We say I here sometimes, just not always.
Rym: Very rarely.
Rym: Remember that big soda versus pop website study from when you were in college?
Rym: They also had a bunch of other things on there.
Rym: Like they asked about all these sorts of-- Like what do you call this?
Rym: What do you call that?
Rym: And the majority of people who always say like I-90 or whatever are from the Midwest.
Scott: We say I, but not often.
Rym: And I feel like I should say it again, because it still sounds weird to me to this day when someone just says a number referring to a road.
Scott: Yeah, well there aren't that many numbered roads.
Scott: Most of the roads have names.
Rym: Well, around here they all have numbers.
Scott: Yeah, all some of them.
Rym: Actually, all of them.
Rym: All the real roads.
Rym: All the state and county roads.
Scott: Yeah, those are big roads.
Rym: Well, I think part of it is that you never really drove out in the east where-- Like I used to take-- What do you mean?
Scott: I only drove in the east?
Rym: No, like in this state around here.
Rym: My commute to IBM was I would take 55 to 216 to 33 to 35.
Rym: And the roads all had names, but only the old people knew them and no one else did.
Scott: But anyway, that's-- Post office knows them.
Rym: Of course they do.
Rym: That's an aside.
Rym: On M33, this guy was driving and he stopped because he saw a tree that was full of shoes.
Rym: Like they were just hanging from it, hundreds of them.
Scott: Now,
Rym: you know all those times in your life where you're driving somewhere, you're out somewhere, or like Scott and I, you're driving in the road and you see something weird and there's no one around and you keep going or you stop and look at it, but there's no one there.
Scott: Or you see something just even walking and you know that's a weird thing.
Scott: There's a story behind that weird thing, but there's no way for me to find out what that story is.
Rym: You're walking down the street, like alone in your hometown, and suddenly a naked guy with his hair on fire rides a bicycle past you screaming and goes around the corner and no one else saw it.
Rym: You're going to be wondering, "What the fuck was up with
Rym: that?".
Rym: But unless you happen, like it happens to be big enough to make the news, or you happen to run into someone else who saw it, but even then they might say, "Hey, did you see that thing?
Rym: Yeah, what was up with that?
Rym: Damn, if I know.
Rym: Oh,
Rym: great.".
Rym: And if it wasn't for that horse.
Scott: Yeah, it's weird.
Scott: It's like you can walk around the world and you can see things which basically say, "A story happened
Scott: here.".
Scott: It might have been lame, it might have been funny, but it's sort of, you know, how that got that way.
Scott: There had to be a story behind it, and there's often no way to find out that story.
Rym: So this guy, being brilliant, stopped, pulled out his camera, filmed a tree, and then he made a little video that he put on YouTube, basically saying, "Hey, I'm this guy.
Rym: What's up with this shoe tree?
Rym: It's on M33.
Rym: Look at it.
Rym: There's all these shoes, all different kinds.
Rym: Seriously, what's the deal?
Rym: Will someone please tell
Rym: me?".
Rym: And I think that this concept needs to catch on in a big way.
Rym: I want everyone who sees something weird to make a blog post or a YouTube or something and ask about it, because hopefully we can start answering these mysteries.
Rym: Yeah,
Scott: I mean, every time something, you know, you go, "Hey," every time you think, "What's the story behind that weird
Scott: thing?"
Scott: make a YouTube or take a picture or something and put it on the internet and ask people what the story behind it is, and eventually we'll start to get answers.
Scott: The problem is, most of the time you get these bullshit answers that are obviously like Snopes.com territory.
Rym: Yeah, but the thing is you can tell, because the only people who would be able to make up a quality bullshit answer are locals who know enough about the area.
Rym: That's true.
Rym: For the most part.
Rym: I mean, you can usually sniff them out by subtle details and whatever, but I point out that one of the responses he got was, "There was a shoe tree in Northville on 9 Mile Road west of Beck,".
Rym: to which Scott asked, "What, are shoe trees a thing in
Rym: Michigan?".
Rym: because I'm wondering now, because actually the person who wrote that comment is from Sterling Heights, where I grew up.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So there you go, but one guy kind of gave an answer, but he's not sure if it's the real answer, but I don't know.
Rym: This is kind of cool.
Rym: Check it out.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: All right, so, you know, Google has lots of stuff that they do, right?
Scott: Like a billion things.
Scott: You don't even know half of the stuff, services that Google offers, right?
Rym: That was a nice global statement.
Rym: Are you going to bring it down to a thesis?
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: I discovered a Google service recently that I was not previously aware of, even though now I think it's kind of an old one, but I didn't know about it.
Rym: They have this search engine?
Scott: Yeah, the Google search engine.
Scott: It's like the greatest thing.
Scott: I didn't know how to do this mail and maps, but do you know how they did?
Scott: a search engine?
Scott: Anyway, no, so Google does this chart thing.
Scott: Google charts.
Scott: You ever hear of that?
Scott: Never.
Scott: So, you know, when you're doing computing, right, you know, one of the hardest things to do on a computer for some weird reason is make charts, you know, pie charts.
Rym: Excel or OpenOffice.
Rym: Yeah, Excel or OpenOffice.
Rym: Or Gnuplot.
Rym: It's super easy.
Scott: No, Gnuplot's kind of lame.
Rym: I've been using Gnuplot and I think Ploticus was the other one I was using.
Scott: I never even heard of Ploticus.
Rym: Oh, I've actually been making a lot of fancy charts at work lately.
Rym: But anyway.
Rym: I've been writing awesome scripts, like Python scripts that just make fancy looking charts and then I copy them to other people and update them in real time.
Rym: And charts are not difficult to make.
Scott: Well, charts are, you know, charts are problematic.
Scott: I mean, okay, so I make a chart in Excel, right?
Scott: How good does it look?
Scott: You know, how do I get it, you know, to look exactly the way I want?
Scott: It's not super easy.
Scott: And then I want to like put it on a webpage.
Scott: maybe, you know, or maybe I want to dynamically generate charts on my webpage.
Scott: Now I need to go and get some like PHP library that does charting.
Rym: Python script plus like Gnuplot or Ploticus.
Scott: There's a lot of, it's not as good as it could be.
Rym: Or MRTG.
Scott: No.
Scott: And I want the charts to look good too, right?
Scott: Google charts makes this like a billion times better than all those other solutions that we just rattled off there.
Scott: The way Google charts works is very easy.
Scott: You type in a URL to Google charts, then you type slash, then you type in all the parameters for the charts, like the data and the labels and they know the type of chart you want.
Scott: And then you push enter.
Scott: And what will happen is an image file like a ping will load.
Scott: that is your chart.
Scott: And it will load pretty much immediately.
Scott: So you make say a web application, right?
Scott: And you want to put a chart in the middle of the page.
Scott: So let's say you want to chart like some numbers.
Scott: So you would, you know, get the numbers from wherever you got them from, say maybe count some things in your database and sum them some things in your database.
Rym: One batty, batty, batty, batty.
Scott: So take those counts and those sums, put them inside a URL, put the URL in an IMG tag.
Scott: Boom, you have a beautiful, wonderful, amazing chart on your web page.
Scott: that's just an image.
Scott: People can right click on the image and save it.
Scott: It's just an image.
Scott: It's not anything weird.
Scott: No flash, no bullshit.
Scott: And it just works.
Scott: And you can make really cool charts.
Scott: And this is even useful even if you're not making a web page because, OK, I want to make a cool like radar chart.
Scott: So I type in the URL for a radar chart.
Scott: I push enter the chart loads.
Scott: I save it.
Scott: Then I put it in like a word document or something.
Scott: You know, it's just an image.
Scott: It just Google generated the image for you based on the URL you typed in.
Scott: So Google charts is super useful and super awesome.
Scott: And I can't believe I never discovered it before, but I'm totally using it for all charts for now on.
Scott: You got to see this, man.
Scott: It can make some crazy kind of charts.
Rym: All right.
Scott: All right.
Rym: So we want to describe someone in and do that for fun.
Rym: But while I was digging out the cables to hook all that back up, Scott discovered that no one wanted to talk to us.
Scott: Well, some people did want to, but it was going to be more trouble than it was worth.
Scott: And, you know, you didn't get the cables out and we was getting late and I want to eat.
Scott: So we didn't get anyone to, you know, basically go for it quick enough.
Scott: We needed someone basically to just jump on.
Rym: But luckily a funny thing happened on the way to the farm.
Scott: That joke is really not funny.
Rym: It's not funny.
Rym: It's not a joke.
Rym: It's a reference.
Rym: It's a big difference.
Scott: It's a little grating.
Rym: A joke was when you called me a weeper yesterday.
Scott: That was a good joke.
Rym: That was really good.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: So, yeah, we've only done this, I think, once before.
Scott: So I don't feel too bad about doing it again.
Scott: We're just going to go through the forum and hopefully looking at the forum will spur discussions.
Scott: And that will basically kill time for the rest of the episode.
Rym: One thing I can say, though, is our forums are really rocking, like kind of scary.
Scott: They're too rocking.
Rym: I can't keep up with them.
Rym: I'm four pages back and there's like 50 topics on the right that I haven't even looked at.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I like I'll, you know, sort of middle click on every unread thing by habit.
Scott: But most of them, I just end up closing.
Scott: I'll be like, open, open, open, open, open, close, close, close, close, read, close, read, close, close, close.
Rym: I'm thinking what we're going to have to do is we might maybe have more categories or something.
Rym: But in the end, what we really need to do is I think people are going to have to start using the categories as their default view, because otherwise there's more things said than fit on the front page all the time now.
Rym: And our forum is almost a chat room in some regards.
Rym: And while that's a good view and it's fun to do that, I feel like you're better served by just having, I don't know, categories open and kind of using it like a traditional forum more.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The thing is I like vanilla mostly because it didn't do the categories and it sort of put them in the background that I like the, just the full on discussion more than the category.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: It's just, it's getting crazy.
Scott: I'm fine with it.
Scott: Whatever.
Rym: I can't say one thing.
Rym: It's funny to see all the political threads because Scott seems to make a point of coming in and talking about how little he cares about politics.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: That's, that's the best thing to do.
Rym: Quote Scott, I was happier about politics when I was a kid and didn't know or care about the difference between a liberal and a conservative.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Those are good times.
Scott: Good times.
Rym: Well, you see.
Scott: When I was in first grade and I, and they pass out little pieces of paper and said, "Vote for," was it Bush or Dukakis, I think, right?
Scott: Was that it?
Scott: And I forget.
Scott: And I was like Bush because his name is funny.
Scott: Those are good times.
Scott: Things are much happier then.
Rym: I campaigned on behalf of Clinton in my elementary school's kind of mock election.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: By the, when it was, when we got around to Clinton times, I still didn't know the difference between left and right.
Scott: All I knew is that every, every politician on TV was a bullshit liar piece of shit and I hated all of them.
Scott: And I couldn't trust anyone and everyone sucked.
Rym: It was actually kind of sad.
Rym: I remember I was in 10th grade and I knew about politics largely from reading Bloom County when I was younger.
Rym: So I knew a lot about eighties politics.
Rym: But we, you know, I was first day of my 10th grade of high school and I'm in this world kind of government social studies history class and the teacher who later on I found out was a dyed in the wool communist, not like Soviet, but like he was like, he lent me books and he like me and the other like three kids who we thought were smart and he thought he could trust.
Rym: He kept lending us books.
Rym: Like I remember he lent me Marx and Soho, which is actually a pretty good play, but that's not a bad gun.
Rym: I like it a lot, but it got more and more hammer and sickle.
Scott: And finally I was like, I like hammer and sickle.
Scott: Hammers and sickles are cool.
Rym: I really like Soviet propaganda and Soviet style and music and all these things, but not so much the Soviet system of government.
Scott: No, we're ignoring mostly the economic system.
Rym: Yeah, but the economic system in theory would have been cool.
Scott: A lot of things in theory are cool, but you know, it's very rare that something in theory actually works in reality except for memristors.
Rym: Ah, memristors.
Rym: Where was I going with this?
Rym: I was going somewhere.
Scott: You're talking about the, you know, politics threads.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Rym: Oh yeah, but what was I going to say?
Rym: But it wasn't communism.
Scott: Well, you were done.
Scott: You want to go, let's move around in the forum some more.
Rym: Oh, right, right, right.
Rym: 10th grade.
Rym: Man, I opened up that communist thread.
Rym: But anyway, so we're in there and he opens the class.
Rym: He's like, so how has America changed in the last 30 years?
Rym: And I raised my hand and everyone else raised their hand and someone else gets called on and they said something stupid.
Scott: How stupid could it be?
Rym: It was like, people are older now.
Scott: I know.
Scott: Try again.
Rym: And the thing is, it wasn't like they were being funny.
Rym: Anyway, but then I said, well, it seems like in a lot of ways we've kind of moved toward the left.
Rym: And the teacher's like, oh, that's an interesting observation.
Rym: I would argue this move more towards the right, but it depends on whether we're talking about economics or politics.
Rym: And then the rest of the class is like, what?
Rym: And then the same girl, the girl who was famous for asking at one point, so do we still have troops in Vietnam?
Rym: And wait a minute, we used a nuclear weapon?
Rym: Did it work?
Scott: Good God.
Rym: This girl was not the, but she asks, like, what do you mean to the left?
Rym: And I looked at her like, wow.
Rym: But then the rest of the class was like, yeah, what do you mean left?
Scott: See, I knew that there was left and right.
Scott: And I knew that Democrats are one and Republicans are the other.
Scott: But it wasn't until like the late 90s that I actually bothered to care and sort it all out because I just really didn't care.
Rym: I learned when I was a kid, mostly from Bloom County, I remember a joke where someone accused Opus of being a left winger and he's flapping his left wing and I kind of associated liberalism with left and conservatism with right and I was correct.
Rym: So I guess I had a 50/50 shot.
Scott: Yeah, it was always a 50/50 shot, but it's one of those things like, uh.
Scott: And, you know, I basically had no, it was like in those days, you know, I mostly viewed, my political opinion was always like a political science opinion.
Scott: You know, like I wouldn't stand for, you know, left or right.
Scott: I would stand for, say, something like, you know, well, the Constitution says this, you know, and I would always be a very academic opinion when I had one, you know, something like that.
Scott: And, you know, if you look, that's one reason where even when the Supreme Court is filled with a bunch of crazies, like it sometimes is, you know, they always seem to make their decisions based on the raw political science as opposed to bullshit.
Scott: That's only sometimes, you know, sometimes they don't do that.
Rym: Well, it's tricky.
Rym: I think what a lot of people need to do that I definitely do, like I do this to a degree that often irks a lot of people I try to debate politics with, but I have two completely separate set of political ideals.
Rym: I, on one hand, I will take everything from the political science, like not necessarily policies or issues, but like political theory, like not what should we do about X, but how should the government decide what to do about X?
Rym: And I'll take an agnostic stance in terms of what they actually will do, what they should do, morals, whatever.
Rym: I just talk, I think about politically, how should we determine this?
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Well, I mean, the classic example, right, is let's say New York state makes a law and that law says something good, something I like, right?
Rym: It's like when we ban smoking, which is like the best thing to ever happen in New York state.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So, all right.
Scott: So let's say New York state bans smoking.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: That's fine.
Scott: You know, okay.
Scott: I agree with that entirely.
Scott: I am very happy with that decision.
Rym: However- Just from a personal issue standpoint.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But the question is, is New York state, do they, does the state have the right to pass that law?
Scott: Is that something that is within the realm of the state's rights, or is that something that is within the realm of the federal government's rights, according to the constitution.
Scott: and, you know, even if it isn't right, according to the constitution, or if it is, should it be?
Scott: So, you know, a lot of times, right, like there'll be a law like that.
Scott: And the people who agree with the law will say, oh, no, no, don't overturn it, whatever.
Scott: And if it gets overturned, they're like, oh, you guys suck your evil blah, right?
Scott: And even if, you know, I'll agree that I like the law, sometimes I'll still say we should overturn it because it's, you know, an issue of, you know, the deeper political science of, yes, I agree.
Scott: I like that.
Scott: I would like it if there were a law like that, but you know what?
Scott: The state doesn't have the right to do that.
Rym: Or like a really good example is Roe vs.
Rym: Wade because I can't stress to you enough how much I agree with the Roe vs.
Rym: Wade decision.
Scott: I agree with that women should have the right to everything.
Scott: It's awesome.
Scott: But Roe vs.
Scott: Wade itself, it's not constitutional.
Rym: Well, the thing is, it technically is because the Supreme Court gets to interpret the Constitution.
Scott: That's correct, but in my opinion, it's not constitutional.
Rym: It's not unconstitutional.
Rym: It was a really crappy way to go about it.
Scott: But at the same time, I think they should have used my favorite amendment instead of using the.
Rym: Well, but at the same time, I feel as though the Supreme Court in the end did the right thing.
Rym: It was kind of a situation where the political climate at the time was going to was very hostile to this sort of thing.
Rym: And a bad thing would have been done.
Rym: Like if people if abortions had been banned and all sorts of bad things happen, I think it would have been terrible for this country.
Rym: And the fact that the Supreme Court exercised its adversarial balances, balance of powers, you know, ability to do something and to take it to say we're going to do this.
Rym: I think in the end it was the right decision.
Scott: Yeah, they could have made a lot worse decisions, that's for sure.
Rym: But to go back to the problematic decision, from an issue standpoint, I am for pretty much all restrictions on smoking on a personal, nonpolitical level because I really don't respect people who smoke in general because it smells bad.
Rym: I don't like to be around them.
Rym: And just the smell of it really, really bothers me.
Rym: And I'm totally cool with banning it.
Scott: And how can you respect how can it's really hard to respect someone who like poisons themselves knowingly.
Scott: Like if you want.
Rym: However, I've got a corona in my hand half finished.
Scott: Yeah, that's it.
Scott: You know, but even so, I mean, like imagine if, you know, someone came up and they're like a really smart doctor.
Scott: Then we're going to give a speech at TED, right?
Scott: And right before, right, they give the speech, they're like, see this?
Scott: This is enough cyanide to kill someone minus a little bit so I'm not actually going to die.
Scott: And then they drink it and you're like, uh, what's wrong with this crazy guy?
Rym: I don't care what people do.
Rym: I don't care if they're poisoning themselves or anything.
Scott: No, I don't care.
Scott: But it's kind of like, huh, you're crazy.
Scott: I'm not going to respect you.
Rym: My personal nonpolitical issue is simply that I dislike cigarette smoke.
Rym: So in an adversarial kind of governmental system, a democracy, I fight to get what I want.
Rym: And other people fight to get what they want.
Rym: And hopefully the political process balances the needs of the many with the rights of the few in order to come up with the best possible workable solution between all the different wants, needs, desires, and et cetera of all the people.
Rym: So my issue stance is ban it all.
Rym: My political stance is New York state has the right to do it and the constituency, by and large, the vast majority of New Yorkers wanted this ban.
Rym: So I feel as though politically it was justified.
Rym: And I feel as though it's more of a state issue than a federal issue.
Rym: Now, if we got to the point where a city in the state wanted to override it or overrule it, I'm not really sure how I feel, but that's a state constitutional issue, not a federal issue.
Scott: Yeah, we should read the state constitution of New York.
Rym: It's interesting.
Rym: I haven't read all of it, but I've read certain passages that have been very relevant to issues I've been concerned about.
Rym: I don't know about whether or not a city or a municipality or county should have the right to overturn smoking legislation, but I definitely feel that the state of New York is well within its rights to regulate smoking.
Rym: however it will see fit.
Scott: Oh yeah.
Scott: Alright, let's move around the forum a little bit more.
Scott: See what else is in here.
Scott: Alright.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Here's some basically, uh, you know, things dragged up from the past.
Scott: Someone says they're starting a retro gaming collection right now.
Scott: I've gone on a rant about collecting before and collecting is a geekery.
Scott: Alright.
Rym: But Scott's a little more vitriolic than I'm going to be.
Scott: Yeah, but collecting is a waste of time and money pretty much.
Scott: You know, why are you going to?
Scott: basically, collecting is basically enjoying having things.
Scott: Why do you want to have things?
Scott: Having things doesn't do anything for you.
Scott: I mean, if you like to, if you like video games, right?
Rym: Alright Scott, I don't think you need to go into your stupid rant again, but like, Dune.
Rym: On one hand, I wanted Dune because I wanted to play it.
Rym: On the other hand, I do, I'll admit that I enjoy the fact that I have this old out of print rare board game and I can be like, check this out.
Scott: Eh, not really.
Rym: I can be like, check it out.
Rym: We have emulators, but let's totally play the Atari on the Atari.
Rym: Oh man, this is fun.
Rym: I mean, when we brought that Atari to Katsucon.
Scott: Right, for playing it, not for collecting.
Rym: But if you just look at them, people walked over and they're like, wow, an Atari.
Scott: Well, that's, that's the, I mean, if you had, there's nothing wrong with having old things, right?
Scott: And there's nothing wrong with, in fact, it's better to share your old things that might be rare with other people to, you know, that's the purpose of the things is to be enjoyed, right?
Scott: The kind of collecting that bothers me is like, you know, comic books, they have like the, these slabs where you take your comic book, you give it to these people.
Scott: They'll grade the condition of it on a scale from one to 10 with a decimal point, even they'll put it in an unopenable, like plastic thing.
Scott: And then it's like, oh, this isn't going to be read anymore.
Scott: It's, it's now an item to be bought and sold and, and blah.
Scott: And they're doing the same thing with video games now too, like museums.
Scott: Yeah, but the point of a museum is that people come and enjoy the thing, right?
Rym: By looking at it, but you got to preserve it.
Scott: Well, no, but if there was a video game museum, the video games would be playable in the museum.
Rym: No, not necessarily.
Rym: I mean, like, look, that Game Boy that was blowed up in the first Iraq war and still works, you don't let people touch that.
Scott: No, but yeah, well, I mean, yeah, but I mean, if you had a video game museum, you would have to have playable video games.
Rym: Yes, but you might also have a lot of rare items or like rare video games like that Atlantis cartridge, probably like behind glass and you just look at them and enjoy them.
Scott: Yeah, but you would also have some that were available for playing as well.
Rym: Yeah, but some and not all doesn't really agree with your argument.
Scott: You would take the destroyed in war Game Boy sitting there and then you would have a normal Game Boy sitting next to it for playing.
Rym: Well, if you could, but the fact that you also have things under glass that people don't touch to preserve them.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, but the point is...
Rym: Someone's got to preserve it.
Rym: At least one person has to preserve the original whatever.
Scott: The point is that you're sharing them and you're not just hoarding these things and, you know, sealing them for your sake of obsessive compulsive disorder.
Rym: Most people who have collections love nothing more than showing them off.
Scott: Yeah, but a lot of people, they just keep these things in their houses and I think they love nothing more than organizing.
Rym: I think you're making a lot of assumptions.
Scott: And a lot of them, they're in it because they talk about, "Oh, it's an
Scott: investment.".
Rym: That's just a completely separate argument.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: You're projecting a lot of your thinking onto other people who might collect for other reasons.
Scott: If you're collecting and you aren't opening a museum and you're not playing...
Rym: Whatever, Scott.
Rym: I think your stance on this is kind of sad.
Scott: Collecting is not cool.
Rym: Whatever.
Scott: Collecting is obsessive compulsive and stupid.
Rym: I disagree with you pretty much almost all the way.
Rym: The only collecting I think is kind of dumb are people who collect for a profit because there's so much better ways to invest your money.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: I can't give you a specific example, but I work on Wall Street.
Rym: I know.
Rym: There are better ways to invest your money than collecting crap.
Scott: Yeah, collecting stuff is not a good investment.
Rym: But there's nothing wrong with collecting something because you think it's cool and then showing it off to people.
Rym: Like, check out my collection of old Atari games or check out my collection of these old ass records.
Rym: Look at these things.
Rym: They're ancient.
Scott: Well, I mean, if you're going to sit around listening to records, it's cool.
Scott: If you just have records on the wall...
Rym: If you can't listen to those records, you'll destroy them.
Scott: No.
Scott: What's the point of having them?
Rym: A historical artifact?
Scott: Then put it in a museum.
Scott: if it's a historical artifact.
Scott: Why are you keeping it in your house?
Rym: Why not?
Rym: The museum probably... One, the museum might not even care.
Scott: Or start a museum.
Rym: That's beyond the resources of most people.
Scott: You can just turn your house into a museum.
Rym: I think your stance is really, really silly and I think you protect way too much.
Scott: People who are collecting are getting enjoyment from the owning of things.
Scott: So?
Scott: That's the definition of, like, consumerism and materialism and everything that's wrong with the world.
Rym: Actually, no.
Rym: It's not the definition of consumerism.
Rym: It's only the definition of materialism.
Scott: It's the same shit.
Rym: There's not that... Okay.
Scott: It's the same thing within people's psyche that gives them enjoyment from getting things and continuing to own things.
Rym: Do you have anything else to say other than bitching about people collecting things?
Scott: I hate people collecting things and I hate it even more when they put them in boxes so they can never be played or read.
Rym: You bring this up all the time.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I disagree with you and I don't care.
Scott: Yeah, you're stupid.
Rym: Alright, so talk about something else.
Scott: Alright, let's see what else we got here.
Rym: This is all you now.
Scott: Oh, it's all me now all of a sudden?
Scott: Why, you giving up?
Rym: Well, no, it's just why you turned into a crazy rat.
Scott: Yeah, 'cause I had to bring that crazy rat back.
Scott: I've only done it once before and I think it's been getting worse lately.
Rym: Once before, you brought this up like a dozen times.
Scott: No, I've only really gone full on of it once before and I gotta bring it back again because they're putting video games in sealable boxes that can never be played now.
Scott: What the fuck?
Scott: I mean, come on.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: That's not cool.
Scott: Alright.
Rym: I got nothing to say after your crazy rant.
Scott: You got nothing to say after my crazy rant?
Scott: You don't wanna pick like a different forum thing here?
Scott: That was your idea to go through the forums?
Rym: Yeah, no, we bought a vacuum cleaner.
Scott: Oh, you wanna talk about the vacuum cleaner?
Rym: We could.
Rym: Alright.
Rym: I don't think we need to matter everything we talk about.
Rym: You wanna talk about this?
Rym: Let's talk about this.
Scott: No.
Rym: Well, we bought a vacuum cleaner.
Rym: We bought a normal cheapo vacuum cleaner.
Scott: It wasn't that.
Scott: It was relatively cheap.
Scott: It was $2.50.
Rym: That's pretty cheap.
Scott: I think it'll last us quite a while.
Scott: You know, if it only lasts us like a few years, it'll be pretty sad.
Scott: But, yeah, basically I went with the canister instead of the upright because it's easier to clean the stairs.
Rym: The thing is, that's the only thing that's easier to clean, sadly.
Scott: Well, it's also lighter because you don't have to move the whole vacuum, right, when you're vacuuming.
Scott: So you only have to move around the accessory part, really.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: It's a lot easier on the arms.
Rym: For now.
Rym: Well, that's just because you're weak.
Rym: But there is one problem.
Rym: If we get a much bigger house, if we have any house with large carpeted rooms, a push vacuum is much easier and you can vacuum a lot faster.
Scott: Oh, yeah, kind of.
Scott: But if I have a large carpeted room, the Roomba is the way to go suddenly.
Scott: You know, as long as there aren't a lot of obstacles in the room.
Rym: Actually, actually, I've read that the Roombas aren't, they're great from a vacuuming perspective in terms of they do it for you.
Rym: But at the same time, they don't do that good a job of vacuuming.
Rym: They don't have quite the suction.
Scott: Well, it doesn't matter if they don't have quite the suction because it vacuums around like every day or two, right?
Scott: It's like constantly vacuuming.
Rym: Yeah, but there's a lot of stuff that leaves.
Scott: That's just as good as vacuuming.
Rym: One thing, while Kirby vacuums are crap, the guy did a nice demo where you show different levels of suction, different kinds of vacuums and pretty much stuff that isn't picked up by one level of suction will never be picked up, no matter how many times you vacuum at that level.
Scott: Yeah, but I'm sure if you had a Roomba, your room wouldn't be, it wouldn't be dirty.
Scott: It would be fine.
Rym: I wouldn't be dirty, but I don't think I'd get a Roomba.
Rym: It takes so little time to vacuum.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, but I guess I don't have time to vacuum often enough.
Scott: It's like two vacuum doesn't take long, but I don't actually vacuum like, you know, every week.
Rym: The only reason you don't vacuum is because there's always stuff all over the floor.
Scott: That too.
Scott: I guess that would hurt the Roomba, wouldn't it?
Rym: Yeah, the only reason you don't vacuum is the same reason the Roomba won't vacuum.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean, at the, at the store, at the Sears, right where they had the vacuums, first of all, I got to tell you, if you buy a vacuum or something at Sears that's, you know, light enough to carry, don't bother with the like, you know, front of the store.
Scott: pickup bullshit.
Scott: It's much slower than actually just carrying the thing out of the store yourself.
Rym: Man, I remember as a kid going to service merchandise, which is kind of, I don't know if they still exist, but they were a store kind of like Sears.
Rym: You could buy pretty much any consumer item.
Scott: Yeah, I've heard of them.
Rym: But the deal was anything on the floor, you pick up a ticket, then you put the ticket into the front, and then they bring you all your stuff.
Scott: Sort of like buying NES games at Toys R Us back in the day.
Rym: Oh, man.
Scott: You take a piece of paper to like the magic box, and then the guy in the magic box, he would bring the game out to you, and it was crazy because there was like every Nintendo game in the universe in this box.
Rym: So I'd stand there for four hours with my brother, I remember very clearly, do we buy Mario 3 or Zelda 2?
Rym: Yeah, we had those.
Rym: We had Zelda 2, and my brother wanted to buy Mario 3.
Scott: Your brother is smarter.
Rym: And they were both $65.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And I remember my dad was like, "Just
Rym: pick!".
Rym: And I think what we were hoping is that he would give up and buy both, just so we could go home.
Rym: But no, he was willing to stand there for four hours until we had to pick one.
Scott: Yeah, kids these days, they don't have the dilemma of picking NES games at Toys R Us.
Scott: Those are good times.
Rym: Yeah, well kids just get every video game they want, I guess.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: It seems to be what happens.
Scott: I don't know how it goes.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Well, it's weird.
Scott: It's also easier to pick nowadays because there's a lot more information out there.
Scott: We had to judge a lot by the covers of games and what games our friends had.
Rym: I bought Hydlide from New.
Scott: Yeah, yeah.
Rym: Because that game looked awesome from the cover.
Scott: That wouldn't happen nowadays.
Rym: Or Nobunga's Ambition and Dr.
Rym: Chayos.
Scott: Dr.
Scott: Chayos, I played Dr.
Scott: Chayos at a friend's house.
Rym: But I'm going through the forum, you can kind of tell who succeeds and who fails at making threads because it's like one thread has three comments.
Rym: One thread has one.
Rym: One thread has a thousand.
Rym: Though I got to admit, this is definitely a meta-forum thing that non-forum people won't care about.
Rym: But, alright Lord Yupa, you don't need to make a million super generic threads.
Rym: You can let that be.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: You're better off posting in an existing thread than making a new thread.
Rym: That's a general kind of advice to all of you out there.
Scott: Yeah, I think that's true on pretty much every web forums and news group and such.
Scott: Anything else going on?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I feel like we're winding down.
Rym: I feel my hunger rising.
Rym: I'm going back.
Rym: I'm trying to find some old ass thread.
Scott: There's a thread about the shaving has sort of come back.
Scott: One of our earliest episodes was about shaving.
Rym: I think Emily was even on that episode.
Scott: I don't remember.
Rym: Because I think the title was Emily and Shaving.
Scott: We talked about using the multi-blade Gillette bullshit.
Scott: It sucks and you should use a brush and do it the real deal way.
Scott: I think people need to be reminded of that.
Scott: Should we redo the episode or should we just tell people to go back and listen to it or what?
Rym: Maybe we should do it as a news bit or a front bit.
Scott: I think we'll do a shaving video.
Scott: is what we'll do.
Rym: Ah, I can do the video on how to shave.
Scott: I think I'll do the video on how to shave.
Rym: Well, I think you should film it and I'll be the one doing the shaving.
Scott: I think I'll be doing the shaving and I'll just have the camera sitting there on a tripod.
Rym: That'll be awful, but that's all you.
Rym: That's alright.
Scott: Maybe we should make Scott versus Rym shaving battle.
Rym: I think I can make a better shaving.
Scott: I don't know about that.
Rym: Because I do the proper technique.
Rym: I do the full three passes.
Scott: Yeah, whatever.
Scott: You and your bullshit.
Rym: My face is real smooth.
Scott: Yeah, whatever.
Rym: Plus, unlike you, I shave every day.
Scott: Yeah, it's not necessary.
Rym: It's very much necessary with me.
Rym: Yes, it is.
Scott: No, it's not.
Rym: Anyway.
Rym: The thing is, you always look like you have this horrible stubble that never goes away.
Scott: Even if I shave, it doesn't go away, so what is the point?
Rym: It would go away if you did the three passes.
Scott: No, I'm not doing no passes.
Rym: Have you ever done them?
Scott: I'll get some ingrown hairs.
Rym: Alright, you got the Jew face problem.
Scott: I can't shave up.
Rym: Because Greg had the same problem.
Rym: It seems like if you have a certain kind of hair, you're kind of screwed in that you can only do the downward pass.
Rym: Because if you do the back pass and the side pass, every single hair will ingrow and you're just screwed.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So yeah, I guess I can't blame you then.
Rym: So I guess you can do the shaving for people with the Jew face, and I can do... Well, it's not just Jews.
Rym: It's common.
Rym: We used to joke about the Jew face, but African Americans have a similar problem with shaving sometimes.
Scott: Anyone with sort of really thick, sort of pointy hairs, as opposed to like...
Rym: Yeah, I have the really fat hairs that just kind of pop out no matter what.
Scott: The kind of beard.
Scott: that's like more flowing would be more of a non-ingrown hair.
Rym: Curly hair really hurts too, but I just swang back to the bottom of the forum.
Rym: And the bottom post here is so old.
Rym: I'll end on this, I think.
Rym: This is way back when we put in this new forum.
Rym: And K-Mac, who is a friend of ours, who has a different name now, posted a thread, probably to post a thread.
Rym: "Shaney under attack and biting back," and it was just a thread about Dick Cheney.
Rym: And Scott responded with, "Alright, you people need to have your own blogs instead of posting this stuff
Rym: here.".
Scott: Yeah, that's true.
Scott: I do notice that in pretty much any forum you go to, right?
Scott: There will be people in those forums who don't have their own websites.
Scott: It's sort of like the forum is the only place they really create any content online.
Scott: It's like they're not big online, they're just sort of small fries.
Scott: But they'll be a member of a forum and they'll post once in a while.
Scott: So that's their only really outlet for anything on the net.
Scott: So when they have something to say, whether it's really long or really short, or if it's just a link, or maybe something they made, they always post it in the forum and it's sort of like, you gotta be able to tell when something is appropriate for a forum post and when something is, you should post that on your own blog.
Rym: Well, I think it's a sign of, I don't know, I would look at it in the scale of internet, not necessarily affection, but the pecking order.
Rym: I'll say it's pretty much subconscious or conscious or whatever.
Rym: I think there's kind of like, there are people who have the websites that they run them.
Rym: Like, I have a blog and I posted it.
Rym: And then there are people who have the blog that other people comment on, that's like higher up.
Rym: And then going down, there's the people who don't even have a blog.
Rym: Instead, they put their content in someone else's blog.
Rym: And that's kind of like the wolf baring its neck to the person who runs that blog.
Scott: It's not like that.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Then, there's a thread here.
Scott: Just so everyone knows, blogs are free and you don't even need to pay for them.
Scott: You sign up and you've got one, like at wordpress.com or blog or spot or any of those, live journal.
Scott: So, there's no excuse not to have one if you want to post essays or whatever.
Rym: So, remember episode 12, How To Not Suck?
Scott: Was that the first?
Scott: How To Not Suck?
Rym: It was just How To Not Suck.
Scott: Was it really?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Wow.
Rym: And you were asking like, "So, what do you think of How To Not Suck
Rym: Schtick?".
Rym: There's a tongue twister.
Rym: And people thought it was good.
Scott: Alright.
Rym: People, one person.
Scott: That could be one of our Thursdays.
Scott: We could bring back the How To Not Suck Thursday and the Fables Thursday.
Rym: Maybe we should.
Rym: How To Not Suck was good.
Scott: The thing is we need more things of what not to suck at.
Scott: So, help us out.
Rym: Wow, Ken hasn't posted in the forum in a long time.
Scott: Nope.
Rym: Oh, wow, Moyterer.
Rym: I remember that game.
Scott: Yeah, well, that game's not bad.
Rym: We only really played it three player.
Scott: Yeah, the four players as far as the period.
Scott: The Farader game, I think, really needs more play.
Rym: But the Farader was, I don't know.
Scott: I think we just didn't give it, you didn't give enough of a shot because- Well, because we also played that three player and it was garbage three player.
Scott: Yeah, well, but Farader has the great sort of trader mechanic.
Scott: It's really all about tradering and we didn't get that, you know, the main core aspect of the game was not exposed.
Rym: Well, I think Moyterer's problem was just that it's so card based that it ends up being random and you don't have any options as your strategy.
Scott: Well, I think it was that we sort of figured out the optimal strategy.
Scott: But Farader, I don't think there is an optimal strategy because a little bit of psychology is going on with tradering and not tradering.
Rym: We had an episode called the crap episode.
Scott: Did we?
Scott: Yes, there was- Did we talk about poop or was it just a bad episode?
Rym: There wasn't so much for us to talk about today.
Rym: And with the Daily Show, that's expected.
Rym: What do we do?
Rym: Is there a?
Rym: what should we do?
Rym: Wow, that was crap.
Scott: Yeah, there's a lot of bad ones in there.
Scott: I mean, that's going to happen when you do so many episodes.
Scott: Some of them are going to suck like this one.
Rym: I think we're done.
Scott: We're done.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our Frapper map, and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology.
Rym: Tuesdays we have video games, board games, and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights.
Rym: And Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via Odeo.
Scott: Just click the link that says "send me an Odeo" on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: For the complete archives, visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share-a-like 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit, don't make money, and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.