Rym: It's Tuesday August 19th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights tonight north and south on the NES.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: It seems like every year our kind of retreat to Wildwood on the beach for a week is kind of Pervaded by a different game.
Rym: I mean it was advance wars that one year when we went to the store and bought all the advance wars as they had.
Scott: That was two years ago.
Rym: I think yeah, and then the year after that it was Pokemon.
Rym: everyone We're.
Rym: we were into Pokemon to a frightening degree for that one summer sure.
Scott: well It was mostly.
Scott: it seems like DS releases.
Scott: There's always a hot DS release around that time of the year or GBA release.
Scott: You know what have you?
Scott: and when we get together for a week And you're not at the beach all day or at the beach Maybe half the day maybe a four or five hours that you're gonna spend some time in the house eating lunch Hanging out and you're not can just watch movies that whole time.
Scott: you got it Play some DS and some GBA.
Rym: we do watch movies the whole time, but we also play games.
Rym: right yeah But I mean it was Pokemon this year could be summed up in two words sieve for oh My gosh did I play a lot of sieve for I didn't actually play sieve for I was mostly playing on my DS Cuz.
Scott: I have that.
Rym: you and Pete were the weirdos.
Rym: you were playing edger in odd Oh, and he was playing Pokemon.
Rym: heat is a year behind.
Rym: the thing is Pete admitted that the only reason he was playing Pokemon is Because he's stupid for one.
Scott: well, okay, so check this out check this out.
Rym: He didn't have a laptop.
Scott: Well, I know he doesn't have a laptop.
Scott: him and Scott Johnson need laptops.
Scott: But the thing is Pete stupid as he was used his master ball to catch dialga Which you can catch at the regular pokeball.
Rym: It's so funny thing is because I didn't know this but apparently everyone else in the crew did so at one point.
Rym: I'm like Pete.
Rym: It's really easy to catch mess for it.
Rym: What do you put the fuck are you doing?
Scott: Just use the master ball, and he's.
Rym: he looks at me, and he it was like a child confessing to a priest He bows his head and shamefully and almost under his breath.
Rym: He said I Already used it to which I said what on a fucking geodude.
Scott: Yeah That's a good joke.
Scott: Six years can't lose.
Rym: And he's like no I used it on Palkia or whatever.
Scott: you know whatever You know.
Scott: probably cuz I can understand you get to it.
Scott: You know it's the real important Pokemon.
Scott: you think it's gonna be hard to know how games like that work.
Rym: That's never the case.
Scott: Yeah, that's always.
Scott: that's gonna be the easy one to catch the obvious obvious Legendary Pokemon, it's the non obvious legendary Pokemon that are hard.
Scott: I mean if you're not gonna use it on the mess Brit at least use it on the magma.
Scott: Whatever the hell it is in the island is after the end of that thing's not that hard either.
Scott: I caught that too without a master ball.
Scott: use my master ball in the mess Brit.
Rym: He's a dust ball on that thing does ball?
Rym: I
Scott: would actually would be pretty cool to see someone who is so crazy with the Pokemon and basically Started and restarted a game of Pokemon master
Rym: ball collection
Scott: basically had caught and not only did they catch every Pokemon But ever they have every single one of every Pokemon in their box and each one is in a master ball.
Rym: I can do that.
Rym: I just don't wanna.
Scott: I really know I can.
Rym: I'll hack the game.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty much the only way In my master ball.
Scott: Think about how intimidating that would be though if you go to fight someone in a game of Pokemon right and you don't know which Pokemon they have but you see the balls lined up and usually they're all ultra balls and maybe a couple pokeballs.
Scott: cuz you know Is there their first Pokemon?
Scott: They leveled it up all the way so it's still in a pokeball.
Scott: You go to someone.
Scott: I have six master balls like six geodudes.
Scott: I can't lose.
Scott: Okay, it's enough all geodudes.
Rym: No items final destination.
Scott: That's enough Pokemon time.
Rym: I just you know the year we played Pokemon.
Rym: I was just I was playing Pokemon and I remember the moment cuz I actually I like that was the kind of peak of my Pokemon fervor cuz I'd never played a Pokemon game before.
Rym: so if you've never played a Pokemon game of our Pokemon is awesome for about a month and I remember I hit the peak when I realized wait a minute wait a minute wait a minute.
Rym: The hell am I doing?
Rym: and I pretty much stopped playing was the fifth night at the shore.
Rym: We were trying to watch I think sars wars again.
Scott: I don't remember.
Rym: We were watching sars wars.
Rym: I think and I was Frantically trying to level up my something or other to get the points to do the whatever And I looked at myself, and I just ripped the game out.
Rym: I didn't play it again for like a week.
Scott: Yeah, I'd played it.
Scott: I beat it.
Scott: I caught.
Scott: you know all the things that are obvious.
Scott: I didn't go to the store to get you know.
Scott: the ones need to go to Toys R Us or?
Rym: no?
Rym: No, and but watching Pete play that Pokemon It was kind of like I imagined is the feeling that a lifelong alcoholic has when he's finally given it up.
Rym: He's kicked the habit, and he's sitting in a bar watching someone drink himself into a stupor.
Scott: Yeah, it's just while he's at four, but I'm playing Etrian Odyssey - which is sort of this torture Did I talk about on the show before?
Rym: I think you mentioned that you were.
Rym: I think I mentioned.
Scott: I was thinking about getting it But anyway, but before I got it I was torn on it.
Scott: cuz on the one hand it's an awesome maze game and on the other hand it's a JRPG leveling up game, and I'm playing it now, and you know what it's half maze game half JRPG questing game And it's just like I thought it was gonna be this
Rym: one of those games where it's just good enough to keep you playing.
Scott: Pretty much I might.
Scott: I've been on the verge of not being able to tolerate it a couple times.
Scott: One time game facts saved it right, but now it's sort of like I couldn't beat this boss So I couldn't go to any new areas, so I couldn't do any more amazing.
Scott: So then I Got on game facts to help me beat a couple quests real quick that were real easy and took almost no effort.
Scott: And then I was able to beat the boss.
Scott: and now a whole nother level of the game has opened up And it's super amazing, and I'm like oh, man, so I think the game is pretty much like every five floors.
Scott: It's gonna throw another boss at me.
Rym: I think the only reason why that game wouldn't like I'm not gonna make the.
Rym: I mean I'll play it so we can talk about it, but I know why the game will not draw me in.
Rym: I Still have somewhere probably in Arizona with all my other junk that'll eventually get shipped out this way including all my Legos.
Rym: Oh, man, but I've got all the grid notebooks filled with maps of fucking Ravenloft.
Rym: When I was trying to beat that game in the pre game facts days Let me tell you I had maps of like every game.
Rym: In fact I still have and I treasure this is a piece of lined wide rule paper and on it as a kid On both sides I had drawn maps of Zelda dungeons while I played whoa.
Rym: I feel like that's a precious artifact.
Scott: I have the complete map of Zelda 1 first and second quest in my brain, so I don't need it.
Scott: I know people.
Rym: where are Scott the silver arrows in the second quest?
Scott: They're in the final dungeon.
Rym: where in the final dungeon?
Rym: because I can go to a map and tell you exactly where.
Scott: Well, I need a map and I would show you exactly where but I have the math.
Rym: I thought the map was in your brain.
Rym: It is where you can't see it, but apparently you can't see it either.
Rym: Okay, but yeah
Scott: Actually, but you know towards the end of the second quest the map gets a little fuzzy, but you asked me any other more easier Questions, I'll tell you right away,
Rym: but Civ 4 was the game of the week And if anything I really want to play another game of Civ 4 with all you foreign people because that was really fun.
Rym: But we're not playing on marathon mode.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: That's it.
Scott: Oh that uh Really if you play online if you play with only two people and you're real dedicated and got nothing better to do.
Scott: marathon mode can work People.
Scott: you got to play the quick mode.
Rym: you forget you can play with a lot of people if you set up the Every other week on Sunday from 4 to 6.
Rym: We will continue this game.
Scott: Yeah I really think the email is the way to go but not marathon mode either because the game will last for years and by then The email.
Rym: the only problem with it is that The first I don't know.
Rym: our worth of play is basically not fun with email mode But after that it's real fun because then you kind of micromanage everything and because you play kind of sporadically Micromanaging doesn't feel bad, and you learn a lot more about the game, and it's really fun.
Scott: Yeah Cuz then I could actually if I was email.
Scott: I feel like my biggest problem when I played the real-time.
Scott: well Real-time game right is that on every turn?
Scott: I just sort of want to get forward quicker.
Rym: So I won't take my time and actually look at everything because if you do take your time you get that rumble on the Skype Of take your turn take your turn.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: Take your turn Bevagon fuck fuck fuck
Scott: right, so If I was playing an email game, I could spend like a good 10 minutes a day looking at every single city managing every single unit into the exact right spot Examining all the territories looking at my science managing
Rym: all my little taxes
Scott: meters.
Rym: See the thing is.
Scott: and then all
Rym: you have to do is play the game a little bit like play it more than you Have now and you'll just do that automatically without thinking
Scott: the same thing as I never did those things in sieve - which I played For years and years and years
Rym: you always played sieve - in the I'm on an island by myself with all the land and everyone Else is on a tiny island together dying.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Yes thing is I think.
Rym: I think I beat the game.
Scott: I got like 16,000 nor excited and put them on a tiny island together dying.
Scott: I put each of them on a separate island so that way none of them could possibly get any more land and Because they were on a single square they you know couldn't get any production to build any boat.
Scott: You would make a terrible God Except for my people.
Scott: know my chosen people.
Scott: yeah chosen people excellent.
Scott: all other people fail.
Rym: Fine you'd make a great monotheistic God.
Scott: and the thing is I'd get these crazy high scores without cheating because I just made a map.
Rym: that's cheating.
Scott: I Didn't have to go to the cheap menu.
Scott: The cheap menu is not there anymore.
Rym: Yeah thing is I Unlike sieve - where I get maybe because I played sieve - so much that I got so bored with it that I'd be like Man, I'm just gonna make a million nukes and fly number.
Rym: Oh, that's Bob.
Scott: I just make weird stuff, and I'd be just like start a new game and say give all sciences give billion dollars Then just build ten mechs, and then what runner I'm going.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: But yeah, I kind of want to play some more sieve for with you people.
Rym: But it is not the show about sieve for nor nor is it the show about Pokemon.
Rym: No, the show about bionic commando bitches.
Scott: That's right, so We talked about I think once in the show, but you know bionic commando.
Scott: That's rims game.
Rym: Yeah, I mean Mega Man 2 is Scott's game.
Rym: bionic commando is my game.
Scott: That's right, and they're making a new bionic commando game and From what it looks like from what I've heard the the new 3d bionic commando game They're making doesn't look too.
Scott: Good.
Scott: I don't know I never played it, but what I've heard is that it's not too good.
Scott: It's got wonky controls etc.
Scott: etc.
Scott: But it does have one positive and that bionic commando in the 3d game is being voice acted by Steve Blum.
Rym: Oh, man.
Rym: voice actor of Spike Spiegel from cowboy bebop yeah, also rogers also Roger Smith and Papa from initial D.
Scott: Yes among other awesome roles best English voice actor of animations and video games ever.
Rym: anyway I don't it's Crispin Freeman's clothes, but he doesn't quite transgend him.
Scott: in addition to this new 3d bionic commando game Which you can ignore they're coming out with a game called bionic commando Rearmed which is a remake of the original bionic commando But with updated graphics and sound.
Rym: there have been a lot of rumblings about this And I was looking forward to it in a big way because I love bionic commando is real near and dear to me.
Rym: But I Really had.
Rym: I couldn't say it whether or not they went in the right direction.
Rym: I couldn't say for sure if they were gonna pull an awesome Or if it was just gonna be the same game kind of reskin.
Rym: well supposedly from what people say it is the same game only reskinned yes, but I Think the video that Scott showed me a little while ago has proven that this game is going to be one of the greatest games Ever made.
Scott: yes, and the thing is I thought this is gonna be the kind of game Where you could only buy it on like Xbox Live for 10 bucks.
Scott: But no you can buy it on the PC for 15 bucks at direct to drive.
Rym: I was already willing to spend about a hundred dollars on that game.
Scott: I just bought.
Scott: it's that it's right downloaded by now.
Rym: Oh my gosh the only real.
Rym: It'll probably run in my laptop.
Scott: Ah so this game is.
Scott: I'm gonna give you the rundown.
Scott: basically you can get everything I'm about to tell you by watching the launch trailer which watch this video half the time I come home.
Rym: You know ready to do the show and Scott says hey.
Rym: Oh my god You got to come into my room and watch this video.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: This video usually like Naren, but Shouldn't ignore me cuz I have to time.
Rym: it's something stupid.
Rym: But this time this video I About had a nerdgasm.
Rym: yeah the music they the music alone proves that they know what they are doing.
Scott: yep, so Here's these the loadout right it's bionic commando the original game pretty much unchanged.
Scott: you can't jump You can't shoot you have to use the arm.
Scott: the layout of the game is the same.
Scott: the graphics are updated But you know the feel and the control is unchanged right.
Scott: there's even like bugs in the control that are still there.
Scott: It's so you know.
Scott: true to form They added some co-op action.
Scott: they added some multiplayer action.
Scott: they updated the musics.
Scott: They added some extra sort of challenge levels sort of like how portal has like the extra challenge levels You know like.
Scott: hey get through this little virtual reality training map we made using your little hook arm there, and it's 15 bucks on the PC, but it's also on ps3 and Xbox.
Scott: if You have any of those systems and the controller you should buy it.
Scott: There's no reason not to unless you're a dumbass.
Rym: I'm just or you're poor.
Rym: I feel like because Megaman 9 and now this.
Rym: We're on the cusp of a renaissance of 2d gaming and like you notice in this video at the end.
Rym: They're like Classic 2d gaming right now.
Scott: check this right.
Scott: There's a. there's a common link between Bionic commando rearmed and Megaman 2.
Rym: oh what could it be?
Scott: the link is capcom.
Scott: you see?
Scott: I'm looking around these days, and I'm seeing Nintendo Pulling the epic fail.
Scott: I mean The.
Scott: we fail for gamers right win for money right, but the Wii is pretty much.
Scott: You know go maybe what.
Scott: what's coming out for we?
Scott: I mean even when there's a drought on a Nintendo system like even when the Gamecube was in a drought and they were like three or four months where no games came out for it that I wanted.
Scott: There was always a game on the horizon that I knew about that was coming that I wanted.
Rym: I can't think of any Wii game.
Scott: I'm looking forward to what Wii game is coming.
Scott: granted name a Wii game That's coming that I want.
Rym: What is the Wii right now?
Rym: It's a Smash Brothers machine.
Rym: if you're us or Possibly if you're not us and you're old it's you know like one of those we waggle waggle game right.
Scott: well in my thingy today I'm gonna talk about some Wii action, but the Wii isn't doing much there.
Scott: and You know the 360 and stuff.
Scott: There's some games over there.
Scott: the PC has some some games.
Scott: the ps3 actually has some games We not so much.
Scott: the DS has a couple games on the horizon like Fire Emblem.
Scott: DS already came out in Japan.
Scott: It should come out here.
Scott: You know I guess by the end of the year.
Scott: I'm just guessing though I haven't seen a date on that you know.
Scott: But the DS in a little bit of a drought kinda.
Scott: But my little flash card is helping me play some games from Japan that I wouldn't pay for.
Rym: yeah You can touch those witches now, which is just Capcom.
Rym: They know what they doing.
Scott: Capcom is busted out.
Scott: Not only they got the bout of commando rearmed not only they got the Mega Man 9.
Scott: They're coming out with right.
Scott: have you seen the Street Fighter 4 5 whatever the 3d Street Fighter that looks like the 2d Street Fighter Man, I'm excited.
Scott: have you seen that the Tatsunoko versus Capcom where they got the?
Scott: you know it's like Ultraman and beating up on M bison.
Scott: I mean come on Capcom is pretty much number one in gaming right now.
Scott: I declare it so and you know I was sort of just kind of like.
Scott: yeah, Capcom is cool But I'm slowly becoming a Capcom fan like double.
Rym: that what I was before Especially with this 2d thing because you know like I said, I think we're on the cusp of a kind of not just 2d but a renaissance of Genres and types of games that existed and were popular that just kind of disappeared.
Rym: as you know 3d games came adventure games kind of Disappeared.
Rym: 2d platformers disappeared except for Castlevania.
Scott: I also recently read this article might have been on kataku or something where they were talking about how Capcom has a system that they develop on like the way they program their stuff to where they make games on the Capcom thing And it makes doing cross-platform stuff real easy
Rym: Which
Scott: is not part of why Capcom is so wicked.
Scott: awesome is then they can get these cross-platform things to work.
Scott: So well you know by sort of doing this separation, and I'm not gonna get into it's not Monday Yeah, yeah, but I just have comes really good lately.
Rym: They're like they've upgraded times 10 because I mean the big problem I had and we've talked about this a lot.
Rym: a lot of gamers in our generation talk about this.
Rym: how When 3d came and you know casual gamers, and there's a lot of reasons people say oh it was this it was that but 2d games and they it was kind of like radio where video appeared and people just forgot about radio But it did not necessarily obsolete radio or at least audio because I mean the case in point drive in my car I can't watch a movie or play a game But I can sure as hell listen to something that's
Scott: right
Rym: and 2d gaming was the same thing that You can.
Rym: they did not make the best 2d game ever and say well We've made them all we're done and they're finally coming back.
Rym: And I I'm so excited about this bionic commando game.
Scott: in addition to the body commando game Which you should buy by the commander rearm.
Scott: just go to bionic commando.
Scott: calm whatever.
Scott: The Mega Man 9 right.
Scott: I learned something because again I have this DS flash cart that lets me play games illegally that I did not pay for Which is pretty much its only use unless you don't have a handheld device, and you need homebrew But if you have an iPod or an iPhone you don't need that stuff, and I talked about it last time.
Scott: Mega Man 9 is being made by the same Programming development team that brought you all the Mega Man zero games.
Scott: now the Mega Man zero games are games I knew about but never played.
Scott: they're basically Real 2d Mega Man games in a line of Mega Man X and such, but therefore the GBA and the DS.
Scott: There were four Mega Man zeros for the GBA and there are two Mega Man Z X's for the DS ZX and ZX advent.
Scott: I had always known about these games and always kind of wanted them and never played them.
Scott: of course I just obtained them illegally to play on my DS illegal flash cart right and They're all fucking awesome Like holy shit, it's like they're totally the underground Mega Man awesomeness of greatness.
Scott: So if those are the people making Mega Man 9 it's gonna be awesome.
Scott: I just know it.
Rym: And I've actually I've been playing through Mega Man 2 and 3 to kind of regain my Mega Man skills so that when 9 comes Out I can play it.
Scott: Haha.
Scott: What what skills you know gain?
Scott: You mean you mean gain?
Rym: or initially I can say this I did beat 2 and 3 at some point in my life.
Scott: Beat them skillfully 2 on normal because people don't realize this when you play Mega Man 2 in the US on an NES It says at the beginning normal or difficult.
Scott: Realize in Japan it was only difficult.
Scott: that normal was added for u.s.
Scott: Wusses.
Rym: well I can say this though that I wasn't the best Mega Man guy.
Rym: But take any gay the average gamer out today.
Rym: You know like a 15 6 year old kid put him down in front of Mega Man 2 and let's see how far they get Nowhere.
Scott: well first you had to tell them what order to fight the guys in but Probably I imagine most would get granted.
Rym: granted.
Rym: I am a quick man first kind of guy You know metal man for a quick man.
Rym: for us your idiot There's no reason not to.
Rym: you can beat him trivially with a P.
Scott: No you got to go in with the F To freeze them up to take away half his life, but I can just kill him with the P. Yeah You go to do.
Scott: you go to freak because you want to save all the ease you got to go to.
Rym: I use my P.
Scott: Anyway, you got a metal man first if you're not put no because you need the the three at the beginning of quick Man's level to get that one up.
Rym: Oh, yeah, so, but I can get a bunch of one up by killing, dude.
Rym: So what do I care about someone up?
Rym: There's a very?
Scott: Right hey we got a metal man first.
Scott: I imagine most people playing Mega Man - if they knew to go to metal man first Mike's.
Rym: next they've met They would get.
Rym: no but why not what man?
Scott: Because you need heat to beat wood man in one shot, but I don't care.
Rym: yeah, you beat him trivially with the metal man.
Rym: You can jump over his stuff.
Scott: You need the metal blade.
Rym: Hey, don't worry cuz I have my.
Rym: I have my crazy best way to beat Zelda that I don't want to get into.
Scott: metal man.
Scott: Bubble man.
Scott: airman heat man.
Scott: wood man.
Scott: crash man flash man quick man.
Scott: That is the only the one true path Right.
Rym: so there's this article that was linked to on slashdot.
Rym: I don't want to talk a lot about the article because Basically the idea is that we have virtual worlds now and these people want to like venus I mean like I don't know MMOs.
Rym: These people want to create some sort of repository of the history of these worlds.
Rym: the same way you You know save the history of the real world or the history of anything That there should be some sort of archive of things that happen in this real war in these virtual worlds For future generations to look at and
Scott: they want to be Wow historians.
Rym: well I don't want to get into that all the details of that because I've noticed something very Interesting that this is kind of a. I bring up the article just to talk about the thing I wanted to talk about anyway but Especially with some of the new MMOs and then some of this is kind of being like a retconned or back patched into.
Rym: Wow.
Rym: But the idea that people want this sort of record I mean look at Civ 4 people love the fact that when you beat the game or lose It gives you this whole history of everything you did everything everyone else did and you you watch these graphs You look at all these statistics and on this day you founded this city and in this year you killed this guy and all that business and gamers today seem to really really really get a nerdgasm over this sort of infinite statistical information about everything they do in any game ever and I feel like eventually there is going to be some sort of market or some sort of Unified data collection thing for all these statistics and people will have their gamer card that will include I don't know everything they've ever done in a game.
Rym: The problem is I hate all the games that kind of require that.
Rym: so I mean, what are you gonna get Rym?
Rym: Killed a rat Rym killed a rat Rym.
Rym: killed a rat Rym killed a rat.
Rym: room is now level two.
Rym: Rym killed a spider.
Scott: Spider is level two.
Scott: Whoa Rym got eaten by a spider.
Scott: Gotta kill Razzle.
Rym: five we doing.
Rym: I stole that blatantly from slash job But it's just.
Rym: I don't know the article.
Rym: It's weird like this article didn't really say much and kind of went in a bunch of directions And they were talking about the matrix online.
Rym: like that was actually a game that people played.
Scott: Yeah, no one played that.
Rym: and how the death of Morpheus with this big deal there, and I don't know.
Scott: yes The thing is is that in all those games right if you want to keep down the history not as Rym is talking about Statistically, but the history as in the story in these virtual worlds.
Scott: You know what happened.
Scott: plot wise It's not some.
Scott: it's not like the history of the real world where it's something that happens as the result of the combined Doings of all humans and all society know.
Rym: if there were an MMO like that.
Rym: I would play it right.
Scott: It's the written work of the creators of the MMO It's.
Scott: it's so.
Scott: it's like they wrote a book.
Scott: Oh We're gonna write a history as if their book that they wrote was nobody.
Rym: the same time there are player things like When there was that funeral in Wow and all those people jumped it.
Rym: that's important history.
Scott: Oh, yeah, so important.
Rym: or when Lord British got killed.
Scott: So important course.
Rym: then again that brings up the whole other issue that anytime someone does something awesome in an MMO like when those Dudes murdered Lord British instead of rolling with it and making the MMO awesome and cool They usually just get super reactionary and ban a bunch of people.
Scott: Yeah When there's an MMO where the story of the world is a rich story that is written by the players Simply by playing and don't tell me Eve online because I've read Eve online things.
Rym: But then I've seen Eve online and the two do not link up.
Scott: Yeah, I read all this stuff about Eve online like the escapist used to write like oh this is the capers.
Rym: I believe you mean Eve online magazine, right?
Scott: Well, it's also a home of zero punctuation.
Rym: So yes Yeah, but he's not in the magazine.
Scott: No, he's not.
Scott: Well, it is an online magazine.
Scott: So we kind of is really I think he writes.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Anyway, the point is is that they talk about all these things that happen in Eve online supposedly syndicates stealing from each other insiders spying right Anyone I've ever watched play.
Scott: Eve online has a spaceship.
Scott: They fly around to asteroids mining them and then they bring the rocks back and sell them and repeat They basically go around mining for rocks on asteroids and meteors or whatever and selling them what they mined Over and over and over to get lots of money and that's all the people do.
Scott: so Don't give me that this shit is going on.
Scott: It might be but the people playing the game are mining rocks to get money.
Scott: They're not doing shit.
Rym: I just I still feel like gamers want this stuff.
Rym: I mean I remember back when in the kind of heyday of quake one quake two FPS is you'd go to the CLQ and It would gather statistics from every quake server You've played.
Rym: on any quake server your stats and what you did would end up there and it was kind of the Definitive record of who was awesome and actually not that many people gamed it back then.
Rym: I don't know if it was because people just didn't think to or did Your own server set up a bot that stands there.
Scott: shoot it a thousand times.
Scott: You got a thousand frags.
Rym: I did that by accident once we were kind of playing around just like messing around like I hosted a server and a few of us was playing around on it and like a Million points.
Rym: if you do this and blowing stuff up and millions of Bob you just set up your own server.
Scott: How did the CLQ know about it?
Rym: I forget exactly how it worked.
Rym: it was a long time ago, but sure enough my server showed up in the role of servers and Actually because of that for about a month afterward people kept trying to connect to me and play on my server Even though my server wasn't running anymore.
Rym: But the olden days.
Rym: Oh the old like.
Scott: now we have steam that lets you know what the server is up to.
Rym: But I feel like Wow This is one of those tiny things that it's not going to kill.
Rym: Wow that other like MMOs that come out in the future are going to have this.
Rym: But this is going to be one more of those things that is going to be done better by whatever it is that replaces Wow Mmm, and I guess watch out for the game that does this well because that will.
Rym: I think that's going to be the beginning of A shift toward a different kind of online gaming different kind of content.
Scott: the one the one game I feel where a rich history is written simply by playing it.
Scott: the only game that I can see like that actually Burning wheel.
Scott: well, no is dwarf fortress And I think if those elements not of course isn't a lot wrong with dwarf fortress.
Scott: But if you take those elements of dwarf fortress to the MMO realm I think that is the right way to have an a were a virtual world in which a rich Story is written simply by people playing the game.
Rym: just take dwarf fortress right rewrite it So it's optimized simplify it a little like a tiny bit Give it a good interface make it massive and multiplayer and stateful and just.
Scott: everyone is one dwarf.
Rym: Either that you know I'd make two games.
Rym: you can play as one dwarf.
Rym: But there's also kind of the world building thing and you know just yeah How about that giant world?
Scott: everyone has a door as their own fortress of dwarves?
Rym: I like that idea a lot and this have it forever one door.
Rym: because the thing about door fortress is no matter how powerful you Are you eventually fall?
Rym: So the game would kind of self-balance, and I just can imagine that is that's true.
Scott: cuz indoor fortress You're gonna lose no matter how awesome you are you're gonna lose.
Rym: So you wouldn't need to do wipes you wouldn't need to scale or change things.
Rym: there Just might be a period of a year where one door fortress is like the giant fortress But eventually resentment builds and other fortresses, and oh my god.
Rym: This would be I would play this game to the exclusion of life.
Scott: We die I would die.
Scott: so until this game comes out and we're no longer able to do anything else Let us continue podcasting.
Rym: So right along with that things of the day Slayer 8-bit.
Rym: That's all I need to say.
Scott: yeah I posted this in the forum.
Scott: It's it's alright.
Rym: Yeah, I just I like 8-bit music and especially This isn't the kind of music I would listen to like on my iPod.
Scott: All right, it's really not something anyone would listen to but it's just a funny video.
Rym: It's not just that it's that it's the kind of music that it really brought back memories of old video games because it wasn't done In the kind of like mock, and I supremacy.
Rym: let's make music in the same.
Scott: clearly took you know an NES sound chip or an emulation of an NES definitely an emulation.
Rym: and they do some funny things that wouldn't have been easy to do in the Create a Recreate.
Rym: you know Slayer song this was not a song you would listen to.
Rym: to listen to music so much as it is a work Of art created in homage to an era long since past yes, and also to Slayer mm-hmm.
Scott: So I was talking about how the Wii's been having a serious drought not much action going on and you know You bought a Wii.
Scott: you got it sitting there.
Scott: you want to use it for something right then off since we got back from the Well actually that strong bad game came out, so I was gonna play that.
Rym: eventually I got to turn it on to play some more Mega Man.
Scott: Yeah, but which is a GameCube game Mega Man anniversary.
Scott: yeah, actually Mega Man one just came out of virtual console.
Rym: fuck that fuck that game.
Rym: That's right I never beat it.
Rym: I never even came close to.
Rym: I need it.
Rym: that game was so hard.
Scott: I beat it once.
Rym: I never saw Gus man.
Rym: Wow really Granted I haven't played the game since I was a kid and I gave up real quick.
Scott: cuz I usually the game doesn't Really hard until you fight the you know the yellow blob guy with the eyeball.
Rym: cuz I'd beaten Mega Man 3 and Mega Man 2 And Zelda 2 and then I finally got Mega Man 1 like at a yard sale somewhere All right garage sale, and I'm like oh man Mega Man 1 this started.
Rym: wow this is hard.
Rym: Oh my god, cut man is ha ha.
Rym: and then I just gave up.
Scott: yep so Was all right.
Scott: the Wii's kind of useless now, so what I get to do with the Wii?
Scott: I got to make use of it.
Scott: I'm gonna do the homebrew action now.
Rym: the ha are you?
Scott: The homebrew for the Wii now is actually even easier than the homebrew for the DS.
Scott: Wow you don't have to buy anything.
Scott: here's what you do.
Scott: I'm gonna sum it up for you But I'm gonna link you to the site that tells you everything in great detail.
Scott: You basically take an SD card put in your computer.
Scott: on the SD card you put these files You go to your Wii you you go to your Twilight Princess save game And you overwrite your Twilight Princess save game with these files right.
Scott: then you open up Twilight Princess and load the fake Save game and of course this vulnerability as buffer overflow and the Twilight Princess.
Scott: and now the.
Scott: you know the the save game Basically got root and now you know writes itself You know runs whatever it wants on the Wii and it installs the homebrew channel And then the homebrew channel can do whatever it wants because it's a channel right.
Scott: so it does all sorts of stuff.
Scott: The reason is the thing of the day because I think I may have talked about it on the show before I remember is Because they have recently added to the homebrew channel DVD playback with M player whoa.
Scott: So if you put this homebrew channel in with the DVD X and M player you can then put a DVD in your Wii and Play that DVD in M player on the Wii Using your we motors the remote control the on-screen display and for anyone who doesn't have you know computer and plugged into the TV and Maybe has a standalone DVD player taking up a lot of space next to their Wii.
Scott: now your Wii can be DVD player and you'll save a lot of room and It's a good idea because it doesn't you know just need an SD card and a Wii.
Scott: That's it.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Yeah, I Look forward to playing with this and not having to do any of the setup because it sounds like it's pretty easy.
Scott: It's stupidly easy.
Scott: The only thing I'm worried about is will I lose my Twilight Princess save game?
Scott: Because I did beat it and I have it saved at the end.
Rym: Do you care a Tiny bit.
Rym: Can you back it up?
Scott: I'm gonna.
Scott: I'm gonna back it up But I wonder if I overwrite the existing or the save game again Like I could back up the save game to an SD card, right and just put that aside.
Rym: Whether or not you lose your save game is available online in information form.
Rym: I'm sure I'm sure there's some bulletin board Where someone said will I lose my save game?
Rym: and some guys said yes or possibly no?
Scott: Yeah, and we'll find out.
Scott: if someone knows just let me know so I don't have to do the research out of time.
Rym: But there's something much more important than that.
Rym: you see.
Rym: from 1861 to 1865 give or take there was a war in the US
Scott: a war of northern aggression
Rym: a war of northern aggression and The one pretty much the most important thing to come out of that war was a game on the NES called north and south Not
Scott: a huge documentary.
Scott: No, not a freeing of enslaved people.
Rym: No, definitely not the establishment of federalism.
Rym: You know the impeachment of Johnson afterward reconstruction all that Gilded Age business.
Rym: No, no, no, no No, it was definitely north and south for the NES.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: I love that game as a kid.
Rym: Oh my god, take this out.
Scott: I mean I was at like some Distant relatively distant relatives house right the kind of person you never go to their house.
Scott: Really, I think only went to the house once in my life.
Scott: And of course, I don't know these people.
Scott: I don't care about these people.
Scott: I spent my time playing on their NES because that's what you do.
Scott: when you went to another kids house He didn't know.
Scott: you found their NES and you played the games.
Scott: They had you never seen before And one of the games they had was north and south and I was playing it and I didn't understand it at the time.
Scott: But I played it a lot and I liked it.
Scott: and then you know I sort of lost it and I was like, what was that game?
Scott: But I remembered it.
Rym: I remembered this game, but I got what it was.
Rym: I definitely I owned it just like desert commander see.
Scott: but then I was at a blockbuster and I saw it.
Scott: I'm like, that's it.
Scott: and I rented it like three times and that was the most.
Scott: I played it back then But then I emulated it later and that's that.
Rym: you know what?
Rym: I just remember.
Rym: I realized something I miss.
Rym: there was something that you that used to happen when you rented games.
Rym: that cannot happen anymore and To this day.
Rym: I lament its loss.
Scott: It's looking at someone else's save game.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: I remember specifically one time cuz Kristallis.
Scott: You can get that experience by buying used copies of Pokemon?
Rym: Yeah But it's not.
Rym: I mean the mystery and the majesty of when I rented Kristallis for the second time because that game was fucking hard and fucking long and I didn't own it at the time.
Rym: so I rented it.
Rym: and you know, I go to play and I go.
Rym: hey, wait a minute load and someone was it like a top level at the end of the game and I spent my entire weekend of the rental casting fly and flying around and psychicking people.
Rym: Yeah I didn't beat the game cuz I didn't know where to go.
Rym: but and I remember I rented earthbound and The guy's superpower was beer and I thought that was really funny when I was a little kid.
Rym: That's all I got.
Rym: Anyway, north and south is a perfectly accurate Completely strategic simulation of the Civil War.
Rym: Oh, really?
Scott: Well, actually, you know what and that's that's all we need to say, you know what?
Rym: I like north and south.
Rym: this falls into the category of games I love but are shitty right back in the day.
Scott: So let me explain the way this game works.
Scott: The game can either be played one or two player.
Scott: if it's one player you control either north or south that if it's two player Obviously someone else controls the other side.
Rym: Yeah, and of course, we're only talking about the NES version.
Rym: I doubt many of you played any of the other versions.
Rym: I there are.
Scott: yeah, there are other versions.
Scott: We're only talking about the NES version.
Scott: That's the only one we've ever played and it is the Civil War.
Scott: there's a map and You have soldiers and you move the soldiers around to create to capture cities.
Scott: You can go and capture the other guy's cities.
Scott: You can fight the other guy or you can get Reinforcements, you know various methods.
Scott: the south just has boats that come over the north.
Rym: No, not quite.
Rym: Yeah No, that's not how that works.
Scott: Anyway There are trains full of money that you can loot to get money which helps you out.
Scott: There are Forts.
Scott: you can go for forts and you have to play this little flag game and There's all sorts other random shit that happens like the Indian the native or is he a Mexican?
Scott: I forget.
Rym: No, there's two.
Rym: Did you actually play this game?
Scott: I did.
Scott: it was just a long time ago.
Rym: See the boats were the French.
Rym: you could turn them on or off and whoever controlled the territory where the French would show up It was always the same territory.
Rym: Randomly France would come by and just drop off some troops.
Rym: But the thing is the game was really.
Rym: it was like a whole bunch of different games and it was close to being a good Game, I mean when you've raided that train that was so much fun.
Rym: she was basically you're your one dude and you're running and you've pretty much got to get to the front of the train for the Time runs out and meanwhile the other do you get a lot of money which helps you out a lot.
Rym: The other guy can also deny the guy money.
Rym: Yeah Your opponent.
Rym: but the other guy has a million Dudes who he has to jump on the train and try to like punch you off the train to make you fall off and lose.
Scott: Yeah And if he kills you like enough times you got you don't make it.
Scott: or well it basically if he Prevents you from making in time he wins.
Rym: man my brother and I play because we my brother and I played north and south a lot And it would get to the point where it would come down to like the second like one second.
Rym: like you're almost there I have I'll pee myself a few times trying to get to the end of that thing as a kid.
Scott: Yeah, and basically, you know, they come out.
Scott: I think they like straight teen units to fight you off with.
Rym: it's designed to be so incredibly bald busting Lee Frustrating.
Scott: Yeah, so they also have the fort which is a very similar thing.
Scott: only instead of being on a moving train You're in a fort and you get to the end of the fort and you pull the flag down and replace it with your own Flag and then you basically capture that place and it's totally awesome.
Rym: Also ball busting Lee frustrating I mean, it's basically the same thing as the train.
Rym: I feel like alright, I'm running I'm running up.
Rym: Scott knifed me.
Rym: I'm laying on the ground.
Rym: Okay, I'm back up.
Rym: I shit a dog.
Rym: Ah Dynamite the dog again dynamite.
Rym: I got knifed again all the times out fuck Yeah.
Scott: But you could get really good at attacking and defending and it would get big.
Scott: the game would be real tight Real tight.
Rym: of course.
Rym: the meat of the game was yeah, you move your troops around control territories.
Rym: none of that really meant much because it was really simple like yeah, like Stupidly said like you'd have like two or three armies you could combine them into bigger armies.
Rym: You see I remember as a kid The realization I had and Scott had this realization when I did it to him the first time we played north and south I sort of had the realization Yeah But it came into stark relief when our armies engaged.
Rym: You fired off all your cannon shots because the cannons are basically useless and all I did was one.
Rym: I blew up the bridge.
Rym: I Positioned my infantry in front of the only other way to get across and then I said I am NOT Moving until you give up and declare me the winner.
Rym: Yeah, and there's no way to beat that.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty much the game.
Scott: the actual battles between armies in the game are a stalemate Unless someone does something dumb.
Scott: I mean, maybe you could get really clever if you were really good with that controller.
Scott: You could like shoot them with a cannonball and they get your horses over there, but good luck with that.
Scott: It's not gonna work out in your favor.
Rym: Yeah, I mean the computer could control all three at the same time but on the NES You could only control the infantry the cavalry or the cannon at a time.
Scott: Yeah, you can't control three.
Rym: So you watch people play just like alright the infantry cannon.
Rym: all my horses are in the water shit up.
Scott: So if they've got their infantry sitting on the other side of the only bridge.
Scott: if you can't hit them with your cannonballs you can't really do anything because they can shoot so your horses can't rush them fast enough and Your infantry if you start moving in on them the best you can hope for is their infantry.
Scott: kill your infantry.
Scott: Then what are you gonna do?
Rym: Thing is the game is still super fun.
Scott: It is way fun fight.
Rym: the fact that the game actually really really sucks I had a lot of fun with it is a lot of random shit like stink just waking up killing you waking up helping you If you're in college.
Rym: Just grab a friend get a ROM and play this game and just have some fun with it because I'm also lots of different settings That you can do.
Scott: you can play different years.
Scott: So the game starts out differently, you know Maybe the north is real strong.
Rym: The south is real strong, you know earlier on 1864 is pretty much the north winds and there is no 1865, right?
Rym: And you could on the start start screen you could poke the photographer in the butt.
Scott: Yep, and you would take a picture.
Rym: He'd go.
Rym: No, he'd go.
Rym: Ah, no, he actually go blue Purdue That's right.
Rym: He'd go pretty pretty pretty pretty.
Scott: Yep And it was.
Scott: it was pretty cool because it's like.
Scott: it was almost like it's like I wanted to be a strategy game But it wasn't actually a. it was sort of a random strategy game and there are all these settings.
Rym: You could change all this weird like when you beat the game.
Rym: It's like sometimes the text would just like spin around backwards and weird stuff would happen.
Scott: and had this really catchy Musics, like it wasn't a lot of music
Rym: Yeah, and then
Scott: like whatever the I think was when the Mexican or when the Native American woke up to do their thing Like doo
Rym: doo doo doo doo doo the game got a lot of points for style.
Scott: I'll say that a lot of players is really cartoony Civil War jokey action And slaves didn't come into it at all.
Rym: Nah, and the thing is if you're gonna play this game Don't play like.
Rym: if you take it seriously You'll have the one game where you just have a standoff and then everyone realizes it doesn't work and then you know an hour later Someone says like this is a game to be played for silly.
Rym: Yes, as in I'm totally gonna send that one infantry over and let's see what happens.
Scott: or let's do yeah Yeah, pretty much when there's a battle going down.
Scott: You just got to go for it, you know, send your horses over go Yeah, you know send you know use your infantry as defense.
Scott: I mean cuz they're really, you know, try to offense with those guys.
Scott: They're just gonna get blowed up.
Rym: I love I mean you watch the game play and it's so like.
Rym: the combat is so fiddly and hilarious.
Rym: He's like, I'll have my inventories.
Rym: Everyone's like step forward shoot back up sit back Into those kind of.
Rym: go back and forth back and forth back and forth and no one actually dies.
Scott: I love the casualties because they just sort of stand there.
Scott: But as soon as you activate them they go doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo.
Scott: And they start swinging their little swords around in a circle.
Rym: Yeah, you gotta hit a to actually make him swing.
Scott: I know it's good stuff.
Scott: and then you can either get the horsies to go in a horizontal line or in a straight Vertical line.
Rym: Yeah, you could also change the formation.
Rym: I mean it was kind of complex.
Rym: You could change the formation of the infantry and the cavalry.
Scott: Yeah, now the infantry formation was either three by three or three by two.
Rym: Yeah, but not a big chain as you start having them die and you get weird lines.
Scott: And yeah, but it was always good because I would keep the cavalry in a straight line You know to sort of help them defend they would.
Scott: you know.
Scott: that way you couldn't kill them all at once.
Scott: But then as soon as I got over to the other side and I was ready for attack, you know Actually hitting people I put him in a vertical line.
Scott: that way I could kill more guys at once.
Rym: Sadly, I don't have a lot more to say about the game.
Scott: Yeah, I know.
Scott: I thought we were gonna do a whole show.
Scott: I was like, yeah, it's a great rolled retro game.
Rym: I think the problem is it's a great game.
Rym: Yeah, are there any other games like that that are like they're really fun, but they're not good game?
Scott: I know one knows about them.
Rym: I mean desert commanders old and really fun, but that's an ad.
Rym: that's basically advanced wars.
Scott: Yeah Games like north and south there aren't that many.
Rym: I mean, there's a lot of serious strategy games like gem fire Yeah, or no bungas ambition because I have fantasy empires.
Rym: Ah, yeah It's a fantasy.
Rym: empires isn't fun because to actually complete a game of it because it takes forever It takes like days because basically you like there's a million Territories on the map and it takes like ten turns to muster enough troops to take like one of them.
Rym: Yeah, ah, the thing is that game had so much potential.
Scott: I really think that our modern remake of fantasy empires would be pretty great.
Scott: Yeah, fantasy empires is an old DOS game.
Scott: I think was D&D related.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: It was based on Dungeons & Dragons.
Scott: Yeah, and it was a strategy game, you know, we're conquering territories, you know turn-based stuff but there was also magic and mana and all this sort of D&D stuff.
Scott: and You know, there's like this wizard at the top of the screen always told you what was going on.
Rym: That was the dungeon master.
Scott: You look like an evil wizard to me.
Rym: that's what dungeon masters look like.
Scott: Yeah, it's like this good old DOS game.
Scott: Well, you I don't know if maybe you could find it at like that home of the Underdogs website or something.
Rym: I've got it.
Rym: I've got all the floppies.
Scott: We have the floppies.
Rym: That game crashed to all fun.
Scott: If you do have if you can get the floppies, it'll work in DOSBox.
Rym: No, it'll crash cuz it crashed in the real world on the real DOS.
Rym: It crashed all the time.
Scott: I'm sure Just fine.
Rym: It'll work as well as it worked on the DOS meaning it would crash all the time Floppities are damaged.
Rym: No, the game was just really poorly written.
Scott: But I do think a modern remake of fantasy empires could be good shit.
Rym: almost definitely.
Scott: So could a modern remake of North or South?
Scott: I'd like for call me Yeah, if you took the idea of North versus South which is basically turn-based strategy, but it's really simple.
Scott: You have all the units are the same.
Scott: They're all just armies, you know You can?
Scott: I?
Scott: you can grill them up to make a double army or triple army turn-based strategy But this the wall of strategy breaks down pretty quickly and beyond.
Rym: that is action game.
Scott: Yes, we're done minigames.
Scott: when you actually want your army to do something, right?
Scott: You have to play some sort of minigame related.
Scott: Wait a minute.
Rym: Wait a minute instead of going silly.
Rym: if we want a little more serious take the ideas of puzzle pirates and couple it with a game like This.
Rym: so instead of having a dumb minigame that's you know, basically I'm gonna stand here until you have to poop and give up.
Rym: It turns into Posture posture.
Rym: now we play a versus puzzle game and then we continue posturing after the puzzle game.
Scott: Yeah, so it's like oh you actually want to fight now, huh?
Scott: All right Well, you got three armies and I got two.
Scott: we're gonna play this action game.
Scott: That's completely unrelated to war but I have a three to two advantage at the start because I have a bigger army.
Scott: Let's go.
Rym: Yeah puzzle pirates plus north and south equals a game.
Rym: Rym would play.
Scott: Yeah, we can do.
Scott: we can do that.
Rym: Yes, we are going to do that.
Scott: we're the turn-based strategy where all the actual direct conflicts are between things.
Scott: Yes, guys decided by minigames.
Rym: So we're going to code this game as opposed to the hundreds of other games We've come up with every single goddamn day.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Oh Yeah, one more thing before we actually stop.
Scott: I guess it's incredibly Disappointingly short show.
Rym: What are we gonna say?
Rym: go play this game will be pleasantly Undisappointed.
Scott: yeah get a NES emulator or whatever, but I got to say one thing.
Rym: on Friday August 22nd from 4 to 10 p.m Bands at 7 p.m.
Rym: In the Belmar Fire Hall at 12 f6 Avenue in Belmar, New Jersey There is going to be a mini gaming convention put on by basically the staff of Katsucon's video gaming.
Scott: ah, so if you go to Katsucon for the video game action and You know that you're not looking for the rest of the Katsucon action.
Scott: Basically, the Katsucon game room is gonna you know, I guess not.
Scott: it's not associated with Katsucon in any way But it's effectively gonna be like the Katsucon game room.
Rym: Yes, remember the video game staff at Katsucon are freaking badasses and that is like the best Non board gaming convention.
Rym: It's so good.
Rym: They know what they're doing.
Rym: They're like the best staffers I've ever dealt with except for like the high up Otakon people.
Rym: Yeah, and it's not just a video game thing.
Rym: They've got P Landers II and fatty like cake x hunters is gonna be there.
Scott: So they got some bands.
Scott: They got some musics.
Scott: They got them video game.
Rym: I'm buying cash prize video game tournaments.
Scott: Pretty good.
Rym: They got a bunch of sponsors.
Rym: It's gonna be a big deal.
Scott: if I was down in Jersey, I might be going.
Rym: we actually we originally had planned We wanted to be there and kind of MC the thing and do the kind of GeekNights thing.
Rym: But it's this week.
Rym: It's you know this weekend We have.
Rym: we had Otakon last weekend and ConnectiCon the weekend before and packs the weekend after.
Scott: the Otakon was two weekends ago.
Rym: Oh, yeah, well, we're at the shore of the weekend after that.
Rym: That's right?
Rym: Yeah, well, we're.
Rym: technically we were in Atlanta Jersey on the wrong.
Scott: if we would have stayed the shore for another week We could have just gone to this thing.
Rym: Yeah, but if any of you are anywhere near Belmar, you know, North Jersey you probably want to be there.
Rym: We will not be there but everyone here is going to be awesome.
Rym: I cannot recommend to you enough Friday August 22nd 4 to 10 p.m.
Rym: The battle at Belmar.
Scott: in addition to this I just want to remind people, you know, if you met us at a convention He didn't know what GeekNights was and you're listening for maybe your first time or whatever.
Scott: It's Tuesday.
Scott: It's a gaming show.
Scott: Tomorrow's give me a show mostly know to kind of review Otakon Otakon.
Scott: Thursday is gonna be who knows what.
Scott: and Also people if you're not in the forums go sign up for form account.
Rym: Yes, we need to say stuff.
Rym: We need some fresh blood in the forums.
Rym: People for people.
Rym: forums foreign people are often people who do not listen to the show.
Rym: Meanwhile the thousands of you out there who do listen are not in the forums.
Rym: I wonder why I really do.
Rym: I don't have any sort of like pithy reason.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, do you just not like talking to people?
Scott: I mean you're bored.
Scott: You're gonna be bored at work for at least five minutes or something.
Rym: That's why you listen to GeekNights.
Rym: You're bored at work.
Scott: I mean, duh, right Well, you could just be in the car but you have.
Scott: you know, you're on.
Scott: you have a computer.
Scott: You're coming to our website or something.
Scott: You know, you found us.
Scott: somehow you're listening to this.
Scott: go to front row crew comm slash forums.
Scott: Go there and click sign up and you get an account and then you might get an email that says you're approved.
Scott: You might not but if you're a real person you're approved pretty quickly.
Scott: So even if you don't get the email Just come back Sign in with the username and password you made up and talk to us.
Scott: We are there.
Scott: we talk.
Scott: you can.
Scott: you can talk to us.
Rym: Yeah, we actually do post in our own forums.
Scott: Yeah, it's not like you're just talking to other listeners.
Scott: You're also talking to us and it's pretty cool and it's fun stuff there and you'll see things in the day.
Rym: more Importantly our forum is not you can.
Scott: you can discuss the episodes if you want to talk about North or South or Bionic commando rearmed, but no more than anything.
Rym: our forum is not like other forums.
Rym: I'm not gonna even try to explain why.
Rym: I just if you go to our forum and look at it pretty quickly You'll see why our forum is not like other forms.
Scott: You can go and just look at the forums and read all the posts without writing anything.
Scott: But if you want to write something you have to get an account granted.
Rym: I see a lot of you lurking.
Scott: so I know you're there Yeah, but I think what we might do is you might make some sort of you know cat members only category.
Scott: We're only people with accounts can read that one category.
Scott: yeah, and you know I guess I don't think we would.
Scott: I might try to find some way.
Scott: so like only we can create the threads that are in That category or something, you know that way, you know, can I still want to keep things public?
Scott: I just want to find some way to give an incentive to People to join, you know, maybe we'll put secrets in there or something.
Rym: What secrets are gonna put?
Rym: it's a secret to everyone.
Rym: I know This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Scott: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.