Rym: It's Monday February 25th 2008.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott and this is GeekNights.
Rym: We are back from a bone itis induced hiatus and we're here to talk about computer literacy.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: well There comes GeekNights for the first time in a while.
Scott: We should just quit the show.
Rym: You know, it's weird.
Rym: I thought man if I don't do the show for a week And this is already a crazy preposition what not doing the show for a week and you're not going anywhere?
Rym: I thought all right not doing the show for a week.
Rym: I'm going to accomplish pretty much every non GeekNights goal I've had in my life combined accomplished nothing.
Rym: I think part of that was that we're not.
Rym: you might hear some coughing Throughout this show because you see the reason there were no shows last night had nothing to do With us being tired from Katsu.
Scott: Come know it had to do with our bone itis.
Rym: In fact, we were actually prepared and planning to do a special on Monday and then continue on Tuesday.
Rym: business as usual.
Rym: But we're not gonna tell the whole story now.
Rym: this might.
Rym: this story might be a Thursday fodder But suffice to say I'm gonna say that a lot.
Rym: I haven't said it in a long time.
Scott: Stop saying it Suffice to say, you know, you say suffice to say a lot, you know, you know, yeah some preenie.
Rym: so, uh Thursday at the con everything's going great.
Rym: Friday Scott's feeling a little crappy.
Rym: I was feel a little crappy Thursday yeah, but you were like, oh you're still kind of okay Friday for a while.
Rym: and then Scott got sick with what I can only assume was bone itis.
Rym: It was definitely bone itis and I'm thinking all right all I got to do is not make out with him or anything not too hard.
Scott: and Yeah, you know bone itis, you know how it transfers.
Rym: Yeah, despite the fact that you know, we're doing a bunch of events together in a dry ass hotel Tired.
Scott: it was so dry All weekend.
Scott: Oh so dry.
Rym: Yeah, that was some of the driest drive ever had to drive.
Scott: There was no water.
Scott: I mean, usually I'm not one to complain about like humidity, but goddamn was it fucking dry.
Rym: It was dry enough to where even when I wasn't sick.
Rym: I woke up with a nosebleed like ah But it's alright Friday Saturday, I'm doing okay.
Rym: Scott's super sick.
Rym: I lost my voice because then Scott was sick.
Scott: I barely like even did anything at the con.
Scott: I was so sick.
Scott: I'm looking back.
Scott: All I remember really is like the hotel room the events we ran.
Scott: I went to the dealers room once I was in the video game room for a little bit.
Scott: That was it.
Rym: Yeah, it was a sad sight.
Rym: I'd like go off to do like take care of all the business that Scott couldn't take care of and I'd come back to video Game room and I'd see our Atari and behind it at the table I'd see Scott kind of huddled over like holding his arms close to his chest.
Rym: He looked half dead.
Scott: I was mostly dead.
Rym: Our listeners would come over.
Rym: They're like Scott.
Rym: Are you okay?
Scott: You know bone itis It's.
Scott: it's a dangerous disease.
Scott: So, uh bone itis awareness, you know, we gotta march for bone itis.
Rym: I think we do.
Rym: Yeah My only regret is having not cured my bone itis.
Rym: so, uh Sunday rolls around.
Rym: I wake up feeling a little bad I mean, but thing is I actually lost my voice because I had to kind of make up for the slack of Scott not yelling At people.
Rym: so I had to yell twice as much.
Rym: but it got worse and it got worse and drinks in the bar Certainly didn't make me feel better like they usually do a convention on Sunday.
Rym: So, uh, oh So we go to the staff party at the Hard Rock Cafe and I remember precisely 25 minutes and change into the party.
Rym: I realized I have to be here for two and a half more hours and I just realized that I feel perhaps the the third or fourth worst I've ever felt in my life.
Scott: Yeah That party was way too long for people that really didn't.
Rym: I wanted to be there because we missed it last year But I was so sick I passed out at the table and we couldn't leave because either wait for the shuttle bus to take us back.
Rym: Plus the worst thing is I feel like shit.
Rym: so and Pete and Scott are not feeling too great either.
Rym: I'll point out that everyone in the front row crew Except Emily have gotten sick with this.
Scott: I check this out though.
Scott: the doctor me ninja guy, right?
Scott: Well, I did not see him at the con.
Scott: He was there.
Scott: I did not see him at all.
Scott: I didn't even I barely even remember that he was there.
Scott: I did not see him or speak to him or anything.
Scott: He said he got sick on his website at the con.
Rym: there would the.
Rym: the thing is there might have been multiple.
Rym: Bonita's is going through cops.
Rym: There's no way to know
Scott: just how much Bonita's is going around
Rym: because I think I think the the real factor here is not so much The Scott was sick and gave it to all the front row crew But it was that it was so dry because you know Bonita's spreads in dryness more so than in any other ness
Scott: Mmm, and I don't more so than Loch Ness.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I don't think you understand how motherfucking dry it was Not just in this convention, but in Washington DC from Thursday through Monday.
Scott: The humidity must have been like negative a billion.
Rym: Yeah, God felt like I was in Arrakis, but Yeah, everyone at the con got sick.
Rym: pretty much everyone the staff in all got sick from what I hear.
Scott: But it seemed like most people were sick towards the end or after the con and not during Except Scott who was sick during most of the con.
Rym: I felt really bad Emily.
Rym: I felt I felt pretty bad And brought him some soup and she came down.
Rym: She's like, I think Scott's not gonna make it He's mumbling to himself about something.
Scott: I bought a room service chicken soup, right Scott Wait, wait, wait.
Rym: now think about this.
Rym: Scott bought a room service.
Rym: now It was like $15 about a $15 chicken soup and an orange juice.
Scott: The orange juice is like 60 now.
Rym: wasn't the like dollar 50 microwave Campbell's soup that Emily bought you better?
Scott: It was far as a barrier.
Rym: Yeah, don't ever get room sir.
Scott: Luckily, I was staffed so I could have access to the microwave in the con suite.
Scott: Yeah, while I was in there some staffer like poured hot coffee all over his hand.
Scott: That was those.
Scott: That's like.
Scott: I felt really bad for him.
Scott: I didn't say anything cuz I was really sick Yeah, and I'm like, oh, well, it's he's still better off than me.
Rym: What a con.
Rym: so, uh, yeah, we were brought low by this disease.
Rym: as a result We missed a whole week of GeekNights, you know art because of our bones.
Rym: Yeah, the worst thing is there was a lot of fucking news last week.
Rym: I had so much stuff for every day, but I couldn't talk.
Rym: I couldn't even get out of bed.
Rym: I missed two days of work.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't go to work Monday, of course because I was off for katsu come.
Scott: I didn't go to work Tuesday.
Rym: I didn't go to work Tuesday or Wednesday.
Scott: I didn't do anything at work Wednesday, right?
Rym: I staggered back into work on Thursday and I went home at the end of the day and realized that I had accomplished basically nothing.
Rym: I sat in my desk and stared at my screen and I thought like oh man, how hardcore am I?
Rym: I'm working then at the end of the day.
Rym: I Didn't have a single goddamn thing to my name done.
Rym: I basically just sat there.
Scott: I'm still.
Scott: I feel fine now, but I'm still coughing up phlegm.
Scott: It's been like ten days.
Scott: Yeah, no, it's a seven eight nine to eleven days.
Rym: This is the sucks.
Rym: Yeah, but Suffice to say yeah, you gotta cut that.
Rym: we're here doing GeekNights and I got some news.
Scott: It's like a GeekNights ever.
Rym: Yeah as before we die of bonitis.
Rym: I would like to say one thing for all of you who are at Katsucon and made out with Scott What you've got is probably viral bronchitis, but that aside Welcome all you new listeners.
Rym: I saw a lot of you hitting the feed after Katsucon probably going thought those guys had like four nights a week.
Rym: Where's the show?
Scott: Oh, they musta Katsucon was their last hurrah.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Why were they advertising there?
Rym: But yeah, I'll tell you all this and if you're looking for Katsucon coverage It is going to come to you in an epic way on Wednesday.
Rym: I got a lot to say about Katsucon.
Scott: Oh, yeah, I got.
Scott: I got some coverage.
Scott: the inside of the hotel room was real nice.
Rym: I can say this aside the bed was not so sick.
Rym: That was like the best freaking Katsucon.
Rym: Like I. it was a great time.
Scott: Anyway, so it's Monday So my technology day is not the anime convention day.
Rym: So I got to talk about this because this is a company that is very near and dear to me.
Rym: I've had a long and complicated relationship with the sharper image.
Rym: now in the days before the internet Sharper image was basically a top magazine a store where you could mail order.
Rym: now book cheap crappy Shotski gimmicky bullshit, but Her image is like I didn't.
Scott: there weren't really any and I didn't get the catalog.
Scott: So I was like I was way late to the game on the sharper image.
Rym: I was looking to these sharper image catalogs as a kid and much like when I looked at sword Catalogs or went to Brookstone all I could think was wow Everything in this man.
Scott: We definitely had.
Rym: Brookstones is Concentrated awesome because they sell crap.
Rym: It was unmitigatedly garbage But it is high-class crap if you want to spend like a thousand dollars on a little gadget that goes meat and rubs your back.
Rym: The sharper image was for you.
Scott: Yeah It is.
Scott: it's the same as Brookstones.
Scott: only the difference was the Brookstones and all the stuff that they sell is like wooden But all the stuff that sharper image sells is like shiny chrome.
Rym: Yeah, that's pretty much the only difference.
Rym: Oh also sharper image killed old people.
Rym: I don't think Brookstone did.
Scott: no, that's true You know, they're still selling those old people killers.
Rym: Ah, you know, we should pick up a few.
Rym: Keep them around just in case they're not good.
Scott: They're not useful for anything.
Rym: Well, what you do is, you know, we've got someone an undesirable has come to the geek house.
Rym: All right, dude, you stay here.
Rym: We're all gonna go get Chinese food and bring it back.
Rym: Don't mind me turning on all these ionizing air fresheners and closing all the windows.
Rym: don't go anywhere for the next four days.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, they sold these ionizing air fresheners and basically air filters.
Rym: All they did was make ozone and ozone is mildly toxic.
Rym: Yep Yeah, that was a real great marketing idea.
Scott: They still sell these things.
Scott: if you want an air filter that's an air filter is an okay product.
Scott: It can be useful but don't buy an ionizing air fill.
Rym: Well, the thing is ionizing.
Rym: air filters can be not bad However, crappy ones and cheap ones and ones that claim to freshen the air usually just make ozone.
Scott: Yeah, it's just an ozone making machine and nothing else.
Scott: Anyway Sharper image.
Rym: So the Sharper image sold crap and you know I never really thought about this but in retrospect the hindsight comes in.
Rym: The Sharper image was one of those companies that pretty much the moment you could buy crap online their days were numbered because the only servers they offered was selling things that people didn't think they could get from anywhere else at Exorbitantly marked up prices.
Rym: I mean, yeah pretty much you if you're there Soviet like night vision.
Rym: That was really crappy and you had 500 bucks to kill.
Rym: Sharper image was where you went.
Scott: You would go there in the olden days You know like in the 90s and you would see things that you didn't even know existed or things you knew existed But seemed you like futuristic soviet night vision.
Scott: You couldn't buy them at Best Buy.
Rym: Do you know how much I wanted night vision as a kid from the age of seven until I stopped making Christmas lists night vision Was number one.
Scott: it was like fancy gadgets that were not available through any other venue that you knew of, you know, but now They don't even sell fancy gadgets.
Scott: They sell completely run-of-the-mill stuff.
Scott: that just well he has to be a fancy guy.
Rym: They don't sell jack anymore.
Rym: They went bankrupt.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: They did.
Rym: That's the news.
Rym: The Sharper image is filed for bankruptcy protection.
Rym: They're probably gonna go out of business.
Scott: Well, how does Brookstone stay in business?
Rym: and Sharper image doesn't I think because Brookstone had a lot more stores.
Rym: Brookstone stuff was a lot cheaper and a lot of a sharper image sold.
Rym: Like didn't appeal to the kind of like the old man old woman Grandma looking for a gift for their son who has some money to burn in the mall.
Rym: Hey a back scratcher Golf tee that also barks like a dog.
Rym: Sharper image sold things that were complicated that the old people didn't understand.
Rym: Brookstone sells very uncomplicated things that massage you that's true.
Rym: So, uh, yeah, they're pretty much done.
Rym: They're gonna sell get.
Rym: they're gonna keep some of their stores open to try to sell enough stuff to pay off all their debts.
Rym: They owe UPS like six million dollars.
Rym: Yeah, not that UPS cares.
Scott: well, I mean if you want fancy gadgets that are futuristic and do crazy things just go to in gadget read it every day and Occasionally, they'll be like hey check out this fancy gadget, you know stuff like, you know The optimus maximus keyboard or whatever and you know you go and you buy it from wherever who makes it.
Scott: That's that's how things go nowadays.
Scott: You don't need some sharper image to display to you the fancy future Don't?
Rym: I think really killed him in the end.
Rym: and why Brookstone still around?
Rym: Mm-hmm Brookstone and sharper image I think capitalized most of all on the market of people who go to Malls because they'd be there and when you went to the mall you'd walk by it and there's.
Rym: there's nothing interesting in the mall.
Rym: You're just you're there in this time warp with your family or something and geeky people would go to like natural wonder or Brookstone or sharper image because there were things to poke at.
Rym: that went meep and you could entertain yourself for like 10 minutes before You got on your way.
Rym: Yep now Geeks don't go to malls.
Rym: Geeks shop on Amazon.
Rym: They hate malls.
Rym: They don't go to malls unless they're gonna play DDR in the arcade because malls the only places that have arcades anymore.
Rym: Yeah So, uh, geeks don't go to malls.
Rym: sharper image markets expensive crap to semi geeky people.
Rym: Oh, well, I find this hilarious and I hope they're out in hell.
Scott: All right, so check this out, right?
Scott: So hard drive encryption is something people have been doing for a while now.
Scott: The idea of hard drive encryption right is we?
Scott: you know, if you encrypt your hard drive, obviously You know your computer needs to like read and use the data that's on your hard drive, you know to work You know like your operating system whatever.
Scott: so, you know it's encrypting the hard drive isn't like gonna prevent you from all sorts of security like worms and viruses and whatever.
Scott: because if you get a Worm or a virus is you'll just be on your hard drive encrypted.
Scott: It'll it'll still be all evil.
Scott: You know what hard drive encryption protects you from?
Scott: is it protects you from someone coming into your house?
Scott: Taking your hard drive and then reading the data off.
Rym: So yes now not we're not talking about file encryption.
Rym: I mean I can have an encrypted directory where all my whatever it is that I'm trying to hide is in there And that's a totally different thing.
Scott: Yeah, we're talking about encrypting the entire hard drive.
Scott: Not just some files.
Scott: the whole thing, right?
Scott: So the operating system everything that way they don't even know what files you have let alone, you know It's not like with file encryption to be like, oh I see a file here, but I can't read what's in it.
Scott: With hard drive encryption, it's.
Scott: I have no idea what's on this hard drive.
Scott: It may as well be blank, but you type in a password and you have the.
Scott: you know The decrypting software in your BIOS or whatever and now you can use the encrypted drive.
Scott: But so if someone stole your computer They wouldn't get any of your data.
Scott: if your drive is encrypted or if the police came to arrest you you turn your computer off.
Scott: Now they can't get your data, right?
Rym: Of course if you're worried if you're one of those people where oh snap the police are gonna come and take my computer one day And you're not a teenager anymore because every teenage geek thinks that often.
Rym: but it's never gonna happen unless you're doing something actually bad.
Rym: but a Better way to go about that is to use nothing but live CDs.
Rym: keep everything resident in RAM at all times.
Scott: Well, that's what I'm gonna talk about in a second.
Scott: See.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Scott: Yeah Um When you encrypt your hard drive like that Right these you still need a piece of software to be running at all times that you know is constantly Decrypting and encrypting all your reads and writes to and from the drive
Rym: unless you get an encrypted like hardware hard drive.
Rym: I guess there are things that do that there.
Scott: I guess there are.
Scott: but the point is is that most of these solutions the way They work is you turn the computer on and at some point it asks you for the passphrase to unlock the keys Right, and then it loads the keys into RAM and then the software, you know reads the key in RAM and you know Reason writes to the drive, you know with within and decrypts and encrypts everything with the key That's in RAM, which is fine because if someone steals your hard drive or you turn the computer off You know that it doesn't stay in RAM.
Scott: They can't get your key.
Scott: They basically need your computer and your password Your passphrase to get the key loaded into RAM to get the software working and it succeeds at the Job, it's supposed to do.
Scott: however Some guys have discovered and this is sort of obvious if you think about it, right?
Scott: So you got some RAM.
Scott: You know how RAM works?
Scott: Well the RAM can work in many different ways.
Scott: It's just memory.
Scott: that's you know random access but specifically the DRAM that's in your computer works this way.
Scott: It's basically a bunch of capacitors, right?
Scott: You know what a capacitor is.
Scott: if you don't I can't help you.
Rym: Yeah, I don't even know if we talked about that.
Rym: No, we didn't but we did a show on basic computer stuff But I think that was a little more basic than we went.
Scott: Yeah, RAM is a bunch of capacitors.
Scott: So if you have each capacitors one capacitor for each bit literally, so if the capacitor is charged It's a one and if it's discharged it's a zero.
Scott: so RAM is basically well.
Rym: Sometimes it's the opposite.
Rym: but don't worry about it doesn't matter.
Rym: specifics don't matter Don't don't don't focus.
Scott: basically your RAM is constantly charging and discharging a like a zillion capacitors.
Scott: You have 128 megabytes of RAM.
Rym: That's like a hundred and twenty-eight mega times eight.
Scott: That's a thousand twenty four million capacitors in a very small amount of space and they're either getting charged and discharged constantly, right okay, so You have this key in your RAM somewhere.
Scott: that is your encryption key and It's in these capacitors that are either on or off.
Scott: Okay, so you turn your computer off.
Scott: What if I spray your RAM with Freon?
Scott: Right or some other sort of compressed air coolant?
Scott: take the RAM out of your computer.
Scott: put it into a RAM reading thing.
Scott: Read the data out of the RAM and people had.
Scott: they just did this.
Scott: they proved that it works.
Scott: You can get someone's encryption key.
Scott: So if I show up at your house and I'm prepared and I know your drive is encrypted and I'm you know I'm taking your computer I can with a can of compressed air and You know a machine to read the data out of your RAM.
Scott: I can get pretty much all the data out of your RAM very reliably and decrypt your drive.
Scott: so Make your RAM warm, I guess when you turn it off.
Scott: We should have a little RAM heaters.
Scott: You turn your computer off.
Rym: How long after you turn your computer off is the data still there?
Scott: You pretty much you know, you spray it's.
Scott: it's not that long but it's it's long enough to where it can be a threat if someone is prepared.
Rym: so basically if Mission impossible happens in your house.
Scott: It's not it's more than mission impossible.
Scott: It's mission sort of likely.
Rym: How I mean I really how long did they say?
Scott: that didn't say but they did it.
Rym: I really don't believe that it's more than a few seconds.
Scott: I it might be a minute.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I didn't even that.
Rym: a minute is not that much of a concern.
Scott: It's not.
Rym: it's not very long because that means that you were still getting mission impossible.
Rym: Someone is coming into your house.
Scott: They're gonna go ready ready RAM free on read hard drive rod Yeah, but I mean it's not even free like they did it with a can of.
Scott: you know Air like it's kind of air you used to clean your computer You turn it upside down and now you have a our frostbite gun.
Scott: Yeah, that's true.
Scott: by the way, the point is is that You know, we need to even though it's it's sort of mission impossible.
Scott: ish Well, you know what not, you know, it's not enough to satisfy security.
Rym: It illustrates a much more important point of much broader point that and and there's.
Rym: this is somewhat tangentially related, but I'm gonna Talk very briefly about the idea of the side channel that you have information that you were trying to protect or access or whatever.
Rym: There's information in a place but there is kind of this ancillary External or meta information about that or dependent upon that and a lot of times you can get information in Unanticipated ways like there was a story a long time ago about.
Rym: you can't do this with Ethernet but with slower old networking protocols.
Rym: You know There's that little LED that lights up whenever you're sending data.
Rym: The way those really worked back in the day was that it literally just whenever there was current going over the line It lit up and whenever there wasn't current it wasn't lit up.
Rym: So if you filmed those light bulbs in a data center those LEDs with a high-speed camera You could recreate from that film all the data that was being sent over the line.
Rym: This was done experimentally several times.
Rym: Yep, that that is like a side band side channel doesn't work anymore Doesn't work on Ethernet or gigabit or anything like that, but it worked on old stuff a long time ago.
Scott: Yeah, that's stuff that was slow.
Scott: now The lights don't actually blink, you know.
Rym: But there's all sorts of info ways to get information that you might not anticipate.
Rym: there are all these other channels Carrying the information that you create that if you actually are worried about security You have to pay attention to these and at least decide.
Rym: All right, how much effort would it take to exploit the side channel?
Rym: How much is it worth to me to defend against such an attack?
Scott: I think what people are just gonna start doing is when their computer shuts down the shutdown sequence You know in the operating system, it's just gonna write all zero, you know, just blank out the the RAM and then turn off.
Scott: It's kind of simple.
Rym: Well, this is more.
Rym: I think this is more the case of if someone breaks into a house or a place where there's a live Computer Yeah, and they rip the RAM out do this to it get the key and then take the hard drive I guess.
Scott: but if you rip the RAM out like that you might break it.
Scott: So it's it's sort of risky.
Scott: You didn't really have to shut down the computer nicely, you know.
Rym: So you could get the RAM out there.
Rym: It wouldn't be that hard.
Scott: No, I mean you could do a shut down and then pull the RAM out.
Rym: But why don't you just got?
Rym: why don't you just pull the power plug pull the RAM out do your thing?
Scott: You could do that.
Scott: There you go.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, anyway, you could build a tiny UPS into the computer.
Rym: All right it's time for things of the day.
Rym: now.
Rym: this popped up on the internet again suddenly and it pops up perennially and it pops up a Lot in kind of like people will quote it reference it.
Rym: Maybe not even realize they're referencing it But there's a film that I think a lot of the internet generation have not actually seen and I'd highly recommend that you do.
Scott: I never heard of it before just now.
Rym: This is a fantastic film.
Rym: The film is called network and it was put out in 1976 and I'm not really gonna get into what it's about other than that.
Rym: It's a lot like the film Bullworth, which is also a fantastic film that I think you should all see.
Rym: This is it said that of all the great speeches of that.
Rym: I that I speeches that I think are great In the top 100. many of them are fictional speeches and this is one of them.
Rym: This is just a clip from the movie and he basically the main character Gives a sort of speech to the people watching the network news the people people watching TV at home And it is commonly referred to as the I'm mad as hell speech.
Rym: This is my thing of the day because I really think that everyone should see this speech think about it and then go and see this movie and think about what that movie is saying.
Rym: and then go see the movie Bullworth and Think about what that movie is saying and think about if they're saying the same thing or not.
Scott: Yeah, I mean I've heard people say, you know, I'm mad as hell not gonna take it anymore plenty of times.
Scott: I just never in my life realized it was a reference to this movie that you know.
Rym: And even though there was a thing to be referenced and if nothing else as a thing of the day This is a really good video.
Rym: It's one of those work you up kind of oh, man.
Rym: Oh, man, if only someone did this in the real world It's a little bit of sanctuary ishness, but not much.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well that that's.
Rym: it's more of a like kind of realistic sanctuariness.
Rym: Yeah, it gets.
Scott: it gets a little silly to be at the end there.
Rym: Well, it kind of may.
Rym: if you see the rest of the movie It makes a lot more sense.
Rym: But the only silly part is that when all the people start yelling outside, there's one woman She has the most annoying voice and I don't know who they got to do those yells.
Rym: But the two got the two people who were standing better ADR in the 70s that that was some some some spectacularly bad voice acting Right there.
Scott: Yeah Is that it?
Rym: I'm mad as hell and I think that's it.
Scott: Okay, so Over the years.
Scott: There's been a lot of little programs that sort of.
Scott: you know Basically do fun physics things, you know, like they'll give you a ramp and some wheels and a. you know a ball maybe and a rope or something like that and they'll they'll let you arrange them in various ways.
Scott: and then you know You can apply forces or set friction.
Scott: and you know, watch what happens.
Scott: just a little 2d physics engine kind of programs.
Scott: There's been plenty of these right?
Scott: But there's one dude.
Scott: I don't have his name.
Scott: I turn my laptop off.
Scott: Oh, well, you'll go to the website.
Scott: You'll see.
Rym: Oh, yeah, by the way, I bought a new lifeboat p80 10.
Rym: It's gonna come any day.
Scott: Oh, man's great he For his master's thesis project, whatever it was in college.
Scott: He made one of these physics engine things but different from all the other physics engine II things that I've ever seen before.
Scott: this one is First of all, it's it's got a superior user interface.
Scott: He's got mouse gestures.
Scott: He's got you know, a really good menu system.
Scott: It looks pretty slick.
Rym: It's not like some crappy flash or Java thing Like most of the ones I've seen before I can just imagine in the hands of a competent physics teacher This being one of the most excellent.
Rym: This is the perfect example of how technology can be used to make the educational environments in this country better.
Rym: Well, that's this country anywhere in the world.
Rym: This is this is how technology should be used in the classroom.
Scott: Anyway, so the program is called fun p-h-u-n.
Scott: it's free.
Scott: You just download it and use it I guess and You can do all sorts of crazy stuff with the fluids with friction you can make you know, you can make machines you can do all sorts of stuff and it's got a really good user interface and it's can be fun and educational and awesome and cool.
Scott: and it's just about everything and Everyone should probably have this and it could be useful and I don't know what else to say.
Scott: I'm still a little bit sick.
Rym: Well, I guess we can get right into the main bit and then go to bed.
Scott: Yeah, let's let's hurry this up.
Rym: Well, we've talked about this a lot.
Rym: We've said multiple times we'll do an episode on this specifically because we've been asked by many of you To do an episode on this and to clarify a very important position that we brought up a lot.
Rym: Yeah, and the position or the idea here is computer literacy.
Rym: We did a show a while back on how Maybe not yet, but in the very near future within our lifetimes Being computer literate and technology literate is going to be tantamount to what literacy as in knowing the Language of English or the language reading
Scott: and writing
Rym: you live in.
Scott: reading and writing it will being able to read and write.
Scott: Yes we have.
Scott: we have said many times in the show before that we believe that in the near future or even in the present not Knowing how to use a computer or not having computer literacy Will be just as bad as not knowing how to read or write.
Rym: just as bad specifically we mean Just as crippling and debilitating just as preventative of living a normal life and ever having a big about.
Scott: think about how Hard it is for someone to live within our system our Western US society not knowing how to read or write the common language.
Scott: That'll be that hard to live within our society not knowing how to use a computer in this in the near future.
Rym: Now in that when we talked about that we had a very long episode But we didn't really talk a lot about exactly what computer literacy means.
Scott: a lot of people are like well You know they were like.
Scott: how much do you have to know to be computer literate?
Scott: How much are you know coming?
Scott: I mean cuz like.
Scott: look at it right.
Scott: a good example is Japan where you can know the language You can know how to speak and read and write, but they have like how many kanji's right like a zillion.
Scott: and You know people are sort of not everyone knows all of them.
Scott: in fact almost nobody knows all of them.
Scott: But different people know different amounts and knowing one amount you can get by pretty well, but knowing an even greater amount That's like a special skill, so you know it's like you know.
Scott: how much computer literacy Do you need to have before you'll be you know literate like how good do you have to be?
Rym: and also?
Rym: It's it's a very complicated thing - I mean we have enough trouble in this country and in the world trying to determine Literacy rates.
Rym: it just in general.
Rym: because what exactly is the line?
Rym: What is the line?
Rym: Yeah, I mean literate person and a non literate.
Scott: per I mean there are people who can read c-spot run.
Scott: They can read a sports page or a magazine, but not a book not a book That was well played.
Rym: yeah, but The the short answer is that there is no short answer to that and also the answer is going to change.
Rym: That'll probably what we impressive on you the most.
Rym: as well as that I want to get into specifics though because that's the interesting part But I guess we really need to get it.
Rym: make it clear that The bar of computer literacy is going to be ever-changing forever Mm-hmm unlike literacy where language reached a point where I think and language changes pretty even language does change though.
Scott: I mean you know there are new words.
Scott: You know you can.
Scott: if someone who's sort of old-fashioned tries to talk to someone who is sort of new and hip they have a hard Time understanding.
Rym: excuse me my good sir.
Rym: Could you direct me to the nearest pugilarium?
Scott: Yeah, and at the same time people who are very you know modern with their love have a hard time understanding the old people's.
Rym: I'd be mad shavin.
Rym: Yeah, shivin whatever ship shab shab shab shab shab.
Scott: so Computer literacy is gonna is a lot like that where you know someone who is.
Scott: you know someone who was awesome with the Apple - right?
Scott: Rocking it hard is not.
Scott: may not be computer literate now.
Scott: They may you know that you have to really Keep up-to-date.
Scott: you know a lot or else you're in trouble.
Rym: But at the same time not everyone needs to be a computer expert.
Scott: not everyone needs to know Everything about like you need to know how to drive But you don't necessarily have to be Michael Schumacher.
Scott: only Michael Schumacher has to be Michael Schumacher or even you know.
Rym: most people know how to drive.
Rym: in America very relatively few people know know more than the Absolute basics of how their car functions and even fewer than that know how to do anything about a problem with a car.
Rym: They take it to a mechanic.
Rym: Yep the problem with computers is that you can do a lot more with them and there's a lot more they can go wrong and I Guess the the total depth that could be achieved is already I think beyond what any one person could do.
Rym: There is no person who could be 100% computer literate.
Rym: no absolutely I think computers are already beyond what humans could ever fully fully fully understand.
Scott: Well, you know, I mean you get to understand the micro electronic engineer.
Rym: I have a working ready knowledge of.
Scott: yeah I mean you'd have to understand the micro electronic engineering the computer engineering.
Scott: you'd have to know programming from the assembly language level all the way up to like.
Scott: You know the the JavaScript levels.
Scott: you'd have to know how all applications work.
Scott: You'd have to understand how the like the monitor works and all the devices work and and all the different electronic components.
Scott: It's I mean, I understand all that stuff but not to the tiniest detail and experts at those things often Don't know a lot about other thing.
Scott: I mean, yeah, I mean micro electronic engineers usually aren't like, you know Amazing application program or like.
Rym: I'm a I'm an enterprise IT guy.
Rym: I know a lot about IT.
Rym: I'm an awful programmer and I barely get by in Python.
Rym: Scott Is an awesome programmer knows a lot about programming.
Rym: Scott couldn't deal too well with being put in front of a Cisco router.
Rym: I could do or should I could do?
Scott: Okay with it, but not what.
Rym: what do you type to make it?
Rym: let you do anything?
Scott: turn on bitch.
Rym: There we go, all right tell that router but I want to get right into it.
Rym: let's talk about Right now as in today Monday, February 25th 2008 in the United States of America in an urban place.
Rym: What is what what?
Rym: what do we believe is?
Rym: The line?
Rym: what is computer literacy?
Rym: Okay What are the things you must know or be able to do in order for Rym and Scott to say you serve our?
Rym: Computer literate?
Scott: the first two things are things that not many people realize but it's the first thing that you know Old people have trouble with trying to use the computer.
Rym: I know what you're gonna say.
Rym: You must have mastery Absolute mastery of the mouse and the keyboard or if you are unable to use either due to a physical problem an Equivalent input device.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: There are many things you can do to get by if you cannot use the mouse to the keyboard.
Scott: For example, if you have no arms, you can use a thing called Dasher coconut monkey.
Rym: How is it that despite having neither arms nor legs you continue to beat me?
Scott: Yes, or if you have boxing gloves on your hands you can type anyway Right, so if you need to be able to type without looking at the keyboard and whatever language it is Your keyboard is in you need to you know Be able to use the keyboard quickly and efficiently and know where all the keys are know what keys do what
Rym: you need.
Rym: You need to be able to use the mouse now not When I say be able to you move the mouse.
Rym: you should be able to now.
Rym: this might sound dumb But you know, we're talking about computer literacy.
Rym: if we were talking about literacy It's like be able to use phonics to figure out a rough pronunciation of a word with which you are unfamiliar.
Rym: You know, that's the level we're talking at here.
Rym: You need to be able to move the mouse pointer relatively quickly from one arbitrary point to another arbitrary point.
Scott: You need to basically have it in your muscle memory.
Scott: If it's not in your if using the mouse is not in your muscle memory and you have to use your conscious brain if you're moving Your whole arm if you're looking at the most to move your whole arm, but well, it depends.
Rym: Yeah different schools of thought.
Scott: There are different schools of thought.
Rym: when I say moving your whole arm I think you get the image of the old lady who's like gripping the mouse for dear life and like Scooting it across at an awkward angle while staring it.
Scott: You need to be able to click you be able to double click you need to be able to drag and drop and you need To be able to do those things without really thinking it needs to be in your muscle memory.
Rym: Yes now you also along those lines.
Rym: when it comes to mice and keyboards you need to understand the the jargon the language the The vernacular of computing.
Rym: you need to know what a right click and a left click and a context menu and a middle click are A double click a triple click.
Rym: you need to be able to execute these maneuvers and if directed to know what they are.
Rym: Yep, it the fact that there that I run into people.
Rym: Well, I'm not anymore now that I work at an awesome company But when I worked at the other the hospital I ran into people on a daily basis who had worked with computers for much of their lives who I Believe could not effectively type or use a mouse.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: It's true We go to be able right-click.
Scott: They'd be like what the other mouse button the one you don't usually use.
Rym: Okay, and Right along those lines you need to be able to identify the most basic of connectivity problems related to input devices.
Rym: if you're typing and Nothing happens you look and see if the keyboard is plugged in.
Rym: You know what num lock does you hit it to see if the light is lighting up or not?
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: You need to know where these things plug in.
Scott: I mean, you don't need to know that this one's a USB or that.
Scott: well, you should know that but you don't necessarily.
Scott: You know that but you need to know this plug goes in that hole.
Scott: You know You need to know which things go where in when you're plugging them into the box.
Rym: Everyone who is computer literate should be able to if given a new mouse and keyboard replace their old mouse and keyboard without direction.
Rym: Yep Now there might be Drivers or crap within like if you get a fancy mouse or like a special tablet.
Rym: and that's beyond this I'm talking about physically.
Scott: Yeah, like it in you don't need to know about the inside of your computer so much But you need to know about every hole on the outside.
Scott: You need to know the power button the reset button the CD-ROM Anything that is on the outside of the box.
Scott: that is your computer.
Scott: You need to know how that works and what it means and what it does.
Rym: we need to know the difference between the reset button and the power button and and You need to know that holding the power button down is different from pressing it and both are important.
Scott: Yeah, you need to know pretty much how everything on the outside of the computer works entirely.
Scott: which hole you know?
Scott: This is the hole where the monitor plugs in.
Scott: This is the hole where the network plugs in.
Scott: This is the hole where you know the modem plugs in.
Rym: now You don't need to understand them on a deeper level than that.
Rym: You just need to know what plugs into what or at least know that that is not where you plug this in.
Rym: Yep, if there's not identified hole as long as you're not using that hole and it never comes up.
Rym: I mean if someone can't identify a firewire hole and they're not using firewire devices, that's not bad.
Scott: But if you're trying to jam a USB stick in there You need to be able to go to the store and buy any external thing and then get it to work.
Rym: and along those lines.
Rym: you need to be able to know when you go to a store and You're buying an external component whether or not you have a USB or a USB 2.0 or not Yep, or at least be able to identify the fact that you do not know
Scott: Mm-hmm
Rym: and be able to ask the right question.
Rym: Do I have this to someone who can then look and tell you if you can't go to the store and buy things?
Scott: They got to go with your computer and know if you're buying the right thing, then you have a serious problem.
Rym: now We're all again.
Rym: We're only talking about simple peripherals.
Rym: I'm not talking about hard drives RAM all that.
Rym: Yeah, you should be able to buy a monitor.
Scott: You should be able to buy a mouse or a keyboard or USB stick or You know an external hard drive or a joystick or any any of these sorts of everyday things You should be able to buy and get them working without help.
Rym: All right people now regards to monitors.
Rym: to be computer literate You need to know at least on a basic level what screen resolution is how to change it in your operating system of choice What resolution your display is?
Rym: Optimally what the benefits and drawbacks are of using or not using the optimal resolution.
Scott: Yep, you need to sort of understand.
Scott: in terms of monitors You seem you need to understand.
Scott: first of all, the monitor and the computer are two different things.
Scott: Yes, a lot of people don't realize the monitor is just a TV and the computer is the computer.
Scott: You know a lot of people like we'll call the monitor the computer and they'll call the computer the CPU or they'll call it the hard drive.
Scott: Yeah All those the basic terms.
Rym: you need to know what the following terms mean hard drive disk CD rewritable media monitor LCD CRT.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much all that, you know.
Scott: video card.
Rym: Yes the basic basic stuff you need to know what a video mouse keyboard?
Rym: all you need to know is what a video card is and Fundamentally that it makes the pixels appear on your screen.
Rym: You do need to know by the way what a pixel is CD-ROM.
Scott: You need to know the basic words of the parts of the computer.
Scott: I mean like you open your car, you may not know what a transmission does but you need to know transmission engine Alternator battery.
Rym: Yes now Word screen resolution.
Rym: You might think what.
Rym: why screen resolution?
Rym: That's like the number two Problem I ran into working with non-technical people is they'd complain that the screens too big the screens too small.
Rym: They can't see everything's too big.
Rym: something disappeared off the side of the screen.
Rym: How do I change the size?
Scott: I don't want to get off on a tangent but a lot of people especially people have a hard time seeing.
Scott: We'll have giant monitors with very high native resolutions and they will turn the resolution way down to make everything larger.
Scott: That is the wrong way.
Scott: What you should do is you should set the optimal resolution To the incredibly high resolution of the giant monitor and you should increase the size of your fonts and icons to be incredibly huge.
Scott: That is the correct way.
Scott: I don't want to say any more about it because that's a rant I have?
Scott: Yes, but nobody does it that way even though it's the way you should do it.
Rym: now onto the computer and operating system itself.
Rym: You need to be able to navigate to and use every basic function of your operating system of choice.
Scott: You need to know how to change any settings.
Rym: You may want to change any at least any superficial GUI setting or basic internal setting.
Scott: You need to know how to be able to add and remove Applications and use applications and know which applications do what.
Scott: generally you need to know how to read.
Scott: pretty much You know what?
Scott: It comes down to is a lot of people do not read the things that it says on the screen.
Scott: and even if they do Read them like they read the words, but they don't process the words in their brain like it'll say warning Mouse not detected and someone will call and say I got this error.
Rym: I don't know what it means.
Rym: Yeah, what's it say?
Scott: warning mouse not detected?
Scott: Well, maybe the mouse hasn't been detected.
Scott: Did you check the mouse to make sure it's plugged in?
Scott: I don't know they don't.
Scott: you have to be able to read what it says on the screen and think about it in your brain and Understand what it says.
Scott: that includes what menus say what dialog boxes say whatever Harsh.
Rym: but if you cannot or will not do that you are not and will never be computer literate.
Scott: You're not even regular literate.
Scott: But that's the number one problem people have trying to use a computer is they don't read what it says.
Scott: or if they do Read what it says they only translate the words into sounds.
Scott: They don't actually translate the words into the ideas that they represent.
Scott: You know and if a word if anywhere on your computer screen There is a word you need to know what that word means.
Scott: Unless you know, maybe you're reading some scientific paper on a website or something but any word that is part of an application interface that is part of the user interface of the Applications you were using.
Scott: you need to know all of those words.
Scott: They need to be part of your vocabulary every single one of them.
Rym: now in terms of files.
Rym: You need to know where any file you put or cause to be put on your computer is.
Rym: You need to know where it went and why it went there.
Scott: Not only that you need to understand the idea of a file system.
Rym: a lot of people don't get file systems buried You know, you don't need to know that, you know, like I know There's in riser FS and XFS.
Scott: but you need to understand the concept of a hierarchical set of files and directories and folders and how they work and file extensions.
Scott: and you need to sort of understand that files are arranged in this way.
Scott: and you know different files go in different places.
Scott: and how to organize files copying the simple test studies running.
Rym: you need to know how to navigate to Any file that you have caused to be placed on the computer.
Rym: if files get on your computer by actions You have taken and you do not know where they are and you do not know how to find where they are You're not computer literate.
Scott: You need to know renaming Copying cutting pasting files moving editing creating.
Rym: Yes, and at least have a basic understanding of Some way to organize your files so that you will be able to find them in the future.
Rym: that might involve something like Google Desktop But you need to understand a lot of people.
Rym: ideally
Scott: you would understand the connection between you know The sort of abstraction of a file system user interface and the actual hardware, you know Understand that C colon is a hard drive and D colon is a CD ROM and a colon is a floppy drive But
Rym: that's a little bit beyond.
Rym: you just need to know where the files you got are.
Rym: Yep, and the number of people who don't that those people are not computer literate new Not at all.
Scott: Now the other thing I think is the hardest thing and I don't know if it's an absolute requirement.
Scott: I think it is going to be pretty much if it isn't already is that you should be able to pick up and install any Application any application whatsoever for your operating system.
Scott: get it installed know how to can can fit be able to figure out By reading and looking at it Intuitively how to configure it and how to use its most basic features and get it to do its basic task.
Scott: now No matter what the application.
Rym: now, there are obvious exceptions to this.
Scott: like you shouldn't be able to pick up Photoshop It'd be a Photoshop master.
Rym: Well, there are very clear exceptions to this programs that have poorly written installers programs that are meant for technical users.
Rym: my two examples are pretty much any craftily written program and Web sphere.
Rym: If you cannot install web sphere you that does not make you not computer literate.
Rym: that makes you a happy person.
Rym: Yeah Because if you are a person who can knows how to intuitively install web sphere.
Rym: you have led a sad Life and I feel sorry for you because good God, but
Scott: if we're talking about web browsers instant messengers word processors spreadsheets Everyday applications anything that you can buy the shelf in staples anything you can download from like download calm any Normal everyday application that is meant for you to be used by you You know as targeting
Rym: or you
Scott: any application that is for you targeted as you being the user You should be able to figure out how to use it without you know Reading the help and spending, you know You need to basically in you have these skill to intuit The default use of any application
Rym: or in the very least in the very very least to be able to articulate Your question if you are unable to install something to someone who will be able to help you in a way That will allow them to help you.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: If you can do that that excuses almost any misunderstanding.
Scott: Yeah, if you can, you know If you call someone for help and you can actually communicate to them your problem Then and they can actually help you just based on what you say then you're a computer literate All right.
Rym: Let's talk a little bit about the Internet.
Rym: Of course, you need to understand the difference between the Internet your web browser Email web pages all these basic.
Rym: You need to know what bookmarks are how to manage them and access them in your browser of choice.
Rym: You should know this.
Rym: this was actually.
Rym: I think this is a straight-up requirement.
Rym: I think anyone who cannot do this is by no means even close to computer literacy.
Rym: You should not at least I'm gonna give a really low threshold here 95% of the time.
Rym: if Confronted with a shady or phishing website.
Rym: You should be able to know immediately that is a shady or phishing website.
Scott: Oh, yeah cannot do that.
Rym: You have not gotten to the point where you really understand the internet.
Scott: you if you can't tell a spam email from a legitimate Email just by looking at say the subject line then and the in the from I say 90% 95% of the time because occasionally, there's the masterpiece.
Rym: but Seriously, the vast majority of the time if you cannot immediately look at a website and say this is trustworthy.
Rym: This isn't trustworthy or This is a phishing site.
Rym: This is my banking site.
Rym: You should not be on the internet because that is very dangerous for you to be there.
Scott: Yeah, that's like if you can't if you're going to.
Scott: you know Some dangerous neighborhood and you can't tell you know, who's a cop and who's a mugger?
Scott: You probably shouldn't be in a dangerous neighborhood.
Rym: Now also in terms of the internet again, you know files.
Rym: if you download files, you should know where they go.
Scott: You should be able to understand the concept of downloading files and uploading.
Rym: You should understand what plugins are Basic plugins be able to install them and use them in your operating system of choice.
Scott: You should know like, you know, what's up like a web browser plug-in and what's another.
Scott: you know, you should understand.
Scott: You know what you're doing when you're doing.
Scott: if you ever do anything on your computer and you don't fully understand You don't have to understand it down to the lowest level.
Scott: But if you're installing say a Firefox extension, you shouldn't have that confused with say, you know a widget for your dashboard or you know a Plug in for your Photoshop, you know, you shouldn't have these things confused.
Scott: You should know what you're installing when you're installing it what you're doing when you're doing it.
Scott: if you ever do something You don't know exactly what you're doing.
Scott: You just know it works or You know something like that.
Scott: Then you have a problem.
Rym: Yeah, but the bare bare minimum there too.
Rym: When it comes to online website, well god online websites, but like websites or computers or anything that has authentication You need to be able to come up with and remember Login names and passwords or at least have a way of retrieving said login names and pass and know
Scott: which ones you should be able to get to Separate the idea of which ones go where.
Scott: if to understand this is a wet This is a password for this website.
Rym: You need to understand my computer what a login and a password are and what they entail.
Scott: Yep, and like a lot of people just you know, there's like oh I have a username and password They don't understand.
Scott: this one is for this and this one is for that.
Scott: you need to you know understand.
Scott: You know the difference in a website and application your operating system your computer.
Scott: You know the separation between which things are what you know where the boundaries are between different items.
Scott: Really you need to understand that now on your computer.
Rym: along these lines You need to understand what an account is that you have one and how to do basic account functions like changing your username changing your password.
Scott: Yeah, if you don't understand the idea of user accounts and multi-user systems then you got a problem now.
Rym: You don't need to understand how to elevate something administrative whatever, you know I mean we're talking about the lowest level here.
Rym: You need to understand that accounts exist that you have one that you log into it Maybe you've set it up to log in automatically that there can be more than one account.
Rym: But you have to know that you have done this.
Rym: Yep, and I think I think that covers pretty much 99% of what constitutes basic minimal Absolutely minimal computer literacy.
Scott: I mean, I think we could probably go on more.
Scott: I mean that's for right now, you know in the future It's only gonna be more and more that you're gonna need to know, you know Things are gonna get more complicated or you know, there's gonna be new things.
Scott: You're gonna have to understand these new things.
Rym: But I really believe at this juncture in time as of today at 8 10 p.m On Monday February 25th 2008 if you can do all of the things that we have said I believe that you are at least minimally computer literate and if you cannot do these things You should really be working on being able to do these things quickly because the world is going to leave
Scott: you behind.
Scott: Yeah, I mean I could.
Scott: we could probably sit her out and think of a few more things to say.
Scott: But you know, I don't know.
Rym: I want to keep it pretty simple because that's enough.
Rym: I mean we're talking about the lowest level like what you need to even be considered competent enough to touch a computer.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Scott: don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.
Rym: I don't have to tell you things are bad.
Rym: Everybody knows things are bad.
Rym: It's a depression.
Rym: Everybody's out of work or scared of losing their job.
Rym: The dollar buys a nickels worth.
Rym: banks are going bust shopkeepers keep a gun under the counter Punks are running wild in the street.
Rym: There's nobody anywhere seems to know what to do and there's no end to it.
Rym: We know the air is unfit to breathe and our food is unfit to eat.
Rym: We sit watching our TVs while some local newscaster tells us that today We had 15 homicides and 63 violent crimes as if that's the way it's supposed to be.
Scott: We know things are bad worse than bad.
Rym: They're crazy, it's like everything everywhere is going crazy so we don't go out anymore.
Rym: We sit in the house and slowly the world we're living in is getting smaller and all we say is please At least leave us alone in our living rooms.
Rym: Let me have my toaster and my TV and my steel-belted radios, and I won't say anything.
Rym: Just leave us alone.
Rym: Well, I'm not gonna leave you alone.
Rym: I want you to get mad.
Rym: I Don't want you to protest.
Rym: I don't want you to ride.
Rym: I don't want you to write to your congressman because I wouldn't know what to tell you to write.
Rym: I don't know what to do about the depression and the inflation and the Russians and that crime in the street.
Rym: All I know is that first you've got to get mad.
Scott: You've got to say I'm a human being.
Scott: god Damn it.
Scott: My life has value.
Rym: I want you to get up now.
Rym: I Want all of you to get up out of your chairs.
Rym: I Want you to get up right now and go to the window Open it and stick your head out and yell.
Rym: I'm as mad as hell and I'm not gonna take this anymore.