Rym: Hey, it's Thursday October 23rd.
Scott: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights.
Scott: It's a Thursday.
Rym: We talk about the dorms at RIT.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: So we're playing burning wheel as we do when the physicals calm.
Rym: It's one of those burning weekends and Power goes out.
Scott: You should have a convention called the burning weekend.
Rym: Maybe I'll just burning wheel only convention Or maybe we'll have the burning wheel track at Connecticut.
Rym: We'll call that the burning weekend Possible Probable, I think we're gonna have to do it.
Rym: Anyway, so we're playing burning wheel and Various reasons we started late as opposed to early.
Rym: so, you know It's like seven or eight o'clock at night and we're still kind of just barely getting into the game.
Rym: people are just really getting into it and then All the power goes out.
Rym: And you know, whatever the power goes out our to play burning wheel.
Scott: You can't see the die roll You just need light.
Scott: Well, yeah, I played some candlelight burning wheel, you know, we tried that.
Rym: we learned something.
Rym: One candle we had that Emily lent to us.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Well, you only had one candle.
Scott: That was the problem.
Rym: candles aren't really that useful.
Rym: the amount of light they give is not enough to do it.
Scott: Well, there's a lot of can they only an actual physical candle only gives up one candle power.
Scott: That's why you need a candelabra.
Rym: Well, no, what you really need is a lantern.
Rym: you see maybe just I grew up in Michigan.
Scott: We had like ten candles.
Rym: We had the kind of ready for a power outage kid.
Rym: We had like seven or eight Coleman Lanards ready to go.
Rym: the second the power went out.
Rym: But you know, we didn't have that at Alex's house and he found his one LED flashlight.
Rym: So we put it on the table pointed at the ceiling.
Rym: But you know actually before that the real thing is whatever the power goes that you always think Alright, it's gonna come back on everyone Just kind of waits like, you know Everyone stops talking and ever just waits like our lives have stopped.
Rym: the power is gonna come back on lives continue.
Scott: And that would be something why you know.
Scott: Ever the lights in your house like light fixtures right run off electricity.
Scott: Someone should make a chandelier right.
Scott: that has a battery in it and the you know, so like a little UPS.
Scott: I think that'd be cool.
Scott: Not like every light in your house, but like just a few key lights.
Scott: You know.
Scott: that way if the power goes out those lights will be on sort of like the emergency lights and office buildings But for a house and they would look good like a chandelier looks good.
Rym: I have a feeling there are numerous problems.
Scott: The only problem I see is the battery, you know weighing down on the ceiling also just having the battery having to convert it.
Rym: There's a lot of problems, but you know, you have that moment the power goes out and you think alright It's gonna come back on.
Rym: and then there's that other moment when the power hasn't come back on yet and you realize Okay.
Rym: Now I have to do something about this.
Rym: So we go outside and we're like, well, I wonder if the power is out for everyone, you know, no The power at least at that point was on for everyone.
Rym: But the building we were in as far as we could tell really because I was gonna say I was not over there.
Scott: So I didn't experience the power outage, but on my way to work this morning, you know there's the light on the corner of Verplank and 9d.
Scott: Yeah, right where the Country Club is and I got there to make a left turn.
Rym: You know You're screwed and it was Blinking red in all directions trying to get out to drive around that whole night because there's the intersection right there by Emily and Alex's apartments.
Rym: Nobody in the world knows to stop when the from the light isn't working.
Rym: if you will just driving through and yeah Nobody stopped on the blinking red.
Rym: usually, you know to assert my right-of-way I literally flash my lights laid on the horn and just pulled into the intersection forced everyone to stop.
Scott: I just waited until it was safe and luckily it was in time for the train.
Scott: But usually my experience has been that people stop on the blinking red, but maybe it wasn't blinking red in the other direction But it was blinking red in mind.
Rym: Oh, no, the one by us wasn't even on See.
Rym: I figured out what happened there.
Rym: as far as I've always been able to tell there are two Relatively separate power grids and beacon because you kind of see like there's one set of wires that comes over from Fishkill But there's this other set of wires that comes over from like the other side through beacon and a lot of times I've seen like half of beacons power go out and the other half be up.
Rym: It's kind of weird, but I guess the apartments and the geek house are on two separate circuits or two separate grids because The power doesn't seem to go out in both at the same time.
Scott: There's a great website I wish I could remember and the website was pretty much like why does my neighbor have power?
Scott: and I don't Told you like this little map of like a sample power grid and how they're laid out and it said if the breakage is Here, right?
Scott: This is the houses that will lose power.
Scott: Isn't that crazy?
Scott: That's why your neighbor has power and you don't.
Scott: and it was really interesting.
Rym: I thought Rod Serling answered that question much more aptly cuz you're in the Twilight Zone.
Rym: You don't remember that episode.
Rym: Oh Wow, maybe that was.
Rym: Maybe that was too inside baseball.
Rym: Maybe I. maybe I've gotten beyond your own grass.
Scott: I remember a lot of twilight zones.
Scott: I don't remember anyone with power going out.
Rym: It was the one where there's a bunch of people, you know during the Cold War whatever like a lot of Twilight Zones were Power goes out and everyone's houses and it stays out.
Rym: So people all walk out.
Rym: They're like, ah, you know townie folk.
Rym: Let's all have a talk.
Rym: Let's hang out be on the porches And then they start getting you know little worried.
Rym: Why is the power still out?
Rym: What's going on?
Rym: and then the power just turns on for one dude's house and They start thinking well, why is his power on?
Rym: He must be a communist.
Rym: and it ends with like everyone shooting each other and freaking out.
Scott: That's how?
Rym: yeah No, that is I come.
Rym: then it pans back to the aliens and they're like humans are so easy to conquer.
Rym: Check it out.
Rym: All we got to do is turn off the lights Flick a couple on and off like a few switches and they kill each other and then they laugh and it fades to black.
Rym: Yeah, I guess I spoiled it.
Scott: There was an outer limits.
Scott: that it's something similar where at the end depends the aliens.
Rym: Oh the outer limits.
Rym: the show.
Rym: that was largely the Twilight Zone done slightly worse.
Scott: try to remember which one it was.
Scott: Oh, whatever.
Rym: Did you ever watch the remake of the outer limits?
Scott: I didn't know.
Scott: there was a remake.
Rym: Oh, it was on in the late 90s.
Rym: I think oh god, it actually wasn't that bad.
Scott: Oh god All right.
Rym: What do you want?
Rym: It wasn't that bad?
Rym: Hey, all right.
Rym: So what do you got in the news?
Scott: All right, so, you know No, what things are not so good in the economics ways, you know, but tech people were thinking It's not gonna hurt tech people right?
Scott: tech has been okay.
Scott: internet's still good, right and For some reasons they were right there back in the 90s, right?
Scott: The big problem was that all those web, you know web 1.0 companies from the dot-com era They were spending bajillions of dollars buying big fancy offices hiring tons of people.
Rym: not even just that I mean work.
Rym: there is this office culture then where if you were one of those companies It was kind of expected that you had multiple air hockey tables and foosball tables and The major expense was hiring people at $80,000 a year because they knew HTML and private jets and every.
Scott: you know.
Scott: People were just going nuts.
Scott: and that's the reason that there was a huge crash.
Scott: is because people just spent money like well No, it was.
Scott: there was no tomorrow.
Rym: Actually, no The reason there was a crash is because the bubble happened that all that stuff was not what caused the crash.
Rym: That was the result of the bubble.
Rym: right that extra money was there.
Rym: spending that money or not spending that money The crash would have happened the same.
Scott: Well, no, but the thing is if they hadn't let's say you had a dot-com company, right?
Scott: And let's say you had spent your money reasonably instead of ludicrous.
Rym: You're gonna have to assume this begs the question Yeah that your company has something worthwhile to sell and most of them did not.
Scott: but in the crash when it came You would have maybe been able to survive as some companies did for example The companies that had a product right?
Scott: Well, you'd have to have a product anyway, but you know Most of those companies didn't have products.
Rym: There were some companies.
Scott: think about if you didn't they were selling that you could afford to pay people for a few more months.
Scott: You would have gone out of business later.
Scott: But anyway, so you spend a few more months making a HTML for people because people nowadays are not IPO in really at all And because they're only they're spending money reasonably the web 2.0 companies Because the web 2.0 companies spend their money reasonably and not unreasonably.
Scott: They're having hard times, but they're not dead.
Scott: Right?
Scott: So we're seeing now is we're seeing Google cut back.
Scott: They're not buying as many servers.
Scott: They're not laying anyone off, but they're not buying servers like they used to right and Some of the web 2.0 companies are just laying off a few people.
Scott: now this you know, okay It's only really a news for me because it's sort of like I want to work at a cool company.
Scott: Ah shit, all the cool companies are laying people off and not hiring.
Scott: Oh, well, I'll just you know Stick with what I got until things get better.
Scott: But there's one particular story of layoffs that is pretty cold and I think I got to bring it out here.
Scott: Start revision 3 which is you know The.
Scott: I guess it's owned or closely related to dig and they make all those video shows and whatnot, right?
Scott: There was a show called I think pop siren, right?
Rym: I've heard that word.
Rym: I don't know what it is.
Scott: Yeah, I think it was some sort of.
Scott: It was a show with someone named Sarah Lane, right?
Scott: And I never.
Scott: I never knew who Sarah Lane was.
Scott: I never watched that show.
Scott: But on twit that I listened to yesterday Sarah Lane was on someone I didn't know until this morning and Sarah Lane is the was the lifestyle programming director for revision 3 and She was on to it for the first time yesterday and she was talking about how she was gonna co-host like dig real something something and whatever and Then today the day after doing the to it.
Scott: Well, I guess she's not gonna co-host the something something because they laid her her and some other people off.
Scott: Wow, of course and that is that is pretty cold.
Rym: laying off that sort of talent usually means that you really Didn't have much of a viable business anywhere.
Rym: You're basically just riding that wave.
Scott: Yeah, they are.
Scott: they laid off some pretty big talent here.
Scott: I think they laid off like Martin Sargent and some other semi-famous people and they cancelled three or four of their shows and You know, it's they're basically only keeping the you know, the top top stuff and you know cutting back everything else.
Rym: Well, I can safely say that there will be no layoffs here at GeekNights or the front row crew just yet.
Rym: The funniest though Scott Johnson might have to give him a pay cut.
Scott: Yeah The funniest thing is they'll be like that hit.
Scott: you read these stories and it's like such-and-such company lays off 10%.
Scott: You're like, oh my god 10%.
Scott: Yes Yes, like three people, okay Yeah, because they're actually small companies, you know, not like the dot-com companies which were too big for their own whatnot.
Scott: So I Just think it's pretty interesting You know because it's like a small company lays off these people.
Scott: It's like everyone at the company is someone with a name that you would know if you paid attention to what the company does and it's You know It's like everyone at the company is a face of the company and it's pretty interesting when you see layoffs of that nature as opposed To the faceless, you know, Yahoo lays off 500.
Rym: Well, it's like I don't know who any of those people are Of course, uh, what's really gonna be interesting is seeing if this continues.
Rym: I mean at least New York hasn't been as affected by this as a lot of other places in the country just because There's a lot of I mean other than the banks themselves.
Rym: like the people are actually going out of business around here.
Rym: Things are things are still pretty good and I haven't seen Craigslist change too much other than I guess all the Lehman Brothers people Think it's gonna happen at least in the tech industry, right?
Scott: Is there a lot of you know, because these companies can't afford it right like Yahoo laid off 500 people.
Scott: not all those people are gonna be wicked talented, but some of them are and All the companies that like couldn't get talent like they were having a hard time finding people are now gonna scoop all these people up and all the companies that were having hard times lose everyone and then all the people without talent are gonna be jobless.
Rym: I can I Can at least
Scott: say happy job
Rym: in IT that that is very very much the case at least around here because you know We we may or may not be looking to hire someone and I've interviewed a bunch of people and you're going through resumes and all That.
Rym: there are not that many qualified people out there.
Rym: No, even now like even with all these stories of layoffs.
Scott: I did not see resumes that look good Yeah, but all the you know, all the talented people are gonna get scooped up really quick.
Scott: So it's good news for companies that you know Didn't lose all their money and have to lay people off because they're gonna be able to hire awesome people and become more.
Rym: It's also good a time of bad Awesome people who are looking for change.
Rym: It is also good news for any of you who are still in college because as you may recall Me and Scott and everyone in the front row crew We were in college and high school pretty much through the dot-com boom and avoid and the bust and avoided All the bad effects of it and we got back on the job market.
Rym: pretty much, right?
Scott: Yeah, but if we had been a little earlier We would have gotten the mad money's in the dot-com boom and then we would have been smart and quit before we lost.
Rym: If we've been earlier, but not as earlier we would have been caught at the bottom.
Scott: Yeah that was remember.
Rym: the only people who are at least to IT wise and CS wise who are really really really gonna be hurt by This are people who don't have really exceptional skills In which case now is your chance to work out open source and bulk up that resume.
Rym: Or people who get out of college right now in which case look at that masters.
Rym: that masters might be a good idea.
Scott: The best advice I can give is the advice that was rightfully given by so many other people on to it and on other Podcasts and I you know, basically everyone's saying it but it bears repeating because born into wealth.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: But also when the economy is bad the only thing the best thing to invest in is to invest in yourself because everything you have is Going to lose its value.
Scott: your house your money and the bank is even gonna lose its value.
Scott: But your skills are the only thing of value that are that are limited and whatnot.
Scott: so you should invest in your skills improve them and and such and that is the way to Keep things going well when you know, everything else that you have is not worth anything.
Rym: I think that's what Warren Buffett was saying about the the stocks in the economy and generally pretty much said What everyone else is being greedy panic, but everyone else is panicking.
Rym: be greedy work on it.
Rym: It pretty much go against the trend and if you see a lot of people going in one direction go in the other direction.
Rym: of course That might just be completely wrong.
Scott: if there's a hurricane coming or I think that those people we Warren Buffett's not stupid You know, he's real smart and he's got a lot of monies and whatnot.
Scott: But I I think that some of the people maybe not Warren Buffett, but other people who write investment books and such I think that what they write in those books is like aha If everyone does what my book says then I'll do this and I'll get money.
Scott: I think that's.
Scott: their plan is Release the book the next day invest in this because people reading the book will invest in that and then I'll make it rich Because of this.
Rym: see the real problem is just that if you add up the opinions of all the experts They basically completely cancel themselves out with the economy.
Scott: I mean, but but Like, you know, there's there's five strong buys on this stock and zero Strong sells.
Scott: it must be good.
Rym: Well, I can't talk about that.
Rym: Yeah, unless we make up a hypothetical stock exactly talk about this fake stock, you know what?
Rym: by fly samo flag Nico.
Rym: Anyway, I had a news that I was a lot more excited about and I became alive.
Scott: SCC's knocking at the door.
Scott: They say semi-flanged companies out of business.
Rym: I Actually did.
Rym: there is paperwork.
Rym: I can buy stock but it's so copy.
Scott: Can't buy a semi-flange anymore.
Rym: Sam a flag box of Sam anyway.
Rym: So I was excited about this news until I read the article and I don't know if the article is just bad But it looked a lot less promising.
Rym: that I was odd.
Rym: I guess I was led to believe by slash dot.
Rym: Here's the slash dot fictional town Eureka to become a real Blah blah blah.
Rym: I'm gonna skip all the crap here.
Scott: Wait, there was a fictional town name Eureka.
Rym: Is that from some TV show that I read a Wikipedia page about it.
Rym: Scott Johnson's dad likes it.
Rym: I think really or Scott Johnson likes it.
Rym: I'm not sure but it was on at the shore a lot.
Rym: Anyway, I never saw it, you know, well, you didn't look at the glowing box.
Rym: Yeah, everyone else was looking at the glowing box.
Scott: My brain is not programmed.
Rym: University of Queensland in Australia Plans to build a multi-billion dollar brain city.
Scott: now wait brain palace brain palace Oh my god.
Rym: dedicated to science and research and the death.
Scott: for well Obviously I should live there because I am the most dangerous.
Rym: I Have an MD.
Rym: I may or may not be a doctor.
Rym: The city hoping to hold at least 10,000 people is looking to attract 4,500 of the brightest scientists from around the world to live and work there.
Scott: Well, I'm brightest scientist number 4,500 and one so I should definitely be living there.
Rym: Well, no, that means you're not going to be living there because there are 4,500 people better than.
Rym: but they said 10,000 people are gonna Live there total.
Rym: Yes 4,500 scientists and I imagine the rest are going to be and ran style grunt laborers.
Scott: But I'm the most dangerous a nerd grunt labor.
Scott: I Don't think you have a gun that is both a machine gun and a hook shot.
Rym: I have a feeling that you're not going to be shrugging.
Rym: you're going to be shrugged upon if you move there.
Rym: Now.
Rym: now basically, you know reading this article and reading all the articles What I envision is kind of like what we talked about in Friday night party line.
Rym: They're making a giant monastery.
Rym: It's kind of like in Civ 4 where I build a city.
Scott: Was it really gonna be like cut off though?
Scott: I mean, it's just gonna be a city like any other.
Scott: leave visitors.
Rym: Well, it's in Australia.
Scott: Oh and the outback are like next to Sydney.
Rym: It's west of Brisbane in Queensland.
Scott: Isn't it Brisbane?
Rym: I Don't know.
Rym: alrighty, honestly I Realized kind of recently that I know a lot about New Zealand and almost nothing about Australia.
Scott: I know.
Scott: the thing is I know Like.
Scott: I can draw like a weak map of Oceania in little like a pencil like, you know That's mostly limited by my drawing skills.
Scott: But if you ask me where the city's go on that map I can tell you.
Scott: I could tell you maybe where Sydney is on the East Coast, right?
Rym: Maybe breathing a little selfish is on the other side.
Rym: I'm gonna keep saying Brisbane unless someone died.
Scott: I have no freaking clue.
Rym: I don't think it's Brisbane because Brisbane give me a map of Albion.
Scott: I can put London on there and I can put.
Scott: I can sort of tell you where Scotland is, but that's about it Really?
Scott: I don't know where the different parts.
Rym: It's not that hard.
Scott: I don't know which part is Wales.
Rym: Wales is kind of in the middle.
Rym: Scotland's on top because the.
Rym: I know.
Scott: Scotland's on top because the Romans.
Rym: the whole Top not just like a point on the top.
Rym: The whole top is Scotland.
Rym: Okay, because the Romans could never conquer it and as well.
Rym: now I'm not gonna make fun of the Scottish because we met that cool Scottish dude, it's at Pax.
Rym: Yeah, I was gonna make a joke about huh?
Rym: I have this really about ducks.
Rym: No, I don't know how I could get there.
Rym: But Brisbane is spelled Brisbane Bane of brises.
Rym: I was gonna make a joke about Jews, but I said weak-ass Joe it is I couldn't quite get there.
Rym: Don't even bother but I had it anyway.
Rym: I'm real excited about the idea of this.
Rym: I like the idea of taking the sieve for thing.
Rym: if I got I build my city over in the corner and I name it Brain palace and I set it up with all scientists.
Scott: Oh, I gotta do that.
Rym: I have that currently because I read this news earlier today.
Rym: I played sieve for on the train right next to new Rome is brain palace.
Rym: Oh sweet.
Scott: Now sadly if you go to the article You should put it right next to Tokyo 3.
Rym: if you go to the article slash dot links to.
Rym: if the headline is Brisbane to build Center to attract 4,500 lead scientists the picture is Just like a horse in the wilderness by himself And the article Does not really have the details.
Rym: I was looking for that's.
Scott: that's a. that's a most dangerous horse.
Rym: I'm not.
Rym: I just Go to.
Rym: don't read the article But think about what I said and how exciting this is and then click on this link and just without reading any words Look at the article and see what kind of dissonance might appear in your brain.
Scott: Are you sure this is real?
Scott: And not like that other story from the Australian newspaper about like the zombie dogs.
Scott: That wasn't true.
Rym: Um, I point out that the Australian newspaper got that from a Russian newspaper that has run that story like five times.
Rym: That zombie dog story has been making the round since like the 80s With the same picture of the dog - it's the most dangerous dog.
Rym: So I don't have much more to say about this because if I if I talk about I feel like I should do a Monday show About brain palace because I like the idea.
Rym: I don't know if Australia is the place but maybe it is.
Rym: I'll tell you what Brisbane?
Rym: if you want me there I'll come.
Rym: if you'll let me live there for free and pursue my science on the condition that you get better internets.
Rym: I Imagine if they're building a town with 4,500 lead scientists, there's going to be a better internet.
Scott: most dangerous internet.
Scott: I'm done with the most dangerous things of the day.
Rym: I got a real kick out of this and I thought oh I should do something clever and put something backwards in the show.
Rym: But now I decided not to.
Rym: maybe I'll put the whole show up backwards.
Scott: We could probably just run a filter reverse the whole show and put it up that you know Two separate episodes that are the same thing, but one's backwards.
Rym: Well, I could put it in the experimental feed, but I don't know if anyone would listen to it.
Rym: Maybe I give you a free t-shirt.
Scott: Then we just do like, you know some sort of Beatles kind of thing or you say something.
Rym: Yep, I used to know how to say my name backwards.
Rym: I practiced that a lot when I was a kid.
Scott: What's wrong with you?
Rym: This is before the internet.
Rym: remember the show We just did about.
Rym: before you had internet.
Rym: you would do things on a computer that were inconceivable.
Rym: today I had.
Rym: I got some audio software.
Rym: So I record stuff and I'd play it backwards and then I'd memorize saying it backwards and then I'd say it backwards Recorded.
Rym: flip that and listen to it played right from the backwards.
Rym: play College humor did that times a million.
Rym: and I?
Rym: Have never been more amused by watching someone sing the star-spangled back banner while un-eating marshmallows.
Scott: See, I've done that.
Scott: the bad scene the star-spangled back The backwards star-spangled banner for The reverse national anthem.
Scott: I have heard that one before in fact I think there was a YouTube of the entire thing going down.
Scott: But they do some other reverse things in this video like the Rubik's Cube and whatnot.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: It's it's pretty quality But just the un-eating that was that really did it for me.
Rym: Yeah, plus it's just.
Rym: it's a clever video.
Rym: I really like it and you know what I'm gonna spoil it for you.
Rym: It's backwards Gasp, gasp.
Scott: All right, so check this out ready.
Rym: I'm checkin in Germany.
Rym: They got some traffic cameras, right and is this an archive of funny things caught on camera?
Scott: No, okay, and There's a guy he's been repeatedly caught speeding On roads in Bavaria, right repeatedly.
Scott: He's driving some Audi and he is driving fast Right, and he should probably get a ticket and you know, we always complain about cameras, you know, giving people tickets and whatnot Sort of for revenue and yeah,
Rym: but I've no I'll just real quick before anyone gets on our cases.
Rym: I have no problem with speed cameras.
Rym: I have a problem with artificially deflated speed limits.
Scott: Yes Anyway, so this dude first of all, I I don't know if I don't know if it's legal to drive a British car in Germany Probably but he's driving a British car in Germany.
Scott: So as his British plates, right and it has the steering wheel on The right-hand side of the car and the passenger seat is on the left-hand side All right, the German speed cameras only get your face if you're on Left side of the car.
Scott: Oh, so that's the first thing here is you have a guy who's speeding and getting away with it because they can't go after him unless they see who's driving even though They have the plates and they can look that shit up brilliant.
Scott: If they don't know who's driving they could have been someone else driving and they can't give him the ticket.
Scott: They got a fig, you know, so they can't, you know, actually mail him anything.
Scott: So there you go.
Scott: That's that's the beginning Part of it.
Rym: is this really involve the police doing something clever to get the dude?
Scott: No, it involves the dude doing something even more clever.
Rym: dummy picture of the Prime Minister.
Rym: He basically I would have put a picture of the Prime Minister in the passenger seat.
Scott: It looks like he has a replica or perhaps an original of what looks to be animal the Muppet.
Rym: And he put animal.
Scott: He puts animal in the passenger seat which would be the driver's seat in a German car or a US car.
Scott: So all you see is this picture of this Audi with British plates and an animal is driving.
Scott: I guess he drives real fast cuz he's an animal.
Rym: I would have gone one step further and put a fake steering wheel in and everything.
Scott: Yeah It looks like he just sort of when he knows.
Scott: it seems like he knows who the camera is cuz he because they see they Multiple pictures.
Scott: so he must know that this is what's going on.
Rym: Well, you know, it's kind of like when I was a kid.
Rym: I go to Cedar Point and I'm you know Every time there's a roller coaster.
Rym: There's always the down at the bottom.
Rym: You can see the picture of you and your friends screaming or getting you know Whatever and they always put it at some spot along the way when I was really young.
Rym: My dad just took me aside and he said alright son I want you to memorize where all the cameras are and I said why.
Rym: dad and he said watch and learn and that was when he brought out the laminated newspaper.
Scott: See I usually don't like to read the article, you know when I know we do a news or thing today But I got to read at least this little bit ready all right.
Scott: Now police have released one of the photographs in the hope so and recognize the furry speed demon.
Scott: a German police source said The number plate is not enough.
Scott: We need a clear evidence of who is driving the vehicle - but because this is a British vehicle We can never get a decent picture.
Scott: The driver has obviously worked this out because he has placed a large puppet in the passenger seat.
Scott: This may be an example of the famous British sense of humor, but it is still dangerous driving (Laughter).
Rym: This guy gets props.
Scott: We suspect he positions the toy deliberately before accelerating past the camera.
Rym: Thank you Rick Romero.
Rym: So Today was a breath of fresh air the likes of which I have not had in a very long time.
Rym: You see I was able to SSH to my computer by not typing an IP address that I have to guess But by typing tochiro.house.
Rym: Oh my gosh We have a freaking DNS server again.
Rym: Thank the gods.
Scott: It's so because the other one died and then my parents.
Scott: so I bought them a laptop.
Scott: So I took their old desktop, but it was eating hard drives.
Scott: But I got a hard drive that works in it, and it's booted up and seems to be good.
Scott: And we have DNS.
Scott: It's it's glorious.
Scott: I think I can print without having to like figure out the IP address of the Mac every single time I want to.
Rym: I'd always forget the whatever command It was to print because we have the printer set up in a way that I don't use anywhere outside of this house.
Scott: I've got it now so you can set it up real easy.
Rym: Oh good, because I I would always set it up and then like a month later I'd have to print something but the IP address had changed And I would always forget what I did and I couldn't print and then I just give up.
Rym: I'd like go down to the Mac and print from there.
Scott: I see most people don't realize this right most people.
Scott: you have a home network and your computers get IP addresses from the router.
Scott: Right if you have more than one and so every computer has some IP address They're all different and you might have a different one today and a different one tomorrow.
Scott: But you don't care right any networking stuff.
Scott: you do it within the house.
Scott: you might do some windows file sharing You might do some iTunes music sharing But that stuff doesn't require that you actually know the IP of the other computer on the network because it just sort of uses Broadcast and Bonjour and things like that that allow computers to just discover any other computer on the network regardless of IP address.
Scott: But if you want to do something like you know have a real file server or Share a printer or you know without Samba you know or something like that you need to know or SSH Or play some games.
Scott: you got to know the IP address of the other machines on your local network.
Rym: now the thing is I Realized that a lot of people don't bother with this sort of thing and most people don't have to bother with this.
Rym: But I remember that thread where you know people are saying What do you name your computers?
Rym: and more than one person said why would I name my computer something?
Rym: It's Kate's computer.
Rym: It's Adams laptop.
Rym: That's it.
Rym: That's all we do.
Scott: What if I'm using you know what if there's ten computers in my house, and I want to connect from the computer I'm using to Scott's computer?
Scott: I don't want to have to go and do an end map.
Scott: figure out that Scott's computer Which has an IP address of 101 at this moment in time and then ping 192 168 1 1 0 1.
Scott: I want to just say Connect to Scott's computer and type in Scott's Computer and have it connect.
Scott: and that is what having a DNS server in your house allows you to do.
Rym: But when we first moved into this house it actually We had a little trouble from the start because this house was lived in by nuns before us.
Scott: None before no nuns and their nunnery made DNS not work.
Rym: Well, no what their nunnery did was the house was set up for people who are not geeks like us as in.
Rym: they must have TV and you know the landlord probably too because normal people would live here.
Rym: So cable comes into the side of the house And then it splits into the two apartments and then in our house it splits into like four jacks all over the place and When he had the cable guy first come out he was doing tone tests And he basically told us that the wiring inside of our house the coax cables are barely wires.
Rym: Wow like the amount like the amount of signal loss was staggering is what he said.
Rym: So we had a little bit of trouble getting internet even when we first moved in.
Rym: and then I remember later We even had a problem where the wire outside the house stopped working and they replaced the entire local loop outside from the from the Pole outside all the way to our house to the switch box.
Scott: and then it still didn't work.
Scott: and eventually the answer was our cable Modem was broken.
Rym: well the answer was our cable modem was weak.
Rym: our cable was also weak between the two disaster Our cable is still weak.
Rym: the cable modem now is strong.
Scott: Yes Yes, everything is okay now.
Rym: Yeah, but you know being geeks We did.
Rym: we couldn't wire the house properly because we don't own this house We rent it.
Rym: so I couldn't do what I want to do which was install actual nice jacks into the walls.
Scott: Yeah, that look all fancy and not have wires running around on the floor, but the wires in the walls where they belong.
Rym: I remember I thought about to have some sort of patch panel in the basement.
Rym: So I remember we first moved in.
Rym: I popped off the coax jack to see what was in the wall And I saw things I didn't want to see and I just put that jack back on and decided that nothing was ever going Through those walls.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: I wouldn't have even been able to get a snake through there.
Scott: Well not even like.
Rym: Well, I guess I could have put a garter snake in the wall.
Scott: Oh, what if you tied some cat5 to its tail and it would it would have you know made its way where it's got to go.
Rym: Yeah, so now I'm gonna have cat5 outside Hey Good or maybe into the apartment downstairs Oh, it's good to.
Rym: maybe maybe into the bathroom through the toilet down into the sewer.
Scott: You know, maybe if we attach some cat5 to some migratory birds We could.
Scott: it'd be real cheap to get some connections down to Florida perhaps Australia where they have slow internets.
Rym: So we you know, basically what we did.
Scott: I'm sorry migratory is.
Rym: I believe it's migratory.
Rym: Oh Using coconut, okay.
Rym: So I like how I didn't even make a relevant Monty Python quote.
Rym: I did whatever high school kid does was someone says something that could be a Monty Python joke.
Rym: They make an unrelated Monty Python quote simply to note that they could have made a Monty Python quote.
Rym: Anyway, me also lame people in college continue to do that.
Rym: That's how you tell lame people in college.
Rym: but what we did?
Rym: As we had the guy install the cable modem downstairs because he wouldn't do it anywhere else He said the signal was all bad and then he left.
Rym: and then we took it upstairs To my room and we realized that that wasn't gonna work.
Rym: So we actually pulled cable across Into the hallway between the two bedrooms, but the cable modem there bought a switch put the switch.
Rym: there bought a router.
Scott: We put the switch way later.
Rym: Actually, I think well we had the for using.
Scott: Yeah, we're using the four port switch right and then we got the.
Scott: so it's six port later seven.
Rym: Yeah, but we had the router.
Scott: we put it there, you know But I think it's a but one of them has to be used for the uplink.
Rym: so we ran a cable to school.
Rym: we ran a cable to Scott's room and a cable to my room and That was it.
Rym: and that did not serve our purposes.
Rym: We're geeks.
Rym: We have a lot more than two computers.
Scott: We got computers downstairs.
Scott: You got wireless computers all over the place, but you know, we had the wireless going on.
Rym: Yeah, so we had a computer connected downstairs and we wanted to watch.
Rym: It was that old Ubuntu computer that didn't even work.
Scott: it worked for a while barely.
Scott: It just didn't serve the TV purposes that well because it was hard to.
Scott: you know Cuz the desktop interface is not so good as a TV.
Rym: Wow.
Rym: Yeah, that was back before I bought the Mac.
Scott: Yeah, we were emulating on the TV and such, you know It's only because we got rid of that that we got to do virtual castle.
Rym: But the tea it didn't have internet downstairs and we couldn't.
Rym: we were trying to figure out what to do.
Rym: I couldn't run a cable properly because I couldn't do it through the wall, you know rental house.
Rym: So we thought we could buy a wireless card for downstairs.
Rym: Wireless cards were way more money than we were willing to spend back then.
Rym: Oh, yeah, and also not fast enough for streaming real-time, you know movies and such.
Scott: also PCI wireless cards You know, they're not really, you know, they're not that compatible even with you know, Windows computers.
Scott: They're not trustworthy I don't.
Scott: I don't like them at all.
Rym: Yeah And we thought about buying like a wireless bridge and those are even more Screw that shit and then I realized kind of randomly that there's a hole in The edge of like the stairway that can go down into the storage closet downstairs.
Rym: So basically by hooker crook, I ran a network cable.
Rym: It goes across the floor at only two points.
Rym: So we have to have this never cable like taped to the floor Across the hallway between the bedrooms and then it goes under the carpet all the way across to this hole Where it goes into a closet.
Rym: I have a service loop in there.
Rym: Then it goes across the hallway downstairs again tape and then I run it like behind and under the carpet again to the TV.
Scott: So finally enough we never trip over that one.
Scott: We only trip over the one in my room.
Rym: Yeah, well because the one in your room is not which is the closest to the cable.
Rym: Yeah, but really, you know being geeks this wasn't enough because the router kind of sucks.
Rym: We had that four port switch, but that also wasn't enough.
Rym: So we bought an eight port switch.
Rym: We plug that.
Rym: basically our network infrastructure is thus cable modem goes to router.
Rym: router.
Scott: It's a linksys router, you know with the wireless and whatnot.
Rym: router has one cable in it Which goes to eight port switch.
Rym: two ports go to Scott's room.
Rym: three ports go to my room.
Scott: all three go to your room.
Scott: What are you doing?
Rym: IP phone?
Rym: All of these are in use and in fact It's a problem because I have a fourth computer in my room and know where to plug it in.
Rym: It's using the wireless.
Scott: Wireless is fine.
Scott: Yeah, actually use my laptop on a wire in my room.
Scott: I just use the.
Rym: I do because I do a lot of large file transfers.
Rym: Yeah, I guess yeah, and then we have one cable going downstairs But then terminated on that cable is the old four port switch because the Roku and the computer are plugged into that.
Scott: Yeah, the Wii uses the wireless but the we could use the wired if I wanted to do.
Rym: the only reason I haven't hooked it Up to the wired is that we need to buy that adapt.
Rym: No, no, no, but we internet sucks and I don't need to lower the latency because there's nothing.
Scott: this is no use at all Other than downloading virtual console games, but I'm never in a hurry.
Rym: So it doesn't matter.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, it's good Yeah, but you know basically the trick to having a geek house is to not use any of the functionality of your linksys router.
Scott: Well, I mean the thing is a linksys router, you know, what it does is enough for most people, right?
Scott: But the problem with it is is that it's not a hundred percent flexible, right?
Scott: For example, if you know a linksys router is really just a Linux computer that has a wireless You know antenna in it and you know a bunch of network cards.
Scott: it's really all it is is a really, you know, weak computer that has these connections on it and You could do everything it does with an actual computer and it would be faster and you could have a lot more flexibility.
Scott: but you have to have a whole computer as opposed to a tiny little cheap box.
Scott: and Some of the things that the router does are you know?
Scott: Actually, what it does is fine for most people for super super nerds even more nerdier than us nothing It does is good enough and yeah, you can't even use it.
Rym: sadly even the switch we have is not really I mean one.
Rym: it's not giggy which isn't a big deal for the internet because I don't need my giggy going to my cable modem, but File transfers in the house could be faster because every modern computer has giggy.
Rym: In fact, my computer has two just on the motherboard.
Rym: Yeah, most computers do most motherboards do so.
Scott: so what we do in the house is we we don't do we don't take all the Abilities that we don't all take all the work away from the router.
Scott: We let the router still do the NAT right the the network address translation Because that's sort of a pain and the router does it nicely and it just works so it can keep going.
Scott: We let it do the wireless.
Scott: We don't let it do anything else.
Scott: We don't let it do DHCP and we don't let it do DNS because it can't do DNS anyway.
Scott: We actually set up another computer to do DHCP and DNS and the benefit of that is that because we have a computer that does DHCP Every machine on the network will always get the same IP address.
Scott: So if I was just using the router and I connect my start my computer Maybe now that means it gets IP address 101, but then I restart it now.
Scott: It's got IP address 110.
Scott: Oh, it just the router just picks up at random in whatever range you set.
Scott: if I have a DHCP Server I can say this MAC address is this IP address.
Rym: It is a Monday show.
Scott: I don't know if we need to explain what DHCP and DNS do no, but the point is is that the benefit is You don't you know have to freaking guess all the time what freaking IP addresses all the computers are.
Rym: you just know It's all good.
Rym: but the other problem we're running into is that most people seem like people know switches are better, but they don't really know why.
Rym: and The Linksys switch we have has eight ports but it only has like a 200 megabit backplane.
Rym: meaning if I'm using my full connection to like the server and Scott is using his full connection to like the Mac downstairs We're already maxing out the switch and we're gonna start losing like things are gonna slow down for everyone.
Rym: and it's not that great because We actually have a lot of data going on
Scott: Even though even though the network is you know 100 megabit per second or you know It's it's 100 as opposed to you know gig you can't actually get the full 100 on every port at the same time.
Scott: You can only get it on like two or three of the ports at the same time.
Rym: But I want to talk about the fantasy because the only reason we haven't made the net basically the network has been this kind of cobbled together thing in this house mostly because we don't own the house and Of course lately.
Rym: I've been putting off way too many things until I own a house.
Rym: It's gotten to the point where I look at my closet and it's a mess and I think I can fix that by moving.
Scott: Yeah, that's a bad situation.
Rym: Yeah, I look at the pile of Leases and over until like the spring Like like more and more like I don't have enough shelves for all.
Rym: my books need to look over to like the wine fridge And next to the wine fridge are like 20 books just in a pile and there's another pile of growing next to it.
Rym: And I keep thinking yeah.
Rym: Well, I'll put them on the shelf in the house when I buy it.
Rym: But we've both been doing that.
Rym: about the network, I mean Ideally, I want a real router.
Scott: Yeah, not some little links.
Scott: this guy like a real one.
Scott: you rack mounted router with an expensive interface car.
Rym: I want because my idea is that I want to actually set up proper networking is in.
Rym: I want to have the kind of External facing network because the plan is I want to put a computer there and use one of those Dynamic DNS things to let our cable modem have a static name out.
Scott: You actually have a DMZ.
Scott: I mean the router we have can do DMZ but not really it's pretty weak.
Scott: Actually have a DMZ or maybe you can run some NS servers or whatnot.
Rym: Yeah Well, I want to do that and I also just want to have this external facing server for any time.
Rym: I just need to like give someone a big file.
Rym: I can say yeah FTP to here just throw up a dumb.
Scott: Also, you should pay the extra money to get a static IP for the ISP.
Rym: Yeah I mean eventually we'll get files somewhere and then I'll just like I'm waiting for that day.
Scott: Maybe we should.
Scott: only you should tell the real estate lady only houses with five hooks.
Rym: But more importantly I want a real switch because I want to have a fully segregated separate internal network so I can have a really insecure everything's open internal network for like Landgaming and file-sharing and all that stuff.
Rym: But yet I want to have this kind of protected zone that like say people who come over and have their wireless laptop They can get on the internet, but they can't access any of our internal network and bring their windows worms with them.
Scott: No, that's true.
Rym: That's true and all that sort of stuff and I want to have kind of the File transfer gigabit separate vlan so that all the internal stuff has its own network mostly so I can have the full speed.
Rym: They're completely independent of the outside speed and the outside network.
Scott: And yeah that way when we're doing like, you know watch a video on this computer, but the videos on the other computer You know it actually you don't have to worry about it slow.
Scott: I mean right now it's actually pretty fast, but that's because no one else is doing anything at the same time.
Rym: Yeah I also really want to set up VPN access to our network from the outside in a legitimate and non hackish non shady website way.
Scott: Yeah, that would be actually like.
Scott: the biggest thing that would you know actually I would use all the time would be you know Get to my home computer no matter where I am and without having to do some sort of shady crap.
Scott: That's untrustworthy Because you know, I'm at work.
Scott: I want to listen to some music.
Scott: It's on my hard drive.
Scott: at home I got to use like simplify media or something like that and it's it's okay, but it's not.
Scott: it's not great.
Scott: You know if I could actually connect to my network at home for real, but other people couldn't.
Scott: oh, that'd be sweet.
Rym: Yeah, I also kind of want to have if I get a good access point.
Rym: I want to have two wireless networks.
Rym: I want to have the kind of our private one like the front row crew.
Rym: actually all of us We use the same SS ID and the same everything so anyone visits anyone's house We all are just online automatically because everyone has laptops.
Rym: But I like the idea of having the kind of private wireless that's super secure You know WPA and then be completely open.
Rym: open public wireless that anyone on the street can connect to.
Rym: because one if People on the street can connect they can get online and check their email And I can snoop and mess with them if I want to.
Rym: and all that.
Scott: We should set up a thing that just automatically like, you know, it takes all traffic on the you know That network and then friggin run strings on it stars all the good stuff.
Rym: and more importantly though I just I like the idea of providing that service because you know how many times you're out there somewhere and Man, if only I could get online.
Rym: Oh snap wireless network and I kind of want to provide that to people but I don't do that now Because I don't trust people.
Rym: I want to have an untrusted Wireless that I can just pipe to the internet and block from everything else.
Scott: Mm-hmm We could also have the untrusted week, you know, we could do evil stuff like with that untrusted wireless Just like no matter what URL they go to it goes to for occur.com.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, we could also remember though saying this I will.
Rym: I'm not saying this as an advocation and I'm not saying that we are going to do this but Supposing that you have an unsecured wireless access point in your house.
Rym: You have basically provided yourself with undeniable plausible deniability.
Scott: Also, it's a nice honey pot.
Rym: Yes, and honey pots are fun.
Scott: Maybe I'd run an actual honey pot.
Rym: Yeah, we could.
Rym: I kind of like that old XK CD where he has all those VMS and he collects worms.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know.
Rym: This is kind of a crowd people show and I ran out of steam.
Scott: Yeah, I don't think there's much more to say but mostly because someone today was like, why do you need DNS in your house?
Scott: it's well.
Scott: the two reasons are as we said now we can actually connect to computers in our house by typing in the name and Because you know, most people just use their ISPs DNS server, which is pretty fast.
Scott: It's a tiny bit faster if your local DNS, you know, you have a local DNS cache.
Rym: Well, it's also a lot better because our local DNS server.
Rym: I got to set it up more.
Rym: I mean Scott did the basic setup But when we set it up originally what I did is I used the three DNS servers that I know our ISP has.
Rym: I also added my favorite secret DNS server from our IT that I still use to this day when I need a quick DNS And a couple other DNS servers that I trust out on the internet.
Scott: I think it's only two or three in there now.
Rym: yeah, we used to have a whole bunch and It basically provides because a lot of times people have a problem where their ISP will be fine.
Rym: But the ISP is DNS stop working.
Scott: Mmm, very true.
Rym: Very true I also have to set up the NTP, which I actually know a lot about now And I'm gonna set up like the most.
Rym: I can basically give us the same NTP.
Scott: all I want to be able to do is have my computer get the correct time.
Rym: I can do that.
Scott: It shall be done without having to ask Microsoft or the government for it.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Well, we're going to ask the government?
Scott: Well, yeah, but I mean, I don't want my desktop to ask the government I just want the server to ask the government every other as this.
Rym: there are two ways to go about this.
Rym: I can either Ask the government and it's not illegal to in fact They encourage people to but at the same time it is taking advantage of a public boon when I don't have to take advantage Of it.
Rym: I can give us fucking accurate time Mm-hmm and redistribute it inside our own internal network or we can just use the NTP pool, which is fine is okay It's good enough.
Rym: We will get an order of magnitude better time But yeah an order of magnitude better.
Scott: So instead of being accurate to the thousandth of a second will be accurate to the billionth of a second.
Rym: Well, no, we won't will be accurate.
Rym: Well, if it remember there's the Accuracy and the precision we will have a percent will have a precision that is pretty good.
Rym: You know 20 to 40 milliseconds, but we'll have an accuracy to within like a thousand ten thousandth of a second most likely.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Hey, whatever.
Rym: We're done.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our crapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in time.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.