Scott: It's Wednesday January 30th.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Scott: I'm Rym, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Scott: Speculation on why the anime industry is doing poorly.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Well we both got home late today, so I'm sure this is gonna be a fantastic show.
Rym: oh The cowboy hat it is on my head cowboy hat.
Rym: you say yeah Perhaps you were logged into a server and doing something you maybe should have thought a second about.
Scott: no actually It was like.
Scott: I think I'm like the 18th of January like I fixed a bug, but I didn't actually fix it.
Scott: I made a typo and I caused something to break.
Scott: and then you know of course we find out about this right We don't discover it until today.
Scott: first of all right, and we don't discover it until five minutes before I'm gonna leave.
Scott: So you know normally I'm like up screw you times up and going home right, but you know I broke it.
Scott: I got to fix it, and it was you know there's the thing processes at the end of the month.
Scott: So of course the end of the month is tomorrow.
Scott: So So I said okay, I screwed up I'll fix it.
Scott: so I stayed there and fixed it which meant you know I stayed at work an extra 30 minutes to fix it.
Scott: Cuz you know I knew how to fix it.
Scott: I and we had problems with this in the past.
Scott: I had scripts to repair it and such you know, but I had to do some things.
Scott: You know it took a half hour which of course means I get home like an hour later than I usually do so.
Rym: See that's a different brand of a cowboy hat.
Rym: usually when I have put on my cowboy hat it is Just type something.
Rym: it's like oh, I see your problem I know how to fix it.
Rym: and I type something in some Unix server Linux server And I hit enter and it's not until after I hit enter that my brain says alright.
Scott: You just typed RMRF slash.
Rym: good job It's more like.
Rym: my brain says alright.
Rym: You just type that and now it's too late to undo it.
Rym: What did that do and what server were you SSH into?
Scott: You know if it caused a problem you'll find out soon enough, and if it didn't cause a problem well Then everything's Jim Dandy.
Rym: yes, everything's Jim Dandy fine until I get arrested.
Rym: oh Yeah, oh well anyway We had there's obvious news to talk about in the anime world, but for obvious reasons We're gonna kind of hold off on that until the main bid.
Rym: so the Scott What do you have in the anime news world since since night?
Rym: that does not relate to perhaps the Elephant sitting in the room.
Scott: well my news is gonna be that elephant, so you sort of stole my thunder.
Scott: I don't know what I'm gonna do for a news which means back to my policy.
Scott: It's time for geek bite.
Scott: see I said I said the right one.
Rym: you did.
Scott: I thought I was gonna say geek back by accident, but now are you gonna geek bite?
Rym: What have you watched that?
Scott: I haven't.
Scott: I didn't watch anything except Galaxy Express TV show, but I got this manga here.
Scott: It's the goo and saga manga volume one the seven magi from vertical.
Scott: You know it's from vertical.
Scott: It can't be bad, right?
Rym: Well is that still true?
Scott: well?
Scott: Let me let me give you a little a little backstory about this goo and saga.
Scott: real quick right the goo and saga is fucking Famous.
Scott: like I didn't know shit about it, but if you would have said goo and saga to me I would have said I heard of that, but I don't know anything about it now.
Scott: I know a little bit more about it, right?
Scott: Apparently it is a series of fantasy novels by a guy named karu kurimoto, right It's been in continuous publication since 1979.
Scott: He planned when he started to make a hundred volumes so far.
Scott: He's made a hundred and eighteen volumes.
Scott: It's it's like think like Lord of the Rings of Japan.
Scott: That's the kind of fantasy We're talking here right and the basic story is there's a dude He's got a leopard head and like a human humanoid body, and he's a badass.
Scott: fantasy occurs You know if you like berserk.
Rym: if you I was about to ask is it like yes Keflon a style of fantasy the lotus war style of fantasy or the bastard?
Scott: It's.
Scott: it's somewhere between.
Scott: you know berserk It's.
Scott: it's the storyline.
Scott: stylings are sort of more like berserk But the thematic things are more Lord of the Rings ish.
Scott: You know in fact the berserk creator according to Wikipedia said that Gooben saga was a large influence on him.
Scott: right so as a hundred and eight a series of 118 novels and so for vertical is actually publishing the novels in English as well so far.
Scott: They've put out four.
Scott: He got a hundred and fourteen to go Maybe and of course in Japan the guy's always writing more.
Scott: You know cuz he's a machine.
Rym: you know this is one of those times where the typical policy of I'll just wait for a box Probably.
Scott: Yeah, I think I'm gonna try to read the novels.
Scott: We'll see if they're any good because this manga all right.
Scott: I read this manga not knowing anything about the goon saga except leopard head guy right and The thing is this is a pretty good.
Scott: You know fantasy story.
Scott: There's some weird stuff going on.
Scott: the leopard guy comes in and it see you know it seems like you don't know enough About really the backstory which I found out later.
Scott: Oh cuz this totally starts somewhere in the middle of the goon saga even though It's volume one of the manga.
Scott: the manga here is not actually just a manga version of the novels.
Scott: It's actually like a goon saga story by the guy who writes the goon saga.
Scott: It's just in manga form.
Scott: so it's like if you don't if you're not already familiar with the goon saga a lot of things I guess they it's assumed you would know while reading this.
Scott: you don't know.
Scott: so Yeah, I basically read it not knowing information that the book assumed I would know and I think there were some things missing because of that, but despite not knowing things It was pretty fucking entertaining.
Scott: I mean you got you got giant spiders.
Scott: You got you got guys chopping people's heads off.
Rym: you got got a leopard head.
Scott: Yeah, you got this like sage and his head falls off, and then he puts his head back on The leopard head.
Scott: the the leopard-headed guy is the main character and he's sort of like a Horatio kind of.
Scott: Wait a minute wait a minute now a little flog a kind of guy.
Rym: where he is he movie Horatio or books Horatio.
Scott: He's.
Scott: he's kind of like.
Scott: he's always smart He knows what's going on, and he's super badass all at the same time, but still there'll be times where he's like Kind of like.
Rym: oh I wasn't quite sure what.
Scott: Well you know it'll be like something like one frame.
Scott: He'll be like well I'm gonna kick ass.
Scott: the next frame he'd be like.
Rym: To me.
Rym: that that sound effect is what I heard in my head when Sean Connery playing in that manga samurai crusader.
Scott: yeah, because he's sort of like that kind of in a way.
Scott: and You know even though I didn't you know I went into this sort of not with the Appropriate background in the goon saga.
Scott: It was still good, and it shows that vertical is really smart, and they only publish the high-quality stuff.
Scott: But I would still probably recommend that You go and get some knowledge and experience with the goon saga before trying to read this manga.
Scott: That way you will get the maximum effect because I definitely felt like if I knew it was going on it would have been way More awesome than it was.
Rym: you got a level up.
Rym: you got to read some other things kind of build up to.
Scott: yeah I'm gonna go and get some of the the novels that vertical published and maybe read one or two.
Scott: of course I'll read those way later like after I read some other things that I was supposed to be reading like other fantasy novels.
Rym: Maybe what about that?
Rym: Anime that you said you were gonna watch.
Rym: I'm gonna do that.
Rym: We were thinking about reviewing this week instead of kind of copping out and talking about current events this week.
Scott: I'm doing it.
Rym: Oh, are you?
Rym: as I am it's already Wednesday night.
Scott: I meant you know for the next week, so you're gonna finish it this week.
Scott: No next week.
Rym: So you're gonna finish it next week.
Scott: I'll finish it soon enough Right.
Rym: so the only other news of interest other than the news is that?
Rym: Otakon.
Rym: well Otakon is run by Otakarp and Otakarp had a president.
Rym: the president was Sam Dang Who is known as generally being one of those kind of epic con staff at Otakon dudes mm-hmm?
Rym: Well he has stepped down for undisclosed personal reasons that apparently are not related to the con.
Scott: Yeah It doesn't sound like it sounds like this is legitimately someone's personal issues with their private life and not some sort of you know.
Scott: Oh, he says personal reasons, but really there was a drama with the con.
Scott: not it.
Scott: really I don't think there was any con drama.
Rym: yeah now luckily I didn't.
Rym: I expected after this announcement to see you know the usual shit store of internet people not understanding what they're talking about But people were kind of quiet about it.
Rym: But just to make sure all indications are that this will have no effect whatsoever on Otakon happening and/or being awesome Mm-hmm.
Rym: in fact a little bird who may or may not be a doctor who fan has Mentioned to me briefly.
Rym: I'm just gonna.
Rym: I'm gonna paraphrase the statement.
Rym: I can't say more right now, but this year's Otakon may quote blow Everything Otakon has ever done out of the water.
Scott: see I don't know what's gonna happen.
Scott: in August We're gonna go to Otakon which if it blows every previous Otakon out of the water Right we'll be.
Scott: we'll be like shot to hell.
Scott: right.
Scott: two weeks after that Seattle packs god a day just said they're increasing the total size of packs by what 20%?
Rym: Well, that's because we're going.
Rym: no they have to accommodate the GeekNights' fan base.
Scott: Let's see the convention.
Scott: This is from penny arcade.
Scott: their news today.
Scott: the Exhibition hall which is already massive is being doubled in size for 2008.
Scott: That's their you know.
Scott: It's not a dealer's room It's the.
Scott: it's sort of like the e3 equivalent where you know all the game companies set up their booths right.
Scott: so they're doubling that Space.
Scott: the overall convention space is being increased by 20% Of course and of course they have these epic pictures here, and oh my god.
Scott: Yeah, it's gonna be like Closest thing that we geeky atheists have to these spiritual journeys.
Scott: I really think so.
Scott: you know I feel like and I even if that's not true I think it's because penny arcade makes you believe it that it becomes true.
Rym: I have a feeling.
Rym: maybe I should just take off the two weeks between these two cons.
Scott: I wish I could.
Scott: I did get you know final permission day to take some unpaid days.
Rym: I actually discover that I have like five more vacation days than I thought I had.
Scott: yeah well I'm gonna get some unpaid days, so I think we're gonna do the trip We're gonna do all the three cons that we need days off for and I think I'm gonna go to Florida to to see my Grandma who haven't seen in like year
Rym: Because I'm thinking about just taking a few days off to chill like after Otakon or something.
Scott: well You could do whatever you want, but it's actually really convenient.
Scott: like the the Monday after Katsucon is President's Day Which we now get off, but we didn't get it off last year and the Monday after PAX I think is Labor Day, so we get that off because it's fucking Labor Day not bad Yeah, so saving days.
Rym: But yeah If if Otakon is epic and all indications are that Otakon is gonna do something epic this year And and I point out this is just observation that the last epic thing Otakon did was get freaking lark.
Rym: Let's come and do a full-on concert in the arena.
Scott: I'm telling you it's gonna be.
Scott: It's gonna be too mix.
Scott: It's good.
Scott: it's gonna be a Yumi Hamasaki and And Utada Hikaru duets with the Yoko Kanno on piano.
Rym: Yeah, something like that.
Scott: And they're gonna raise Tezuka from the dead and Miyazaki's coming.
Rym: Satoshi khan is going to Satoshi khan.
Scott: Satoshi khan Miyazaki and Tezuka risen from the zombie.
Scott: Tezuka are all gonna get up work together and create an anime live for us While at Otakon and we can watch it there, and that will be the only time it's shown.
Scott: And then it'll be destroyed and zombie Tezuka will go back to his grave.
Scott: it'll be animated in real time and oh, yeah, and since you know, Yoko Kanno and Yumi will be there.
Scott: They're gonna make all the music.
Scott: Oh, yeah, and once again Right, but yes, I think that that is pretty much the oh, you know It's awesome as awesome as Otakon is and as much as I'm sure they are gonna completely blow us away.
Scott: You know just looking at the history of things Pax has done and how it has consistently topped itself I really think that they are gonna need zombie Tezuka to beat Pax Or 2Mix.
Rym: I just don't not me so much anymore either But I got to admit in the 90s 2Mix was as far as I could tell the best band ever.
Scott: You were way into the 2Mix before like.
Scott: I didn't even find out about it till I got to RIT and I didn't you Know every song is the same.
Rym: So yeah, I didn't realize that right away.
Rym: Yeah But I remember like every year for a long time.
Rym: There was always the rumor that yeah, I heard Otakon's got 2Mix.
Rym: Yeah, I heard Otakon's got.
Rym: Otakon never had 2Mix.
Rym: What were you people thinking?
Scott: That Yoko Kanno once.
Rym: But yeah, Otakon's gonna be epic.
Rym: Pax is gonna be epic.
Rym: We're gonna be at both.
Rym: and don't forget KatsuKan August 2008 epic things of the day.
Rym: now I really like aside from 2Mix Japanese like historical kind of music like with the traditional old instruments, you know the drum that goes pong pong pong the guy that goes.
Rym: oh I can't do it.
Rym: I can't make those noises.
Rym: You know the nice little guitar with the little.
Scott: uh, it's not a guitar But it has that sort of weird shaped white plucking thing like a gigantic fan pick.
Scott: Yeah anyway I wish I knew what they were called so I wouldn't sound like a moron.
Rym: Yeah, but I really like that music.
Rym: in fact Band that I think Alex was listening to.
Rym: that was all something brothers.
Scott: Yeah Now we're huge morons Ready to prepare for your thing of the day.
Rym: I like that music a lot and someone sent this to me.
Rym: I thought it was Scott, but I guess it wasn't because he hadn't seen it until I showed it to him.
Rym: So whoever sent this to me Tell me who it was because I forgot and you're kind of cool for finding this.
Rym: the website is in Pockner ease, but it is Smoke on the water as done by a band playing these traditional Japanese instruments and it looks like this was a kind of big deal, you know classical concert and They just kind of randomly in the middle of the set just played smoke on the water instead of whatever they were gonna be playing because the audience says the reaction you would expect of Rabble rabble rabble.
Rym: Hee hee hee rabble rabble rabble rabble followed by cheering Doo doo doo doo doo.
Rym: Okay, so do you have a thing of the day?
Scott: Yes, I do.
Scott: Are you ready for this?
Scott: I don't know if you can handle this thing of the day.
Rym: I don't know if it can be to smoke on the water as done by.
Rym: He's banned on a website though.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: it's not as awesome as that because it's not really a cool thing.
Scott: It's just sort of a Wow Internet's kind of thing, right?
Scott: See, you know, they have those what the OS tons, right?
Rym: I know all about things.
Scott: time they create characters to represent operating systems, right and they've got what the Mecca Musa Mays.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: All right.
Scott: What else they have?
Scott: They have a whole bunch of things like that.
Scott: Anyway, anyway, the newest or like the most recently discovered by me of those things is here.
Scott: Are you ready?
Scott: Can you handle this?
Scott: Ah, we'll see It is headphone Musa.
Scott: may.
Scott: what we have here are basically incredibly fancy headphone sets from around the world such as the Sennheiser HD 4140 the Bose tri-port the technics RF 30 even the Eddie modics that are way more expensive than ours the Let's see the grotto RS 1, you
Rym: know, I'll say one thing.
Rym: just be related to that.
Rym: I don't care how much you are into audio how much you think it matters you.
Rym: there is no reason to ever spend more than About two hundred dollars on headphones.
Rym: That's true.
Scott: But the costs?
Scott: porta pro.
Scott: But yeah They've got a picture here of a girl for every set of headphones and all the girls are wearing the associated headphones So they're not like hanging on some guy's head.
Scott: Yeah Look over here.
Scott: Look at this, huh?
Rym: You know, it's kind of a logical extension.
Rym: I have a feeling that eventually there will be a ton for every possible device.
Rym: that I don't.
Scott: this isn't a time This is a Musa may get it right the same thing.
Scott: No, they're not.
Scott: I don't know what the difference is.
Rym: I'll say one thing they're all girls aren't they?
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Rym: Oh, huh?
Rym: Yeah see that they're all girls.
Scott: They're not really that perverted.
Rym: None of them are now all.
Scott: some of them are a little bit but which ones?
Rym: what have you been?
Scott: Looking at now some of these are Like this one.
Scott: that's where like the AKG k271 is a little.
Rym: well Well, that's understandable because those are some really really perverted headphones.
Scott: Let me tell ya The AKG k1 seems like the AKG ones are more perverted some of the others.
Scott: What's up with that?
Scott: Yeah, so Yeah, this just shows you how far those crazy Japanese people go.
Scott: plus you look at the quality of the art on this.
Scott: you know, it's not like the best art in the universe, but Someone with art skills made this.
Scott: I think I'd like to get them to the fucking design chip for us Instead of making useless headphone moose.
Rym: amaze, they're not useless.
Scott: Oh Hey, what's the use then?
Rym: I wasn't gonna back that statement up.
Scott: Oh, that's right.
Scott: Yeah, you get some of challenges you step down, right?
Rym: So, uh The news the big news.
Rym: I'm not gonna get into the details of it.
Rym: I'm sure if you care you read anime news network, and that's pretty much as much as you're gonna get about this.
Rym: But a TV is in some trouble.
Scott: Yeah, we can't exactly figure out what the real like exactly the full story of who what where when why how.
Rym: but We know who.
Scott: well, okay but the what where when why how.
Scott: but they have removed various titles that they previously licensed from their website.
Scott: and You know, I've I've been to the ATV website many times in the past, right?
Scott: And we're talking about a website here where these people had like three volumes of yotsuba on the shelves and not one mention of Yotsuba on their website.
Scott: right is a shittily Poorly updated website and not frequently updated.
Scott: so the fact that they're removing titles from their site show that there was a problem and people looked into it and Apparently yes, they've through some sort of business of dealings Who knows the exact detail say because the anime industry is a secret cabal in this country.
Scott: Yeah, we don't really understand exactly what happened had to do with some kind of Financer something company.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I don't understand it, but they lost or temporarily lost the Licenses to some things they licensed.
Rym: Yeah, now the
Scott: only one I care about which is project blue earth SOS and the other ones I don't give a shit
Rym: Don't know because there was like a letter that was leaked that was sent to retailers but then someone came forward and said that that wasn't true and it just I'm not gonna say the obvious that maybe if you weren't always so secretive about all this
Scott: People wouldn't be spreading bullshit rumors.
Scott: if he just came out and said what the deal was.
Scott: I think the other problem maybe your fans would feel closer to you and give you more money if you were more friendly with them Instead of distant and secretive.
Rym: I think the other problem is that they are kind of keeping silent and as a result All it really does is lend veracity to all these rumors.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much
Rym: but the official statement that they as as of recording of GeekNights that they have put forth is that quote We know There are a lot of rumors swirling about and the fans are looking for assurances that ADV will continue to distribute the anime series They know and love.
Rym: While we can't go into any detail at this time Please know that ADV is working through a few short-term challenges and fully intends.
Rym: I know the word intend To continue our releases.
Rym: we thank you for your patience.
Rym: And as far as I can see that is all they have said.
Scott: We're having technical difficulties, please stand by Now.
Rym: that is not really doesn't instill a lot of confidence.
Rym: It's not really what I want to talk about because what I've seen the internet saying about this is largely It's all the fans subs fault.
Rym: you damn pirates ruined it for all of us.
Rym: We told you this would happen and now it's happening.
Rym: You got to buy anime to support anime.
Rym: if you don't buy anime anime is gonna go away.
Rym: And I'm talking until I run out of air in my lungs.
Scott: Here's the thing I find really interesting.
Scott: right is that genie on went under?
Scott: right but other than that You know other than genie on going under We really you know, there's no information about sales figures for anime DVDs or anything like that, right?
Scott: That's we always complain.
Scott: There's no sales figures.
Scott: yet for the past many weeks People have been starting to discuss and rumble about anime DVD sales going down the shitter.
Scott: How did you know they were going down the shitter?
Scott: How did anyone know?
Rym: I think the only thing I have to go on is word of mouth and I know that I don't buy anime and I know That most of the people I know I buy anime just rarely.
Rym: Well, that's that.
Rym: but as a result What art?
Rym: look?
Rym: look at the shows I have bought in recent memory.
Rym: Let's see.
Rym: I bought utenna again I bought eska flown a again.
Rym: I bought Evangelion again.
Rym: I bought El Hazzard again.
Scott: Why don't you buy even Jillian for the first time?
Rym: Well, I bought it for the club.
Rym: Yeah, okay with the club's money.
Scott: Yeah, when'd you buy eska phone a for you?
Scott: besides the time you just bought HS.
Scott: You didn't buy it for you.
Scott: Someone else bought it.
Scott: It's not yours.
Scott: Where those VHS.
Rym: I sold them to Ken.
Scott: Oh, you sold them to him.
Rym: I thought he bought them in the first people like the second half of the series But I bought the first half.
Rym: Uh-huh, cuz no one wanted to like that.
Rym: No one liked that show until I showed it to him.
Rym: They're like that is big a big noses I don't get it.
Rym: And then I was like, well, you're gonna watch and you're gonna like it.
Rym: then.
Rym: Oh, yeah, I guess they liked it.
Rym: I Can't think of a new show.
Scott: I've bought New show new show about master Keaton on a discount rack.
Scott: Oh Boy bebop that new cheat box set.
Rym: Oh, yeah, cuz cowboy bebop just came out like what about project blue cheek usos.
Scott: Oh But wait, that's they just lost the license for that.
Rym: Who knows what's gonna happen Now what we want to talk about tonight?
Rym: and well, we'll see how far we go with this because this could be broken up in any number of topics, but It's either why I don't buy anime DVDs or more importantly why no one's buying anime DVDs now.
Rym: If this is wrong if this is a lie, and in fact anime DVD sales are just fine.
Rym: Well, I just asked for anyone in the industry to tell us we're wrong and I'll gladly say oh, yes it turns out that animated sales are fine, but Every indication I have is that your DVDs aren't selling.
Scott: well I think this episode is really gonna be gonna be two things, right?
Scott: It's gonna be well and one is the result of the other.
Scott: this episode is just gonna be us Speculating and you know what?
Scott: I found speculation speculation You know what?
Scott: I found out a lot of really entertaining shows on TV and radio are just people sitting around Speculating, you know, especially things like sports shows and and stuff like that, you know where there's no actual news.
Scott: You know people deliver the news.
Scott: then what do they do?
Scott: Well, well all they can do besides after they comment on the news is speculate and apparently the speculating is mad entertaining.
Scott: So get ready Speculation.
Rym: Well, I'm pretty sure that the anime industry is gonna be okay in the end because I can't believe bebop 2 is coming out tomorrow and So let's let's let's start talking about why we don't.
Scott: we already did a show on.
Scott: You know, this is not a charity whatever so I don't want to retread that ground but in the forum recently There was a discussion about this.
Rym: No region 1 anime DVD sales are in the crapper we think and The argument basically came down to half the people saying it's you damn dirty fansubber Pirates not watching the show on the fansub and not buying it.
Rym: That's why there's no money in anime anymore and the other half of people saying I don't care.
Scott: Well, here's the thing right with the fansub.
Scott: so let's let's get the fan.
Scott: we could do a whole show on the stupid fansub just to get her out of the Way, right?
Scott: I Think personally right everything that I've ever seen right?
Scott: I watch the fansubs right and I also buy the anime but rarely and you know what.
Scott: I'm gonna be perfectly honest.
Scott: I am not lying if you choose not to believe me.
Scott: Oh, well, right?
Scott: I don't have some sort of addiction to anime.
Scott: It's not like crack or heroin where I need anime, right if the show wasn't on fansub I just wouldn't hear about it and wouldn't watch it Like what?
Scott: what's one of the new shows?
Scott: we just watch spice and wolf spice and wolf, right?
Scott: Spice and wolf is an okay show.
Scott: It was a free fansub.
Scott: It was incredibly easy to get and incredibly convenient to watch.
Scott: it cost me nothing.
Scott: So I watched an episode or two, right if that show let's say fansubs didn't exist and spice and wolf was only on DVD And let's even give them the benefit of the doubt.
Scott: I heard about the show and I found out that I would like it.
Scott: right I probably wouldn't buy it.
Rym: You know what I do?
Rym: I Netflix it at best.
Scott: I'm only watching it because it's free.
Scott: I mean, I only I want to watch it, but I don't want to watch it so badly that I'm gonna pay money for it.
Scott: I only want to watch it a very tiny bit.
Scott: So because it's so easy for me to watch it My desire is very low, but the effort required to achieve that desire is also very low.
Scott: Therefore I watch it.
Scott: if the difficulty required to achieve the desire was higher such as I had to buy the DVD and My desire for it would not change, you know, so I then I just wouldn't watch it.
Scott: and I think Anime is very popular because it's so easy to watch with the fansubs.
Scott: They're all these people who are watching the fansubs.
Scott: They're watching it because they have a slight desire to watch anime.
Scott: not a huge desire Just a little bit of desire, but it's so easy.
Scott: So they watch it and if it wasn't easy, they just wouldn't watch.
Scott: They're not losing out on DVD.
Scott: the people who want to buy the DVDs are buying them.
Scott: the people who are the strong desire To watch these shows, you know, those people are buying DVDs.
Scott: Do you I really?
Scott: I've never met anyone who is like He he he.
Scott: I want to watch anime really badly.
Scott: I need it like crack.
Scott: I'm willing to go through any you know steps in the whole world to watch it.
Scott: I need it so badly that I would buy it on DVD, but I'm not gonna buy it on DVD.
Scott: I get it squashed the fansubs to save a bunch of money.
Scott: Hahaha I've never met anyone who's that has such a strong desire to watch pays for it.
Rym: Oh, there's a lot of kids who are super into like Naruto or whatever.
Rym: They they love that stuff and they they pirate it, but they don't have.
Rym: they don't have money Yeah, but they could probably convince their parents.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: See, I'm gonna go on a slightly different tack here because I mean it's one thing to say Yeah, well watch the fansub but I but I watch fansubs.
Rym: I don't watch a whole show on fansub it.
Rym: I'll watch a couple episodes and when I haven't watched the whole show on fansubs since like since Fullmetal Alchemist.
Scott: Yeah, Fullmetal Alchemist is the last show I watched entirely fansub.
Scott: then you know what?
Scott: If the DVDs had come out I'm gonna be honest if Fullmetal Alchemist was a good example because if the DVDs were coming out While the show is still really wicked popular right like at that time.
Scott: I probably would have bought them You know because the show was so popular right then and there right but the show You know after you finished watching it, there was no desire to ever watch it again.
Scott: It was a one-time show.
Rym: so That's the thing.
Rym: That's the tack.
Rym: I'm going out of here.
Rym: is that one?
Rym: All right I'll look at me about my the example of me as a person and why despite being a huge anime fan I never having lots of money and having plenty of money and Not pirating.
Rym: I still don't buy any anime.
Rym: Let's see first off.
Rym: The only reason I would ever buy a DVD and it's not just an image for anything.
Rym: Yeah Me too is if either one it's something that I expect to watch multiple times over the course of my life - that I want to lend to and show to other people Mm-hmm if one or both of those are not true.
Rym: I'm not gonna buy because there's no reason to now.
Rym: Alright, let's look at the legal ways.
Rym: I can watch my anime without buying it one Netflix.
Rym: now You say yeah, they get some money if the Netflix buys the DVDs and that is true But you don't get nearly as much money if Netflix buys four copies of your DVD Even if they're expensive rental copies and then every anime fan watches those DVDs versus if they buy them for $23 each.
Scott: Yeah, I mean there might be some.
Scott: I don't know exactly the finances of that situation But I can definitely pretty much guarantee that.
Scott: uh-huh, you know you need One rental is not as much money as a purchase at Best Buy.
Scott: There's no way.
Rym: Now the thing is Netflix serves the purpose of one thing and that is alright.
Rym: There's a show I want to watch.
Rym: it already aired on Japan.
Rym: It's done airing.
Rym: I heard it was good.
Rym: So now I want to watch it.
Rym: Well, I'm going to put it in my neck Netflix queue.
Rym: I don't care when I see it.
Rym: I'm gonna see it at some point and that's it.
Rym: Now if I want to see something more Urgently or I want to see while it's coming out the option would be obviously to watch it on TV.
Rym: now You might say yeah, but a lot of anime isn't on TV.
Rym: I get to that.
Rym: Let's say that all anime was on TV in the u.s.
Rym: It was just on TV at like eight o'clock with ads and that's how they made all their money.
Scott: or we lived in Japan.
Scott: How about we live in Japan?
Rym: Yeah, or I spoke Japanese.
Rym: so I get a satellite and I pay and I can just watch anime.
Rym: No That's ooh.
Rym: now if anime were on teeth like spice and wolf is a good example or fma or anything?
Scott: What about those animes that are on like over-the-air broadcast in like one part of Japan?
Rym: Well, I'm screwed there.
Rym: Yeah, but then alright those shows.
Scott: I have a house in Osaka with an internet connection and it goes to my house in New York.
Rym: Now most shows like that like most media in general most television shows unless there's something crazy.
Rym: Awesome I only want to watch it once.
Rym: then I want to watch it as it comes out.
Rym: So I'm gonna watch it on TV.
Rym: All right, I'll watch it on TV as it comes out, but I'm not an old man.
Rym: I Have a TiVo So I tell my TiVo to record all the anime I want to see off of the TV whenever it comes on and then whenever I want to watch it I sit down and I watch it skipping all of the ads along the way.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: now there are a lot of arguments one way or another but the the
Scott: fact
Rym: is that Me downloading a fan sub and watching it and then not watching that fan sub again and not buying the DVDs is no different Than me TiVo in a show Not watching the ads and then not keeping it or buying the DVD or ever watching it again because the same amount of money changes hands regardless.
Rym: and in fact you could argue that the TiVo solution while perfectly legal is more fraudulent.
Rym: because now the only way that show is still making money off the TV is if the Advertisers are fooled into thinking that I saw those ads that I clearly did that starts a whole nother show about how and we're selling Ads is all about lying to people.
Rym: Well, especially when it comes to television ads because you can just skip them.
Rym: You don't have to watch them Yeah, and I don't yep.
Rym: So, all right all the ways I have a watching anime.
Rym: Let's go one step further.
Rym: Let's say a show is really good and I buy it cuz.
Rym: I really like it.
Rym: All right I bought Eska flown at pretty much no one I know Bought Eska flown a. you want to know why?
Rym: because I lent my copy to everyone who wanted to see it.
Rym: Nothing wrong with that right or Evangelion.
Rym: we own it, right?
Rym: Only one person in the entire front row crew needs to own any anime ever because we'll all just lend each other DVDs or we'll all Get together and have a marathon.
Scott: Oh, but you know most anime fans.
Scott: who loses?
Scott: no friends?
Scott: So basically it's because people are going to conventions and making friends.
Scott: That's ruining the anime industry because they can still have to sell less DVDs But everyone's a troubled loner like comic book fans.
Scott: They can sell more copies because they have no one to share with.
Rym: cuz I can say one thing at RIT I remember.
Rym: All right, someone would like have money and they'd buy an anime DVD from media play for like 25 bucks, right?
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: They would then watch that anime DVD multiple times in lounges with crowds like 10 or 15 people every time.
Rym: So none of those people had to.
Scott: this is this is when an anime DVD was like a new thing like oh my god It's on DVD.
Rym: I can't believe it and I guess the point that I could get.
Rym: there's a lot of other ways I can watch anime But every single way that I can watch anime except one of them is perfectly legal Perfectly legitimate and in no way gives any substantial amount of money to any anime producer or creator.
Rym: Yep So there's a problem here because I I'm arguably a huge anime fan.
Rym: I love anime.
Rym: I I've seen you ten like seven times because it's like this amazing show and cowboy bebop and eskaflowne and all the half of those Lupin movies.
Scott: No, but let's say like you like the spice and wolf show, right?
Rym: I really like spice.
Scott: What if the only way to get it at all was to buy the DVDs for like 15 bucks each for like?
Scott: Four or five episodes?
Scott: would you buy it?
Rym: See the thing is I bought eskaflowne because I could buy the whole box set for $23 because it was on sale.
Rym: Hmm.
Rym: I bought Evangeline Because I could buy the whole series for $30.
Scott: So even a huge anime fan with plenty did this all anecdotal.
Scott: but you know This is a speculation show here right?
Scott: a huge anime fan Who's not?
Scott: some high school kid with no money someone with a real job and lots of money, right?
Scott: Arguably, you don't have enough free time to spend in the anime and that probably would change things But you're only willing to spend $23 for an entire anime series.
Rym: Oh, it's even worse.
Rym: All right master Keaton master Keaton is one of those shows.
Rym: when I say those shows I get to that because I think this is the car of the Problem.
Rym: but master Keaton is a show where there is with one exception that exception being the Cali man of the desert.
Rym: There is no reason to ever watch an episode of master Keaton more than once Mmm, because everything the said the drama the suspense and everything is gone.
Rym: It's like bleached Naruto.
Rym: the shelves are good, but you've seen an episode, you know, what happened You know how it was resolved and they're not the kind of show.
Rym: They're like a TV show in America.
Rym: you watch an episode and other than the crazy rare amazing shows like the Simpsons No one's gonna watch an episode of that again episode of master Keaton again is just boring Mmm, so I bought master Keaton Scott and I bought.
Rym: I bought it.
Scott: Well, yeah, I was gonna buy but it was it from who those people with the really good DVDs.
Rym: We bought it because it was only five dollars a disc.
Rym: It was real cheap.
Rym: and While we bought it and I'm glad I watched it.
Rym: I would rather have Netflix did because I'm never gonna watch it again I'm probably going to lend or give away the entire set.
Scott: Hey, it's mine.
Scott: What are you doing?
Rym: You're probably gonna lend it.
Scott: I gotta watch it all and then I can lend it.
Rym: Yes, but after you watch it You don't care if you still have those DVDs.
Rym: You're never gonna watch them again.
Scott: Probably not.
Scott: No, I mean I bought.
Scott: we bought those guys Iraqi VHS's and we watch those I think twice and then But like initial D right I've watched those DVDs.
Scott: how many times yeah or ask a seed how many times we watch those?
Rym: I've seen that Gundam seed two and a half time.
Scott: that cross TV series I own that I bought.
Scott: I actually macross TV series because back when it first came out on DVD from anime ego.
Scott: They had a pre-order for the box set of the original macross TV series subtitled only Remastered and that was like holy shit.
Scott: This has never been something I could see ever before.
Scott: You know the because I had seen Robotech but the original macross TV series, holy shit, so I was willing to pay.
Scott: Well, it's like two hundred something dollars at the time because it was like oh my god is amazing.
Scott: This is like my only chance in the entire universe right because I thought it was.
Scott: you know, it is something I wanted Desperately, and I thought the supply was very low.
Scott: That's the amount of money I was willing to pay one up But that's not true anymore for anything.
Scott: Even if you came out with something else that I desperately wanted to see in a rare ultra box set just like a blue GQ for 40 bucks the whole thing 40 bucks pretty.
Scott: no not gonna happen Even though it's not a really really really want to see.
Scott: cuz I've only seen one episode and I loved it.
Scott: I really want to own it on DVD because I think I would watch that many times.
Scott: I've already watched the first episode like five times.
Rym: I have a worry about that show.
Rym: I feel like sadly the first episode What set up expectations way too high?
Rym: I don't think the show can keep up that level of awesome.
Scott: I think it's gonna be like the read or die OAV in terms of quality.
Rym: It might be read or die is like crazy exception.
Rym: and that it started with this level of awesome Right away that you look at it.
Rym: You think all right.
Rym: There's no way they could keep this up.
Rym: This is gonna turn into one of those gonzo shows.
Rym: Yeah, but They kept it up and part of that was because the show was really really short.
Scott: Yeah Well the project blue cheek you I think is a short OAV also or short T's very short.
Scott: I don't think it's a lot of episodes.
Rym: Yeah, but spice and wolf all right, if it was on TV, I'd watch it by T going it and That's it.
Rym: I would never.
Rym: I would never buy the DVDs.
Rym: It's definitely not gonna be a show that I'm gonna watch over and over again forever and it's gonna be timeless Unless that show really goes in a really interesting direction.
Rym: Yep, but So I'm never gonna buy the DVDs.
Rym: It's not even a question.
Scott: So because if it wasn't fansubbed, we just wouldn't watch it.
Scott: The fansubs aren't ruining the show or causing them not to not make money.
Scott: We're not going haha watch the fansubs instead of buying it.
Scott: It's if there were no fansubs if their way for wasn't on TV, we just wouldn't watch it.
Rym: Well, what I'm saying too is that if it were on TV, which is the best way to show a show like that They're still not really gonna make any money because I'm pretty sure that the anime make money by lying to advertise.
Rym: that's the thing though.
Rym: the the anime watching demographic probably heavy heavily overlaps with the Technological enough to know that you can skip ads in television demographic.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: the Adult Swim gets enough ads to make monies.
Rym: Yeah, but how many people watch those ads?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I really don't think that many people do.
Scott: they still make money because they lied to the Advertisers and the advertisers still pay out because they don't know any better.
Rym: I just I don't get it.
Rym: But here's the thing for forget.
Rym: Let's say everyone else watches the ads, but let now.
Rym: I'm not advocating this I'm just pointing it out as an interesting conundrum.
Rym: How is now really I want to?
Rym: I want all our listeners to answer this.
Rym: How is me watching spice and wolf on American TV with a TiVo?
Rym: Skipping every single ad any different than watching the fans up.
Rym: It's dubbed Alright, so it's worse for me.
Scott: Yeah, cause them more money because they had to pay for that dub Whereas the subtitles didn't have to pay anything.
Scott: So I'm just less.
Rym: but think about it economically.
Rym: I mean, what is the difference morally morals aside?
Rym: Just think about the economics of it because all that matters in the end is the economics.
Rym: and the economics are that?
Rym: I don't think The anime industry in America is doing very well at all.
Scott: No, I really don't think they are.
Rym: now what I think the primary reason and it relates to kind of everything we said is pretty simple The place they make all their money as far as we can tell is merchandising.
Rym: The majority of the merchandising is for the super popular pulpy shows shown in fighting stuff.
Rym: the super popular the bleaches that sort of thing are the shows that have a million episodes that people only watch once and They're the kind of show that you watch dragon ball and you forget about.
Scott: I mean There are some crazed fans who will watch Naruto again or watch Dragon Ball again You know, they'll want to own those things on DVD and watch them again and again and whatever.
Scott: but most of the Naruto fans They just want to see the newest episode and go.
Scott: Oh my god.
Scott: What happened this week?
Rym: And in fact, I see a lot of these people.
Rym: they'll buy like one or two DVDs But they'll buy the DVDs that have the specific episodes that were crazy awesome and they don't care about everything else.
Rym: So, uh, what you've got here is a market that is based primarily on making money off of people who have no desire or incentive to buy the DVDs and Probably would just not watch anymore if they couldn't get the shows for free or very cheap.
Scott: You have a product that is designed to make money by being shown on TV Weekly, you know, you're not showing it on TV weekly and you're not.
Scott: well, they are.
Rym: they had Naruto's on TV no, but the problem is people already saw the fan sub so I got ahead.
Rym: and then because of the the Idiocy of how the Japanese companies license anime and they're so afraid of re-importation They always make the licenses get so delayed.
Rym: that all right by the time.
Rym: All right.
Rym: I've seen some fan subs.
Rym: I like the show by the time they released in the US in English Legitimately, I'm already on episode 30 now.
Rym: This is me.
Rym: I don't do this, but I'm speaking from a Naruto standpoint.
Rym: Why the hell am I gonna start from episode 1 again?
Rym: I already know what happens and why the hell am I gonna wait until forever?
Rym: When they bring out the next DVD past episode 30?
Rym: So these kids really have no incentive other than charity to buy the DVD.
Scott: And if they're not and if they're not a Nielsen house What does it matter?
Scott: if they watch the fan sub or if they watch it on TV?
Scott: They're gonna still.
Scott: the person who's downloading the fan sub will actually probably is a is a more dedicated fan.
Scott: It will probably spend more money on The Naruto headband and the merchandise and the manga and all that jazz.
Rym: now, I don't know what to do about this.
Rym: I mean, here's the problem.
Rym: We we don't have the solution.
Rym: I don't think anyone has a solution.
Scott: I have some ideas.
Rym: I know I can't guarantee their solutions though I know that what the anime industry in America is doing right now is not the solution.
Rym: No, but I really don't know what to do.
Rym: I see no way to make money in the long run off of selling DVDs that the majority of people who Theoretically would want them are not going to buy and you can't stop the fansubbers Even if you no matter what you do, there's no way to stop it.
Scott: I think the key I think the way to make money from selling DVDs is just you shouldn't?
Scott: DVDs shouldn't be the primary Focus, right?
Scott: It's like look at HBO, right.
Scott: HBO She sells the DVD box sets of all their series, right?
Scott: The Simpsons the Futurama box sets are very popular and then they sell lots of make make lots of copies, right?
Scott: But those are primarily on TV and the DVDs are secondary.
Scott: What they should do is if I was an anime licenser, right?
Scott: Especially with this writers strike the TV channels are dying for content, right?
Scott: I would push my anime series hardcore to get it in a great TV time slot with lots and lots of marketing.
Scott: I try to.
Scott: maybe I would try to work with Japan to make a new anime that would really appeal to like the HBO Audience or something I could get on prime time or something, right?
Scott: And since I was just something I licensed from Japan and not a new thing made by writers in the US I wouldn't need to hire any writers and I could get it on TV and there be no competition and then
Rym: or I think another Equally valid way with the shows.
Rym: these shown in fighting shows would be to release them Subtitled because it seems like most fans are willing to just watch the subtitles Digitally online for a couple bucks an episode.
Scott: Well, they do do that sometime kinda now.
Rym: Yeah, but not not as it's coming out in Japan not as quick as the fan suppers, which isn't good enough for these kids.
Rym: It's got to be right away or there's gonna watch the fan sub.
Rym: Yeah, the probably the Japanese companies don't seem to ever want to have that.
Scott: but if you put the show on TV you get your money because all these Advertisers give you all this money because they don't know any better.
Rym: What if all the anime fans just Tivo it?
Scott: it won't matter because They'll buy the incredibly cheap box set because you only gonna release the season boxes just like HBO does.
Scott: the DVDs are sort of The supplement.
Scott: you put something on.
Scott: TV is primarily a TV show and then you sort of make a few extra bucks because you can Sell DVD box sets on the side.
Scott: You don't make DVDs and downloads the only the primary thing because those are there.
Scott: a supplement not a you know.
Scott: In terms of the money-making it.
Rym: I mean we have a bunch of other ideas too, but just in the up in the in the Interest of brevity and so I can go to bed and maybe make some dinner.
Scott: I want to make my point about this not good anime anymore.
Scott: Also, though.
Rym: It's already gone on too long.
Scott: No, let me make the point.
Rym: All right, hurry up and then we're going to bed.
Scott: I had the other.
Scott: the other factor here that I've been thinking about recently is right look Anime has been around for a long time since you know, technically a longer but basically since Astro Boy anime.
Scott: as we know it It's like late 50s early 60s, right?
Scott: It's ancient, right?
Scott: But anime, you know took off as a as a cool thing in the US.
Scott: and what like mid late 90s Ish right something like that.
Scott: and at that time when anime took off it took off because of sci-fi animes from you know, like the 80s 70s and the 80s and things like that.
Scott: and When the anime got big at first they you know, they slowly licensed more and more things.
Scott: But what they did is they cherry-picked the best anime from history.
Scott: They had all this history of anime.
Scott: and why they do?
Scott: they went for the big guns.
Scott: They went you know for the Robo tech action.
Scott: They went for the gun jim action cowboy bebop Evangelion as Capone, right?
Scott: They got all these great Chuck here all the great movies of anime all the Miyazaki's Akira You know all the stuff right all the good stuff is what they got.
Scott: And then after they finished up getting the best of history of anime, you know, they said alright, what do we do now?
Scott: Well, let's see what's coming out this year.
Scott: You know We've already and they just they started licensing every show or almost every show every year.
Scott: And the thing was is that while they were able to you know, garner fandom in a lot of those shows Most of the shows are crap.
Scott: There's maybe one even as an anime fan a big anime fan This may be one good show every few years You know, not one good show.
Scott: It's not like.
Rym: well One great show.
Rym: cuz there are good shows but I good show.
Scott: there aren't these great shows that they I'm willing to buy on DVD maybe once every few years and movies are even rare.
Scott: Satoshi khan makes a movie every two or three years, right?
Scott: Miyazaki makes a movie about just as slow if not slower.
Scott: There's the speed of anime production in least for the big High-quality shows that everyone loves and will remember forever and spend a lot of money on and buy DVDs of is not common.
Scott: So they made a lot of money when they licensed all the greats of history all at once and now There's not a lot of new things to be licensed that are great at a fast enough rate to sort of have Constant new content making a lot more money and everyone already bought all the good stuff.
Scott: They license before it's now What do you do?
Rym: Well now they they're selling those great shows again to try to make more money.
Scott: Yeah, that's a good idea.
Scott: cuz I'm buying cowboy bebop, you know now that it's gonna be a $30 box set.
Rym: But so basically what it comes down to is fans like us people who are really really in anime really have no incentive to buy Anime DVDs or anime merchandise.
Rym: and yet we're not breaking any laws or pirating either.
Rym: So as a result What do you do?
Rym: If you're if your biggest fans are no longer a source of income you're you're kind of screwed.
Scott: Yeah, it's.
Scott: it's not that I don't want anime in general I do.
Scott: it's that these specific there's not enough specific Animes that I desire greatly enough that I'm going to spend money to watch them or that I need to own the DVDs.
Scott: And I think you know from seeing a lot of other people.
Scott: I think that's the sort of a general even if people don't realize they they feel that way.
Scott: I think a lot of people do feel that way like there's just.
Scott: you know Their desire for the anime is not so high the you know They're not watching a fan sub in lieu of buying.
Scott: They're only watching the fans up because it's so easy.
Scott: if there was no fans, so they just wouldn't watch.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: if you like what you hear.
Rym: you can Catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.