Rym: It's Wednesday April 16th.
Rym: I'm Rym Scott's downstairs making dinner, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight we talked about some comic books that I kind of liked.
Scott: surprisingly Let's do this.
Rym: So what I'm about to say is not often what you would expect.
Rym: a geeky podcast like this to start with.
Rym: it's one of those Sentences that sets off a whole bunch of alarm bells.
Rym: Usually the alarm bells along the lines of the person I'm listening to is a wacko.
Rym: I should probably stop listening.
Rym: Are you gonna say what is the number for the police?
Scott: Are you gonna say something that sounds like like two in the morning middle of nowhere a.m.
Scott: Radio?
Rym: No, but I feel like our duty now is to hook up an a.m.
Rym: Radio two in the morning in the middle of nowhere.
Rym: record something and bring it back.
Scott: CC will come down and us like a ton of bricks.
Rym: They'll have to find us.
Scott: I guess they're pretty good at that.
Rym: I'm gonna say another kind of thing.
Rym: so today the the Jews tried to kill me Did they?
Rym: but luckily I escaped.
Scott: yeah my knife wasn't sharp enough That Jews plural.
Rym: you see Passovers coming up as you might know because the New York anime festival comic-con the New York comic-con.
Rym: I always confuse the two.
Rym: Apologize for the fact that it's happening over Passover, and you know it is despite all our pressness.
Rym: We'll have to go to his family's house on Saturday.
Scott: Well, it's in Queens.
Scott: It's not very far, but The thing is it's pretty funny because you know like comics are very Comics in the American the United States and Jewishness are pretty tight.
Scott: You know most of the big-time creators of comics in the olden days were Jews.
Scott: Stanley's Jew Will Eisner was a Jew.
Scott: you know Jack Kirby and pretty sure is Jew.
Rym: But there's something that happens mostly in New York City.
Rym: You don't see this sort of thing in a lot of other places except this kind of the downstate, New York greater metropolitan area.
Rym: I was almost run over by a mitzvah tank.
Scott: The mitzvah tank is driving around.
Rym: those know that the mitzvah tank went over the line this year.
Scott: Uh-huh cuz usually right that that's a special kind of Jew.
Rym: the the mitzvah tank Jews This is this was all right, so I'm walking on 42nd Street actually on 43rd Street.
Rym: Don't ask why.
Rym: up toward 5th Avenue, and I get to 5th Avenue.
Rym: I want to cross 5th Avenue, and I'm waiting but up ahead I hear all this ruckus all this noise, and I hear fire trucks.
Rym: I think all right something's going on Mm-hmm which is no big deal.
Rym: you hear that almost every day in the cities.
Rym: I just ignore it, and I'm you know waiting.
Rym: what's going on?
Rym: I see the light turn green, but no one's going and there's honking up ahead.
Rym: I finally get there and Despite having a green light in a walk signal and There's a crowd of people not walking because mitzvah tank upon mitzvah tank is running the red light going.
Rym: I Kid you not about 50 miles an hour really a lot of them.
Rym: there were like 70 of these things.
Scott: Yeah They have a lot of them.
Rym: they blocked 5th Avenue in a line one after the other going as fast as they could Refusing to let anyone get on the streets running red lights.
Rym: They almost hit this old lady.
Rym: They almost hit me because eventually a bunch of us like you know what screw you people.
Rym: And we all walk out into the street and one of the mitzvah tanks doesn't slow down and just barely swerves around the crowd.
Rym: And then all the other ones kind of pile up sounded like one of them hit another one way back.
Rym: And then there's all this yelling and they're trying to push through the crowd.
Rym: one a guy got out of the car starts yelling everyone To get out of his way, and then I see where the fire truck noises were coming from.
Rym: there's this red sports car convertible And in it is the most acidic acidic Jew I've ever seen and he's standing up and he's got a loudspeaker and he's yelling at everyone to get out of his way and He's got a large boombox playing the sound of a fire truck.
Scott: Uh-huh, and he's not legal.
Rym: No so I'm kind of just watching this whole spectacle and the the people in the Mitzvah tanks as they get bogged down by people who eventually start walking out in front of them Start yelling at people and people are yelling back and one guy like kicked one of the mitzvah tanks.
Rym: Everyone's getting all crazy, and then the police came.
Rym: yep That's what they do and the police didn't know what to do because there were far more Mitzvah tanks than there were cop cars at that time because this had just begun.
Rym: yep So I see the cop.
Rym: one of the cops had figured out that there's this red sports car guy who's driving up and down the street Illegally directing this whole thing.
Rym: so uh Chase ensued, and I did not get to see the conclusion because I couldn't run fast enough But something happened down by like 38th Street And I can't wait to see what the New York Post has to say about this tomorrow.
Scott: You care what the New York Post says.
Rym: they're the ones that'll sensationalize it the most.
Rym: there'll be some stupid headline.
Scott: I'd rather read the daily news, and that's a piece of shit, too.
Rym: The New York Post is something special.
Scott: It's funny that they sell all these like newspapers at the train state.
Scott: I see all these newspapers, and they think most of them.
Scott: You know they're pretty cheap is like 25 cents, and I go wow That's.
Scott: I would use it as toilet paper if it didn't have ink on it, but seriously You don't know what a Mitzvah tank is.
Scott: Basically the deal is right.
Scott: is that there's a?
Scott: you know there's.
Scott: there's different.
Scott: you know unlike you know Christians Right they have.
Scott: there's different all different kinds.
Scott: you got Catholics you got Protestants, but then within the Protestants You got different kinds right and you got the.
Scott: you know it's all different kinds.
Scott: They all believe different things right?
Scott: and the Jews?
Scott: there's some groups of Jews who believe different things right, but in general You know just sort of speaking generally they they're Jews really.
Scott: they don't believe different things They just believe more strongly or less strongly right.
Scott: It's like a Reform Jew is like yeah, I'm Jewish.
Scott: Whatever a conservative Jew is like yeah, I'm Jewish all right all right.
Scott: an Orthodox Jew is like I am so Jewish.
Scott: I'm like kosher, and I got two sets of dishes and a Hasidic Jew is like a Mitzvah tank.
Scott: You know well yes now The has not.
Scott: all the Hasidic Jews are Mitzvah tank driving types.
Scott: those are specifically the Lebovitches.
Scott: The Lebovitches are not only Hasidic, but they are crazy.
Rym: You gotta watch out for them, and you know how many people in the street today were like hey, you Jewish I was like nope They were just checking.
Rym: Yep, just checking.
Rym: but These Mitzvah tanks like.
Rym: the spectacle that I beheld on Fifth Avenue today was epic And I wish I'd had the video camera because they almost ran over so many old ladies.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, they're crazy Lebovitches.
Scott: Yeah, you gotta watch out for them, so that was my day.
Scott: Yeah, all right my day was not so exciting.
Scott: I went to work and did work.
Rym: That's it.
Rym: No no excitement.
Scott: No, huh, not really all right.
Rym: Well anyway.
Rym: I got some actual anime news coming here.
Scott: Oh my god.
Scott: Yeah, well you know are you guys talking about the comic?
Rym: I had a lot to talk about this weekend is the New York comic-con in the Jacob Javits Center in New York City.
Rym: Friday Saturday Sunday, we could go Thursday, but I don't think I'm gonna.
Scott: What is there?
Rym: Thursday press.
Scott: What do we do?
Rym: we could go do press stuff if we wanted.
Scott: I have to go to work.
Rym: There's interviews.
Rym: yeah I have to to the press.
Rym: the press thing closes at 5. so theoretically if I left work a little early and took a cab I Could do like a half hours worth of pressy stuff.
Scott: not worth it.
Rym: But Friday Saturday Sunday New York comic-con.
Rym: it's probably if you're gonna go to something like this.
Rym: I'm gonna tell you straight up it's really only worth it to go to one day because You're gonna want to do.
Rym: you're gonna be able to do in one day unless well Specific events that are on days other than the one day you go that you want to see.
Scott: yeah unlike a lot of other Comic-cons you know this one actually has a crazy number of events.
Scott: the schedules in a PDF online.
Rym: It's a lot more like an anime con in that regard.
Scott: well kind of but they just have a shit ton Number of events.
Scott: so most of them are industry events.
Scott: like you know it's basically Like you go and sit there for a half hour while people from a company like advertise their product to you You know or like say hey buy our new comic.
Scott: the craters here talking about the new comic to make you want to buy it.
Scott: So a lot of the events don't really count in my book But there are like.
Scott: I think there's over 200 events at this con.
Scott: It's crazy, but unless you care about the events if you do like comics right you should and you're in New York And you you know you don't go to comic-cons too often.
Scott: You probably should go to the comic-con.
Scott: It should take you maybe Three hours at most maybe four because it's bigger than last year to sort of walk around See all the booths see the whole artist alley and all that business.
Scott: You know.
Scott: if there's no particular events you want and to do that I think is worth it especially if you have kids and you go on Sunday and the kids I think are 12 or under maybe 13 or I'm not sure they get in free.
Scott: so cuz it's kids day.
Rym: Beyond that TMR TM Revolution is doing a concert there and the price of admission for one day to this convention is well worth seeing.
Rym: a live Concert especially from a pretty good guy Yep, but speaking of TMR.
Rym: We weren't going to go to the comic-con in any official.
Scott: I was gonna go maybe Friday night But not in any official capacity like we.
Rym: we kind of burned ourselves out with a million cons And we got every con in the freaking world this summer, so we were gonna just like show up to this one maybe say hi to some people chill a little bit do a little bit of our press blah blah blah and then go home.
Rym: but One thing led to another and for one repress.
Rym: we're gonna actually be doing the press thing and you get me that badge.
Rym: Well, I got a press badge.
Scott: good job.
Scott: See if you get always seem to you know fail to.
Scott: when talking to people mention that there's two.
Scott: now.
Rym: It's more that they most people see no reason for more than one reporter from any given group to show up.
Rym: Yeah, besides when is this ever happened before?
Scott: nah when quite a few times when I can't think of it for specific circumstance.
Rym: Is there ever been a time when I didn't get you a badge?
Scott: No, there have been times when now you've failed to mention that there are two of us Such as I'll remember in a minute.
Rym: I'm curious when this has occurred.
Rym: Yeah, we'll continue with the show and then I'll remind Okay, cuz it's never happened This time either yet.
Rym: No, actually didn't.
Rym: I said yes me and my co-host would like to come and then they gave me one press credential.
Rym: uh-huh, but anyway We're gonna be going and doing the press II stuff but independent of that.
Scott: It's supposed to see my co-host and I Okay, yeah take that that's just cuz you have nothing.
Rym: you're making stuff up and now you're trying to cover for it But you got nothing and when confronted with having nothing you got nothing to do.
Rym: you got nothing to say.
Scott: That's all you've got.
Scott: continue while I remember.
Rym: Yeah, you're gonna remember shit.
Rym: Anyway, the long story short is is that we also have our friends at Tokyo FM and We've set up this sort of event where we and them are going to be interviewing TM revolution at Kinokuniya bookstore on Sunday at 3 p.m.
Rym: For Japanese radio.
Rym: Oh, yeah, this is going to be pretty cool.
Rym: I mean if you're going to this con and you want to see TM revolution They have their panel with Brian Nishi I think and all this stuff and you'll see the concert obviously But if you want to see him up close.
Rym: You're probably better off going to Kinokuniya or at least you should go to the Kinokuniya thing at 3.
Scott: If you've never been to Kinokuniya, you should probably go there.
Scott: if you're going for the comic-con You should probably go to Kinokuniya.
Rym: Anyway, yes, cuz one if you're an anime fan or a manga fan, you've never been to a Japanese bookstore.
Rym: You're gonna realize there's a lot of stuff that's not in English that you would probably kill to be able to have a great English Selection.
Rym: they do.
Scott: you'd be saying I'm a brand new store in Bryant Park.
Scott: That's crazy and Beyond that it's just fun to go to the store.
Rym: If you're not an anime fan.
Rym: You're just a comic fan You're going to the comic-con.
Rym: You might want to go just to see all the different kinds of manga in Japanese comics that are out there.
Scott: I mean Kinokuniya will have a booth at the con but you know They won't be.
Scott: that won't even be like a drop in the bucket compared to the store.
Scott: and it's not.
Rym: as I've seen with Scott You know, he's in the comic geeks big forums.
Rym: a lot of comic fans Automatically kind of dismiss manga and think it's one thing and don't see.
Rym: well realize I think it's just comics from Japan.
Scott: Well, I'm thinking you know more and more right that it's.
Scott: it's not like an either/or thing But I think that some people are fans of comics.
Scott: They like comics and all their forms, you know They don't care about you know, they like web comics.
Scott: They like mangas.
Scott: They like your you know, they like comics You know, they like, you know sequential arts, right, but there are some people, you know They say I'm a fan of comics, but really they're not a fan of comics as a whole.
Scott: They're superhero fans.
Scott: They're fans of you know, spider-man maybe you know and they actually you know.
Scott: That's why you see all those comic stores selling toys and movies and cartoons on because they're you know These people.
Scott: they say they're comic fans and they go and buy comics every Wednesday, but really they're superhero fans.
Scott: Now there are people, you know are somewhere in between like I'm a tiny superhero fan and a big comics fan.
Scott: there's some people who are sort of like half and half or whatever, but I think that Even still the US comics industry with more than 50% of it if its weight relies on Superhero fandom as opposed to comics fandom.
Rym: I'm just saying all I want to say.
Rym: My only point is that if you don't.
Rym: if you think you don't like manga you think you know What manga is.
Rym: you don't really read it?
Rym: Go to the Kinokuniya after the comic-con one the TMR thing will be cool and to Look at you're gonna see comics about like old men playing golf Really closely.
Scott: don't just sort of like stand back and see like a wall of crazy stuff and be like, ah, it's all crazy.
Scott: Actually get in there and look at it like closely and examine all the different stuff even though you can't read it.
Rym: You know a lot of times you don't need to read it.
Rym: that golf manga.
Rym: I know exactly what's going on.
Scott: I know exactly what.
Scott: I don't know the details but know in general.
Rym: Yeah, that guy's crying that guy's shot-putting That's all I need to know.
Rym: Yeah So yeah at 3 p.m.
Rym: On Sunday at the Kinokuniya bookstore in New York City Brian Brian Park.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Yeah, you can find Kinokuniya bookstore.
Rym: I'm sure you'll be able to get directions to it from the comic-con.
Scott: if you ask anyone if you go to the Kinokuniya booth At the comic-con, I'm sure they will tell you where their store is.
Scott: They'll be happy to tell you.
Rym: I'm glad the anime news network has mentioned this even though they didn't mention us despite us being in the press.
Scott: I think my news network hates us.
Rym: They must you know, I guess now we'll find out if anyone from the anime news network listens or not.
Rym: Maybe I'm curious.
Rym: I really am because they got one thing going for them.
Rym: They got anime news.
Scott: Nina Yeah, I mean is Nina's the best thing on that website actually animates new work, you know You know, I guess there's.
Scott: you could you could criticize them about some things but really they're the only Game attack like in the end.
Scott: They're not doing that bad in the anime press world.
Rym: They're effectively the AP wire.
Rym: They're the wire that at least the English anime press world because the English anime press world is a sad sad world.
Rym: There's almost nothing.
Rym: There's I mean what we are right there after the anime news network.
Rym: They say something happened.
Rym: We say rabble rabble about something that happened.
Scott: I mean, it's anime news service calm, but they haven't updated since September 2007.
Rym: I have some ideas about how to make the anime press better, but it's a show for another time.
Scott: Just have a competitor.
Scott: No, I have a lot of people who speak Japanese working for you.
Rym: I actually have some very specific ideas that involve some friends of ours.
Scott: So I got.
Scott: I got some news here from anime news network.
Scott: I haven't done an anime news network.
Rym: actually my other news is from slash dot but it's actually from the anime news.
Scott: Now you have.
Scott: you have another news?
Rym: Yeah, but you can go first.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: I thought that was just your news.
Rym: No, I got a couple of things.
Scott: Okay Yeah, so in Korea, right?
Scott: There's some people they want to make a movie about Captain Harlock, which is awesome.
Scott: All right Captain Harlock was created by Leiji Matsumoto who created Yamato and Galaxy Express and he did that the movie with Daft Punk interstellar whatnot?
Scott: five five five five five five five five.
Scott: He's pretty awesome.
Scott: As far as anime making dudes go right one of the number but easily top five easily.
Scott: so in Korea though, they want to make a Carlock movie when they have a budget of like a hundred million dollars.
Scott: But Matsumoto says hey, I didn't say they could do that.
Scott: What what's going on?
Scott: And It's kind of you know, and okay, that's that's all there is to the news, but It's I find it kind of funny that Japan the country where you know Do jinchi is so hot so allowed, right?
Scott: It's like oh if you want to use my characters to create your own artistic work and profit from it.
Rym: Go right ahead.
Rym: I think part of it's because they seem to tolerate that up to the point of large professional operations.
Scott: Well, yeah now see here's the thing It's like.
Scott: where are they exactly drawing the line here?
Scott: because in the u.s.
Scott: We draw the line at you are making money You are not making money.
Scott: I think that's a pretty clear line, right?
Scott: But there's no jinchi people.
Scott: you see a comic kit.
Scott: They're making a profit.
Scott: They're not making a large.
Rym: Well, actually the line in the u.s.
Rym: Isn't even that clear?
Rym: because technically you're infringing even if you're not making money I know.
Rym: I know some people do go after you.
Scott: Yes, that is true.
Scott: However in Japan right they see they allow people to do this while making you know small to moderate profits.
Scott: But it's suddenly when you know, they're spending a hundred million dollars.
Scott: That does a problem.
Scott: Well, what if I spent fifty million dollars?
Scott: Would that be a problem?
Scott: How about one million?
Scott: How much is how much you know, what is the scale where on the scale?
Scott: Is it suddenly?
Rym: One of those?
Rym: technically you shouldn't do it, but we're all cool with it But we might not be cool with it in the future and there's a lot like that.
Scott: It seems just you know, it seems as a as a moral thing.
Scott: It seems they're very inconsistent and they're just sort of.
Rym: but we're just as inconsistent I know but the only difference between us in Japan is that our inconsistency line is Equally wide but much lower.
Scott: Yes, but it's very hypocritical of you know A single person because I'm sure there's plenty of Harlock dojinshe's out there that me that Matsumoto's not cracking down on maybe not maybe he hates all of them.
Rym: That's possible Sits up at night.
Rym: Just how can I get those bastards?
Scott: How can I get those bastards?
Scott: They don't know how to draw my tell properly girl But I'm sure he's not going after them.
Scott: You know, I don't.
Scott: I guess I don't.
Scott: I'm not a hundred percent sure on this, but I'm pretty sure there's plenty of dojinshe's of Matsumoto's characters.
Rym: But at the same time if you're making a movie off real movie with a studio You should probably at least ask the copyright, right?
Scott: All right, that's true I'm not.
Scott: I'm not saying these Korean people are doing great at this point, you know, plus the you know.
Scott: This is only gonna get worse from here as you know, let me look at us.
Scott: They're podcasting right now, right as amateur media production Right and professional media production get closer and closer to each other.
Scott: Where's the line gonna be?
Scott: you're not gonna be.
Scott: you know, if you say it's okay for amateurs It's not okay for professionals.
Scott: Well as amateurs are able to make professional products You know, what?
Scott: what really is your distinction?
Scott: Well, I've seen really whimsical and subjective.
Scott: deciding who to pick on.
Rym: the way It's usually determined is simply by the scale of distribution.
Rym: If I make a hundred dojinshe's no one cares.
Scott: But what if I find my doji and put it on the Internet's?
Scott: that's that's different because that's not that's the biggest scale of distribution You can get.
Rym: yes, but no one pays attention to that.
Rym: or because not yet at least Yeah, it just seems like cuz then you're not making money off of it.
Scott: You could be so.
Rym: you're selling it online Possible.
Rym: Well, how many do you sell?
Rym: You'd probably sell more of your selling in person.
Rym: Maybe you could sell memberships to your doubt your doujinshi downloading site And I don't know how many people would pay for that.
Scott: I don't know if you had a really good doujinshi's in English and there were lots of them.
Scott: I might pay.
Rym: I just don't know.
Rym: not as much of a hypocritical issues.
Rym: You're making it out to be.
Scott: I just think Japan really needs to straighten out their their situation.
Rym: I think the US needs to straighten out it's situation.
Scott: Everyone needs to straighten out the situation.
Scott: I think Japan has a little worse and I also think that This this movie.
Scott: I hope they make it because it sounds like awesome.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: I mean, you don't know a hundred million dollar Harlock movie can't go wrong.
Rym: We'll see.
Rym: I've seen some hundred million dollar movies in my day.
Scott: There's a lack of Movies.
Scott: I will take what I can get.
Rym: What are you talking about?
Rym: There's tons of movies.
Rym: What movies?
Rym: what do you mean?
Rym: Well, we've never even seen strange days.
Scott: I'm talking about like.
Scott: I'm talking about the anime movie.
Rym: Oh anime movies.
Rym: Yeah, but isn't this a live-action Is it?
Scott: no, I don't think so.
Rym: Are you sure?
Scott: Uh Into a film something so it doesn't actually say, uh-huh Yeah, huh, that's a good question Captain news.
Scott: Yeah, it doesn't say live-action or not.
Scott: You know what if it's live-action double awesome That would be sweet live-action Harlock.
Rym: Anyway, I want to really briefly mention this.
Rym: just because it was brought up in the anime press and a lot of people lost their shit over it.
Rym: some kind of know how.
Rym: I used RF IDs and I saw a lot of rabble on the internet rambling about oh My god, I'd never go to a con that did that.
Rym: All I have to say is chill Totally chill.
Rym: eventually every convention in the world is going to be doing that.
Rym: It's just a matter of the technology getting better.
Rym: Yeah, and it's a good thing and I'll leave it at that.
Scott: No, you see that's all.
Rym: I guess that's all I'm gonna say.
Scott: You're not gonna talk about RFID technology and how it works and what oh god.
Rym: No, that's a Monday show.
Scott: All right, we should do a Monday on RFID.
Scott: It's pretty simple though Yeah, but I guess we could talk a lot about not just the technology of it, but the implications.
Scott: Yeah, cuz the technology is really really really really yeah and the uses for it and you know when you should worry when you should Things of the day.
Rym: While ago, we used an awesome awesome sumo fight as a thing of the day.
Rym: This one is not technically as awesome But in many ways it is more awesome and I will leave it at that.
Scott: I really think that what was done it to the in this video that you're gonna see.
Scott: I really think that we should develop a technology that does this in real time.
Scott: Football exact adds it in real time to all sports all sports on television.
Rym: And if you thought that I remember when you should patent that idea before you invented I remember in hockey when they added the glow puck the glow puck and then they added the comic the comment whenever someone shot Yeah, the fire.
Rym: Yeah, and I remember thinking wow, that's really stupid.
Scott: It was cool for like five minutes and then it wasn't cool anymore.
Scott: Yeah, but the one thing is it did make it a little bit easier to see the puck.
Scott: when they're a bunch of guys It's out.
Rym: Well in the pre HD era it was critical for watching sports on.
Scott: Yeah You realize like hockey was one of the first things ever put in HD because Madison Square Garden the building which is where the rain New York Rangers, New York Knicks basketball play right is owned by cable vision, which is the people who give us cable here.
Scott: And so cable vision actually has a TV channel called MSG which basically shows Rangers and Knicks games.
Scott: and I Remember we had cable vision.
Scott: and the first thing that was ever in HD like way before Like HD was even popular.
Scott: like we're talking Mid to late 90s here like before most people even knew HD before.
Scott: there are any standards before anyone knew 720p or anything like that.
Scott: if you had bought an HD TV in those days, it probably wouldn't work nowadays.
Scott: But New York Rangers hockey was like the first thing ever in HD.
Scott: And if you actually went to Madison Square Garden and HD TVs all around and you could you know You know what and he was like, wow, look at that.
Rym: Why leave this for sports.
Rym: We should add this to the news.
Scott: Oh That's cruel and funny.
Rym: anyway, okay.
Scott: Oh my thing of the day, right?
Scott: Yeah So, you know when you're looking for a place to live this has nothing to do with anime or anything.
Scott: Is that this new thing of day out of nowhere, but I have a better thing a day for tomorrow.
Scott: So I didn't want to like, you know use this one tomorrow, whatever.
Scott: When you're looking for a place to live right the the two biggest things you got to worry about, right?
Scott: I mean if you look at I look at my expense report on my accounting little program right two basic expenses right our rent and Transportation.
Scott: right those like the place you live and the thing that gets you to other places, especially if you commute to work, right?
Scott: so When you pick a place to live it's like well I could move over here and the rent is $500 less a month But my transportation is gonna be $600 more a month.
Scott: So I'm actually better off staying where I am.
Scott: All right, and there's other factors you have to take into account But here's an interesting website That begins to solve the problem of helping you figure out where the most economically efficient place to live is where you want to go and what they have is they show you Housing or housing plus transportation as A percentage of the median income in the area in a visual way on this map,
Rym: huh?
Scott: Yeah, so you can look at this map in New York, right and you look like it's funny because you look at Manhattan Right and it's like tan means zero to thirty percent or you know, you can.
Scott: there's different options.
Scott: You can choose, you know, but tan is like, you know, you're spending less than you know Some percent of your you know income on housing and transportation and blue is you're spending more than a certain percent of your.
Scott: You know stuff on housing and transportation and it's like, huh?
Scott: You see all these like blue specks in Manhattan You can tell like some areas.
Scott: It's like oh, yeah, that's that's a cheap place to live.
Scott: That's an expensive place to live That's the place where nobody lives.
Scott: All right.
Scott: And then as soon as you go up into the Bronx It's all tan and then as soon as you get up to like Yonkers Tarrytown It starts turning deep blue all the way up pretty much Splotches in the places where people don't live far away from highways and transportation.
Rym: Huh?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah well at least Scott and I are at the point and as with much of the front row crew where we really We can't live more than an hour away from a global like international city or there's no jobs for us.
Scott: Yeah, anyway, let's see.
Scott: I'm looking here.
Scott: Yeah, actually beacon is tan and Like the thing is Putnam County below us is blue.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, you want to know why?
Rym: Yep, because we we tend.
Rym: I think we make actually a lot more money than the median for beacon right now.
Scott: But the thing will tell you what the median income is Income for beacon.
Rym: What's it say?
Scott: I got to go to the beacon area.
Rym: I'm curious.
Scott: Oh, actually it only tells you for New York North in New Jersey Long Island doesn't tell you for beacons.
Scott: visit the map.
Scott: It's not perfect, but it's a start.
Rym: So then how's it even calculating up here?
Scott: it cuz it has I don't know but you don't tell me the number.
Rym: I assume it's just making something up.
Rym: Yeah, it'd be blue here a little purple here a little bit.
Scott: Uh, yeah, it is an advanced mode that I haven't used but it's you know, it's interesting at the least.
Scott: if it's not It's not.
Scott: you know that useful yet, but I definitely see it going places Right.
Rym: So we were gonna try to review Toki wa kakoto shoujo tonight, but Scott didn't watch it.
Scott: How am I supposed to watch it?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: train where is it?
Rym: we had it for you.
Rym: We said several times you want it.
Rym: I'll give it to you.
Scott: I'm reading books.
Rym: Okay, and stuff Do you watch a Kazanoyo Jimbo yet?
Scott: Nope.
Rym: Do you watch?
Rym: Boca Rondo yet.
Scott: I did.
Scott: I watched as many as I watched before.
Rym: How about Baca now?
Scott: I watched as many as I watched before avatar.
Rym: No, okay great.
Rym: So, uh, I guess instead since Scott won't watch anime.
Rym: I read some comic books.
Scott: Oh, yeah, that's right.
Rym: I liked half of the series that I read All right.
Rym: So tonight first we're gonna talk about I. let's start with something.
Rym: I liked.
Rym: All right, Scott handed me Invincible volume one.
Scott: so invincible is written by Robert Kirkman.
Scott: Who's the the Walking Dead guy, right?
Scott: He also did that at the The the Wolfman comic on free comic book day that I didn't like.
Scott: that was terrible, right?
Scott: So I had heard about invincible.
Scott: people kept talking it up talking it up talking it up Right, and I'm like, all right, whatever.
Scott: I'll buy the first trade paperback.
Scott: It can't hurt, right?
Scott: I mean, I'll try it, you know, and I don't knock things till I try them.
Scott: So I bought the first one and It's not deep.
Scott: It's not serious.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: it's not like the Watchmen.
Scott: It's not a comic for all time.
Scott: It's just sort of plain and fun and bright and happy and I liked it.
Scott: It's sort of just like a nice diversion like ah I think the only real like.
Rym: I liked it partly because it was it so clearly did not take itself seriously.
Rym: I'm just like, yeah, whatever.
Rym: Yeah, let's go.
Rym: Let's go funny funny funny and One thing it uses the dot eyes a lot.
Rym: Yeah dot eyes the thing I think that's a good half of why I like Nana was the dot eyes.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah Do you want to summarize the plot?
Scott: we can summarize the plot.
Rym: whatever world of superheroes kid becomes a superhero because his dad's a superhero.
Rym: The mom is awesome.
Rym: yeah, basically they fight crime.
Scott: his dad is basically like Superman and then as he grows up eventually he Gets powers and he's like, I got some my superpowers and they're like, that's nice dear.
Scott: And it's you know, he's.
Scott: he's dealing with sort of normal high school life and has all the classic You know tropes of a superhero story, you know keeping your identity secret, you know Teams of other people, you know All this stuff.
Scott: but everyone it just sort of doesn't?
Scott: it doesn't?
Scott: it treats it in a different way.
Scott: it's just sort of like every people act normally despite living in a Stereotypical situation.
Rym: It's so light and it's it's funny.
Rym: Just the one part that I laughed out loud is at the end near the end Where the dad comes home.
Rym: dad comes home and you just see like his tattered arm Poking and he's like I need to shave.
Scott: Yeah, basically this is one point at which the dad gets sucked into another universe, right?
Scott: And you know the whole time you see, you know, the mom usually doesn't worry that much.
Scott: You know, I mean now how much can you worry when your husband is Superman, but you know, he's flying around You know the world saving people and stuff and he's not home all the time and he's always running off and you know But you get sucked into another dimension.
Scott: So then the mom is like I always worry when he gets sucked in another dimension and you see the mom being awesome Right, and then you're like, huh?
Scott: I wonder if they're gonna keep him sucked into that other dimension for how long?
Scott: and I wonder if he's ever gonna come back.
Scott: You know, are they gonna?
Scott: and I was like, huh?
Scott: If they had him die, that would be sort of obvious.
Scott: And then I'm like, oh they just had him show up, you know They're all and you know.
Scott: Then it would be also sort of lame though and it has brought him back at exactly the right time in a humorous fashion.
Rym: But the thing is other than that, I mean what else can I say?
Rym: It's funny.
Rym: It's clever.
Rym: It's cute.
Rym: I don't know if I'd read anymore.
Rym: I think I already got everything I could ever get out of this kind of comic.
Scott: Well, this is this isn't the kind of comic right?
Scott: There's some comics like.
Scott: they're so great All right that you just run out and get all of them and you read them all straight through right invincible You know, I don't think I'm gonna run out and get them all and read them straight through.
Scott: that seems like that Seems like a bad idea.
Scott: But I mean if I was sitting around going like doo doo doo doo and I felt like just a fun comic, you know And I didn't have one available.
Scott: I might be like, huh?
Scott: I could use something fun right now.
Scott: Maybe I'll go by the second one and see if it's it's as fun as the first one.
Rym: It doesn't have a lot of those little you know comic book cameos.
Rym: I mean the nerd that gets beat up in the beginning is clearly Steve Urkel and later on you see like Charlie Brown walking by.
Scott: Yeah, you know funny.
Scott: So it's just totally you know fun.
Scott: It's it's not serious.
Scott: It's just kind of hey, what's up?
Scott: Totally cool.
Rym: And say it's worth reading.
Rym: Yeah now Scott was amazed when I came back and said hey, I liked it.
Rym: Yeah, so we handed me this Marvel team up and said if you like that you like this right.
Scott: so Marvel team up is written By also what we're talking about.
Scott: There's.
Scott: no there's more than one Marvel team up here.
Scott: There's the old Marvel team up from way back in the day.
Scott: Don't read that.
Scott: There's a new Marvel team up.
Scott: It's relatively new.
Scott: it was from a few years ago right and You can buy it is in four trade paperbacks the whole series and it's also written by Robert Kirkman and it's sort of a fun Superhero book.
Scott: and the first I read the first two volumes and then it took a while before the third and the fourth volumes came out.
Scott: so, you know, that's I sort of read it that way.
Scott: and The first two volumes I think you know in my opinion They're a lot like invincible only they have Marvel superheroes instead of you know Original invincible superheroes.
Rym: see I guess the thing that I guess got me about is that on the surface that might seem true But if I read it, it's so.
Rym: it takes itself seriously.
Scott: I think in the starting around the the third volume is because the third volume is way different than the first and second.
Scott: Right, it sort of takes out this big tangent and then the fourth one sort of ties them together and kind of an airway It's just.
Rym: it's.
Rym: so I don't know what I never really liked the whole the Marvel Universe.
Rym: There's a billion superheroes and they all know each other and there's a billion super villains.
Rym: I'll see that they all know each other and they all fight with each other and Like they fight a green guy and then someone who's news like is that the Hulk and spider-man is like no you dumbass That's so-and-so from such-and-such.
Rym: It's not the Hulk because of blah.
Scott: See, that's why I kind of like the more at least the first two volumes of this Marvel team-up is because it's sort of.
Scott: It takes the mark, you know normal Marvel Comics take themselves like 10,000 times more seriously, right?
Scott: So it's just sort of like poking fun at you know, like it at the other Marvel Comics in a way But at the same time it's just having fun like it's like yeah, we don't need to worry about you know bullshit.
Scott: But it also it's sort of like a truth in advertising kind of thing, you know.
Scott: It's like you read another Marvel comic that takes itself so seriously, right?
Scott: but it doesn't make sense.
Scott: because like if Really you expect me to believe that all these serious comics what you're saying is right Then that means there must be like a bajillion superheroes flying all over New York all the time, but we don't see that.
Scott: So it's like the serious comic doesn't make sense.
Scott: So in this non serious Marvel team-up It's like they're just superheroes all over New York knowing each other as they should.
Scott: So it's it's sort of a weird thing and where yes, it takes itself less seriously yet somehow It makes more sense.
Scott: And that is that is why I find at least the first two volumes of it enjoyable Yeah, but at the same time I feel like it just takes itself too.
Rym: Seriously.
Rym: There's too much of that.
Rym: I'm a superhero giving my monologue before the other guy describes what he's about to do and then does it.
Scott: I don't really notice that so much.
Rym: There was a lot of.
Rym: there's a lot of needless exposition and expounding on the behalf of characters talking about what happened.
Rym: And well, I'm gonna do this.
Scott: a few things that did but I mean, it's not as it's not perfect.
Scott: I mean a few things that bothered me in.
Scott: it were like, you know, it's Marvel team-up, right?
Scott: So it's all about you know characters teaming up.
Scott: But really they should have just had it be spider-man teaming up with different people because it when spider-man leaves like that because the most Fun part of the book is spider-man wisecracking at everybody.
Scott: All right, I always think that's funny when it's written.
Rym: Well, yeah Wasn't that funny?
Rym: It was kind of pedestrian.
Scott: Well, I like his wisecrack and I also like how.
Scott: it's just sort of like, you know, his life is kind of rough.
Scott: It's like I'm gonna beat up some guys.
Scott: I dropped my donuts god damn it.
Rym: I just because a lot of the plot kind of behind that is so Serious compared to something like invincible where the way it was handled was a lot lighter.
Rym: I didn't I couldn't get into it at all and I find myself just glazing over these long long speeches.
Rym: that people give Really notice that many long speeches going on like this kid here the kid who was the killer right in the beginning with his weird Power at the hands.
Scott: and all I thought I like I liked how when they revealed that that you know They give you this kid who's central to like the first story, right?
Scott: He's like a mutant and he's got crazy powers.
Scott: So they're trying to you know, like, you know, keep him from being too dangerous.
Scott: and you're like, oh, you know.
Scott: And at first it seems like he's innocent.
Scott: He doesn't realize he's all powerful and you know He's just sort of like a victim of his own mutant stuff.
Scott: and maybe they'll get him hooked up with the x-men.
Scott: It'll be.
Rym: it was done.
Rym: Well when he's like you should look in the other rooms, too.
Scott: Yeah I like.
Rym: at the same time that was serious and the rest of it like it.
Rym: just it didn't fit with what I wanted I guess.
Rym: Oh, well, it's like there's an example of what I don't like about these Marvel superhero the comics with these team-ups and whatever.
Rym: Quoth Wolverine after a bunch of people were looking at him on the bus.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah Wolverine on the bus I mean, come on was hilarious.
Scott: Come on Wolverine on the bus.
Rym: That was great And I was this guy.
Scott: that's that's the thing is like Wolverine can't fly, right?
Scott: He doesn't have the blackbird or anything cuz he's nice in New York.
Scott: He's not in the new x-men.
Rym: She's also on everyone's teams who has to get around to like all these places.
Rym: all the right.
Scott: So, you know and that's what happens in a serious Marvel Comics.
Scott: So in his non serious one, right?
Scott: They take.
Scott: well, what would be true?
Scott: Wolverine would take the bus.
Scott: So it's like the thing that makes sense is humorous, especially because this one guy's looking at him.
Rym: He's like, what are you looking at?
Rym: It's healing already.
Rym: Yeah Yep, but then he gets off the bus and he says all of the following in one speech bubble Frigging bolded tourists.
Scott: No, it does have some bolding in there.
Rym: act like they'd never seen a superhero before.
Rym: I saw Nova fly by bolded twice while we were on the bus.
Rym: This is bolded New York.
Rym: for Pete's sake you can't buy a bag without bumping into bolded speedball or bolded Darkhawk.
Rym: now Why?
Rym: Did he have to say all of that when he could have just said friggin tourists like these extra words?
Rym: I would bother me about superhero comics and - why did he have to name three proper nouns?
Rym: Superheroes, it's like they named these three superheroes Just to get the people who know the universe and like those three superheroes to go.
Rym: Ah, he said the name of the superhero.
Rym: I like it's anime-con name a Pokemon syndrome.
Scott: It does.
Scott: it is in there.
Rym: I hate that.
Rym: like it stands out so shallowly and it bothers me so much.
Scott: Yeah I guess it.
Scott: I guess it stands out a little less to me because if you read the really old comic books like you read Some Stan Lee's that is like times a billion.
Scott: so I know I don't read them I know.
Scott: so when you read this one you barely even notice it.
Scott: It's it's totally relative.
Scott: But yeah invincible you know is the same feeling.
Scott: only I guess it doesn't have that because it's not a Marvel or a DC book.
Rym: I don't know the only point.
Rym: I mean I read I'd like the first one for about 20 pages and I kind of phased out and I skipped the third one after trying to read it.
Rym: And then the fourth one was I like the ring thing at the end when the guy cool guy has the ring And he does what any cool guy would do.
Rym: But then they kind of superhero comic.
Rym: if I it and it goes nowhere.
Rym: I was interested in.
Rym: there's all this epic Superhero crap and I yeah.
Scott: when they're like all out in the middle of nowhere and his giant bat Yeah, that was kind of a. I didn't like that.
Rym: none of that was like.
Rym: wow just superheroes and underwear perfect costumes fighting.
Rym: It's lost all the charm.
Rym: I don't care about all this plot.
Rym: Why is everyone so serious then?
Rym: at the very end they kind of redeem it with an okay joke.
Scott: yeah But I definitely think Marvel team up.
Scott: the first two volumes are where it shines and volume three is the crapper in.
Scott: volume four Is a little bit better than the crapper, but yeah, it's the same thing anyway.
Scott: Do you wanna tell anything else?
Rym: no?
Rym: I think we're done here.
Scott: That was pretty quick.
Rym: Not really.
Rym: no no all right.
Rym: standard GeekNights episode.
Scott: Okay good thing else is I'll try I'll watch an anime for next week.
Scott: I guess all right.
Scott: I don't know when though cuz he'd be doing this comic-con all weekend on the train.
Rym: That's how I watch all of like all these shows.
Scott: Then I got to bring my optical drive.
Scott: Yeah, well not for the fansubs bokurano and tokiwakakator shoujo And I don't have the fansubs for any of those again, but my I only have a flash drive in my laptop.
Scott: I can't fit them all.
Rym: all of bokurano was like four gigs.
Scott: That's a lot.
Rym: take half at a time.
Rym: So hard to watch anime these days it takes so long to watch it, but it's good.
Rym: You could watch an equal volume of comics in the same time And actually I can read really fast.
Scott: That's the thing plus.
Scott: You know it's like okay.
Scott: I kind of want to watch bokurano.
Scott: I want to read the books I'm reading more.
Rym: oh the bridge of nothing books that you wouldn't read for so long and now you're finally reading.
Scott: well Come on you keep.
Scott: everyone keeps saying Scott read this Scott watch that Scott read this guy watch that.
Scott: I don't say no I say later, but you know what.
Rym: you know what you know What.
Scott: instead now is later for that stuff?
Scott: You told me to watch months ago, so you're gonna have to wait months through.
Rym: I do you know instead of reading this and watching that you read things like Marvel team up.
Scott: I read that even way before.
Rym: it's not that good wasn't worth it.
Scott: Yeah, it was good.
Rym: Avatar is much better than Marvel team up.
Rym: Objective scale.
Scott: no no see the thing is.
Scott: you tell me to watch and read and you know such and play more things Than I have time to do.
Scott: so they build up.
Scott: So you can't tell me to watch something and expect it to happen soon.
Scott: It's gonna happen eventually.
Scott: you know what I'm gonna after I finish reading these things.
Scott: I'm gonna read and watch something you told me to watch months ago.
Scott: great That's how we gonna review things the things you tell me to watch months ago.
Rym: I don't even know.
Rym: yeah You know what months ago cause I know you Jimbo.
Scott: Yeah, which you still haven't watched.
Scott: I'm gonna watch it as soon as they finish reading this stuff.
Scott: Yeah great code to one thing at a time.
Rym: people This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback Via audio.
Scott: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.