Rym: It's Wednesday August 20th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight after our week at the beach We return to bring you our somewhat haphazard coverage of Otakon 2008.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Well here it is the moment the night.
Rym: You've all been waiting for.
Rym: it's finally the Otakon coverage that I'm sure a lot of new listeners have been asking about waiting for looking for.
Scott: yeah We really kind of stink at this Otakon coverage because first of all it always comes way after Otakon.
Scott: It's already been like a week and a half since I ended a week and a half right and We don't cover any of the news or anything that actually happened there.
Rym: so much because it is the rationale for that.
Rym: I mean we go to all these conventions And we could do that.
Rym: the report of and such and such company licensed such and such and then so and so said that they were going to license such and such.
Rym: but You get that on the anime news network, and what are we gonna say?
Rym: well that show was good?
Rym: And that show was bad, and I don't know why they license that show, but you get that from us anyway, so Yeah, I don't know.
Scott: It's it's more of a Review of.
Scott: you know what it was like at Otakon.
Rym: Well that is that is convention coverage to me.
Scott: when someone says they're coming as we've done that show We've done me what it was like an Otakon show two or three times already yeah, and every year It's different.
Rym: I guess I think so.
Scott: It's a little bit different plus.
Rym: We have a lot of new people.
Rym: I mean we have more new listeners than we had listeners from previous Otakons.
Scott: I hope so.
Scott: Anyway, so before we do that should we do some non Otakon news and such?
Rym: well We should at least you know.
Rym: blah blah blah.
Rym: This is GeekNights I'm sure you.
Rym: I'm glad you finally found our website.
Rym: you listen to us.
Rym: you saw our panels whatever.
Rym: if You really want those lists of anime you should see or the creators or all that we're gonna put together something.
Scott: Yeah, we promised like some stuff to people who came to our panels like we did an anime You should see panel, and it was like.
Scott: yeah, we'll put a list of anime You should see on a website somewhere cuz we know you haven't been writing it down and well We'll get around to it.
Rym: I think I've got about half of it done because I'm making a good slideshow to use that.
Scott: future cons where we've been asked to Do this actually just upgraded our the WordPress you know so that it would work with the iPhone app You know.
Scott: so we'll be able to do a little bit more until I eventually redo the site completely when we'll be able to do anything we want.
Scott: and In addition anyone who is not in the forums you should join them.
Scott: I mean if you're listening to this right now that means you're a listener of GeekNights.
Scott: Why aren't you in the forum?
Rym: talking might just be people who are like?
Rym: Oh Otakon coverage and all the other Otakon coverage is gone, and I'm bored, and I'm looking forward to the next Otakon.
Rym: Oh my gosh.
Scott: Well if that's the case you're awesome because you have found the best Otakon coverage in the universe.
Scott: And now that you found it and you realize that you have stumbled into this world of the most amazing podcast Why would you not want to join the forum of this amazing show?
Rym: Anyway, so yes well I mean just so.
Rym: you know the way the show works the way we do this every night for the last six hundred or so Episodes is we talk about the news a little bit.
Rym: We have a little bit called things of the day Which if you can't figure out what what that is then you might have some problems with the rest of our show.
Rym: And then we talk about what we're talking about.
Rym: and tonight We're talking about Otakon, but before that I want to talk a little bit about the New York Anime Festival.
Scott: When is that?
Rym: that is actually at the end of September.
Rym: in fact it is specifically September 26th 27th and 28th.
Rym: and Jacob Javits Center in New York City.
Rym: ah We got plenty of time.
Rym: It's still.
Scott: it's too close.
Rym: It's several weeks after Pax.
Rym: I think we'll live plus live.
Rym: MC Chris is going to be there.
Scott: Oh that helps me out of it.
Rym: Yeah, you never actually saw him in concert.
Rym: I'm curious if he's the man the same set that he's done before.
Rym: if he's going to do something new he could do any set.
Scott: He could just get up there and give me the finger and walk off and obviously that.
Rym: but anyway for one The New York anime festival.
Rym: we're going to be there.
Rym: We're doing a ton of panels.
Rym: We're actually we are doing the final.
Rym: This is it.
Rym: It is never going to be run again.
Rym: Gekiga panel there Saturday night first off.
Scott: Yeah, we're only going to be there Saturday.
Scott: We're not going to go Sunday or Friday.
Rym: So if you for whatever reason have heard of the infamy of the Gekiga panel that we've run at other Conventions like Otakon or Katsucon this is your last chance to see it And I don't want to run it again because I don't want to get any more hate mail.
Scott: Yeah, we're pretty much we're going to start with.
Scott: you know We basically I think we decided we're going to come with new panels every year and then retire them.
Scott: So if you go to any of the conventions we go to odds are you can you'll get a chance to see most of the panels For the year, you know depending on what that convention wants.
Scott: But we're not going to run any you know Say the same panel at the same convention.
Scott: two times now We did actually is the one time where the rule is sort of being broken because I thought the Gekiga panel was retired But the New York Indian festival really wanted us to run it.
Scott: It was really even though we ran it last year.
Rym: But here's the thing you know.
Rym: we the Gekiga panel has like all these different levels I mean we every con we're like.
Rym: alright We can run this anywhere from PG-13 to beyond the beyond quintuple X and boom.
Rym: We ran it as the kind of PG-13.
Rym: you know this is purely educational and not so much hilarious And not so.
Rym: it was like a Friday morning panel to wasn't at the New York anime festival and you know that's what they wanted.
Rym: and apparently they heard tell of the the epicness that was this panel at Otakon and Katsucon and they asked us all right.
Rym: Can you run the Otakon one here, and I said no We're willing however to run the Katsucon one there.
Rym: yep, I don't want to fly Gerald out to show us that thing again.
Scott: No, I don't want to see that thing again.
Rym: That was one of the worst things I ever seen.
Scott: it was also funny, but also the worst thing I ever seen.
Scott: I think that was the most offensive and it's like take this stinkiest poop in the world But then put a smiley face sticker on it.
Scott: It doesn't reduce the stinkiest Wasn't poop.
Rym: it was an eyeball.
Rym: That's all right.
Rym: and a tree.
Rym: the tree was pretty good though.
Scott: Yeah, we're gonna do the tree.
Rym: we are gonna do the tree all right anyway.
Rym: But there's other news about the New York anime festival And this is the main reason I'm bringing this up because there's plenty of time before the con to actually talk about the con But Hideyuki Kikuchi is the creator of Vampire Hunter D. You may have heard of him.
Scott: I thought you should talk.
Scott: Amano was the creator of Vampire Hunter D.
Rym: No actually this guy wrote the novel.
Rym: ah Okay, he created Vampire Hunter D. Amano just gave him.
Scott: so is his idea to put the eyeballs in the hand or the mouth in the hand?
Rym: I have never actually read them on the novel, so I don't know exactly.
Scott: I know it's for sale in English.
Scott: Maybe you should buy it.
Rym: I should I just I haven't read it.
Rym: I don't know why.
Rym: all right, but he's done a bunch of other stuff.
Rym: I mean he's done a lot of work.
Rym: I don't want to get into all these things like you did the original manga for like Wind of Amnesia Which oh I want to read that was a really good anime that suddenly turned pornographic.
Rym: did it Remember that?
Rym: you realize that they showed it on sci-fi?
Rym: I was like all right, but I rented it later to show my parents.
Scott: Wasn't that the one that was all sort of pastel and kind of wiggly?
Rym: it was the one.
Rym: where are I humanity?
Rym: Aliens come down take away all of mankind's memory and the deal is They're trying to test to see if mankind at its core is good or bad.
Rym: And if they're good great memories back.
Rym: if they're bad destroy the planet.
Rym: move on.
Scott: well That's not the one that's.
Rym: I'm thinking of a different show that involved win, but then at the end they all have sex.
Rym: Okay, yes, so I didn't see this coming and I'm my mom's watching it with me, and she's like all right I can.
Rym: these these cartoons aren't as weird as I thought.
Rym: that's a nipple.
Rym: He's low.
Rym: This is why you watch these.
Scott: She didn't believe you for shit.
Rym: but He wrote a bunch of little stories and a bunch of other things, but one thing in particular that he wrote has never been published Anywhere in English or Japanese in English or Japanese in America or Japan not even in moon language.
Rym: He was doing this conference in Japan, and he wrote a short story entitled entitled the wanderers ship for end.
Rym: He gave the publishing rights to one of his fans.
Rym: Just because he's a really nice guy.
Scott: wow that's sort of crazy.
Rym: So one thing led to another man.
Scott: if I was if I was a crazy writer or something I would like write little tiny things create tiny works and just give them out to fans.
Scott: You have the rights to this.
Scott: you have the rights to this.
Scott: you know that'd be crazy awesome.
Rym: so yasue hitomi who had the rights took it and Gave it gave the the New York anime festival the right to publish it for the first time ever in The con book at the New York anime in the con book.
Scott: oh, man No one's gonna be throwing that shit away.
Rym: I'm really excited about that's.
Scott: that's pretty good.
Rym: The thing is this is the kind of thing a lot you people who read the Anime news network might have seen that headline and gone.
Rym: ah no the story is much more interesting than you might have thought.
Scott: Wow, that's pretty good.
Scott: I'm suddenly like I read that headline, and I was like a man, but now you tell me the story And I'm like oh shits.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: He will act.
Rym: I mean he will be at the convention.
Scott: I might take two of those.
Rym: him and Yoshitaka Amano are going to be together.
Rym: add to the convention.
Rym: in fact He's having a birthday party there.
Scott: Well.
Scott: It's the writers birthday party.
Scott: yes, man I should get him to write a story.
Scott: give me the publishing rights And then get a monitor to illustrate it.
Scott: then get the publishing rights to that and then I won't have to work anymore.
Rym: now Obviously it is going to be published in Japan after the fact.
Scott: I'm sure I'm sure Japanese wouldn't stand for that.
Rym: I think this is really cool because that is way cool Especially since vampire hunter D in particular.
Rym: that was the first anime I ever saw.
Rym: that that got me into anime.
Rym: the reason I'm here talking about anime the reason I go to these conventions all of it Because of a vampire where the mouth in his hand that mouth in the hand was the snarkiest coolest hippest mouth in a hand ever.
Scott: It's one of the only mouths at hand ever.
Rym: There's been a couple more man we should make.
Scott: I just thought what if you had mouth in a hand, but also eyeball from Gitaro and Thing from Adams family and all the sort of body part creatures together.
Scott: That's called a person and it does know.
Rym: but like you have all those characters together and like a doujinshi You know, it could be like that gonna guide Chibi Kara world except not stupid exactly.
Scott: Anyway, is that all you got to say?
Rym: That's all I got to say.
Rym: So, all right.
Scott: well as people may or may not know all the anime news that we can get because we speak English it comes to man in the news network calm and
Rym: Anime news
Scott: network calm has this habit of whenever the USA today book list comes out if there are any mangas on it They tell you about it.
Scott: So for many many weeks, they'd be like, you know Naruto volume 29 is number six on graphic novels.
Scott: it.
Scott: Well first it was like, you know, it's number ten on the book list.
Scott: Then it was number three on the graphic novels book list, you know.
Scott: and now All mod is no manga on the USA today book list.
Scott: Not even the graphic novels book list anymore.
Scott: So now they've resorted to saying hey, you know what Naruto volume 30 Is number three on the you know direct market Best-selling graphic novel.
Scott: All right, so that means in comic book stores Naruto volume 30 is number three.
Scott: So if you judge that really that doesn't tell you anything about the manga market as a whole But it tells you that the big hitting manga their sales are decreasing relative to the sales of other Graphic novels and other books in regular bookstores.
Rym: now, this is why I feel like the time is ripe To take the weird stuff from Japan the golf monger from going it, you know All those sorts of things and bring them out in America.
Scott: I know I got.
Scott: I got.
Scott: two other sort of combined news is here.
Scott: I don't think they tie in that much but here we go ready.
Scott: So it's a gumi Oba and Takeshi Obata the creative team of Death Note, you know One of whom is an anonymous person who has only done Death Note.
Scott: It's totally L I know and the other person is the person who created the art for her car.
Scott: no go and some other awesome things Right.
Scott: They're making something new called bakuman Uh-huh, and it's actually it's about making manga or something.
Scott: But anyway Bakuman you can read it right now But it's not in the store.
Scott: It's also this price scan.
Scott: I don't know if there's cancellations or not, but legally you can read it right now.
Scott: Because if you go to jump land calm, which is the official, you know shonen jump Kind of website put up by Shueisha, you know, the Japanese publisher of shonen jump.
Scott: they have bakuman available there digitally in English French German and Japanese and You basically download this file and then you download the little reader and you can read it in English.
Rym: Wait, so I need a file and a reader.
Scott: they give you the reader for free.
Rym: But why?
Rym: I mean, what kind of format?
Rym: I'm just curious.
Scott: It's it's some kind of weird file format.
Scott: I downloaded it just before I came in this room and I didn't actually open it yet.
Rym: so I can't tell you what it's like because I was curious if maybe it's like.
Rym: this reader is some sort of Optimized for reading manga thing.
Scott: It might be but bakuman actually began and showed and jump like in early august.
Scott: So there are probably cancellations also that you can read if you don't like this particular reader.
Scott: But you know you can.
Scott: here we go in English Translated a manga that's coming out right now by a hit team and it's it's in four languages English French German Japanese Is a big move.
Scott: now, there's another similar big move that's going down, right?
Scott: Yoshitoshi Abe Serial experiments lane, you know him also does some stuff in robot.
Scott: What.
Rym: that's an interesting way of putting that.
Scott: yeah, um He made a doujinshi, you know a lot of that's.
Scott: the one thing is that people don't seem to understand is that um, you know Doujinshi isn't just.
Scott: you know, I take naruto and make it porn and put it out there.
Rym: That's only like 98 of it, right?
Scott: That's only 98 Actual real creators, you know professional creators in japan make doujinshi sometimes.
Rym: I mean for example, I have you know The azumanga guy azuma.
Rym: I have a doujinshi.
Rym: he did Of tenji muyo and it's hilarious, right?
Scott: And it's not always a fan, you know parody of of an existing work.
Scott: Sometimes it's an original thing.
Scott: I mean, you know in this in the united states, right?
Scott: Let's say I get a job for dc comics and i'm the guy who makes superman.
Scott: I write it and I draw it, right?
Scott: Let's say i'm frank miller.
Scott: I wish right.
Scott: Uh, i'm doing batman or something.
Scott: If I just decide if I decide to go and make some comic on my own Not for any company just for myself right and put it out there.
Scott: It's called sin city in the united states and it someone picks it up and publishes it.
Scott: But in japan if you go if you're even if you're a professional if you just go out and make something on your own You know, you don't have a publisher tell you to make it or you don't put it in a manga magazine You just sell it at comic cat.
Scott: Uh, that's called the doujinshi even if it's not Parodying or using characters from existing works or anything.
Scott: All right, so yoshizobi toshiabe made this doujinshi called pochiama at the pharmacy.
Scott: pochiama at the pharmacy Is 53 pages and you can buy it in 20 countries In the itunes app store for five bucks or equivalent.
Scott: I bought it.
Scott: I got it on the iphone And I tried to read it and you know what?
Scott: It's not.
Scott: uh, I don't.
Scott: I didn't read more than a couple pages of it So I can't tell you if the manga is good or not.
Scott: But I can tell you is that the translation is terrible.
Scott: Really?
Scott: Oh, it's bad.
Rym: I was expecting this build up to be that it's great.
Scott: Oh Oh the translation it's like it might as well be bootlegs from southeast asia.
Scott: Because at a time like this even at a time like this It is a bad trend.
Scott: and the other thing about it right is basically what it's the software that they've built this on.
Scott: Uh, it seems like the way it works Is they erase they have the images and you can zoom and pan and that's all good.
Scott: The images are fine With the text.
Scott: the way it seems to work, you know My programmer's intuition looking at the interface of a program and then determining how it works underneath Is that in addition to all these image files they have text and then they have you know?
Scott: location on the page And so the font of the text.
Scott: it really doesn't fit in with the images around it and it sort of Crappily fits in the bubbles.
Scott: Sometimes it sticks out and it looks kind of dumb and it's.
Scott: it's not so great, but You know 58 pages a month 53 pages of manga for five bucks on your iphone or ipod touch.
Scott: He's trying something, you know, you know, and this it actually, you know I read two pages of it and there were some funny jokes in there because he could.
Scott: you can't understand what's going on You know, but it's just a little bit painful with the bad translation at least into english.
Scott: It's been translated into 19 other languages too.
Scott: So who knows about those?
Rym: You know what?
Rym: They probably did.
Rym: is they just translated from each language into every other language?
Rym: and english was like the eighth one along the way.
Rym: Who knows who knows?
Scott: The point is is they're adding a whole bunch of other Uh mangas to the uh, ab store in japan also with bad translations in america I don't know in japan, but the other ones don't have translations at least not yet.
Scott: So You know, if you're if you like yoshitoshi habe which I do, you know if you want to spend I would wait if the translation's bad.
Scott: Yeah, if you want to spend five bucks on a bad translation on your iphone.
Scott: go for it.
Scott: I just did it mostly not because I actually wanted it but because I wanted to report on it, you know It's like the same reason.
Scott: I just bought four ssh clients for the iphone So I could report on which one was the best.
Scott: one of them is useless.
Scott: The other ones are all good and bad simultaneously.
Scott: So there's.
Scott: no there's no one good one not yet But it looks like one of them is the next version is going to be the good one, but it's not out yet.
Rym: Anyway enough of that.
Rym: we should get right into things of the day so we can actually talk about odecan for a while.
Rym: So my thing of the day luckily is from odecan.
Rym: You see the last panel we did it wasn't actually our panel.
Rym: It was you know a front row crew panel, but it was katsu doing his kendo panel.
Rym: and katsu does one hell of a kendo panel.
Rym: He does it like every count we go to now and it's always great.
Rym: but uh there was some unfinished business with kendo and maybe I was the undefeated vice president of the kendo club at rit who had never actually attended a meeting and never actually accepted the challenge.
Rym: and uh That ended and I present to you the video of me dying.
Rym: Oh my god, is he fast?
Scott: Is that it?
Rym: that's it?
Rym: This isn't?
Rym: we have a better video of this.
Rym: In fact, we have two videos of this but Someone else in the audience captured a third video and since it's already on youtube I figured I would just use it.
Scott: All right, so check this out, you know, you go to websites maybe our forums maybe you know Twitter something else and a lot of these sites now, especially the social networking sites They need you to have an avatar.
Scott: maybe you know I mean it started with buddy icons and aim but now you need an avatar all over the place And a lot of people don't have a good photo of themselves.
Scott: So someone made this website.
Scott: face your manga.com and it's basically an avatar generator.
Scott: It's sort of like a me kind of thing where you you know, choose eyes choose nose choose hair But it makes a manga style you and no matter what combination you pick.
Scott: It looks really good and it's it's really really slick.
Scott: It's like amazing professional website.
Scott: It's free to make an avatar on there.
Scott: Uh, there's.
Scott: I think you can pay for some other shit, but whatever Go there face your manga.com.
Rym: so otakon 2008. now We've realized it's it's often difficult for us to do our reviews or coverage of a lot of conventions because Not so much otakon but like ConnectiCon or often Katsucon we basically are staffed the whole time and as a result our Our perspective is kind of skewed toward the things we do.
Rym: because you see When you really think about it And this is something I didn't realize when I first started going to fan conventions not just anime but any sort of convention That it's such a different experience depending on like where you are and what your function is and why you're there.
Rym: I mean if i'm a dealer and I go to an anime con I have a completely different experience from a fan Or from someone in the artist alley or from a guest or from a staffer or from a press guy Or from a hobo out in the street.
Scott: Yep, I mean you Listeners.
Scott: most likely you are going to a convention as an attendee.
Scott: You want to go to events?
Scott: You want to go to dealer's room?
Scott: You want to go to things and experience them.
Scott: then you paid to get in?
Scott: Or maybe you go to artist alley and sit at a table for most of the con but you still go around and experience stuff.
Scott: We do something else and it's very unlikely that you will be doing the thing that we did If you go to any of these conventions.
Scott: So it's not really helping you to review the convention if we tell you what it was like for us Because that's not what it's going to be like for you.
Scott: It's going to be completely different.
Rym: But at the same time I remember the window when I first realized like I really realized this I became fascinated with.
Rym: it was a friend of ours.
Rym: they actually, you know, they're they're dealers in a lot of the conventions and we talked to them a lot and We were we're in a con one day and we use our press badges and we got in early and we're hanging out in the dealer's Room talking to these people and it was interesting, you know They were telling us about you know loading and getting the dock set up and sitting in the dealer's room all day and dealing with a shoplifter and All the kind of details and stuff that you never even think of.
Rym: you go to a con.
Rym: Oh the dealer's room i'll buy that and i'll buy that and i'll buy this and then.
Rym: but Actually talking to someone who sat there and did this completely different.
Rym: We're both at the same convention for the whole weekend and yet they basically were at a different convention.
Rym: They were at the sit in a small box yelling at kids convention.
Scott: Yep So we're going to try to do this otakon review instead of just telling you what we did in chronological order Which is our typical convention review style.
Scott: I mean we've done two otakon reviews in this style.
Scott: If you like that style, you can go listen to the old ones because really if we did it for this one It wouldn't be that much different.
Scott: It would be different but not that much different.
Rym: Well, it'd be different.
Rym: in regards that I mean in previous otakons We actually did a lot more things at the con as fans.
Rym: I would go to panels to see what was going on And actually sit through them.
Rym: I'd go to the rave and dance for like an hour, you know all the stuff that you're supposed to do with the con.
Rym: We don't have time for that anymore.
Rym: No
Scott: So now we're going to try to review the con by telling you we're going to go through all the different Perspectives of people at the con and tell you what it was like from that perspective and obviously some of those perspectives aren't ours But we talked to people while we were there and we can make educated guesses and all such and such and such.
Scott: So let's start with the perspective of the special guests the super people who come to the con perhaps the musical guests?
Scott: Okay, they have no idea what it's like to be them.
Scott: They're super rich and famous and everyone goes.
Rym: Uh, actually just having work staff at other cons the way that works is pretty much you fly in and you're picked up by a con staffer who you know introduces you and drives you to the con and They basically take care of you for the whole weekend and then they make sure you get on your flight home.
Rym: Yeah If you're an american voice actor you then proceed to go and get totally smashed And then come back to the con drunk and sit on one of our panels randomly.
Scott: One thing I can definitely say though is that the special guests at this convention or at least there were many special guests But the most special of guests at this Otakon was jam project the musical act.
Scott: I think one of their members is missing I'm, not sure And I didn't actually get to go to the concert because we had a panel during it.
Scott: Otherwise, I would have gone All right, so I don't know what it was like, but I heard only good things.
Rym: I can say this there were a lot of people who were really like they.
Rym: they either weren't aware of the concert Even though they were at the convention or they just they're like, yeah It's not really up my alley and I actually spent much of friday at all our panels and everything I could do Telling people look go to the concert.
Rym: Trust me.
Rym: Oh my god, it's in the arena.
Rym: It's a real concert live music And every one of these people came back to our table at some point during the con the next day basically saying That was one of the best cons.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: I I can't believe I was thinking of not going.
Scott: Yeah It was surprising.
Scott: i'd go to a panel and i'd say who here's going to the concert tomorrow And like not many people raise their hands and be like what the hell is wrong with you?
Scott: You don't have a panel to run during the concert.
Scott: Why are you going to it?
Scott: don't come to my stupid panel, but um We actually walked in on the bandai surprise panel and the bandai surprise was lucky star shirts And jam project and I was only in there for maybe a minute But I could totally tell the jam project was living it up and hanging loose and they were just oh, man They they totally.
Scott: there is no doubt that they had a wicked awesome time and they were just letting it all hang out.
Rym: Because I know I mean they.
Rym: they did a full concert in the arena.
Rym: and the thing is Before larku came a few years ago and they did a full concert in the arena and I remember that they had a crazy awesome time and they that was like the best thing ever for them.
Rym: and These arena concerts I know are very taxing on the odicon staff and on the odicon budget and everything.
Rym: but at the same time They're so amazing and I think more than anything else These are starting to really make odicon stand out as like the ultimate anime convention.
Scott: Yep, I mean tmr sent a special message to odicon which the staff read to us at.
Scott: I think the closing ceremonies.
Rym: I don't have the text some other time.
Rym: It basically was like yeah, you guys are awesome.
Rym: I had a good time.
Rym: I want to come back someday.
Rym: Omg, lol.
Scott: Yeah, he's cool dude that tmr.
Scott: Yeah, he is.
Scott: All right.
Rym: So, uh, what are we going to start with?
Rym: I mean we can.
Rym: we already said everything about the guest and there's the low-level guest.
Rym: But it's not that different except people don't cater to your every whim And usually you disappear.
Rym: then they're looking for you.
Scott: Let's talk about the artist alley because we do spend a lot of time in the artist alley because we had a table there.
Rym: I mean, I remember how to go to early cons.
Rym: I'd be amazed that I had friends who would like show up at a con And thursday they'd set up in their artist alley and they would stay at their artist alley table through the entire con And then go home and they wouldn't go to anything.
Scott: and i'd be like, oh, how could you not go to anything?
Rym: So for one odicon's artist alley was handled Magnificently.
Rym: this as usual, I mean the staff are all right there and together everything was organized.
Rym: There was not a single problem with it at all.
Scott: You go up you sign up they get your table everything's set.
Scott: You can set up your stuff on thursday.
Scott: nice and easy.
Scott: You have plenty of time.
Scott: everything's all good in terms of setting your stuff up and doing your business.
Rym: and the thing is It seems this was the biggest and best Artist alley i've ever seen at an odicon.
Scott: the way they arranged those tables allowed for more Take more actual seats and tables than ever ever before and at the same time They eliminated.
Rym: the only problem with last year's artist alley was that there are too many people in it and you couldn't walk around.
Rym: Yep, this year the aisles were just big like they spread it out just enough to where it was perfect It was.
Scott: it was really nice and also the the.
Rym: the quality of the art every year just staggers me.
Rym: I mean, I cannot believe some of these people that are just sitting in the artist alley.
Scott: there was.
Scott: one thing is that it seemed like a lot of the booths there were.
Scott: they seemed to be all the same thing like Picture of a character and a gigantic print that was really on shiny glossy paper with shiny glossy printing.
Rym: Yeah, it seemed like it seems like the problem there was like at least 10 booths like that Those particular booths and luckily they were at the minority.
Rym: I mean most of the stuff there was either really interesting fan art or really good original art or just a lot of neat stuff.
Rym: one guy in the back, which is live djing through the whole thing, but those particular people it's like That fan art is almost I don't want to say obsolete.
Rym: But I mean, it's good art, but It doesn't really add anything to the character.
Rym: It's not like it's special It's just a good rendition of the character as though you would see an official merchandise stuff.
Scott: It's like xkcd.
Scott: right xkcd has no graphical art to it.
Scott: That's you know.
Scott: quality, you know, it's not bad But it's sick figures.
Rym: it is there are better stick figures than I can draw.
Scott: Yeah, it has something to it in its content.
Scott: in addition You know that in a lot of this art there a lot of these super glossy prints that a lot that these booths had Has art graphically but it doesn't have anything below the surface.
Scott: There's no heart in it.
Scott: There's no Life in it.
Scott: There's no content.
Scott: It's just a rendering of the character that's shiny and it's not so exciting.
Scott: But that's maybe 10 booths at most and most of the booths were not those.
Scott: but it was still kind of weird to see like You know so many, you know Because it's hard no matter where you look.
Scott: there would be one booth like that because there are hundreds of booths in artist alley.
Scott: But there would be one booth like that no matter where you looked and it was kind of like, uh, huh?
Rym: Yeah, and I really want to give shout outs, but I don't have time and I don't I have a list but There were a lot of cool people in that alley that we met.
Scott: All right, the one shout out I do want to.
Rym: you're gonna give it to the radish mart, aren't you?
Scott: You knew I was gonna give it to the radish mart, but I bought something from the radish mart.
Rym: What did you buy?
Rym: I bought a bookmark.
Scott: All right, you did.
Rym: It's a really good bookmark, too.
Rym: It's got the young radish the older radish and the rotten radish.
Scott: So check it out.
Scott: There's this one girl and she set up this booth.
Scott: That was the radish mart and she was just selling like stuffed radishes and bookmarks with pictures of radishes on them.
Scott: It wasn't really anything, you know complicated but the setup of the booth was like.
Scott: It was like oh my gosh she was wearing this costume of radish mart merchant and It was all these radishes and she had these buckets like with little wooden barrels.
Scott: and uh, but the thing is around the corner Was fake radish mart.
Rym: well fake radish studios because the deal is the artist there We've we talked a lot of these people and the story was that an anagram of her name is fake radish Which gave her the idea to have fake radish studios and then a radish mart.
Scott: The radish mart booth was just so.
Scott: I mean, I don't need a stuffed radish, but the radish mart booth makes you want one Desperately, they're really high quality too.
Rym: Like if you want a stuffed radish, I can't think of a better place to go.
Scott: But I mean just the presentation of the booth.
Scott: Oh my gosh.
Rym: Yeah, I mean I walked around.
Rym: I looked at every table.
Rym: Most of the art there was amazing.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Oh the art show the art show.
Scott: Uh, the art show every year is basically, you know, instead of selling an art at your table You can put it in the art show to have someone buy, you know The auction is a silent auction and then at the end if something gets seven bids It goes to the live auction on sunday.
Rym: now granted that a lot of people will put something in the art show nominally to sell It but mostly to get people to see it and then find them in the artist alley and buy prints.
Scott: Yep, it sort of works both ways.
Rym: I love the art show and this year actually was better than last year.
Scott: It was much better than last.
Rym: It was a good art show.
Scott: There was a lot of really interesting stuff in there And for the first time I won something in the art show.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah scott bought this really cute thing.
Rym: What's it from?
Scott: I think it's from something called hat.
Scott: I didn't know it was from something until after I bought it and there was a url on the bottom of it.
Scott: But it's a it's just.
Scott: basically it's a painting on a little canvas.
Scott: It's square and it's of something called the hatpire which is I guess is a vampire that wears a top hat.
Scott: But it's basically this little hatpire and he's swimming and there's like a big squid and it's just sort of like yay.
Scott: And uh, I it's.
Scott: it's the kind of painting you would hang up in the bathroom because it's just sort of watery and happy.
Rym: And and it was it was 15 bucks Despite all the good art in there.
Rym: I I have to mention as always the uh adult content area because Last year there was a grand total of one thing in there and that thing was the rod of light which was Basically a crudely drawn penis on a piece of lined paper highlighted.
Rym: It was a good time and it had a bit of a dollar and I remember last year on my oticon coverage I basically said You know, it would be hilarious if we took turns bidding it up so that it had to go into the auction.
Scott: That would be great.
Rym: Well this year I went in there to see just to see.
Scott: I was curious if there's anything you gotta go in for the lulls.
Scott: You don't go in to act for series you go in for lulls and also for another reason.
Rym: I wanted to prove something to myself that i'll talk about after this because I noticed a trend in the artist alley that is very heartening to me.
Rym: But anyway, I walk in there And the first thing I confronted with is actual pornography as in someone took a picture of themselves many pictures of themselves.
Rym: I I don't know.
Rym: I mean, I guess it wasn't against the rules and i'm sure the only reason it was in there is because what would be worse Than taking pictures of yourself and trying to sell it in an artist alley at a convention being denied that privilege.
Rym: Yeah But at the same time a little frightening it was.
Scott: it was pretty scary.
Scott: I mean, it wasn't super scary.
Scott: You'll easily find worse on the internets because you know, it's the internets.
Scott: everything is on there But it was kind of disturbing to see it in there.
Scott: It's like someone took pictures of themselves in you know, so it had nothing to do with geekery at all.
Scott: It was just someone took naked pictures of themselves in sort of scary.
Rym: I could have understood if it was cosplay.
Rym: Yeah, it wasn't.
Scott: it was just scary bondage whatever.
Rym: but while I My horrifying disappeared when I looked one step to the right and saw the dracula penis.
Rym: Ah the dracula penis which was in the same vein as the rod of light from the previous year.
Rym: It was probably by the same person but I have to say very very very very.
Scott: Dracula penis is the win.
Rym: It was bid all the way up and it went into the auction.
Rym: I I need to find the staffer who did the auction and find out what came of that.
Rym: Oh, really?
Rym: It was bid all the way up and you could see it was two people.
Rym: I don't know if they were inspired by us or if just the idea of getting that into the auction is so overpowered You just can't resist it.
Scott: This one thing is that the Otakon auction is not perfectly silent because you put you basically works with these barcode stickers.
Scott: It works really well.
Scott: You put the sticker on the bidding thing and it says bidder number like 1010 and then you're right in the dollar amount.
Scott: But someone can look at the bidding list and see you know 1010 2222 1010. they know that both of those visit the same person and thus the auction is not perfectly silent Which is fine because it allows the dracula penis to make it to the art auction.
Rym: Yes But and there were.
Rym: actually it was about 50 50 back there actual pornography versus Just kind of hilarious things that are.
Scott: obviously there's a sequel to the rod of light.
Rym: Yes, we've spent too much time talking about we have but here's the point I wanted to make.
Rym: the main reason I went back there was to see if this trend of I don't know.
Rym: It seems like there was almost a backlash Against the yaoi bs that has been pervading anime conventions for the past several years because there was less Less of that garbage to put it bluntly in the artist alley this year than there has ever been.
Rym: I mean it was there.
Rym: there were some slashy things.
Rym: There were some bl things but a lot of it was Light-hearted ironic or funny or actually very artistic and there was very little of that kind of scary.
Rym: You know You go to a lot of artist alleys and you just see people just porn porn porn porn porn porn porn porn And in the dealer's room porn porn porn.
Rym: But this year even in the dealer's room Not nearly so much porn and that yaoi guy wasn't yelling nearly as much as he usually does.
Scott: I don't think he was yelling at all.
Scott: At least I didn't.
Scott: I only went to the dealer's room once.
Rym: Yeah, I didn't hear him yell at all.
Rym: I was very thankful because I have horrible memories of being in the dealer's room and hearing that guy yell and then hearing girls scream just all day.
Rym: But really it seems like It's coming around and people are kind of sick of that stuff.
Rym: I it was a fad.
Rym: I can't.
Rym: i'm so happy that it was a fad.
Scott: Well, the artist alley kicked ass for you know People buying as well as people selling.
Scott: it was totally awesome.
Rym: You know to talk about the perspective of people sitting behind a table.
Rym: We noticed something interesting.
Rym: and there's another trend that I didn't quite expect.
Rym: By and large people do not buy prints of things anymore.
Scott: No, not a lot.
Rym: No just compared to.
Scott: I mean I bought one but they're not as much as they used to.
Rym: but come I mean in the back in the day.
Rym: I mean I remember people would bring you know 50 60 prints of something and sell out and it's I don't know if it's because of digital media because most of this art is available on people's deviant art sites.
Rym: now if You know, maybe it's the rit anime club wall scroll syndrome where we kind of we broke our local economy.
Rym: we had the golden ticket raffles where we would give away wall scrolls to members and Eventually all the hardcore members of the anime club had wall scrolls on every free space of wall in their dorm room And thus did not want to win another wall scroll.
Rym: Maybe people just ran out of space.
Rym: I have no idea.
Rym: but By and large and I talked to a lot of artists and they all said the same thing People are not buying prints as much as they used to.
Rym: what they are buying is social currency.
Rym: if you have a Sticker or a button or something that you can carry around or put on your badge or wear a t-shirt something that shows off Your geekery something you can say check me out.
Scott: I'm a fan of naruto cell phone charms Necklaces, you know anything that is wearable placeable doable usable anything like that?
Scott: Then people are buying.
Scott: if it's a print what can people do with it?
Scott: They put it in a folder to bring it home then they put it in a frame maybe in their house.
Scott: It's not really doing it.
Rym: in terms of the social I think what's really happened Is that back when I used to go to anime conventions?
Rym: If I saw a print or a piece of art in an artist alley that was really clever like wow That's hilarious.
Rym: or wow, that's really good.
Rym: I would buy it mostly to show to other people and for the novelty of it It's like check this out and I'd show it to people.
Rym: But seriously nowadays I can just go to whoever's deviantart and see everything.
Scott: Yeah, or if I see something at like an artist alley, that's really clever.
Scott: You know a lot of times it's clever things.
Scott: The art quality is not so great.
Scott: Like I saw there was uh, It was like was it a snoopy evangelical?
Scott: It was a snoopy lord of the rings mashup I think I saw and I basically just said hey look at that and pointed it out to people I knew who were also in The artist alley and thus there was no need to actually have it and bring it to show anybody.
Rym: So I guess people, you know If you want if you're in the artist alley and you want to sell stuff bring your art your art will sell.
Rym: and also It's not so much about selling anymore because a lot of people what they told me was that yeah people didn't buy prints But they took business cards and I made a bunch of friends and we traded a bunch of art.
Rym: Yeah, a lot of people were trading prints, but not actually buying and selling prints.
Scott: That's a lot of people do at mocha is they trade their mini comics.
Rym: That's always good times Yep, but you know if you're just if you want to sell stuff in an artist alley You've got the clever idea the print bring your prints make a bunch of friends.
Rym: But if you actually want to make money you have to make the clever social currency the clever t-shirt the space makeout button the things that are That in some way people will buy them because they can show off to other people at the con.
Rym: All right.
Scott: So for an attendee, that's that's the most important one, right?
Scott: What was it like there?
Rym: Well, well I guess we should start with the reg line because Has like the best reg lines of any convention ever.
Scott: Yeah the reg line was a little bit weird on thursday and that You know, it didn't.
Scott: usually it flies like you there'll be no line after like a couple hours.
Scott: There was actually a little bit of a line after a couple hours But then again, not that much of a line.
Rym: It was still a real quick.
Scott: It was very quick, but it wasn't stupid quick It was just.
Scott: but yes, it was definitely quick enough.
Scott: I did plenty quick.
Scott: I didn't
Rym: actually verify this with anyone but my guess is that Over the years more and more people are showing up thursday night Because there were a lot of people hanging out around the con thursday night way too many more than last year And
Scott: at the front of the reg line It was the same guy the army guy at the front of the reg line from last year.
Scott: He didn't die.
Rym: Yeah, remember the guy who we showed up?
Rym: We asked him why he was in line and his answer was basically that he was shipping out to iraq the next day But he wanted to be at odicon and be the first one in just because he loves odicon so much.
Scott: Yep, I didn't actually get to go talk to him But I did see him from afar and other people said he was there and well, uh, I have to take their word for it.
Rym: now.
Rym: the only issue really with reg, I mean panel registration all those sorts of things was fine, but Because we were pressed to this this is delving into us a little bit They had the special needs line, but the special needs line was basically for anyone with an issue anyone who couldn't just you know Walk up.
Rym: Here's my free reg.
Rym: Give me my badge.
Rym: They had to go into the special needs line now.
Rym: The idea was you can skip the real line and then have your problem dealt with.
Rym: But because everyone with a problem with it was in that line They didn't have a lot of staff over there.
Rym: They had a few staff who were very hard working, but I think they needed another special needs booth.
Rym: We got in that line because our press thing way back told us yes You have to go into this line, which we found out later.
Rym: We could have just not gotten into that line.
Rym: Yeah, but that's fine.
Rym: a staffer came and saved us.
Rym: He pulled us out and got us our badges, but We got into that line skipping the entire outside line.
Rym: Our friends with pre-reg badges got into the giant outside line.
Rym: Within a short span.
Rym: we saw them and their line get into the building get up get their badges and leave.
Rym: Meanwhile, we had moved four feet.
Scott: Yeah, it was not good.
Scott: Not good in the special needs line.
Scott: the special needs line needs two or three booths instead of one booth.
Rym: See my only real concern is that if I if I had been you know Someone who had a medical condition and you know, the idea was I don't I can't stand in this line I need my badge.
Rym: help me out.
Rym: It was faster to stand in the real line than it was to get into the special needs line.
Scott: Yeah, that's a problem.
Rym: But I mean that was the only complaint I could see.
Rym: other than that thursday night was super smooth.
Rym: Plus people who had odicon badges could go see a screening of I think it was tropic thunder a movie in the area Yeah, and that seemed to go real well.
Rym: a lot of people were real excited about that.
Rym: It gave people something to do on thursday.
Rym: Yeah It's a good tie-in and A lot of people say they want a four-day con again.
Rym: And i'm sure jim bowles if he's listening to this right now about had a heart attack at the mere mention.
Rym: But If odicon does this again make a deal with the area have local venues do stuff that is not directly related to odicon.
Rym: But you know, hey if you have an odicon badge happy hour at the local bar.
Rym: Hey, if you have an odicon badge, uh, there's a concert down at the power plant thursday night, you know Something like that.
Rym: The con doesn't have to do any adcon work.
Rym: They only have to do pre-con work.
Rym: And it seems like it worked really well with this thing this year And I really hope odicon is able to pull off bigger things next year.
Scott: Yeah, just get places to say anyone with an odicon badge special shit for you on thursday And it can be totally awesome.
Scott: I think that's something that other cons should work towards.
Scott: also is getting places in the area To do special things for anyone in the badge, you know the day before the day after anything like that.
Rym: Yep, because I mean we actually ran into daryl.
Scott: I know for an example packs.
Scott: I just realized looking at the pack schedule Pax doesn't begin until 2 p.m.
Scott: Friday.
Scott: The seattle area around the convention center should do stuff for packs people with their badges before 2 p.m On friday, but granted odicon did it it worked.
Rym: I hope they do it again in the future.
Rym: So, uh, yeah friday, you know, actually the regular reg line was gigantic.
Rym: There were a lot of people.
Rym: i'll tell you right now the the number this year was like 26,000 something.
Rym: but beyond that the general con I mean Actually unlike previous years crowd control was very little of a problem compared to what has been in the past.
Rym: I mean It was very easy to get around the con for once and there were.
Rym: they didn't seem like they needed as many staffers.
Rym: Pushing people around.
Scott: yeah They maintained the same layout as last year utilizing the area in the front under the reg for the dealer's room exit.
Scott: But in addition they opened up the doors in the back of the artist's alley to use that as an additional entrance.
Scott: Exit you could actually was brilliant.
Rym: It was awesome because one that was an in and out for the artist alley and there was the other main entrance for the artist Alley, but it was only the exit to the dealer's room.
Rym: You couldn't enter the dealer's room from back there unless you were a dealer or press or something.
Rym: So as a result people would you know, the dealer's room is crazy crowded and gigantic and people are in there They're coming out and they're kind of funneled into this extra space Thus keeping them out of the rest of the con.
Rym: and you know people can hang out there and chill There.
Rym: extra bathrooms back there, which was real important, but then hey since you're here Here's the artist alley and it just kind of funneled these people.
Rym: There's a constant stream of people coming into the artist alley from the back Walking all the way through the tables and going out the front.
Rym: the whole con and as a result the main issue here The back of the artist alley was rocking.
Rym: the people who were stuck in the back back corner Had just as much traffic as the people in the front.
Scott: Yeah, no longer was it.
Scott: Ah back at the artist alley No one's gonna see me chirp chirp cricket cricket.
Scott: It was back the artist alley.
Scott: Oh, yeah better than the middle All right.
Scott: the other thing was I was using the artist alley is pretty much a shortcut to get under most of the con because It had an entrance on one side and exit on the other side.
Scott: so I could go Both ways through the artist alley rather than going upstairs through the crowds walking in the hallways to get from one side to the other.
Rym: Now the dealer's room If you've never been to an odeacon before and you've never listened to our previous shows about an odeacon.
Rym: You can go to them to hear all about it.
Rym: But basically the dealer's room at odeacon is bigger than you're imagining and whatever you're thinking about right now It's bigger than that.
Rym: It is gigantic.
Rym: It is bigger than most conventions.
Scott: Think of like, you know the size of three best buys and it's all anime store.
Rym: That's what the odeacon dealer's room was like and it was Actually, I think it was better than last year in a lot of ways too.
Rym: There were the dealers were had a lot more stuff.
Rym: There was a lot more variety.
Rym: There were fewer porn peddlers and while there were a lot of those sword dealers They there didn't seem to be nearly as many as there were last year.
Scott: yeah, there were also lots of people actually selling lots of dvds and lots of manga at Decent prices and with a lot of pretty good selection.
Rym: I actually bought the whole.
Rym: I bought all of the deshigo for like 30 bucks.
Rym: Well, that's.
Scott: the other thing is that there's all since all the companies are sort of going downhill.
Scott: There was lots of blowouts on stuff.
Scott: You can get basically 80 v leftovers, you know wicked cheap lots and lots of slim case boxes.
Scott: It was pretty much.
Scott: Oh, man's if you had money at odeacon and you wanted anime stuff You were going to be in good time and I saw stuff that wasn't on the internets, you know It wasn't so good maybe for the robot buying but for the manga dvd buying.
Scott: it was right up there with the awesomes.
Rym: Yeah the only thing I really didn't see that I kind of wanted and I don't know why because I see him less and less was I need I had a really nice utenna pin that I used to always like put on my lapel Pretty much anywhere I went, you know dressed up nice.
Rym: I was a little lieutenant pin And I eventually lost it because you know those things wear out.
Rym: I could not find anywhere in that dealer's room high quality pins.
Scott: There were a lot of that misato pin.
Rym: Yeah, there was and while the art was high quality the actual manufacturing quality of that pin was very low And I suspect that it was a bootleg.
Rym: I highly suspect most of those are yes, but You used to be able to get.
Rym: this is my only gripe and it's not a gripe with odeacon It's just a gripe with anime dealers.
Rym: What can I do?
Rym: I should just buy it online, but I could not find high quality pins anywhere.
Rym: Yeah, but of course all the cool people were in there Like, you know, there's always that the table selling the old like leji matsumoto movie posters.
Scott: Oh, it's that same guy every year every year.
Rym: I say wow.
Rym: I really want that arcadia of my youth poster.
Rym: Wow, it's seventy dollars.
Scott: every year He has that same non-bootleg wall scrolls of like ronma hanging up there for like hundreds of dollars and he never sells them.
Rym: But there they are and I always want them.
Scott: I can always go over there and say hey you see that.
Scott: Yeah, that's a real wall scroll.
Scott: You're not going to see any others like that around here.
Scott: These are all bootlegs.
Scott: Yes, even those that every single booth is selling all bootleg or that they're american.
Rym: It's it's a tricky subject.
Rym: Yeah, we don't really need to get into that I know we don't.
Rym: let's just say that wall scrolls in america are not quite held to the same standard as wall scrolls were In japan,
Scott: no, but as for what, you know while we're talking about what it's like to shop in the dealer's room, basically Uh, if you've never bought, you know had access to anime goods before and you don't buy stuff online
Rym: You'll have a nerdgasm.
Rym: Oh my god.
Scott: Oh my god, if you're a dealer Right mad money's raking it in people.
Scott: I saw people buying stuff all over the place.
Scott: It was not every like.
Scott: oh it seemed like everyone walking around the con is some bag with something in it.
Scott: You know, we interviewed actually people sitting at the front of the dealer's room line because we were like, why are people waiting it?
Scott: You know, why do people wait in the dealer's room line every year, you know?
Scott: Is do you really need to get in there right away?
Scott: Is something really going to sell out that you want so desperately there?
Rym: and almost everyone we talked to.
Rym: their answer was basically Yes, I want this thing.
Rym: It sold out last year.
Rym: I'm not going to miss it again.
Scott: I can't buy it online because it's hard to import.
Scott: It's too expensive.
Scott: I you know and uh The people the prices are higher.
Scott: the shipping costs whatever.
Scott: i'm buying the dealer's room and a lot of the people wanted like import video Games and stuff like that.
Scott: So import video games are big money.
Rym: Someone was making money in the dealer's room and a lot of people were selling import video games Which tells me something really interesting.
Rym: now think of this.
Rym: the anime industry is basically collapsing in the united states Yet The industry around it is largely thriving.
Rym: I mean you go to that dealer's room and More money probably changed hands there than went into advs coffers last year.
Scott: Yeah, I know if you look The video games with anime characters in them are probably selling better than the dvds with those same anime characters in them.
Scott: It's kind of crazy.
Rym: But I mean people were buying stuff like crazy and people were buying like 70 80 90 Imported video games that they could probably if they wanted to pirate.
Rym: probably the fact that they're buying them Is really interesting to me and it it really starts to hurt the idea that piracy is the only thing destroying the anime industry.
Scott: Yep, there's also someone near the front of that line who went to rit.
Scott: They were like, yeah I went to a really nerdy school.
Scott: We're like was it rit?
Rym: They're like, yeah No, but he went.
Rym: he was funny because we're like was it rit?
Rym: and he stopped.
Rym: she's like, uh, Yeah, it was.
Scott: and we're like, how did you know what's up?
Rym: and i'm like yeah I was the president of your anime club.
Rym: He's like i'm in that anime club.
Rym: Yep Thank god, though.
Rym: He didn't know who I was for.
Rym: It's.
Rym: finally there's a generation at rit.
Rym: You don't know who the hell I am.
Rym: I could i'm done.
Rym: I'm gone.
Scott: Actually rit was representing pretty strong at the otakad I saw.
Scott: I saw at least two people with rit shirts and then add in the people that said rit that weren't actually Wearing any rit stuff.
Rym: a lot of people came up to our table in the artist alley and we're like, yeah Blah blah rit anime.
Rym: and I was like word to your mother Yeah, do you know these people that I I?
Scott: they were like the last people I met before I never went to rochester again.
Scott: And i'm like, yeah, I know them.
Scott: Those are the last people I met.
Scott: they were from the anime club before.
Rym: Yeah, people come up and like yeah, I was there when president so and so was present.
Rym: I'm like, yeah.
Rym: Well, I was the president before the person before the person before that person.
Scott: Yeah Uh good times good times.
Rym: Yeah, but uh, I really want to get into.
Rym: you know, I don't want to go forever On this review, but let's talk a little bit about panels now.
Rym: Last year otakon had some trouble with the panels department.
Rym: You can listen to our review and we talked all about what happened.
Rym: But this year the panels people particularly omar and meredith.
Rym: They had their act together to a degree that was frightening.
Rym: otakon put on As far as I could see and from what everyone that I talked to said The best panels as a whole that they have ever had in terms of quality and perhaps quantity I mean, well, I don't know.
Scott: i've seen panel.
Scott: I've seen conventions that have more panels Technically like that new york comic con and technically like 200 something panels is ridiculous.
Scott: But the quality of the panels was Outstanding.
Scott: now absolutely every single panel before our panels every single panel I walked in on Every last one was like top tier quality of panel.
Rym: I mean look we did anime.
Rym: You should see on friday right early more like at noon We walked in, you know during the panel before it dubs that time forgot that was mike tool.
Scott: that Was amazing.
Scott: Oh my god, and we only saw 10 minutes of it, but I knew it was amazing.
Scott: And afterwards I was like, oh you're mike tool that awesome guy.
Rym: No wonder Yeah, and you know like every panel there's this panel on samurai and ninja.
Rym: that was right before one of our other panels.
Rym: It's also amazing.
Rym: and you know, I went around with the kind of the press pass and I poked my head into all the full panels to see what was going on and Every single panel I laid eyes on was extremely well put together.
Rym: And part of that, you know, as we said was that otakon the staff.
Rym: they were really good about Reading out panelists who either wouldn't do a good job or wouldn't be professional.
Rym: They made panelists check in.
Rym: make you know They made sure the panelists were there who were going to do their panel and that worked with the only exception.
Rym: I think was this toho panel that apparently a lot of people wanted to go to and the panelists didn't run and there was some Minor debacle there, but other than that the panels were fantastic.
Scott: Yep Another thing there was this rakugo guy.
Scott: You want to talk let's talk about him for a minute.
Rym: Yes, this was more of an event than a panel.
Rym: now rakugo is this traditional form of japanese comedic storytelling.
Scott: Yes, basically, it's sit down comedy instead of stand up comedy.
Scott: This guy sits on a pillow right kneels on it and he has a fan And some chopsticks.
Rym: right and no no, he has a fan and a towel.
Scott: Oh fan and a towel.
Rym: He does not have chopsticks, right?
Scott: He folds the fan together and it becomes chopsticks.
Rym: Ah, he fooled you.
Rym: I see he did.
Scott: he has a fan and a towel and he sits on this pillow kneels on it And while he sits there, he tells you his story and it's always a hilarious story.
Rym: now the cool thing is I mean This is a traditional japanese art and you can read all about it But the man who performed at otakon was sent basically by the japanese government.
Rym: He travels the world because he speaks english.
Rym: So he does this traditional japanese comedic art form In english for american audiences and he goes around the world Spreading rakugo and showing people check this out And it was super awesome.
Scott: It was so great.
Scott: The only there's one criticism of it is that he had this big panel and it was so great.
Scott: But he spent a lot of the panel teaching what rakugo was rather than actually doing rakugo.
Scott: He only did Full on rakugo and actually telling funny stories for maybe like the last Five ten minutes of the panel and I just wish he would have done that the whole time.
Scott: people get it.
Scott: You know, you don't have to spend half the panel telling us what you're gonna do.
Scott: It's like, you know, it's like, you know, you don't see a hockey player.
Scott: come in and say i'm along and hit the puck Into the goal.
Scott: It's like no just do it.
Scott: I You know i'll figure it out.
Rym: See the thing is I mean he came to otakon not really knowing what to expect and he's he hasn't.
Rym: I mean He was trying to figure out how to do this how to?
Scott: actually I understand why he did it that way.
Rym: But on the other hand, it's like, okay, we get it You know, but I think he still did a really good job and it was.
Scott: he was amazing.
Rym: He's going to be performing.
Rym: I forget when i'll have to look it up again.
Rym: I'll let you guys know in the forum in new york city Sometime in the near future
Scott: as well as some other cities in the us
Rym: And if we i'm gonna find out if he's doing just like a full normal ad because if that's the case You can bet your butt that we're gonna be there.
Rym: Oh, man But the thing.
Scott: i'm sad I forgot the guy's name.
Scott: I don't have the con book on me.
Rym: the thing that really made me happy Was that you know?
Rym: We we show.
Rym: we walked over about a half hour 45 minutes before the event was going to start because they had a a seating time a lineup time.
Rym: The line for this was insane.
Rym: The panel
Scott: filled up and it was one of the bigger
Rym: panel rooms to the point that the line went all the way down One hallway and then they cut it off and formed a new line that went all the way down the other hallway And then they had people at both ends telling people not to line up.
Rym: It was already full.
Scott: It was the second biggest panel room and it was full up 100.
Rym: See i'm sure there was worry.
Rym: I mean, what if people don't come?
Rym: what if this was all a big waste?
Rym: Are people interested in this?
Rym: and i'm very heartened by you anime fans for the fact that you all Really thought this would be cool and wanted to see it and the fact that everyone seemed to get it.
Rym: Everyone seemed to enjoy it And i'll admit sadly the only reason we were able to get in is because we had our press passes.
Rym: Otherwise by the time we got there we couldn't have gotten into this thing.
Scott: Yeah, and that was actually something that was the one problem that I noticed.
Scott: that was the biggest problem at the convention this year.
Scott: And if that's the biggest problem, you know, not too bad The biggest problem is that things are too popular.
Rym: exactly people
Scott: things at this convention, you know They use a hundred percent of the space they can't use any more of it and many of the things that are happening were just too popular and People would line up for things well before they were over And sometimes they would clear the room out.
Scott: sometimes they wouldn't.
Rym: now despite a few people tried to complain about this at the feedback session, but Otakon actually makes it very clear.
Rym: They only clear out the room before an event if they have scheduled a hey We're clearing out the room before this event.
Scott: or if it's an 18 plus event that follows a non 18 plus event Then they clear the room also for obvious reasons Yes But otherwise they don't clear the room which I guess is an okay policy.
Scott: because the problem with clearing the room is this You clear the room let's say you clear the room.
Scott: That means the people who are waiting in line for the event get to go in and they're going to get a seat Whatever seat they want.
Scott: that's kind of good.
Scott: The problem is what?
Scott: if people really did want to see two events in a row now, they're fucked.
Scott: They can't possibly see the second event because they're not in line They're going to get kicked out of the room while they're in it sent to the back of the line and they're screwed.
Scott: That's not really so great because usually similar events are scheduled next to each other.
Scott: because it makes sense.
Rym: but I mean really I mean You can't.
Rym: it's not a thing you can really complain about because there's really nothing that can be done about it Other than having a lot fewer panels and having spaces between them and staggering it out.
Rym: But that doesn't really serve Otakon's purposes.
Scott: No, it doesn't.
Scott: so the other solution never clear the room.
Scott: Okay, so now i'll just camp out in this room see two panels I don't care about just so i'll be in a good seat for the third panel Which I do care about which is going to be crazy crowd.
Rym: Basically if they clear the rooms out all the time half of Otakon will complain.
Rym: if they don't clear the rooms out The other half will complain.
Scott: It's a it's a no-win situation.
Scott: Luckily.
Rym: It's a moot point because I actually got a chance.
Rym: I walked over and I looked around the new wing of the convention center.
Rym: It is gigantic.
Rym: it is connected via a skyway like just from you know, where the rave is.
Rym: there's like a sky Way that goes across the street to the rest of the convention center.
Rym: And i'm not sure exactly how Otakon is going to be using this space.
Rym: but Believe me when I say that i'm going to be following up with them And talking to them to find out what they're going to do because that space is going to allow them to.
Rym: I think next year's Otakon is going to transcend all Otakon's previous in terms of layout in terms of function in terms of lines because There's so much more space.
Rym: Yeah, they can do so much like.
Scott: I think it'll be two years from now.
Scott: That'll be transcending because they I think they need a year to learn to use the space properly.
Scott: true The first year it'll still be great because they'll be using this extra space but in the second year They'll realize fully how to use the space most efficiently.
Rym: But the staff has already been doing walkthroughs and it it's looking to shape up pretty nicely.
Rym: There's that whole new hotel the hilton right there kind of connected to this thing.
Rym: Apparently there's a million panel rooms in there.
Rym: I could I don't know what they'll do.
Rym: I got a lot of crazy ideas But maybe i'll save all that for a future.
Rym: show what I would do if I had any say in how Otakon has run.
Scott: Right, right, right.
Scott: But yeah There were some events that were very difficult to get into even if you lined up well in advance.
Rym: most for example The uh, there was a phoenix right kind of like.
Rym: it was basically a long cosplay skit that these people wanted to do as an event.
Rym: You know, they're all in costume and they kind of acted out a phoenix right trial.
Rym: the line for this thing Was already larger than the.
Rym: basically people waited for two hours and still didn't get into this event.
Scott: Yeah, and they feel it was the largest panel room.
Scott: the room filled up.
Scott: We went in with our press badges to see what was going on.
Scott: It was pretty corny to be honest what was going on up there.
Scott: It felt like it could have been good if they put more effort into it and were a little more Professional and clean and more prepared.
Rym: but at the same time it was weird because the half the crowd seemed to be really Really digging it.
Rym: but there were other people there who were just kind of playing on their ds and they were kind of walking out or And I looked into picto chat and it was well, it was basically just penises picto chat's not useful for anything Yeah.
Scott: But anyway, it was you know, it was still pretty amazing that hey, there's this huge huge panel Oh my gosh, and I feel like with new space and with you know, Otakon could have a lot of events like that.
Scott: And I imagine if you put a phoenix right trial and then something else Equivalently appealing to the audience in another place simultaneously I think that would solve a lot of the problems.
Scott: Yep uh of lining up for things but mostly what the?
Scott: The problem that the things we had to wait in line for that were problematic were the live action 18 plus showings that happened on friday and saturday night.
Rym: Let's talk a little bit about the showings video rooms, whatever.
Rym: I don't really watch stuff but the live action asian cinema and in classic otakon fashion They did in fact have the asian tasteless movies late at night in video five, yep let's see the movies were tokyo gore police, which is uh, So other.
Scott: I didn't see it But the people who did see it said it was very nice With the many gores.
Rym: a lot of people said it was the best of the tasteless movies.
Scott: Uh, so sad because I didn't see that one.
Scott: Uh, there was a movie.
Rym: Uh, the one after that was Don't you have it pulled up?
Scott: Oh, no the one before it would think was bohachi bushido Which is based on a kazuo koike manga.
Rym: now I the only reason I didn't stay this is the only.
Rym: the only complaint I personally had with otakon was that In some of the video rooms the subtitles were too low on the screen So you could not read them unless you were in the front row.
Scott: because I mean it's obvious.
Scott: There's no stadium seating.
Scott: obvious, you know, it's just a bunch of chairs laid out flat with the projector in the aisle.
Scott: Okay, you can't fix that but you can aim the projector higher, you know, because it's a wide screen movie You don't need black at the top of the screen.
Scott: Just aim it higher.
Scott: You can use the remote control to do it and everyone be able to see the subtitles.
Rym: sadly I talked to the tech guys.
Rym: I was like, hey, can you do something?
Rym: They said no.
Rym: So I talked to an otakon staffer.
Rym: He's like now we're not.
Scott: well, some people aren't allowed to touch the projector.
Scott: You need someone who's allowed to touch it.
Scott: Yes, and the people who are allowed to touch it leave earlier.
Scott: They're not there, you know 11 o'clock at night, but regardless that movie Actually looked really good.
Scott: We just couldn't stay there for more than like 15 minutes because not being able to read the subtitles Through the person in front of me's head was not worth it.
Rym: I mean it started out weird and scary and actually in the beginning I almost wanted to walk out because I thought it was going to be really kind of disgusting and tasteless and not in the good Way, but then like there's a twist about 10 minutes in and that made the movie go from scary and perverted to Hilarious and amazing.
Scott: It was totally you could tell right away.
Scott: It was all Kazuo Koike You know, he only wrote the manga that it was based on but it had a strong influence on the movie, super strong.
Rym: I had an idea because you know, but I'll admit this is the one time in the entire convention where I Slightly abused my press pass.
Rym: All right, because the line to get in to see this movie was crazy.
Rym: So I walk up and we're like, hey, we're press we'd like to cover this event and the staffer stops.
Rym: He says wait a minute You want to cover a really violent tasteless movie that we're showing at this con late at night.
Rym: and I said yes, and he stands there and he says That's the most awesome thing i've heard all night.
Rym: go right in.
Scott: Yeah, that's good times.
Rym: So I stood in the front of the room and as people walked in I walked around.
Rym: I asked people You know, do you know what this movie is?
Rym: I kind of interviewed all these people around the room and Half the audience was like this is some Kazuo Koike thing Oh my god, and the other half were like, I don't know i'm just here.
Rym: so I started explaining to people who didn't know What this movie was and who Kazuo Koike was and all that business and they were really interested.
Rym: and actually a few people the next day came up to me at the artist alley and were like man, I went Kazuo Koike and I looked up and you guys should do that at more video showings.
Rym: and What if this is a crazy idea?
Rym: this is the kind of thing that would need a lot of dedicated volunteers because There's no way Otakon could provide staff to do this.
Rym: What if you had showing rooms?
Rym: Maybe not all of them but select showings that had an MC where instead of just people file in you show a film It's people file in.
Rym: Someone is up at the front of the room They talk for maybe five ten minutes about what you're about to see.
Rym: they explain, you know This is directed by so-and-so or this is a Kazuo Koike based on this movie.
Rym: If you don't know who Kazuo Koike is lone wolf and cub and such Oh my god.
Rym: and just kind of.
Rym: do that.
Rym: do a short really quick panel 10 minutes at most about the movie and then give some context And then let people watch the movie and then after the movie have a short discussion and then let everyone go.
Scott: Yeah, I definitely think that certain video showings especially showings of you know Uh videos that have a history to them or you know There could be definitely be enhanced by some sort of MC Briefing the audience before or after the showing.
Rym: now even better.
Rym: look at the anime showing rooms, which honestly I feel as though anime showing rooms are an artifact a holdover.
Rym: There's something that does not need to exist as they did in the old days.
Scott: You don't need that many of them Anyway, it's more it also.
Rym: I mean there are a lot of people surprisingly who come to anime cons to watch anime but not that many.
Rym: but You don't need a showing room.
Rym: that's showing like eight episodes of a show or an entire show or anything like that.
Scott: Well, some of them you need basically to satisfy the industry, you know, they come in they set up a booth.
Scott: They're like we want you to show this anime so that people will come in and buy it.
Rym: But at the same time Otakon is classically known for not being beholden to the industry and they could just say no Yeah, yeah, we'll see anyway.
Rym: But what if instead I would like to see showing rooms that are not?
Rym: we are showing the first four episodes of slayers revolution.
Rym: But imagine if there's a showing room called So you want to get into anime or you've already seen bleach watch.
Rym: next like showing rooms Or showing room events that are like an hour two three hours long That are themed or titled or set up like a panel.
Scott: So it's like a panel.
Scott: but you know during a panel usually if you have a video panel Usually showing many short clips with talking in between each one But what you could do is you basically have it be a panel room But it's a panel where you say a little bit and watch a lot of video And say a little bit and watch a lot of video.
Rym: So for example, what if you had a show on your own that was called, you know Anime next steps and the description is basically, you know, you've just gotten into anime.
Rym: You don't know a lot about it.
Rym: What is out there and what it would be is you have an mc and you show like?
Rym: Six different shows the first episode of each one From like.
Rym: six different like the heavy hitters from six different genres of anime show like the definitive robot show Show the first episode of evangelion show the first episode of cowboy bebop.
Rym: and you know Talk a little bit about each one between them and have it be an extended panel where you're explaining anime you're showing anime You're getting people excited about anime.
Rym: It's a. it's a format that i've never seen anywhere and I think otakon is the kind that could pull it off.
Scott: Yep anyway.
Scott: So yeah, there was.
Scott: there was a little problem lining up for things in advance But there's really not a solution to that other than have a lot more things going on.
Rym: And just to understand the scale of this.
Rym: and at otakon it wasn't just these crazy big events.
Rym: our anime You should see panel not only had a line out the door too big But they actually came in and for fire code reasons kicked a whole ton of people out before we started.
Scott: Yeah, because the panel before us is standing room only.
Scott: but they decided you know No one's allowed to sit on the floor.
Scott: No one's allowed to stand.
Scott: It's once all the chairs are filled.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: Everyone out.
Rym: But yeah, I mean overall This was a fantastic otakon for the fans.
Rym: I mean There was always something to do and a lot of times i'd be at an anime con especially even older otakons And at a certain time be like i'm bored.
Rym: Let's see what there is to do.
Rym: And I wouldn't really be excited about.
Scott: last year at otakon the previous one There were definitely long swatches of time where it felt like uh, what do I do?
Scott: And I sat in the artist's alley bored at the you know The table doing my fanboy feud survey.
Scott: I would go to the dealer's room multiple times this otakon.
Scott: I was only able to make it into the dealer's room once on saturday for like an hour And I was always worrying about the time of the next event that I had to get to at a certain time.
Rym: I mean if I went through the schedule there was something that I would like to do at every point throughout this con pretty much And I mean what else.
Rym: the video game room was as always gigantic and a lot of people were in there And there were a lot of good games.
Rym: and I always like otakon's video game room because it's actually kind of chill.
Rym: It's a good place to go and relax.
Scott: They have a lot of shoot-em-ups and a lot of good ones and they had the witch one again the versus which one And they have a lot of just kind of weird japanese games and they have.
Rym: you know They run the tournaments and all that stuff, but it's a really chill place to hang out.
Rym: I like it and uh The lark was crazy as always.
Rym: there were a lot of people in there.
Rym: otakon was rocking as always.
Scott: Yeah, I never actually went into otakon before which is basically the otakon daycare.
Scott: It's a place you can bring your kids, you know little kids at otakon to give them something to do.
Scott: That room is actually rocking in there.
Scott: There's all sorts of arts and crafts going on There's.
Scott: they got a little, you know kids anime showing on the screen.
Scott: It is totally awesome in there.
Scott: I mean It is worth the price.
Scott: just to if you have little kids just bring them to otakon.
Scott: forget about the rest of otakon.
Scott: Just bring your kids to otachan and it's like totally awesome weekend daycare.
Rym: And I mean I was told that like all the events I didn't get a chance to go to, you know we kind of sent people out and they they really had a good time, uh, really of note, I do have to say something about the Animation.
Rym: we've talked about it before but you know, we actually saw the otakon opening animation.
Rym: They showed it.
Rym: they were actually as we found out later Contractually obligated to show it no more than once or any given day.
Scott: Yeah So the way it works is jim vowels and you know otakon Teamed up with madhouse the japanese animation studio.
Rym: jim is credited in the animation as producer.
Rym: That is so cool That's pretty cool.
Scott: And they are um, you know madhouse is really buddy buddy with otakon muriyama The guy that basically the head of madhouse dude is always at otakon always being awesome.
Scott: He had a couple panels, you know hanging out.
Scott: He loves otakon that guy.
Scott: and You know, they teamed up and they made this short animation.
Scott: It was maybe a minute or two long.
Rym: It was basically if otakon were in anime, this is the opener.
Scott: Yes, and They played it at the opening ceremonies.
Scott: They played it at the cosplay the masquerade and they played it at the closing ceremonies.
Rym: And well, we actually weren't going to make it to the opening ceremony.
Rym: So we had a panel to run.
Rym: so we sent emily to cover it for us and she came back just bubbling about how great it was and actually Opening ceremonies partly because of that animation.
Rym: but from what she said otakon really stepped up the opening ceremony.
Scott: Yeah opening ceremonies the most anime conventions is lame.
Scott: It's basically like hey, we're having a con And everyone goes in.
Rym: I mean basically anyone there.
Rym: until this otakon The only con I had been to that had a really good opening ceremonies was like one of the two anime centrals I attended a long time ago.
Rym: Yeah, it was just.
Rym: they're always kind of weak, but it was a great opening.
Rym: and then they showed the animation and that animation It did not just meet expectations it exceeded them to a degree that I could not believe.
Rym: yeah It was full of inside jokes.
Rym: the the level of homage in there was epic.
Scott: I mean when the manhole covers start flying across the screen to destroy the eva and only someone who was at the otakon Which is the year all the manhole covers in the city exploded would know would get the joke.
Rym: It was it was it was clearly made with with all the love and dedication it was.
Rym: Otakon is clearly the best american anime convention and there is nothing you could say to change my mind on that.
Rym: And this is just the solid proof of that.
Rym: So if you can find it somewhere to see it, yeah animax, but where's your opening animation?
Scott: You got nothing.
Rym: I'm sure there will be a way if you did not see it to see it someday.
Rym: Because if if no other way at the next otakon it is so worth seeing it is worth going out of your way to see Especially these two minutes of animation because it's really well animated.
Rym: and I mean It's not just so much to otakon the things the references They I can't even I don't even want to get into it.
Rym: There's so much in there and that's such a short span of time.
Rym: Yep but also I mean briefly otakon.
Rym: as always they're running the masquerade in the Arena next door, which is great because you know, we talk about lines at otakon.
Rym: but otakon has solved the one of the biggest problems of cons, which is What do you do with the masquerade line?
Rym: because at most cons the masquerade cannot seat?
Rym: Everyone in the con who wants to see it and the line will be forever and it's crazy and horrible.
Rym: And people basically had to give up their entire saturday to attend at otakon.
Rym: You can see like 30 000 people in that arena And it was like there were a lot.
Rym: there were at least 10 000 people in there during the masquerade by my rough Count and you can just walk in and out.
Rym: You might not.
Rym: I mean you have to wait in line if you want to sit in front But you don't need to because the masquerade if you've never been to an otakon This is pretty much the best masquerade you're going to see because one they have a full three camera camera crew live And giant jumbotron screens everywhere.
Rym: So they have real professional cameramen doing a real professional job.
Rym: Even you're sitting in the back watching the cosplay is amazing.
Rym: Yeah, if you're into that sort of thing and two I walked in and I watched five skits.
Rym: They were all actually really funny and well put together.
Rym: The thing is they were all basically musical numbers like choreographed dance and music.
Scott: Yeah, because I mean doing the the the the spoken word sort of voice Talking and things because they make you they don't let you talk into microphones.
Scott: They make you pre-record all your audio.
Scott: So if it's talking and you're going to lip sync the talking it always comes off sort of bleh.
Rym: See the thing is I actually saw one group that they did that first and then it was the song and dance number And it worked really really well that I I mean I didn't stay through the whole thing.
Rym: I can't say how good it all was but the ones I saw Were actually good and I wouldn't have I was actually If I didn't have things to do I kind of wanted to hang out in there and watch a bunch more.
Scott: Yeah, I still do.
Scott: I miss Sort of the old otakon of three or four years ago where I would sit and watch the last hour of the cosplay on the simulcast video screen not in the masquerade room, but in another room just watching it on video and Then as soon as it was over the horribly violent movies would come on on the very same screen.
Scott: That I just love that and I sort of miss it.
Rym: But think about otakon.
Rym: what this says about otakon?
Rym: every other con they have their cosplay.
Rym: otakon's cosplay is in a 30,000 person arena With a real professional camera crew.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: It is if you're a cosplayer that is the place to be.
Scott: Another thing that was done professionally at least from what I heard I didn't actually go to it was the otakon game show.
Scott: now otakon never lets us do our match game because they have the official game show and they do pre-screening forward and the whole thing and basically It's jeopardy but with a twist of some kind
Rym: and the key is Super professionalism coupled with the fact that they screen the people before they let them in the contest.
Scott: They also apparently have really like they have wicked high technology like using wiimotes to buzz in and It's totally off the wall in terms of the production quality of the show.
Scott: So it's tough for us to compete with that with our little match game.
Rym: See the thing is though the match game doesn't need the high technology.
Rym: All it needs is the star power.
Rym: That's right Of course, it also requires the stars.
Rym: Thank you ConnectiCon for not providing it.
Rym: Oh All right, oh well, but yeah, you'll be seeing our match game at every other convention this year.
Rym: I think I don't know.
Rym: I think we're running at the new york anime festival.
Rym: Not a hundred percent sure.
Rym: I gotta actually look at that schedule.
Rym: It's coming up.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: But yeah, I mean otakon was fantastic.
Rym: Everything went smoothly.
Rym: if you went to the con feedback session, there were really practically zero legitimate complaints.
Scott: Yeah, there were some people complaining that the masquerade went long.
Scott: It was pretty long.
Rym: last year They complained that it went short and otakon knows they're trying to figure out exactly how to make it the right length.
Scott: Yeah, it pretty much, you know, there's too many factors in there.
Scott: You can't account for everything.
Scott: It's difficult.
Scott: Um, What are the complaints to be here at the feedback session?
Rym: really nothing that was worth talking about.
Rym: some people complained about dumb things.
Scott: They there was the complaint about the subtitles being unreadable but to which they basically said duly noted.
Rym: We'll fix it next year.
Rym: I mean what more do you want?
Rym: There was the guy who was like but 4chan 4chan, why can't we come back?
Rym: and the otakon staff was fantastic.
Scott: Oh, there was a complaint about the um, The wristbands, right and as soon as he got up there and he's like, yeah, maybe we should just idea that a boo.
Scott: I love it.
Scott: That's the one thing I love about the otakon feedback panel.
Scott: if you go up there And you complain about something stupid and you're wrong, right?
Scott: The whole audience will boo you like you're wrong.
Scott: You know where that?
Rym: oh it was so good when the guy was like you should let 4chan in.
Scott: But Otakon's response is so great like you have to prove to us that you're not gonna be idiots and that's pretty much impossible But even better.
Rym: actually one guy went up and he asked the question of the staff and his question was What is your favorite anime?
Rym: and they all answered.
Rym: and I gotta say?
Rym: The otakon staff like the head staff have some classy taste in anime.
Scott: Yeah, and one guy even said I can.
Scott: he said the otakon opening animation Which is perfectly okay?
Rym: But before we stop I mean otakon was great, but i'd love to.
Rym: i'd love to give you guys a little insight.
Rym: I'd like to talk a little bit of meta because you know most cons we get the press badge or we don't kind of willy-nilly but Unlike any other con otakon is a convention where if we want to cover the convention We want to see all the events.
Rym: We want to kind of get the feel of everything.
Rym: We actually do need the press pass because otherwise we can't get into the events without lining up for an hour.
Rym: I mean katsu kana.
Rym: I just kind of walk into everything and amazement.
Rym: I just kind of walked into everything.
Rym: but otakon the press badge actually gets you everything you need.
Scott: Yeah, but we didn't do a lot of the stuff it gets you like.
Scott: it gets you like interviews in quiet rooms with guests.
Scott: We didn't do any of that.
Scott: All right We didn't want to do that.
Rym: but luckily if you want all that press coverage our dear friends in anime world order They kind of covered the other half of press.
Rym: They got all the interviews.
Rym: They did all that sort of stuff.
Rym: we kind of went around and got the fans perspective, but For the first time I actually went in, you know, I did the paperwork.
Rym: We got the press badges walking it out and I got to say otakon is so professional when it comes to the press.
Rym: They it was better than the freaking new york anime festival, which is a professional for-profit con.
Scott: Yeah, it was good times.
Rym: I mean i'm holding the press kit they gave us and it was.
Rym: it was perfectly put together.
Rym: They gave us these really really nice little press notebooks to say otakon 2008 with like business card holders And pretty much if you wanted that business card holder was real useful.
Scott: We got a whole bunch of business cards in there.
Scott: Yeah, well actually they gave us a pen otakon pens.
Scott: We will actually have really suck it up to the press.
Rym: We'll have a lot of kind of tertiary and follow-up otakon coverage In the next several shows as news is as I get to kind of Writing them up and I got to clarify things with otakon, you know I want to talk about something.
Rym: but I want to ask them like well What were the numbers and what were this sort of thing?
Scott: But yeah, we'll also talk about.
Scott: you know, here's we met so-and-so in the artist alley check out their arts.
Rym: That's the thing and we also will have talk in the future about.
Rym: you know here's all the actual announcements like this was licensed and that was licensed and all that stuff.
Rym: but Pretty much otakon was fantastic.
Rym: It was a great time to be had by all there.
Rym: I can't think of anything that really really went wrong.
Rym: Nothing affected us.
Rym: Everyone had a great time.
Rym: I'm kind of tired because the show went on for a long time.
Scott: Yeah My only real problem with otakon is that it would felt It all.
Scott: it felt a little bit shorter than other otakons because I was doing stuff the whole time and I didn't You know other.
Scott: I kind of liked, you know, sort of having more time to go around look at stuff.
Scott: See what was going on?
Rym: Oh, no, I kind of had too much good stuff to do.
Rym: What will I do?
Rym: I was.
Scott: I really felt like I only experienced a smaller fraction of the con, you know.
Scott: As opposed to previous years where I felt like I really went around and saw what there was to see this year I felt like I was missing.
Rym: something does really well is that there's so much good stuff going on at any given moment now That no matter what kind of anime fan you are You'll always have something to do.
Rym: if you want to watch anime you can watch anime.
Rym: you want to see a panel?
Rym: There's five of them and they're all great.
Rym: You want to go to a concert?
Rym: There's a giant concert and then there's another concert missing.
Scott: the concert was pretty painful But packs is no way.
Scott: i'm going to see at least one of the two concerts.
Rym: Yeah, but you know that was the price we pay for doing a million panels.
Scott: Yep Oh, well Can we end the show so I can like get a bed or whatever?
Rym: I think we can end it if you guys have any specific questions about otakon other than Kind of the general stuff that we didn't have like an outline prepared and we did the show.
Scott: So we sort of just kept talking and talking and talking partly
Rym: because we're kind of really I mean This is basically the only chance we get to kind of relax and recuperate a little bit before we fly out to packs To do that big panel there and all that business and then right after that we have the new anime festival coming up.
Scott: So right, so if you have a specific question about otakon go to the forums Don't email us.
Scott: go to the forums And go to the thread for this episode And ask it and then we'll answer it there for everyone to see the answer.
Rym: or just email us.
Rym: I mean if you want generic otakon coverage you haven't listened before you could go back and listen to all our other otakon shows because Previous otakon coverages we've talked a lot more about.
Rym: You know what all the things that otakon is like that We really don't need to talk about again because they're the same every year You know, you go and watch anime and hang out and all that sort of stuff.
Scott: Yep All right Oh and you can.
Scott: uh, you know You can find all about the violent movies by go if you want to find out more about the violent movies you watched.
Scott: Go to the otakon schedule and then go to imdb and put them together.
Rym: Oh, yeah, and I want to give a big shout out to all the people who were at our panels who actually knew about anime.
Rym: That was real refreshing to to mention an old obscure anime and have half the crowd scream and yell and go.
Rym: Oh my god.
Scott: Yeah, on the one hand it made it hard to do a panel because the audience knows more than we do.
Scott: On the other hand it made it awesome because the audience is awesome.
Rym: Well, the cool thing is we're trying to start this meme.
Rym: We explain this at every panel how you go to any panel at a con and people say just the name of an anime the crowd goes Whoa Every time they did that we stopped them.
Rym: We're like, what are you doing?
Rym: And we've been doing this for at ConnectiCon too and it's starting to work a little bit like at uh, otakon By our third or fourth panel people kind of stopped doing it.
Rym: Yeah, it was amazing.
Rym: Maybe we can change anime culture a little bit making them stop going.
Rym: Whoo This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and rpgs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at frontrowcrew.com Or you can send audio feedback via odeo.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an odeo on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in itunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: For the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.