Rym: It's Thursday, May 8th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight on Thursday, the lounge, we bring you the GeekNights book club.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: This morning I drive down to the train station.
Rym: Like you do.
Scott: I'm pulling my car into the parking lot there.
Scott: Oh, you gotta stop saying that.
Scott: And there's a really big goose in the parking lot.
Scott: Right?
Scott: You know, it's not like, it's right in the middle of the road.
Scott: So it's like I can't pull into the spots on the left or the right because the goose is there.
Rym: Now is this a Canadian goose?
Rym: Or one of those white geese?
Scott: I'm not a goose expert.
Rym: Alright, was it all white or was it gray and black?
Scott: It was whitish-gray body with like a black...
Rym: Alright, it's a Canadian goose.
Scott: Anyway, it was huge.
Scott: Like, turkey size.
Rym: That's how big Canadian geese are.
Scott: It's a big ass goose.
Scott: And it was just standing there.
Scott: Like, it can fly, but it wasn't flying.
Scott: You know why?
Scott: It can only take off from the water.
Rym: I'll tell you one thing.
Rym: I really like geese, but Canadian geese are...
Scott: And then they shit everywhere.
Rym: Canadian geese are assholes.
Scott: Pretty much the assholes of the bird kingdom.
Scott: But anyway, so this goose is just standing there in the middle of the road and I just sort of stop.
Scott: And I'm like, honk at it.
Rym: He'll just honk back.
Scott: I could flash my brights at it during the day.
Scott: I'm just sitting there and it starts to slowly just walk to the left a little bit.
Scott: I was able to pull around it and park, but just like big goose standing in the road being like, whatever.
Scott: I'm big goose.
Rym: You know why geese do that?
Rym: Because it was kind of a pastime in Michigan when I was a kid where, you know, we'd go to a park and there'd be Canadian geese.
Rym: They'd all kind of keep to themselves.
Rym: Inevitably, the drunk guy would walk over and try to chase the geese away.
Scott: And they'd all peck him to death.
Rym: Well, they'd all just look at him for a while like, all right, drunk guy, we've played this game before.
Rym: You obviously have not.
Rym: And it would always end in ahh and they got to be running away and they'd be like 50 geese just killing it.
Scott: It's like other birds, like, you know, this problem with other birds, it's only like geese and seagulls, the only birds that ever cause a problem.
Scott: Even crows are less like not bothering people.
Scott: You know, they're just hanging out crowing.
Scott: It's only geese and seagulls that fuck with people.
Scott: And I think so.
Rym: I think, well, seagulls do it for food and geese do it because they're pissed off.
Scott: It's like turkeys, wild turkeys.
Scott: don't bother anybody.
Scott: You know, it depends.
Scott: Little birds like little tiny birds don't bother anybody.
Scott: Hey, pigeons don't even bother people.
Rym: You've never spent any time around a lovebird.
Rym: Pigeons are lovebirds.
Rym: Sometimes I'd be sitting there, like working on the computer, and suddenly I just hear fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff
Scott: fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff
Rym: fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff
Scott: fluff fluff fluff fluff
Rym: fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff
Scott: fluff
Rym: fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fl
Scott: fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff
Rym: fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff
Scott: fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff
Rym: fluff fluff fluff
Scott: fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff
Rym: fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff
Scott: fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff
Rym: fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff
Scott: fluff fluff fluff fluff
Rym: fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff
Scott: fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff
Rym: fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff
Scott: fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fl
Rym: fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff
Scott: fluff fluff
Rym: fluff fluff
Scott: fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff
Rym: fluff fluff fluff fluff fluff
Scott: fluff fluff fluff or bad ones.
Scott: but i say they're bad and i haven't tried them.
Scott: then that's sort of like proving the high quality of my judgment.
Scott: it's like if i can.
Scott: if i consistently pick awesome things without actually looking at them very closely and they all actually turn out to be awesome then that shows that i'm very good at judging what is good and what is bad based on very little information.
Scott: so maybe if i keep doing that and i'm consistent then nobody would be much more difficult for someone to come to me and say don't not get before you tried it because i could say hey i didn't try another shit and i was right about that.
Scott: but anyway my thing of the day is something i glanced at for about a minute.
Scott: so i guess it doesn't really count towards my uh evidence pile and based on the title alone i mean it's not really you know uh telling you how awesome i am at judging because anyone upon seeing the title could immediately know how awesome it is plus you the fact that it's on boing boing sort of.
Scott: you know someone already awesome already judged it.
Scott: so that's like you know.
Scott: i sort of be uh ganking i guess it may be the right word or vamping off of someone else's judgment powers to uh it's all right.
Scott: but basically what this is is soviet sci-fi illustrations.
Scott: hard to go wrong with that people.
Scott: now the one thing i want to say about these soviet science fiction illustrations is not only are they awesome soviet sci-fi illustrations but they really bring across this message of being optimistic about science and the future and for all the bad
Rym: that
Scott: was in the soviet union in fact for all the bad that was the cold war in general one and perhaps the best thing about the cold war if there was any good thing about it was that in the?
Scott: u.s.
Scott: in the soviet union in most of the world everyone was really optimistic about science and technology were going and they wanted to progress science and technology in a real bad way.
Scott: and i think since the end of the cold war we've sort of lost that quite a bit and uh we needed some more.
Scott: i definitely think so especially looking at all the anti-intellectualism stuff that's been happening.
Scott: it's not pleasant for us science.
Rym: uh thinking types yes not to say that the soviet union had the the wonderful open scientific discourse.
Scott: no no no but all i'm saying is that the attitude of the people towards science was like we want science we want better science than everyone else.
Scott: you know we want to move science forward.
Rym: well we used to have space races.
Scott: yeah now we should have other kinds of races.
Scott: we should have like you know tech races or something.
Scott: i don't know.
Scott: so uh we got memristors.
Rym: take that going along with the whole soviet thing.
Rym: i i really couldn't find anything i cared about.
Rym: i mean what i'm gonna go to dig and there's gonna be nothing there.
Scott: did you find a soviet thing?
Scott: maybe?
Rym: so then i go to.
Rym: uh college humor but something soviet there.
Rym: if you're smart now you've probably realized that if you want to see good stuff or you want to see our things of the day just go to college humor.
Scott: well anything that video ones at least yeah because i mean there's a bunch of video sites now.
Scott: but college humor is the only one that seems to have like editorial people picking the videos and they also all their original content that they make is also really good and they seem to be really good at picking or at least really in line with the tastes of Rym and Scott in their picking.
Rym: thus i have for you not one not two but three things of the day.
Scott: oh good god.
Rym: oh scott i think he can see over my shoulder.
Scott: no i'm not looking i've got my eyes closed.
Rym: you should look at this all right let me look hold on.
Scott: i saw something involving uh soviet osamanga dio.
Rym: someone made a kind of soviet cross between.
Rym: well the soviet cross a cross between osamanga dio and soviet propaganda and it's it's pretty cool.
Scott: that's how it should be done.
Scott: people take a lesson.
Rym: but also i found this fairly awesome old soviet animation that is super anti-hitler which i guess is expected it should be.
Scott: i mean worst enemy i mean if you're thinking worst enemy of the soviet union right.
Rym: probably hitler probably hitler i mean or maybe cold.
Scott: i mean they were more anti-hitler in world war ii than they were anti-us in the cold war that's for sure.
Rym: but this is i mean while the first thing's kind of funny this is kind of one.
Rym: it's subtitled which makes this extra interesting.
Rym: oh sweet they gotta watch because you always see the american like world war ii gotta get the nazis like cartoons and things.
Rym: but here's kind of the other side of it i. well i guess the third side of it the soviets who were on our side and their propaganda in the same direction i.
Scott: that's one thing that i was actually i learned like in middle school.
Scott: you know.
Scott: that really surprised me because you know it's sort of like.
Scott: i didn't really have a full grasp of history yet so i knew sort of like hitler bad and communism russia.
Scott: there aren't many people who don't know i know right but i didn't realize at the at my young age that they were actually like.
Scott: you know i figured bad and bad.
Scott: they're not too much hating each other.
Scott: really though i mean we have russia the communism right hitler the fascism and the u.s.
Scott: the you know representative democracy type.
Scott: if you think communism hates representative democracy of capitalisms they fascisms like 10 000 times more.
Scott: so um in our changing of the thursday action right one of the things we sort of decided to do is something that's really cliche and just about all sorts of different shows do it.
Rym: we're gonna have the GeekNights book club.
Rym: oh man it's a book club.
Scott: i mean geeks i mean everyone has a freaking book club.
Scott: i mean what show does?
Scott: it's hard to find a show without a book club.
Rym: anime world order does not have a book club.
Scott: i guess they don't but they probably should.
Scott: but anyway.
Scott: so we decided hey everyone else is doing a book club.
Scott: right book clubs are actually kind of cool and you know what.
Scott: i think that our book club will actually be more valuable than a lot of the other book clubs out there because we're not going to pick the super popular books.
Scott: we're sort of going to pick books that people don't know about.
Scott: and you know it'll sort of because we've been sort of lacking on these spoilerific final thoughts kind of things and if we do a book club properly we'll sort of have these monthly final thoughts on the books and it should be fun.
Scott: and also it'll sort of you know if we just say hey people buy this right some of them buy it.
Scott: but if we say hey people buy this and exactly one month from now there's going to be a show on it where we're going to spoil the crap out of it i think a lot more people will buy it.
Rym: yeah plus i mean the thing is we're experimenting here so we're going to see exactly how this all plays out.
Rym: but i think the plan going forward is anytime we do the book club we'll kind of review a book and then that will be yours.
Rym: all right this is the book we're going to read this month but we'll review it as a so you can tell right away if you think it's the kind of thing you're going to want to read or if you just don't care.
Scott: yes i think the plan is where other book clubs right they sort of just say read this book and then at the end of the month or whatever they review the whole book.
Scott: like crazily i think what we'll do is we'll review the next book.
Scott: well we'll probably start the.
Scott: my headphones are fucking up.
Scott: we'll probably start the episode right by doing the crazy final thoughts on like the current book club book and maybe get some people on and have like discussion topics.
Rym: that yeah there's.
Rym: there's very much going to be a round table element to the final thoughts.
Scott: maybe you can skype in some listeners who've read the book or some other front row crew people who've read the book.
Rym: i can tell you one thing though the book we're starting with which is kind of a cop-out but the reason why it's a necessary book to start with yes it's we.
Rym: i've brought it up several times but don't even try to be skyped in because already i think everyone in the front row crew is thinking well i'm certainly going to be skyped in or be in person at least you know well.
Rym: only i guess ten of you can be in our house for the final thoughts episode.
Rym: i only have that many microphones.
Scott: if that boundary mic shows up we'll be all right.
Rym: yeah we'll see when that shows up.
Rym: thank you amazon.
Scott: yeah oh we could all you know we could do the amazon affiliates thing.
Scott: so we kind of get money if people buy the book by clicking the link on our website.
Rym: oh yeah set that up tonight.
Scott: all right the thing is i gotta we'll be full disclosure though about it.
Scott: we'll be like we'll put a link to the book on amazon on our website.
Scott: but if you click on that link and then buy the book we get money but you don't pay any more money.
Scott: you pay the same normal amazon price.
Scott: basically amazon makes less profit than they normally would and we get some money.
Rym: so if you want to stick it to the man feel free to not buy it through our stupid link.
Scott: yes you you will.
Scott: in that case you will give more profit to amazon and no money to us.
Scott: and you know while we i don't like making money off of people like this um being wide open about it.
Scott: well i have the option not to do it i don't like doesn't cost you anything extra.
Scott: if you're going to buy the book anyway you're given the same amount of money and i think people are listening to the show would would gladly.
Scott: you're basically by clicking a link taking a dot and buying a book you would have bought anywhere taking dollars away from amazon.
Rym: and well how many people have just sent us money unsolicitedly over the year even though we tell them not to.
Scott: yeah don't send us money.
Rym: yeah and we're serious we really don't need it.
Scott: yeah and only click on the affiliate amazon book link if you want to.
Scott: you don't.
Scott: we won't be mad if you don't.
Rym: yeah but don't worry i mean we.
Rym: we said way way back years ago you know 480 something episodes ago that there will never be ads and GeekNights.
Rym: you know what?
Rym: there will never be ads and GeekNights.
Scott: no there won't.
Rym: so tonight we are going to introduce for our inaugural book club in this kind of cop-out tired thursday night episode that we're totally almost bailing on here the prince of nothing.
Scott: now wait for the so one month from now right?
Scott: so i guess there's gonna be three thursday episodes and then the fourth thursday episode from now will be the book club episode.
Scott: we fully spoil this action.
Rym: june 5th 2008 we will.
Rym: we will have the prince of nothing round table.
Scott: so it's like the third the first thursday of the month every month unless the uh well most yeah pretty much the first thursday of every month.
Scott: now the thing is right.
Scott: this is a three book series and then there's more books coming out later that aren't out yet but it's pretty much a trilogy that stands on its own and the other books are going to be sort of separate-ish but also in the same universe.
Rym: i feel like we should do the whole trilogy.
Scott: see but can people?
Scott: i can read the whole trilogy in a month.
Rym: god i read the.
Rym: i read the first book in like like.
Rym: i started reading it and then two days later i was done.
Scott: do you think that's too much to ask people to read three entire novels in a month?
Rym: i see i don't think so because these books i i really feel like once you start reading them.
Rym: it's a rare person who is not going to finish them as fast as humanly possible it is true.
Scott: the other thing though is i'm not sure like when i bought them.
Scott: i bought the first one amazon the third one on amazon but the second one was not available on amazon except for used so i had to buy it.
Scott: i was luckily in the crappy bookstore i hate but you know the worst bookstore in the city.
Rym: it's not that bad of a bookstore.
Scott: no it's not that bad.
Rym: you know what i think it's better than the uh barnes or no the borders near us the borders near us is all right.
Rym: no the barnes and noble near us.
Scott: i'm sorry the one with all the bullshit books we have.
Rym: we have a borders and barnes and noble up here in beacon.
Scott: and well they're both in poughkeepsie.
Rym: well the lower duchess county.
Rym: they're not in poughkeepsie.
Rym: actually they're far from poughkeepsie.
Rym: the barnes and noble's in poughkeepsie actually no it's in the town of poughkeepsie which is completely separate.
Rym: no it's not.
Rym: they're not even border right now.
Rym: anyway anyway they're completely separate one's way south one's much further north.
Rym: but uh the borders isn't typical borders.
Rym: barnes and noble is full of randy craft like that.
Rym: that place must be run but like managed by the most randy person you can imagine because other barnes and noble aren't like that.
Rym: it's just that one yep all right anyway.
Scott: so the prince of rims talked about on the show before.
Scott: i think i talked about in the show a lot before.
Scott: that's why it's the perfect first for the book club.
Rym: yeah scott in fact actually made a somewhat clever joke about the prince of nothing during the escaflona episode.
Scott: you might have caught it you might have not.
Rym: i don't think it's hard to miss.
Scott: well who knows if people listen to that episode or not?
Scott: so the prince of nothing is basically.
Scott: it's a series of fantasy novels.
Scott: it you know.
Scott: so we're talking.
Scott: you know wizards dragons evil things that are kind of like orcs but not candidates paladins crusades.
Rym: see i understand why you you know jocularly pronounced knights incorrectly.
Rym: but why paladin?
Rym: and why?
Rym: yeah yeah added letters.
Rym: you can't add letters.
Rym: the joke there is.
Rym: you got to take a word and pronounce all the letters like alfred hitchcock's precise.
Scott: i did pronounce all the letters.
Rym: paladin there's no ing there's no.
Rym: in the end quiet you could say paladin no that's all right anyway.
Rym: but the one thing we got to say is that while these are fantasy books they are far from i guess stereotypical fantasy books.
Rym: i mean you expect a fantasy book.
Rym: go to the store.
Rym: there's a million of them.
Scott: well i mean the thing is you have it's.
Scott: it's weird.
Rym: they all have like the dragon and the guy on the cover and they have a lame title and they're just like generic stereotypical.
Scott: all right let's go he's the bad guy though a lot of those right are the kind of fantasy book where it's like a pulp shallow fantasy.
Scott: it's pretty much.
Scott: i'm on an adventure.
Scott: the evil wizard captured the maiden.
Scott: i will go save him the dragon's defending his castle slaying slaying slaying.
Scott: oh no but i am fought i am fought back by magic.
Scott: aha but i come back and i save the day.
Rym: hurrah of course.
Rym: then there's the extra special.
Rym: you have a licensed franchise like the uh forgotten realm.
Scott: are the dragon lands?
Rym: good god those dragon legs book oh god those are some of the worst books ever.
Scott: there's a there's a lot of those.
Scott: the thing is not every.
Scott: it's.
Scott: it's hard to tell by the cover like which ones are the quality and which ones are not.
Scott: sort of like the same thing with science fiction.
Scott: you have the pulp science fiction like i'm in a rocket making having sex with aliens and shooting robots and then you have the other ones that are wow this is hardcore like isaac asimov sci-fi heinlein.
Rym: yeah heinlein type the way i've been able to do.
Rym: well the one way to tell good fantasy books is to look for ones that don't have pictures on the cover and possibly are hardcover and large.
Scott: look for ones that have hugo and nebulae award winnings.
Rym: but there's a much much easier way.
Rym: you see there's a man named alex and what you want to do is say alex i want to read a fantasy book that doesn't suck and he would give you one because pretty much that is how i found out about the prince of nothing.
Rym: what other people were talking about.
Rym: i was like alex give me a fantasy book.
Rym: he was like here you go this is one of the best.
Rym: yep i read it like right away.
Rym: and i was like so there's more right.
Rym: and he gave me the other two.
Scott: and everyone constantly said scott read these books scott read these books and like everything else everyone tells me to read watch look at listen to.
Scott: i say i will later after i get through all the things that you told me to watch read listen to.
Rym: before the thing that the result here is that some people in the crew had read these books some time ago and then they would talk about these books and then other people in the crew had not read them would be like what's the thing you're talking about?
Rym: and then they'd go and give you the books and make you read them and then every time more people read them there were like these there was the first wave and then like four aftershocks because every time another group of the front row crew read these books suddenly everyone would be talking about them again.
Scott: maybe that's the thing like if we all read the book at the same time.
Scott: right maybe the excitement about the book won't last because we'll all be really excited about all at once and then we'll all forget about it together.
Scott: but if we if one person reads it then another person then another brand we pass the book around then each time someone reads it the excitement throughout the entire group will be reinvigorated because causing the excitement to last longer and actually the total enjoyment of the book to be increased.
Scott: because
Rym: i've seen the same thing happen with other things before especially with anime where i watch an anime all right but then knowing that someone else who had not seen it has just watched it and then having a conversation with them it's like i can almost relive vicariously through them the first reading i had or the first watching
Scott: i had.
Scott: yeah it's like as awesome as it is watch cowboy vbop infinity times which i could definitely do.
Scott: it's even more awesome to when there's someone watching it with you who hasn't seen it.
Scott: it's like if i had even if i've seen like attack the gas station is the perfect example.
Scott: attack the gas station.
Scott: i've seen it enough times you know and it's good.
Scott: but i've seen enough times where watching it again on my own is not going to be that enjoyable.
Rym: yeah the blues brothers i've seen that movie possibly more than any other two-dimensional media ever when i was a kid when i'm when i say i was a kid i'm talking when i was like four i would.
Rym: i had these little cars.
Rym: i guess they were kind of big but they're plastic cars and i would watch the blues brothers and every time there was a car scene me and my little brother would run around the house with these cars reenacting and yelling and screaming and crashing them and then we'd watch the next part.
Rym: oh god i love the blues brothers.
Scott: it's a good one but yeah um so yeah it's like if i have even if there's even one person with me who has not yet seen like the attack the gas station it's suddenly worth it to like watch the whole movie again just to watch their reaction to it.
Scott: i don't know what it is about that but it's like watching someone enjoy something that you might you know be sort of bored with.
Scott: suddenly like makes the whole thing new again.
Scott: i don't know how that works or why but it does so.
Scott: it's.
Scott: it's pretty cool.
Rym: so as a result we keep having these aftershocks and even now now that there's all this excitement again we've suddenly as a group lent these books to yet another wave of front row crew
Scott: i mean because suddenly you know i went out and bought all three books and Rym bought a hardcover the first book.
Rym: that smells like locks.
Scott: yeah yeah we're just.
Scott: you know buddy used and we're just like passing copies out.
Scott: like everybody passed the books around and alex is like well i've got to reread those because he read them longer than anybody.
Rym: i want to reread them but all the copies are lent out.
Scott: uh i got books two and three that's not not lent out.
Rym: yeah uh so i what makes these books good?
Rym: i mean we gotta convince you to read them and you do want to read these books because i think i figured it out.
Rym: i know how we're gonna do this all right when we do the round table we'll we'll make note ahead of time because i kind of kind of forget exactly where each book begins and ends.
Rym: but we'll kind of demarcate it and we'll talk about just the first book.
Rym: then we'll do the spoiler line and bring up the second book.
Rym: then we'll do the spoiler line and bring up the third book.
Scott: yeah i'm really thinking we should just do book one for the thing.
Scott: but we'll figure it out.
Scott: i'll put links uh to all three of the books in our in our episode you will not be risking much by buying all three instead of just the first one like to.
Scott: oh and i think what we should do also is i really want to emphasize because it's kind of scary.
Scott: there are people who don't read like you know.
Scott: they'll read a comic and they'll read a newspaper or magazine but they don't read books.
Scott: it's like.
Scott: it's not always that they're stupid even though i you know i could say someone doesn't read it super but reading is sort of gone out of favor with a lot of people.
Rym: what i think.
Rym: marjorie said it best those who can't read and those who don't read are the same.
Scott: yes everyone listen to this podcast right?
Scott: you think this podcast.
Scott: we're not geniuses.
Scott: this isn't the highest.
Rym: well one of us isn't a genius.
Rym: i think we both know which one right.
Scott: uh so this isn't you know the highest brow thing in the world.
Scott: we're not like.
Scott: you know one of those like high brow pbs news shows or anything right but we're higher brow than i think the average level of pop.
Scott: you know popular television entertainment if you're listening to our relatively high brow entertainment and you consider yourself like a respectable high brow more intellectual than the average person.
Scott: you gotta be reading.
Scott: i mean if you're not reading at least a fantasy book i got a fantasy book.
Rym: i remember when i was a little kid and i'd be encountered with people like that.
Rym: i just figured yeah kids are stupid.
Rym: and then i got to.
Rym: you know high school and college and i never ran into those people again.
Rym: but there was one time i was out for a walk with a bunch of friends.
Scott: i was not there.
Rym: yeah it was me and a girl i liked at the time and a guy who's uh really cool i actually realized now i haven't talked to in a long time and i kind of missed that guy.
Scott: i chat him up once in a while.
Rym: i haven't chatted up in a while.
Scott: i'm gonna chat him up pretty soon because i got a co-worker who's moving out to boston and he's out in boston.
Rym: well we all went off for a walk and it was this nice time in rochester like in the early days also a lame guy there.
Rym: well yeah but we're walking and we're talking and this is like this four hour long epic walk.
Rym: and we're talking about politics we're talking about the world and philosophy and everything and one guy who's who shall not be named again was walking along.
Rym: yes hence again he was kind of quiet most of the time and he's not a really quiet person.
Scott: generally you know i mean he's not like you know super friendly but he's not like one of those really shy quiet people.
Rym: and usually when the crew was together like the epic crew when we'd fill our tiny apartment with people and it was so loud and everyone's talking and yelling it was crazy and it was just a kind of small more intimate group.
Rym: we're out walking and we're talking and he's really quiet.
Rym: and finally we get talking about books and we start talking about science fiction books and we're going on and on and on.
Rym: then we get into the classics and i think we got to the point where we're talking about the Iliad and whether or not it was actually worth reading and then
Scott: out of the blue it's a tough one
Rym: he kind of pipes up and says i feel stupid and we're like oh come on enter the conversation.
Rym: what's up?
Rym: what books do you like to read?
Rym: he's like ah i just have nothing to say to you guys.
Rym: all right well what's a book you've read recently?
Rym: we'll talk about that.
Rym: you know we'll bring you in.
Rym: we want to.
Rym: i know we're talking about things.
Scott: we've been walking with you for how many hours.
Scott: why are you not?
Rym: we want you to say and he says i don't really read books.
Rym: what do you mean?
Rym: i don't know.
Rym: i just i don't like reading books.
Rym: and then there was this long pause as we all kind of stopped walking and stared at him like what do you mean you don't read books.
Rym: well i mean i'm kind of forced to for school and all that.
Rym: but i just i really just don't like reading and i didn't know what to say to that.
Scott: that's like someone's coming up to you and saying i want to be illiterate.
Rym: i really didn't know what to do.
Rym: it was like all right.
Rym: i have very little to say to you now.
Scott: yeah i mean we're gonna go nothing to say to us but now there's no reason for me to even associate with you.
Rym: it's like all right.
Rym: there's this.
Rym: uh i'm gonna go back to talking about the alien.
Rym: you can.
Scott: uh you can walk.
Scott: i guess yeah um read read a book read a book read a book.
Scott: so we're gonna.
Scott: we're gonna emphasize reading because i don't think we've been doing that enough.
Scott: we're gonna emphasize reading fun yet also awesome books.
Scott: i think that's what we need to do.
Scott: we need to pick books that are both fun and geeky but also with the intellectual high brownness.
Scott: we need to get that combo.
Rym: let's finish this up because i'm kind of hungry i'm kind of tired and this show is such a cop out.
Rym: i promise the next uh lounge will be rocking and awesome.
Rym: i got.
Scott: oh you better prepare something in advance because i got nothing.
Rym: i got something don't worry don't worry.
Rym: but i got to sell to you the prince of nothing books so that you'll read them.
Rym: so here's the deal.
Scott: we told you to have we been wrong?
Rym: i have excellent judgment.
Rym: i just proved it anyway.
Rym: it's a trilogy.
Rym: it consists of three books the darkness that comes before oh my god the warrior prophet and the thousand fold thought.
Rym: now these are the prince of nothing trilogy written by a canadian author r scott backer for whom i have respect.
Scott: that is undying r scott backer's credentials about his philosophy degrees.
Rym: his doctor is doctor.
Rym: he is a doctor of philosophy.
Scott: is he a doctor of philosophy?
Scott: i'm the unknown thing.
Scott: that's exactly.
Rym: r scott backer a canadian fantasy author he grew up on a tobacco farm in the simcoe area.
Rym: in 1986. he attended the university of western ontario to pursue a degree in literature and later a master's in theory and criticism.
Rym: after new oh after nearly completing but ultimately abandoning his phd in philosophy at vanderbilt opting instead to devote himself to the craft of literature rather than the crap of academia he moved on to london ontario where he now lives with his wife.
Rym: i read that from wikipedia.
Scott: yeah that's fine.
Rym: now uh he is completed.
Rym: he has also completed a science fiction thriller entitled neuropath.
Rym: why don't we get that hopes to publish in 2008?
Scott: oh that's why we don't get that now.
Rym: here's what i want to say about the prince of nothing.
Rym: here's how i will sell this to you.
Rym: if you like high fantasy but are disappointed by the fact i mean we'll say like the kinds of people that will like this book you like high fantasy.
Rym: you are disappointed that most high fantasy is pulpy crap.
Scott: it's like you want books with lots of wizards and crazy magic and wicked dragons and crazy knights stabbing each other.
Rym: but you don't want them to be stupid.
Scott: you don't want them to be shallow and lame of just haha i'm saving the day i'm the hero.
Scott: you want them to actually be intellectually deep and have meanings and messages and metaphors and analogies and all that good literary stuff.
Scott: this is that book.
Rym: if you enjoyed the idea of the silmarillion but did not enjoy reading the silmarillion i think you know you like everything about it except actually reading it.
Scott: if you like those really hard sci-fi novels but you just wish you could replace the spaceships with horses and replace the laser guns with swords and replace you know such replace the bigs big spaceships with siege engines.
Scott: that's this book.
Rym: if you want a fantasy book that is gritty realistic like the level of grittiness and this is not a happy fantasy world this is not.
Rym: the emily says this lot like yeah the middle ages are great if you don't think about the reality.
Rym: where do you think people pooped in the middle ages?
Rym: how long do you think they showered?
Scott: yeah this this book.
Rym: really nights were not clean people.
Scott: this book really throws you it doesn't you know?
Scott: put that glossy shine on the middle ages.
Scott: yes this is a dirty and filthy and disgusting and unclean and you're down in the dirt with the peasants and even the the big kings and princes are down in the dirt with the peasants.
Scott: and really oh it's good stuff.
Rym: i mean if it if you want a fantasy book that is it is fantasy.
Rym: there is magic but it's realistic to the point.
Scott: realistic magic it is.
Scott: it's self-consistent with.
Rym: it is self-consistent and the worldview presented and the world you were immersed in is very realistic even with the magic you'd be surprised.
Scott: yeah it makes sense within the context of itself even though it's impossible in the real world.
Scott: well some of it yes and it takes you know real world viewpoints and then sort of it's sort of like.
Scott: what would it be like for someone you know who thinks like a person in the in this natural world in the fantasy world and it's it's good stuff.
Scott: now beyond that well i mean how many times have i said good stuff it's good but i mean other kinds of.
Rym: if you're reading this if you're intrigued by the idea of a fantasy book that takes kind of the fundamental questions of philosophy and existentialism and basically embodies them in the thoughts and actions of not only characters but nations and cultures and basically create situations where these ideologies will in the real world come into immediate conflict with each other just to see which ones win and why this book is up your.
Scott: yeah also this book doesn't just answer questions of like philosophy.
Scott: it like it doesn't it like questions like the fundamental laws of physics in the universe.
Rym: it questions the fundamental nature of morality.
Rym: yeah and not even that motive.
Rym: yeah motive causality and it does it.
Scott: causality is pretty much the central theme of the book.
Rym: yes well especially this isn't a spoiler by any stretch.
Rym: but the title of the first book is the darkness that comes before.
Rym: and there's a point in the book when the dark pretty early on actually the darkness that comes before is explained to you in no uncertain terms.
Scott: and yeah because i mean you hear the title the darkness that comes before and you think oh well this book is probably just about like you know the big evil bad guys looming up and then in the next book like they come on strong right.
Scott: so this is like you know the building up of the big bad guys.
Rym: no not at all to express to you.
Rym: that's not what the darkness that comes before means because i remember when scott he got the book he didn't even read it.
Rym: yet he's like darkness that comes before.
Rym: i know what this is about.
Rym: and then later he's like oh okay wow.
Scott: and now if i say comes before that has a completely different meaning from what it means to most people haven't read this book and especially like this is a book.
Rym: ram i'm coming before you i don't know i don't think you've come before me yet uh-huh.
Rym: so yeah that's what i want you to think but especially when this is a book that will introduce concepts and ideas and things like that and you'll understand them you will understand them.
Rym: this is what then and later on you i guess you won't have understood the full ramifications.
Scott: yep this is actually you know usually i read a book and a book might present me with.
Scott: you know things to think about but they're like they're not new things to think about mostly because i've read books before that explored similar intellectual questions.
Rym: the zebra storyteller problem of.
Rym: i've read a book that's like like evangelion.
Rym: you watch ava.
Rym: it's like all right.
Rym: it brought up all these interesting ideas.
Rym: but at the same time if you've studied psychology and some in certain other fields of interest then all the ideas presented in ava are not very new and they're not necessarily handled in a interesting or new way.
Rym: it's like it's a good introduction but if you've already read a book not so much yeah like if i've watched battle royale.
Scott: right and battle royale is a good movie.
Scott: i haven't read the book but it didn't really have anything new for me to think about because i had already read lord of the flies and it basically britain lord of the flies too.
Rym: it brings up a cut like a few really interesting like ideas and i and you don't know what the answer is and it kind of explores the.
Rym: it kind of sets up a situation to explore these ideas and see like from where morality and humanity and all these things really derive.
Rym: yep but once you've explored those ideas it's really difficult to find something that explores them deeper.
Scott: so the prince of nothing explores ideas and things that i might have thought about in the world.
Scott: some of them and you know some of them i might have read about.
Scott: but it goes places that other books did not go or places my brain had not previously gone.
Rym: it hits you over the head with what are you?
Rym: no really what are you?
Rym: and you think all right i've thought about that before.
Rym: but then it presents for you a world where that question what are you?
Rym: is inescapable.
Scott: what do you see?
Scott: what do you say?
Scott: what do you see what am i?
Rym: uh you know.
Rym: uh these books are so good it's real good.
Scott: so a month from now what date you say?
Rym: that was i said june 5th.
Scott: june 5th is going to be an episode of GeekNights where we will do two things.
Scott: one we will do sort of a non-spoiler review of the book that we're going to fully review in july and we're going to do a group sort of book club maybe with skype maybe in person maybe a combo of the two about the prince of nothing.
Scott: at least the first book read all three if you can.
Rym: yes because in the very least i i don't know if we're gonna do three separate shows though i feel like they'd almost be warranted.
Scott: see i don't think i. i really actually and if we do when we do the final thoughts book club on it a month from now really there's not going to be much plot talking.
Scott: it's mostly going to be talking about like you know the themes and the characters mostly.
Rym: yeah i i really think if nothing else we're probably going to talk a lot about because i the reason i said you know we should break it up into three different like spoiler lines is that we can bring up concepts and questions and scenes that mean something
Scott: but
Rym: they mean something completely different after you pass the spoiler line of the next book.
Rym: yeah because new context like you see a scene or a flashback and you think oh the great war of ancient past.
Rym: and then after the second book you think oh the great war of ancient past.
Rym: and then the third book you think heron spear.
Rym: ah the heron spear nagika heron spear nagika mogg furrow.
Scott: it's mogg furrow desert punk desert.
Scott: god let's let's stop.
Scott: so at the very least before we go every all the podcasts learn to stop stealing dave and joel's jokes.
Scott: until now that's actually a really good joke dave.
Rym: yeah dave that is like the bet.
Scott: i really.
Scott: i actually think that's really funny when you do that.
Scott: so keep doing it.
Rym: i don't think you understand how often we do that.
Rym: now unreal it's the kind of you know when there's an inside joke.
Rym: that's so inside that it loses its context.
Rym: duality to where unrelated to the current conversation.
Rym: someone will suddenly say nagika yeah desert punk friends or nothing.
Scott: read it read the book.
Rym: if that didn't sell you on it.
Rym: here is the kind of plot synopsis of how these books begin and an idea of where they're going.
Scott: you can do a plot synopsis.
Scott: watch out.
Scott: so you're gonna do the shallow plot synopsis here in the ancient ancient time.
Rym: but think about this two thousand years ago.
Rym: think about this.
Rym: in the.
Rym: in the way i'm describing this you might not get the writing style which by the way these books are written amazingly like the the the diction and the prose.
Rym: he what was the line he entered the circle described by his sword?
Scott: no i don't think that was.
Rym: that was a good one but there were much better ones than that.
Scott: did it our scott packers?
Scott: way smarter than either of us that's for sure.
Rym: his writing is is wonderful.
Rym: but you should make a blog thinking if you haven't read other high fantasy think in terms of tolkin in terms of like taking these ideas.
Rym: but they are presented properly.
Rym: they are not done in a cheesy way or a pulpy way.
Rym: but basically we are presented with this kind of prologue of there is an ancient war and it will present in real time like ancient long time ago ancient times two thousand years ago exactly the no god rose.
Rym: there was a plague upon the world the horrible war between existence and non-existence.
Scott: it's pretty much the end of the world like this horrible war that like ruined all of civilization.
Rym: the end of the world happened the high times.
Rym: the ancient high fantasy world is destroyed by this this entity.
Rym: and when we talk about an entity i mean this is an entity where it was born unto the world and every living being in the womb of every mother was still born in that instance.
Scott: until for as long as the evil thing existed and no children were born.
Rym: tense yeah and wars armies of horrible beings descended from the north upon the greatest civilizations of the world that banded together attempting to fight them off.
Scott: yep so the apocalypse happened two thousand years ago.
Scott: so it happened and one king and his little kingdom of people went to their castle in the middle of nowhere.
Rym: these are the high kings.
Rym: who is basically?
Rym: yeah what the kunarik high king?
Scott: yeah it's like the king of kings like king arthur like the kingiest king there was.
Rym: these are like uh the kings of gondor.
Rym: right the guys had the big colossi of imaginative instead of you know scattering to the winds whatever they did if they had a secret castle passed down through genera like.
Rym: this was intended to be the sanctuary from the end of the world sort of like the secret base for the president under nora.
Rym: it's like if minus tereth was there but there was another minus tereth that was such a secret that no one but the ancient kings knew about it.
Rym: the ancient kings went there two thousand years ago running away from the apocalypse and i think this is so well described and then they waited and no armies besieged their gates.
Rym: no horrible demons came.
Rym: the world just slowly ended around them and they were left alone.
Rym: and then they struck by plague and one by one they died until all that remained was effectively the prince the prince the young incredibly young prince the young incredibly young bastard prince of one of the ancient kings.
Rym: yep and he's alone.
Scott: and then there's a bard who's left right.
Rym: yeah but that's not too important.
Scott: no it's not so.
Rym: then the the the dunyane these monks these monks so secret so removed from the world that no one knew about basically these isolated monks that no one had ever heard of from like the far north.
Rym: they just like they had avoided the end of the world by effectively not existing like no one knew.
Scott: if you would have gone to pretty much anyone in civilization and said dunyane basically people would have said who who?
Scott: i don't know you're talking about because they were basically unknown.
Scott: like imagine if there was some tribe of monks living in the like in antarctica under the ground.
Scott: no one knows about them no one will ever know about them but for some reason we.
Scott: they show up at this castle and the only person left in that castle is this prince.
Rym: and these monks show up and they take this prince in.
Rym: and these monks their philosophy very shallowly and briefly as you will learn very much about them is that everything can be controlled.
Rym: they they internal and external they understand the world understand their own minds understand themselves to the point that they can read other human beings perfectly.
Rym: you look they look at a human who is not one of them and they know everything.
Rym: that person's thinking not magically not through any sort of bs like that simply by the way they carry themselves.
Scott: they they know everything.
Scott: that's it's absolute.
Scott: you know logic absolute information seeing everything there is to see you know being able to do anything that they can possibly do.
Rym: so they take the prince in and they the prince becomes one of them.
Rym: fat now.
Rym: now this is this is the important part fast forward two thousand years after shows a date and the date is two thousand years later.
Rym: and remember that this is two thousand years later but it picks up as though it happened.
Scott: it was just one thousand years after the end of the world when the horrible evil conquered the world.
Rym: the much much removed ancestor of this king anna surinbor kellis his greatest greatest greatest greatest greatest grandson.
Rym: the the product of these monks and all these two thousand years of living in isolation and training he's still a monk there.
Scott: the monks are still just living in this castle that no one knows about.
Rym: after two thousand years and for reasons that become apparent later in the book the this ancestor is sent out from the monks with all of their knowledge and all of their training into the world outside to accomplish a task.
Rym: and there is a beautiful and remember this all takes.
Rym: this is a few pages.
Rym: this just sets it up and yeah this is like the prologue.
Rym: the scene where he walks out from these monks and encounters the world outside is reminiscent though does not is not done justice by the first episode of samurai jack where he learns how to see without seeing.
Rym: that's not the first episode the first one i ever saw.
Scott: that's the best episode though i've seen that episode more than any other episode.
Rym: i think there is one better episode the monks when they climb the mountain.
Scott: it's an okay one.
Rym: you've seen that one right?
Rym: maybe the one where he climbs the mountain with the monks and he gives up i don't remember.
Rym: he gives up on his quest.
Rym: all right he gives up his short.
Rym: i'm done forget aku but anyway that is not the prince of nothing.
Rym: but the scene is like that where the thing that was walking remembers that it is a man and it is apart from the things around it.
Scott: and then he meets the woodcutter and doesn't he meet the non-man before he meets the woodcutter?
Rym: oh yes the non-man i think that that's after.
Scott: yeah i don't remember the exact order it doesn't really matter.
Rym: let me put it this way in this world there are not elves like the tulcan elves and dwarves like the tulcan dwarves.
Rym: there are i mean the races.
Rym: there's the race of man there's the race of strength this abomination upon the earth.
Scott: they're sort of orkish.
Rym: there is the race of non-men that came before men and they're imagine burning wheel elves thousands of years past to the point that they've been consumed by the grief and the insanity of their immortal lives.
Scott: yeah i mean these are basically the non-men ruled the world thousands of years ago and then the ad the apocalypse sort of just ruined them.
Scott: and now they basically are ruined and crazy.
Scott: and they've been ruined and crazy for two thousand years.
Rym: and the thing is these are.
Rym: these are my favorite elves ever.
Scott: yeah i could definitely go for the non-men.
Scott: it doesn't say they're elves it just calls them non-men all the time but they sort of fit the elvish spot the same way.
Scott: the strank are not orcs but they fit the orcish spot in the fantasy world.
Scott: yeah.
Rym: but and from there from this humble beginning of this man walks out of this monastery sequestered away for two thousand years of generations upon generations is encountered with the world and from there we are taken into the present day of this world and there is an epic holy war being undertaken and kings of all the nations and it's that's it.
Rym: i don't want to even spoil beyond that point the where these books get from where they began.
Rym: it is almost impossible to have expected it get where it is from where it began.
Scott: it's like you look at the map in the back of the book and you know how you look at like maps and tokian books like half the map doesn't get used and stuff like that.
Scott: right you look at this map that map gets super used.
Scott: i was flipping back to the map constantly more than any other book ever and you know what you got to do.
Scott: you know books with maps.
Scott: those are dangerous books.
Rym: also books that have depictions of the actual writing of the people in the books.
Scott: yeah you gotta watch out for those too.
Scott: those are dangerous.
Rym: but uh to do not really say any more about the plot there's one other type of person who will like these books if you like burning wheel.
Rym: these books are so set up to be a burning wheel campaign.
Scott: yeah pretty much the.
Rym: every character is so strong and interesting and it it's very difficult to not become lost in these characters.
Scott: oh yeah pretty much and i'm sure like everyone you know it's.
Scott: it doesn't seem like there's that many characters but like you think of any person in your life after reading these books and you'll see a character in this book that's like for them.
Rym: it's like oh that's your character yep because like i look at scott johnson it's like wow scott johnson is all about akamian.
Scott: he's super about it.
Rym: he could also be about the priest guy.
Rym: in the beginning i feel like he would have that person who would have been friends with akamian.
Rym: yep of course he would have been stupid and turned to religion and Rym.
Scott: he's either the confess or maybe the proyas.
Rym: of course the way these books were introduced to me is our friend kate.
Rym: in the front row crew said Rym you gotta read these books because you were callous and i was like all right whatever and i read the book and i was like the fuck.
Rym: do you think of me kate what the hell?
Rym: yeah yeah i like proyas but he's very conflicted.
Rym: he is very conflicted and i'm i don't think i'm con fast but or confess i think that sounds better.
Rym: but my character in burning wheel that we're playing right now is definitely going down that path.
Scott: yeah and i'm some sort of nayer.
Scott: ish not quite but maybe you know i also have some zinnamus action.
Scott: i like zinnamus a lot and this is my man.
Rym: i like everyone except sereway but i like stairway sucks.
Rym: i like her as a character though she's.
Scott: no i don't.
Scott: i completely don't like her at all.
Rym: she's a great character.
Scott: yeah great to hate.
Rym: she is my proof and she is my prize.
Scott: no not really man.
Scott: she's great for hating all right.
Rym: look these books are absolutely amazing.
Rym: i you must read these books.
Rym: read the first one if nothing else.
Rym: i practically guarantee unless you're illiterate you will want to read the second two.
Rym: if you're illiterate learn to read and then read these books.
Scott: yeah all right.
Scott: sorry sorry blind people i don't think there's a braille edition.
Rym: i'm sorry i'm sure they're audiobooks.
Rym: okay there's got.
Rym: there is an audiobook i'm sure.
Scott: check audible.
Scott: yes check it right now.
Rym: i feel like i should buy the audiobook and then listen to it.
Scott: well check audible right now.
Rym: all right all right all right i'm checking audible scott say stuff while i check audible.
Scott: uh rims checking audible.
Scott: okay uh audible i actually think is still a rip-off.
Scott: but if you're blind i imagine it's worth like like.
Scott: it's like a bargain.
Scott: yeah i'm not a big fan of.
Scott: i wonder who does the audiobooks?
Scott: does it say like who?
Scott: who does them?
Rym: i think there's a different like actor for each one.
Scott: uh if they had you know what'd be cool is if you actually did different actors for all the characters and did like a full audio drama.
Scott: the whole thing the thing is is a lot of characters thinking and there's a lot of descriptions of.
Rym: i don't see it in here.
Scott: uh so sad wait wait wait i looked wrong.
Scott: let me look again and there's a lot of details like.
Scott: i don't think this is one thing where like i tried to imagine it being a movie and it would be real.
Scott: i don't think this is possible to translate to any other medium without basically destroying it.
Rym: it's not in here.
Rym: well the thing is i feel like the events of these books would make an amazing movie but they wouldn't be the books.
Rym: no well that's the thing.
Rym: what happens in the books in terms of just like i imagine like make a movie that was these books and it would be absolutely amazing.
Scott: i think it could put the lord of the rings to shame easily but it would be so hard to make but it would leave out like so much.
Scott: oh no that's the thing the stuff you couldn't get it across.
Rym: it would be a movie that would probably be in my top three movies ever like.
Rym: if it was done correctly.
Rym: it what happens is so cinematic but at the same time there is so much that could not be portrayed on the screen.
Rym: i feel like they should make the movies anyway but only if like.
Scott: remember how there's so many dreams and there's so many like people.
Scott: just like giving people knowing looks.
Scott: but those knowing looks like mean a lot more.
Rym: but you can't really also what is going on in people's head like there's a scene where here i will there's.
Rym: this is one of my favorite scenes in the first book but i don't want to spoil it but there's a scene where uh confus the nephew of the emperor of what is effectively the Byzantine empire.
Rym: it comes back from his from a campaign that he has been successful in.
Rym: he comes back to his nation and he is kneeling before his uncle the emperor and there's a big procession and him and his uncle are talking before the crowd and talking quietly to each other.
Rym: so they're already these two conversations going on simultaneously the public conversation of the triumphant general returning and the emperor who is greeting him.
Rym: but then they're kind of talking to each other quietly because there's somewhat of an adversarial relationship.
Rym: there there's also the looks and the the interaction between the emperor and his vizier who definitely has an opinion on the whole thing.
Rym: and then the whole time you see what is going on in the head of the nephew and what he is thinking makes that scene one of the best scenes in these books.
Scott: yeah well another great thing about the book is that it's sort of it's told from like.
Scott: it's a first person book but who that first person is changes.
Scott: so like it'll be telling the book from the perspective as if you know uh a kamian was the main character and you're seeing everything through his eyes.
Rym: every chapter is like that so it's not every chapter it's.
Scott: and then there'll be a little horizontal line.
Scott: oh yeah yeah and then it'll say okay now everything is from the barbarian's eyes.
Rym: now the great thing here is that basically what you were presented with is that every narrator is an unreliable narrator but at the same time you have many many narrators.
Rym: so like in the course of like there are these scenes where everyone is sitting around a cat like there's this group of people who sit around a campfire marching along with the holy war and you keep seeing this campfire and the people around it from all these different perspectives and every one of them casts it in a completely different light.
Rym: yep and the book will trick you too because there's a couple times where i'm like yeah yeah yeah wait a minute god damn it he tricked me.
Scott: i knew he's tricking me and he tricked me anyway.
Scott: are we going long here?
Rym: i think we're done.
Rym: this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to dj pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the rss feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: mondays are science and technology tuesdays we have video games board games and rpgs.
Rym: wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: you can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: if you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in itunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Scott: don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.