Rym: So continuing on with our kind of brand new series, Profiles in Geek, or I don't know, maybe we'll rename it, I'm not sure.
Rym: We're here with one of our friend podcasters, and it's one of the few podcasts out there we actually listen to, so take heed.
Rym: This is Gerald from Anime World Order.
Guest: Hey guys, what's up?
Guest: Woo, alright.
Guest: Alright, Gerald.
Scott: So Gerald, we just said that we listened to the Anime World Order.
Scott: Do you listen to the GeekNights?
Guest: Yes, I do occasionally.
Guest: Because my job is largely sitting in front of a computer all day, podcasts are kind of how I make it through the day.
Guest: Mm-hmm.
Guest: Yeah.
Rym: See, I can pull the card of, "But I listen to all of Anime World
Rym: Order!".
Guest: It's so hard to listen to all of us since we come out with an episode a month or so.
Rym: I know, god, it's like I'll hit iTunes, like, "Oh, they updated!
Rym: Download,
Rym: listen!".
Rym: And then that's it.
Rym: It's done, and now I gotta wait.
Scott: But I guess in some ways it makes it sort of, you know, special, where like you'll actually listen to all of them because it's like a rare treat, whereas GeekNights is like, "There's so
Scott: much!".
Scott: So you don't feel bad, you know, not eating, you know, eating all of it.
Guest: I don't know.
Guest: Yeah, how many episodes do you guys have now?
Guest: Like, 100-something?
Rym: 490-something.
Rym: A lot.
Guest: Okay.
Guest: That's a lot.
Guest: Yeah.
Scott: That's why I marked them with dates instead of numbers, so I wouldn't get scared.
Rym: Well, also because the ID3 version 1 only lets you have three digits in the podcast or number episode field, so we realized early on we couldn't go with that.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Alright, so if you do listen to GeekNights, how did you discover the GeekNights?
Guest: I'm pretty sure I found it through when Daryl met you at, was it Katsucon?
Rym: It was Katsucon two or three years ago.
Rym: I forget which Katsucon.
Scott: I think it was four years ago because I think you went, you didn't go.
Rym: No, it was.
Rym: Yeah, because it was one of the Katsucons where I drank, which was every Katsucon, but the most recent one.
Guest: Yeah, Daryl insists that you had short hair then.
Scott: No, that's... Rama has had long hair since I've known him, which is since 2000.
Rym: I've had long hair since 10th grade.
Scott: Yeah, so Daryl is...
Rym: I did, however, still have the mustache.
Scott: He did have the stache.
Rym: And I was, I remember very specifically...
Guest: Maybe that was a beard time, actually.
Rym: I might have had a beard because that whenever I was drunk, the times when I'm drunk, I tend to have beards, but I was quite drunk when I met Daryl.
Guest: Maybe he was mistaking the beard for hair.
Scott: Maybe he thought it was someone else.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I wasn't sure what to make of Daryl because he came over to me and showed a microphone in my face.
Rym: He's like, I'm a podcaster, blah, blah, blah.
Rym: And I was like, well, I'm a podcaster too.
Scott: I wasn't there.
Scott: So this story is still funny to me.
Scott: Because didn't you have Scott Johnson's like tape recorder?
Rym: I did.
Rym: And I couldn't.
Rym: actually, it was the worst thing ever.
Rym: I got drunk and decided I was going to be a real podcaster journalist.
Rym: So I went around interviewing people at the convention, but I was drunk.
Rym: So this tape was this rambling collection of, how are you enjoying the con?
Rym: Get away from me, dude.
Guest: So are you like the friendly drunk or the quiet drunk?
Scott: Rym is the root beer tapper playing drunk.
Rym: That's pretty much it.
Rym: I get drunk and eventually I end up at a root beer tapper machine somewhere.
Guest: Interesting.
Guest: You should experiment and put yourself in like the middle of the Sahara or something.
Guest: See if you just unearth the root beer tapper machine.
Scott: You kidding?
Scott: That's what they put all of them.
Scott: That's why there's so few in this country.
Rym: Have you ever been to the Katsucon?
Guest: Me?
Guest: No.
Guest: And I really wanted to go because that year that Darryl went, they had Akira Kamiya there.
Guest: And Akira Kamiya is one of my favorite.
Guest: He's awesome.
Rym: Actually, if you really want to hang out with him, go to an amazement because he's there almost every year.
Rym: And as long as you make friends with the staff, he totally just hangs out with everybody in the back room.
Rym: And then he's awesome.
Rym: He's like the best guy ever.
Guest: I bet.
Guest: And I mean, he spends all his time now, like teaching other voice actors and not not doing enough voice acting himself.
Guest: But well, I guess he doesn't need to since like Detective Conan fills that void.
Rym: But he did this panel one year I was staff at an amazement where he actually, despite not really speaking English with the audience, he ran a voice acting clinic.
Rym: And it was.
Rym: it was crazy how awesome that panel was.
Guest: Yeah, Darryl was telling me that at the panel he went to, he talked about like how he did the voices.
Guest: And he'd talk very specifically about how he positioned his mouth to to like do Kenshiro's voice and things like that.
Guest: I guess if you've been doing it for 30 years, you've pretty much got it down, which is unfortunate that he can't do the voice of Kenshiro anymore.
Scott: Yeah.
Guest: So, you know, I just I just heard recently that Mari Ijima can't physically sing the songs from Macross anymore.
Scott: Really?
Scott: Because she was she was like going around the country singing like not more than like a year or two ago, right?
Guest: Like, yeah, she was actually just at some concert in Japan.
Guest: It was like Minmay meets like Fire Bomber or something like that.
Guest: It was like.
Scott: it was also like all that Macross anniversary stuff.
Scott: And then, yeah, it was all that she was like New York Comic Con, like one of the not this year, but maybe two or three years ago.
Scott: I forget.
Guest: Yeah, I just heard from from a friend of mine, Mike Dent, that she she does can't.
Guest: I thought it was a licensing issue, but I guess she can't like physically sing those songs anymore.
Guest: Like her voice just can't take it.
Scott: We can get the Hatsune Miku whatever to sing the song.
Guest: As far as I'm pretty sure that she probably has, because geeks have got nothing better to do with their time.
Guest: Have you seen that one that one video?
Guest: I think that was one of your things of the day where they set like the Mario 2 to like some music and it had it play some music.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: Those perpetual motion slash Rube Goldberg Mario machines.
Guest: Yeah.
Guest: And it had just played like the music from the Nico Nico Doga medley.
Guest: OK.
Rym: The one I listened to that I really liked, it was.
Rym: it was just all I could think when I first listened was, wow, it's Nightwish in Japanese.
Rym: This is awesome.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The best one that I saw was the one that was doing the the Bocorato uninstall.
Scott: That was a good one.
Scott: I like that.
Guest: Yeah, it was really impressive.
Guest: And from what I understand, it was like a team effort.
Guest: Like they just sent it off and some people did one bit of it.
Scott: That's why it was so many separate screens as opposed to just one big long one.
Guest: Right.
Scott: Right.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So, Gerald, you listen to, I guess, some GeekNights.
Scott: We in so many episodes, you know, we often run out of show ideas and end up making shows like this, which are sort of cop outs.
Scott: So can you give us an idea for a GeekNights' episode that you would like to hear?
Guest: A GeekNights' episode, why?
Guest: why Black Lion is an awesome show and anyone who dislikes it is stupid.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So how can we get this Black Lion that I've never heard of?
Guest: You can buy it.
Guest: It's it's on DVD.
Guest: It's just out of print.
Rym: Oh, great.
Rym: I'll get it.
Guest: There are many.
Guest: there are many haters of it.
Guest: They don't understand that, you know, a show set in the 15th century about that contains time machine cyborgs that spits missiles out of their face, out of their mouth.
Guest: And the guy that's gotten his head cut, cut off and been blown up several times can be good.
Guest: It's by going to guy.
Scott: So, well, there we go.
Guest: Yeah, we go.
Guest: Yeah.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Well, we'll put that on the list somewhere.
Guest: It's forty five minutes long.
Guest: That's the entire show.
Scott: Really?
Scott: Oh, maybe then we will do it.
Scott: That's that actually sounds doable.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: That's the biggest problem we have now is we want to review a lot more shows because, you know, we kind of split up with comics and all that.
Rym: But we don't have time to watch.
Rym: I mean, I'm just now watching Kazuno Yojimbo from like 2002.
Rym: Yeah, it's not that good.
Guest: Well, that's kind of how we live.
Guest: I mean, I'm getting through what?
Guest: Nobody's Boy Remy.
Guest: That's from nineteen seventy three.
Guest: That is the saddest show I've ever seen in my life directed by Asama Dezaki.
Guest: It's it's so sad.
Rym: Have you seen Bocorano all the way through?
Guest: No, not all the way through.
Guest: But I have a hard time believing Bocorano can be sadder than this show.
Scott: I haven't I haven't seen enough of either show to make a judgment.
Scott: But remember, what was that show?
Scott: It was like blue boy, blue something.
Scott: Why do we watch it?
Scott: Anime club like freshman year in the science of Romeo's blue sky.
Scott: That's it.
Guest: That's I've actually I think I've seen that show.
Scott: Yeah, that's the show where that's a sad show.
Rym: Oh, you're a kid who's poor.
Rym: Oh, don't worry.
Rym: Your dad's going to pull through and make it.
Rym: Oh, no, your dad's got cancer and your house burned down.
Guest: Oh, it's.
Guest: it's like that every episode.
Guest: It's like, oh, you're such a happy kid.
Guest: Oh, you're you're so poor.
Guest: Oh, you're you're you're a cow.
Guest: That's the only thing that's good to you in the world.
Guest: was was sold.
Guest: Oh, now you are sold.
Guest: You have to act like an idiot in front of people.
Guest: Oh, your best friends die.
Guest: Oh, a meteorite hit your house.
Guest: So there's horrible things constantly happening.
Rym: Of course, then there's the now and then here and there, which is all.
Rym: that show was particularly brutal because it started out like a fantasy rock.
Rym: In the next episode, dead cat and rape all around.
Guest: Hilarious.
Guest: Laugh a minute.
Scott: OK, so something other than basically what I'm going to ask is I want you to give me a suggestion on how to make it better.
Scott: But I think you're just.
Scott: I don't want you to say do an episode about black lines.
Scott: You have to see something else.
Guest: Hmm.
Guest: So are you talking about like any particular day?
Scott: No, no, no.
Scott: Just like, you know, it could be anything.
Scott: Just something that we can change about GeekNights.
Scott: that would improve the show in some way.
Guest: I think if you if you played every episode like Dolomite, then that would be awesome.
Guest: Were you saying the entire episode in rhymes that you would have people listening?
Guest: That would be pretty awesome.
Scott: I think that might take too much preparation, but maybe we could be one episode like that.
Rym: You should you realize that hesitation rhymes just fine.
Rym: And then you totally missed your chance.
Scott: I know.
Scott: What do you want?
Scott: I'm I'm hungry.
Rym: All right, Scott, do you have any questions that aren't so blah, blah, blah GeekNights?
Scott: I know.
Scott: I know those are.
Scott: it's just I sort of stack the top of the questions that way.
Scott: And I'm I'm still reworking on these.
Scott: All right.
Scott: There's only the second one of these we've done.
Scott: Give me a break.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So, Gerald, you're obviously primarily the anime geek.
Scott: But do you have any other geekries besides that?
Guest: I do like video games a lot.
Guest: I'm actually was playing through Metal Gear Solid three subsistence because Metal Gear Solid four is coming out and I kind of want to be up on that.
Guest: I like I'm a really big fan of like 90s adventure games like PC games, like the LucasArts stuff.
Rym: Oh, man, that's for glory.
Rym: You ever play Quest for Glory?
Guest: Quest for Glory now.
Rym: Oh, that's the best one.
Scott: It says the way.
Scott: if you would have said yes or you would have we would have just been able to kill 10 minutes of you talking about it.
Guest: But stuff like Graham Fandango and Dave, the tentacle and Sam and Max and those point and click ones, I'm a I'm a huge fan of those.
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Scott: I really like the stories and the plots and a lot of those games and the animation and everything, you know.
Scott: But I found that when I try to play them now, like I loaded up the scum V.M.
Scott: a little while ago and I tried to play like full throttle and some of the other ones.
Scott: And if you use a fact, basically you just burn right through the game and you see the you know, the story and then it's over.
Scott: If you don't use a fact, it's just really frustrating because it turns into a game of click on absolutely everything and absolutely every combination until you move forward or, you know, pay attention.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Solve the play.
Scott: Sometimes it makes sense, but sometimes it just doesn't.
Guest: Sometimes it really depends on the logic of the world.
Guest: Like there are some point and click adventures where the answers are logical and some of them are just crazy.
Guest: Like if did you guys ever play any of the Legend of Kaelandria series?
Scott: I've never heard of that.
Guest: A Corandia?
Scott: Oh, actually, no.
Scott: Yeah, I might have heard of that.
Scott: I think I saw the name somewhere.
Guest: Yeah, it came out in the early 90s and it was by Westwood.
Guest: And they were like the epitome of if you do not collect these items and go to this area, then you will die and you will have to reset your entire game.
Scott: So Shadowgate.
Guest: Yeah.
Guest: And like one of the one of the problems that came up was like you had to sneak into this bathroom or something like that.
Guest: I forgot.
Guest: And you had to fool the guy who was guarding it.
Guest: And the way to fool him.
Guest: And if this makes sense to you, like if you would figure this out through the game's logic, you had to find a squirrel, hypnotize the squirrel and wear it on your head as a hat before you could sneak in.
Scott: So wait.
Scott: So these this is Westwood, right?
Scott: So those are the same people that made Command and Conquer.
Scott: And I believe, didn't they also make like the Blade Runner game?
Guest: Yep.
Guest: That one, too.
Rym: That game was actually really good.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Didn't they?
Scott: I think they made the Planescape torment game, you know, maybe.
Guest: I don't think so.
Scott: I don't remember, but I think there was an advertisement for it in one on one of the CD-ROMs for like Red Alert.
Scott: I don't remember.
Guest: Yeah.
Guest: Some of them were just out there.
Guest: Like even today, there's the the the touch detective on on Nintendo DS is like that.
Scott: No, really?
Scott: Because I was I was thinking about getting that when it was like 10 bucks.
Guest: It's a really great game and I really like the style in it.
Guest: But you can't get through the game without a fact, because like, again, one of the puzzles is you have to get into this room.
Guest: And in order to get into this room, you have to make the landlady have memories of her youth.
Guest: How do you have her have memories of her youth?
Guest: By finding a bicycle pump and pumping her up so she floats away.
Rym: See, you got to go with the deja vu strategy where you knock her out and pump her full of methadone.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Deja vu was actually.
Scott: that was a game that I was able to beat on logic alone.
Scott: I mean, it took me a while as a kid, but I was a little.
Rym: there's one problem with logic in that game, because I remember the first time I beat it.
Scott: Right before you go to the police station at the end, give absolutely everything you can to the evil alligator in the sewer.
Rym: No, no.
Rym: My problem was I had everything I needed.
Rym: I went to the bungalow.
Rym: I got it all.
Rym: I, of course, saved my game.
Scott: You didn't have enough money to pay for the taxi.
Rym: I had.
Rym: no.
Rym: I had two twenty dollar bills, but not enough quarters.
Rym: And the cabbie wouldn't take a twenty.
Rym: And that was the end.
Scott: Yep.
Guest: Yeah.
Guest: At least they're not like the any of those games done by Roberta Williams.
Guest: Those are just brutal.
Scott: No, I'm playing the new penny arcade one.
Scott: I play.
Scott: I played it for like five, 10 minutes.
Scott: Well, we'll see how it goes.
Guest: So it was only worth playing for five or 10 minutes.
Scott: Well, no, it's all I've had the time to play it so far.
Scott: Oh, OK.
Scott: My my first impression of five, 10 minutes is that, you know, the theme of the game is absolutely amazing because it's all penny arcaded and the gameplay is average, not really exciting or revolutionary.
Rym: It's better than that card game.
Scott: You know, it's like click on a box, get an item, you know, turn based, fight the little fruit fucker, you know, Final Fantasy, you know, fighting combat, whatever.
Guest: The very few impressions that I've heard of it give me the idea that if you do not if you are not a penny arcade devotee, then most of the humor will be over your head.
Scott: That probably makes sense.
Scott: That makes a lot of sense.
Guest: Yeah.
Scott: All right.
Rym: So well, speaking of penny arcade, you read any webcomics?
Guest: No, actually, I don't.
Guest: I've actually had a hard time getting into webcomics because I read.
Guest: I tried to read a couple like way, way, way back when.
Rym: Oh, and they were all awful.
Guest: Yeah.
Guest: And I think that that probably scared me away.
Guest: And then then people have like said, oh, you should check this out or you should check that out.
Guest: And I guess with webcomics, they being a webcomic, you can be very, very focused on what sort of humor you want and what sort of audience you want to to read you.
Guest: And invariably, I'm not that audience.
Guest: And like, I like XKCD some of the time.
Rym: I love that comic.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I get the feeling, Gerald, to be a Dr.
Scott: McNinja fan.
Rym: I think you'd be a Perry Bible Fellowship fan.
Scott: Oh, yeah, definitely.
Guest: Yeah, I read a bunch of that.
Guest: Like that's one that I heard about and I read a few.
Guest: And again, that was kind of hit and miss for me.
Guest: And I guess that that's kind of the best you can say about any webcomic.
Rym: Well, if you're if you seem to enjoy, I mean, now and then here and there is a laugh riot and the parking lot is full is probably right up your alley.
Rym: Oh, boy.
Rym: That's goofy time is all I got to say about that.
Scott: Don't don't keep talking about that stuff.
Guest: It's no good.
Rym: Or I'm surprised I never read like the Thin H line.
Guest: I did read to the Thin H line way back when, like when I had a really old dial up modem.
Rym: Yeah, I remember.
Rym: I love that comic, but at the same time, I look back at it and I'm not sure if I actually find it funny.
Guest: Well, I just remember that it had like five different jokes or so.
Guest: And once it had gotten through all those jokes, basically just had to recycle those jokes.
Guest: I'm not actually certain if it's it's still going today.
Rym: I don't think so.
Scott: No, it ended when we were in college still.
Scott: And then he went out to do something else and then he think he quit.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I don't remember.
Guest: Yeah, that was really popular for a while.
Scott: Well, you read the manga, right?
Scott: But do you read any non manga comics that are printed?
Guest: Non manga comics that are printed?
Guest: No, not really.
Guest: And that's not like meant to be a stub towards American comics at all.
Guest: It's just more like I've got piles and piles of unread manga here.
Guest: I don't need to add piles and piles of unread American comics.
Scott: Yeah, I've got.
Scott: I got piles and piles of unread both.
Scott: So.
Scott: Yeah.
Guest: It's kind of like how people were saying to me, you know, you should get onto World of Warcraft.
Guest: You should play that with us.
Guest: And I've got a bunch of unopened games here.
Guest: Tons.
Guest: Like I got.
Guest: I just buy them when they're really, really cheap.
Guest: So I've got enough games.
Guest: If I never bought another game, I'd probably be set for years.
Rym: I know that.
Rym: I mean, I bought Bioshock like right when it came out.
Rym: I played up until that doctor.
Rym: I killed him.
Rym: And to this day, I have not played beyond that point.
Rym: I've got.
Scott: I got Bioshock right now.
Scott: I've got let's see.
Scott: I still didn't be.
Scott: I got Okami for the Wii.
Rym: You haven't even turned that on.
Scott: I never actually beat Super Paper Mario.
Scott: I didn't.
Scott: I'm still working on Mario Kart.
Scott: I got the Rondo of Swords.
Scott: I didn't actually beat Mario Soccer ever.
Scott: Right.
Scott: OK.
Guest: That game or is it more like?
Scott: you can get all you can like.
Scott: do all the single player like tournament cup.
Scott: You can win all the cups.
Scott: OK.
Rym: Scott tends to unlock everything for me in multiplayer games.
Rym: And I just play the multiplayer.
Rym: All right.
Scott: I got Civ IV, which I just bought.
Scott: I got the Bioshock.
Rym: I got that already.
Rym: I think you're right.
Scott: Oh, I got Bioshock, Everyday Shooter and the Penny Arcade game.
Guest: Yeah.
Scott: So none of those games I've beaten.
Scott: I have them all sitting there.
Rym: Plus, where do you watch the most recent Yahtzee?
Rym: You got to buy Painkiller now, too.
Scott: I probably do.
Scott: Actually, it's I read someone.
Scott: I read a review of Yahtzee's review and it sounded like a game.
Scott: I want to sound like a game I might be interested in.
Guest: Yeah.
Guest: And so I don't really need to get World of Warcraft.
Guest: That's fifteen dollars a month that will fill up my life.
Guest: And I will never talk to anybody ever again.
Scott: Well, you'll talk to the World of Warcraft.
Rym: You'll make friends in the game.
Guest: But World of Warcraft people are the most vile people in the world.
Rym: General, I could kiss you right now because this is listeners that love that action.
Rym: This has always been a we always get into arguments in our forums about World of Warcraft.
Rym: And my feelings are just that I've better things to do with my life, implying that you also have better things to do with your life.
Guest: And well, I pretend that I've got better things to do with my life, but I just I just tend to do them alone rather than with other shitty people.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I think I think people like us could enjoy a game like, wow, a lot more if it was more skill based and less.
Rym: How much time do you spend in front of it to get the mad loot with a one point four eight nine percent drop rate?
Guest: Yeah, I don't know.
Guest: I mean, it might be a perfectly nice, perfectly good game.
Guest: And I've heard from people that, you know, it's still a fun game to play.
Guest: But it just seems like I don't really want to get involved in that because everybody I know who plays it is insane.
Guest: And they spend every night doing only that.
Guest: And I never see them and I never talk with them.
Guest: And I don't want to be like that.
Guest: I'm I'm perfectly fine doing my things.
Guest: And I've got enough anime to watch.
Guest: I don't need I don't need a World of Warcraft to be taking up any more time.
Rym: Got anime, just like unfinished games.
Rym: There's enough anime that I haven't seen to where they could never make an anime again.
Rym: And I'd still have stuff to watch for the rest of my life.
Scott: As long as you get your hands on it.
Guest: Yeah.
Guest: Well, I tend to go wild when there are sales on.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Whenever I'm at a con and there's the guy with the four or five dollar DVDs.
Rym: I have three separate copies of the second or say it's a movie just because I love that movie.
Guest: Yeah, that's a really good one.
Guest: I just ordered all of Gotcha Man, the original Gotcha Man, Battle of the Planets.
Scott: That's the one with the guys with the bird hats, right?
Guest: Yeah.
Guest: So they had a. those box sets are kind of tricky to find.
Guest: And the show is just awesome.
Guest: And it's I'm afraid that that's going to be one of those shows like or Battle of Dunbine that you're just never going to see the end of it because those DVDs, they're only going to produce like 20 DVDs of it later.
Guest: And then they're just going to be gone forever.
Scott: Mm hmm.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So anime is obviously your biggest geekery.
Scott: But how did you originally become an anime fan?
Scott: I mean, you weren't born with like, you know, a fan sub hanging out of your mouth.
Guest: Were you close to it?
Guest: Well, it's kind of a long and boring story, but I'll keep it as short as possible.
Guest: No, it's actually not long and boring at all.
Guest: It's just boring.
Guest: The I started watching anime when I was living in South Africa.
Guest: And we had one channel on television that was on for about six hours a day.
Guest: That was ironically called TV one.
Guest: And we that they showed Robotech on there.
Guest: And I remember watching that and I was really young.
Guest: But I knew that this was just something very different from, you know, Paddington Bear and Scooby Doo and things like that.
Guest: And when I came to America, there was a little bit more of it on TV, not a whole lot.
Guest: But we were in the Virgin Islands and in the Virgin Islands, it's impossible to get much anime down there.
Guest: And my roommate is looking at me very weirdly as I'm talking.
Scott: Hello, roommate.
Scott: We should talk to your roommate.
Rym: What's he really like?
Guest: My roommate is female.
Guest: No, no.
Scott: That's what we would tell you.
Scott: We would ask your roommate, what is Gerald really like?
Guest: Oh, what am I really like?
Guest: Oh, she's going to say horrible things about me.
Scott: Yes, that's the idea.
Guest: She's laughing.
Guest: She's agreeing with that.
Scott: All right.
Guest: She said Gerald's a faggot.
Guest: I disagree with that.
Scott: So the Virgin Islands, where Gerald's from?
Guest: Yeah.
Guest: Then basically every time we'd make a trip to Puerto Rico or to Florida, I would generally get to the comic book stores, because that's the only place you could find anime.
Guest: And I think around 1988 or '89, I found a copy of Akira in a comic book store.
Guest: It was like 40 bucks.
Guest: Wow, that's a lot.
Guest: Video comics edition.
Scott: Is it the subtitled one?
Guest: No, that subtitled version came much later.
Scott: Oh, really?
Guest: Yeah.
Guest: It was the special subtitled edition that I think was like widescreen, but it wasn't actually widescreen.
Guest: It was cropped.
Scott: Yeah, that was the one that the anime club had a VHS of.
Scott: It came in like a little white box.
Guest: Yeah, yeah.
Scott: Yeah, that one.
Guest: Yeah, this was the old video comics one.
Guest: And I remember watching this and it seemed like pretty hard for a while.
Guest: And then suddenly like there's the guy walking through the cars and then the dog runs at him and then he pulls out the gun and shoots the dog right in the head.
Guest: Like, wow, this is pretty rough.
Guest: And then the other dog jumps at him and then he shoots it and it splats against the car.
Guest: And there's the kid inside the car and there's this dead dog guts all over the car.
Guest: Like, wow, this is interesting.
Rym: And that's how I felt, you know, vampire 100D when I was in fourth grade.
Scott: No, it's funny because actually I haven't seen a care in a long time.
Scott: And I actually sort of I needed to buy something on Amazon to get an order to have free shipping.
Scott: So I'm like, oh, I'll get the Akira DVD, you know, the the the pioneer genie on one, because I didn't have it.
Scott: So I said, all right, I'll get it.
Scott: I should own that.
Scott: So I just showed up recently and I was like, oh, I remember this.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: Oh, yeah, that's good.
Guest: Yeah, I really I really miss that dub, though.
Guest: The the old Cam Clark Streamline Pictures dub, which I miss some of it.
Rym: Do you think it's really?
Rym: I mean, is it good or is it just pure nostalgia?
Guest: I think that it has its moments that are certainly memorable because I can't like things ironically.
Guest: I either like them or I don't.
Guest: There's no distinction for me if it's like an ironic love or any other sort of love.
Guest: But I mean, the one like the Colonel was played by the guy that did Macruff, the crime dog.
Guest: And there are points in that dub where he growls and you can hear it.
Guest: The I do like it a whole lot.
Guest: Actually, what?
Guest: And I don't think Akira wasn't the first anime that I owned, though.
Guest: I think I might have owned.
Guest: No, no, no.
Guest: I couldn't have owned much before that, because I think the other anime after that was like Project Aco and Gal Force and things like that.
Rym: Now, now, were you one of those people?
Rym: I don't know if you've said this.
Rym: I forget.
Rym: And I had my world order because I forget where a lot of people seem to watch Project Aco as kids and they didn't get that.
Rym: it was a joke and they see because I actually had.
Rym: it was serious business and what's going on and where'd you get those powers?
Rym: Oh, my God.
Guest: I actually we actually had this discussion and I'm in the group that that I watched it and I saw it as a comedy because, you know, the faces weren't all crazy and such.
Guest: And to me, that was a sign of a comedy.
Guest: And Darryl was in the in the group of that.
Guest: This was, you know, an action movie with some comedic moments.
Guest: So and I don't really know disparage people either way.
Guest: I just want them to watch Project Aco.
Guest: So, yeah, I was actually thought I actually thought it was a comedy like I don't know that the big Mari, the like Kenshiro.
Rym: I love her voice in the dubs.
Guest: Yeah, well, but they did actually get two different people for both the dub and the subversion unless they just like cut the sub like screaming in the sub into the dub.
Guest: That dub was really good, though.
Guest: That was I thought it was actually one of those dubs that was done in London, but it wasn't.
Guest: It was actually done by just off Broadway actors.
Guest: But I really love that old dub a lot.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, I there was a period I think it was a few months back where I went around like listening to like audio clips from, you know, old dubs that I thought I liked or or did like and just listening to them.
Scott: I sort of had it was it was very weird because on the one hand, my modern sensibility of, oh, that dub is terrible, hit me on one side.
Scott: But then the other half of my brain was like, oh, the nostalgia, it's so great.
Scott: Don't you remember this?
Scott: And I'm like, no.
Scott: And it was it really tore me in half.
Rym: Kind of I think those old dubs had in some ways a lot more heart than a lot of modern dubs, even if that's just a product of less professional development.
Guest: Yeah, well, I kind of see it sort of like that, maybe like the dubs today are technically very well done.
Guest: There's no no comparison to those old dubs.
Guest: And but I don't know.
Guest: It seems like they're having a lot less fun doing the dubs.
Guest: I don't know.
Guest: I really can't tell because like I was I was comparing the the ADV dub of Project not of Project Eden, the Dirty Pair movie to the streamlined dub of Project Eden.
Guest: And the streamlined dub of Project Eden is a terrific, terrific dub.
Guest: It's got a lot of heart.
Guest: It's got a lot of jokes in it.
Guest: And they rewrote some lines, but they still maintained like the flavor of the show.
Guest: And the ADV dub technically was better, but just came off as sort of.
Guest: we're doing this because we have to do it and get our paycheck.
Scott: Yeah, I think they just back then, you know, I guess they just took it a lot less seriously.
Scott: You know, it's like, yeah, we're just making a dub of an anime, whatever.
Scott: But now they're like, oh, it's a serious business.
Scott: We got to do this right.
Scott: Well,
Rym: especially you meet a lot of the American voice actors at conventions and they I don't want to disparage any of them that I may or may not have met over the years, but they seem like they take themselves a lot more seriously than even the professional original Japanese voice actors do.
Scott: And some of them, I mean, it really depends on who you're talking about.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, I mean, yeah, like Lisa Ortiz was just awesome and cool, but obviously I'm not naming names of the ones who are a little for obvious reasons.
Guest: Oh, we'll we'll say the names of them.
Guest: But like we've only met like I've only met Vic Mignogna very briefly and he was very pleasant, like went up, shook my hand and just said, oh, that's cool.
Guest: You've got a podcast or whatever.
Guest: It was a brief meeting, so I can't really say anything about him because he's the one that stands out because he's got like fan club and everything.
Guest: So but I mean, I guess I can't think of any that I've met that have really gotten on my nerves or anything.
Guest: The one thing that does annoy me and this isn't necessarily like a dub voice actor thing, but it's when you get you when you get these these people that work on the American editions and then they talk about how, well, I was working on the show and I wrote the episodes for this show and then I wrote the episodes for this show.
Guest: And when they didn't write these episodes, really, they they adapted them from the Japanese script because there's a different level of writing when you're writing something that from scratch and then when you're just adapting something.
Guest: And when they say, you know, I'm on the same level as the guy that just wrote this from scratch, that kind of annoys me a little bit.
Scott: Yeah, it seems like I've noticed that a lot is that you'll see in manga or anime that they'll credit someone as a writer, you know, even though, you know, they really like an adapter or, you know, just sort of a translator.
Scott: You know, it's like they didn't even translate it.
Scott: Someone else translated it.
Scott: And then they just sort of took the raw translation, converted it to something, you know, intelligible instead of just, you know, a bunch of translation notes.
Guest: And it's certainly not to disparage that because there is an art to adaptation and translation, but it's just.
Guest: it's not like writing a show from scratch.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, it's definitely.
Scott: it's not something like, oh, that's a bad job or it requires no talent or it sucks.
Scott: It's that, you know, should it be called writer is the question.
Scott: Should it be called something else instead of writer?
Scott: And that's sort of like.
Scott: I had a similar argument recently with some comic book nerds because they were like, oh, who's the best writers of all time in comic books?
Scott: And they were all like, Stan Lee, Stan Lee.
Scott: And I'm like, look, Stanley, he came up with some ideas that happen to be successful, but the man can't write for a hill of beans, you know, I mean, alliteration, spelling errors, grammar errors, you know, it's
Guest: a bold face,
Scott: random boldface text, a guy, a picture of a guy punching a guy and the guy who's throwing the punch says, I punch you,
Rym: you little guy.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And like, it's not good writing.
Guest: I don't, you know, so so so you don't have much hope for Ultimo, I guess.
Rym: You know, I think I said this in our coverage of the Comic-Con, but all the promotional material that we received or that we saw was not Ultimo by Stan Lee.
Rym: It was Stan Lee's Ultimo.
Guest: Hmm.
Guest: So so they know what they're pushing there.
Rym: Oh, they definitely do.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And Stan Lee is.
Guest: Stan Lee has been big into like.
Guest: he's known about manga for a long, long time.
Guest: There's actually like photographs of him meeting with Osamu Tezuka and such.
Guest: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, the guy is a smart guy.
Scott: He's a friendly guy.
Scott: He's he's really good at business.
Scott: He's really good at lots and lots of things, but he's not good at writing, according to my definition of writing.
Scott: I mean, he can come up with ideas for characters or, you know, depending on how much of the characters he came up with, you know, versus how much the other guys who worked at Marvel came up with them.
Scott: You know, you're not going to have that argument, but, you know, there's a lot of things about Stan Lee that are that are positive, but he cannot write for shit.
Guest: Yeah, I haven't read enough of his work to actually make a decision on that.
Guest: But did you guys happen to see this?
Guest: Are we running long on time?
Scott: Oh, whatever.
Scott: Don't worry about it.
Guest: There was this very interesting like article up on the Star Wars website and it was comparing the Star Wars manga that came out in the 1970s.
Scott: Oh, I've seen that one.
Guest: To the Star Wars American comic book that came out at the same time.
Guest: It was absolutely fascinating.
Guest: And this is again, I don't mean to disparage American comic books because American comic books do things very well that the Japanese could learn from.
Guest: But they specifically talked about that one because there were so many things that the manga did very well that the the American comic book didn't didn't really get across, like the the destruction of Alderaan.
Guest: I guess you guys don't.
Rym: Spoilers.
Guest: I have the feeling everyone listening to the show knows what that's about.
Guest: Like in the American comic book, it was just one panel and it was just one panel of just Alderaan exploding and that's it.
Guest: In the Japanese comic book, it was six pages of just the death star firing up and then shooting and then hitting the planet and then the planet like rumbling and then exploding and then a shot of Leia's eye and a tear running down her face.
Guest: And it was.
Guest: it was a very sort of decompressed way of telling the story.
Guest: it's fascinating to see it because you just see like like some of the rough things that like the American comic book writers had to deal with them.
Guest: Like every single panel almost had a had a narration block of text describing what was going on, like the picture wasn't enough.
Guest: They had to describe it as well.
Rym: I punch you, you little guy.
Rym: He punched the little guy and then a picture of a guy punching a little guy.
Guest: Yep.
Scott: That's it.
Guest: I was absolutely fascinating.
Rym: Let's get a little bit away from the kind of traditional geekery nerderies.
Rym: So you're a podcaster.
Guest: Why?
Guest: Because we have nothing else better to do with our times.
Guest: No, no.
Guest: Oh, God, I don't know.
Rym: I mean, because it seems like podcasting like had a mini explosion.
Rym: It didn't pick up like webcomics did, but it was like Puff.
Rym: And there's a lot of podcasts.
Rym: And then a lot of those podcasts disappeared or faded as they called it or whatever.
Rym: I don't know if we need a word for that.
Rym: That word's always kind of bothered me.
Guest: It's pretty much gone.
Guest: Yeah, I think we started doing anime world order because we were listening.
Guest: Well, actually, it was all Clarissa's idea, actually.
Guest: Like Clarissa should take all the credit for it because she was the one who started it up and she was and it was actually like an extra credit project for her.
Guest: And then what we wanted to do was honestly, really, honestly, we want people to watch good anime.
Guest: And we we just really like talking about anime a lot.
Guest: And we were listening to a lot of the anime podcasts at the time.
Guest: And some of them were OK.
Guest: Like we were listening to the Ninja Consultants and we thought they were really good.
Guest: Nobody really addressed the things that we wanted to talk about.
Guest: Like nobody was talking about virtually anything older than the Naruto.
Guest: And so we thought maybe we can do something that focuses on old school stuff.
Guest: And there were a lot of podcasts that were reviewing like one or two episodes of a show.
Guest: And we thought, well, you know, one or two episodes doesn't really give you a good impression of the show because the show can shift halfway through or the show can start to suck after a few episodes, because that was when Gonzo was coming out with all their stuff.
Scott: Yeah, great.
Guest: Like one or two first episodes or first five episodes.
Scott: Of course, who are we to talk?
Scott: We pretty much review single episodes all the time.
Rym: No, but we make it very clear that they were like, we're reviewing the first episode of this.
Rym: Blah, blah, blah.
Rym: Don't take this as a blah, blah, blah.
Scott: Yeah.
Guest: Yeah.
Guest: And so we just decided to start our own because, well, we just really wanted people to check out good stuff.
Guest: And we every single podcast out there that we were looking at, another one, another reason was because all of them out there were the anime and video game slash Halo slash lifestyle podcast.
Guest: And we wanted it just to be about anime only.
Guest: In fact, we've gone back and forth saying maybe we can do, you know, a video game episode.
Guest: No, we're going to do just anime and manga.
Guest: That's it.
Guest: We're just going to stick to that.
Guest: And because that's what we know best.
Rym: Yeah, I think it's worked really well for you guys.
Rym: I mean, I feel like even if you ever wanted to do like a video game special, it should be this separate thing like anime world order presents or I don't know what you could call it.
Scott: And maybe if you did it, you'd have to do it on like anime related video games or something like that.
Rym: Or if you want to totally get away with that and cop out, you guys could appear on gig nights as guest hosts for, say, a Tuesday, because we're going to three conventions in August and we need and then we're going out of town for a week in the middle of all that.
Rym: So we kind of we need some guest hosts.
Guest: I see.
Guest: Oh, speaking of anime video games, have you guys heard about the the new Capcom game?
Scott: Which one, DC versus Mortal Kombat?
Guest: That's going to suck.
Guest: That's not Capcom.
Scott: Capcom does the Marvel and the Capcom.
Guest: They do the versus games and they're coming out with it's Capcom like Ryu, Chun-Li, Street Fighter, Mega Man, all that versus Tatsunoko.
Guest: So Gotcha Man, Cushurn, Captain Tyler is part of it as well.
Guest: Like part of Tatsunoko.
Scott: It's a crazy game right there.
Guest: Samurai Pizza Cats is part of it.
Rym: I love that show.
Scott: The thing is, is that game ever going to be in this country?
Guest: That's the problem.
Guest: And I don't think it is.
Guest: I think we're going to have to import it because that's totally an arcade game, too.
Scott: That's not a console game, you know.
Scott: So we're we're definitely not going to see the arcade version.
Guest: I'm pretty sure they're going to probably put it on consoles at some point, but I really hope that that game doesn't suck because just like playing as the Gotcha Man characters is just awesome by itself.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Captain Tyler will do it for me because that show is one of my favorite shows in all of anime.
Rym: I just I love Captain Tyler.
Guest: Supermovus is just that he's.
Guest: he's just going to smack you over the head with a mallet.
Guest: That episode where he lit the ship on fire.
Guest: The Shio Kaze is just going to fly in and then crash.
Rym: I was always just a fan of the general who kept every time things screwed up, he just tried to commit seppuku and they're like, no, God damn it.
Rym: Stop that.
Guest: Captain Tyler, that would be neat if that made it in.
Guest: But there's so much to pull from, like Hurricane Polymer.
Scott: And I had no idea.
Guest: Tons and tons.
Guest: That's another kind of older show.
Scott: Yeah, I figured.
Rym: That's why Anime World Order is the more, I guess, literate anime podcast compared to GeekNights Wednesdays.
Guest: Yeah, we try.
Scott: I definitely think that's what, you know, made me like Anime World Order in the first place.
Scott: You know, when I listened to it was that you knew all this information about anime that like no one else knew.
Scott: Like I was at Anime Club at RIT with like the biggest anime nerds in the universe.
Scott: But they if they knew the shit that you guys know, they weren't saying it.
Scott: You know, they didn't know directors were they weren't you know, they didn't know all the really obscure stuff or anything like that.
Guest: That's what a lifetime of dedicating yourself to only one thing will do will keep your blinders on everything else.
Guest: But you tend to know you tend to be super good at one thing only.
Guest: And that's that's.
Guest: that's the price you pay.
Rym: Plus, I feel like I mean, there's not a very well developed professional media or press presence when it comes to anime in the United States, not like video games and comics and all these other kind of traditional geek things.
Rym: I mean, what our equivalent of the AP wire is basically the anime news network.
Rym: And then people like you guys and us are kind of like the second tier where there's the more commentary and opinion pieces.
Scott: The thing about the anime news network is the most professional, like top tier of media when it comes to anime and such.
Guest: And an anime news network is is good.
Scott: It is good.
Guest: But it's like, yeah, I mean, that's that's I mean, basically the privilege they get is that they don't have to.
Guest: I don't actually know because I don't know them, but like they don't sign up for press at Otakon.
Guest: They're just assumed and they get if they have an interview with a guest there, it's not like an interview when I go to Otakon where I'll be sitting at a roundtable with like five other podcasters.
Guest: They have it to themselves, every guest.
Scott: And but I'm just basically I'm just saying like, you know, we have anime, anime news network is pretty it's pretty good.
Scott: It's high quality.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But that's like the best we've got.
Scott: But compare that to, say, the media covering, you know, a different geekery, say, you know, look at the video game press, you know, and if you play if you had anime news network was about video games, it would be way low on the totem pole.
Scott: I mean, like it's lower than joystick.
Scott: It's lower than Kotaku.
Scott: It's lower than.
Scott: And those are that's sort of like the mid to low range.
Rym: But also look at the popularity.
Rym: I mean, just the anime in general, anime fandom and the way it is.
Rym: I mean, it's kind of it's it's very low hanging fruit in that regard.
Rym: And that like we go to Connecticut and it's like, yeah, do 11 panels, do whatever you want.
Rym: Please come.
Rym: And we go to Otakon's like, well, you've been panels for the last six years.
Rym: Here's your list of panels for this year.
Rym: And then we try to do a panel at PAX.
Rym: And it's like, well, are you guys professionals?
Rym: I don't know about this.
Guest: Yeah.
Guest: And the problem, the rough part is, is that for the most part, video game press still sort of sucks.
Guest: Like, yeah, outside of like outside of like, you know, and guy Kroll and such who actually have like something to say about it.
Guest: Like reviews on in the video, the world of video game like reviews is like its own show.
Guest: Oh, it's I'm sure.
Rym: I mean, I'll be honest, my like my favorite video game press is still Dave and Joel.
Scott: Well, yeah, I think the Dave and Joel and you've also then guy Kroll and Zero Punctuation.
Rym: Yahtzee tells me what to play, Zero Punctuation and the Angry Video Game Nerd.
Rym: Those those press.
Rym: He does not tell you about games that you are going to play.
Scott: He does.
Scott: He tells you about old games I didn't play and will not play in the future.
Scott: He's warning me.
Scott: He's the opposite of repeat.
Rym: His show is just like you guys talking about OD over and over.
Guest: Yeah, I mean, I guess I don't know, video games, it's certainly more mature because the video game press has been around for 20 years now.
Rym: I think it's just that there's more money involved.
Rym: I think that's the only factor.
Guest: Yeah, there definitely isn't.
Guest: I mean, anime, even though anime is very mainstream, it's still largely niche, while video games are no longer niche at all.
Rym: The anime industry is I don't want to say it's on the verge of collapse, but it's not doing well anymore in the US.
Rym: And I know there's a lot of reasons for that.
Rym: We could we could get you guys and us together on a separate show.
Rym: We could talk for a couple of hours about the video game industry.
Rym: I mean, it's pretty obvious that you guys talked about it recently and all I could think was, wow, I don't have anything to say except what they just said.
Guest: We we've got.
Guest: we still have a lot to say about it.
Guest: We're all just really hoping that it doesn't collapse.
Guest: And what's what's weird is that I was reading a I was going back in the archives, I was like editing some Wikipedia entries or something.
Guest: And I was going back to like the press panels from Anime Boston 2006 at the ADV panel there.
Guest: And it's really funny because they were talking about how, oh, the crash that everybody predicted was over exaggerated.
Guest: And those are the exact words from Anime Boston, like anime and state of the industry panel.
Guest: So it's weird looking at that now.
Rym: Maybe if they weren't trying to primarily sell throwaway shows that people don't want to buy DVDs for the kids who don't have money.
Guest: It's it's very complicated.
Guest: I can't blame either side completely because both sides are.
Rym: I mean, granted, I have this feeling, though, that I mean, we talk about all the anime press isn't quite mature yet from every interaction I've ever had with the industry, and especially the people who bring the anime out over here.
Rym: And I know you guys have more interaction with them, but it seems like the companies involved are run very much in many ways unprofessionally, or at least not as professionally as I would expect, you know, a corporation that is doing this sort of thing as its daily operations.
Guest: I don't know if I agree completely because I've I haven't had a chance to meet John Ledford.
Guest: He was the head of
Guest: A.D.V.,
Guest: but John Ledford is known as kind of the the businessman.
Guest: He's not an anime fan.
Guest: He is.
Guest: he was design.
Guest: He went out there to run A.D.V.
Guest: as a business.
Guest: And I believe that like the the kernel of A.D.V.
Guest: actually came from like Matt Greenfield and David Williams and those guys.
Guest: But as far as like the other companies like Bandai Visual, I don't know who's running them.
Scott: Well, Bandai Entertainment is actually very professional.
Scott: And Bandai Entertainment is also.
Scott: Well,
Rym: I guess I should have been more clear, because it's not I mean, not necessarily just the the actual, you know, we license anime and release it, but all the kind of tertiary and related industries like the the people who sell all the tchotchkes, the people who import those things, the people who make licensed merchandise.
Rym: Like remember when the MythBags company just disappeared?
Guest: Yeah, they I don't know what happened to them.
Guest: They just like their website wasn't being updated.
Guest: They weren't answering their phones or whatever.
Rym: And that sort of thing is it's just.
Rym: it's a lot more common in the anime industry than it is in a lot of other even kind of niche industries.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, in the video game industry, when you have something like the Phantom Game Console, it's like a big deal.
Scott: It's like, holy shit, look, there's an unprofessional company.
Scott: What the hell is going on?
Guest: Yeah, I guess one of the problems is that there's no good example for the anime industry to follow, really.
Guest: Like like the the Kung Fu, like if you look at like the other niche like video markets, like the the Kung Fu movie industry in America, like not the ones, not the guys, the movies that are licensed by the big deal companies, but like the smaller companies.
Guest: That is it is the worst thing in the world.
Guest: It must be to be like a martial arts movie fan in America because you get horrible dubs and the movies are cut up.
Guest: You still cannot get an uncut copy of Return of the Dragon today.
Scott: Wow.
Scott: And not even on the BitTorrents?
Guest: Maybe on the BitTorrents, but I know that you cannot buy a DVD of Return of the Dragon uncut today.
Rym: Well, you know, maybe that's it.
Rym: It's that, you know, that industry isn't trying to go like professional mainstream.
Rym: And it's a lot of these kind of flyby, like I never like when I get a Chinese action Kung Fu movie, I have no idea if it's a bootleg or not.
Rym: I don't care.
Rym: It's always a different company putting them out.
Rym: And maybe it's just that the anime industry is a similar industry that's trying to break into the professional mainstream.
Rym: So they're only as a whole unit, like the entire industry is only halfway there.
Rym: So it looks bad, but it's not because it's sliding.
Rym: It's just because it's trying.
Guest: Maybe.
Guest: There was a really good article that a really smart guy named Dave Merrill wrote about this.
Guest: And he talked about how I think this was in relation maybe to also the American comic book industry in that the anime industry really wants to play with the big guys, but doesn't realize that it can't like.
Guest: like if you take in other niche industries as well, like like toy trains or the doll, the guys, the doll making industry, like the doll making fandom, like they're quite happy being, you know, their small little niche thing.
Guest: They're they're not like trying to get everybody to make dolls or everybody to to get into trains.
Guest: But anime, they're trying every they're trying to get everybody to watch anime.
Scott: Well, I think the reason for that, though, is if you look at, you know, say the people who make like, you know, little trains like Lionel or model rockets or anything like that, is that they don't have a lot of, you know, they don't see a lot of interest.
Scott: They look around and they have a few guys coming into the hobby shop every week and that's it.
Scott: But imagine if you were running the hobby shop and like a million people came in every day, but you only made like one hundred dollars.
Scott: You'd be like all you could think is I got to do something about this.
Scott: You know, so if you're an anime company, you know, you you could just be a happy little niche kind of thing.
Scott: But so I think anime ego definitely goes that route of just being happy, being a niche thing.
Scott: But, yeah, you go to Otakon, you see twenty thousand people and you're like, God damn it.
Scott: Twenty thousand people are crazy enough to come all the way out here.
Scott: Think about how many other people are out there.
Scott: I should be making some mad money off this.
Scott: What am I?
Scott: You know, this is not a niche.
Guest: And that's the problem is that the the Japanese companies go to Otakon and Anime Expo when they see this and they're like, well, every person here obviously, you know, represents many more people in America.
Guest: Therefore, if we release our crappy show over here, then it's going to be a gigantic seller.
Guest: And they don't realize that that audience that you see, like less people that go to Otakon are going to buy the eighty dollars for, you know, the Sento Iose Yukikaze on DVD.
Scott: Well, at eighty dollars, that's for sure.
Guest: Or like one hundred dollars.
Guest: Sento Iose Yukikaze is like one of these weird things where Bandai Entertainment released it for like thirty dollars over here and then they lost the license and then Bandai Visual picked it up and sold it for like one hundred dollars or something.
Rym: Brilliant.
Guest: Yeah.
Scott: No one bought this for thirty.
Scott: Let's sell it for a hundred.
Scott: Then people will buy it.
Guest: Yeah.
Rym: Well, especially it's really hard to buy a crappy show for a lot of money when I can still buy Cowboy Bebop for thirty bucks.
Guest: Yeah, and I mean, the repack, like I guess it's people aren't really buying a lot of the new stuff as well, like they they just keep replying the old stuff.
Rym: So I've done that.
Rym: I bought Eska Floname almost twice.
Guest: Yeah.
Guest: And I guess there are crazy people who have bought Evangelion four times.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: The VHS, the DVD, the better DVD, the more better DVD.
Guest: Yeah.
Guest: The one that was going to come out that had like a jacket in it and such.
Scott: Those people definitely exist.
Scott: because I was in an ADV panel at Otakon, I think, maybe three or four years ago for like five minutes.
Scott: I think I was in this panel and people were standing up being like, you know, when is it?
Scott: Tell me more about this new Evangelion box you're making.
Scott: That is somehow different from the previous box, which I own and the procs before that, which I own because, you know, they didn't actually say they own the previous boxes, but this wasn't someone who had never seen Evangelion before.
Scott: That was for sure.
Guest: Right.
Guest: And yeah, like the licensing, like I guess people don't realize that anime is like 80 percent merchandising and so much of the merchandising that we get is just like imported from Japan.
Guest: There's not.
Guest: there's not as much like domestic merchandising, I should say.
Rym: It seems like comics are definitely going the route where like we at the New York Comic-Con, you saw a lot of this and there's some anime stuff, too, but the kind of high class licensed properties, the like the nice, very expensive, but very fancy looking bust of the major and that sort of thing that it's worked really well for the comic industry because the comic nerds will spend a lot of money on those things.
Guest: Oh, that's why you have those crazy, awesome solo chogakins in Japan.
Guest: Those are the.
Guest: those are the super awesome die cast metal like figures of of robots.
Guest: They'll have like Mazinger Z and and they'll have like obscure shows like Gold Lighton and God Mars, these obscure shows from the 70s.
Guest: And they'll make these hundred plus dollar solo chogakins things.
Guest: I don't believe you call them figures.
Guest: You call them like lifestyle accessories or something.
Guest: So, yeah, I mean, I'm not saying that we should go that route because that's.
Guest: but I do want one of those solo chogakins Mazinger Z.
Scott: I'd take one for less than a hundred dollars, but not paying that money for it.
Scott: But yeah, definitely like I look even in Japan, not just for anime, but it seems like Japan is much better at merchandising almost everything.
Scott: I mean, you go to like any Japanese convenience store and you can get like a Mario toothbrush.
Scott: You can get a Mario anything almost.
Scott: You can get a Hello Kitty almost anything.
Guest: But in Japan.
Guest: Yeah, go on.
Scott: But in the US, right, if you go to the toothbrush aisle, you know, the only place you're going to see licensed thing is on like a kid's toothbrush.
Scott: And you're only going to have a choice between like three things.
Scott: Yet there's, you know, hundreds of popular properties, but there's only like three toothbrushes.
Rym: So you're saying that you would buy a Makoto toothbrush?
Scott: I'd buy a Gundam toothbrush.
Guest: I'd buy a rape man toothbrush.
Scott: Yeah, it had to come up sometime.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Well, at any rate, before we wrap up, we should get in a couple more non anime questions.
Rym: So what should we ask?
Rym: Because I don't want to go the route of.
Rym: so is there ever strife in the anime world order?
Rym: How much do you guys hate each other?
Guest: Oh, we hate each other a lot.
Scott: Do you do you have any like, you know, we pretty much got over, you know, what your hobbies, do you have any hobbies that like aren't generally considered geeky?
Guest: I work out a lot.
Guest: I exercise, but I don't know if that's considered a hobby.
Rym: Like I think it is.
Rym: If you enjoy it, I enjoy.
Rym: I see people who work out and it's like they hate every minute of it, like they're lifting these little weights and they're like, I hate working out, but I'm fat and I don't want to be fat.
Guest: I do it.
Guest: I don't enjoy working out.
Guest: I don't enjoy it as much when I'm actually working out, but I do very much enjoyed when I'm finished because I feel like I've accomplished something like even though what I've accomplished is extremely minor.
Guest: But yeah, I working out, I guess, is not typically a geeky thing.
Guest: They need to develop some sort of system where people can like watch anime and work out easily.
Guest: Like you should watch Fighting Spirit, Hajime No Ippo.
Rym: That show will make you want to live the way you want to watch it.
Rym: Yeah, because Initial D really made me want to drive my car very dangerously.
Guest: They should just pull your car into the lounge and just like drift in your lounge while you're watching Initial D.
Rym: All right, so we'll end on a bunch of kind of quick, easy questions like now, obviously, it's a bad question is what's your favorite movie ever?
Rym: But name like, I don't know, three or four movies, anime or not, just that you really, really like.
Rym: We'll get a picture of Gerald here.
Rym: Like what do you like or not?
Guest: I'll just run off a couple, but most of them are probably going to be animated.
Guest: But let's see.
Guest: I really like The Goonies, the 1980s movie.
Guest: I'm a big fan of that.
Guest: I acknowledge that it's probably not a good movie.
Guest: Oh, it's.
Rym: it's awesome.
Guest: But I love it to death.
Guest: I really like Galifor's Eternal Story for an anime movie.
Guest: That's I really like Murder by Death.
Guest: It's kind of an.
Guest: it's an 70s murder mystery that kind of made fun of a lot of the tropes of murder mysteries at the time.
Scott: I never heard of that from Netflix.
Guest: It's that they have like Ecule Poirot and all of these people all in one mansion at once.
Guest: And Truman Capote is in it, like the writer.
Guest: Just at the end, it's a pretty awesome little movie.
Guest: I like Wings of Oneamis a lot.
Guest: That's probably what that movie is.
Rym: I watched like an eighth generation fan sub where you couldn't even read the subtitles.
Scott: Damn you, Bandai Visual.
Scott: I'll buy it if you make it cheap.
Scott: Why is it really?
Guest: in a way I feel really bad?
Guest: because the guy that wrote that movie was twenty three years old and I'm older than him and I've done less with my life than he has when he.
Rym: Don't worry, because we realize that Formula One drivers who have tens of millions of dollars, they're the most highly paid professional athletes in the world, are younger than us.
Scott: Oh, you know that video game pianist guy?
Scott: What's his name?
Scott: We met him like a few years ago and at the time.
Guest: Yeah, not piano squall.
Rym: No, no, I don't think you understand the depth of Martin.
Scott: Martin Long.
Scott: Martin.
Guest: Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Guest: That guy.
Scott: Yeah, we met him and we were like 20 something.
Scott: We must have been like twenty four, twenty three.
Rym: It was like last year.
Rym: No, it wasn't.
Rym: It was two years ago.
Scott: So we were twenty four, twenty five ish.
Scott: He was nineteen at the time.
Rym: And I remember we were sitting with like the con chair of this con and then him and then us two.
Rym: And he reels his age and all of us look at each other and go.
Scott: He's a really nice, nice and modest guy, though.
Guest: That's cool.
Guest: Modesty is a is a great, great thing to have, especially especially the more awesome that you are.
Rym: Yeah, I always like that, like the sleeper car where it looks like a piece of crap, but then it beats off the line.
Guest: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Guest: Let's see other movies.
Guest: I'm a. I really love Porco Rosso.
Guest: I think that's Miyazaki's best movie.
Rym: We were just talking about that yesterday.
Guest: I think that that's probably his least.
Guest: it was his least successful movie for a reason.
Guest: And I think it was for good reasons, even though I think it should have been successful.
Guest: Other movies that I like, I'm trying to think of like some some non anime movies and I'm trying to think of like things that people might not expect.
Guest: Tootsie.
Guest: Tootsie is an awesome movie.
Rym: Actually, it is.
Scott: I can't really make fun of it.
Scott: It's not bad.
Scott: My mom loves Tootsie.
Guest: Yeah.
Guest: What's I'm looking at my shelf now.
Guest: Project Aco I really like.
Guest: We just talked about that, so that shouldn't count.
Rym: How about any TV like any one of those people who watch like The Simpsons or anything?
Guest: Oh, God, I'm so bad on that.
Guest: I like.
Guest: I like watch virtually no American TV.
Scott: Good.
Scott: Good for you.
Scott: We don't either.
Guest: Well, the sad part is that I have cable.
Rym: No, just get rid of it.
Rym: We actually haven't had cable in like a decade.
Guest: Yeah, but I watch like.
Guest: I watch like The Simpsons and those sorts of things.
Guest: And then I'll watch Ninja Warrior.
Scott: And yeah, I like that.
Rym: Awesome.
Guest: And Unbeatable Banzouke.
Scott: I don't know what that is.
Rym: Did you ever watch American Gladiators back in the day?
Guest: Back in the day, I caught a couple of episodes of it and I saw that they were making a new show.
Guest: And apparently the I'm told by my friends that the new American Gladiators are some of the roughest people that they've ever seen.
Scott: Yeah, we'll have to check out at least one episode.
Scott: Maybe it's online somewhere or something.
Scott: Are there any books you like that?
Scott: are, you know, like words, not pictures?
Guest: Wordy books.
Guest: Yeah, let's see.
Guest: I really like The Count of Monte Cristo.
Guest: I'm just turning that up again.
Rym: What translation do you like?
Guest: I'm nuts.
Rym: I'm just curious, because if you thought you liked the book, read it again with the most recent Penguin Books translation.
Scott: The Unabridged Penguin?
Rym: Yes, it makes it.
Rym: I was surprised that I could read a book again and like it more just because it's translated differently.
Guest: Now, I need to give that a shot.
Guest: I don't have that edition.
Guest: There's a couple of like weird books here and there, like there's this one very weird little book that came out some years ago called Angry White Pajamas, which is about this skinny little like Oxford poet that goes to Japan to and gets training in the Japanese riot school, Japanese riot police like training program.
Guest: He almost dies.
Scott: Oh, I see.
Scott: I see the book right here.
Scott: It's ten bucks on Amazon.
Guest: Yeah, it's a. it's a weird, interesting little book.
Rym: Like any genres of fiction you like, like.
Rym: do you like fantasy books or science fiction or speculative fiction?
Guest: Oh, I like.
Guest: I've tried reading some more science fiction, but it's it's hard for me to get into that because I I have no idea what's going on in the world of science fiction writing today.
Guest: And everybody I talk to has got totally different opinions on what to read.
Rym: Yeah, it seems the same way for me with fantasy books.
Rym: I finally we have one guy in the front row crew who pretty much if I want a fantasy book, I go to him and say, hey, Alex, give me a fantasy book that I will like.
Rym: And he just hands me something and I read it.
Scott: I think the key with sci fi is you just you know, you don't want to go for the new stuff.
Scott: Just try to read all as many of the old classics as you can, you know, like the Asimov's and the Heinlein's and all that business.
Scott: And then by the time you run out of that, you might be an old man not being able to read anymore anyway.
Scott: So, you know, don't worry about the other stuff.
Guest: Like I really like the original Conan a lot.
Guest: Hmm, because I really like the philosophy in Conan.
Rym: You know, if you like, you should join the GeekNights book club and read that book that we've been talking about for the last like a year, The Prince of Nothing.
Rym: I, I don't think I can recommend that book enough.
Rym: And if you like the Conan, then you will probably enjoy The Prince of Nothing.
Scott: Probably like the Nayer.
Rym: I think Nayer is up your alley.
Rym: WEEPER!
Rym: Nayer is the most violent of men, breaker of horses and men.
Guest: Oh, so is he more violent than than Riccio?
Scott: You know, he's pretty close.
Rym: Maybe not in terms of spraying blood, but in terms of like.
Rym: you look at a man and you try to gauge based on the way he's described the amount of violence contained within him.
Rym: He is definitely Nayer, Sko, Eartha, most violent of men.
Scott: You know how in like Fist of the North Star, right, like Ken Shiro is really big, but all the guys he kills are like twice his size.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Now imagine if you sort of flip it around and it's like the whole world is normal guys and there's one guy who's twice the size of everybody, but he doesn't just get he doesn't go down like a chump.
Scott: He's actually twice the size and twice as bad ass as everyone else.
Rym: And he's not even the main character.
Rym: He's just there.
Scott: He's like this supporting character barbarian who just fucking kills everybody.
Guest: So how many people does he punch directly in the mouth and punch their brains out?
Scott: Quite a few.
Scott: All I can think is depends on your interpretation.
Rym: All I can think is that is the face of a man who has no option but to try to kill Dracula with his face.
Scott: Yeah, I think he actually punches a horse's brains out at one point.
Rym: I mean, I can say, yeah, I mean, is also their cultures where whenever they kill a man, they have to scar their arm and it's symbolic and they carry the weight of that man's soul on them and this sort of.
Rym: And he is also Nersk or the most scarred of men.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Like the guy has scars all over his body.
Scott: And if you know that each scar means he killed someone, that's that's quite frightening.
Guest: Right.
Guest: I wouldn't.
Guest: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And like, you know, all his barbarian friends who do the same thing have like a few scars on one arm.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I'll say this.
Rym: Go whenever you get a chance.
Rym: You should probably listen to the GeekNights book club about it, because I don't think we want to derail the show.
Scott: No, we're already derailed here.
Guest: But was it on rails to begin with?
Scott: All right.
Scott: So.
Rym: So.
Rym: All right.
Rym: One last one.
Rym: This is so Anime World Order.
Rym: Do you guys have a kind of a vision of the future?
Rym: Are you?
Rym: are you?
Rym: do you?
Rym: I mean, even if it's not one of those like feasible things, if you could, would you try to go pro with it and live like?
Rym: that is your life and that is your job?
Guest: Oh, fuck yes.
Rym: That's all I wanted to hear.
Guest: If we could if we could like sustain ourselves, that would be awesome.
Guest: But I think I think as you keep going in the world of podcasting, you you have your like original goal and then you're like, oh, well, I guess this is not attainable.
Guest: Then I guess our goal is well, originally our goal was to have, I believe, a hundred listeners.
Scott: Wow.
Guest: We could get 100 listeners to then we would be happy.
Rym: And I think you got that.
Rym: I think they've got a few more than 100 listeners.
Guest: Yeah.
Guest: Well, the rough part is that if we got like we got to like a thousand listeners really quickly and then to get to two thousand listeners subscribed, like on on our on our blog.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, remember, there's only like three thousand people listening to podcasts.
Guest: Yeah.
Guest: And and the thing is that we we have a hard time like getting the exact numbers because there's probably at least double or triple the number of people that just download it directly.
Scott: It's very it's very, very difficult to figure out exactly how many people.
Rym: I mean, you look at the stats and it's like if you do a real statistical analysis, like people like us can say things like, wow, I can say with a ninety five percent degree of certainty that I have between fifty and five thousand listeners.
Guest: That that's pretty much like how we are like and it's rough because we did have like some advertisers come to us and they said they want to know they want to know.
Guest: And I understand that they want to know.
Guest: And but we can't give them exact numbers.
Guest: We can give them a very we can give them a relatively narrow range, but they want something more narrow.
Scott: Yeah, I think the trick there is to just lie.
Scott: That way you'll get money.
Rym: or just what we usually do is we tell the advertisers when they come basically that unless you can give us enough money, that's just.
Scott: that's our personal policy.
Scott: that, you know, if I was actually if I didn't have that policy, I wouldn't be saying this.
Rym: Yeah.
Guest: Speaking of which, what is the weirdest swag that you guys think that you would ever like do for GeekNights?
Scott: I got we're doing a pretty weird swag, depending on your point of view, pretty soon.
Guest: Well, I'm thinking of like GeekNights condoms, GeekNights, you know, stamps on apples at the grocery store to steal from our last match game, the GeekNights' pregnancy test.
Guest: Oh, that's a good one.
Rym: Well, I mean, considering that our listeners, I don't know if you guys get this.
Rym: I don't think you do to the degree that we do, which is it's.
Rym: it's not frightening.
Rym: It's just.
Rym: I never, ever thought in my entire life up until now that there would be a point in my future where there would be fan fiction slash gay doujinshi about me.
Rym: That and and the fact that it's there and the and the worst part is now we're making this T-shirt and now I think it's like, wow, there's going to be a T-shirt with my face on it and someone other than me might wear it.
Rym: I don't know what to do about that, but we're making this shirt.
Rym: Actually, Emily is making it and we're saying make it please.
Rym: But it's our this catchphrase from a long time ago, you know, get the hell off my Internet's and it caught on.
Rym: So we, you know, two years later decide to make the shirt about it.
Rym: And it's this Soviet propaganda poster like straight out of Soviet propaganda.
Rym: And it's a stylized room and a stylized Scott standing in that Soviet way, fingers pointing.
Rym: And it says, get the partner off.
Rym: my Internet's partner, of course, is whatever the Cyrillic is for hell.
Rym: And it's pretty snazzy looking.
Rym: Yeah.
Guest: Neat.
Guest: We we really have not done much with this merchandising just because we just don't have the time.
Rym: Oh, forget not just the time.
Rym: it like getting like even our vinyl banner and stuff like.
Rym: you need to do a lot of kind of difficult stuff to get these things printed.
Rym: And you got to have a lot of money up front and then the taxes.
Scott: And it's yeah, I think that's the thing about podcasting.
Scott: is podcasting requires, you know, knowledge about what you're podcasting about, speaking abilities, right.
Scott: You know, radio abilities, which is sort of an add on to speaking abilities.
Guest: You don't have.
Scott: you got to have the audio technology abilities and you got to have the computer abilities, you know, doing websites and things.
Scott: So if you're someone who has all those abilities, it's going to be a rare case where you also have like graphic design, digital printing abilities.
Guest: Yeah, well, we're lucky in that Clarissa is a really good graphic designer, so we have that as well.
Guest: And I'm good at standing around and doing nothing.
Guest: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Guest: We just have not done what.
Guest: what we really, I don't think we really planned on it.
Guest: It was just kind of like, wow, people want T-shirts of our show.
Guest: Yeah, we'll do some T-shirts.
Rym: Let's just little things like.
Rym: our website's been this ugly looking WordPress forever.
Rym: And we're finally trying to redo that.
Scott: And it's I really got to talk about that after the show.
Rym: Oh, we do?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: We got to pay her, right?
Scott: OK.
Rym: We paid one of our friends to redesign our website because she happens to be a professional graphic designer.
Scott: Like actually, probably.
Guest: Yeah, probably the best thing to go with them.
Rym: Actually, we're trying Scott's working on it now.
Rym: I think we're going to actually just write our own content management system in Django and just use that entirely and just give up on this WordPress crap so we can do a lot more.
Rym: I guess if it works, if you guys like it, we could just give it to you.
Guest: That'd be cool.
Scott: It'll be sort of custom made for our show.
Scott: Those seem like, you know, things of the day, searches and stuff.
Rym: Well, honestly, I think is the way that sort of stuff works.
Rym: This is I I'll give you an open letter to Anime World Order because I feel like there's a way that you guys could really bust out in a big way.
Rym: is you keep doing the long shows.
Rym: But get like a Libsyn account and break every show up into each discrete bit.
Rym: So whenever you record a show and you put it up, have a news feed that's just like all the news is and a review feed that's just like all the reviews as individual bites.
Rym: And I think you'll get a lot more casual listenership.
Rym: And that's the kind of thing that we would do if we had time.
Rym: And I know you'll say, oh, yeah, we would do that if we had time.
Guest: But that's an idea because we've kind of hit like this block where we I think we've got about as many people listening to the show as well as are listening to podcasts.
Scott: Yeah, we sort of had a plateau on our download graph.
Scott: also, you know, even though you don't know what the numbers are, you can see on the chart it sort of went up and then sort of flat.
Guest: Yeah.
Guest: It's it's inching up a bit.
Guest: It's now like I don't really know how we were not too sure what we need to do because we want to keep our old listeners because we love our old listeners because they've been with us since the beginning and we love them all.
Rym: It seems like what you have to because like we're trying to do something similar where people need if you want to get linked to it has to be like this discrete unit.
Rym: Like if someone links to your show and says, oh, my God, there's a great review of Odean or whatever.
Rym: And then you guys talk about a bunch of other stuff, which we get this problem all the time.
Rym: It doesn't get linked to as often as and hook people in.
Rym: But if there's also that direct link where people can say, man, check out this review of Mazen Kaiser and they link directly to just the review of Mazen Kaiser.
Rym: And then they go, oh, it's by these guys.
Rym: Oh, look, they reviewed that other show.
Rym: I like.
Rym: Oh, hey, I can just listen to the whole show.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The YouTube generation definitely wants lots of smaller things as opposed to fewer bigger things.
Guest: Yeah.
Guest: I mean, on the other hand, we're kind of aiming for that that office worker that just wants sort of some hum in the background while they work so that they don't actually have to listen to it.
Guest: But it's entertaining in some sort of some sort of subconscious way.
Rym: I feel like the way to go is you have to do both.
Rym: And I think we're going to try to do both.
Rym: So if it works, we can show you how to do both.
Guest: Yeah, that's kind of a weird thing with podcasting, like you don't see people really running to podcasting anymore.
Guest: It's sort of that was sort of like two years ago now.
Guest: And now it's sort of that's we would.
Guest: there's really no killer app and podcasting just yet.
Rym: Well, there isn't even a good like.
Rym: I mean, there's iTunes and that's really the best you've got to even listen.
Rym: And most people don't even know what podcasts are.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: It's like it got really big and then it leveled off before people really figured it out, you know?
Guest: Yeah.
Guest: And the thing is, is that I'm not even against people calling them netcasts because so many people I say podcast to, they still think they need an iPod.
Rym: God, our flyer even says that on the back.
Rym: You don't need an iPod or iTunes or a Mac.
Guest: Yeah.
Guest: And so the naming needs to change.
Guest: Something something needs to happen where people start listening to podcasts again.
Guest: Or maybe it's just at that point where, you know, how can you get more people to watch television?
Guest: You can't really do it.
Rym: It's I think we can, though, because I think just the technology has to get to the point where people carry something like an iPod or a cell phone thing.
Rym: But instead of like I go home, I run my podcatcher, I sync up, I go out because only like there's a certain kind of person who does that.
Rym: It was just like the radio, if it was like on demand radio all the time where someone's like, I want to listen to a review of anime and they hit anime in their cell phone.
Rym: Oh, anime world order.
Guest: Yeah, it definitely has to go beyond to do something like that.
Guest: Like I have got an iPod and it's still annoying for me when I have to unplug it, load up iTunes, let the shows download, sync it up, take it back out.
Scott: That's the worst part is that the iPods in the Zunes have Wi-Fi now.
Scott: This is technologically within reach.
Scott: You can have it.
Scott: It's technologically possible on the iPod touch if the software was there, which it isn't for you to, you know, go and just browse podcasts, download them directly to it anywhere with this Wi-Fi.
Scott: But they don't.
Scott: Apple doesn't put the software on there to make it happen.
Scott: But they could.
Scott: And I don't know why they don't.
Rym: I mean, at least I don't think podcasting will go away.
Rym: I think it's just going to be in a lull until technology gets better, because it's not like video can replace audio because you can't watch a video while you're driving or working.
Scott: I think this is going to be a gradual shift from all the current content distribution mechanisms like TV and terrestrial radio to just, you know, things are on the Internet and you can download them.
Scott: And then there's just going to be, you know, there's going to be professionally made content on the Internet and none professionally made kind of on the Internet.
Scott: It's all going to be just downloading video and audio from the Internet that people made.
Guest: Yeah.
Guest: And yeah, because I mean, I don't listen to morning radio.
Guest: I can't really stand morning radio.
Rym: Hey, it's wacky morning, DJ.
Rym: We're here to talk about the stuff we're stealing from far.
Guest: But after I farted the microphone.
Guest: There you go.
Guest: Yeah, I I don't know.
Guest: I think that would help.
Guest: I think it would help as well if we could get, you know, decent Internet in America.
Guest: I know that.
Guest: Yeah, I know that, you know, in Europe and such, it's it's a whole lot better supposedly.
Guest: Yeah, because I think people have a problem with just waiting for the downloads as well, even though everybody has got high speed Internet.
Rym: Yeah, but we get periodically emails from people saying, hey, could you make a dial up friendly version?
Rym: And I usually just laugh.
Guest: So a MIDI file.
Scott: Yeah, that's sort of like if you had like a.
Guest: You should release a MIDI file.
Rym: That's going to be the next April Fools, because no one's going to remember this by then.
Scott: That'd be like if you had a 286 and you sent like a letter to say, you know, Valve and you're like, hey, can you make a version of Half Life 2 that works on my 286?
Guest: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Scott: Help me out here.
Guest: Yeah, yeah, really.
Scott: Port it to the Wolfenstein entry, then I could play it.
Rym: All right.
Rym: We I think we've we've gone through our allotment, so we'll probably end on that one.
Scott: Let's end it here.
Scott: I just want to make because.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So just to end it, I wonder if Gerald has any like a message for the listeners, perhaps something you want to pimp besides Anime World Order or, you know, anything.
Guest: Yeah, well, I guess the regular is, you know, check us out if you liked what you heard, because normally we're a whole lot more edited on Anime World Order out of www.animeworldorder.com.
Guest: Clarissa and Daryl, they write for Otaku USA.
Guest: So check that out, too.
Guest: It's the most entertaining anime magazine out there because Peak is is not something else.
Scott: I haven't read the peak, so I don't know.
Guest: Yeah.
Guest: Peak is because it's a magazine.
Guest: I can definitely say it's printed on paper.
Guest: Yes.
Guest: Sold in stores.
Guest: It's got a P and I and a Q in its name.
Guest: I can definitely say that.
Guest: Yeah, that's that's about all I've got to pimp, really.
Rym: Well, I guess all I can say is that you guys keep doing Anime World Order because, I mean, it's the rare compliment from GeekNights.
Rym: But you guys are one of the like five or six podcasts we actually listen to at all.
Rym: And you guys are great.
Scott: Well, non profession, I listen to some professional podcasts.
Rym: Those don't count.
Rym: Those are those are separate.
Rym: Yeah.
Guest: Yeah.
Guest: ESPN does not count.
Guest: We we like every one of our listeners.
Guest: So except that guy,
Rym: you know, the ones
Scott: not like us.
Scott: We hate our listeners.
Rym: Well, what's his name?
Rym: Admiral Beefy or whoever seems to hate us.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: What was up with that guy who would like said that voicemail to you?
Scott: That was like so seething about hating us.
Guest: Oh, I don't remember that one.
Scott: It was really scary.
Guest: We get we get very.
Rym: Oh, you guys get some fantastic.
Rym: I maybe because we don't play this stuff on the air, but we don't get the really weird ones like you guys do.
Guest: Well, I guess our sort of podcast being as geeky as it is, it kind of breeds the especially geeky sort of people in a good way and in a bad way.
Rym: I guess, you know, you can't.
Rym: you can't have the rose without the thorns.
Rym: You can't have the.
Rym: I don't know if that's the analogy to use with anime fans and video game fans.
Guest: And I think that that applies.
Guest: And yeah, I mean, we get.
Guest: I'd like to say that we have the the smartest listener base in anime podcasting.
Rym: I think on average, I might have to agree.
Guest: I do believe that.
Guest: I think that our podcasts, our listeners are some of the smartest people in anime.
Guest: But we get crazies, too.
Guest: And they're awesome because crazy people are awesome.
Rym: Crazy people.
Rym: I mean, if you don't a guy is any example.
Guest: Well, going to guys and crazy going a guy is a prophet.
Guest: He's predicting the future.
Scott: I was I was under the impression that, you know, to be a prophet, you must be crazy.
Rym: I mean, you go hand in hand.
Guest: You realize going a guy came before noted him before something before any like people said with Elvis, like before anybody did anything.
Guest: Elvis did everything before anybody did anything.
Guest: Going to guy fuck them all.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Thank you.
Rym: Once again, this was Gerald from Anime World Order.
Rym: Check them out and bother us to get Clarissa and Darryl on the show at some point in the future.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes, links, our awesome forum, a link to our Frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology.
Rym: Tuesdays we have video games, board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime, manga, comic nights and Thursdays are the catch alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to geeknights@frontroadcrew.com or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear, you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: For the complete archives, visit the website, which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit, don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.