Rym: It's Tuesday, January 27th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, the little engine that could kill Let's do this.
Rym: My DS hadn't been getting a lot of love lately.
Rym: I mean I actually took it out of my bag like a month ago And I just I stopped bringing it around with me because the only game I owned that I hadn't already played that I wanted to Play was Castlevania, and I don't know.
Rym: I got about halfway through and then I suddenly got Intensely Intensely full of apathy toward the game like it was weird.
Rym: I was playing I was enjoying it.
Rym: I beat like this one really hard boss this big tall guy who punches things and I got a little bit further than suddenly.
Rym: I was fighting the next boss and I just Like put the game down and didn't pick it up for like three weeks.
Scott: that happened to me with You know Bioshock.
Scott: I got to a certain point where everything was like covered in plants And I was just like.
Scott: I don't care anymore.
Scott: It also happened to me with.
Scott: I was playing Symphony tonight in a PlayStation emulator on the PC And I got to the upside-down castle and then I beat like a couple bosses, and I was like I'm done.
Scott: Well, I didn't actually say I'm done.
Scott: I just sort of stopped playing and didn't feel like I wanted to keep playing.
Scott: Yeah, I know when I played it was it was pretty great.
Rym: It's weird more and more.
Rym: like I feel like my gaming tastes are.
Rym: I don't know if I want to say maturing But when I was a kid Maybe it was just because I had more free time and I had like you know at any given time I had like 10 Nintendo games.
Rym: I hadn't beaten that I owned and I was willing to Continue to play them all oftentimes playing the same level over and over and over again for months at a time.
Rym: Yeah until I beat them.
Rym: But now like I'll play a game And if I don't get enough novelty out of it in a certain amount of time like this Meter of fatigue is constantly going up the longer.
Rym: I'm playing, but there's also this novelty meter That's going up, and if the novelty meter doesn't get high enough before the fatigue meter maxes out I suddenly don't care about the game anymore, and I quit.
Scott: I mean it's like you're playing Mario right, okay?
Scott: So there's all the things Mario does all the mechanics of the game right jump get big firepower star bad guys vines right but after Level four right.
Scott: you've seen everything there is to see.
Scott: you've seen the flying fishes.
Scott: You've seen night time.
Scott: You've seen locky - you've seen Koopa.
Scott: You've seen.
Scott: you've seen hammer brothers.
Scott: see.
Rym: now at that point the game Especially a simple game or a platformer has to kind of escalate to the next level which is we have given you all of the tools You need to succeed now.
Rym: We are going to test your mastery of these tools Increasingly until eventually you either fail or beat us.
Scott: right now the thing is right.
Scott: When like for example look at the Castlevania right it's like in when you're in the upside right castle You're getting all this stuff new weapons new abilities like turn into a bat and shit like that.
Scott: right when you get to the upside Down castle you don't really I mean there must be new stuff somewhere, but really it's just using the stuff You've got.
Scott: so eventually it's like The level is just more and more of the same even though it's harder and the mechanics are there aren't really new ones.
Scott: So it's sort of like even though.
Scott: There's a lot more game left.
Scott: It's like you know and the game that is is a fun game.
Scott: I've done it enough to where I don't really want to do it anymore because it's not a different it.
Rym: I've noticed something kind of interesting that this is rarely happened to me.
Rym: when I'm playing more than three or four games simultaneously Like if I've got four or five games that I'm actively playing I never get tired of them because I'll play one and if I get a little bit of fatigue I'll just play NS instead of tribes, or I'll just play counter-strike instead of Civ 3.
Rym: You know for example, but now especially on the DS I've only really got this one game that I'm playing.
Rym: so if the fatigue's up my choices are either continue to play or Not use my DS and do something unrelated to gaming.
Scott: well I ordered I pre-ordered the Fire Emblem DS, which is finally coming out early next month.
Rym: Yeah, and I've been just pre-order it too, so we can play it quickly and then talk about it.
Scott: I've been doing the Japanese coach on the DS, which is pretty good.
Rym: Yeah, I gotta borrow that when you're done with it I don't know if I'm gonna be done with it.
Scott: I mean it has.
Scott: they can teach you like thousands of kanjis.
Rym: So you think it's worthwhile?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: It's not the greatest thing in the world, but there isn't another DS.
Scott: I mean if you could find something else that does the same thing maybe not for the DS it might be better.
Rym: There's some really bad JavaScript web pages.
Scott: I mean it's pretty sad But it you know it's like it does teach you to mean I'm learning the katas.
Scott: It works You know.
Rym: but anyway I'll skip to this because we have news and stuff and we really got to talk about what we're talking about tonight.
Rym: It's people.
Scott: people saw it in the in the show title.
Rym: yes I know, but we have to talk about it in that they do not know what we have to say about it.
Rym: but anyway what I realized while I was playing this was that despite I The one thing that this Castlevania has the current one the newest one on the DS right now But the runes and the girl and everything is that I think it is the most perfectly put together Side-scrolling Modern since symphony the night Castlevania game ever made however.
Rym: They've pretty much removed Exploration from the game a hundred percent.
Rym: It is basically a fighting puzzle game not as in your fighting and solving puzzles but as in is a series of encounters fights which themselves are minor puzzles.
Rym: you have to figure out the best way through each encounter and It kind of removed like all the leveling up bullshit And it really kind of pared down to where every item you get is useful And there's a lot less of that really lame secret BS.
Rym: like there's a thing with numbers on it And if the last three digits of your gold match the numbers the door opens, and you get a kajigger.
Scott: God yeah Hated that shit.
Rym: so but at the same time I kind of liked the exploration like I want.
Scott: I like the Metroid style exploration, but I don't like the stupid secrets.
Scott: I like the cool secrets like whip the wall that is obviously has a crack in it.
Rym: Yes, not like find obscure secret from game facts and then implement.
Rym: But it's a great game, and I love it.
Rym: But at the same time the it's a. it's a tight race between the fatigue meter and the completed game meter.
Rym: right now I hope I beat it because I kind I don't know.
Scott: I'll play it when you're done.
Scott: I guess I don't know.
Scott: we'll see.
Rym: yeah Yeah, we'll talk about it eventually I don't know.
Rym: lately I've you know we have these moods these trends and right now the trend in my life is really Anime role-playing games.
Rym: Yeah, that's what I'm into right now, and you know we've had these it comes in and out.
Rym: I mean we'll have times where it's board games and nothing but board games for a month straight.
Rym: Yeah, I'm doing some board games lately, and then suddenly we're watching movies again, and it just jumps around.
Rym: right now I'm all about the role-playing games in a big way.
Rym: That's why I'm kind of looking forward to the New York Comic Con.
Rym: mm-hmm cuz I one.
Rym: we're gonna hang out with Luke Crane again.
Rym: We're gonna pester the PA guys, but anyway you got any news.
Scott: news, okay, so Games for Windows.
Scott: right you know about this.
Rym: What in particular?
Scott: well you know what games for Windows is?
Rym: it's games or Windows?
Scott: No, that's not what it now no, but but nominative determinism.
Rym: That's what it must be.
Rym: it can be no more or less than so.
Scott: so Microsoft You know they they label games certain games with games for Windows.
Scott: right they have games for Windows Live Which is basically use your live account which is also an Xbox Live account right?
Scott: And it's basically sort of Xbox Live features on the PC and a few games Support this.
Scott: every other game uses Steve because you know it's basically Microsoft.
Rym: steam is really what it is now if steam Integrated with this or it integrated with steam.
Scott: I mean fallout 3 uses it.
Scott: so I launch fallout 3 in steam, but steam only acts as a launcher.
Scott: But it also does its tech you know overlay on top of fallout 3.
Scott: But then also in fallout 3 I can push the live button to go open up the games or Windows Live.
Scott: So it's not an integration.
Rym: Yeah But I feel like if steam just integrated like I like the features of Xbox Live like I look at what it does And I would enjoy it.
Scott: Thing is right.
Scott: games for Windows Live is like this pale imitation that barely implements any of the features of Xbox Live.
Rym: well thus the problem.
Scott: It's like it's basically a complete failure on every level and in fact in Microsoft's recent layoffs They laid off the guy who was in charge of games or Windows.
Rym: So so I guess the news is this isn't gonna get any better anytime soon.
Scott: Well, it's a. it's a question of is it going to get better if they're gonna get a new guy and try again and do it properly?
Scott: or Are they?
Scott: is it?
Scott: is it dead?
Scott: and is his team just now the king right?
Scott: and that's that's sort of where we're going here.
Scott: And really I'd sort of like to see you know games for Windows.
Scott: I don't know why they did that.
Scott: They should have just called it.
Scott: You know.
Scott: basically what they should do is they should just let you buy a thing for like a hundred and fifty bucks.
Scott: that basically Turns your PC into an Xbox if it's powerful enough.
Scott: I mean when you write a game for the Xbox you program with this Microsoft XNA platform You know DirectX and some other things.
Scott: So you program a game and then you basically push a button and barely change any code, and if you did it the Microsoft way You'll have your game working on the 360 and also the PC.
Scott: obviously you have to put in some changes.
Rym: you know for Controllers and stuff like that, but you know it's not significant, but I honestly in the long run I really do foresee Microsoft going in a direction like that.
Scott: like my vision my idea Microsoft has always wanted you know the the open gaming platform.
Scott: We're just you know and every but every time anyone has ever tried to make an open gaming platform It has been a complete failure.
Rym: part of it I think is that the gaming community has always reacted with immediate and violent disapproval.
Rym: I mean I remember way way back before the Xbox actually came out when the original Xbox was kind of Microsoft's making a game kind of like back in the day when we were all Nintendo gamers and the news was like Sony's trying to make a game console.
Rym: isn't that cute?
Rym: yeah, but Little did we know.
Rym: But the thing is back then even Microsoft was like.
Rym: consoles shouldn't be the way they are.
Rym: they should be a commodity That is generic and uniform and just anyone makes them, and then everyone makes games for the one platform.
Rym: I think I said, but we live in a castle made of money.
Rym: Why would we open the door to our castle?
Rym: and Sega said well?
Rym: Our cast our money castle kind of burned down, but well I think the two problems here are thus right.
Scott: number one if you look at like the Phillips CDI or I don't know the 3do right those are open platforms.
Scott: anyone could make a 3do anyone could make a Phillips CDI right.
Scott: That's why there's so many different ones right.
Scott: What happens is number one?
Scott: The people who you know like Phillips right would charge a license fee to anyone who made a CDI.
Scott: So what reason is there to make a CDI machine if you're gonna have to pay this license fee?
Scott: You're just gonna have to make yours expensive and more expensive than Phillips's one And no one's gonna buy because everyone's gonna buy the cheapest one.
Rym: in the case of Phillips I mean what one thing that Nintendo has always done very well And it was like they were part of the reason why video games came out of that crash of the Atari era Was that they they really nurtured and took care of what games were available on their system And they made sure that there were enough high quality.
Rym: You know Nintendo seal of quality good games to make it a success to where there would always be some good games on the system.
Rym: But Phillips basically said yeah, yeah bums make some games.
Scott: Also, you know when you dig the big money.
Scott: I mean most of the consoles right except for the week.
Scott: What's wrong with you?
Scott: They are sold at a loss.
Scott: You know they sell the Xbox 360 at a loss.
Scott: They don't profit.
Scott: when they sell that the ps3 is sold at a huge loss.
Scott: So not as huge as it used to be but still you know.
Scott: so if you know you're a company That's getting license fees from the games Right then you can sell your console at a loss a low price that everyone will buy it at and then when people buy games You make all your money back because anyone who makes a game has to give you money.
Scott: if you make a PlayStation game You got to give Sony money.
Scott: if you make a Nintendo game you got to give a Nintendo money, right?
Rym: Here's the thing with modern consoles the the hardware that is able to be used effectively by developers is Becoming more and more affordable because we're hitting a lot of limits of game development.
Rym: where to really utilize the hardware That like the cutting-edge hardware that was in these consoles when they came out the next couple of generations Might not get you monetary returns in terms of making money from games.
Scott: Well, I think what it is is that if you have an open platform right for example the PC when you make a PC You don't have to give a license fee to anyone not to Microsoft not to you know anybody right.
Scott: so an open gaming platform means more expensive consoles.
Scott: right and Nobody makes money from the games except for the game makers.
Scott: You know the cut the person who designs the consoles or makes them.
Scott: You know it doesn't make them so that doesn't get money from the software unless they also make software.
Scott: So really it just can't compete with.
Scott: you know the the closed Console platform where the console is such a low price sold at a loss You know and anyone who makes a game for the console has to pay a license fee to the person who makes it.
Rym: well I guess I could really see Microsoft pushing for.
Rym: Eventually they sell an updated Xbox every five years or six years or whatever I mean.
Rym: well We don't even know how long this console generation is going to last and probably at least five years from when it started.
Rym: I feel like it.
Rym: I feel like the drop-dead date at the end of this generation keeps getting pushed back by a lot of things.
Rym: I'm thinking like 11 12 you know maybe 13 even yeah because the gamecube generation was Like when the gamecube came out like people were already rumbling about what was gonna come next.
Rym: This time there wasn't as much rumbling other than there's gonna be a PlayStation 4 OMG, but I feel like what Microsoft would like to do is every five years ten years whatever release This is the reference Xbox and then at the same time release a thing where if you've got a Windows computer above these Requirements it is also an Xbox.
Scott: I know that's what I'm saying right people even though the PC right has the problem of it's an open platform.
Scott: See they don't you know?
Scott: you don't make money from the games and whatever.
Scott: right if They put out a thing that lets your Windows just any Windows computer play Xbox games first of all They'll get a lot of people back into Windows away from the Mac and the Linux that are eaten up at them.
Rym: Right, but they don't lose the non PC gamer.
Scott: I just want a console that I plug into my TV market at all and people are willing to pay more a bigger price For a computer that also does other things than they would be willing to pay for.
Rym: you know a non Sold at a lost console and Microsoft could get a lot of PC Part manufacturers on board because then they can start selling their crazy video card.
Scott: Yeah, if you get games faster It's like well.
Scott: It's like this video card guaranteed to play Xbox games.
Scott: You know that sort of shit all right.
Scott: So yeah, and you know they've already got the Xbox controllers and the games for Windows Live.
Scott: It's just they really bombed at it, and they could have gone all the way.
Scott: Just had your computer do Xbox Live.
Scott: the thing is like.
Scott: Tycho was actually talking about how he asked some Microsoft people like what the Fuck right cuz he had a problem.
Scott: He signed into games for Windows Live and then his Xbox which his kid was watching like Netflix streaming on Signed out cuz you can't be signed in in two places brilliant.
Scott: So Microsoft was like what are we supposed to do about that?
Scott: and Tycho's like.
Scott: that's not my problem.
Scott: It's like your shit sucks.
Scott: You need to fix that.
Rym: Think about the power that man wields that.
Rym: all he has to do is Mention briefly a minor issue.
Rym: He had with something related to video gaming and the world has listened I think.
Scott: he called them and said hey Oh, that's the fact that they would as as what an you know what you or I would do.
Scott: But if I called Microsoft he called you know the customer support and complained the same as you or I would.
Rym: oh You're bursting my.
Rym: I was gonna make this really grandiose point, but never mind because clearly it's not true.
Scott: Yeah, it's not.
Scott: It's in his post.
Rym: you can read it though speaking of which if you if you live on the East Coast And you've always wanted to see gave in Tycho.
Rym: You know the penny arcade guys in person They're actually going to be at the New York Comic Con this year.
Rym: Yep doing panels and stuff.
Rym: They'll have a table.
Rym: They'll be there.
Rym: So we're going to be there too, but before you get your hopes up.
Rym: We're not actually doing any panels or events.
Scott: We're just walking around Walking around looking to be there.
Rym: I'm not even sure which days will be there.
Rym: Scott and I might be there on different days.
Scott: It's hard to say, but I think maybe you know I think I'll be there Sunday cuz it's the quiet day.
Scott: It's like at first I was gonna go Saturday, but Saturday was my grandma's birthday party.
Scott: so and also Saturday I kind of realized that's the crazy stupid day.
Scott: Why do I want to go on Saturday?
Scott: Yeah, but I definitely want to go on Sunday.
Scott: But maybe because I have a press pass I could go on Thursday to the ICV to act.
Rym: I'm kind of thinking about taking that Thursday off work.
Rym: I kind of want to go to that because we get in yeah, and I can also go Friday.
Scott: You know before it's really rockin.
Scott: You know and sort of when shits quiet.
Scott: Maybe you know yeah I don't know.
Rym: I kind of want to.
Rym: I want especially because here's the deal.
Rym: the only reason I'm talking about the New York Comic Con on a Tuesday night is that one We're going to be there even though We're not going to be there doing panels.
Rym: and there's actually a funny story as to why we're not.
Rym: because you see every year We just go as press to the New York Comic Con.
Rym: You'll walk around Interview some people.
Rym: last year we played the wild card game and Discovered that it was terrible.
Rym: Yeah, but the thing is this year.
Rym: They emailed me not that long ago, and we're like hey, so uh people were talking about you.
Rym: It packs you know packs the penny arcade expo.
Scott: And they said you did this crazy badass panel and packs you know is related to the New York Comic Con.
Scott: because Read exhibitions that does.
Scott: the New York Comic Con in the New York anime festival is also doing PAX East.
Rym: so they were like Do you want to come to the New York Comic Con big?
Rym: I don't think they realize.
Rym: the guy who emailed me that we perform like eight panels every year at the New York anime festival and We're already pressed at the New York Comic Con mm-hmm, so I respond and I'm like oh you want us to do panels.
Rym: Here is the list of offerings.
Rym: We have this year.
Rym: We have like seven or eight gaming or comic related things We could run.
Rym: and he emails me back.
Rym: He's like oh, uh I didn't realize you guys were professionals.
Rym: I'm sorry you want to do stuff next year.
Rym: It's a little late this year.
Rym: Please come and be pressed.
Scott: and why table.
Scott: Why did you email us?
Scott: It's like what did you want us to do?
Rym: Oh, they wanted to put us in the podcasting alley which with the table we could do that.
Rym: Yeah, but I didn't really want basically.
Scott: I don't want to sit there all three days though That's the thing.
Rym: if we took one of those tables some smaller Podcast that really really wants to be there wouldn't be able to be there.
Scott: actually.
Scott: no they don't have as many people.
Scott: they got more Tables than people in that area.
Rym: it depends.
Scott: they might know they definitely do have more tables than pot.
Rym: Actually, he gave me a list.
Rym: They got a lot of podcasts.
Rym: really I saw the list was pretty short, but maybe people maybe the list he gave.
Scott: I guess we'll find out if we go.
Rym: look at the map you know, but anyway the the result is Next year the New York Comic Con.
Rym: We're probably going to be doing the same kind.
Rym: I just do it packs every one.
Scott: thing I think was interesting is we were gonna do a panel that was sort of like.
Scott: you know comics for the manga reader and Manga for the con.
Scott: you know non manga comics reader right, but I find it funny that on the schedule Wizard you know wizard magazine and also because they also do an anime magazine anime insider or something like that They're doing that exact panel from both sides, and I was like huh is that a coincidence or Or what?
Rym: well we'll see how well they do it.
Rym: Maybe we'll attend.
Rym: nah I don't know if I'll be there that day But regardless the reason the main reason I bring it up since you probably won't find us at the con unless you Either know what we look like or more importantly if you just walk around listening for us.
Rym: Yeah, that's how most people seem to find us at conventions, but at the New York Comic Con They're making a big deal about expanding their gaming content.
Rym: There's gonna be a lot of video games stuff and a lot of gaming stuff and Luke cranes gonna be there with the mouse guard The mouse guard RPG table and with David Peterson.
Rym: if you're thinking about going I'd say go for at least one day to check out the gaming con.
Scott: It's definitely a one-day con unless you're a crazy comics superhero nerd.
Scott: yes If you were really into color unless you're really into like you know nerdy TV shows.
Rym: Yeah, but we got or you live.
Rym: You know like in New York City.
Rym: You can just pop over there.
Rym: Yeah, why not, but February 6th through 8th, so not this weekend But next weekend at the Jacob Javits Center in New York City Which is basically on the far west side of town in the middle of nowhere.
Rym: there aren't even hobos over there.
Rym: There's no food.
Scott: You do the street meat and there's expensive food in the convention center.
Scott: I suggest if you need food Get in a cab or a bus or something and get away from the convention center because otherwise you're gonna be there right you're gonna Be hungry.
Rym: the only food is either a fake Starbucks the street meat outside Or there's gonna be like this waffle guy making waffles the closest thing you can get the closest.
Scott: Not you know thing to the convention center That's not in it.
Scott: or a street meat is a McDonald's.
Scott: so you need to go pretty far.
Rym: No, no no the problem is those waffles because you'll be hungry And you'll smell these waffles and they will smell the longer you were there like the best food You have ever smelled in your life.
Rym: They pump that smell around like we know a guy who's vegan.
Rym: He's a comic artist.
Rym: He was sitting across from the waffle stand one year, and he's vegan.
Rym: He can't eat that stuff.
Scott: Why can't eat a waffle?
Rym: milking eggs?
Rym: Okay, so by the end of the con.
Rym: He almost bought one.
Rym: It smelled so good.
Rym: Yeah, but the thing is they're like eight bucks, and they're just a waffle.
Scott: Yeah, you know great that a con had like great prices on the concessions.
Scott: remember that It's like I got the chicken fingers and fries and they were like they're like four dollars.
Scott: I was like hells.
Rym: Yes, yeah, and even Otakon despite.
Rym: You know it is still kind of a rip Ripoff but not as much as the Javits.
Rym: well Otakon has cut the prices like in half over the years.
Rym: They did a good job of that.
Scott: They pushed it down, but not down far enough.
Rym: But anyway, New York Comic Con will be there.
Rym: Well if you don't go you'll hear a lot about it since we'll have those press things and we'll walk around Doing the press thing.
Rym: maybe we'll record and or film things.
Scott: maybe we'll see.
Rym: But anyway things of the day.
Rym: now There's a lot of buzz about how those Final Fantasy legend games at least some of them are gonna be coming out in the u.s.. At some point.
Scott: I think they've only mentioned number two which is sad because I like number one and three more even though no one else seems To agree with me because two was the best.
Rym: one one was broken and three one Bullshit.
Scott: one had an awesome tower right and three had.
Scott: your dad is a stealth bomber spoilers But she's.
Scott: how awesome is that?
Scott: your dad is a stealth bomber.
Scott: That's the best.
Scott: what beats that then?
Scott: nothing could possibly be more Japanese.
Rym: You know what beats that?
Scott: Anything everything anything?
Rym: Everything I see.
Rym: we're in a chord everything.
Rym: My thing of the day in case you have never seen this is The first bit.
Rym: enough to see what the deal was with the original Final Fantasy legend - now There's a lot more to this story than meets the eye And I want to kind of bring this up.
Rym: you can do all the reading on your own if you're Really interested in the history, but when I was a kid Final Fantasy came out on the NES, and I thought it was like the best game.
Rym: I had ever played like I. I Loved the ever living hell out of that game mm-hmm, and I beat it like four times I optimized.
Rym: I figured like I would go with all these different parties.
Rym: I tried to beat the game with four white mages found.
Rym: That's actually not that hard.
Scott: It's hard in the beginning for black mages.
Scott: nah, not happy because you can't heal for shit.
Scott: Yeah, these are the white mages.
Scott: you might not do as much damage right away.
Scott: Not only that you can heal up, and then you could do my damage later.
Rym: It's not that you can't heal for shit so much as the fact that in the early game You can't do damage.
Rym: you can cast fire only so many times, and then you're left with a knife.
Scott: Yeah, that does nothing.
Scott: it takes more like at least the white mage has like the hammer that does something.
Rym: Hammers not that bad plus.
Scott: It doesn't do.
Scott: it doesn't do as much damage as like Silver Sword, but it works.
Rym: Well the Thor's hammer, but anyway there you go.
Scott: so
Rym: Final Fantasy was great and then a long long time later Final Fantasy 2 came out on the SNES and then 3 and Then 7 and then I found out oh wait a minute there was a real 2 3 4 5 6 And you know all that business that you should already know.
Rym: if you're.
Scott: all these games have been remade Plenty of times for the PlayStation DS and GBA and everything.
Scott: But there was played them all by now, but in the tradition of messing with American gamers.
Rym: You know they took sick or they took four called it - they skipped five.
Rym: they skipped two and three.
Rym: they took six called it Three then they called seven seven for whatever inexplicable reason.
Rym: they couldn't hide it anymore.
Rym: But there were this.
Rym: there were all these other games.
Rym: there were Final Fantasy legend games on the Gameboy and Final Fantasy Adventure games.
Rym: I think there were five in total legend 1 legend 2 legend 3 Adventure 1 adventure 2 and adventure 1.
Scott: and adventure 2 were actually Saiken Densetsu games, which is Secret of Mana series.
Rym: See that's what I'm getting into.
Rym: these games were called Final Fantasy in the US, but they were actually popular series from Japan Rebranded to sell to the American audience that knew and loved Final Fantasy.
Scott: Yeah, we didn't have Secret of Mana yet, and they actually called it.
Scott: You know they gave us Secret of Mana, which is They didn't call it Saiken Densetsu.
Rym: so they also reskinned a little bit to make the games look like Final Fantasy games, but Final Fantasy legend 2 and 1 and 3 were actually from a series saga.
Rym: So Final Fantasy legend 2 is actually saga 2 the treasure legend?
Scott: well See this is something right.
Scott: is that you look at say the GBA?
Scott: right and the GBA Was sort of really good at doing NES games and sort of okay at doing Super Nintendo games, right?
Scott: So what do they do?
Scott: they didn't really make a lot of new games to the GBA.
Scott: that did a lot of SNES Remakes and the DS.
Scott: they're doing like n64 and SNES remakes and only a few new games, right?
Scott: But for the original Gameboy it was sort of behind so they couldn't remake anything it for it.
Scott: So a lot of the GBA games were originals And there are a lot more originals in the original Gameboy than there are on any of the future portable systems that came after it because those got remakes of console games,
Rym: but Final Fantasy legend 2 is Memorable for many reasons.
Rym: I mean one.
Rym: it is a game where you know you have your theme music.
Rym: It's a fight.
Rym: It's a Final Fantasy ish game.
Rym: So your characters have a theme song the music.
Scott: I just I hadn't heard it in so long But as soon as it started playing I was like oh fuck.
Rym: Yeah, who did the music?
Rym: No, no, boo.
Rym: No, boo the same man who did the music for Final Fantasy.
Rym: so But this was a game where the bad guys are in a room plotting and I am eavesdropping and suddenly I'll start hearing my music like I'm the heroes and I think all right I'm gonna bust in the door and here we go We're gonna kick the bad guys asses and suddenly they look up and go what's that music?
Rym: Oh shit the heroes are here Let's get the hell out and they empty the three treasure chests and leave.
Rym: Damn it.
Rym: The game is hilarious I don't know.
Rym: Maybe it won't stand up when I play it again But feast your eyes upon the first bits of this game and I point out that the mutants are sexy.
Rym: The robots are awesome.
Rym: Monsters are awesome, but not actually useful to play.
Scott: I like them.
Scott: I like all the Final Fantasy Gameboy games and I love the monsters.
Rym: The monsters are cool, but legend 2 has a special place in my heart and Apollo is a bastard.
Scott: Oh and I like the boss of legend 3 Zagor.
Scott: He's very Cthulhuoid.
Scott: He's a big blob with a bunch of mouths Tentacles but a lot.
Rym: I mean almost every square boss in the early Final Fantasy games was either some amorphous blob or something weird.
Rym: He was a big
Scott: blob with a bunch of tentacles right and like an eyeball and then you cut him up a bunch and when you like beat him up halfway like he would change And all these mouths would appear and then you would beat him up and then he would die
Rym: Alright, so what do you got for me captain coffee?
Scott: so This is game that's been you know Getting a lot of press around the the blogs and such called gravity bone and I saw it and I said I'm gonna play that Eventually, so I played it and it's an FPS little indie FPS, you know independently made.
Scott: It takes about 10 minutes to play if you have any FPS skills, but actually even though it is very small It is so slick and so well designed.
Scott: They're only like two minor flaws in it.
Scott: But one thing about the game is that it is executed.
Scott: the chase scene like no other game I think I've ever played.
Scott: it actually has like an amazingly high quality chase scene and I Realized not a lot of other games just either completely bomb The chase scene or don't have them and I think a chase scene is something that gay would be really awesome in games.
Scott: It's really awesome in this one and this game is 10 minutes long.
Rym: I haven't played it yet, but on a scale of dino run Dino run dino runs a game.
Scott: Well, I mean, it's not as long as dino run.
Scott: So you're gonna be done with this in like 10 minutes, but it's it's better than dino run I just want.
Scott: but this isn't a chase where you're being chases.
Scott: chase where you're chasing something.
Scott: It's completely.
Scott: it's completely different.
Scott: You know being chased by something a lot of games do actually but chasing after something else right.
Scott: most games that do that either a the thing that you're chasing is sort of Programmed to stay a certain distance ahead of you.
Scott: So it's sort of scripted right.
Scott: or The thing just gets away from you unless you like do some incredible time run and it's annoying.
Rym: or it's like a One of the a lot of 3d games will have where you have to chase an object or a guy But there's kind of the arrow and you just kind of follow the arrow, right?
Rym: It's not really a fun.
Rym: what
Scott: this game does is it actually does do this scripted chase but you don't realize it because it's so well paced and such and You really feel like you're chasing it and trying to keep up with it and and you're you know It's not doesn't feel like a time trial, but it doesn't feel like a stupid scripted thing either.
Scott: It's it's pretty good.
Scott: So anyway, it's free play.
Rym: We over the weekend got together with the front row crew and we engaged in a gaming experiment.
Scott: right so I was on Boeing Boeing and I saw this link to a Role-playing game an indie a free indie role-playing game.
Scott: a lot of people do these nowadays where you just download a PDF print it out and Congratulations, you've got a role-playing game right because a role-playing game just is just a book, right?
Scott: You don't need you know, if you need stuff It's usually dice and pencils and character sheets all of which you can print.
Scott: So there's no reason to actually need anything physical for a tabletop role-playing game As long as you got dice already.
Scott: and this game didn't even need dice.
Scott: It needs nothing except the paper that you print out.
Scott: So I'm like, hey This game looks pretty interesting.
Scott: I'll print it out.
Scott: Let's try it.
Scott: We need exactly eight people and we can only play it once.
Rym: now the title if nothing else get implied to me.
Scott: I really like the time that this would be awesome.
Scott: I mean the little engine that could Kill the little engine that could kill and I mean, I like the little engine that could so little engine that could kill.
Rym: I think I can.
Rym: yeah, it's like one of the best parts in Dumbo anyway, so But the deal with this game was that now don't worry if you're worried about spoilers There'll be a spoiler line in the show.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So in case you actually want to play this yourself But don't we'll review it so you can make an informed decision as to whether or not you want this game.
Scott: So the deal is it's a railroad murder mystery, you know Orient Express type action.
Scott: So that's that's already plus points, right?
Scott: I love that action.
Scott: who doesn't love that action.
Scott: I don't know anybody who doesn't.
Rym: anyway I don't know anyone cool who doesn't like that Agatha Christie style all the way crazy elaborate murder mystery.
Scott: Let's go Yep, so the way the game worked see I. the thing is you had.
Scott: the game works like this There are eight characters and there are eight packets.
Scott: you print out the eight packets right and you give a packet to each player and then everyone reads their packet and then When you're done reading the packet You're supposed to just know what to do and you'll roleplay and then come to the conclusion, right?
Rym: Think about that.
Rym: that isn't a very interesting idea.
Rym: This is something that games like Final Fantasy crystal chronicles used to.
Rym: I mean to minor effect But the idea that you have a bunch of players who may have different information from one another.
Rym: This takes it one step further in that all information is given individually to players.
Rym: So for all you know, the rules could have been different for different players.
Rym: Yeah, you know your piece of paper might have said you're the murderer.
Rym: Here are the things to lie about.
Rym: here's the deal.
Rym: it could have said everyone's the murderer.
Rym: It could have told all the players.
Rym: They're the murderer.
Rym: Yeah Cuz I'm something crazy.
Scott: So the first the first page in the book is a cover that sort of hides everything from everyone else.
Scott: The second page is your rules right your personal rules.
Scott: So I got the rules for the conductor here, right?
Scott: And this is what they.
Scott: I'm just gonna summarize them, right?
Scott: Don't show your packet to anyone else.
Scott: Don't read directly from your packet, you know.
Scott: roleplay your character You know say I don't say my conductor my character, right?
Scott: If someone asks you a question and you and the answer isn't in the packet just make something up.
Scott: that makes sense.
Scott: This might be science fiction in the story.
Scott: Just let it go.
Scott: Lie with caution because someone will catch you because a lot of the packets have you know corresponding information.
Scott: You may not lie about something you heard someone else, you know Some things you may not lie about and some things you may lie about.
Scott: so the only thing there is you know You you.
Scott: there's no GM for this game.
Scott: So you have to sort of police yourself about the lying and the not lying, you know Because you don't know you have.
Scott: these are your personal rule sheet.
Scott: Maybe someone else is allowed to lie about things or isn't?
Scott: so no one else can police you.
Scott: So you just had to sort of follow this rule sheet on your own.
Rym: Plus I just like the idea that you have these eight secret pieces of information.
Rym: you give them to eight people gaga And then theoretically at the end of that a game will emerge.
Rym: I feel like this mechanic could be used to make a really really interesting game.
Scott: It's like I didn't want to spoil the game cuz like if I hadn't read it in advance.
Scott: I felt like that would sort of ruin it.
Scott: So I sort of didn't read anything and I hand that out all the packets.
Scott: I told everyone the the very minor amount of information I knew about the game and I said, alright, let's go.
Scott: So everyone started reading right?
Rym: So I'll kind of paraphrase my experience here again.
Rym: No spoilers.
Rym: Don't worry.
Scott: Well, the first problem right I think was that people read at different speeds and not all the packets were the same length.
Rym: Yeah, so one packet was like 15 pages longer than mine was 12 pages, right?
Scott: So some people who read slow and got bigger packets didn't finish when we all started at the same time.
Scott: So I guess that could be solved by everyone reading in advance And I guess that that could be good if you gave more lead time on it.
Scott: But I sort of like the everyone reading it at the same time thing that you know.
Scott: I think that really adds to the experience in a way.
Rym: it did in a way because you see what happened.
Scott: We're all sitting there reading our packets and after about 45 seconds someone in the room goes, huh, and then people would you know people just started having Reactions like they would giggle or they would go like what the fuck see that was.
Rym: I was worried when?
Rym: After about a minute an unnamed person said what the fuck?
Rym: Yeah, and then I look up and I'm like, all right and of course Having read mine.
Scott: I was trying not to react but yes I didn't want to give anything away.
Scott: that was on my secret sheet.
Scott: I was trying not to.
Rym: you know as other people started reacting it became impossible not to react Because I started to get the impression that perhaps the experience that everyone else was having Reading their packet was similar to my own.
Scott: Yeah See everyone giggling was sort of making me not be able to focus so much so I went upstairs to read mine and That you know, I was able to actually pay attention to what I was reading more and that that didn't help.
Rym: Yeah you see it got to a point where I looked up and I looked at everyone the crew and I said I Am NOT going to try to spoil anything for anyone But the word penis has appeared for the third time on the first page of my packet.
Rym: How does anyone else feel about this?
Scott: see mine had some nasty shit, but it didn't actually have the word penis.
Scott: So I was just like wow, I guess I don't have the worst one.
Scott: The thing is mine was pretty bad.
Rym: This is when someone suggested and I'm paraphrasing here Scott.
Rym: Are you sure this is a game?
Rym: Are you sure this is not just a collective goatse?
Rym: see that we have all been tricked into.
Scott: See that's the thing is at the one hand right you this is a game that sort of defies the demo, right?
Scott: It's like you have to just go for it.
Scott: You can't, you know, test it before you try it, right?
Scott: Well, you can't try before you buy.
Scott: you just got to buy otherwise you ruin it.
Scott: if it was good I would have ruined it by reading the packets beforehand.
Scott: But by not reading the packs beforehand I read them and then find out that they're all fucked up and crazy.
Rym: So we're we're about to spoil.
Rym: So if you really care you can stop listening in a second, but I will say this if you listen no further.
Rym: This game Terrible is not a word because it does not do how bad this is justice.
Rym: This is an abomination to man and god.
Scott: So basically the first problem I had right was that every character was despicable.
Scott: now There's nothing wrong with having a good end to a degree Disgusting.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: I mean there's nothing wrong with having a despicable disgusting character.
Scott: in an RPG They can.
Scott: they can be quite good right and in a murder mystery The murderer being despicable pretty good or in fact having a despicable person who's not the murderer?
Scott: very good because that throws you off, right?
Scott: but Everyone hated their characters with a passion just about.
Scott: so I really my guy was a piece of shit.
Scott: I was the conductor.
Scott: I was like, wow, this guy is terrible.
Scott: He's like the worst person.
Scott: He's just disgusting.
Scott: It sounds like I don't really don't want to be this guy.
Scott: It made me feel bad reading about this guy because I was supposed to be him.
Scott: Every time I put myself in his shoes, I was like, oh fuck get the hell away from me.
Rym: So, I mean the best way to take you through my experience was I opened my packet and it starts out really strong because I was The violinist.
Rym: it says you are the violinist and it gives me this basic information.
Rym: on Wednesday, August 5th 1932 you and eight other passengers boarded a three-day express train from Bombay India to Lisbon, Portugal, Portugal.
Rym: Unfortunately One did not survive the journey.
Rym: It is now up to you and the seven passengers left even though that's wrong To decide there are you and seven passengers?
Rym: Oh, yeah to decide who killed the eighth.
Rym: No, you killed the ninth And then it tells me to read my backstory and all this and the next page is a map of the train.
Rym: and I look.
Rym: And oh, I have my own quarters.
Rym: All right, there's a peasant I see the Lord and the tennis star.
Rym: I see the staircases.
Rym: There's the bar car.
Rym: There's the cigar car.
Rym: Here's where all the doors are.
Rym: Alright, cool.
Rym: I can dig this and I didn't know if I was a man or a woman or anything.
Rym: I didn't know if that even mattered.
Rym: I'm going to read the the first bit of my backstory and You will see right away where my problem begins.
Rym: The leather of his shoe feels cold and wet likely due to too much shoe shine.
Rym: You hate a man who uses too much shoe shine, but you smile.
Rym: Anyway, he rubs a shoe a little higher on your leg Alright and attempts to show you his pearly whites except they aren't pearly white and they barely make it out of these several layers Of chins that line the lower half of his face.
Rym: Ah You shuffle your bar stool a few inches away leaving his shoe to drop despondently and disappear beneath the seam of his finely tailored chalk-striped slacks.
Rym: He doesn't so much as break eye contact.
Rym: You hate it when men look at you like that as if you were a prize to be purchased in one of their gala London auctions.
Rym: Skip a bit.
Rym: You hate men, but you need money to get off this train.
Rym: You let the businessman buy you a total of 11 martinis The minimum number required to numb your senses enough to tolerate a night in bed with an ogre like him.
Rym: now You would think that it was going to skip past the night in bed with an ogre like him to the next morning when I murder him or whatever.
Rym: But no, I know exactly how big this man's penis is.
Rym: In fact, it uses several analogies relating to avalanches of flesh surrounding tiny mine shafts with barely any silver to plumb It.
Rym: the page informs me in no uncertain terms That I don't feel bad about the fact that he doesn't pay me in the end Because his penis was so small that I barely even felt it.
Rym: It was hardly even any work.
Rym: There are like 15 more pages of this.
Scott: It's it's just disgusting.
Rym: It was terrible.
Scott: And the thing is right is my?
Scott: my guy was the conductor right.
Scott: basically it starts out We're like aha.
Scott: He's secretly working for Scotland Yard.
Scott: All right.
Scott: He's a stickler for the law.
Scott: So he notices all these small legal infractions or pretty much anyone doing anything that's illegal.
Scott: He's like, aha Alright, I'm like, okay, he's a little weirdo like that.
Scott: The tennis star is like, you know super hottie with a giant rack and this guy is totally a perverted voyeur like sneaking in and taking photos of her and Shit, and then he like he wants to get rid of.
Scott: you know he's pretty sure she's doing it with everyone on the train and she is except him and He wants to get rid of all those people so he can have the tennis star all to himself.
Scott: It's just like.
Scott: yes, he has no problem.
Scott: Yeah, he's like, you know, you're like, aha He's an adulterer.
Scott: So I'll get him.
Scott: but he has no problem like Getting rid of these people in order to be perverted and lecherous.
Rym: but like my character the violinist is actually a sex slave in control of the peasant and the barman being sold at the end of this train ride.
Rym: and The peasant.
Rym: let me tell you about the peasant That like the description of his penis and Multiple characters get descriptions of his penis.
Rym: I believe the words were slug-like smelled like a mushroom that the smell of him is like a combination of urine and death and The smell is described in to the point that it is almost a ninth character, right?
Scott: So I read the story and it's you know, it's just sort of perverted shit Right, and then eventually it gets to a point where the writing just like Collapses to where it makes no sense.
Scott: They all kind of do that every single care every single person complained of the same thing in their packet.
Scott: Basically Everything just starts everything sort of going along sequentially and slowly right and then suddenly everything just collapses into an incomprehensible heap.
Scott: it's like you had hit over the head and then you're in a closet and then you see something and then you smell something and Something else and then there's no transitions.
Scott: everything is rapid fire and nonsensical and you have to just read it incredibly slowly and even then it doesn't make sense.
Scott: and You know, I guess the point of the game is that everyone is supposed to take these rapid-fire nonsensical bits at the end of their packet and sort of combine them to figure out who the murderer was.
Scott: You know like oh, well, you smelled that thing.
Scott: Well, I saw that thing and smelled it.
Rym: Details of you, you know, I had sex.
Rym: I look up the clock said 445.
Rym: I walk outside.
Rym: I hear a noise.
Rym: I see this I do that description of the peasants penis again.
Rym: I go here.
Rym: I see these people I look up.
Rym: It's now 515.
Rym: I walk over here.
Rym: I do this and the writing just got like crazier and crazier and There were gems throughout mind like eventually I find the abortion pills Which I also found the abortion bill.
Rym: everyone finds the abortion pills or steals them or whatever and it just so happens that if you take One you get an abortion.
Rym: if you take two you die.
Scott: That's great.
Rym: And they're described in mine as quote the candy of the feminist movements unquote awesome brilliant brilliant.
Rym: It turns that basically the barman the guy behind this sex slave selling business And the bags all Catholic who's working with them.
Rym: it all comes together.
Rym: I really felt bad for Adam who played the Lord because apparently the Lord is Crazy and has like a war flashback and like the last eight pages of his is a nonsensical acid trip.
Rym: flashback through the war.
Rym: Great, it has nothing to do with well know that it.
Scott: obviously it has parallels to the same trips that everyone else is having.
Rym: And then at the end you were presented as a player with the most contrived Situation.
Scott: this is this is what really ruined it.
Scott: when I read I mean it was already ruined.
Scott: But when I read this I was like, oh wow That is it's like I knew that somehow and we got to the end of the packets.
Scott: We would know what to do.
Scott: because think about it, right?
Scott: It's a murder mystery.
Scott: now think about other murder mysteries like say clue, right?
Scott: There's a little envelope that has the answer in it.
Scott: Well in this game.
Scott: There is no answer.
Scott: There is no GM There's no nothing.
Scott: It's just eight people with packets and the answer is supposed to come out somehow.
Scott: So there has to be some rules for when is it over etc, etc.
Scott: So I figured that would be at the end of the packet and I was right.
Scott: But what it was at the end of the packet was like the topper.
Scott: it was like it was already poop But this was like poop on the poop eyes.
Scott: It was the cherry on the diarrhea on the dog.
Rym: I really have to read this to you verbatim.
Rym: Yeah, you do.
Rym: it is so contrived.
Rym: and the worst part is I thought I was the murderer because I'd looked like I killed the Guy, well, you got to read the final page.
Rym: A lot of people thought they were the murderer except the magician whose package said you are the murderer.
Scott: did it really?
Rym: Yeah, basically, okay, but finally basically the gender arms of France appear.
Rym: eventually.
Scott: Those are French police.
Scott: Someone actually didn't know.
Rym: I forget who.
Rym: actually a few people didn't know.
Rym: Okay, I was surprised But you get around and they say all right They arrest everyone and they pull the dead body out.
Rym: and they it says the following the gender arm speaks.
Rym: He says that France has found judges to be corrupt and juries to be inept.
Rym: Justice is becoming through the French as impossible ideal to on it unable to be implemented from the crooked benches of its more crooked courts.
Rym: the writing by the way is Awful to see you now.
Rym: if you haven't noticed the country has loved justice in the hands of you eight passengers.
Rym: It is your duty to reach a verdict.
Rym: It is your duty to make France proud again.
Rym: a vote can be taken at any time in secret or by a show of hands.
Rym: in Order to reach a verdict the voter conviction must be no more than one shy of unanimity.
Rym: France will only accept one guilty party and that guilty party must be sitting at this table right now must be alive.
Rym: Anything less will reflect shame and dishonor upon the good people of France.
Rym: Upon the arrival of an acceptable verdict the murderer will be swiftly and the gender arms assure you Brutally disposed of the decision before each of you is a simple interrogative.
Rym: who killed the barman?
Rym: Now here's the thing.
Scott: how contrived is that it's so good and we Didn't even roleplay.
Rym: We all looked at you were like just like fuck this.
Scott: We're not role-playing.
Rym: Proposed the following the peasant is a piece of shit.
Rym: who sells women as sex?
Scott: everyone is a piece of shit.
Rym: But the peasant was the biggest piece of shit regardless of guilt I knew particularly because my character was the least piece of shit.
Rym: the worst I did was try to murder the barman who deserved it and I kicked the magician in the balls twice.
Scott: my guy was a piece of shit but not a bigger piece of shit as say the businessman or Oh my god the business then.
Rym: Okay, it was hilarious cuz apparently he is crazy.
Rym: He just he thinks like capitalism is the rule of the world and he's just thinking about capitalism all the time.
Scott: Yeah, he's just like oh you got me there.
Scott: He's like the computer.
Rym: It's so crazy like oh my god.
Rym: But I proposed the peasant is the biggest piece piece of shit of everyone.
Rym: I vote.
Rym: we all just say he did it and that's the end.
Scott: and everyone said yes Mostly because they wanted the game to end.
Rym: it wasn't even a game.
Rym: It's not like.
Rym: it set up a role-playing situation.
Rym: It was basically a bunch of gibberish that gave you a bunch of information and then a really really weak Logic puzzle at the end where theoretically you would like try to trip other players off because you know information and lie
Scott: Because you theoretically right it's got the the fear.
Scott: You know the idea was that on the one hand you're trying to share information to figure out who the real murderer is and solve The puzzle but on the other hand you never.
Scott: if people are starting to decide that maybe it's you You don't want that to be true Even if it is true.
Scott: and the actual Mert, you know, you can lie about some things and not others.
Scott: I don't.
Scott: you know and such.
Scott: so you're you this tripping up other people as well.
Rym: But it was so poorly written so contrived so poorly implemented.
Rym: The writing was like.
Rym: I don't think you understand how bad the writing is.
Scott: Worst.
Rym: I've seen fanfics that were much more well-written than this.
Scott: This is one of the worst fanfics ever basically, but it's not a fan of anything.
Rym: I don't think it was actually a game.
Rym: I think whoever made it just wanted to trick eight people into reading the Pornography.
Scott: the price is too high.
Scott: It's free.
Rym: They should have paid people to play it because even then my time is worth more than that.
Scott: I've noticed this though, right the problem this game has I've noticed with some other indie games, right?
Scott: It's that it has some clever idea at the core, right?
Scott: The actual premise is everyone reads something and then everyone role-plays and it could be that could work that mechanic, right?
Scott: But the actual fundamentals, you know good writing Non-contrived Situation etc.
Scott: Etc.
Scott: They fail on all of those.
Scott: look at dwarf fortress, right?
Scott: Really clever core idea dwarf sim with emergent, you know story Problem all the fundamentals of user interface and playability and all those things Complete fail, right?
Scott: You know and there's lots and lots of other indie games, you know of all sorts tabletop You know and video that sort of have the same problem.
Rym: Well, that's multi winia.
Rym: The concept was great.
Rym: yeah game looked cool, but you can't change your controls and some of the networking doesn't work.
Rym: and Alright games already ruined.
Rym: I can't change the control.
Scott: It's like they made this RTS with the idea of the RTS was good, but they failed to do something that Fundamentally every PC game needs.
Scott: I can't change configurable controls And networking that works and even if the networking it worked the controls Yeah, two fundamental basic things and you know, if you look at like professionally made games Professionally made games aren't perfect.
Scott: They also often fail at the fundamentals But they fail at the fundamentals.
Scott: less and Usually most professionally made games have all the fundamentals just right.
Scott: the games work.
Scott: They're bug free for the most part.
Scott: They have configurable controls for the most part, right?
Scott: Not so many glitches But they have no core concept.
Scott: That's any good.
Scott: They're like cookie cutter crap.
Scott: It's just just another FPS just another RTS.
Scott: No clever idea nothing interesting.
Scott: just you know a cookie cutter.
Scott: We have the basics right, but we don't have anything else.
Rym: but then in a situation like this or with multi win Yeah, or of course exceptions on all sides, you know, but yes.
Rym: But we have a lot of indie games where it's the exact opposite.
Rym: great idea terrible implementation still not worthwhile as a result.
Rym: Yep Yep, but like.
Rym: if you wanted me to go into these specifics as to why this game was bad I mean the characters had no like if you really role-played it out Really?
Rym: It's just going to come down to the peasant being executed in the end because no player has any Motivation other than to not be implicated and they'll all just gang up on someone in the peasants.
Rym: The easiest one to game up.
Rym: gang up on because he was friends with the bar man.
Rym: Yep, who is dead?
Rym: Yep, and you don't have to prove they did it.
Rym: You just have to vote.
Rym: That's the rule.
Rym: So that's that.
Rym: that's what we did.
Scott: Yeah, who cares?
Scott: who cares who really did it?
Scott: That's you know, I mean Theoretically.
Scott: my guy cares who really did it because he's also from Scotland Yard and is you know pretending to be a conductor You know.
Scott: But it's such a blur that out of you know The meta fails to.
Rym: most of the interesting role-playing that could have happened would have been in playing out the scenario.
Rym: Instead the whole scenario already played out and you're just analyzing it.
Scott: There's very little left to do and what you're analyzing right is such a mess that you just don't.
Scott: it's just a chore.
Rym: The writing was bad.
Rym: The details were too numerous and too useless and even a little inconsistent.
Rym: There was no like bullet-pointed list of.
Rym: you know, these people, you know these facts.
Rym: You know, it was just like this.
Rym: but
Scott: thing is I feel like if you did that the bullet-pointed list that it would be too simple to figure out who did it and You would just you would you know rapidly maybe within 10-15 minutes Figure out who did it based on all those bullet points and then it'll be over.
Rym: but at the same time the bullet points.
Rym: If you made the game to where there you had motivations other than something so simple and pathetic at the end The character is definitely not much motivation going on.
Scott: I mean my character's main motivation, right?
Scott: It started out where he had dual motivations.
Scott: He had the hots for the tennis star, but also he was working for Scotland Yard.
Scott: He was investigating something for reals Very quickly.
Scott: as I read on he mostly just cared about getting in the pants of the tennis star.
Scott: I was not motivated to do that and that really didn't play into.
Scott: you know Choosing who was gonna get it except for maybe I wouldn't vote for the tennis star because I want her to live and maybe I Would definitely vote for people who you know She was getting with that way I'd get them out of the way and make it easier for me to get with her.
Scott: But other than that the motivation didn't play into it at all.
Rym: The characters were so one-dimensional It was painful like a bird an NPC and burning wheel that I roll up for one session is More multi-dimensional than these characters.
Rym: Yeah, I mean no beliefs.
Rym: No instincts.
Rym: No traits No driving forces.
Rym: so simplistic.
Rym: and again the writing the writing the writing.
Scott: I feel like if you got a good writer, like let's say, you know Neil Gaiman made one of these.
Scott: It could be wicked awesome, but this this one is ass.
Scott: This is the title was wasted on.
Rym: it takes one of those like do the murder mystery over dinner boxes that you can buy in like gaming stores and Removes everything fun about.
Rym: it removes the play out the murder part has a trivial Contrived piece of crap at the end and it takes so much investment in reading that it's pathetic.
Rym: This needs to be burned.
Rym: I'm sorry, whoever it is who wrote it.
Scott: It's a free PDF though.
Scott: So I mean really but can we complain?
Scott: Yes, because he wasted time on it But you should not waste time on this.
Rym: do not play this download it and read it to see how bad it is.
Rym: But seriously do not play it.
Scott: Yeah, I don't.
Scott: a lot of people out there have trouble getting RPG groups just to play like D&D, you know.
Scott: So I don't think too many people out there can get eight, you know people together for this I got.
Rym: I mean everybody is inside everyone else's wife fucking everybody and everybody's room.
Rym: Okay, back door fucking fish I think.
Scott: I think though I am gonna try to you know Play like a one shot of a different RPG every month or so And I think next time I'm gonna do the the mouse guard RPG.
Rym: So, you know what we're reading them.
Rym: from now on I don't care.
Scott: Well, you're not I'm not gonna do any more that are secret like this.
Scott: You know, the mouse guard RPG is just burning wheel with mouse guard on it So that shouldn't be a problem, but this needs to be burned and I think we can end on that.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio.
Scott: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Scott: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.