Rym: It's Monday February 9th.
Scott: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: GPS's location and privacy.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Friday is a big day if you're a total nerd.
Rym: I mean, I think things like this are neat, but I don't celebrate these holidays like I do other geekly holidays.
Scott: Yeah, I don't really celebrate so many the hell geekly holidays.
Scott: I sort of recognize them.
Scott: I have them on my Google Calendar, but I you know most of them.
Scott: I just give like a nod and that's my celebration.
Rym: except for Well, I think the thing for me is that I Celebrate the holidays that are interesting to celebrate But I tend not to celebrate any of the geek holidays that involve big round numbers.
Rym: Yeah, like pi day mold a mold a I celebrated when I cared about organic chemistry.
Rym: I no longer care about organic chemistry.
Scott: You know moles are not.
Rym: moles are for any kind of chemistry not just organic Yes, but organic chemistry is what destroyed my love and interest in chemistry for the rest of forever.
Scott: I kind of like you know like simple chemistries, but I don't like the complex chemistry.
Rym: Yes, organic chemistry.
Rym: I was cool with it until I realized that every lab Basically involved me taking naphthalene and making bad smelling things.
Rym: At that point I decided that I didn't like bad smelling things.
Scott: see my main problem with chemistry Is that it always involved like boiling something right and boil it like you would boil hydrochloric acid.
Scott: I'd always just be like oh fuck shit Worried about spilling the acid on myself.
Scott: Okay, sure yeah, that's the thing right.
Scott: you worried about spilling the acid.
Scott: You know what.
Scott: I'm twice as worried about spilling boiling acid Because you can't even like with the regular acid like in a beaker.
Scott: I can hold the beaker with my hand.
Scott: It's very sturdy grip.
Scott: I'm not gonna spill it.
Scott: You know with the boiling acid I have to pick up a big heavy beaker with like you know half a liter of acid with tongs.
Scott: Oh, yeah
Rym: Actually what I was always kind of worried about wasn't so much the chemicals in the end But it was mostly the physical manipulation like we had to whenever we needed like glass pipettes or anything We had to make them ourselves like we had to go through full lab procedures.
Rym: So I'd have to take like this 10-foot piece of glass Score it in a couple of places kind of break it on the table and then you know oh take the Bunsen burner Melt the end so it kind of rounds out and do all this manipulation and more than one kid in my high school Totally shoved one of those things through their hand.
Scott: Yeah, I was worried about like you know someone tripping and falling over like you know Like a power cord to a hot plate or something like that.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, it was a lot scarier when I mean a good all the good labs and the power outlets up on the table.
Scott: But even then yeah, of course luckily.
Rym: I didn't realize until later.
Rym: I was always kind of worried that someone released like leave the gas out and just you know blow us all up.
Rym: Yep I actually found out that none of the gas lines worked except in the senior labs because they never really used him.
Scott: But yeah That's what I was worried about too is like because I'd sit in a lot of just like lecture classes that right have gas right In front of me and all I could think was the kids in this school aren't that smart.
Scott: the thing is All the gases have central controls.
Scott: It's like if the gas is turned on as soon as you smell it There's a big button to push that says turn it the fuck off even no matter which you know knob it is.
Scott: Yeah, that way you don't have to go searching for the knob while you asphyxiate right and they keep them off all the time Unless you're supposed to be using them right then.
Rym: but Orgo was really scary partly because I didn't take it in high school.
Rym: I actually took night classes.
Rym: So I went to the local college and I took Orgo there.
Rym: So, you know, I'd like to really quit.
Scott: How do we get to this topic?
Scott: I don't know all day, right all day So Friday, but Friday is the day where?
Rym: This is kind of arcane.
Scott: Oh, yeah, I should explain this right.
Scott: Well, so a computer a Unix computer a real computer pretty much anything but a Windows computer, right?
Scott: Keeps track of the time.
Scott: It has a clock.
Scott: Yeah, it wants to know what time it is, right?
Scott: So how does the computer know what time it is?
Scott: Well, it has a number in it, right now It doesn't just have a number for hours and another number for minutes and another number for seconds and another number For date and another number for time.
Rym: the reason for that is because that's a whole bunch of separate numbers not just that.
Rym: math in regards to time sucks because time as we counted was invented by Barbarians from days long ago, right?
Scott: So, how do they keep track of time?
Rym: I mean thing mod 31, but then it changes to mod 30, right?
Scott: Basil Unix was invented like in the 70s, right?
Scott: So for the time in the computer It's the number of seconds that have passed since what midnight 1970?
Scott: I think it's like something like that first way.
Rym: I forget exactly what it is.
Rym: It doesn't matter.
Scott: It doesn't matter.
Scott: So what you do is you look at that number of seconds, right?
Scott: And how many seconds are in a year - the new seconds for the leap days, you know.
Scott: I mean you can figure out.
Scott: you know by math how many days have passed.
Scott: for example I have the time now and I have the time five hours from now.
Scott: It's going to be.
Scott: if I subtract it's going to be.
Scott: you know, five hours is what I said.
Scott: Right five times 60 times 60. right five hours times 60 minutes times 60 seconds.
Rym: But anyway, this number just counts up now.
Scott: eventually this number is gonna max out But you can just make it bigger and bigger with modern computers.
Scott: We have 64-bit computers We can make 64-bit number will be good for the rest of our lives.
Rym: Yeah, but you could talk well It depends.
Rym: final question.
Rym: I mean the last question.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: This is one of those.
Scott: I think that the last I think we can ask it late.
Scott: if we use a 64-bit number for the time.
Scott: The last question will be a problem before we run out of time.
Rym: There's a quote in the slash shot article.
Rym: Alan Cox does assure us that Linux is now working on 64-bit time and the Unix epoch rollover will happen Sometime around when the Sun burns out exactly.
Scott: It's not like IPv6.
Scott: It's a billion IPS per like square millimeter.
Scott: It's like we're not gonna run out on Friday the 13th 2009.
Scott: Oh snaps at 11 31 30 p.m Get your conspiracy theories.
Rym: Unix time is going to reach 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 0.
Rym: Oh my god conspiracy.
Scott: It's the end of the world.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: So if you do a Numerologies, I don't know sir.
Scott: Davis.
Rym: I don't know why they used Perl here.
Rym: There are better ways to do this.
Rym: But if you do a Perl - e and then you just print scale our local time 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 9 0 It'll tell you, you know, you can just do date percent s. Yeah Anyway, this is you can do.
Rym: you can do watch date percent s watch but watch only updates every two seconds.
Scott: You could tell it to update every one second.
Rym: Yeah But only every one seconds.
Rym: you could be up to point nine seconds off.
Scott: you could write you could take an alarm clock program.
Scott: Set it for that time.
Rym: tada How do you know what?
Rym: it doesn't really matter.
Scott: it doesn't matter.
Scott: It's just an arbitrary number is sort of like, you know, oh my god the year 2000 was just an arbitrary number on the year You know, but it's big.
Scott: it is big and round arbitrary and round.
Scott: people love those round numbers in symmetries except for 2012.
Rym: That one kind of came out of nowhere.
Rym: All right That's how you know, it's legit.
Scott: Do I talk about news or should I talk about work business?
Rym: you got work business?
Rym: Yeah, I heard rumblings in the forum.
Scott: There are some rumblings.
Scott: basically, you know This has been something in my work for some time and you know, they I sort of stroll into work.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: I want to and leave.
Rym: what I want to.
Scott: it was my life at IBM Which is you know enough time to get the show done and get on the train and do the commute and the whole thing.
Scott: Right, you know, I'm not gonna give you know.
Scott: with this commute I'm not about to spend extra hours at work because it means I get home like an hour and a half later and that it's Like, you know, it's it's terrible, you know, it's not good.
Scott: And then if I stay at work too long and I do the show I don't get enough sleep and then even if I go to work at the right time I'm sleeping on the desk and not eating three meals because I don't get home time for dinner.
Scott: and if I could buy dinner But it's too much money, right?
Scott: So basically I you know my we never had these before because I've been working there for two years And it was just sort of laid-back, but we got acquired recently, which I think I talked about.
Scott: so now it's much more corporate and such.
Scott: and Basically, you know, I had a yearly review And I had been told that they wanted me to stay there for longer hours and I'd be like, uh-huh.
Scott: Yeah, it's not gonna happen.
Scott: So today was that the review which is all formal and office space kind of shit, right?
Scott: It's weird.
Rym: I I've never really worked at a company where I had to go through anything like that.
Rym: Views have always been like we go out to lunch and we just kind of chat and then that's it.
Scott: So the review is pretty much instead of I thought I was I walked in and I'm like Are you letting me go?
Scott: and they're like, you know, do you want to be let go?
Scott: and I'm like kind of It would have just been easier that way.
Rym: But that's the office space answer.
Rym: because remember in office space the less he cared the more they wanted to keep it.
Scott: I know right No, but basically they wanted me.
Scott: they basically wanted more from me.
Scott: They're like, they think I'm a brilliant technological genius.
Scott: That is just not working hard enough.
Scott: They're like we need you to work more hours.
Scott: Like if there's a problem at like 11 at night We need to be able to call you and fix it.
Rym: I'm like, uh-huh Now what you could have done it because there is a price.
Rym: there's always a price.
Rym: You could have said what the price is for that from you.
Scott: The thing is I am incredibly honest, you know.
Scott: So I'm like look, all right, I Care more about stuff outside of work than I care about work.
Scott: And in fact, I really don't care about this work.
Scott: I only care about it because a the money pays for what I do that I do care about.
Scott: and be you know, you people are cool.
Scott: I like you people, you know, I just this work I don't give a shit about right, you know, I don't care about the company.
Scott: I just you know, it's sort of like.
Scott: the only reason I'm still here Is that if I leave it's sort of like giving you guys, you know the dick move, right?
Scott: Because I mean if I leave the other guy is all you know, the other developer guy he already Sort of, you know works incredibly crazy hours, and I think he's crazy, you know, but you know from their perspective They think it's unfair, you know, which is completely understandable.
Scott: It's like they're working the hours.
Scott: They're supposed to they see me strolling out.
Scott: They're like, oh, it's not fair.
Scott: He's leaving but of course the at the same time I look at them and I go they're crazy.
Rym: they're Better ways to handle this than your company is handling it.
Rym: I mean like what do we do?
Rym: my company we need?
Rym: People to support the production environment from 7 a.m.
Rym: To 6 p.m So what do we do?
Rym: We don't hire someone to sit there from 7 a.m.
Rym: To 6 p.m We have me.
Rym: I come in from I work 7 to 4.
Rym: We have someone else who works 9 to 6.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is even 6 is like too late, you know and You know, there's the 7 to 4 guy and you know the company I mean, they they're only right.
Scott: I went.
Scott: I started working there two years ago, right?
Scott: And if you don't count the people who work for the company that acquired us you only count for people who work for.
Scott: you know Our part.
Scott: there are only five people there who have been there longer than me.
Scott: now It's kind of four of them are named Mike.
Rym: It's got two of them.
Scott: two of them work outside of the you know away from the office most of the time because you know They work from their homes most of the time.
Rym: Well, of course remember when I worked at the hospital I went through four and a half managers because they kept quitting.
Scott: So it's I'm sort of in a situation though because like I've looked at some other jobs I've applied around right and it seems like, you know, I could get another job.
Scott: But a lot of those other places it's like they also want someone to work crazy hours.
Scott: and I'm like, you know, look That's just.
Scott: it's probably not gonna happen unless you know Your company is like way awesome and I own it or something like that.
Rym: Or they pay enough to where then you quit after a year.
Scott: That's the other problem.
Scott: right is if anyone pays me enough money Right.
Scott: I might like let's say someone paid me two hundred thousand dollars a year, right?
Scott: It's some crazy amount of money right and that's pretty crazy for me, right?
Scott: I Would work for one year.
Scott: I would work crazy for one year.
Scott: hell I'd put off GeekNights and everything else for exactly one year, maybe two years.
Rym: I mean then you have twice as much at 400,000 Cuz.
Scott: that's a slippery slope, you know, it would be about a year basically cuz.
Scott: that way I'd make sure I get any 401k rollovers.
Scott: I do the taxes, right?
Scott: I Would probably have after that year was over.
Scott: I would have a hundred thousand dollars in the bank in cash because my cost of living is so low and I wouldn't go and buy extra luxuries.
Scott: Then I would just run away to Europe or something crazy.
Scott: You know have a hundred thousand dollars in cash.
Scott: I could live for like three years or four years on that without having to work.
Scott: So no one can afford to pay me that much money cuz I'll just leave You know, so I and I don't know what I could do.
Scott: But I if I can either a I can find a job that doesn't want me to work.
Scott: crazy Be find a job that'll pay me a shit ton of money.
Scott: Or see I get rich some by some miracle.
Rym: lottery on FARC sees usually the option that ends with you in jail.
Scott: Jail is an option.
Scott: At least at least I don't have to work so hard in jail.
Rym: It is an option.
Rym: Make license plates nice nice and comfortable, you know If you're an open-source guy and you're you really want to learn something that you can learn from slightly out-of-date books.
Rym: You could go to jail for a year Lift weights read books someone pay if I just had a computer with the internet in jail.
Scott: I could be like, you know be great.
Scott: Well, except for I mean, I'm not allowed to make money while I'm in jail But basically I would work for you.
Scott: You would collect all this money into a company and then when I came out of jail You would give me my half of the company.
Rym: So is this the plan now?
Scott: The plan is you to go to jail for me to do the company.
Rym: I'm more of a front man.
Rym: I'll set all this up for you.
Scott: And then Yeah, come out of jail and you're like, hey Scott.
Scott: Yeah, it's a nice hobo beard.
Scott: You guys what half company?
Scott: What what's good?
Scott: I don't even know who this guy is.
Scott: So I'm not hiring ex-con.
Scott: the investors wouldn't like that.
Rym: I finally get out of the joint and you pick me up.
Scott: Maybe I should go to jail if something like that'll happen.
Scott: It'd be totally worth it.
Rym: Anyway, so what are you on the news captain McNews?
Scott: Okay, so people may know I have an iPhone, right?
Scott: But I don't use mobile me, you know.
Scott: So I have the problem in that there's some Google stuff on the iPhone, but most of it is not so great, right?
Scott: It's like I can't use the integrated calendar on the iPhone.
Scott: I have to like go to the Google Calendar website I can't use.
Scott: you know, I can't get my Gmail push to the iPhone.
Scott: I have to use IMAP and like, you know, it automatically checks it every 15 minutes or so.
Scott: I can't get my Gmail contacts onto the iPhone, but I really care about contacts, you know It's mostly the calendar that I care about.
Scott: I want to use the iPhone calendar application But I want it to be my Google Calendar and the ways to do that existed but they sucked.
Scott: the easiest way to do it would have been a I have to buy a copy of Outlook and Be I have to sync with a wire.
Scott: right my iPhone to iTunes iTunes syncs with Outlook Outlook syncs with this tool.
Scott: the tool syncs with Google and Google makes the tool part, right?
Scott: See I'm only syncing my calendar when I'm at home and going through all those different applications Basically removing the point of even having the kind of moving the point of even right.
Scott: so Google came out today.
Scott: They paid Microsoft.
Scott: This is the first time that Google or Microsoft has ever licensed the others intellectual property ever.
Scott: They licensed Microsoft's active sync.
Scott: Active sync is the thing that lets phones Synchronize with exchange servers, right?
Scott: So if your work has an exchange server and You got your Windows mobile phone and you synchronize with it.
Scott: You're using active sync, right?
Scott: It's the same thing that you know, the iPhone uses to sync with exchange servers and such and such.
Scott: right blackberries Don't use active sync.
Scott: You have to get a blackberry server.
Scott: That is a separate add-on to the exchange server, right?
Scott: Anyway So Google licensed active sync from Microsoft.
Scott: They paid Microsoft money and now you can synchronize your iPhone or a bunch of other phones Blackberries and all sorts of things with your Google, you know stuff your Google account Over the air with pushy with push everything right synchronize both ways don't have to plug it in.
Scott: The problem number always a problem.
Scott: number one problem The iPhone specifically can only synchronize with one exchange server at a time.
Rym: now I've said this before but I need to say it again.
Rym: This is that's like the most ludicrous Restriction is completely retarded.
Scott: So this means if you let's say you have an iPhone and you use it to synchronize with your work email You cannot use Google sync.
Scott: you can't because you would have to basically stop syncing with your work and sync with Google.
Scott: instead.
Scott: You can't do both at the same time.
Scott: I can do like a hundred.
Scott: I'm at mail servers killed you one Active sync, it's like really Honestly, honestly, really?
Scott: Seriously, there's no reason for that.
Scott: It's completely stupid.
Scott: Problem number two, and this is really really stupid.
Scott: It only synchronizes your contacts and your calendar.
Scott: It doesn't synchronize mail yet.
Rym: So basically it does nothing.
Scott: basically does nothing, right?
Scott: It's it's beta still but I mean come on.
Scott: It doesn't synchronize the mail.
Scott: So if I wanted to use this I would have to synchronize with my company's email by IMAP synchronize with my gmail by IMAP and Synchronize with my calendar and contacts only by push.
Scott: That's not worth.
Rym: They have basically released the goggles and nothing more, right?
Scott: I mean If you only use Google stuff, maybe it'll be worth it to use the push because you can't get the Gmail by push Anyway, so you might as well do it with IMAP and then synchronize the other stuff with the push because you're not using it.
Scott: But I mean, come on see I guess push it's still not a real solution.
Scott: It's the one thing I can say in their favor.
Scott: They did release it for Google apps right away.
Scott: They're not giving Google apps people to stick anymore.
Rym: Finally, we've been living on like the second class citizen island for a while.
Scott: Anyone who is a front row crew Google apps.
Scott: You can.
Scott: you can use this if you want.
Rym: I guess at least luckily one I'm still using like the original razor.
Scott: No my cell phone because you only make calls.
Rym: I mean Well, I have the word blackberry which I use as my blackberry and I I don't really care about push because work.
Rym: I need push because I'll be on call for things sometimes but for my real life, I don't really need push.
Rym: Yeah, I understand how it can be useful.
Rym: It's not like I'm gonna be you punk kids.
Rym: Why do you need push?
Rym: I understand why some people would need push.
Rym: I only need pull.
Rym: In fact, I dislike anytime media is pushed upon me.
Scott: I like well, I kind of like, you know being notified of like a new email or something.
Rym: yeah, only if I'm at a con where it would matter.
Rym: like say I email Luke crane and I'm like Yeah at the con blah blah blah and I want him to email me back.
Rym: The only way for him to get my attention is to call me or send me a text message and text messages suck And I don't like answering my phone to push emails.
Rym: great for that, but that's the only time.
Scott: so Hmm I like.
Scott: I like pushing big.
Scott: I guess it.
Scott: what it is is that you're the pusher robot.
Scott: I don't have that.
Scott: I mean if if I have the thing constantly buzzing with shit, it's like fuck that right?
Scott: But if every push is something significant, you know like I'd recently went through and I've just been unsubscribing like crazy from all these bullshit newsletters that you sort of accidentally sign up for even though you try not to.
Rym: when you like Websites and things one thing it does do that I can see is if every email you get is significant or you have good filters In place is that it removes the desire to go and check your email exactly.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: I mean not only have I unsubscribe from all these bullshit newsletters But I have filters in place that move all sort of like the automatic emails into a separate folder.
Scott: So like if someone follows me on Twitter, I don't I get an email but it goes into a separate folder So that I you know, it's just sort of hidden.
Scott: So every email that actually ends up in my inbox is a real email.
Scott: That's like the real deal for me and I you know, that's something that is seriously want to read.
Rym: yeah, well I the thing is I get more and more because I tend to do more of the producer side of GeekNights.
Rym: I Get a lot of email from various press outlets and it's not easy to filter it because it comes from a lot of different sources.
Rym: Like I'm on these lists where I'll get.
Scott: you could always they'll filter out the the GeekNights emails from you know, the ones that are to GeekNights I don't know.
Rym: I'm talking about the ones that go to me.
Rym: My personal email is also on all these lists because I'm like I'm the point of contact for all.
Scott: you could do stuff Like if the email, you know There's filters that you can do that say like if I am the sole recipient do this.
Scott: if I am NOT the sole recipient Do something else.
Scott: that way you can get off lists and things.
Rym: I think what I need to do is eventually just make another email alias.
Rym: That is just.
Rym: you know personal personal personal.
Scott: Yeah, we could do that too.
Rym: And then you know Rym at frontrowcrew.com.
Rym: basically is the.
Scott: you know Exeter sucks though that Rym isn't the personal one.
Scott: It's like you'd want that to be the real one because it's the stage name.
Rym: I mean, it can't be the real one.
Scott: There's no way you can use like Brandon the coster.
Scott: I think you have that anyway.
Rym: Yeah, I do but no one in the world owes me by that name.
Rym: Like people I work with and even them they kind of they kind of know the deal.
Rym: All right, like.
Rym: no one calls me that but I like it met like gave in taiko, right?
Rym: There is no way either of them could ever even check Gabe or taiko at penny arcade.
Rym: calm Yeah, the same deal.
Rym: Yeah, I mean any listener can figure out my email address.
Rym: I have to have the.
Rym: you know Rym - you're actually my friend at front row crew.
Scott: I can.
Scott: may I just tell me what you want.
Scott: I'll make it.
Rym: Yeah, I'll figure it out.
Rym: Well, yeah, anyway along those lines actually not along those lines at all.
Rym: the the Kindle was announced actually like it.
Rym: It was leaked already.
Rym: You could have found most of this stuff out already But the Kindle 2 is out and you can read all the business and there's a million videos.
Scott: You're not gonna break it down.
Rym: I am gonna break it down.
Scott: All right, break it down.
Rym: Basically, it's $360.
Rym: Mm-hmm, which is I'm gonna wait.
Rym: That's too much money.
Rym: I Really?
Scott: I'll tell you what I think of it when you when you're done Like I really really want one.
Rym: and I gotta say like they were talking about how it's a lot thinner than the original which I Found hard to believe when I heard that rumor because the original was already pretty freakin thin.
Rym: This thing is thinner than the iPhone like it's tiny.
Rym: It's like a. it like it's smaller than anything I carry around But it's $360 and you still can't just put PDFs on it.
Rym: Like.
Rym: those are the two things that really bugged me.
Rym: but I mean otherwise.
Rym: The screen is a lot better.
Rym: Like it's a lot more contrast.
Rym: It changes pages a lot faster, which might sound dumb, but Using the old Kindle like it took it.
Scott: Yeah, you listen to our episode about you know, ebook readers and the screens and whatever.
Rym: I'm trying to avoid talking about anything that we covered there.
Rym: Yes, like general needs but it took it a Noticeable amount of time to flip pages.
Rym: It wasn't a deal-breaker But like you noticed and you kind of went and it sped up.
Scott: now to the point.
Scott: I'm sure though that when they make a the Kindle 3 or the Kindle Nana or whatever that it will flip pages even faster And that the car the new one will seem slow, you know, but I was watching videos of the difference.
Rym: It is fast enough now to where it is no longer a concern of mine Like it is.
Rym: I no longer care about that.
Rym: It already flips fast enough Yeah, but the battery lasts a whole bunch longer.
Rym: the screens a lot sharp.
Scott: battery lasts for fucking ever apparently.
Rym: Yeah, they it lasts officially 25% longer, but I'm hearing reports that it basically is now like the Nintendo DS.
Rym: You just never charge it Yeah, and the other thing that was interesting was that they Sorry Basically, they made the screen like actually sharper.
Rym: There are more levels of darkness that it can display.
Scott: There's 16 colors of gray something like that.
Rym: Yeah, and I can't verify that in person.
Rym: I haven't touched one yet.
Rym: But as far as the internet has said it really stands out as being different.
Rym: Mmm, and other than that, they haven't really changed anything.
Scott: Yeah, here's is the thing.
Scott: is I really wanted to want a Kindle right?
Scott: What do I like about it?
Rym: Oh, no thing.
Rym: They added text-to-speech again.
Rym: Why?
Scott: well, that's good for people who can't.
Rym: you know see but there are better ways You know if you can't see you don't really need a Kindle.
Rym: You need a purpose device for people who can't see.
Scott: I know Yeah, if you can also you can listen to audible audiobooks on it, but I can do that on my you know I thought right which is smaller.
Scott: Um, so I wanted to want the Kindle.
Scott: Why did I want to want it?
Scott: Well, I Had.
Scott: I hate.
Scott: I like reading to want me.
Scott: I like reading a lot.
Scott: You can stop.
Scott: I want lots of books.
Scott: I want to pay less for those lots of books, right?
Scott: So Sometimes Kindle books are more expensive than actual books and sometimes they're less expensive, right?
Rym: I don't even like care about that because basically even if Kindle books cost more Well carrying around physical books if it's just text like if I'm reading, you know, farewell to arms or something.
Rym: I Just want the words.
Rym: I don't care about anything else.
Rym: now if I'm carrying around the mouse guard book I don't want the Kindle.
Rym: I want the mouse guard book Yeah, but I'd only.
Rym: I want a device where I can just read what I want without having to buy and carry around physical books.
Scott: Yeah, but the thing is here's the problems right.
Scott: number one.
Scott: when I buy physical books I mean book lending happens a lot, you know, it's not like with other things like with music or movies, right?
Scott: There's not a lot of lending going on.
Scott: Usually, you know you watch a movie together with all your friends and then you know Maybe you rent it or what you'll stream it or something like that.
Scott: So you don't need to have it and lend it.
Scott: but books.
Scott: There's a lot of lending especially like comic books.
Scott: I lend them like crazy, right.
Scott: so well basically the DRM to ebook.
Scott: There's no lending going on.
Rym: It's not even just that it's a more fundamental issue.
Scott: So why am I paying this price?
Scott: that could possibly be more than the cost of the paper bag?
Scott: Clearly it's for the convenience of having the yeah, but I'm losing the lending ability Which I care about much more than the space taking ability.
Rym: Well, I care more about.
Rym: well in for me personally I care more about the space and the convenience.
Scott: I care about the space a lot But not as much as a lending.
Rym: but the lending is not the issue.
Rym: It's much deeper than that And I've realized this and I've mentioned it before but it really hit home when I actually went from yeah ebook readers to will I buy this?
Rym: and I realized that I can't buy the Kindle because I can't support The erosion of first sale rights.
Rym: I have a right to first sale the fact that DRM and we saw this in video games with downloadable content and we're seeing this now with ebook readers and with Netflix and these things.
Rym: But I think it's going to be a serious issue that is going to affect lower income classes of
Scott: people
Rym: as time goes on that because secondary sales are increasing and Pete there's so much media that People will they're more willing to buy use things or borrow or lend not even pirate but perfectly legally get used DVDs You know rent in return these sorts of things.
Scott: I just saw it speak.
Scott: I I just sold right the.
Scott: I sold four things on Amazon.
Scott: I just mailed the last one today.
Scott: They all sold.
Scott: someone bought Gundam f91.
Rym: Haven't helped them losing the right of first sale?
Rym: well, I think is going to have far-reaching societal implications that I am not comfortable with mm-hmm and That coupled with the fact that because it is DRM.
Rym: I'm basically renting these books not buying them.
Rym: I've decided in the end that just philosophically and morally I cannot support the Kindle as long as It is set up in such a way that I lose the right to first.
Scott: Yeah, I mean if I buy a paperback book I can sell it again on Amazon Kindle book.
Scott: you're stuck with that book forever.
Rym: Well, not even forever.
Rym: Never say forever.
Rym: It's DRM.
Rym: It's not forever.
Rym: It's you know a number of years.
Scott: maybe You know, it's stuck on your Kindle.
Scott: It can't be removed from the Kindle.
Rym: Well, no, it's an account.
Rym: like you can download it to another Kindle in and all that stuff, but You were reliant upon that DRM and you could you know at some point we're probably going to lose our access to these works.
Scott: They did one thing they did that was nice.
Scott: on the new Kindle is now It actually connects with USB and you can like send text files over and such Not PDF because PDFs need to be converted which is an understandable to convert PDFs.
Rym: You can't just convert them.
Rym: You have to basically email them to Amazon and they convert them and then they email them back to you And then you put them on the Kindle or they email them to the Kindle.
Rym: Oh Scott you email them back to you and you put them on.
Rym: I'm pretty sure.
Scott: the I'm pretty sure they email them directly to the Kindle.
Rym: You've got to let me finish because I read all the articles and I know I read the thing on amazon.com.
Scott: It says your kindle has an email address.
Rym: Yes, you realize there are two ways to do this and they're important caveats to both.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Rym: You either email it to Amazon they email it back to you and then you sync it to the Kindle for free over the USB or You email it to Amazon.
Rym: They email it via the 3g to the Kindle and you pay ten cents.
Scott: Oh, I didn't know you had to pay ten cents.
Rym: Yes It says that straight up very clearly.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Rym: These are two ways to go about it Uh-huh, but the part that bothers me is you have to email it to them.
Rym: Why don't they just give me the?
Scott: why don't they?
Rym: The official answer that it kind of makes sense is that it's still beta and because of the way PDFs are a Lot of PDFs just get totally fucked up.
Rym: So by emailing them to them they kind of get to test the converter and continuously update it on their side without having to constantly update everyone else.
Rym: and Theoretically someday they'll have a converter that works pretty reliably and then we'll get it.
Scott: The problem is it's only gonna work on a PDF that is predominantly text.
Scott: It's not gonna work on a PDF that has like you're like if I had a PDF of the mouse guard book.
Scott: That was all scans.
Scott: you like the mouse guard RPG Even if the text was in time with all those pictures and shit, but I'm fine with that because it's just a text reader.
Rym: It's clearly not an image or video or color or anything like that.
Rym: But in the end we lose the right to first sale wide reaching societal implications.
Scott: Like far the price is too high.
Scott: the amount of money I'll save on the books isn't enough to make Like zero concern.
Rym: Yeah, I can.
Rym: I'm concerned with societal implications and personal use.
Scott: Yeah, anyway, and oh the one other thing that I don't like about the Kindle that it kind of bothers me, right?
Scott: It has his keyboard on it, which is you know, it's.
Scott: it's a fine keyboard, right?
Scott: And the device is still pretty small.
Scott: but How much type am I gonna do on it?
Rym: Realize people who own Kindles now from what I see they just surf the web on it and like check their email.
Rym: The thing is I have I found it.
Scott: Oh, I only want to use it for reading books.
Scott: I don't want to use it for any of that stuff.
Scott: I have an iPhone.
Scott: That's way better as a color screen.
Rym: Other people want they wanted enough, right?
Rym: They're willing that they want it like that is a.
Scott: that's fine for those people.
Scott: But for me, I don't want that.
Scott: In fact, I specifically don't want that Something that doesn't have that keyboard in the way and is actually much smaller and just reads books.
Rym: But Scott, you know, give me the Kindle Nano.
Scott: You're forgetting the point.
Rym: You're probably never going to be the demographic for the Kindle.
Scott: I mean.
Scott: the thing is I really want to want one.
Scott: I just did just I get caught up in the specifics.
Scott: Just fuck it over.
Rym: But the thing is the technology.
Rym: the Kindle is fine.
Rym: I'm okay with that screen.
Rym: I'm okay with everything.
Scott: Oh, yeah, I'm okay with the screen.
Rym: I'm even.
Rym: I'm okay with the price to the point that if the DRM were not a concern or if Instead of this model because the reason why I'm okay with Netflix on demand or even Netflix in general but I'm not okay with this DRM or you know, the old iTunes DRM is that DRM that pretends you're buying something when an actuality you're renting it is BS DRM.
Rym: that is straight up.
Rym: you are renting it is fine.
Rym: And if the Kindle here's if the Kindle cost the same it does now and I had to pay 20 bucks a month on top of.
Rym: But that 20 bucks a month got me access to Any ebook on Amazon like maybe 10 at a time for as long as I kept paying?
Rym: Like I wouldn't even can I would have already bought it.
Scott: There is one difference though that I do agree with that mostly about the renting.
Scott: there's one difference though between renting of a physical medium and Renting of like a streaming thing, right and Netflix is okay because they still send you the physical thing if you want, right?
Scott: But you can also get the streaming.
Rym: I don't care about the physical thing Amazon.
Scott: Well, the difference is right and this is this, you know, you might not care about it, right?
Scott: But I think it's very important is let's say Netflix is only streaming right, you know.
Scott: And you say compare it to Blockbuster where you rent DVDs, right?
Scott: And let's say they were the same price, whatever, right?
Scott: Just get all those other things.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I'm curious where you've got that thing.
Scott: That will be a problem of everyone.
Scott: switching to the streaming is now We can't like take those streamed Netflix's and make YouTube mashups or we can't you know remix them or any of that.
Rym: That's a good thing for the industry in the end.
Scott: because look I don't care about the industry We're caring about us.
Scott: We care about the industry.
Rym: You should buy the Kindle Scott and for us, I mean, that's not a concern I mean your rights, right?
Rym: You're renting the media just to watch it.
Rym: Like.
Rym: that's what you're paying for.
Rym: if you want the actual media in an open format to deal with personally for you know Remixes or whatever just buy the DVD.
Rym: they sell it in the store.
Scott: Yeah, but they have to.
Scott: you know, the thing is if I rent from Netflix on DVD I can do that You know with only renting.
Rym: but that's just because they give you this extra thing that most people don't want.
Scott: Yeah, but that's you know, I'm still.
Scott: that needs to be.
Scott: you know That's just because I can see.
Scott: I you know If the streaming and it's not it access becomes the norm and ownership goes away.
Scott: I mean you can't you know copy and paste from a from Amazon book and you I've never said that ownership will go away.
Rym: The thing is that it's.
Scott: the thing is I can see ownership going away in favor of these.
Scott: You know street just giving access.
Rym: But Scott ownership only goes away if the majority of people don't care about the rest of it and the majority people don't.
Scott: I know That's a problem.
Scott: It's it's a severe detriment to to art and creativity.
Rym: I don't think it's nearly that much of a detriment because even with the streaming people just hack it and I'm pretty sure that the ownership media will still be there because the the average people at least for the foreseeable generation of people They still like to own these things.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know but if we start moving to lot to access and you know Ways to own things become incredibly expensive or impossible.
Scott: It's gonna be problematic.
Rym: from that standpoint I think that is a much weaker concern than the much more pressing concern.
Scott: I still think it is a very strong concern.
Rym: I think it's.
Rym: I think it's weaker because it's much deferred by the fact that culture changes much more slowly.
Rym: I'm more concerned with DRM Rapidly removing our immediate first sale.
Rym: right then I am with DRM.
Scott: Yeah, I'm more concerned with that.
Scott: But I'm concerned about both and I don't want to give up either one.
Rym: You're basically the concern that the rental model will destroy.
Rym: the buyers model has been a concern since blockbuster first existed And that is not panned out yet.
Scott: Meanwhile DRM getting rid of first sale Yeah, but what's happening is renting is become is because is expanding and not just rental but into an Access to anything you want at any time.
Scott: but access only.
Rym: But but Scott everything that has that the physical media and the ownership has gone.
Rym: Nowhere is still right there in a van Yeah, but I could you know, give me any example of something that became on-demand only Yeah in a few years.
Rym: Do you really because so far there's zero examples?
Scott: Yeah, it's not happen.
Rym: But but there's no trend at all.
Rym: It hasn't happened at all.
Scott: It's gonna have.
Scott: DVD sales are going down the shitter Is going up.
Rym: DVD sales are going down for a lot more reasons than that.
Scott: I'm just saying, you know, it's it's coming.
Rym: But Scott, like I said, it's coming.
Scott: We got so we were gonna wait until it happens and then worry about it.
Rym: No, I'm saying that you have to prioritize.
Rym: No, nothing is.
Scott: I'm saying both we can.
Scott: why can't we do both?
Scott: Why do we have to stick with just one Scott?
Rym: In the world no priority is ever equal to another priority.
Rym: there is always a point of decision.
Scott: So therefore there is always a matrix of my point of decision after both of those.
Rym: Okay All I'm saying is that I think it's a much less immediate concern than the loss of first sale because is a less of a concern But it is still a great concern.
Scott: The other one is a greater concern.
Scott: Okay, I'm both great concerns.
Rym: I still feel that the loss to first sale is a much greater and more immediate concern.
Scott: That's fine.
Scott: That doesn't mean the other one is not a great concern.
Scott: That is also great I don't.
Rym: I think it's a concern that can be deferred for at least five years if not a decade.
Rym: not even Okay, but the thing is we already have evidence of DRM and first sale like being taken away by downloadable content.
Rym: There is already zero precedent for losing access to original ownable media.
Rym: but anyway things of the day, uh I found this a long time ago and I ignored it because it looked like one of those really dumb things like this.
Rym: looked like The kind of video that wouldn't even be worth clicking on in one night.
Rym: I'm sitting around with Emily and Scott.
Rym: You know, we got the computer open.
Rym: We're looking at funny internet videos in my room.
Rym: Just you know, hang it like you do and We've run out as we do there.
Rym: There aren't that many worthwhile things on the internet anymore.
Rym: Kind of it's hard to find something that's so novel or so new in.
Scott: Actually good That is also quick and new.
Rym: I mean, alright some guy getting in the nuts.
Rym: I've seen a hundred videos.
Rym: What do you have new?
Rym: does it get hit in the nuts twice?
Rym: I've seen that three times.
Scott: seen that I We're so jaded.
Scott: We need to see something new and amazing.
Rym: So we run out and I do the thing that always happens where I click on like one last video.
Rym: it's like I'm going to bed after this and I click on this video of the counts from Sesame Street, you know batty batty batty One of my favorite Sesame Street's if not my number one favorite.
Rym: now all this video does.
Rym: is it a run for it with the Cookie Monster is censor out one and Exactly one word the word count and it is just bleeped out.
Rym: That is all they do.
Rym: is they bleep out the word count for this entire song.
Scott: Well, actually they don't bleep it out when he's referring to himself by name saying I am the count But they bleep it out whenever he uses it in any of its other meaning.
Rym: Yes So basically they bleep out the verb but not the proper noun exactly.
Rym: The end result is Funnier than you would have I think expected.
Scott: I think they did it on purpose back then the Sesame Street makers Jim Henson and whatnot.
Scott: I think they did it on purpose.
Rym: I wouldn't be surprised because you listen to this and It goes beyond you know, like Pink Floyd matching up with Lord or not Lord of the Rings Though someone did that too to prove that is BS.
Scott: Yeah, but it goes beyond Pink Floyd matching up with something and goes into like Because I really love Sometimes I sit and all day But sometimes I get carried away.
Rym: Hi slowly slowly slowly getting faster.
Scott: once I start It's very hard to stop Faster faster, it is so exciting.
Scott: I could One two three four one two three four one two three four one two One two three four One two three four one two, that's a song of the count Like the spiders on the wall Like the cobwebs in the hall The candles on the shelf.
Rym: I That's what I got Scott.
Rym: It's funny like every time Scott was gonna try to steal this from me and do it on Thursday because it was so good.
Rym: So I had to preempt him.
Scott: No, what could I do?
Scott: I can't I can't steal I stolen.
Scott: like every good thing in the day whenever there's a battle over it He has and so I have to let one go.
Rym: I have lost at least five or six good things of the day and to my power of dibs.
Scott: So back when I was in RIT and in times before right, you know, you go to a college.
Scott: You have these old computer science teachers.
Scott: They've been teaching computer science like forever since before, you know modern computers And there's always this one Computer that's always sort of mentioned, you know as like.
Scott: ah back in the day We used this machine and the machine is the pdp-11.
Scott: It's sort of a really famous old computer that you know sort of a generation or two of computer scientists before me.
Scott: That's what they use, you know people in the 80s and such Pdp-11s were what they learned to program on.
Scott: that was the mainframe.
Scott: that was.
Scott: you know what all the sort of you know jobs Wozniak gates type people.
Scott: if they went to college, you know, it didn't drop out.
Scott: That's what was there, right?
Rym: It's one of those.
Rym: if you don't even know anything about computers, you'll just you'll hear that now It's a.
Scott: it's a historic famous computer the pdp-11, right?
Scott: There's also a pdp-10.
Scott: This is a pdp-11 simulator and as a guy He's got this whole how-to and a whole bunch of tutorials and you can learn to program the pdp-11 which I Think is pretty awesome.
Scott: If you got some free time You can learn the real deal computer science just like you're a computer science student in the 80s.
Rym: This is one of those things where if you want think of something
Scott: or the same I don't know what you're just
Rym: thinking something cool and simple and try to do it here and You'll learn a lot more than you might from just taking Python writing if you
Scott: can if you can make this happen.
Scott: This is only for people who really really want to be programmers not for people who just want to learn some programming To do normal everyday stuff.
Scott: This is something only computer science.
Scott: people really need to know but it is You know, you'll learn a fuck ton.
Scott: if you can understand what this shit is going on You will be a master.
Rym: so we're not really gonna talk about the direct news of this because the news is you know, Google has this cool thing, but there are a lot of issues related to this and we have to explore at least the beginning of this because It's a topic that I've been thinking about ever since.
Rym: a long time ago when Penn Jillette of all people brought it up He posited on his old, you know, Penn Radio this hey, wouldn't it be cool?
Rym: if oh, but what if the government's?
Rym: And I remember back then thinking Like I immediately I thought of like a hundred cool things I could do with it And then I thought of a thousand bad things other people could do with it.
Scott: So basically just to sum up the news Google has a thing called latitude And basically what they do is if you have a phone or some sort of GPS device It will you basically let Google know where you are as you move around town and then it will update a Google map and People can see you on it, you know But only people you allow.
Scott: so like I would let Rym follow me and then Rym could know where I was.
Scott: So let's say I was coming to meet him at I don't know the train station.
Scott: He could see aha Scott's on 27th Street.
Scott: He's a little far away, but I'm not gonna lies around the corner.
Rym: I'm not gonna let Petto bear 978 at AOL see where I'm going.
Scott: Well, you're not to let him see where your little kids ago.
Rym: No, I'm not gonna see where I'm going.
Scott: Alright, and the fundamental problem here is on the one hand you want to take information about yourself Record it digitize it and share it with people you trust because that is incredibly useful right.
Rym: secondarily Analyze it for your own purposes.
Rym: I mean imagine if every day you could go home and look at a heat map of like where you went every day and like what watch your walking paths and where you slow down and where you sped up and the Work and all
Scott: this data about you is useful in a million ways and you know.
Scott: In fact, it's even good to share some of it depending on what data it is with the entire world because I mean like, you know Maybe I only want the people I trust to know where I am right now.
Scott: But I might trust the whole world to know what book I bought and that's totally useful to like, you know listeners whoever what you know, they want to know what books I bought and it's it's helpful to them if they think I'm a good judge Of taste and such, you know The problem is is any information you release about yourself can also be used for nefarious purposes and specifically location data is some of the most sensitive because it can be used for stocking.
Scott: Now and if you're a hot lady that is doubly troublesome.
Scott: Or if you're an internet person in general, I mean or any sort of famous person like even if you're like You know a mayor or a senator or you know anything not even famous because famous is too broad a term.
Rym: But I would say have brought the attention in famous Have brought attention to yourself on any level.
Rym: I mean anyone whose name is mentioned on the internet in places where a lot of people go is immediately Subject to it.
Scott: could even it could even be local fame.
Scott: I mean if you're just like the popular girl in school or the really unpopular person at school.
Scott: Or maybe you have like a book club, but like they don't like you or you know or some anything even a small group You know, it could be anyone in that group, you know if you got troubles.
Rym: So, let's talk first about the fun side of this.
Rym: Pretend for a moment.
Rym: We're in a magical world where?
Rym: Every possible negative concern has been magically addressed by the Flying Spaghetti Monster.
Scott: So if only that could happen, please Flying Spaghetti Monster save us.
Rym: There is a God He's made of ramen because because you posture farians can burn in the everlasting pasta hell.
Rym: I Sorry, so there are no privacy concerns whatsoever.
Scott: worship the kitchen era.
Rym: the government never looks at it.
Rym: What are the cool things we could do like this here?
Rym: This is the kind of the we could optimize walking paths.
Rym: one this is kind of the fantasy baseball side of man wouldn't be cool if I could do X Y & Z and Two.
Rym: this is why geeks like us are so excited about the possibilities.
Rym: I mean if there weren't cool possibilities like this Like if you could only do a few cool things with it Then the privacy concerns would far outweigh to the point that we wouldn't even bother.
Rym: but example Hanging out with the front row crew.
Rym: one of the biggest thing problems we have is on a weekend where we're all hanging out like we're all gonna play some burning wheel or some mouse guard or something and No one really says when they're gonna show up.
Rym: or like someone gets delayed and we're sitting around.
Rym: It's like noon on Saturday.
Rym: We're wondering who's showing up when we're trying to like call people.
Rym: Hey, did you leave yet?
Rym: Well, I just saw Pete posted something in the forum.
Rym: So he's probably still in the Albany and blah blah blah.
Rym: What if I could just go to the heat map or the Google map and I see a dot for everyone?
Rym: I know dude.
Scott: I just had a. that gave me a greatest idea.
Scott: You could use these with a road rally.
Scott: Oh my god, you would know.
Scott: like if you know, you could just see where everyone is.
Scott: So even though you say you could do any kind either rally you could do you know The long-distance sort of rally with the checkpoints or you could do the actual downhill rally Right where you just see the cars go around the turn you're standing at, you know But you can see who's winning there.
Scott: You know how fast he's going down the mountain by looking at your little Google map or even the annual you know GeekNights road rally raced from Baltimore to Wildwood.
Scott: Yes, something like that, right?
Scott: You could you know and if the GPS is precise enough you could like if we're at Otakon, huh?
Scott: Where I wonder where Pete is.
Scott: Oh, he's in the dealer's room.
Scott: Oh, I wonder where a Rym is.
Scott: Oh, he's at the artist alley table, you know you or like.
Scott: hey, I'll meet you someone.
Scott: So let's meet in the middle.
Scott: So you're walking towards someone and sometimes you know, you're trying to meet someone in the middle You'll pass each other not seeing each other in a crowd This way.
Scott: that can't possibly happen.
Rym: that happened Emily and I. once next to Brian Park We were trying to meet and we were walking toward each other on the same side of the street on 42nd Street.
Rym: We passed each other three times.
Scott: Wow Yeah, I mean, you know one step further.
Scott: I think about New York Comic Con yesterday, right?
Scott: We sort of you know We tried not to split up and such we could have split up and then found each other like nothing without even picking a meeting spot.
Rym: go one step further and do the Outlook thing where there's a function where you can tell outlook to schedule a meeting when five people are free.
Rym: You're right now.
Rym: combine this with Twitter or something like it.
Rym: I hit the need to meet up button with my defined group of people I need to meet up with.
Rym: it pings everyone.
Rym: I want to meet up with Immediately and says Rym wants to meet up and it calculates a meet-up space based on who all accepts the meet-up.
Rym: that is the optimal location for all the people who agreed to Distance wise.
Scott: so everyone has the shortest walk to meet us.
Rym: Yes Yes, or you define like ten meeting places like the bar downtown.
Rym: We hang out at the bar uptown.
Rym: we hang out at the bar cross town like.
Scott: how about this?
Scott: We're in a giant dealer's room, right?
Scott: It's wicked crowded, right?
Scott: I see something way awesome Right, so I just go and I type let's say I see I don't know what'd be really awesome.
Rym: You see a hot today Miku Holograph generator that will act out and sing the site.
Scott: So I see Hatsune Miku, right?
Scott: I take a little video of the Hatsune Miku with my phone and then there's.
Scott: It sends it out to all my friends who are also at the con and they know exactly where that video was.
Scott: They can see it right then and they can see where I am when I was taking the whole thing.
Scott: So then if they want to see the Hatsune Miku, they can go right there During the con or alright, I'm skiing me and Scott Johnson.
Rym: We you know, we go skiing together that way.
Scott: You know if we get like I'll be like, oh, where was that Hatsune Miku?
Scott: I forget we're in the dealer's room.
Scott: It was oh shit.
Scott: We lost it.
Scott: Uh, that won't happen.
Rym: But one of the problems I often had was that all right I'm at the bottom of the hill or you know, he's waiting at the bottom of the hill.
Rym: How do I like?
Rym: how long do I wait?
Rym: do I just go back up and ski down again?
Rym: Like maybe I can just look on the GPS on my iPhone and be like, oh he's going down way out All right.
Rym: Well, I'll go up and I'll ski down the backcountry trail and I'll meet him at the bottom of the z-lift.
Scott: Oh, we're in the grocery store.
Scott: I'm already done with all my groceries.
Scott: Where's Rym in the grocery store?
Scott: Do I have to run back and forth down every aisle?
Scott: Maybe he checked out already and is outside at the car waiting.
Scott: I'll just know.
Rym: Or even you know.
Rym: privacy concerns aside, obviously The police can find me when I want them to find me.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, oh no So I broke my leg in the woods.
Rym: help help.
Scott: I am right here help.
Scott: Oh god.
Rym: or even better I can see like the rescuers are coming after me can ping and so I can see where they are in the woods and they Can see where I am so we can move toward each other instead of the.
Rym: if you can move Yeah, but if I can as opposed to the old standby of when in doubt you have to wait because you don't know where the Rescuers are or actually you.
Scott: just you know, I mean regular GPS can do this already, right?
Scott: But you know, you could let your kids just got into the woods and then know where they are and then go get them Yeah, or you know, you're a parent.
Rym: if your kids agree to it You can.
Rym: just you can see where your kids are all the time.
Rym: Yeah And I can think of like like.
Scott: I can think of so many things that you don't need to call and embarrass them while they're Friends basement or whatever.
Rym: there are things I could do with this sort of technology the being able to share location data with friends in real time in real time.
Rym: that would Revolution.
Scott: the real time is what gives it an advantage over just like buying a GPS in your car.
Rym: But it would I could revolutionize my life and resolute revolutionize my social interactions to an unprecedented degree.
Rym: Mm-hmm Of course, it's not a fantasy world.
Rym: You really want Governments that you may or may not agree with being able to track semi secretly all their citizens all the time.
Rym: Do you want your boss to be able to see?
Rym: That you took an hour and ten minutes for lunch because you went all the way across town to a bar?
Scott: Do you want you know your boss to see that you went to like the porn shop?
Rym: Do you trust Google to know where you are?
Rym: Yeah, Google already knows everything else about you.
Rym: Do you want them to know where you are all the time?
Scott: I mean we trust Google now and basically I figure trust is something better where you put your all your eggs in one basket because When you're trusting your data, right?
Scott: I mean if I trust it all to Facebook and Google then it's sort of like there's a two Chances of me getting fucked this way.
Scott: the only chance of me getting fuck because you're completely fucked if one of them goes away Right.
Scott: So the fewer the better right.
Scott: does that make sense?
Scott: It does Yeah, so I figure out.
Scott: trust Google because they have been proven the most trustworthy.
Scott: They're not gonna stay trustworthy forever.
Rym: probably the only reason I trust Google now is a very calculated game theory as Basically what my benefit of trusting them far outweighs the damage?
Rym: No My logic is thus if Google turns evil the odds of them turning evil against me in Particular are very low.
Scott: I also the one thing another reason I want to trust Google.
Scott: if Google decides to fuck everyone They're also.
Scott: they're probably gonna fuck everyone.
Scott: They're not gonna fuck just me, right?
Scott: They're gonna fuck everyone.
Scott: at the same time There'll be a very giant lawsuit happening.
Rym: No, I don't forget lawsuit.
Rym: You got to think on the Mad Max scale.
Rym: You've got to think in absolutes.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, it'll be Mad Max when Google fucks everyone.
Rym: it might be right but no In in a board game.
Scott: I have to search on Google for.
Rym: look in a board game if There are option.
Rym: you have nuclear options you have brinksmanship and all these things.
Rym: But you don't just weigh how much an individual decision helps or hurts you.
Rym: You also weigh how much it helps or hurts or has the potential to help and hurt other people.
Rym: You may or may not be competing with and if a decision hurts everyone equally.
Rym: as in you know, there are 10 people playing the game if we all Choose to accept the help from the mysterious power and then at the end of the game we flip over the mysterious power card and it says minus 10 points.
Rym: if Everyone chose to trust the card Everyone loses the same.
Rym: I am no better or worse off because alright Google knows all my secrets.
Scott: You're no better worse off relative to the other people who are also on Google But you're still worse off compared to people weren't on Google.
Rym: But this is the thing the almost everyone who is Functional in the modern world Basically is trusting Google to a large degree.
Scott: So basically you're just betting along with everyone else like a game of craps.
Scott: Everyone's betting to win.
Rym: You know, it's that the more Google decides to be evil the more the wider their damage is the less damage They're doing individually.
Rym: because alright, they know everything about me They know everything about everyone.
Rym: if they go after everyone The what they can do to me compared to what they can do to everyone else Becomes a drop in the bucket because the information they have on me becomes more and more like an unto noise if they try to Break into everyone's bank accounts at the same time and steal everyone's money The the response from the world is violent.
Scott: Yeah Alright, so forget about Google being evil for a second.
Scott: What if you know other people are being evil, you know someone who looks and sees where I am is a stalker.
Scott: They're going to stab me and great me this great.
Rym: Yes grape This sucks because our IT there was a big problem with the IT and CS labs and that people needed to use them.
Rym: They weren't open all the time.
Rym: there wasn't enough space in the labs for everyone who needed them to use them at the same time and The you know pretty much on the weekends, you know, you couldn't sign up for lab time.
Rym: It was like first come first serve and they were debating all these different ways to make it work better.
Rym: Like maybe you can reserve time or maybe you can look and see you know, if the labs free and then reserve a spot.
Rym: but the reason they didn't implement a lot of these things the primary reason was that stalking was a big problem on our IT's campus like Stalkers were not that uncommon.
Scott: In fact, I mean I've heard of a couple but I didn't think it was a big problem.
Rym: It was a big enough.
Scott: I mean, I heard of a few that it was a problem definitely, you know with some of the scary nerd types.
Scott: But I didn't think it was like oh my god.
Scott: It's all over the place.
Scott: no,
Rym: it was a big enough problem to where it was a concern a specific concern here in that if they set up a System where you could check into a lab and then you could look at the computer, you know in real time and see If there is a spot in the lab, like I could see there are two tables free in the sysadmin lab.
Rym: I'm gonna reserve one and head over there.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: Mm-hmm creepy people can look and say alright, it's 11 o'clock There's only one person using the lab right now Someone is alone in the IT building.
Rym: Mm-hmm And that was enough of a concern to veto several of these cool options.
Rym: It's not just our IT.
Rym: stalking and I've read some reports on this when I worked in a capacity to see the academic papers being written by professors or that were being funded by grants and studies on students and everything and stalking a low-level Non-violent stalking or low-level stalking that causes non-deadly or non-violent but still important concerns is a growing and huge problem on college campuses because Kids be creepy.
Rym: internet-leds.
Scott: creepy kids, especially Especially nerdy kids be creepy.
Rym: Yes We're not talking about geeky kids thing about nerdy kids And I don't know what to do about this because every time we enable to I mean even get them all girlfriends.
Rym: Yeah It's our boyfriends.
Rym: Even if we secure this technology like alright only your friends can access this.
Rym: if the system gets compromised Someone can access your data now you're fucked.
Scott: Yeah, it's true.
Rym: So what do we do about that?
Scott: Yeah, I mean look even with the Google system, right you choose who can follow you and who can't and all that stuff, right?
Scott: But someone could like maybe they could hack into Google or maybe what if someone like takes rims phone now?
Scott: They know where I am, you know It's a. it's a rough situation.
Rym: The problem is the first half of this was pretty much I could revolutionize my life in a way that would be far-reaching and like Difficult to determine the end result but definitely positive in manifold ways.
Rym: But when it comes to the caveats and problem side, I have nothing but concerns and zero answers.
Scott: Yeah, I know right.
Scott: It's like what can we do about this?
Scott: It's just we just do a risk-benefit analysis for each thing and put as many safeguards in as we can.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, I guess we could like require a password every time but then that Reduces a lot of the utility as any security reduces utility.
Scott: I mean think about it putting a lock on your front door doesn't seem like a big deal It does it me you have yet to.
Scott: now every time you want to go in your house You have to have a thing turn an extra knob, you know, it's like extra work.
Scott: Right, you want to have a fence around your house.
Scott: It's extra work.
Scott: You have to open this fence.
Scott: every piece of security that I have ever seen adds extra effort.
Scott: You know a password.
Scott: I have to actually type in a password.
Scott: you have to do more work.
Scott: So I need to have a security.
Scott: you put on this adds extra work and in something like location data Where like, you know, it changes constantly.
Scott: that few seconds of typing in a password or doing something like that Really decreases the utility very very significantly Compared to the security that it provides.
Scott: to the point at which it's sort of like putting 20 locks on your front door It's like well fuck this isn't even worth it at this point, you know better off not having a door
Rym: I guess for me personally, I am because I'm generally Confident and capable and I feel as though I can deal with the majority of situations I would be put into and I'm generally not risk-averse and I am generally unafraid of well just about anything.
Scott: Yeah, if any if any cute girls want to stalk me That would be welcome.
Scott: I as long as you're not the scary knife stalker.
Scott: That is not cool.
Scott: Stay away.
Rym: I would be kind of okay, like to the point that I might just be willing to If I had a GPS device publish my location data almost all the time and just see what happens.
Scott: My problem with it would be not so much that I care about my location data It's that there it wouldn't be useful to me unless my friends also did it, you know, it's like unless everyone does it.
Scott: What's the point right?
Scott: It's like let's say we use it to arrange meetings at Otakon, right?
Scott: Well, what if two of our friends don't do it because they are afraid of stalkers.
Scott: Well now it's useless.
Scott: We need to fall back to another system, right?
Rym: Yes, so even if so the solution is pretty simple only for very technological people.
Rym: The solution is to as a group of friends Develop our own system that integrates with all of our technology and not give it to anyone else Mmm, but you know, basically the answer to a lot of these problems is slowly big.
Scott: you know all these cloud computing type problems is slowly becoming.
Scott: everyone make your own private cloud and That is not you know.
Scott: for us we can achieve that but many people cannot.
Rym: well in the long run Maybe the answer is open source clouds that like open source cloud device I mean we sorta.
Scott: I mean think about it's like we set up a laconica server instead of using Twitter.
Rym: Take that to the extreme.
Rym: eventually you buy a cloud computing self-contained open source device bring it home Plug it in buy all the associated dongles like sync them all together and now you have your private cloud Mm-hmm.
Rym: I think that's the future in the deck.
Rym: I
Scott: mean they do have like the Microsoft home server, but most of those things are for like Low land stuff, you know like in my house all the computers in my house The whole family can share photos and videos and watch movies on the Xbox and those sorts of things, right?
Scott: And that's a. you got to just expand that out past the router somehow and let people get at it from no matter where they are Without having to deal with network bullshit.
Scott: and then you've got that All right.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I think we've got a lot of topics we could talk about.
Rym: any one of these related.
Scott: I think we can talk about privacy more in general at some future.
Rym: Yeah, but for this point, I think we're done.
Scott: I also think we're done.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: For the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution Non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.