Rym: It's Thursday June 25th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We talk about the realization that all our heroes will eventually die.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So I came home today to box on the porch and in that box were 20 smaller boxes.
Scott: Why was there a box of boxes on the floor?
Rym: I needed boxes to pack up a lot of my books and stuff to get them off the floor since I wasn't about to buy a bookshelf for a Temporary house.
Rym: I'm not gonna buy like a No more half measures in my life.
Scott: So so why didn't you just get some free boxes?
Rym: because free boxes are usually not a consistent size and shape And I have moved enough times to know that I'm willing to pay a premium to not have any difficulty whatsoever.
Scott: Uh-huh Well, you could have made you know you could have done is you could have bought like some sort of cardboard bookshelf?
Rym: No Yeah, cuz you can't pack books in that you can't.
Scott: cuz.
Scott: then what you do is you slide the cardboard bookshelf into a box.
Scott: That is exactly the shape and width of the cardboard Something.
Scott: and then there you go.
Rym: I realized something like that would cost a lot more money and not be that nice there when you get to the other end you Just owe a slide it out.
Rym: Tada cuz I'm gonna get a real bookshelf at the other end.
Scott: Yeah, but you could have the temporary cardboard bookshelf.
Rym: I don't need that.
Scott: It's gonna be good.
Rym: plus I mean I was looking online and buying New boxes was cheaper in most cases than buying used boxes or recycled boxes.
Scott: You don't buy used boxes you go and get them for like the supermarket.
Rym: Well, no if you want them in a consistent size and shape without any possibility of strange smells What's wrong with strange smells?
Scott: Yeah, go to the UPS store and just go in the back Don't you know?
Scott: don't take him from the front take him from the back.
Rym: You mean steal them because you've got to buy them from the UPS store.
Scott: They haven't for you got to be buddy buddy with the people work there.
Rym: Yeah, now you got.
Rym: I mean, I'm gonna go to grocery stores and stuff to get a lot of the boxes I need.
Rym: but for books you want to get small Consistently sized boxes that are guaranteed to hold the weight of a box full of books a zillion pounds Because the other mistake I made in the past was trying to put a whole bunch of books in one box.
Rym: No, you need tiny little square boxes for books.
Scott: Yep, because they are heavy.
Rym: Plus.
Rym: actually if you want free boxes supermarkets are so passé.
Rym: That's not where you really want to go.
Rym: You know where you really want to go the liquor store.
Rym: Liquor stores have more boxes than grocery stores.
Rym: there's nothing spilled on those boxes unless a bottle broke which is unlikely and You can also get partitions in the boxes to hold like kitchen stuff.
Scott: Well, yeah, but but I mean, you know those partitions.
Scott: it'd be nicer if the partitions are smaller.
Rym: the pretty bigger.
Rym: Scott those partitions Just come out if you don't want to use them.
Scott: I know but I'm saying if you could modify the size of the partitions it'd be much better.
Rym: smaller Do you need?
Rym: what are you gonna put like?
Rym: bigger bigger because it's Like one pencil for not smaller.
Scott: bigger.
Rym: If you need bigger just get a smaller box and use more of them.
Scott: Oh, maybe you can get one of those like ba boxes that came with like magnums of wine in it.
Scott: That would have bigger partitions.
Rym: Anyway, yeah, the other thing that came earlier was the RAM for the Mac mini.
Rym: Mac mini.
Rym: has you know, I bought the Mac mini early on in the Mac many days.
Rym: I bought the slowest cheapest Mac.
Scott: Well, it wasn't.
Scott: there was a g4 Mac mini.
Scott: people don't remember that that I don't count that.
Scott: We have the very first core solo Mac mini and I got the minimum.
Rym: I didn't spend the 200 bucks for this.
Scott: We did not realize that it only had like 512 meg of RAM.
Rym: I realized that when I bought it and I didn't care because it was like four hundred dollars to get more RAM.
Scott: Well Apple charge.
Rym: Yeah, and back then the RAM that went into it was pretty expensive.
Rym: So I figured screw it I got the cheapest one.
Rym: you all remember the night I tried to record and then edit GeekNights on that thing with garage band.
Scott: That was that's an old episode.
Rym: that night is in the top 20 of worst nights of my life.
Rym: Well, I was up until like 3 a.m.
Rym: Because remember I had burned every bridge.
Rym: I when I plug that Mac in on my desk into that CRT that 19 inch CRT.
Rym: It was so beautiful and I had unplugged my computer and like moved it aside.
Rym: It was completely dismantled effectively.
Rym: Mm-hmm and Around.
Scott: the thing is realizing now, right?
Scott: Even if you had liked OS X and I like garage band and liked all that stuff That Mac Mini was not powerful enough to be your computer.
Rym: Well by any stretch it would have been had I never ventured into video and had I never wanted to play a computer game again.
Rym: Yeah, cuz back then what computer game was gonna play?
Rym: what?
Scott: Now?
Rym: now yeah, and s2 is coming.
Scott: you would have been l4d lists.
Rym: But I remember around midnight when I gave up plug my old computer back in spend an hour setting it up.
Rym: It was about 4 a.m.
Rym: When I uploaded that.
Scott: show Was a good times though.
Rym: No, it was a terrible times.
Rym: It was a terrible night.
Rym: I rue that day, but the Mac Mini served a much better purpose not as a primary computer But as a media PC.
Rym: because whatever you want to say about Apple their industrial design is some of the best in the world.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty much.
Scott: It's pretty much the only thing they've actually had to sell Mac Mini.
Rym: all the iterations of it are The perfect size the perfect weight.
Rym: They are completely silence.
Rym: They're tiny and they're beautiful.
Rym: yeah, and We bought RAM for it.
Rym: Now.
Rym: It has two gigs of RAM We had.
Scott: it's much less painful.
Scott: watch movies.
Rym: We had a living room jam a putty knife and pry the top off to get into it.
Scott: Yeah, getting that opening it up and fiddling with it was not a pleasure.
Scott: It's not something you're supposed to do.
Scott: So I didn't expect it to be a pleasure But I do it and it works.
Scott: So fuck you Steve Jobs.
Scott: I opened your box.
Scott: What you gonna do about it?
Rym: Yeah, the other thing that came is I have my hands a 1 terabyte external drive that I'm finally properly backing up all of GeekNights' on - But that wasn't my reason for buying it.
Rym: I bought it because I got a. basically I'm giving up on Linux for now and I'm gonna have a Windows 7 computers my primary Computer.
Scott: Yeah, I mean I pretty much you know, I I use Linux pretty much all the time every day all over the place But it's always in a virtual machine or on a server or actually also on my laptop.
Scott: But yeah, that's pretty much it.
Rym: That's the direction.
Rym: I'm going.
Rym: I'm gonna have a Windows box with a one Virtualized Linux image in it.
Rym: Hmm I mean my laptops could be up Linux except for the fact that Windows seems to still have better power management and better support for the weird.
Scott: Well, I mean if I wasn't doing all this gaming and other stuff, you know I would probably still I would run Linux on my desktop also, but I am doing that stuff.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, what do I do?
Rym: I do gaming and multimedia Development which are the two things Linux can't do.
Scott: Yeah Well, actually, you know, there's some things happening in Linux department that are Scott's coming up from behind.
Rym: will dual head work without me having to go through arbitrary bullshit.
Scott: You mean two monitors?
Scott: Yes, that's worked for a long time perfectly.
Rym: Yeah, absolutely perfectly as good as Windows.
Rym: Yeah without any problem ever of any kind.
Rym: What's no no possible problem in Ubuntu.
Scott: Yeah, this works.
Scott: You've never had a just works for like three versions of Ubuntu.
Rym: Never had a dialog box pop up in the middle between two monitors ever.
Rym: That's a deal-breaker for me.
Rym: If that happens, I'm done.
Scott: happens if you use some like shady ass programs in Iran.
Rym: Yeah That was the last time I tried dual head on a Linux box.
Rym: Yeah, I use cinerama.
Scott: Yeah, that was a long time ago.
Scott: Yeah, no, that's that's fake.
Scott: the problems you have now or so are more basic things like There is no real video editing software except cinellara, which is shit, but they're working on something new, but it's not ready yet.
Rym: But to get back to the boxes I was pleased that my box of boxes arrived and there was a note in the box of boxes saying Don't forget you can use the box.
Rym: the boxes came in to pack something.
Rym: Don't throw it away.
Rym: It's great for paintings and stuff And it is it's kind of in that shape.
Scott: All right.
Rym: The other thing is this box of boxes.
Scott: How much was the box of boxes?
Rym: It was 40 bucks for 20 box.
Scott: That's a lot of money.
Rym: No tax.
Rym: No shipping.
Scott: That's a lot of money.
Rym: Not really look at the UPS store or you haul.
Rym: buying them in person.
Scott: cause more than that I know but I'm still saying it's a lot of money.
Scott: That's how much the liquor store for free.
Rym: Yeah, but those aren't the right kind of boxes.
Rym: I am getting boxes from the liquor store.
Rym: They're not.
Rym: do not believe that I will not be getting Primarily to hold all of my liquor.
Rym: great, I Don't know I. what am I gonna say?
Rym: I couldn't top the alligator head story from Tuesday.
Scott: That's why we should have just you know, if you can't beat it just don't say anything gotta say something.
Scott: No, you don't.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So, uh, you got anything to say.
Rym: no nothing.
Rym: No Did you say beat it on purpose or is that just what I came out?
Scott: I didn't.
Scott: I wasn't even thinking about that till you just said it.
Rym: All right Well, I have one announcement not really a news, but we finished the previous book club of cavalier and clay Which is an amazing book and you should listen to both the preview and the final thoughts and read that book.
Rym: It's amazing.
Scott: Also, you know book club people I mean if you are not listening to the book clubs or not participating in the book club at least tell us Why and your thoughts and such because our goal with the book club is to increase reading of books without pictures Among the listenership
Rym: While a lot of the people in the forum are pretty erudite and they seem to know their stuff.
Rym: I got to tell you guys a lot of the emails we get Bali One's literacy.
Scott: Yeah, so, you know, that's sort of our goal here.
Scott: So, you know if you're not liking the books we pick.
Scott: if you think they're too long You don't you want us to change the format of the book?
Scott: The frequency of it?
Rym: if you don't like the books were suggesting you're wrong.
Scott: Well, that's also true.
Rym: We haven't suggested a bad book yet.
Rym: Yeah, we're going to.
Rym: don't worry, but a long time.
Scott: for that.
Scott: We'll warn you when we do, you know, so let us you know, give us some feedback about yon book club.
Rym: So I really really still wanted to pick the Odyssey, but I know none of you assholes are gonna read it.
Scott: I wouldn't even read it.
Rym: Have you ever read it?
Scott: No, really?
Rym: I never read it.
Scott: I mean, I know the way never read it.
Rym: what like you've seen it perform.
Scott: Well, I saw you know, like adaptations of it like Odyssey the you know, the cartoon or the Ducktales episode.
Scott: That was the Odyssey.
Scott: So Claymation the Odyssey.
Scott: actually I remember and I don't know there was a claymation that is it just made that up very much.
Rym: Enjoy that Ducktales one.
Scott: Yeah, I had that on a VHS.
Rym: I'm just I'm really feeling I gotta watch magic.
Scott: a dispel played the the role of Cersei.
Rym: but anyway, and I wanted to do Historical nonfiction, but again you assholes won't read that.
Rym: I know you won't read it.
Rym: So I was gonna try to make some sort of like nonfiction.
Rym: But it's all pop or relevant or pot, you know, something like guns germs and steel or collapse or history of the world and whatever glass, you know that sort of thing.
Rym: and While I really want to do that I feel like that would be better served as doing a show talking about the topics they raise as Opposed to the book because you can get this information from anywhere Mmm, and the book itself doesn't add anything other than a pop culture easy to digest version of that information.
Rym: But I wanted to do something at least literate.
Rym: so Randomly today Scott quoted some Hess at me from Steppenwolf and I realized in that moment that while I am a fan of Hess I have never in fact read Steppenwolf and I feel stupid as a result.
Scott: Well, it's like you can't listen.
Rym: That's like yeah Shakespeare.
Rym: I know all about Shakespeare.
Rym: I love him.
Rym: Yeah, Macbeth.
Rym: That was great.
Scott: You know, I've only read like three Shakespeare's maybe two.
Rym: Let me guess because everyone knows Macbeth Hamlet and maybe Richard the third.
Scott: No, I don't really know the story of Macbeth other than those witches.
Rym: Wow, yeah, so I take you've never seen or read all the the king ones none of them not even Richard the third.
Rym: You know like, you know, like even the tempest.
Scott: I don't know what the story is, but I really like the name the tempest.
Scott: I just picture this tornado That is.
Scott: I don't know what it's about though.
Rym: That is exactly what it's about.
Rym: It's about a tornado that comes to town and kills everybody.
Scott: Oh, I gotta read that right.
Rym: taming of the shrew That's good.
Rym: They basically going to the top of the queue they catch the shrew in the woods and they try to tame it to perform in a circus.
Scott: I Know that's not what that's about.
Rym: Hamlet.
Scott: I know I know Hamlet and I know the Hamlet was remade recently.
Rym: There is a new not the because there's a Patrick Stewart Hamlet.
Rym: That's awesome.
Rym: But there was actually remade as a movie You might have heard of.
Rym: it was called babe Hamlet.
Rym: So The book I'm choosing is a book that I have not read but I know is good.
Rym: it is Steppenwolf Not the band.
Scott: Oh Damn it.
Rym: I Was disappointed that I. I have a bet.
Rym: I'm curious.
Rym: I think I'll make a poll.
Rym: I want to know Do you know Steppenwolf primarily as the book or as the band the band?
Rym: they are both important.
Scott: No, so I would even almost argue similarly No, I had this pile of books many of which are thanks to fade sending us too many books For Viennese too awesome.
Scott: So, you know, I had this large unread pile and I told myself look I'm what I'm gonna do is I'm gonna take all my books that are just books of words and not comic books and I'm gonna Read all of them that are unread.
Scott: I'm not gonna buy any new ones and after that I will buy an e-book reader of some kind probably the open B-book, which can just read PDFs and is not a closed-ass Kindle type thing.
Scott: So rest recently, I just started reading and last over the past few days I read make room make room which is the book that soylent green comes from even though Soylent green is nothing.
Rym: There's no soylent green in the book Although there is soylent in the book as the whole time Scott's reading it because I kept asking every day So is soylent green?
Scott: people know so in that book There's no soylent green and nothing that anyone eats as people.
Scott: there's absolutely no cannibalism accidental or intentional.
Scott: But if you read it, you'll understand why soylent green is people in the movie.
Scott: Anyway, so the next book in the queue.
Scott: I finished that the next book in the queue is Steppenwolf and I've read like 30 pages on the train home today.
Scott: And then there are some interesting choice bits like, you know an interesting paragraph here.
Rym: there They were relevant to a discussion Scott and I just I just quoted them at Rym and then he was like, alright Long time listeners know that we eat that shit up anytime like that's why ghost in the shell innocence was such a great movie.
Rym: Cuz it's just two people Quoting at each other for almost the entire movie.
Rym: Yeah, I Love that sort of thing.
Rym: But you know you quoted at me and suddenly the realization that I had not actually read Steppenwolf.
Rym: In fact, I did not even know what it was about.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: I've only read One point.
Scott: one books by Hermann Hesse, which is Siddhartha and Steppenwolf is the point one, right?
Scott: I can't name a single other thing.
Scott: that he is written Demian.
Scott: Don't know what that is.
Rym: Actually Demian is Nominally either the basis for or heavily influenced utenna the anime.
Rym: You know that the whole if a chick cracks a shell that whole thing a Braxis That I've heard the word a Braxis.
Scott: Is that where that comes from?
Rym: It's a Gnostic thing.
Rym: Yeah, but that that whole speech if the chick does not break its egg shell it'll die without being born.
Rym: You know, we're the chick.
Rym: the world all that stuff is a paraphrase of something from Demian, which is a story of Adolescence, you know this.
Scott: this brings me.
Scott: this is a great bridge If we didn't have things of the day.
Scott: in between I could make a really great connection.
Rym: Well, let's do things of the day and then go back to that bridge before we burn it.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So then briefly things of the day, I'm sure many of you have seen this But in case you haven't go watch John Hodgman in his speech with Barack Obama and about Barack Obama and to Barack Obama Because
Scott: at the correspondence dinner
Rym: it is not only hilarious and well done and you know Just right on par with what I expect from John Hodgman who I love because he more so than anyone I've seen in recent memory is the master of the straight man.
Rym: delivery Someone actually I saw someone is difficult to tell when he is kidding.
Scott: I saw somebody ask him You know if he ever has trouble like laughing at his own stuff because he's so, you know Not laughing at his own stuff and he says he was talking about like.
Scott: there are a few things like he has trouble not laughing And he has like hold it in because you know to keep it up, but funniness aside it is very poignant and very Biting and very relevant and it is one of those things.
Rym: It is a barb that cannot prick the numb fingers.
Rym: You still have to read that book.
Scott: is that still the judging eye?
Rym: Yes, it's still the judging eye.
Rym: Yes, numb fingers will not be will not get this and we'll just find it funny but alright.
Scott: so my thing is they have go ahead.
Scott: so here is a It's just little photos of Train stations because train stations are some of the awesomest buildings in the world, especially United States.
Rym: train stations You mean like a Penn Station in New York City?
Scott: Yes, not around anymore.
Rym: Well, yeah Well, there is a Penn Station that doesn't mean anything.
Scott: You know, of course, that's the first one on the list, right?
Scott: and basically what it is is pictures of train stations that no longer exist and then immediately followed by a Picture of what's in the place where the train station used to exist, you know what?
Rym: you know what's really said.
Rym: the things that are where they used to be boil down to either an empty lot a windowless 1970s era brick building usually a post office of some kind.
Rym: Yeah, or a freeway.
Scott: Yep See what's very place.
Scott: good shit with bad shit.
Rym: Well, it's down great sad on a number of levels.
Scott: It's like we got all this failing infrastructure.
Scott: We can upgrade but when we had quality infrastructure we downgraded.
Rym: Well, it's sad on multiple levels.
Rym: because look in places like New York City You know, they demolished Penn Station and built another train station because they still needed a train station.
Rym: Yeah, but they bought it underground and it wasn't really that aside though But they replaced beautiful architecture with theoretically efficient architecture, even though it ended up not being efficient, but that's beside the point.
Rym: outside of like New York City.
Rym: Most of these examples are a train station replaced with nothing because there aren't trains anywhere else.
Rym: Yep, that was the saddest part like all those beautiful train stations down south and out west replaced with empty lot because there are no trains Yep, or no need.
Rym: like Rochester had an amazing train station.
Rym: It was replaced with.
Scott: it looked a lot like the Poughkeepsie train station, which hasn't been knocked down.
Rym: Yeah, because it's used by Metro North and Amtrak.
Rym: Yep, but I mean you've seen the Amtrak station in Rochester.
Rym: It's basically just a low like.
Scott: well see that's the thing.
Scott: I don't get right.
Scott: is that in Rochester?
Scott: Why do they knock that one down if they replaced it with an Amtrak station?
Scott: It's like you would rather have that dank ass like Amtrak station.
Scott: That might as well be a Greyhound stop lower maintenance as opposed to the fancy awesome station that you had already.
Rym: The saddest one is still for me the Grand Central Station in Michigan, Michigan.
Rym: So there though it is but if there's no way that there's no way that's gonna be kept in detour There's.
Rym: I am almost certain that it will not last.
Rym: yeah Less I I saw it once.
Rym: well now I've only actually seen it in big.
Scott: This is why I should be a rich person with enough money because I would make all my buildings as awesome as old train stations I would never make like the boring-ass buildings people make today.
Rym: Well, the thing is what I didn't realize.
Rym: Michigan Central Station was designed by the same people who made Grand Central in New York.
Scott: Well, there aren't too many train station designers really.
Scott: I mean there's not.
Rym: it's not like Grand Central and then they use like the same design principles in Michigan Because that used to be a very maintain the constellation theme.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: Yeah, that's that's key.
Rym: It said yeah.
Rym: All right, so resume your bridge.
Scott: What was my bridge right?
Scott: So recently, you know, we were talking about like a Braxis.
Scott: now I said I didn't know what that meant, right?
Scott: Well recently, I've sort of been getting on a kick of sort of whenever something comes up that I don't know what it is.
Scott: I've been taking double diligence in going to research it on the Internet's, you know, just like, you know learn about Whatever like.
Scott: because you know, someone mentions a famous person.
Scott: I don't know who it is.
Scott: I look it up now instead of just going out on who that is, you know I mean like some famous person.
Scott: I work at Broadway.
Scott: calm now some famous person came in the office.
Scott: I didn't know who it was, you know that people were making a hubbub and I was like, oh, but I looked them up.
Scott: That didn't really help me understand why they were famous.
Scott: But you know.
Scott: But anyway, so, you know some people in the office.
Scott: they were talking about some, you know reality shows something something's you know how they do and You know I sort of remembered this old show that was like is one of those shows Back in the day where you'd be watching the show you cared about.
Scott: It would be over then this other show would come on and then you would turn it off.
Scott: But you would always see the beginning of that show or maybe you'd see the end of it because he was on before the show That you actually wanted to watch.
Rym: Yep I would always see the end or beginning of Friends because they sandwich the shows I liked with friends when I was in high school.
Scott: So I'm like earlier this week, right?
Scott: I was you know, I remembered I like hey wasn't there that show like star search?
Scott: That was a talent show and I was like these new reality shows.
Scott: a lot of them are just like that show.
Scott: Are they just ripping that off?
Scott: Let me go find out about that show.
Scott: So I went to find out about that show and it was hosted by Ed McMahon.
Scott: so I went.
Scott: I'm like, oh, yeah There's all these guys named McMahon.
Scott: Let me sort all them out because I don't know which one is which.
Scott: and I found out you know Like Vince McMahon was the wrestling guy and Ed McMahon was the guy in the Johnny Carson show and star search, you know.
Scott: And then the next day Ed McMahon died and I was like, whoa Gotta call Randy Scott.
Rym: You'd better stop looking people up.
Rym: Don't go to your own Wikipedia page.
Scott: Fuck.
Scott: I know right good thing I don't have a Wikipedia page for Scott Rubin.
Scott: Now you could But yeah, that was uh, that was a little bit weird.
Scott: Obviously, it is not psychic or any way supernatural It is mere coincidence But well part of it is freaky regardless.
Rym: part of it in general is that every generation goes through the phase where?
Rym: Their heroes and the institutions in their lives disappear because the world changes.
Rym: I mean when you're young.
Rym: most of the people you look up to most of people you see in the media that sort of thing Are a lot older than you.
Rym: they're like the current successful generation.
Rym: They start dying.
Scott: if you're like a little kid like three years old, right?
Scott: Let's say you're watching.
Scott: I don't know The busy town right.
Scott: the girl with the pink hair is a lot old easy town lazy time.
Rym: No one's busy.
Scott: Oh, no, Richard scary is is busy town is there you go?
Scott: I don't know anyway, but if you're watching lazy town right that girl with the pink hair She's older than you.
Rym: if you're in preschool So, you know, but right when you hit your like late 20s early 30s is when all the institutions of your life start dying.
Rym: Yep, either physically dying or disappearing from the media landscape.
Rym: Mm-hmm, and both are.
Rym: it's kind of this.
Rym: I don't want to say coming of age, you know We were just talking about Stefan wolf and Herman s and all that But it's definitely a one of those rights that all Generations go through is your heroes all start dying and you reach the age where you realize that All my heroes are dying and then I'm going to die.
Scott: Well, it's sort of weird because it's almost like this is it's almost three parts, right?
Scott: The first part is you're born and you have all these sort of people that are already dead.
Scott: You know like Elvis.
Scott: Elvis was dead before I was born.
Scott: So, you know the it was sort of like Elvis.
Scott: then it's almost like he's not even a real person.
Scott: He's almost like, you know a mythical and legendary Type figure effectively no different than you know Gandalf or You know Luke Skywalker really, you know because he was never alive at the same time.
Scott: I was alive.
Scott: So it's just he's a legend.
Scott: and then you have the people who you know, like Michael Jackson who you know.
Scott: I was a fan of Michael Jackson when I was young.
Scott: and now that I'm old, you know He's dead and it's it's kind of weird.
Scott: and then there's the people who are like they come up You know after you and you're like you're like who the fuck are these people trying to be someone else's, you know famous person Stupid kids who they looking
Rym: at because I think that's another component of people grow old and you know to people who grew up in the 80s and the early 90s, you know, you look back and you remember Michael Jackson primarily as Possibly one of the greatest entertainers to have ever lived One of the biggest stars ever and you think thriller people not that much younger than you will look and think oh That's that crazy pedophile guy, right?
Scott: Yep If you you know, cuz when do they see thriller?
Scott: maybe on YouTube once?
Rym: Yeah But what do they see all the time?
Rym: the current fat Elvis in the media?
Scott: Yeah, isn't that?
Scott: there's a lot of parallels and weird connections, you know, I'm not getting all conspiracy not in this episode You know me But I mean look at it right.
Scott: first of all Michael Jackson for a time married Elvis Presley's daughter, right?
Scott: weird enough.
Scott: number two Michael Jackson and Elvis were both like the two kings of music in the United States Pretty much one and two, you know time for first
Rym: Kennedy had a secretary named Lincoln and right and had a secretary named
Scott: anyway, and they both died early relatively early early and they were supposed to and they both had sort of this dual career of the Early part where they were awesome in the later part where they were less awesome.
Scott: You know, there's always young Elvis and fat Elvis and there's young Michael Jackson Who is the king of pop and there's old Michael Jackson?
Scott: It was a scary pedophile and it's like wow Alleged yes, the estate can still sue that's true alleged pedophile But even so it's.
Scott: you know, those parallels are very weird and you wonder if there is you know Something behind that like if there is a third king of music will that person also follow a similar pattern?
Rym: Well, I think it's tricky that it's very.
Rym: it's almost impossible for someone who has a high level of output to maintain a High level of consistently good output for the entirety of their life.
Rym: people live 60 70 80 90 years.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: I realized just the other day.
Rym: What'd you realize?
Scott: Well, Tezuka probably had the highest quantity of output right above just about any crater I can think of almost right.
Scott: But he had some duds.
Scott: We know this Cleopatra queen of sex, you know ambassador magma All right, so Tezuka is not perfect.
Scott: Hayao Miyazaki has not had the prolific miss of Tezuka.
Scott: He has never done anything bad Ever.
Scott: he's perfect.
Rym: You know, there's this tiny conspiracy not chance, right?
Rym: That he has made like five other movies and he shows him to the rest of the studio.
Rym: They knock him out they burn them and they pretend.
Scott: I discussed I discussed this with Daryl Surratt and other people and we have decided that there are two possibilities.
Scott: number one Miyazaki truly is perfect.
Scott: number two He actually knows.
Scott: he can tell what's good and what's bad after he makes it.
Scott: and there's a secret trove of all the unreleased not so good Miyazaki's that we need to go.
Rym: number three.
Rym: He is also going a guy and that is how he releases everything else.
Scott: No, but I mean, you know Miyazaki's an old dude, he'll be you know dead in 30 years or less probably most likely.
Rym: I really feel like he is destined to die in the midst of his latest work.
Scott: Oh, probably he's keen.
Scott: Oh, he's the.
Scott: he's one of those guys.
Scott: He's like.
Scott: he's like Brett Favre.
Scott: I'm retiring.
Scott: Just kidding.
Scott: Just kidding I'm gonna play another season.
Scott: That's Miyazaki right there.
Rym: so Yeah, so Farrah Fawcett and Michael Jackson and Ava Gota died.
Scott: not Ava Gota Ed McMahon Does anyone?
Rym: even the Ava Gota joke is old enough to where I know this.
Scott: I know the Ava Gota is a famous guy and I know that there's a joke about him being dead and he's not dead You don't know.
Rym: famous for a famous for not being dead.
Scott: That's it.
Rym: He was famous for something.
Rym: It was the 70s I don't know.
Rym: All right, maybe even the late 60s.
Rym: All I know is that someone reported that he was dead.
Rym: They basically they had some news story and you know His career faded at this point and some guy on TV some talk show said something to the effect of bla bla bla bla the late Ava Gota.
Scott: Were they joking?
Rym: They just they thought he was dead.
Rym: Yeah, he wasn't perfectly fine.
Scott: But hey, I'm zombie.
Scott: Ava Gota.
Rym: based on the image based on the comments on FARC I don't think anyone who posted a picture of Ava Gota Even knows that much.
Rym: I think they just know to post a picture of Ava Gota every time someone dies Really?
Rym: I don't think they know in any capacity and I'm not kidding All right putting that on a list after show Wikipedia Ava Gota.
Rym: All right All right, luckily at least I knew who Farrah Fawcett and Michael Jackson were.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know.
Scott: It's always strange when a famous person dies because it's you know, you have that sort of situation.
Scott: I mean, I've sort of seen a microcosm of this situation with our fans and that you know and also being a fan of other internet peoples in that you Consume.
Scott: so, you know you you consume someone's works or you know You listen to them or you see them a great deal and thus you sort of feel like you know them.
Scott: You don't really know them.
Scott: You know, they're this show of them, you know, this this Of them.
Rym: even though it's one-way communication for the most part you still you generate this Feeling like you know the person.
Rym: I mean, I'll admit I've done that I've listened to enough of the penny arcade podcast that I feel like I'm in the room hanging out with them.
Rym: But they don't know who I am.
Scott: They don't know who you are at all.
Scott: Maybe twice for ten seconds each if you say saw you on the street.
Rym: Everyone who runs PAX knows us, but they don't.
Scott: yeah, but anyway, they don't let on that they do.
Scott: Maybe that maybe they got this elaborate elaborate scheme.
Scott: It's conspiracy theory night here.
Rym: Well, one thing I can say is that they like D&D for all the wrong reasons.
Scott: That's for sure.
Scott: question about it.
Scott: Yeah, but it's like someone like a famous person dies.
Scott: It's so weird.
Scott: It's like I don't know this person but I care.
Scott: But really I don't know them at all.
Scott: Why do I care?
Scott: And it's it's sort of I don't know.
Scott: at least that's what I feel.
Scott: It's like it's sort of strange.
Scott: It's like I shouldn't care but I should and there's plenty of people dying who aren't famous.
Scott: that I don't know and I probably should Care more about them because they're probably actually more important in the actual scheme of the world.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: it's sort of fucked up.
Rym: one thing I do wonder though is how because I feel like the internet and the democratization of Publishing is gonna change this as time goes on because the internet is a weird situation and that Anything like something large enough like penny arcade you would find out.
Rym: but for smaller things like a medium-sized webcomic Or like gig nights, you know that sort of thing if something happens and the person making that content dies Very it's very likely that you might never find out what happened.
Rym: It just stops updating the website goes away and The fans.
Scott: I don't know about that because if you look at what's been happening on the internet's right even like people who are just members of Communities, you know like so they're on some forum and that's their internet presence.
Scott: Is there a member of this forum?
Scott: and they post kind of often?
Scott: When they die people find out and call and everything is.
Rym: the thing is though it's this it's more diffuse in that There's no way to find out directly usually but then indirect sources will come out, but there will never be news coverage.
Rym: It's just word-of-mouth mmm, and That sort of thing also just in terms of you know, how rapidly the news comes out.
Rym: I remember way back when I was hanging out in the computer club in sixth or seventh grade in my middle school.
Rym: You know, I didn't have a computer at home yet.
Rym: I was not a good computer.
Rym: So I'm hanging out there playing scorch and the guy who ran the computer lab was this kind of techie guy.
Rym: he read FARC all the time and that sort of thing and Well the FARC equivalents of that time at least yeah, and he just kind of pipes up and says Wow, John Candy just died and There wasn't a news story about that for another day.
Rym: Wow Or when Princess Diana died in that car accident you told the story Yeah, but my parents did not believe me.
Rym: They thought I was making stuff up because how could I know how could I have possibly known that?
Scott: well times are definitely changing?
Scott: because I was on the train home and People were saying up my Jackson's head is that on the train.
Scott: so people on the train They all knew what the score was on their cell phones or whatever.
Rym: So because it's no longer just the people who go to places like FARC find out now, it's you know Twitter.
Scott: Yeah, I mean basically I saw on Twitter that it was like, you know heart attack something coma something dead.
Scott: No, not dead.
Scott: Yes dead not dead.
Scott: And then by the time I got home It was like, you know on the radio they were like dead dead.
Scott: So that was that.
Rym: Yep It was interesting how it was one of those things that came out of nowhere as opposed to the kind of expected celebrity death.
Rym: Mmm, I mean that it was not what I expected at all.
Rym: Farrah Fawcett.
Rym: Everyone knew was kind of she wasn't doing well.
Scott: Yeah, there's another weird thing right?
Scott: It's like people have been talking about, you know, okay, so Michael Jackson died.
Scott: Well, sorry for Farrah Fawcett.
Scott: No one's gonna pay attention to her now and it really shows you that Really the attention economy is becoming more and more important.
Scott: It's like didn't?
Rym: didn't?
Rym: John Henson and Jim Henson?
Rym: Jim Henson a god I don't know who.
Rym: John Henson and Sammy Davis jr.
Rym: Die in the same day.
Scott: Someone said that I don't know if it's true.
Scott: I had to look it up.
Rym: Multiple people said that it's been said a bunch today.
Rym: I saw it on FARC I saw it on Wikipedia.
Rym: I saw it in our forums.
Rym: All right, I can't verify the veracity of that at all.
Scott: But yeah, you know what?
Rym: I'll verify.
Scott: right now It's like look something happens right and there's a certain amount of you know interest and talk discussion about it, right?
Scott: But if something else happens at the same time Right and thought and if that means that the other thing is gonna get less discussion or it's gonna be less Spread or less paid attention to I mean that means that we sort of you know our new limited resource in the world of today the Internet's world is attention.
Scott: and You know, I mean people sort of knew this and people have been talking about you know the the attention economy and these sorts of things.
Scott: but really it's I think it's gonna be a lot bigger deal than people really really expect at all.
Scott: and You know how much attention people give to various things is really what's gonna make a difference in the long run.
Rym: Well, I mean if you go fully out, you know the maximum fully extended scenario.
Rym: Eventually humanity if it doesn't get wiped out We'll have basically infinite energy resources and that sort of.
Rym: you know Diamond Age stuff.
Rym: if all physical desires can be provided trivially the only commodity left on earth is fame Mmm, I guess.
Scott: But even then, you know, even that could dissolve.
Rym: Well, it could if we had changed some sort of super sentience to the point where we're omnisciently aware of all Communication at all times.
Scott: and well Fame is a product of our culture of you know, people being social with each other.
Scott: and if we could have some sort of You know post social society, it would be all fucked up.
Scott: Then, you know, there would be no fame.
Rym: Well, I fame or immortality or that sort of desire is definitely something that is deeply ingrained in humanity Definitely a biological thing, you know.
Scott: right next to you know, just the desire to have friends.
Scott: But you know, well Maslow's pyramid.
Scott: Yeah, but you know many other biological things You know are being you know in conflict with our society and you know Eventually, all of them will be or you know, just a matter of time All right.
Rym: Yep, so That can be summed up as in the long run things will change everything will change It's no matter what.
Scott: Yeah, no, but something, you know specific about the Michael Jackson death.
Scott: that's sort of weird is that you know You've got this huge Variety of comments about it because Michael Jackson was sort of you know, these multiple people I mean Elvis, you know, I said there was young Elvis and fat Elvis, but you know people liked old fat Elvis, too.
Scott: He wasn't a bad guy, you know, even though he liked to eat a lot and such.
Rym: Well Park was this mix of sadness praise Gallows humor and too soon humor.
Scott: Yeah, and Well, yeah too soon is I think there.
Scott: I don't think there's a too soon anymore.
Scott: Everything's that FDR's everything from now on from here to eternity.
Scott: Everything is immediate.
Scott: There's no too soon anymore, but the You know Michael Jackson, he was like these multiple people, right?
Scott: It was.
Scott: it was you know He was a kid who a performer who everyone sort of loved even though he had some troubles in those days in the family and such He was you know, the king of pop.
Scott: and then he was a alleged You know sort of scary freaky dude who people really didn't like and you know didn't really entertain nearly at all.
Scott: and You know that most recently he was the not so good and not so well-loved Person.
Scott: so, you know when people think of that person being dead, you know, some of them are kind of like oh well You know, maybe you could say good.
Scott: maybe if you could say good about you know Someone, you know, if he really was a nasty pedophile as was alleged then you you know, some people might Think that that was a good thing.
Scott: That's such a person was no longer around.
Scott: but you know you think about the king of pop died.
Scott: You know if he had died in like the 80s It would have been like the worst thing in the entire universe.
Scott: It would be like no one would have said anything bad whatsoever.
Scott: Everyone would have been like, oh my god is the worst thing ever.
Scott: So you think about that person dying?
Rym: It's like ah, but in a way well, that would have been more like John Lennon's death.
Scott: Yeah, but in a way Did not that person die, you know sort of in the 90s.
Scott: Well, you can think about it that way.
Rym: that's that's the real crux of this that celebrities on any level from you know The you know D list celebrities like us all the way up to real celebrities.
Scott: I think we're on the cue list.
Rym: We're at least F at this point.
Scott: I don't know about that.
Rym: We're still a couple of steps under I think the F list or the big podcast not the little ones, but there's the Persona of the celebrity.
Rym: that is in and of itself and it's a real entity.
Rym: It's out there.
Rym: Yeah, well, that's.
Scott: that's why you can be like an Elvis fan Even though he died before you were born because his persona is alive.
Rym: But it if he isn't but like in perfect blue or like in super dimensional space fortress macross.
Rym: Oh shit Yeah The media persona is as real as a real person.
Rym: for the majority of people it effectively is a real person But yet it's not a real person that it can have a life completely independent of the person who created it.
Rym: Mmm, and we're going to see a much more interesting dichotomy there when you know, the Hatsune Miku's start becoming Good enough to where they are pop culture mainstream.
Scott: How'd you make who came out with the new album and It's like on the charts.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well think about that.
Rym: We're going to get to the point to where there are celebrities who cannot die.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: what will that do?
Scott: Well, we also right.
Rym: I think that that moment when we get to the point to where Institutions and celebrities do not die.
Rym: we are going to have a fundamental subtle but profound shift in society because a Right of passage that we have had from the dawn of civilization of your heroes dying will disappear and you will be able to if you were a fan of Michael Jackson imagine if you could Continually listen to Michael Jackson making the pop and lock music and everything that you loved for your entire life.
Rym: It's very easy for people to get stuck in ruts then.
Rym: Mmm.
Rym: I think the deaths of celebrities either spiritually philosophically physically it doesn't matter how but the the changing of that persona the loss of one thing and the Forcibly you have to forcibly move on to some other thing.
Rym: I think losing that is gonna change society.
Scott: Also think about this right.
Scott: we talked about how like on the internet like you're not actually on the internet your biology You know biological entities is in the real world.
Rym: Well, the internet is just the surrogate.
Rym: so it's not physical, right?
Scott: But there's like, you know, there's this data this set of data the set of information that is you it's it's you know.
Scott: That data combined is your identity in a way, right?
Scott: So even if you die, that's all still there now if you think about this, right?
Scott: Compared to say, you know, John Lennon who you know had a great deal of content produced of him and about him in his day compared to other people of his day.
Scott: Even so there is probably a greater quantity of data That is me on the internet than there is, you know unique stuff.
Scott: That is John Lennon.
Scott: Yeah, I mean sure there's more pages about him But in terms of just you know, he total information that is him, you know, like videos of him.
Scott: So there's only so much so here.
Rym: to consider this with the whole virtual performers thing and the media kind of I'm trying to come up with a new word other than just avatar or you know Surrogate.
Rym: have you read I doru?
Rym: you don't know you should read it.
Rym: It talks about.
Scott: I have a feeling that book is very relevant to this guy.
Rym: But that extent information of you the performer and and by performer, I mean just the things you did on the internet.
Rym: Mm-hmm The technology will exist to take that and Emulate your persona as it was on the internet and basically allow you to live forever on the internet without any.
Scott: Yeah, I mean it's it's a second If you want.
Rym: it is straight up a second-order simulacrum ghost in the shell.
Rym: It is a it is a self replicating Pointer.
Scott: Yes If you wanted to make me right?
Scott: Well, you probably couldn't make me.
Rym: I would make a bot that post anger into a farm.
Scott: If you wanted to make me right you probably couldn't.
Scott: but if you wanted to make me the host of GeekNights right, you could take every GeekNights episode as sort of your data for the machine to learn from and With that data you could you know get a program that would learn it to be Scott the host of GeekNights and that that is a very very real and probably could even be done in a very near future Technological possibility.
Rym: we're going to live in a world to where media personas Independent of the people that created them can outlive the people who created them and live forever.
Rym: hmm That is going to destroy things.
Rym: I don't know what that's gonna do.
Scott: I really do you think that you know, this sort of goes back into like, you know the fact that you know People are you know, not so caring about the celebrity deaths.
Scott: Do you think that might be because you know, there's just so much You know material left over by the celebrities that it's like they're not really gone?
Scott: You know, I mean like, you know, you'd be more upset.
Rym: there isn't new material being created.
Rym: I mean there aren't more thrillers exactly, but we will live in a world where there will be more thrillers forever Mm-hmm to where it won't even take effort.
Rym: It will just happen.
Scott: So does that contribute to the people caring less?
Scott: I mean, you know, it seems you know, like back in the day You know a lot more people.
Rym: or will the rumbling of society and just the information we create on the internet in the course of our lives and the course of striving for Consuming and creating media as a whole converge into the perfect Idol the perfect celebrity that is the aspirations of every human on earth simultaneously?
Rym: That's a problem which is you know, again super dimensional space fortress macross Not really, but similar.
Rym: I think it leads to the same end.
Scott: Plus it's completely different Yet also the same.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know.
Rym: doo doo doo doo Wrap this up.
Scott: Yeah, it's warm today.
Scott: It is real warm and it's gonna rain again tomorrow.
Rym: It's gonna rain.
Rym: Yeah, ollie Williams is gonna rain But can we ever find a Braxis if we can't break out of these shells that are the celebrity personas Wikipedia right after the.
Scott: we hang this up and I'm gonna check out a Braxis Struggles and I'm also gonna check out it struggles out of its egg.
Rym: The egg is the world.
Rym: who so ever wants to be born must destroy a world.
Rym: We're done.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our crapper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback Via audio.
Scott: just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: this means you can do whatever you want with it.
Scott: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.