Scott:
Rym: Hey, it's Monday, July 13th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight we were going to talk about full disclosure black hat white hat ass hat but Kind of ramble.
Scott: let's do this.
Rym: So I come home from work today, and there is what I can only people.
Rym: There is what I can only describe as a bomb that has been delivered to our house.
Rym: There's this shady looking is not a big deal like ripped off like just really crappy looking package That's half opened.
Rym: It's addressed to Scott.
Rym: It was mailed from Beacon of like a while ago, and it has no return address.
Scott: I mailed a book to somebody because they sold the book on Amazon and somehow the book showed up on My front porch.
Rym: yeah, so as a result you know shady looking package ripped open no return address mailed from B.
Scott: I have to go check my Amazon's after the show to see if this person like returned it or why?
Rym: That whatever mailing label you put on it fell off and the post office got it.
Rym: They're like.
Rym: well, there's only one address here.
Rym: We'll mail it to Scott Reuben and oh he put plenty of postage on it.
Scott: I put the.
Scott: the address was clearly.
Scott: it was on a piece of paper that was heavily taped to the front.
Scott: So I do not know what the hell happened to it.
Scott: But I will go and correct this situation Emailing the purchaser and such-and-such, but much more importantly I come out of work for lunch.
Rym: I'm kind of in a hurry, and it was like tourist day like more so than any other day.
Rym: I walk on a 42nd Street, and I just can't walk.
Rym: They're just slow people blocking every sidewalk in every direction.
Rym: It took me like 10 minutes to walk to the Chipotle But on my way, there's a inside of this crowd.
Rym: There's another crowd this long line of people lined up somewhere.
Rym: It was like down the street And I'm like all right.
Rym: what's going on here, so I walk up to the front of the line.
Rym: I see that the line terminates at that shady looking KFC slash Dunkin Donuts on 42nd Street by Grand Central.
Rym: But then I look and I realize that it's no longer Dunkin Donuts.
Rym: it is now Shady looking KFC and a shady looking Tim Hortons.
Scott: really, so that's where it is.
Rym: That's where the Tim Hortons is.
Scott: they got rid of the bad place.
Rym: well No, it's in a great place if you get rid of that KFC.
Scott: I didn't know the Dunkin Donuts and Tim Hortons and KFC were all the same company.
Rym: I don't think Tim Hortons is I think the Dunkin Donuts.
Scott: Do you think that the guy who just owns that storefront like has bought two franchises and put him in the same place?
Rym: I think Dunkin Donuts.
Rym: they realized that that Dunkin Donuts was not making him money.
Rym: I mean that's the one where the those you know the people were complaining about their 80 cent coffee.
Scott: Well he definitely made his money back with his uh Switching to Tim Hortons franchise.
Scott: The thing is don't?
Scott: usually franchises make you have agreements like you can't have like a McDonald's.
Scott: If I buy a McDonald's franchise and a Burger King franchise They don't let me put them in the same building.
Rym: it depends everyone's different.
Scott: I mean subway basically doesn't give a shit about anything.
Scott: subway is the easiest franchise in the universe exactly which is why they're everywhere.
Rym: That's also why most subways you get into are super shady.
Scott: Yeah, like.
Scott: basically you like if you wanted to open up.
Scott: I don't know a cold stone right.
Scott: they don't say yes That easily you got to.
Scott: you know be pretty cool bad, and you know slick or else They'll just be like no We're not gonna let you.
Scott: but if you want to open up a subway all you do is say yeah Thinking about you got one here.
Scott: you go open anywhere you want.
Rym: the best part is of all those subways are so Shady's the word today.
Rym: because like a lot of my co-workers will just like go to subway real quick and the people know they'll like Cover up the $5 footlong sign and try to get away with not following the promotion that they have to follow.
Rym: Really, I've never seen that or they'll just charge people full price unless they complain.
Rym: oh Yeah, I basically have given up subway forever.
Scott: I mean I'll go to subway.
Scott: You know it sits on the lid.
Scott: I rarely eat at any sort of emergency food.
Rym: There's the list of.
Rym: you know it's an acceptable emergency food.
Rym: It's like the bottom of that list is pretty much like I'll go to Arby's I'll go to Subway I'll go to Taco Bell.
Scott: I won't go to Taco Bell ever.
Rym: I would go to Taco Bell before I go to McDonald's or Burger King.
Scott: I would go to McDonald's or Burger King because at least they before Taco Bell because at least while I would you know Those three are way at the bottom of the list way at the bottom the bottom Taco Bell is still lower than McDonald's or Burger King because McDonald's and Burger King especially.
Scott: McDonald's has Some menu items that are you know acceptable?
Rym: What does Taco Bell not have?
Rym: they're like high school cafeteria tacos.
Rym: They're not that bad.
Scott: They're pretty bad.
Scott: at McDonald's I can get like you know A cookie that's not dinner a chemical milkshake.
Rym: That's not dinner.
Scott: Oh a dinner.
Rym: Yeah food.
Rym: This is the situation of cinecon.
Rym: We're in the middle of nowhere, and there's no food.
Scott: a dinner from McDonald's.
Scott: Yeah, I get a chicken sandwich at McDonald's.
Scott: right you can't be chicken something something.
Rym: Yeah It's not as good as the Arby's one.
Scott: I mean.
Scott: It's just mechanically separated chicken McNugget whatnot?
Rym: yeah Alright, so McDonald's or Burger King I?
Scott: Take McDonald's slightly over Burger King because King's at the bottom.
Rym: for me the only thing Burger King is like Papa eyes at a rest stop.
Scott: Well, you know there's like Chick-fil-a is way down.
Rym: Well Chick-fil-a is in a different category.
Rym: I won't eat.
Scott: Roy Rogers is way down there Chick-fil-a.
Rym: I'm against both for food reasons and for moral reason.
Scott: White Castle is pretty much the bottom.
Rym: White Castle is awesome castles in a separate category.
Scott: Well, I guess it's pretty much the most disgusting worst food.
Scott: You could possibly I will seek out White Castle.
Scott: I know this.
Scott: that's why I called it out.
Scott: Yeah to show how disgusting you are right.
Scott: It's no hot now getting your chicken sticks chicken rings at the White Castle.
Rym: I don't need the chicken rings.
Rym: Nothing on the White Castle menu other than the standard White Castle burger You think I'm gonna eat.
Rym: look like fried oysters that they have.
Scott: yeah, that's what White Castle is about it.
Rym: No, that's not what it's about.
Rym: you go there and order a sack of like a hundred.
Scott: You know what I heard White Castle is 88 years old and they have a special sale going on right now.
Scott: 88 cents.
Rym: Oh, yeah, they do that periodically.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is next year.
Scott: It'll be 89 cents.
Scott: I don't think it's gonna keep up with inflation though.
Scott: So I think when they're like a hundred and the burgers are a dollar they'll probably worth like five dollars.
Rym: See the thing is the way they get away with that is that people go there like oh, yeah G burger and then they realize how awesome White Castle is.
Scott: No, it's it's really not awesome at all.
Rym: When was the last time you ate a White Castle burger?
Scott: when you and me went to White Castle?
Rym: You actually ate.
Rym: I recall you not wanting to eat and just sitting there.
Scott: Oh, I mean, I yeah I went there, but I didn't.
Scott: I didn't eat.
Rym: when was the last time you ate one?
Rym: You don't know what they taste like.
Scott: they're all right back in Jersey Jersey way back.
Scott: that's where.
Scott: that's where the only place that real White Castles are is Jersey.
Scott: No, I don't let them anywhere else because they're so disgusting Way.
Scott: they let you make a subway anywhere.
Scott: cuz at least it's you know, it's just food on a roll.
Scott: but as a kid I mean that's only legal in like certain places.
Rym: as a kid in Stirling Heights White Castle Burger King and Taco Bell were banned from the city limits.
Rym: So at every corner like at the edge every road that went out of the city right there It was a Burger King a White Castle and a Taco Bell.
Scott: KFC is also way down.
Rym: It was funny.
Rym: They banned Taco Bell and White Castle I believe for the grade of meat.
Rym: they banned Burger King because that had ordinance against smells and apparently Burger King could not Possibly conform to that ordinance.
Rym: Wow Yeah.
Rym: So so there's a Tim Hortons there and I can get Tim bits in the morning.
Scott: I guess I'll just buy a doughnut from a cart if I really want one.
Scott: Yeah, I used to like pass by like maybe one cart going to work.
Scott: now I passed by like eight carts.
Scott: think there's like so many.
Rym: if you're gonna get the cart doughnut You got to get the coffee stick.
Rym: It's pretty much the best doughnut in there.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know.
Rym: I sort of like the regular old glaze, but the coffee stick is the closest thing to a real doughnut I've seen.
Scott: also those cards have actually pretty good bagels and they're only 75 cents.
Scott: Yeah, like you go to like, you know, like they're hot and crusty.
Rym: It's like a dollar a dollar and it's not dollar Eighty it's a dollar eighty if you get cream cheese.
Scott: I don't get a cream cheese.
Rym: What kind of bagel you eat?
Scott: It's too much money with the cream cheese.
Rym: I Can't be a big spender.
Rym: Not everyone has all this money laying around.
Scott: I know right.
Scott: I get a cream cheese at home where I could buy some tempe.
Scott: But the cream plus they don't give you this the whipped cream cheese.
Scott: They give you that solid cream cheese is no good.
Rym: Problem is they put like a pound of it on my bag.
Scott: That's also a problem.
Rym: I like scrape some off before I eat it.
Scott: All right, so you're paying for all that extra cream.
Scott: Actually, you know what those those really generic metro cafes.
Scott: They're actually a pretty good place to go to get a bagel because a you don't really have to wait in line because no one Else is getting a bagel.
Scott: there be the bagels not too bad and see like they toast it and there's no line.
Scott: So other places like it's hard to get it toasted, you know, well, you know, I get the city early enough.
Rym: There's never a line for anything.
Rym: No, except the goddamn Starbucks.
Rym: No 7 a.m.
Rym: There's like 10 people.
Scott: That's the only place it's gonna be a lineup that early.
Rym: All right tech news is some tech news.
Scott: What was my tech news?
Scott: Oh, yes.
Scott: I don't believe we talked about this on the show earlier But the creators of gizmodo and who moved on to also crate and gadget which are pretty much the same thing as gizmodo Have moved on yet again and they opened up GDGT Which is not like gizmodo or in gadget at all really other than it is, you know, that's gadget website.
Rym: I don't know what your opinion is, but I'm pretty much I went from.
Rym: this is awesome - this is crap in about a day.
Scott: Yeah, I pretty much read from.
Scott: this is awesome - this is crap - this is okay And it's got to improve a lot.
Scott: Basically, the site is sort of what I hoped it would be right and that you have this situation Where you know a gadget comes out, let's say it's I don't know a particular model of digital camera, right?
Scott: And you want to discuss this particular model of digital camera with other people who have that particular model.
Scott: And that's not so easy on the Internet.
Scott: So, I mean I had a. my previous cell phone was like a LG VX 8600, right?
Scott: And I found some weird forum on the internet.
Scott: That was one at some crazy V bulletin thing and there was one category in that forum that had a threads for my phone as I get to join it and it's you know, it's Like that one phone happened to have this nook and cranny on the internet.
Scott: you know, like the TiVo used to have these TiVo forums that all these TiVo people would go to like these AVS forums and who knows what.
Scott: and You know, it really was not a good situation for people who wanted to like, you know, sort of connect in a community around gadgets either specific or general.
Scott: and I remember
Rym: very very very much way back when we had that Apex or whatever DVD player Yep, and I had to troll around and there the forums about that device to figure out how to hack it to be region-free
Scott: Yep, and also, you know even to talk about general tech stuff, right?
Scott: I mean, you know slash dot and you know dig and those sorts of places that have tech news Right that also have I guess discussion, right?
Scott: They don't really cover the tech news the way they engage it and gizmodo do and while engaging gizmodo have comments.
Scott: Those comments are these flat comments.
Scott: There are thousands of them within like a minute and you can't really have a discussion or connect with anyone.
Scott: All you can do is post a comment that no one's ever gonna see.
Scott: so GDGT sort of also You know, they sort of bring in the RSS from gizmodo and engage it in other places and allow, you know Discussions actual discussions on the tech topics and things, you know.
Scott: So it's sort of good in this way.
Scott: And also there's a gadget database that you know They sort of started it up, but people you can go in and contribute, you know And add in new gadgets that aren't in there and I've added a few and you know.
Scott: Then you can also search gadgets based on specs Like you can say.
Scott: show me all the 40 inch plasmas that have at least this much like refresh rate and stuff like that Which is pretty cool.
Scott: The things that bother me about the site is you know First of all any entries into the database need to be approved by some people who work for them Which is Pretty problematic.
Scott: They should have just made it an open wiki like Wikipedia and let people go.
Rym: No Didn't you try to add your happy hacking keyboard and you couldn't.
Scott: I tried to add the happy hacking keyboard because I want to discuss It with other happy having keyboard people.
Scott: I first I couldn't add it because the company that makes it was not already added in the system.
Scott: So I had to add PFU systems.
Scott: They denied my entry for PFU systems because they didn't realize that they made the happy hacking keyboard.
Scott: They were like consumer electronics manufacturers only and PFU systems primarily makes non consumer electronics the happy hacking keyboard.
Scott: It's pretty much the only consumer product they make.
Scott: so I had to go in and they have a separate.
Scott: one thing They did that was smart is they have a separate forum for talking about GDGT, you know and I really like that.
Scott: there is you know stack overflow gets that right.
Scott: also You need to separate the meta from the site itself.
Scott: putting them in together Really really hurts.
Rym: how long have people wanted that for slash job some sort of place to argue about slash dot in independently of the articles?
Scott: exactly because if people talk about Slash on slash dot then people who come to slash that who don't care about slash dot itself But I actually care about the content are inundated with all this.
Scott: talk about mod points and shit and they're like, oh fuck days Right, like if you go to stack overflow, you're looking for the answer to your tech question.
Scott: You're not looking to talk about this site that you never even heard of because you just came to it through Google, right?
Scott: So set they have a separate forum on their site for talking about GDGT and I'm like Hey, I was denied and they fixed it.
Scott: so good for them And then I was able to enter my keyboard and they accepted that as well.
Scott: So they're they're good about it But it's still.
Scott: they should have made it a wiki.
Scott: all the data that people are entering should be Creative Commons wiki license Just like Wikipedia.
Scott: right Wikipedia compatible And you know the.
Scott: they could use a little bit more Cleanliness in some of the interface bits.
Scott: it's sometimes hard to figure out exactly what to click on and such like that.
Scott: and You know, it's.
Scott: you know, it's definitely got the right idea, but the execution is not yet perfect, but I'm still sort of hopeful because the people behind it are smart and also the.
Scott: You know, they're gonna iterate.
Scott: they're nowhere near done, right?
Scott: They got a lot of a lot of room to grow and you know, they've got to start.
Scott: I just wonder How long they can hold on to all these people they grabbed with their sort of initial go, you know It's like they started up.
Scott: a million people rush in.
Scott: how many people are still there?
Scott: I guarantee like less than you know, a very small percentage of the people are still Actively coming to the site all the time.
Rym: plus there's the problem of any thing like that on the internet where You'll probably just distill everyone down to the dig around Paul people.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: And well, I think another thing is that You look at a site like in gadget right and Even though these people are not in a gadget anymore.
Scott: You'll still read it once a day Maybe even twice a day because the updating with new news GDGT doesn't have that update thing going on.
Scott: You know, it's like the front page is just the only go when you need something And once you go, yeah, you only need something or you know, if you're if you're you know It's.
Scott: it's not something you're gonna go to all the time.
Scott: So it's sort of you have to really you know.
Scott: the only time you're gonna visit it a ton is if you're heavily invested in some gadget and the Community around that gadget builds up on GDGT.
Scott: However, if there is a gadget that warrants a community building up around it I think GDGT has sort of become the default place to form that community So that that's gonna help them and I think they just need to wait for more gadgets that are community worthy to to appear.
Scott: And the thing is though I sort of feel like when a gadget is too popular like say the iPhone Just GDGT has the iPhone section is just so crazy.
Scott: It's not even really, you know, maybe if you want to like find a how-to for hacking it or something like that be in there.
Scott: But for discussion, I think it's too intense still.
Rym: the thing is I think the majority of people for any act any device don't care about the discussion.
Rym: They literally just want these step-by-step back.
Scott: And I think that GDGT, you know in those discussions the facts will appear and that will be helpful to people's One interesting thing they did.
Scott: the last thing I'll say is that you can do reviews of gadgets and you can either a you find A gadget you can link to an existing review elsewhere on the net like CNET slash dot.
Scott: wherever your blog you can also Submit your own review, but your review has to be at least like I was like some number of words.
Scott: So like you can comment and discuss your your brains out But if you want to put a review up it has to be at least so long You know which implies that it's you know good.
Rym: So I think that was a thing that it says fuck you iPod followed by the letter a repeated 150 times.
Scott: Yeah, I somehow think that won't make it through but you know that was.
Scott: that was shows that they're thinking about that sort of thing.
Rym: I mean slash dot always had the lameness filter Yeah That's true Which more often than not seemed to stop legitimate posts that we're trying to post code than it did to stop spammers.
Scott: Yeah, but you know what you do.
Rym: But I remember way way back when I was in high school And I was really like that was when I was really into hacking and all that sort of stuff.
Rym: And I kind of the more I learned about computers the less I cared about that sort of thing.
Rym: I know right it's funny how that works.
Rym: and now the Security is a big deal and I work for one of those big iron companies.
Rym: yet again That sort of hacking is just no longer even useful or interesting or any.
Scott: well I think what it is is a lot of that hacking is You know it's only Pragmatic for people with more time than money.
Scott: and there's also the situation that it's kind of like it's also Pratt It's only pragmatic as a entertaining hobby if you have tons of money.
Rym: well No, it's kind of like the freaking days like the Golden Age of hacking the phone system where you know a technology appears.
Rym: in this case It's internet computing all that sort of stuff.
Rym: And they'll kind of be this early Wild West phase where the technology is being suddenly widely deployed But there are very few safeguards or controls and nothing's really tested or proven.
Rym: And that's when hackers can really do crazy awesome stuff.
Rym: But then it won't take long for the sophisticated Companies and the people who know what they're doing to come in patch everything, and then there's no more Wild West.
Rym: yeah It's a different kind of Wild West.
Rym: I mean it.
Rym: it used to be the Wild West of we're Omnipotent gods walking through a sea of ants and now it's the Wild West of everybody has a gun and nobody Has a way to start the real Wild West.
Scott: no But you know some stuff like say overclocking right is really good for people who don't have a lot of money But have a lot of time because you know they can get there.
Scott: you know really they can hack to sort of get more than they paid for.
Scott: and Certain stuff like say jailbreaking your iPhone is really great if you have a ton of money because if you break your iPhone You can just get another one, but for someone like us or we have more money than time But we don't have so much money that we can afford two iPhones.
Scott: right it's sort of like well We got enough money.
Scott: We can just buy a faster CPU instead overclocking, but I don't have so much money.
Scott: I can buy two iPhones.
Scott: You know I'm gonna take.
Rym: so I'm not really happy to take a completely different Tech here in that I think a big part of it is now.
Rym: I was talking about the golden age of hacking and all that.
Rym: Yeah, it's just like with science.
Rym: I mean back in the day you could have a Ben Franklin who kind of dabbles and everything and the bar of doing something cool Or interesting or novel or new were so low that It didn't take a lot.
Rym: you didn't need this gigantic body of prior knowledge To do some crazy things early on.
Rym: it took very little to do very much, but as things got more sophisticated I mean the level of skill and knowledge it takes to write a modern worm or a modern effective virus is So much that by the time you learn that much you've given up on your desire to own swords.
Rym: Yeah, I think that's the primary factor.
Scott: of course most you know people doing the worms are either a they're making so much bank Cuz they're the guy doing it or you're just some script kitty who just takes them from that guy and then uses exactly.
Rym: But that's a whole script.
Rym: kidding is a whole different thing from actually hacking.
Rym: Yeah, all right But I remember one of the hot topics back then was tempest and the whole EMI shielding and that Theoretical this.
Scott: this is like this funny joke RIT.
Rym: yeah, well everyone always went after it and tried to do it and well it was this really fear.
Scott: It was this theoretical thing that worked, but it was sort of like more trouble than it was worth right.
Scott: the idea Was that you know if someone has CRT monitor?
Scott: And you had like this really fancy equipment you could basically spy on see their screen Even if you weren't looking at their screen.
Scott: Well, it's basically.
Rym: it's close to fundamentally the idea that you can take the extent kind of radiation because you know there's electromagnetic radiation coming out of any electronic device yep and Theoretically that contains everything is being processed by your computer.
Rym: It's just obfuscated by the fact that there's a lot of electromagnetic radiation going around yep.
Rym: But because computers are synchronous and they have buses and they're very reliable timing it is Theoretically possible to identify a particular computer in that radiation and get information from it.
Rym: and like this is true It can be done.
Rym: There are lots of proof of concept.
Rym: It's been done, but but at that time Hackers in particular people like me were real into it and as a result I remember it was just a huge thing and people were trying to do it all the time.
Rym: There was a lot of software and hardware like that.
Scott: What's the practical?
Scott: Situation where that hack is actually a gonna work and B. There isn't a better hack that would work in the same situation.
Scott: that is less stupid.
Rym: I think there definitely are.
Rym: just a matter of.
Rym: it was a lot more difficult to do than a lot of people thought but The disparity between how difficult it was and how difficult people thought it was led to a really interesting situation where people were building RFI or EMI shielded computers.
Rym: people were building Faraday cages around them.
Scott: I didn't say I didn't see much of that.
Rym: There was a lot of that on the internet.
Scott: I think there's a lot of reports of that on the internet.
Rym: I saw a lot of pictures and designs for it and PGP.
Rym: the early versions back in the day had a mode.
Rym: It was called temp is secure and what it would do is when you viewed you decrypted a document It would show it on your screen in this very low contrast kind of shifting window.
Rym: That theoretically would be much more difficult to read in some sort of tempest attack that was built into PGP.
Scott: I don't remember that but I used your word for it.
Rym: I used it because I was a paranoid high school hacker nerd and tempest was totally remember that.
Scott: I don't remember hearing about the tempest Until we were at RIT.
Rym: So it was all really around back.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: People were people.
Rym: it was the theoretical thing I mean around that time.
Rym: There's also the idea that you could Theoretically if you could film What was going on on some really slow network equipment that had those LEDs that would light up when data was being sent.
Rym: You could recreate the data that was being sent because the LEDs were triggered by the pulses on the wire.
Scott: We need to know if the pulse is a one or a zero.
Rym: No, you don't know.
Rym: But and it actually did work.
Rym: But what most people failed to realize was that it worked on technology.
Rym: It was already obsolete and that that can't work with like.
Scott: well The other thing the other thing that's stupid about that right is like, okay Let's say that even if you could do it with modern networking equipment, right?
Scott: Well that assumes right that you can get into a situation where you're next to The networking equipment with a camera.
Rym: that's trivial.
Rym: Have you ever been to a modern colo data center?
Scott: They just let you walk right in.
Rym: Well, no you have your cage.
Rym: when you have a key You can only get into your cage and no one can get into your cage without your permission.
Rym: So in my cage, I just put a fucking camera That looks at your own stuff.
Rym: Look at someone else's stuff in another cage.
Rym: The cages are usually just like bars But that's so.
Scott: that's a very, you know narrow scenario.
Rym: It's not.
Rym: it's not as narrow as you'd think because for example Like some of the data centers that I have stuff in it like there's a giant like a huge important Google thing.
Rym: It's like right next to us and like one of our competitors is like right next to us like all that sort of stuff.
Rym: uh-huh, there are a lot of that's why data center security is such a big deal because there's a lot of Very important information right next to other very important information and people on both sides want that information.
Rym: Luckily the camera trick doesn't work on any modern infrastructure whatsoever.
Scott: Yeah, now the lights is pretty much tell you it's working.
Rym: It's not working but tempest was a huge deal among the 2,600 phone freaker hacker types because that stuff was yeah I guess let's define the 20s.
Scott: There must be a 2,600 article articles.
Rym: Not only was it really cool, but in kind of that sort of thing back then.
Rym: It was a lot easier to do partly because things were slower and things were less shielded used it a lot more power.
Rym: Your computer was just a gigantic antenna.
Rym: I mean look at a ps2 keyboard and how loud that is Electromagnetically compared to like USB keyboard.
Scott: I think the my headphones died, but that's alright.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Alright, but anyway The news here is that this whole thing Suddenly got rediscovered by the internet and we're gonna see a lot of people losing their shit over this again because there's well I thought there's a new.
Scott: someone just came up with a new one That was pretty much like the same thing.
Scott: only it looks at keyboards, right?
Rym: Well, there's a proof of concept at some conference where basically you can read what people are typing on ps2 keyboards and possibly other devices by Having Lasers or something right?
Rym: No, but I have an electrical outlet by having an outlet on the same ground as someone else's outlet.
Rym: Yeah, and there's a proof of concept and it looks like it works at about scenario Do you have physical access to the same outlets as someone else?
Rym: That's pretty trivial.
Rym: I'm in a skyscraper.
Rym: I'm on the same floor as some other company.
Scott: Yeah, still, you know, yeah, and they got a lot of computers over there.
Scott: How you gonna separate which ones are which?
Rym: well That's the part of it.
Rym: I mean, did you even read the article?
Rym: Do you know anything about this?
Rym: No, not at all It doesn't.
Scott: it doesn't sound that to me though.
Scott: Like it's a plausible hack.
Scott: That's useful.
Rym: What it is is it's actually pretty much equally plausible to a lot of the tempest stuff in that if you have sophisticated equipment You could probably engage in some very sophisticated attacks.
Rym: however, the real thing here is that the majority of people will never encounter this on either side and People are going to talk about this a lot more than is warranted probably.
Scott: I mean if you want to hack someone you could probably just get him with any old normal worm and it's it's gonna work.
Scott: It's not like a. you know, this is sort of like ridiculous kind of.
Rym: well, it's not ridiculous It's just interesting fun kind of hobby hacker stuff.
Rym: I mean if you're into ham radio, let's say or Electromagnetic design or anything like that.
Rym: This stuff is really cool.
Scott: It's cool Yes, but I'm saying is that if anyone actually takes this as a as a legitimate security consideration you're going overboard.
Rym: Well, it depends on what you're doing and who you think your enemies are and there are industries where that sort of thing.
Rym: You've got to take it into account.
Scott: I don't think anyone's gonna do this hack ever?
Rym: Well, the thing is it's pretty trivial to counter these sorts of attacks.
Rym: It's the same thing with PGP where there's a theoretical attack.
Rym: There are relatively innocuous ways to prevent said theoretical attack But the people who primarily use the theoretical Versions of the attack are the people who are least likely to be targeted by ultra super secret spy organizations.
Rym: However, I will point out that I could probably steal your password.
Scott: I'm not worried about it.
Scott: Maybe I should try to have a USB keyboard and LCD monitor.
Rym: I didn't.
Rym: actually I think it could be done on a USB keyboard.
Rym: I'm not sure it doesn't matter.
Rym: I think it's neat stuff though I mean you're.
Rym: I also have a UPS That barely works and probably just gonna pass through.
Scott: I bought the newer one.
Scott: Remember?
Scott: Oh, yeah you did.
Scott: I have the fancy one.
Scott: So what are you gonna do?
Rym: Just put a key logger on your USB in line.
Scott: You know what this actually?
Scott: I'm pretty sure UPS would just completely right Wouldn't it?
Rym: No, because remember UPS is usually passed through and it's the same ground.
Rym: Your UPS doesn't have some magic special ground anywhere.
Rym: It's not the good UPS like James would tell us about.
Rym: it's the crappy UPS Whatever.
Scott: Let's uh, let's just continue.
Rym: Plus I mean ground loops have been used to transfer information in the past.
Scott: That's why if you plug That's something I'd be more interested in right instead of like snooping on people and using this for evil Use this as some sort of way to surreptitiously communicate that.
Scott: I would be cool.
Rym: that already works.
Rym: It's trivial to do.
Rym: you can buy devices that you plug into all the outlets in your house and have a poor man's 10-based network.
Scott: Actually, I was reading that it was the Philippines that they were gonna do internet overpower lines like for like, you know ISP?
Rym: Oh, yeah, Scott.
Rym: They've been talking about that for 20 years.
Rym: That never happens.
Scott: Anyway, it sounds like someone's actually gonna do it.
Rym: I will not believe it until it is actually deployed.
Rym: I also agree with you But there's been a story every six months for almost the entirety of the time that I have owned a computer saying Internet over the high voltage power lines is coming tomorrow.
Scott: Well, I heard in the Philippines.
Scott: That's all I'm saying.
Rym: I heard in the Philippines.
Rym: That's right But I think I think everyone should read this article because really this stuff is pretty cool and you can do cool stuff.
Rym: And if you're a hobbyist hacker try try to do this sort of thing.
Rym: It's not that hard and from what I gather from this article For under a thousand dollars you can put together something that will be able to replicate this proof of concept.
Scott: Yeah, five thousand dollars.
Scott: I just buy nice HDTV or something.
Scott: Maybe another Mac mini that was newer and better.
Rym: Yeah, well if you want to just consume as opposed to create interesting and useless hacks Also pay a month of rent.
Rym: Good - I think you're getting old.
Rym: You've lost the hacker spirit I'm hacking.
Scott: the software is where you know shits easy.
Rym: Oh have you what would you written recently?
Scott: a lot of work?
Rym: Yeah, yeah, we're old But anyway things of the day.
Rym: so buddy have for me Scott.
Scott: So this is video here of these kids and they got a pool and they must be rich because it's a fancy pool in a Fancy looking house in a fancy looking neighborhood.
Scott: All right, and all they do is they video themselves Dunking, you know doing slam dunks on the pool basketball hoop, right?
Scott: So that's you know.
Scott: Okay The thing is a they're real good at it.
Scott: and B They come up with some really creative multiple person dunks on this little pool basketball hoop and they pull them off.
Scott: I'm pretty sure they tried a bunch of times and only actually edited the ones that they succeeded into the video.
Scott: but they're looking like they're having a lot of fun and This was totally the kind of shit we did when I was a kid all the time and so when I watched it I was like, ah my childhoods they have it.
Rym: Well, there's not fair.
Rym: There's definitely something about the the miss and it's just like that game.
Rym: I think we made a thing of the day a long time ago Where those people covered the table in soap and would spin the frisbee on the soap.
Rym: There's something about taking an arbitrary activity.
Rym: someone does something once and then you have a bunch of friends together and You decide to become the best people in the world at this thing you just made up and that's an entire afternoon.
Scott: No, it's you know, but it's like, you know Just sitting around just thinking of shit to do and coming up with something sort of funky like that.
Scott: I mean that was that was I know when I would go to like the town pool and that's.
Scott: the other thing is that you Know.
Scott: a lot of the stuff I did when I was a kid was pool related, you know I had a pool in the backyard went to the town pool pretty much any summer camp.
Scott: There was always pools.
Scott: go There's a lot of pools all over the place Except without the summer camp or the town pool.
Rym: Everyone just had pools.
Rym: Yeah No, but there was a lot of whose house we go to and we'd all hang out in their pool.
Scott: But yeah for as long as it for my whole life every summer up until when I went to RIT There was a lot of pool action.
Scott: So, you know This is like this is really close to home and it's totally epic and I wish I'm gonna get a pool so we can go Back to those days.
Rym: I definitely think it comes out of the same impulse that created the frisbee game.
Rym: It's just the you you take something and just you have nothing to do in the afternoon.
Rym: You turn it into your entire afternoon.
Rym: something dumb like things are totally enjoying it.
Rym: do like like you're gonna do something like that And not enjoy it.
Scott: Well, no, but like you can tell that they're they're rocking out.
Rym: Yeah, those frisbee people were rocking out.
Rym: It's good times.
Rym: Flash mobs come and go and they're good ones and bad ones.
Rym: But after the whole Michael Jackson thing, there were a lot of Michael Jackson flash mobs.
Rym: They were mostly pretty mediocre.
Scott: Well, at least, you know, none of them really stood out.
Rym: Well, they were mostly pretty mediocre, especially the one that tried to happen in New York But thanks.
Scott: I think it might have been the next day, but I never saw a video of it.
Scott: So it's like there was no video.
Rym: it clearly fizzled out.
Rym: But here I have learned that in Stockholm That is where people not have put together a goddamn flash.
Scott: Well, actually those MC hammer ones are pretty good, but they were commercially orchestrated.
Rym: Yes, they were.
Rym: that's why I didn't mention them.
Rym: Yeah, but this one does not appear to be commercially orchestrated and appears to be some of the more epic of the flash mobs I've ever seen.
Rym: because the the degree to which the tiny one person dancing Grows into hundreds of people without you even realizing it and the fact they melt out of the crowd like it's beautiful.
Scott: They got skills.
Scott: Definitely.
Rym: They practiced is the thing to behold and anyone who wants to do a flash mob You could learn from these people.
Scott: My guess is that they like must have like scheduled and like an attempted one out in a field where no one could see and Practiced it and then brought it somewhere else because that's what I do.
Scott: if I was doing a flash mob that had to be so Coordinated or something.
Scott: I would a if it was a dance or something along those lines I would send out a video teaching people to dance, right?
Scott: Everyone would watch it on YouTube and learn it on their own.
Scott: then I would schedule a flat like a drill, you know I'd be like, okay, we're gonna do one for fake out in this field right at 1 p.m On Saturday and we do it in the field until we got it Right, and then I'd be like, okay, and then I would send out the other.
Scott: the next message would be okay everyone for reals At the train station tomorrow and then there you go.
Scott: That's how to make it awesome.
Scott: Like they got.
Scott: well Yeah, you know much like an anime cosplay you practice you choreography it Yeah, but I think that I have a hard time believing that this was actually a hundred percent spontaneous Like this is.
Scott: they just said all right everyone at the train station and then pulled it off that awesomely without you know.
Rym: Well a flash.
Rym: my prior preparation is not necessarily I wouldn't say Necessitate a spontaneous.
Rym: Hey, we're gonna do this here and everyone just shows up.
Rym: They can also be extremely well coordinated because the the flash mob is either.
Scott: it is full But I just think that if you prepare that much in advance it removes some of the flash Aspect.
Rym: but how?
Rym: it's a flash?
Rym: in that you have a normal crowd of people doing normal things and suddenly a mob Appears out of nowhere.
Rym: it flashes.
Scott: Yeah, it's true.
Scott: But you know, but what it's alright, it's you know, it's not as Flash as the mob was not, you know, it was pretty much just like.
Scott: let's do it Because it was like I most.
Rym: most of what people call a flash mob is usually a well-coordinated You know set up event that then appears somewhere later.
Rym: Yeah, that's what almost all of them are.
Scott: So it is I just you know, I think it's a lot more impressive though if the mob is truly a hundred percent.
Rym: So yes, it's a lot more impressive if people do something with less practice and with less preparation.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah Alright, so what are we talking about tonight?
Rym: We've gone out a long time on this show.
Scott: That's good.
Scott: We probably need to because we I don't know how much direction we have for the main bit.
Scott: Anyway, so what we decided downstairs and we're gonna talk about like, you know black hat for his white hat.
Rym: I just wanted to talk about full disclosure because I'm pretty sure we've already talked about all the hats a long time ago on GeekNights.
Scott: I don't think we ever talked about the hats on GeekNights And I don't think I don't know how much there is to say about full disclosure As an IT professional.
Rym: there's a lot to say about it But it'll do if it's just gonna be me talking.
Rym: we can just skip it for now.
Scott: Well, we could start by talking about the full disclosure and then branch off to other hatters if necessary.
Rym: Well, the reason I thought about it There is not really wanted to talk about at least just full disclosure was the whole image check thing.
Rym: that happened not too long ago.
Rym: we're basically a vigilante group hacked image check and replaced all the images with their kind of poorly put together manifesto and their whole idea.
Rym: their whole Thing is that there should not be full disclosure and that full disclosure is just a ploy By the security people to scare people into buying their firewalls and their antivirus and that sort of thing.
Scott: That's what they hacked image check for.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: It's basically their manifesto is crap.
Rym: I'm not even gonna read it, but They clearly do not work in the IT industry in any real capacity.
Rym: But at the same time they pulled off a pretty clever hack and owned image check pretty thoroughly.
Rym: yeah, but as a professional I'm kind of 50/50 on full disclosure because really what it comes down to is that full disclosure Will cause lots of problems.
Rym: It's basically the equivalent of if you can't fix your government by voting burning down a building to fix it.
Scott: Yeah, it's like okay in fear.
Scott: Well, this is a theory versus pragmatism situation, right in theory, right?
Scott: If there's a security hole you it's probably better that people Know right because then they know how to protect themselves from it.
Scott: Right be?
Scott: it puts pressure on someone to fix it see the fix will come sooner etcetera, etcetera.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The thing is right.
Scott: Is that in reality?
Scott: if you look at the actual numbers?
Scott: it's that if a Vulnerability is not published it pretty much never gets exploited.
Scott: every all these windows worms and exploits like ninety nine point nine 99.99% of all exploits and Windows and Internet Explorer are Against things that Microsoft has already put out a patch for and Microsoft when the patch comes out They'll tell you what the patch was for.
Rym: you look things up But you're forgetting that a lot of these kind of full disclosure situations aren't windows or anything like that.
Rym: They're things that are much more vulnerable and much more important like routers or ATM.
Scott: Yes, of course, but it's the same situation with those.
Scott: if you don't it's if you don't Disclose the vulnerability.
Scott: It's hardly hardly ever gets explored.
Scott: Well,
Rym: no because the thing is they actually as far as there's a lot of evidence to suggest that these sorts of things Do get exploited quite a bit But they're exploited quietly by people who you do them use them to very great effect And even if the companies find out about it They're probably better off covering it up then, you know letting loose that they have.
Scott: That's it like when.
Scott: yeah, it's a different situation like if you're a bank and you get hacked You don't want to let anyone know you got hacked because then you look real bad and everyone takes their money out.
Rym: But the reason that these people are stupid in my opinion is one their rationale.
Rym: They're no better than the.
Rym: you know We invaded Iraq for the oil people who just know nothing about the issue and just kind of make up some Half-baked conspiracy theory.
Rym: that doesn't actually make sense.
Rym: Whoever hacked Image Shack is stupid, but no no doubt about that.
Scott: But
Rym: the issue with full disclosure is I feel like in the end I am for it for the simple fact that Almost any time someone who is a white hat someone who is good and smart and knowledgeable discovers a vulnerability they will inform the company that has the product privately and say look I found this vulnerability you should fix it.
Rym: it's a huge vulnerability.
Rym: if someone in the wild finds out about it, they could compromise on your customers.
Rym: this sort of thing and The vast majority of companies that receive notices like this either ignore them or Sue the person who contacted them for hack.
Scott: that's happened a lot.
Rym: So it is in the best interest of a person who discovers something like this to not Contact the company because the company is very likely not going to respond with any sort of goodwill whatsoever And you're only putting yourself in danger by trying to help.
Scott: but it depends on the company It depends how you contact but it depends on a lot of things.
Rym: the problem here Is that even if you you know you can't be sure and the company because the way the laws are Have a lot of leverage in coming after you.
Scott: so Really, well you can look at the history.
Scott: You know especially if it's a tech company.
Scott: They probably have a history of people telling them about vulnerabilities And you know their policies and official ways to let them know.
Scott: but usually you know Adobe's had a lot of exploits.
Scott: You know that people have told them about and you know there's a. there's a way to do it.
Scott: that makes Adobe happy There's a way to do it.
Scott: that makes them angry.
Rym: But even then if you tell them usually they're not going to do anything even if they don't sue you or go after you in Some way well they do do something.
Scott: usually they're just not as fast to say open-source people who fix it in ten minutes.
Rym: I would say that usually it's been my experience that they don't do anything that most people will just not respond and not respond and That unless you threaten them with full disclosure.
Rym: They will never fix the vulnerability.
Scott: I think that I from what I've seen they do fix it.
Scott: It is slow.
Rym: You know Couple you say slow.
Rym: this will be a situation We're like a hack for an ATM is discovered where you can just like rob someone else's account of all its money.
Rym: Yeah, and it'll be years with no fix or no indication of a fix or anything.
Scott: Yeah, it takes a long time because the people are so slow.
Rym: yes, but that is a serious problem because if you threaten full disclosure Usually these companies fix it almost immediately.
Rym: Well, you know that's it's just the way you do business plus the other probably realize if you give if you privately contact a company and say all right here's what I have found.
Rym: here's the vulnerability.
Rym: please fix it and Someone else finds the vulnerability before they fix it and it gets out in the wild.
Rym: That company might just go after you because maybe you'll.
Rym: they'll assume you're the one who released it secretly to the wild.
Scott: yeah But you know if you're talking about an ATM company though, that's not really a technologically savvy company.
Scott: I said it depends a lot on the company that's involved.
Scott: You know Microsoft Adobe these types of people Apple They're a lot you know savvier and a lot smarter when it comes to this kind of situation.
Scott: They're used to it.
Scott: random bank number three You know d-balled government contractor.
Scott: a lot less savvy a lot less.
Rym: Those are the people that have more power over me.
Rym: I don't even want to do business with these people But just because of our society I'm forced to and they have a lot of my information.
Rym: that is true If there is a vulnerability that they have that they won't fix They're basically making me vulnerable without my consent and I see professional.
Rym: I Feel like in the end full disclosure is justified because it is information.
Rym: It's real information.
Rym: You can't hide information.
Rym: You should not be obligated to hide information that you know about.
Rym: no Yeah, no, I signed a contract.
Rym: You know independently of that obviously.
Rym: I mean if I sign an NDA I shouldn't be able to say anything.
Rym: Yeah, so if you get in the situation where you know I go to an ATM conference I signed an NDA and they basically will show me here's how to hack our ATMs.
Rym: check it out I can't really do anything of course, then there's the moral conundrum of maybe I should anonymously, but that's that's great.
Scott: Yeah, the hair.
Scott: how about this situation?
Scott: right exactly what you just said?
Scott: The the ATM is hackable right.
Scott: if you reveal the hack full disclosure someone's gonna exploit it.
Scott: bad for the company, right?
Scott: Possibly bad for you.
Scott: Also if you disclose it because the company might come after you right, okay?
Scott: If you keep your mouth shut well this vulnerability stays there never gets fixed.
Scott: Maybe someday someone else discovers it and now you're fucked and the bank is fucked again, right?
Scott: So what you know?
Scott: how is it ethical perhaps to?
Scott: Use the exploit to hack into the device and fix the vulnerability yourself is you know how?
Scott: how do you feel about that?
Rym: Well the problem with that is that the people one White hat hackers who decide to do something like that if they're sophisticated enough to do it well Understand that they're putting themselves a great personal risk for pretty much zero reward Yep, and very few people are willing.
Scott: well if the reward is you're making yourself a little bit safer.
Scott: You know if you are really worried about the fact that someone else is making you vulnerable You're making yourself well sort of less vulnerable if you get away with Because the problem is because you're doing this without the consent or knowledge of the person who manages the system.
Rym: Even if you're a super awesome professional ghost in the shell style There's a good chance you're going to cause further problems And you're going to make things worse than not better.
Scott: And it's also true because you're even if you manage to fix the the one hack.
Scott: It's like you don't really know their system inside and out probably especially if it's a closed source system.
Scott: And you know your change is not really gonna go through the whole testing procedure And the QA and all that sort of big stuff to make sure that it doesn't affect anything.
Rym: Here's a much more interesting situation.
Rym: One of the biggest problems with security in the world is that a lot of people's home Windows computers are secretly parts of gigantic Spam spyware zombie networks yep, and the people who own these computers.
Scott: pretty much the number one security concern There is.
Rym: if we got rid of that security be like a joke, but the problem is the people who own these computers are Effectively illiterate when it comes to technology, and they cannot in any way protect themselves.
Rym: They refuse to learn.
Rym: There's nothing we can do.
Rym: There's.
Rym: no we can't even consider the idea of teaching them.
Rym: It just won't happen.
Rym: mm-hmm and What?
Rym: if you know a grey hat hacker Made a malicious virus as opposed to a virus that just makes money for some Russian spams.
Scott: I actually actually did read recently that there was some sort of Virus out there.
Rym: there is it's the.
Rym: the Independence Day one is that it's basically counting down to a point where supposedly It will wipe out the hard drive.
Rym: yes someone every device is infected with.
Scott: yes Someone took this virus into their you know security lab, and they basically talked to it and told it.
Scott: You know that you know they triggered.
Scott: they looked at the code.
Scott: obviously It's got.
Rym: it's funny because we just watch Independence Day, and this is the Independence Day virus.
Rym: What are you doing?
Rym: It's the.
Scott: it's a self-repeating cycle that counts down to zero and it explodes Intentionally you know made the virus think that it was you know triggered and then it erased the hard drive of the computer.
Rym: It erased every attached storage device.
Rym: yep, but here's the thing that's interesting.
Rym: The speculation is that one.
Rym: it is a rival Russian Chinese spyware spam syndicate Wiping out all the hosts that are probably infected with it.
Rym: You know the other syndicate stuff so that they can then re-attack these people and put on their own stuff and then block their competitors Out.
Scott: mm-hmm could be.
Rym: there's another theory that it's just some sort of you know The probably the first straight-up malicious attack like maybe North Korea or someone is just trying to wipe out Western infrastructure.
Rym: Yes, you know I mean It's so interesting that like third suggestion the third theory out there is that it's some misguided white hat hacker thinking.
Rym: if I do This I will I will lower the amount of spam in the world by like 40% for about a day.
Scott: Yeah, it's not such a white someone who's actually a white hat hacker wouldn't go that route.
Rym: Some other route now because remember white hat People who are white hat I'm talking more gray hat like someone who's a script kitty kind of person.
Rym: Someone in high school who's super had a much better idea would be.
Rym: I'm not saying idea I'm saying there are people there's always the debate.
Scott: I don't think that's plot.
Scott: I don't think that's likely.
Rym: I think it's plausible and likely it just hasn't happened yet that someone with the ability to write a worm Might make a malicious one solely for the purpose of destroying dangerous species.
Scott: I don't think they would destroy dangerous pcs by erasing all attached storage devices.
Scott: I think that they would perhaps maybe disable all the network devices, you know somehow.
Rym: but why not?
Rym: because I'm surprised it hasn't happened yet.
Rym: I really am because it would be pretty trivial to do.
Scott: I'm surprised it hasn't happened yet for just pure maliciousness, right?
Scott: I mean, it's just as trivial to turn someone's computer into a you know Spam and spyware who knows what as it is to just you know Completely fuck the person over and make skulls show up on their screen and who knows what else.
Scott: crazy shit.
Rym: Here's an idea.
Rym: What if you know, this is not me advocating this but you could make rampant vulnerability exploits that went around the internet and basically just attacked compromised computers and Destroyed them to one punish the people who have poorly put out stuff and to make it almost impossible to maintain a compromised server For any amount of time in the wild.
Rym: because if you're compromised these things these roaming viruses will just destroy you.
Scott: Well, the reason that would not work is because if the computers are destroyed Then which computer is propagating the virus?
Scott: if it just got erased you need to keep the computer up to propagate the virus.
Rym: No You basically you set them up to propagate with a timer payload and then there are periodic kind of days of reckoning.
Rym: We're say 40 percent.
Scott: Well, you're right.
Scott: Yeah, your virus will move across in sort of a wave, but then it will dissipate.
Scott: He won't spawn into this big giant mole.
Rym: You didn't listen to what I said.
Rym: It's pretty straightforward.
Rym: You have pure you have semi random days of reckoning to where the viruses go out.
Rym: They propagate but they have kind of semi randomized timers such that they will.
Rym: You know 30% of the network will be wiped out on this day and then a year later The morphed virus wipes out another 30%.
Rym: So there's this constant kind of rolling blackout.
Rym: it.
Rym: the problem with this that it would be a very sophisticated attack To get.
Rym: anyone who has the ability to make something so sophisticated would probably shy at the obvious moral implications of you know Possibly shutting down hospital networks and that sort of thing.
Scott: Yeah, it also seems like people want credit card numbers more than they want erased hard drives.
Scott: Well the other situation I would do is I would make one where as soon as it got your credit card number Then it would erase your hard drive.
Scott: It's like I got nothing more I need from you.
Scott: I
Rym: will say this though I have a small hope that regardless of why this virus came to be If the payload does what we think it does and there is this sort of mass wipeout of every compromised computer I think that is going to do more for computer security than anything in the last 10 years.
Scott: has yeah a little bit.
Scott: It would help because at least somebody's the problem would get.
Rym: this is just a watchman situation.
Scott: Yeah, it would help a little bit though but I think a better way to go about it would you know it's there were.
Scott: there are instances in history of Not even that long ago people hacking and then like popping up a message that is like you have you have been hacked blah Blah blah, but we did that.
Rym: I remember.
Rym: we were visiting Pete and Albany.
Rym: we wardrobe.
Rym: We found a wireless access point to you know email Pete, and then we saw that you know all the guys.
Rym: window Shares was open.
Rym: read write admin.
Rym: So we put a couple of text files in obvious places that explained how to turn off those shares and secures wireless access point.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is right is that You know just what.
Scott: let's say I make a fire a website and the website says you know your computer is vulnerable.
Scott: Click here to be secure and of course that is an insecure thing.
Scott: So we can't.
Scott: teaching people to trust that message is a very bad way to go.
Scott: They're already don't know what to trust.
Scott: Well, that's
Rym: why I feel like this is going to be a big deal if it happens because if we find it's been a long Time since there's been a widespread Actually malicious and damaging virus of any kind if it happens You're gonna have a lot of people whose computers get wiped out who take serious damage.
Rym: They're gonna lose like family photos and music collections and like all this important stuff And they're not gonna be able to get online right away And they're gonna have to.
Rym: they're gonna flood the Geek Squad and all these things.
Scott: No, they're not.
Scott: they're gonna take their computer back to the Best Buy.
Scott: They're gonna say it stopped working.
Scott: Give me a new one.
Scott: They get a new one that go home is gonna fire us again.
Rym: But at the same time if enough of them happen at once there's gonna be enough outrage to where a lot of people there's Gonna be.
Rym: I think mainstream media talking about how could this happen?
Scott: Yeah, and you know what's gonna happen is all the Norton's and stuff.
Rym: We're gonna make a lot of money You know what while Norton's and those things I think are just a bad idea all around for someone who has no who's basically technologically illiterate.
Scott: And then people are not going to use the Norton's properly and it's not gonna help at all.
Rym: It'll help a little.
Scott: it's not gonna help at all.
Scott: People have the Norton's now, and they still get virus.
Rym: they don't actually have the Norton's anymore.
Scott: Yeah they do.
Scott: I have it and they still get virus because they don't update it and they don't use it and they turn it off or Well doesn't work right is it hits?
Scott: they click on shit anyway?
Scott: And then the real.
Rym: the real problem is that viruses and worms are dandy.
Rym: But I'd say 95% of the compromised computers out there are compromised by Trojans alone.
Rym: Yeah, Trojans probably the biggie and the Trojans are the easiest things to not get owned by.
Rym: don't double-click on dot exes That come in random emails.
Scott: Well, I mean like look at my cousins right there computer was all messed up right and and I basically I was like wow Those computers way messed up and I found out pretty much the only reason it was messed up.
Scott: And so they just never do updates.
Scott: It was like I'm like, you know when it says update it you're supposed to say yes They're like, oh I just ignore that.
Scott: and like someone else I talked to like a week later was like all the updates.
Scott: Yeah, I just ignore those, you know It's Pete.
Scott: the primary problem is that people do not read.
Scott: even you know, they do not read Whatever is written on their computer screen.
Scott: They just don't you know They just they.
Scott: all they want to do is if there's a window that pops up They want it to go away as quickly as possible.
Scott: Okay, cancel, whatever makes it go away.
Scott: They don't read anything.
Scott: So if people don't read what's on their screen, nothing can make them secure.
Scott: Absolutely nothing.
Rym: I mean work.
Rym: when I worked at the hospital It was just.
Rym: it was amazing that I could get a call from like a doctor someone who operates on people for a living and he would say something like My email is not working and this is a critical problem.
Rym: You have to fix it right now And I'm like, so what error did you get?
Rym: He's like there wasn't any error just now working.
Rym: So I tell him to try again and I'm like, so what happened?
Rym: He's like a thing popped up and I clicked OK.
Rym: So I'm like, okay.
Rym: What did the thing say?
Rym: He's like, what do you mean?
Rym: What did it say?
Rym: I was like do it again and don't click.
Rym: Okay, so he's like, alright I'm like, what does it say in the box that you keep clicking on?
Rym: and it's like.
Rym: it basically said your email account is not set up.
Rym: And he's like, what does that mean?
Rym: I was like.
Rym: it means your email account is not set up.
Scott: This means exactly what it says.
Scott: It's in English, right?
Scott: It's not.
Scott: I mean It doesn't say like, you know I mean I can understand if the error is like one of those Like in the olden days of the blue screen in Windows or it be like blah blah blah.
Scott: error 0xx53 poo poo, right but poo poo.
Scott: nowadays It's like, you know, sorry you have a blah blah blah.
Scott: You know make sure you do this.
Scott: It's in English.
Scott: nowadays on Windows Mac and Linux all the errors that a user will see operating in the GUI 99% of those errors are in English and they will tell you what to do.
Scott: And if you don't read them, fuck you You deserve what you get.
Scott: All right, I think we're done but I don't even know what to call this episode.
Rym: I don't know either but it's all you.
Rym: I feel like we could do some shows on some related topics about computer security And I think our listeners would love some high-level.
Rym: I think we should talk about.
Scott: I think I think yeah I think there's more to talk about in the ethics department than I mean the security department.
Rym: All right here.
Rym: the next Monday show will be ethical hacking And this one will be something else.
Scott: It's gonna overlap a lot with this one.
Rym: No, I want to talk about the technology side of it.
Rym: All right ethical hacking means something very specific in IT.
Scott: Yeah, well the job of it.
Scott: Is that when you talk about?
Rym: Yes This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our proper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew calm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website.
Rym: If you like what you hear you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: this means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit.
Scott: Don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.