Rym: It's Tuesday April 14th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We talk about spooky games.
Scott: Let's do this Being home not working.
Scott: I'm well not working at an official job with a where I have to file at the w2 and such.
Rym: But instead of working hard at being a bum.
Scott: I'm working hard at actual stuff.
Scott: I'm doing a lot of stuff anyway.
Scott: related thing one of the things that you know.
Scott: and even if you're working hard on real stuff You can't do it all day.
Scott: You gotta you know even the hardest work in workaholic person has to take a little break.
Scott: You know whether it's a watch a little TV read a little book.
Scott: You know something to ease the mind, so I've been playing earthbound in the emulator.
Rym: now You've beaten earthbound.
Scott: I assume yeah a long time ago.
Rym: once Ben is it long enough to where?
Rym: you don't remember all the little details.
Scott: I don't remember the details.
Scott: I only remember the generic parts.
Scott: You know the the Fundamental facts, I don't.
Scott: you know the small thing like.
Scott: I don't remember individual dialogues and things like that anyway But yeah, I've been.
Scott: I've been playing it again.
Scott: I think it's kind of weird how when I had a job like I mean earthbound is You know a Japanese style RPG at its at its core even though the rest of it is sort of not you know anything Final Fantasy game,
Rym: it's like a comedy game, and there's a lot of interesting elements
Scott: I just think.
Scott: well first of all I want to point out isn't it weird how like there's the vast majority of Japanese style RPG type games are fantasy slash sci-fi one of the other or both and like so few are not and Earthbound is like just one of the ones that isn't you know.
Rym: like is he had Dragon Warrior and Final Fantasy?
Scott: Yeah, it's it right.
Scott: so first of all.
Scott: It's not fantasy.
Scott: I guess it's kind of sci-fi.
Scott: It's a kid with psychic powers going around saving the world from From aliens and monsters with it with a baseball bat right anyway.
Scott: But that aside perfectly realistic, but it's weird how now that I don't have a job like suddenly RPGs are tolerable at least a little bit more tolerable than they used to be I don't know.
Scott: I think it's how tolerable a time-wasting game is is directly a function of how much time you have to waste.
Rym: well by the same Token you know I'm playing through chrono trigger again, and I'm also in that situation.
Rym: I don't remember a lot of the details.
Rym: and But every time I find something in the game like it all comes back And I'm remembering how much I love that game.
Scott: well I think what it was is you know back in the day when I had time for RPGs the thing that frustrated me Was random encounters.
Scott: right.
Scott: and I'd like to point out the chrono trigger and earthbound of All JRPGs are some of the best at the way they handle the random encounter right because they still have them.
Scott: They're there they have them right, but earthbound and chrono trigger first of all it's not random like you're walking around the map And suddenly this bad guys It's.
Scott: you see the bad guys on the screen.
Scott: you can sort of run away from them or try to Or you can sort of sneak up on them and get them from behind for a sneak attack Or if they sneak up behind you you get sneak attacked right.
Scott: and also Earthbound has the best thing in the world which is if you bump into a bad guy Who's just so weak that you can't.
Scott: they can't possibly hurt you they just die and you get the experience You don't even have to do the fight, and that's that's pretty great.
Rym: I wish the threshold had been a little higher the threshold.
Rym: I believe is they couldn't possibly do any damage.
Scott: well actually yeah That's true, but actually it's surprising like how sometimes you know a bad guy You'll bump into you'll think you have to fight it, but then it just dies like oh, yeah, sweet Like you'll even level up because of it.
Scott: you'll get so much experience.
Scott: another thing is usually when you beat a boss in an area They'll make you walk out back the way you came in sometimes But when they do that All the bad guys like be running away from you, or they'll all be gone.
Scott: Which is pretty awesome.
Rym: It's weird though I I often would be very miffed when I had to walk out of something.
Rym: Final Fantasy did that.
Scott: well you can use if you have an exit mouse or You know whatever like.
Rym: remember Final Fantasy you if you beat the fiends they were teleports You're right back out, and we beat Garland.
Rym: they teleport you right back out.
Rym: Yeah, but when you hike into that goddamn cave to get the floater or something you had to hike all the way back out.
Rym: Yes, you didn't.
Rym: but it was this odd as you had to get in get the thing and get out without dying Or it was all for naught.
Scott: I think you know.
Scott: so I think the fact that those things are made You know easier is part of the reason I can continue to play earthbound.
Scott: But I think another reason I can continue to play it is that I'm in an emulator.
Scott: So I can do the save and load state which helps a lot, right?
Scott: And I could do a lot of cheating tricks with that.
Scott: for example I can go to the guy who sells hints save talk get a hint for $75 then load and get my money back.
Rym: I see you play money-making game.
Scott: I play money-making game.
Rym: indeed old man run money-making game Always win.
Scott: I'll also do other things such as Save the game get into a fight use the spy ability to figure out what the bad guys weaknesses are Load then do it again, and so that I you know can instead of wasting an action on spy I can waste spend an action on doing damage.
Rym: You know what else would do that cheating game facts game genie.
Scott: So And something else I think that makes the game a lot more tolerable and isn't necessarily cheating.
Scott: Is I'm using an Xbox 360 controller to play this game, right?
Scott: So I only really need the d-pad the four button the four face buttons LR and start and select, right?
Scott: So I've got a lot of extra buttons going on.
Scott: So what I did is I took r2 and I bound r2 to speed up the emulator So I can walk real fast.
Scott: I don't need to use like a skip sandwich.
Scott: You know I can just or like if there's a guy who's got a really long dialogue.
Scott: That's annoying.
Scott: I'll just hold down r2 while pushing the button to speed through the dialogue real quick Like when the fuzzy pickles guy comes up comes down.
Scott: I'll make him go away in like two seconds.
Rym: I Remember I had that for my SNES emulator when I was working it as an SNES emulator But I didn't have it for my NES emulator.
Rym: So as a result I would play games And I got so used to the speed up that I would hit it when I was playing NES games And it wouldn't do anything and I'd get so frustrated.
Rym: I just quit right that in there.
Scott: Yeah, but it's like.
Scott: you know when I'm instead of wasting.
Scott: You know like 30 seconds walking down like this street I'll walk down the street in like three seconds.
Rym: You know what game could have used that.
Rym: you know what game would have would have been a thousand times better If I gave you a game where you walk really really slow Pokemon.
Scott: Yeah My god forget the bicycle whoosh who needs that?
Scott: Or in fact get on the bicycle.
Scott: Yeah, you go even faster whoo.
Scott: It's Good, but I think I heard the Pokemon Platinum actually has faster combat.
Rym: Thank the gods of course little too little too late.
Rym: I like your strategy of always buy the second Pokemon.
Scott: It's like I regret buying diamond.
Scott: I should have just waited and bought the platinum one.
Scott: I should have known they were gonna do it.
Scott: so next time I'm just gonna buy the platinum equivalent.
Rym: next time you can buy it and then buy.
Scott: yep That's what I can do all right.
Scott: Yeah, earthbound if you haven't played earthbound Good game.
Scott: normally we're anti of that kind of RPG.
Scott: You know it's called RPG, but it really shouldn't be.
Rym: earthbound or mother is one of those exceptions.
Rym: Yeah, it's it's like.
Scott: well mother one is the NES game.
Scott: really you shouldn't play that whole game.
Scott: It's not worth it It's too much.
Scott: It's it's just.
Rym: it's worth playing.
Rym: the beginning.
Scott: well It's very very big.
Scott: just play it to see what it was like.
Scott: don't actually play it to win.
Scott: You know.
Scott: just play it to see what the game was about what how it worked etc.
Scott: right earthbound or mother Too as it is known in Japan play that entire game And then I have the mother three fan translation in a GBA emulator.
Scott: So I'm gonna play that when I'm done with earthbound.
Rym: about the slash mother - but you know I'm thinking one of the reasons I feel like Chrono Trigger is tolerable to me even though.
Rym: I have a job, and it's not just nostalgia is that I?
Rym: Mostly play it when I'm idle like on the train or like someplace when I'm waiting for something or doing anything like that Primarily on the train mm-hmm.
Rym: so whenever I play a game like that at home I feel like I should be doing something because I should be doing something.
Scott: E-commerce I got a lot of shit.
Scott: You didn't do.
Rym: yeah, I've been busy unlike you I have a job you're talking about.
Scott: I'm doing so much shit.
Scott: You have no idea.
Scott: Yeah, yeah Today I did more today than I've done like in a long time.
Rym: Yeah, I did a lot too.
Rym: But anyway on the train or if I were jobless let's say I Wouldn't feel this need to be doing something kind of like it Wildwood when we go to the beach.
Rym: I feel it needs to be doing something now more than ever but see when I like when I'm at the beach I don't think oh I could be working on GeekNights, or oh, I got a.
Scott: true I think Yeah at the beach I could definitely.
Scott: I mean think about it.
Scott: most of my Pokemon playing was down the Wildwood days.
Scott: remember that.
Rym: I Remember that.
Rym: I remember I was.
Scott: we were all Okay to just push.
Scott: sit there pushing a for a few hours when you're at the beach.
Scott: He got nothing else doing.
Scott: why not push a?
Rym: at one point I was watching something on TV playing Pokemon with one hand and playing Civ 4 on the laptop at the same time.
Scott: Oh, that's a good time.
Rym: That was a real good time.
Rym: all right, but You all should know this is coming.
Rym: We've talked about it.
Rym: Everyone's talked about it, but it's been street dated the Wii motion and Wii Sports resorts.
Scott: We forgot all about that thing.
Scott: I don't even know what's going on in the way.
Scott: It's been so long since they even turned it on or played it that I have no idea What's going on on the way or anything?
Rym: I haven't played a non virtual console game And I don't know what Wii games are coming out.
Scott: I don't know Wii games are out.
Scott: I mean they announced the Wii motion, and then I completely forgot about it, and now it's.
Scott: they're actually releasing it.
Scott: I'm like oh, yeah, when that thing?
Rym: when do they announce that it's gonna be available on June 8th?
Scott: all right for 20 bucks All right, not buying it.
Rym: Probably as people pointed out if you buy for remotes for remotions and for dun shucks That's basically a ps3.
Scott: Oh my god.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, I mean Nintendo has always Always been about the accessories.
Scott: trying to sell you power pads trying to sell you power gloves.
Scott: trying to sell you Memory cards trying to say memory expansion cards for your Nintendo 64 the Nintendo 64.
Scott: You know why they made four controller slots.
Scott: not because they thought four player gaming would be fun.
Scott: They could sell you three controllers instead of just one more controller.
Scott: remember when they did that on the any Score and it'll sell you a four score.
Scott: They'd sell you an NES advantage.
Scott: They would sell you an NES max.
Scott: They'd sell you a zapper.
Scott: Right you know that was.
Scott: that's what Nintendo's been about and that's always where the money is.
Scott: the margins on accessories are Ginormous compared to the margins on games and console.
Scott: Well.
Rym: I wouldn't use the word ginormous because ginormous because it's not a fucking word.
Scott: I mean the Wii motion probably cost them like a dollar or two to make.
Scott: I mean I wonder is Didn't?
Rym: there are only two options here.
Rym: either Nintendo originally said you know thought we're going to make the Wii and then someone in engineering said we can't get it as Accurate as you guys promised in time.
Rym: So why do we split off the accurate thing and we'll release it as is it's good enough And then we'll release this bundle later, or they said we could make it more accurate now, or we could charge 1999 mega time.
Rym: make a team make it to make it to.
Scott: It was fine, I'm not sure what the situation was.
Scott: I would not discount any of these reasonable explanations that we can come up with.
Scott: It could be any one of them.
Rym: But what's interesting is the reports.
Rym: when this first first came out and there were demos for some reporters and everything Was that it wasn't any different, and I kind of expected that.
Rym: but now there are reports coming out that it's actually a lot different.
Scott: I mean someone I think at EA said it's too Precise like it's.
Scott: it's exactly one-to-one like the fidgeting of your hand is picked up by this thing Which is and that they have to.
Scott: they have to decrease the sensitivity on it in order to actually make the game playable?
Rym: No, no all they get.
Rym: all that means is that they need.
Rym: they can make better kinds of games.
Scott: Hopefully we don't Trust with.
Scott: some guy at EA says you know it's like I need to.
Scott: I need to experience this Probably at a PAX demo station.
Rym: see there.
Rym: There are two very important eras in rims gaming life.
Rym: I'll call them the pre and the post.
Rym: the ad in the BC Before WarioWare smooth moves came out and after Because that was when the dream died.
Scott: You know that game would have been just fine if the multiplayer had good modes.
Scott: If you wouldn't the Wii part wouldn't have mattered.
Rym: no wouldn't have.
Rym: but you know what they butch.
Rym: the only part of the game the series the entire Ever good.
Scott: the part the game where you catch the things and sort of hold them up is okay was a great $5 minigame.
Rym: Yes, it was was not a great.
Scott: even fight at $1 50 cents.
Scott: Did nice.
Scott: I sold the game.
Scott: I think I think you did Amazon.
Scott: yeah It was did I?
Rym: I don't remember it wasn't the worst game on the Wii.
Rym: I mean remember that monkey ball.
Scott: Yeah, I sold that definitely an Amazon.
Rym: That was possibly the worst game ever made, but you know what.
Scott: actually thinking back right and on all the Wii games That because we've got quite a few Wii games.
Scott: You know Wii games.
Scott: I played the most I played.
Rym: Let's see Mike Tyson's punch-out.
Scott: Well.
Scott: I mean Wii games actual games on discs for the Wii The tennis.
Rym: no that was GameCube.
Scott: Yeah, huh, you know what games I played the most for the Wii.
Rym: I've zero.
Scott: well.
Scott: No that was a GameCube game.
Scott: Yeah, huh, you know what gives away the most of the way.
Scott: Okay, well the Zelda game comes in second place.
Scott: the Metroid game comes in third.
Scott: the Zelda game was a GameCube game That's true.
Rym: They just made it on the way.
Scott: So okay the Metroid game was in second place.
Scott: You know what the game.
Scott: I played the most excite truck.
Scott: Huh yeah Excite truck is actually really good.
Scott: looking back got it.
Scott: You know I mean I think and I think this they're making like something else.
Scott: They're making like some sort of monster thing or like you drive creatures around.
Scott: I don't know what to do.
Scott: it's like excite something else they're doing I don't know.
Scott: but Whatever, it's just looking back on that.
Scott: It's like huh really Wow Honestly, yeah, honestly late excite truck the most before WarioWare smooth moves which I kind of.
Rym: what that really entails is when I realized that Nintendo will never allow any of its platforms to achieve what they could possibly achieve.
Rym: yep I mean back in the Crystal Chronicles day.
Rym: when they tried I all I could think was that this is it.
Rym: Nintendo has proven that they can do something awesome and different, but what Nintendo saw was everyone hated that game.
Scott: Well, I think what happened right is that the GameCube right.
Scott: the GameCube was actually kind of awesome Right, but the thing is is people don't care about good gameplay And that's why Miyamoto is sad in the GameCube era.
Scott: right because people didn't care about the awesome game.
Rym: I did an entire show on this topic right.
Scott: so people were buying PlayStation twos which had quantity and not so much quality well they had quality there too, but a lot of quantity more so So when the Wii came around people like us were psyched up for because it was like wow we're gonna get all the awesome Games that like the GameCube had only on this Wii with this motion stuff.
Scott: It's gonna be awesome.
Scott: But they they dropped the quality of the GameCube games by the wayside when they made the Wii And that's why the Wii is sitting there not being played.
Rym: But so pre Wario or smooth moves Rym would have said.
Rym: now they can make the freaking Star Wars lightsaber game and it'll be the best game ever.
Rym: but now What I know is what I what I predict is that they're going to make a bunch of very uninspired Wii Sports clones.
Rym: One or two people are gonna make games that use this thing and then it's just gonna completely disappear.
Rym: That's right And all the fanboys will have bought one and all the grandma's will have bought one because now they can play the next Wii sports game.
Scott: maybe and That's it that that's it.
Rym: like I I've basically given up on Nintendo.
Rym: unless they prove to me unless they try to make another Crystal Chronicles, yeah They did.
Scott: well there is one for the Wii isn't there?
Rym: I have no son And there was no sequel to Crystal Chronicles.
Scott: No, I'm pretty sure there's a new one the way have no son.
Scott: No, I'm pretty sure there's a new one for the Wii.
Rym: Yeah, and when's it coming?
Scott: I think it's out right now.
Rym: and did it integrate the DS?
Scott: I think it did.
Rym: did it.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't pay attention cuz I'm not on a job.
Scott: I can't buy it, but you can go investigate it after the show.
Rym: I'm highly dubious of this.
Scott: go investigate.
Scott: I heard it.
Scott: Anyway, I'm a taiko talking about it.
Rym: Uh-huh I'm just I'm very leery.
Scott: All right, so I got.
Scott: I got a news here.
Scott: Oh, yeah, so apparently I'm not gonna go through the whole story here.
Scott: You can read the story in this blog posting.
Scott: But basically there was a sequel to punch-out that was being made at some point.
Scott: that was going to be called Mike Tyson's power punch, right and in the game you actually played as Mike Tyson and Don King was there instead of you know Doc, whatever, but Little Mac.
Scott: I know Little Mac wasn't in this game But you know for reasons Pertaining to Mike Tyson and other things this game was not made.
Scott: a game called power punch 2 was released But that game did not involve Mike Tyson in any way and it was also terrible.
Scott: Of course, Mike Tyson's power punch was also terrible Power punch.
Scott: Mike Tyson's power punch is a game where Mike Tyson punches aliens much like that episode of Dexter's lab where with macho man Randy seven.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: All right, Scott.
Rym: I got interrupt and monkey I have to interrupt in the middle.
Rym: The Wii version of Crystal Chronicles is almost identical to that The the DS.
Scott: Oh, you looked it up already.
Scott: Yes, okay quotes.
Rym: The Wii version of the game contains all of the major elements of the DS version.
Scott: Oh, yeah, it's just is it?
Rym: a port comma But must be played on a single screen period.
Rym: to compensate.
Rym: This version has two adjustable in-game fucking screen.
Rym: There's no integration with the DS listed here.
Scott: Bullshit, oh my god.
Scott: I thought it was a new game.
Scott: It's just the DS game for the Wii.
Rym: the fact that they just give you a split screen, I guess Oh fuck that Wow Wow Wow.
Scott: Okay, anyway, okay, so this power punch game Basically some collector had it right And the community had to get $1,500 together to get the dude to give the game up so that they could rip a rob and share the ROM with the world.
Scott: And so I want to you know, the news is you can go get this ROM and play it of this terrible old game.
Scott: That's actually historically significant even though it's terrible.
Scott: But I want to start a discussion.
Scott: I don't want to have the discussion right now I just want to pose this question out there.
Scott: Maybe we'll discuss it later, right?
Scott: Let's say I had a Van Gogh some historically significant piece of artwork, right?
Scott: Yeah, it's very important Yep, and we had the technological capability to like perfectly duplicate this historic piece of work.
Scott: You know Adam by Adam right would and there was only one of them in the world left right say the Mona Lisa, right?
Scott: Would we not be you know?
Scott: Morally like required to use that technology to make a duplicate, you know for this historically significant thing.
Scott: so these collectors who are like Holding these games, you know that they have the only copy in the known universe.
Scott: We have the technology to perfectly duplicate them and they're just not giving them up.
Scott: I think that this that's a serious a serious problem and it need we need to do something about it because it's not Say that I disagree.
Rym: Yeah, I would love to play this game.
Scott: Well, you can it's a free ROM now.
Rym: Yes Okay, anyway to get it out there more.
Rym: It's out there But how many people know about it except for all of you?
Scott: now just it was on Kotaku.
Scott: plenty of people know about it.
Rym: You know, I feel like not that many of our readers read things like Kotaku or College Humor.
Scott: I know right.
Scott: Maybe maybe you should because that's where we get our news Pretty much like 80% of them.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: All right, and the rest are from slash shot.
Scott: Yeah, so go ahead with your news.
Rym: I already did my name.
Scott: Oh, that was your news.
Rym: Okay, so then I guess it's time for things of the day.
Scott: This thing of the day is so epically fucking amazing.
Scott: Oh, is it?
Scott: Oh shit.
Scott: All right, so so This is a video right?
Scott: The story is in 1993 1993 when I was 8 11 11 years old.
Scott: Dan Linton a guy who ran a BBS called software creations went to Tejas and in his in Tejas He went to id software which is where they made Wolfenstein and doom and everything right.
Scott: Wolfenstein Wolfenstein DeStein Goldberg, okay so Wolfenstein came out before 1993 but doom came out in 93 or 94.
Scott: So this was this video was taken Before doom was finished and released.
Scott: before doom one was finished and released, right?
Scott: And it's a kind of a long video that John Romero has posted on Vimeo here.
Scott: But this video you should watch the whole thing and pay attention to every minute of it because it is like epically Historic and amazing and I mean the main things you got to get out of this video.
Scott: if you get nothing else Right is that you watching this video the people in software early in the video They're playing Aladdin for the Sega Genesis, which just came out.
Scott: So that was like a top-of-the-line game right at this point in time And that game was pretty good.
Scott: but then you compare that top-of-the-line game Aladdin for the Sega Genesis, which is actually a really good game it is and Compare that to the unfinished doom that is using.
Scott: that is not even.
Scott: that is still using sound effects from the Super Nintendo Wolfenstein.
Rym: right this is probably I did.
Rym: I didn't watch the whole video.
Rym: Do they shoot a BFG?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: but because the BFG used to use different Mechanics and they had to change it.
Rym: Yeah I've all started.
Scott: but I mean you watch this video of John Romero Demonstrating doom and then having like one of the first death matches in all of history right with one of the other guys that in software while this guy is videoing it.
Scott: and I mean You learn that the mean nowadays the doom is not so amazing, right?
Scott: And you know you think of doom is this historic FPS.
Scott: But really the gap between doom and all the other games at the time doom came out Was just so enormous.
Scott: I think do no other game has had that kind of gap ever.
Rym: I mean, they're they're definitely better games than do.
Rym: I mean do was great and amazing But they're better come out like quick to was a gigantic like Revolution in gaming and half-life was a gigantic revolution FPS and all these sorts of things.
Rym: But and you know Mario 64 and 3d platformer.
Scott: But the gap between half-life and the other games that were out at the time Was not nearly as big as the gap between doom and the other games that came out at that time.
Rym: I would argue that doom was possibly the biggest leap in gaming technology biggest individual leap ever in the history of gaming.
Scott: by by Orders of magnitude.
Rym: I mean looking at the games that I was playing when I then got the shareware of doom.
Scott: I mean you look at this video and they're talking about like commander keen and shit and then guy whips out do It's like holy fine?
Scott: There are things in doom that you don't even notice nowadays That you don't realize how amazing they were like the facts that there was areas where lights turned on and off Yeah,
Rym: dynamic lighting in 1993
Scott: or the fact that it actually really looked 3d and you can go up and down in real time smoothly.
Rym: I mean quick to was this gigantic leap and quick through to.
Scott: is the game the fact that bad guys would start shooting each other?
Rym: I Credit quake to with beginning the true modern 3d FPS era, but it wasn't that big of a leap.
Rym: Well, it was a big leap from doom, but there was that pesky quake one in between.
Scott: Yeah, that sort of did the in-between leap.
Rym: Yeah doom was just like.
Rym: No game has ever been that amazing Compared to the other contemporary game you're really.
Scott: if you don't get it.
Scott: you need to watch this video and watch it carefully and Watch the whole thing slowly and carefully and let it sink in how much of a leap doom was in its day.
Rym: so Completely not along those lines and not related at all.
Rym: I use this on a Tuesday as opposed to a Wednesday Partly because I'm sure a lot of the Wednesday listeners already see this sort of stuff all the time But I feel I should spread it.
Rym: I don't think I'm not going to explain who Hatsune Miku is.
Rym: you can you can look online and figure that out?
Rym: But we're fans and as long as she doesn't go all Macross on I was just about to say Of course if she does that's dumb.
Rym: I can't really fault her for it.
Scott: No, there's not much you can do about it.
Rym: Yeah Well, you can crash a plane and you don't have it.
Scott: You don't have a transforming plane.
Rym: Anyway, I could take my one of my ring Raiders.
Scott: It's not gonna work.
Rym: take it into the monitor.
Scott: It'll just get owned.
Rym: Anyway, so The long story short is that there's an old 60s duet by these cool Japanese.
Rym: I'm using this and if you look any more info on this video, there's a link to that movie and This was redone by another set of Japanese twins more recently.
Scott: I don't think they the more recent ones were twins.
Rym: Well, they're similar looking and they're cute.
Rym: Yeah, that's that's all that really matters.
Rym: Okay, so this has been taken to the third degree and Someone has made an animated Miku dance to this song and I don't just watch it.
Rym: I don't think I need to say anything.
Scott: Yeah, watch all these.
Scott: like there's three or four videos.
Scott: Just watch all of them and you'll understand what happened.
Rym: It's it's cute.
Rym: It's cool.
Rym: And I really really really like this song.
Scott: I was gonna say the songs pretty awesome.
Scott: It is catchy and both the modern especially.
Scott: I mean considering it's a Japanese song for the 60s and it's awesome.
Scott: now That's pretty.
Rym: Japanese music from the 60s is awesome.
Scott: I say it wasn't but I'm just saying Considering that the fact that this song is like so awesome now is is less, you know It's a pretty damn good song.
Rym: remake is good.
Rym: But so is the original.
Rym: Yeah, and it's really cute.
Rym: Okay, that's all I got.
Scott: All right, we're gonna talk about scary games spooky game.
Scott: So basically the edges boo, which is boo, which is which is brew is scary.
Rym: Scott I got a question.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, it's about which is.
Scott: So Basically it's sort of come up that like, you know games aren't scary even games that want to be scary.
Scott: I mean, maybe other people are scared by them, but we definitely aren't.
Scott: you know games like eternal darkness resident evil Silent Hill These sort of games that are supposed to be scary are not scary.
Scott: not at least not to us and you're scared by them You're a sissy.
Rym: It will see.
Rym: all these games are different.
Rym: like Resident Evil went through this long evolution from What it was to what is basically a third-person zombie shooter.
Scott: Yeah, actually like Resident Evil 4 more than I like the older ones Yeah, but I haven't played five but I'd like to but that's it's a third-person shooter.
Scott: Yeah, it is.
Rym: but then there's games like Fatal Frame, which I would argue were a lot more scary.
Scott: I know I didn't play that so I don't know.
Rym: I only played it a little.
Rym: I played most of Fatal Frame vicariously watching other.
Rym: Yeah, I never played that which is kind of how I enjoy those games.
Scott: I never really liked playing them Right, but the thing is is like all these games that are supposed to be scary now I mean occasionally like they're like the first time I played eternal darkness.
Scott: There are a couple parts that were jump out.
Scott: boo surprise like boo.
Scott: There's a body in a bloody bathtub, but it wasn't was the exam but it wasn't scary.
Scott: You know, I wasn't like you or you know, I didn't feel fear.
Scott: I just just like oh I jumped a little bit because it went boo right and that's not scary.
Scott: That's just boo.
Scott: So I realized that sort of like.
Scott: I was scared of video games Way back in the day like for example.
Scott: I think nothing is scared me as much as like the last level of Zelda 1 but I was also scared by like the entire second half or more than The majority of Zelda 2 and like towards the end of Megaman 2.
Scott: I was getting a little scared when I was a little kid.
Scott: at least, you know It's like these old NES games are scarier and still are scared a lot of these games that try to be scary.
Scott: And I think there's a discussion to be had just in general about like what make games scary Why why one game scary and one isn't how to make a game scarier, etc.
Rym: I think we really need to break out because there are many different kinds of fear And I think for the purposes of a gaming discussion There are three.
Rym: the first one obvious is the startle the jump out and boo the.
Rym: I look in the bathtub There's nothing I like.
Rym: there's a bloody body.
Scott: I don't even think that counts as scary.
Rym: In video gaming that is definitely.
Rym: it can be used to scare and it there is an element of fear.
Rym: It's just.
Rym: it's a different kind of fear and it.
Rym: I think it can be used effectively.
Rym: I think it's usually overdone.
Rym: I think a lot of maybe try to be scary end up just being full of boo.
Scott: Maybe so but personally When you know the boo feeling is nothing like a fear feeling for me.
Scott: So I sort of like I. when people make things they call them scary and they're actually just boo.
Scott: I sort of like no, you're not actually scary.
Scott: You're just boo.
Scott: It's it's not you're cheating It's not the same thing.
Rym: I think for the purposes of this discussion that it really fits.
Rym: I think it's one of the three kinds of scaring.
Rym: startling fear, you know It's an aspect of this kind of game.
Scott: It is an aspect of the kind of game, but I think it's not scary.
Rym: I would say it definitely counts.
Rym: It's one of the three pillars of scary.
Scott: Well doesn't scare me.
Rym: Well Maybe this is a no-true Scotsman situation, but possibly sure it falls in the realm of scaring.
Rym: Startle is just another kind of scare.
Rym: It has a different reaction.
Rym: I I guess the point I'm trying to make that you keep desperately trying to derail with your semantic bullshit Is that there are different kinds of fear different kinds of scaring and different sorts of feelings?
Rym: You can evoke along these lines but I feel like most game designers don't necessarily differentiate between them and just kind of make games with these stereotypical things that they that should be scary.
Rym: and Sometimes they touch on the elements of one kind of fear and sometimes on the other.
Rym: and I think this alone accounts for just 90% of the disparity between What games scare people and what games try to be scary?
Rym: But aren't in games that don't try to be scary but are and all that sort of thing I just I don't think people really analyze.
Rym: What is scary?
Scott: Yeah, they're dead.
Scott: You know, it's like a lot of people.
Scott: you just go up to someone say what's scary?
Scott: Well zombies monsters goes things that are ugly things are nasty things that are dark.
Scott: You go to other people who are being quiet then jumping out and going boom.
Rym: Okay, you go to other people What's scary and they say AIDS the Holocaust?
Scott: Yeah, those are scary.
Scott: your mom Your mom is pretty scary.
Rym: Yeah, not as scary as your mom.
Rym: Yeah, but Startling I think is one but I think the much more interesting second kind but the kind that is most often Conflated with fear in general is the mundane fear the meta fear.
Rym: I guess the example I have for this is Remember games like Final Fantasy where you have to fight your way in and get the floater and fight your way out And if you die or get lost or fuck up You have to go through all that all over again because you couldn't save your game.
Scott: Oh, that's true.
Scott: I mean games today.
Scott: They don't really punish the player very much because you know that sort of makes the games very frustrating and no one likes them.
Scott: So even a game that's supposed to be scary usually doesn't punish you.
Scott: I mean Resident Evil.
Scott: lets you save on the typewriters all over the place, right?
Scott: So, I mean if a game doesn't you mean even if a game isn't supposed to be scary if the game has a serious Punishment for failure then failure suddenly becomes very very frightening if you know that there's that extreme punishment.
Rym: but at the same time punishment and meta fear are This almost logical Calculated controlled fear.
Rym: It's not like it's not this visceral feeling.
Rym: It's this very literal.
Rym: I don't want to have to play through the part of the game that I just played again feeling it's this calculated Oh my god, and
Scott: but I mean if you're Mario and you're there's a big hole and you got to jump over it You're actually afraid to fall down it.
Scott: Whereas if you can just load it up again You're not afraid to fall down it and go just jump with no fear.
Rym: But while you're afraid on this calculated meta level, you're not afraid on this human visceral level.
Rym: You're not like Imagining yourself as Mario fearing this bottomless chasm you have to jump over Not trembling.
Rym: no, you're not.
Rym: it's.
Rym: it's this very meta fear.
Scott: if you are you need help.
Rym: It's the shit.
Rym: and I think the problem I had with eternal darkness Was that it really only had these first two kinds of fear.
Rym: It was primarily either boo or meta and the meta was always either, you know, you walk into a room.
Rym: You think you died crap up?
Rym: No I didn't die or I'm gonna spoil because it statute of limitations.
Rym: seriously The point near the end of the game where if your sanity meter gets low enough You go to save your game and then it's just like up format error and then your save game disappears.
Scott: Well, no There was a part I think towards the middle ish latest part of the game where it popped up like the GameCube error message like got your game screwed up and then I was Like aha just kidding.
Rym: Yep, but that scared me.
Rym: It got me.
Rym: I was like what.
Scott: I wasn't scared I was just pissed.
Scott: I was like off fuck.
Rym: I wasn't like oh god But that is fair, but it's the pure Metalogical fear.
Rym: you don't have the visceral like.
Rym: you don't get that spine tingling that like Incomprehensible primal feeling of fear that that are actually afraid and it doesn't have to be fear in the like Whoo, but just that you know every now and then you're you're all at least most of you human.
Rym: Everyone has felt that kind of visceral.
Rym: You don't have any logical reason to be afraid.
Scott: the same feeling you have when like you're a kid you're afraid of dark There's.
Rym: there's no guy with a gun.
Rym: or even if there is a guy with a gun That's.
Rym: there's a logical fear of that.
Rym: But the the kind of primal there is nothing to actually be afraid of.
Rym: but you are having a physiological reaction.
Rym: your body Feels this certain visceral primal urge to flee That you can't control.
Rym: and even if you can control it and you can still feel it.
Rym: It's there And people feel it to different degrees and everyone has different kind of ways to deal with it, but it's there.
Rym: it's part of being an organism that reacts to stimuli in a solid cystic world and all that stuff, but I feel like very few games ever have consciously tapped that.
Rym: a lot of games have tapped it by accident like I think.
Rym: I do feel that Zelda 1 Tapped it for some reason with Ganon's dungeon in the end, and I don't think it was intentional.
Scott: I think a lot of it definitely It's like I try to figure out why.
Scott: right cuz it's like.
Scott: well if I'm gonna complain about Resident Evil and stuff not being Scary right why was all the one that last dungeon?
Scott: Why was it scary?
Scott: You know what?
Scott: it wasn't just the last dungeon.
Scott: It was that whole northwest corner of the map was scary.
Rym: You know On a good example Zelda to.
Rym: you know keep going along the Zelda's.
Rym: Zelda 2 is a pretty good game And the the hammer plays had this metaphor of fuck.
Scott: the hammer place is pretty scary Yeah, but that was mostly meta.
Rym: It was fuck.
Rym: I have to do this again.
Rym: that took me like four hours Mostly the game.
Scott: as soon as you took the raft over to the other island.
Scott: everything was scary Super scary all the time.
Rym: It was almost like and it wasn't.
Rym: it wasn't strong fear.
Rym: It wasn't the like you drop.
Rym: the controller wasn't.
Scott: it wasn't super strong But it was constantly ever-present, and it was real fear.
Scott: It's the kind of fear that I was looking for.
Scott: that isn't in these other games.
Scott: It should be in but it still.
Rym: it was weak.
Rym: It was a very.
Rym: it was like.
Rym: there's this Something.
Rym: some aspect of the game either by design or by chance touched just briefly just barely Infinitesimally on some factor that causes primal fear and at least some humans Mm-hmm, and I can't think of games very few games that have done that.
Scott: yeah This is not too many But
Rym: I we I've been trying to think about games that caused that feeling even for a second and I realized that almost every case Seems to either have something to do with the uncanny valley like something just isn't quite right or Something is unpredictable in an unexpected way.
Rym: Not not in the unpredictable You know.
Rym: the monster moves in this random pattern that I can't figure out.
Rym: but like if you're playing a game like Castlevania 2 and The game glitches and you end up in just this weird space in the game.
Rym: You can't get out.
Rym: There's this feat there's this slight alien feeling that something's wrong.
Rym: Mm-hmm kind of like how in the uncanny valley where if something's fake enough It doesn't bother you.
Rym: something real enough doesn't bother you if something's almost real almost together But it's just a little bit off.
Rym: It's like humans are like on a hair trigger to feel something is wrong.
Rym: with that as a result.
Scott: Yeah, it's like and I try to think about like, you know these games like.
Scott: what was what was up with them, right?
Scott: and you know The music and Zelda in the last level of Zelda 1 definitely was a Contributor right the fact that the bad guys were really dangerous in The end of Zelda 1 and in the second half of Zelda 2 that was a contributor Primarily
Rym: on meta fear there.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But you know also if you look at Zelda 2 right when you're on that first island think about the bad guys, right?
Scott: You know this their staff losses.
Scott: They look alright, you know Moblins.
Scott: Moblins look just fine, you know little slugs your little slimes that are you know, perfectly rendered, right?
Scott: You go to the other island, right?
Scott: And first of all the grass over there isn't clean shiny grass.
Scott: It's sort of like got all this crap all over it.
Scott: and like the bad guys that you got those guys like those bugs with The extending legs that bounce up and down.
Scott: Yeah, and like they're a little bit sort of shaky Right, and they're sort of pixely and not clearly defined.
Rym: and then like a lot of these those like weird bugs It was kind of come down and move in this really like weird Methodical pattern that didn't fit the way a thing would fly.
Rym: It was.
Rym: there was a lot of uncanny valley kind of stuff going on there.
Scott: Yeah, and then like you look at like some of the map areas It's like the in the second half and it's like it just wasn't as well.
Scott: It's like it felt like someone took real care in like, you know Well doing a really good design and that first half of the game But the second half of the game it feels like a lot of the design isn't so perfect, you know Like for example, is that spirally part in the mountains, right?
Scott: but like one hallway is like three wide and other ones too wide and it's like it just sort of Thrown together a little bit and I think that it's just little things like that things that you don't you know consciously notice It's just you know, it's the kind of thing where someone making a game today, you know If you made one hallway wide and the other ones sort of narrow and it looks sort of broken like that Like it was just sort of it.
Scott: look it looks like someone screwed up doing the art, you know It doesn't look like it's supposed to be that way.
Scott: It's like hey you fucked up fix it, you know.
Scott: But I think that that sort of thing is actually contributes to you know, the real fear I'm sort of like this, you know subconscious level
Rym: I think part of it and I feel strongly about this is the idea that a game that has this sort of consistency and Expectations the world is created and defined and it works around you in some way and like in the first part of Zelda 2 everything is very clean and together and orderly and there's roads between all the places and you get this sort of comfortable feeling.
Rym: you have expectations about what should be and everything is in its place and everything works and Then suddenly you're confronted with a place where that's not true.
Rym: You've been lulled into the sense of security and expectations and then one by one All of those expectations are kind of pulled out from under you.
Scott: Yeah You've got nice safe roads connecting all the town to good examples in Zelda 2 and in Dragon Warrior 1.
Rym: You find eventually a place That should be one way that is very strongly not a town in Zelda 2.
Rym: There is a town that if you go into it, there are no people.
Rym: there are just invisible monsters that kill you Mmm, but up until that point in almost every game you played not in just that game But in all games like that towns were the safe places where you go and save your game.
Rym: It's like if in a Final Fantasy game you go into the end You save your game go to the end save your game.
Rym: One in you go into you go to save your game and there's no one to save your game in that it There's just like a dead guy.
Scott: Let me think it can even be even simpler stuff than that, right?
Scott: I mean think about this right, you know, you're playing say a Mario game, right?
Scott: What colors of Goomba?
Scott: It's it's brown with a white face and blue feet, right?
Scott: Well, you go into it someplace.
Scott: It's like well you got like there's a black Goomba, you know.
Scott: I mean if you portray the black Goomba just you know not as you know.
Scott: cute like it, you know could be but you could Portray that Goomba in such a way, you know, someone comes in.
Scott: It's like oh shit black Goomba.
Rym: No if you just made the Goomba's black in one level that doesn't do it.
Rym: or if you if you build up to the Goomba if you like I think partly it's the unexpected the unexplained and the nonsensical.
Rym: if In one of the places there's just one black Goomba that's like all the other Goombas.
Rym: It just looks different and that's the only one and there's no explanation and you never run into it again.
Rym: that Triggers.
Rym: that's feeling just a little bit.
Scott: Yeah tiny bit just a tiny time Mario You know, it doesn't have the design to do it so well.
Scott: But you know, it's that kind of idea or like.
Rym: I brought this up before too.
Rym: But I remember I read some article about how the key to making Scary bosses or scary monsters in games is to make them be unpredictable in a visceral way or unpredictable in a way That isn't in and of itself predictable.
Scott: that might sound dumb But let me think about pretty much every boss has a pattern every single one.
Scott: I mean what boss doesn't have a.
Rym: they can act randomly, but you sort of start to expect them to go in a certain way.
Scott: But I mean even if they're acting randomly, they're select.
Scott: they're randomly selecting from a set list of moves.
Scott: So, you know what moves they have.
Scott: so it doesn't matter if they choose this move three times and that move two times You know what?
Scott: All the moves are and they give signals as to what move they're about to do which now I'm not saying the game shouldn't be that way because for a game Especially like Castlevania if you don't want a game to be scary don't make it scary.
Rym: Not only that but if you don't make the bosses telegraph their moves then it's basically just like impossible.
Rym: Yeah, as opposed to half reaction half puzzle
Scott: exactly,
Rym: but if you can make it Unpredictable, I think if every now and then things just going away that you can't possibly expect not necessarily just to kill you but just unexpected like if the monster turns away and Regards something else or runs away from you inexplicably or just does something that takes you a back That that's odd that we may not do it in and of itself But I think that's on the road to bringing that feeling out.
Scott: Mmm just doing more things like that, you know things that make you you know feel like, you know, oh shit this You know, I mean you go into like different areas in a game, right?
Scott: It's like, okay.
Scott: This is a different area Okay, now I'm in a different area, right?
Scott: But there's sort of like when you go to that last level and it's all to one it's like there's that this is it Feeling you know, it's like that knowledge that this is it and a lot of games I think don't actually have the this.
Scott: is it because you know, they keep coming on with the square bosses and stuff like that.
Scott: Right because it was like.
Scott: you don't really know when you're at the end of the game.
Rym: Well, you know if you sometimes you do.
Rym: you've already beaten the main boss, you know, there's one more boss That's true.
Scott: But I mean, you know, a lot of games don't do a very good job of being like this is it?
Scott: You know, they don't want to let you know that this is really.
Scott: this part is the end part, you know.
Rym: but then look at like Castlevania to the Right, but like the whole game is kind of consistent up to a point right before the end of the game you get before Dracula's castle.
Rym: there's a town like every other town But the bricks are all gray and you've never seen that before.
Rym: and there's no one in the town No one.
Rym: you go into the church all the buildings No one.
Rym: you find secret passages in some of the houses nothing in them.
Rym: you go all the way down multiple levels Sometimes in the secret passage another secret passage There's just nothing.
Rym: in one of the houses in the secret passage You find one person sitting there by themselves and all they say is please stay with me.
Rym: Yeah, it's kind of creepy.
Rym: so then you leave that town and then next is this bridge and then Dracula's castle and When you go in it plays music, you've never heard before, you know, this is like the Castlevania theme.
Rym: Yeah, and there's nothing there.
Rym: and for five minutes you just walk and walk and walk down and down and down and down.
Rym: There's nothing there and then at the end there's nothing.
Rym: there's just an altar.
Rym: You brought Dracula with you and then you resurrect him in the basement.
Rym: Yeah That again that I'm not gonna try to say that that is scarier than Fatal Frame I don't think it is.
Rym: but what I think it does it's also not a very good game No, but I think that that game because of its glitchiness and just that last bit Also goes down the road of what could be a viscerally scary game.
Scott: I mean, that's another thing is a glitchiness is scary.
Scott: Metroid 1 has a lot of scariness going on just because of its glitchiness, you know and I think that when you make a game Even if you try to make it scary with monsters and zombies and Cthulhu's and ghosts and boo and whatever you got in there Right, if you should make the game glitchy, but even like, you know eternal darkness again with its insanity meter Right appearing to be glitchy It's fake glitchiness and people can tell.
Scott: people can tell when it's real glitchiness and when it's fake glitchiness.
Scott: I don't think you can fake real glitchiness.
Scott: I think you just need to make a glitchy ass game to make it scary and I Have a lot of ideas.
Rym: I feel like we should cut this short.
Rym: We've already got really but I I we came up with we were talking about this.
Rym: I think we have a really good idea for what could be a scary game.
Scott: But yeah, I definitely think one key though is don't polish the games.
Scott: Don't do things that you're supposed to do.
Scott: don't make the graphic design consistent Don't you know.
Scott: don't make the game well-designed, you know.
Scott: Make it a little crappy in a few places because some of the scariest things are the things that leave a few glitches in there That aren't showstoppers that make the game actually break Just don't make sense at all.
Rym: and because things might not make sense from a realistic standpoint But they make sense in the context of the game or even if not in the game in the context of video games.
Rym: But if you have things that don't make sense in any of those contexts, they're just there.
Scott: That's on the road again Mm-hmm, and I feel like just like usually here's an example before we cut this out, right?
Scott: You know, usually, you know, there's the Chekhov's gun scooby-doo type of thing, right?
Scott: You know, we're like, you know They'll put some some sort of graphic that you haven't seen anywhere else and it stands out from the background.
Scott: So obviously it's supposed to do something or it's special in some way.
Scott: But I mean some a lot of games a lot of NES games in certain places.
Scott: They would have things like that But they wouldn't do anything.
Scott: They would just be there.
Scott: But then and you'd sit there trying to play with it or whatever and like depending on the game though It might sort of freak you out.
Scott: Like you think it might do something Yeah,
Rym: but then like look at a lot of the scary games now where you walk by the window and you just you know Something's gonna jump through the window exactly, but then they switch it up and something jumps from behind the window.
Rym: But I guess in closing that the best thing I think you could do to make a scary game that I've never seen anyone really do is One have everything be well-lit and not scary Completely, you know normal well-lit defined.
Rym: not you know resident evilly or eternal darkness not dark gray and brown.
Rym: but to You have to engender this false sense of security this false set of expectations this false set of like this false context for the world and Establish all these norms and guidelines and rules to where the person like things make sense in the game and then one by one After after a while you have to start pulling the rug out from under each and every one of these expectations and video games can do this more so than a lot of other ways to scare people because The person you know as a human you're looking at a 3d world say it's a first-person view game.
Rym: You have all these expectations and Metacontacts that you're bringing with you because you live in a 3d world and you see it in the first person.
Rym: you expect things to work in a certain way.
Rym: you could make a House a small house that is actually non-euclidean in a video game that you make four left And you don't end up where you started again, but yet it doesn't look like you did anything weird.
Scott: Yeah, I mean you know.
Scott: think about say Resident Evil 1 right and Resident Evil 1.
Scott: You know every door goes to where you think it goes.
Scott: you know I mean you have a map.
Scott: the map is correct.
Scott: What if like you went in a door and you just ended up in some other room and then you went back through the door You ended up some other room that thought not the one you came from and you just like what the fuck?
Scott: Yep, but you know and that thing is okay.
Scott: if you do it all the time Then people are just like oh well You know I guess every door just takes me someplace random whatever What if you just did it once did it like once and if you go back through the door it never happens again?
Scott: Yep, ever and you just and you do things a whole bunch of different things once each.
Scott: But even then because in general the game is still playable right because it's just these weird things only happen once each.
Scott: But as a whole those things combine to make the player very uneasy psychologically, but even then there's the jarring disconnect.
Rym: video game wise video game context when you go through a door.
Rym: going through a door is Contextualized in video games as the expectation that there could be a teleportation that you're moving to a different zone That you're not in this one contiguous three-dimensional space.
Rym: in a first-person continuous game without loading screens You could do this within the same room as in.
Rym: I look to the right I see you know a fireplace with a mantle over it and a portrait and like some candles on the On the mantle and I kind of look away and I'll do something else and I look back in the course of doing my other thing and One of the candles is missing or it's lit or the portrait slightly different not obvious things just subtle disconnection subtle Decontextualization subtle things that break your expectations, but otherwise have no effect or that Maybe we'll have an effect later like you'll like.
Rym: maybe the portrait changed and you don't realize it.
Rym: later in the game Something happens that make you realize way back that the portrait change.
Scott: Well, how about this?
Scott: right you walk into a room, right?
Scott: It's a square room.
Scott: You're facing north right on the north wall.
Scott: You see the fireplace, right?
Scott: You turn to face the east wall.
Scott: There's a door.
Scott: you turn to face the north wall.
Scott: you turn to face the west wall.
Scott: There's a fireplace.
Scott: the fireplace moves from the north wall to the west wall.
Scott: You can make and then the fireplace just remains on the west wall forever.
Scott: So it's like was I really look what and you can.
Rym: you can make.
Scott: the fireplace forever is now on the west wall.
Scott: It never moves back to the north wall.
Rym: I mean things can be continuously and subtly Disconcerting you.
Rym: you can turn 90 degrees to the left, but that 90-degree turn takes a hundred and twenty degrees worth of turning.
Scott: Oh, you could do that.
Rym: You can do all sorts of things.
Rym: Mmm, and I just I. We've got a lot more to say.
Rym: we'll have to cut it short.
Rym: We will talk about this topic again?
Scott: I don't think we will.
Rym: well not not the overall.
Rym: We're not gonna do another show spooky games But we'll probably do more specific shows about some of the things we talked about.
Rym: maybe I think we will.
Rym: I will.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com Where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our proper map and links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: We say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm Or you can send audio feedback via audio.
Scott: Just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it.
Scott: As long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.