Scott:
Rym: It's Thursday January 29th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We are addicted to the night.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: So I walk out the door this morning right and I close it and I go oh shit Cuz.
Scott: I thought for a second that I'd left my keys on the other side of said closed door.
Rym: That would have been the worst because you can't get back in to get him, but you can't get in the car.
Scott: Yeah, I'd basically be uh-oh.
Scott: I can't do anything.
Rym: What do you do?
Scott: It's like if I could at least get in the car.
Scott: Well, you know I could just drive to the train station go to work come back come home And by the time I get home, I'll just come home late and I know someone will be here the key.
Scott: But well, you could just walk to the train station I guess but it was too late and it was cold.
Rym: Yeah, it is cold.
Scott: I wasn't gonna happen.
Scott: so I Luckily, I just left the keys in a different pocket and I had them But it was uh, it was worrying for about 10 seconds.
Rym: It's one thing why I always kind of be sure whenever I go outside from my house that I am prepared to deal with Any situation that involves me not being able to get back.
Scott: I had my phone So, but who are you gonna call?
Rym: I'm at work.
Rym: Emily and Alex are at work.
Scott: I could have called somebody Called the landlord.
Rym: I guess yeah someone like I locked myself out the locksmith.
Rym: Huh now the problem would be if you had left your wallet and keys inside because then you can't even take the train.
Rym: You can't prove to the locksmith who you are.
Scott: I could have looked on Google Maps or whatever and gotten a taxicab to the train station.
Rym: How are you gonna pay for that with my wallet?
Rym: What if you don't have your wallet?
Rym: Well, I did.
Scott: I'm saying what if I'm talking about only keys?
Rym: what if you forget wallet and keys?
Rym: then you're fucked.
Scott: Oh, it's a pay him with cell phone.
Rym: What if you also forget cell phone?
Rym: just remember that.
Scott: how would I couldn't pay the cab I couldn't get the cab No wallet.
Rym: You got no ID.
Rym: Plus now you got to worry about what do I do before I freeze to death.
Scott: I Would just find a friendly neighbor with the telephone walk to like the car dealership.
Scott: Can I stand inside for the gas station pick up a quarter off the ground?
Rym: Use the pay phone quarters not enough and I don't think that pay phone works.
Scott: I'm pretty sure pay phones take quarters.
Rym: well, the last time I collect I used a pay phone two years ago when I was in New York and my cell phone battery died and I luckily Somehow remembered the phone number that I had to call Numbers either.
Rym: so I tried to call this cell phone number and then I discovered that It would have been I think 40. it would have been 40 cents or 50 cents to make a local call But because it was a cell phone it wasn't actually a local call so I was screwed anyway.
Rym: So I had to use my credit card Through the pay phone to make a call.
Scott: Did that work?
Scott: Yeah, that's not too bad.
Rym: I had to call and then it was like You know credit card number and had a type of credit card number in and I paid like five bucks.
Scott: I'll just push zero and be like if I could make it happen.
Scott: Collect if possible collect.
Rym: Yeah Well, you know when I was a kid and I would I you know before I had a cell phone that I could use all The time because the family had two cell phones.
Rym: So often I wasn't the one who got to have the cell phone.
Rym: It's like high school.
Scott: Well, yeah, whenever I was like in middle school in high school on a field trip or something like that I would always call home collect.
Scott: Oh my I called home collect from like Israel.
Scott: It was like yeah Take that either.
Rym: my parents would give me the cell phone unless they gave it to my brother.
Rym: They were using it.
Rym: But we realized I didn't need it because I used to go to the community college to take classes like after school.
Rym: Like I'd go take chemistry and stoichiometry and jazz band and stuff.
Rym: So when I needed a ride home whenever class ended what I would do is collect call home and they would get.
Rym: They would be asked if they wanted a call from pick-me-up.
Scott: And you said they say no, I don't want to because they'd come pick me up.
Rym: Yep Except that one time.
Rym: I I fell asleep in class.
Rym: It was a night class here.
Rym: So I go to high school and I come home and then at like eight o'clock, I'd go to this class.
Rym: They'd ended it like 1030.
Rym: I just fell asleep in class and no one said anything.
Scott: So you're just sleeping in this classroom.
Rym: I woke up alone with the lights off in this classroom But I didn't know what time it was and I wasn't sure where I was for a few minutes.
Scott: Is this was this building closed?
Rym: Well, the building was open.
Rym: there were classes until like midnight But the hallways were all kind of dark and for a while.
Scott: How long would you have stayed in there without not doing anything?
Scott: I
Rym: don't know if I if I hadn't woken I woke up at like 11 So I dealt with
Scott: what if you had not woken up until say like, you know The next day when it was time to go to school again, uh, well
Rym: one I would have just skipped school.
Scott: well, obviously, but you know what like Who?
Scott: would anyone like a security guard have found you?
Rym: or maybe the janitor would have found me?
Scott: Maybe if there was a janitor that day, maybe I would clean the classrooms every day.
Rym: Maybe I would have gotten woken up by the like the 8 a.m Class the next day and then I would have gone.
Rym: Oh, well, I'm a couple hours late for high school might as well not go.
Rym: Yeah, I'll hang out here all day.
Rym: Yeah, that was before I could drive legally so I was still like I needed rides everywhere and it sucked.
Scott: yeah those days Those are not good days.
Rym: Yeah, it's weird to think that there was a time when I could not drive.
Scott: Yeah, there was a time when I could.
Scott: well I guess if I had been allowed to I could have driven but I totally could have Driven as yes when I like as soon as I was tall enough to reach the pedals and also see.
Rym: well It's like an RIT when my car got repoed that one time or when I was living here working at IBM and my car broke And it took him a week to fix it.
Rym: Those times like I take cars for granted and suddenly the simplest of tasks were impossible.
Rym: It was like alright, I'm hungry.
Rym: How do I get food?
Rym: There is no way to get to the grocery store.
Rym: I tried to call a cab and they're like the cabs not gonna take me to the grocery store there.
Scott: I mean there are plenty of people I've seen.
Scott: take cabs.
Rym: the girl depends on where you live.
Rym: No cab was gonna drive me from that house on the top of the mountain down to town to the house of the mountain.
Rym: Yeah Now when I lived in Poughkeepsie, I could walk like 45 minutes and get to a grocery store.
Scott: Yeah, you should have done.
Scott: you should got an airport cab.
Scott: they'll take you to the airport fly to JFK right take the subway into the city and then get a hotel which you realize it's only 50 bucks to take a Helicopter from Midtown to JFK.
Scott: Is it $50 $50?
Scott: I found also it's like 45 to take it to LaGuardia.
Scott: Oh $50 per person, even if it's just one person probably.
Scott: or is there a number of people that you need for the trip?
Rym: I think it's perfect.
Rym: I did not look.
Rym: where does the helicopter leave from?
Rym: like 34th Street?
Scott: I'm so doing that.
Rym: I know seriously.
Rym: It's not that much more money than like the shuttle or the car service I'd take anyway, the shuttles like 20 bucks.
Scott: The helicopter is no traffic.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: No fun helicopter ride.
Scott: Yeah, so why the fuck does I found out about this?
Rym: some guy works like Well, you know what?
Rym: I just found out and the guy next to him was like what he's like.
Rym: you can take a helicopter to JFK for like 50 bucks for Midtown.
Rym: They had the same conversation.
Rym: We're having now the set.
Scott: the next time I had to go to JFK Helicopter for reals.
Scott: Oh, man.
Rym: Alright, so it's Thursday, you know, we're kind of right.
Scott: I bet it's loud though You're probably gonna bring the headphones.
Rym: Yeah, helicopters are loud.
Scott: I mean, I guess you know, it's a good question though.
Scott: It could be right It's probably one of those little glass bubble helicopters, you know, like the traffic, right?
Scott: But it could be like a big two-roader like military hospital helicopter.
Scott: They're not gonna send you in a Chinook No They could if they cuz think about it for 50 bucks.
Scott: right that thing can make the trip real quick.
Scott: right and Think about how many people you can get in there, right?
Scott: The little tiny helicopter you get what.
Scott: maybe three people in there with the luggage Right the big one you get like a bus worth of people in there, right.
Scott: so $50 times a bus That's pretty good money.
Scott: It makes it worth it, you know, so maybe it is a big-ass helicopter But they kind that you know people jump out of.
Rym: I imagine it would be loud though because I took a.
Scott: yeah It's loud.
Rym: I like when I flew down to a Columbia In near DC for that business trip because I because of the time and when I flew I ended up taking a prop plane Both ways.
Scott: Oh, I guess this helicopter takes off from the top of a building, right?
Rym: I have no idea.
Scott: So I guess you had to go to the building and get to the top and then where do you buy the ticket?
Scott: And what's the schedule?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I found like I found out about this now.
Rym: It was like oh, man The next time I fly like the first thing I'm gonna do and then where does it land?
Scott: at JFK?
Scott: How do I get from the helicopter to the airplane?
Rym: Like I said, I didn't sort all this business out.
Rym: All I can think is 50 bucks.
Rym: That's probably worth it.
Rym: Yeah, probably Especially considering how long that bus took to get there.
Scott: Well, cuz I had to go and you know is in rush hour right going down like the Grand Central Parkway Like the Queen's Midtown Tunnel, it's you know, it's traffic there.
Scott: But anyway, that's mood sailing.
Rym: it is Thursday You know hanging loose nice and nice and relaxed here.
Rym: We can do it everyone and I got to bring this up.
Rym: it's kind of a almost a Tuesday news, but and we don't even really need to do news, but a Story about some doll and some crazy woman said that Apparently the doll would periodically say Islam is the light.
Rym: What yeah, and the news reported this like it was a big deal.
Rym: It was all over the place secret messages and toys.
Rym: Islam is the light.
Rym: Did you hear it?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: and I heard it and it sounded like you're gaga gaga buh-gah.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, you know, it's sort of like seeing Jesus in the bread, right?
Scott: If you just make enough random noises, you know, someone's gonna hear.
Scott: you know something in.
Scott: it's like playing records backwards.
Scott: Someone's gonna hear Satan something and sometimes someone will do it on purpose.
Scott: And it's like looking at static on the TV screen.
Scott: You're gonna see a face Cuz you know or you're gonna look at the clouds and you'll see a dragon.
Scott: It's how it happens, you know.
Rym: But anyway that that's not the story that sort of thing happens all the time and the fact that the media Always kind of makes a big deal about it Especially the local news the like local interest.
Scott: you called the news station.
Scott: the next time I see a cloud that looks like a penis or something.
Scott: And now they'll put a news story like local pranksters make cloud penis-shaped cloud.
Rym: But I saw this story where Someone else apparently found that in some Nintendo game.
Rym: It also says Islam is the light.
Scott: was it a gay?
Scott: Did it actually say it in text?
Rym: No, no, so here I looked into this a little bit.
Rym: I did a small bit of investigative reporting.
Rym: fact number one.
Rym: It is in fact the same crazy lady.
Rym: Number two It's the same sound clip like I listened to it and I went to the old one.
Rym: It is the exact same Baba Guga like it's identical.
Rym: you listen to him.
Rym: It is clearly both of these.
Rym: toys took the audio.
Scott: So a Nintendo game and a doll have the same exact audio clip in them.
Rym: Yes Well fact number three, you know what game it is.
Rym: Oh, you know the pets franchise.
Rym: Yeah, the like dogs and cats.
Scott: Oh, yes games.
Scott: I think you're talking about an NES game.
Rym: No, no DS game.
Rym: I just said, okay, okay, so Apparently as far as I can tell there is a knockoff of those and there's a game called baby pals with an S Not a Z. Whoa and That is that alone is one of the saddest things I've ever heard.
Rym: But yes this game and that doll Used they might have been they use the same like stock baby going but goo goo gah.
Rym: that According to one crazy lady sounds like Islam is the light.
Scott: They got giga.
Rym: Gah gah gizel.
Rym: Islam is the light.
Scott: Nothing, baby says sounds like Islam is the light.
Rym: So this woman is crazy.
Rym: Obviously the reporters for this story are even not easier.
Rym: not quote quote quote quote.
Rym: This is a quote.
Rym: This is verbatim from the video Nintendo's Manufactured by a third party, so they're not responsible for the content.
Rym: But the game's packaging clearly states that the game is licensed by Nintendo.
Rym: People don't understand how this works.
Scott: Oh Oh, you're the reporters don't understand what licensed by Nintendo means.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: I thought you were saying like Nintendo is stupid.
Scott: I was like, wait a minute.
Rym: No, no, no, no, no and quote the woman not just my daughter's toys But we have a son too.
Rym: now I feel like I have to listen to all his little toys to make sure they're not saying it.
Scott: What first of all, right?
Scott: Okay Obviously, you're crazy.
Scott: The toys are not saying it.
Scott: But if they were so what?
Rym: So what I mean?
Rym: cuz this is what bothers me.
Rym: this article and the article from before Beg the question.
Rym: They the question that is begged is that how come this is bad.
Scott: even if it said it Would it be better or worse if it said Jesus is awesome Yeah, all right, and even if it was saying it right did these kids say hey, mommy My toy said Islam is the light.
Scott: know that kids just hear gaga gaga guy It's only the mom who hears it.
Rym: Actually.
Rym: The mom says that the kid brought it to her attention.
Rym: I think it's because he has.
Scott: it could be wasn't at that kid?
Scott: if the kid wasn't raised by the crazy mom The kid wouldn't have thought of that.
Rym: you look at the woman.
Rym: She she's almost crazy eyes.
Rym: She's not quite but she she's like.
Scott: I bet she'd be indignant.
Scott: She is in a situation, but she's very slight Huh?
Rym: And it it's not that often you find a very slight person who is also the ultra indignant.
Rym: It is usually the big fat one But I don't know.
Rym: but all these facts that I discovered about this I linked you an article that she had a stomach surgery.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I found this funny.
Rym: But anyway things of the day nice and quick.
Rym: This is pretty cool.
Rym: It is a XLR camera not XLR SLR.
Rym: yeah, I got microphones on the mind But no the the important thing is that it is cut in half and you can see the insides and it's pretty cool.
Scott: Yeah, knowing how it works will help you a little bit.
Scott: But you know what you still won't know how to use it.
Rym: nah, actually Emily is currently borrowing her mom's super fancy digital digital SLR and It's pretty cool.
Scott: It is very cool.
Rym: It's also not easy to use Yes, but once you learn like you start your pictures look a lot better.
Rym: No kidding But I point out that there are one two, three, four, five six seven eight nine Lenses inside.
Scott: Well, usually right there's this stuff on the inside But then there's also.
Scott: you screw a lens on to the front of it, right?
Scott: So they just cut it the camera in half or do they also, you know, I also have a front bit attached.
Scott: Okay, see you so there's a lens on the front.
Scott: The lens is not actually the camera.
Rym: the lens Yeah, there's the front one, two, three, four five lenses.
Rym: Then there's a middle lens that moves and then there's one two, three, four five more lenses and then there's three more lenses.
Rym: Yep, it's pretty cool.
Scott: Yeah, that's that's how it works thing of the day.
Rym: It's cool.
Scott: cuz I mean think about it right to do all that Right.
Scott: I mean, you know, you always need the moving lens right to sort of be able to adjust the focal length and whatnot.
Scott: right, but Think about how precise and perfect you're like the one lens would have to be that would just do like the work of all The front five, you know, this is why the lenses cost thousands of dollars And the cameras also cost hundreds of dollars,
Rym: yeah, at least we don't need any spider silk in there anymore.
Scott: We used to need spider silk for telescopes.
Rym: Mostly actually they used to use silk to make telescope.
Rym: It's completely different to make but to make the crosshairs for or precision Instruments or scientific cameras do.
Rym: if you need had a crosshair or anything to aim precisely they would use spider silk.
Rym: Ah That's clever clever girl.
Scott: they use it on like scopes on guns and things also, I don't know I'm not really an expert on this sort of thing Alright, so I was gonna use this on another day, but I got nothing.
Scott: so check this side out.
Scott: it's called Miffy's I think and What they did is they wet and they found fonts from video games and they made them and that's pretty much it.
Scott: so if you want to type in double dragon ease or You know, I guess Gradius ease or Donkey Kong, you know made of you know, metal I beams font then This site's got like a whole bunch of them.
Scott: So if you're doing like a video game remix parody or something These could be real useful.
Scott: or maybe you're making like a fan site or you know anything along those lines.
Rym: So, okay over the weekend, you know We had the crew together and we played our burning wheel and we played the little engine that could kill.
Rym: We talked about that.
Rym: We also did something good over the weekend as opposed to that bad game that we'll never talk about again.
Rym: It's okay I thought it was pretty good.
Rym: I enjoyed it.
Rym: Uh, we watch Sorry for the edit.
Rym: there Scott's up Ellen and he kind of blew his nose all over what I was saying.
Scott: I'm not Ellen.
Scott: I just had my.
Scott: I'm done it.
Scott: I'm done ailing.
Scott: I'm just Expulsing.
Rym: but So Scott who never gets sick except when he gets sick is sick.
Scott: I was sick and now I am just Expelling snots.
Rym: so you're not sick.
Rym: You're just expelling tons and tons of mucus.
Scott: Yeah that you know, it was from when I was sick and now that's not how that works.
Rym: Yeah, it is now It's not.
Rym: it is anyway What we did that was good over this weekend.
Rym: was we finally watched repo the genetic opera?
Scott: Well, not finally me we weren't.
Rym: it was like a long period of time between me from the moment when I knew this existed Until that time it was too late.
Rym: I had wanted to say it.
Rym: I was excited about it.
Scott: I was a little I was interested but I wasn't excited.
Rym: I love this sort of thing.
Scott: I'm okay with this sort of thing.
Rym: You know It's good If you didn't see the forum thread or you live under a rock repo.
Rym: the genetic opera is the story of a horrible future Where suddenly everyone has organ failure?
Scott: Yeah, basically what hat?
Scott: I'll summarize the plot, right?
Scott: Someone in you know, wait, wait, wait.
Rym: now if we're gonna summarize we can summarize it much more succinctly than you were about to do.
Rym: It is a future where organs can be repossessed much like cars.
Scott: Yep, people buy organs, you know to prevent themselves from dying, but they also buy organs.
Scott: you know because they want, you know for vanity reasons and They're very expensive.
Scott: so rich people are are just living it up but poor people are Buying them anyway, and then if I
Rym: like this you finance the secondhand liver But then you know your fall behind on the payments The repo man comes and cuts it out
Scott: and then you just fall over and you have no liver.
Scott: and I've been bleeding everywhere.
Rym: Yeah, and it's basically.
Rym: it's not that gory.
Rym: It's a lot less gory than you might think but the gore is really like cheesy Movie gore.
Rym: it's not that much of it.
Rym: It's primarily singing.
Scott: well pseudo singing yeah, well, I mean there's not that much compared to each of the killer but there's it's in there as I think my favorite one is the repo.
Rym: man is kind of singing to himself while he's repossessing from a guy and Toward the end of the song as he's ripping the guts out.
Rym: He kind of sticks his hand up the guy's abdomen and Manipulates him like a puppet to sing close harmony.
Rym: It's just the way it's done is because it he's doing it.
Rym: then he kind of looks at the thing and then he kind of like Realizes what he's doing and kind of pulls his hand out like huh?
Rym: Okay enough of that.
Rym: Back to work.
Rym: Yeah But it's an opera like.
Rym: it's an opera in almost the truest sense but it's just about organs being repossessed and it's Pete said it best this is if nothing else Over the top in every way that something can be over the top.
Rym: It is.
Scott: I think you could be more over the top, but it wouldn't be very easy.
Rym: well, I think it's more that every individual aspect of repo the genetic opera is Over the top.
Rym: to a degree it is like the singing is just Silly.
Rym: it gets to the point where the the businessman semi bad guys in the limo with a girl and he's basically Singing the plot at her In a scene where it almost looks like she's surprised that he is singing.
Rym: Mm-hmm Yeah, he's like.
Rym: this is the plot.
Rym: I am singing the plot to you.
Rym: What?
Rym: Yes the plot.
Rym: This is the plot.
Rym: Here we go the plot.
Scott: Sometimes it gets like a little bit corny and in the singing, you know Because he'll be saying things you already know.
Scott: But it's like they just need something to sing and it needs some words that both say something and you know They they had to sing them.
Scott: so they'll just sort of like sing for the sake of singing and just they'll be.
Scott: basically it feels like the characters are like It.
Scott: sometimes it almost feels like they're making it up as they go along.
Scott: Just try to get any word they can Fit in.
Rym: Yeah, I guess what I would say is that this is repo.
Rym: I Recommend you all.
Rym: see it.
Rym: If you're listening to GeekNights, you will glean some enjoyment from this.
Scott: I guarantee It's not gonna be your favorite thing ever.
Scott: I don't think but it's not bad.
Rym: It's got a chance of being your favorite thing ever - I guess.
Scott: yeah There are certain people for whom this will be their favorite thing ever
Rym: because it's kind of silly and kind of gory and There are a few really really good songs in here, of course, I'll admit While the this the set pieces I guess or while what's going on is kind of cheesy.
Rym: It's an opera not a musical and a lot of the songs are not memorable like they're interesting to watch.
Scott: Yeah It's like usually when you have a musical right you get some show tunes and the show tunes are like Memorable and they are fucking stuck in your head like that Seinfeld.
Rym: George comes back.
Rym: He's like a master of the house.
Scott: Exactly, I mean, that's a fucking song right?
Scott: This doesn't really have any song.
Rym: I can't even read.
Rym: lifelong shit the only little brain regular Voltaire thinks he's quite a lover.
Rym: But there's not much of that God.
Rym: I think I remember.
Scott: I don't remember all the words.
Scott: I remember all that the tune.
Rym: really.
Rym: I think I remember all the words to all the songs of Les Mis as I go.
Rym: Yes, I do.
Rym: I know them all.
Scott: I know much of the words.
Rym: I know the whole thing.
Scott: Not all of it.
Scott: Anyway, the Right, the only song that you can really that I really remember from this thing tonight.
Scott: Yeah, is that one because that's the it's sort of like they do that one like a few times, you know.
Scott: So like the recur the what's it called?
Rym: The it's not a leitmotif because that's all the character.
Rym: It's the What though I forget.
Scott: but they you know, they do it like, you know It's the one that they play when they come in and then they do it for real somewhere in the middle And then they sort of do a little bit the I think part of it.
Rym: Just that that song is over here.
Scott: Maybe is that what that is?
Rym: No, that's not the overtures.
Rym: Yeah, the overtures what they play but the overtures what plays when the curtains are still closed at an opera.
Rym: Yeah, go in but then usually like, you know how like you'll um, I Come on on the curtains that are closed and then if it's a Wagner opera You've got about four hours of him masturbating all over you before the actual opera begins.
Rym: That is the overture.
Scott: But see usually like, you know There's like a theme in the overture and then they sort of like it's not attached to a character like leitmotif is it's just they Sort of play it, you know throughout as like a some sort of theme?
Rym: Maybe I guess is it just a theme a musical theme perhaps a recurring theme of some kind.
Scott: Yes But anyway, I was looking for a more fancy word than that.
Rym: That song is the musical song I would say because yeah You will it'll be in your head and every time someone says a phrase that fits lyrically or rhythmically into Any part of that song the whole song is gonna come out.
Rym: Could you hand me that bottle the little blue bottle the little blue bottle?
Rym: And.
Rym: but otherwise a lot of the songs are not Memorable at all.
Rym: They're really fun.
Scott: and I want to point out It's like there are some songs in there and I remember there was a song there.
Scott: It was sort of fun.
Scott: It was.
Scott: maybe some of the lyrics were corny But the song itself was.
Scott: it seems like you know, what happens is like here's a good example, right?
Scott: Look at something like Oh Detroit Metal City, right They basically when they did Detroit the music in the Detroit Metal City anime They took the lyrics from the manga right and then they made Songs that sort of matched those lyrics.
Scott: So the result is that the actual words they were saying were Funny words that were written right but the music didn't always go with those words.
Scott: So well, so the result is that the music was slightly not so great.
Scott: A lot of it would be kind of like if GeekNights sounded like this all the time in Repo, they did the opposite right which is that they said, all right, let's make good music.
Scott: All right, here's the tune You know dead in it and in it, you know, they would come up with a song and they'd be like, okay Somehow make the lyrics fit this song and it's like.
Rym: but even then I'll admit I really enjoyed this.
Rym: but the songs Were not that good.
Rym: They were more.
Rym: Kate said they were set pieces.
Rym: They were not songs.
Scott: yeah, it's like.
Rym: the few songs there were were like there's.
Rym: there's a point and I really enjoyed this even though it had almost nothing to do with Anything but the.
Rym: it suddenly cuts to the the girl singing the song 17 Yeah, and like suddenly nothing to do with anything.
Rym: suddenly It's a music video.
Rym: and like the stuffed animals in the background like dancing and skeletons.
Scott: dancing And the skeleton was pretty good.
Rym: Jonah Jett makes a cameo.
Scott: It's not Jonah Jett.
Scott: It's Joan Jett.
Rym: Anyway, she makes a cameo.
Rym: Sarah Brightman and Ferris Hilton by the way are also in this along with a man named ogre Really?
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Rym: Sarah Brightman plays blind mag which is interesting if you because she's basically playing Sarah Brightman except the line a Little especially if you've heard her a dive album.
Rym: Yeah If you've never heard Sarah Brightman's dive album, I suggest you seek it out If you want to that.
Rym: I feel your seed raining down on me.
Rym: could this be my once-in-a-lifetime?
Rym: I like Sarah Brightman.
Rym: I've always been a fan.
Scott: you like any sort of diva ish lady.
Rym: Yeah, I kind of do.
Rym: I mean how to do?
Scott: I mean you put you like, you know fifth element.
Scott: You like the blue lady.
Rym: Well, you know what?
Rym: I do like opera.
Scott: I also like Musicals, I like those too, but not all of them.
Rym: Scott name an opera One.
Rym: just name one off the top of your head one Romeo and Juliet's an opera.
Rym: Yes, there technically is an opera Romeo and Juliet.
Rym: Have you seen it?
Scott: Yeah, I did it.
Rym: Can you name another opera?
Scott: Um Yeah, what was that one that was playing at the?
Scott: the thing that we wanted to see the magic loot the marriage of Figaro Barbara of Seville.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: There you go.
Rym: Okay, I Like those two kinds of things but This is this is not a musical.
Rym: This is an opera.
Rym: I mean, honestly if you're looking for good music or like I would say that dr Horrible was better produced and better music than this.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I didn't see it.
Rym: You probably should die.
Rym: It's really good.
Rym: I really really enjoyed it.
Scott: horrible.
Rym: It's awesome.
Scott: I think it's horrible.
Scott: It's In fact, I can guarantee that it's horrible.
Rym: Actually.
Rym: I can't believe you haven't seen it.
Rym: You really should see it.
Rym: I think you would like it.
Rym: It's up your alley.
Rym: It's funny.
Rym: It's just a short musical.
Rym: Yeah It's really short - you can watch the whole thing in like half-hour.
Scott: I got stuff to do.
Rym: Stuff you have to do.
Rym: I can spend like an hour and a half on a repo.
Rym: You can't watch a 30-minute musical.
Scott: Yeah, I'm watching captain Harlock.
Rym: Oh, so you given up on a hookah tono Ken.
Scott: Yeah, I gave up Little repetitive but a little bit I Don't know.
Rym: I we all watch this.
Rym: the front row crew watched this as a group and it was enjoyed by all.
Rym: no one said I didn't like this or that was not worth my time.
Scott: It's a good six and a half or seven out of ten somewhere in there.
Rym: I would say it's maybe seven and a half funnier than it is good.
Rym: Like it is.
Rym: Yeah entertaining this.
Rym: It's interesting.
Rym: It is unique.
Scott: really what it has is the style of.
Scott: it is awesome.
Scott: It's like if someone just made a movie in that style, that was just a normal movie.
Scott: Actually, I sort of almost feel like if they would have just made you know a movie about the repo man.
Scott: That was just a normal movie not a musical or an opera.
Scott: It would have been like eight or nine out of ten.
Rym: It would have had to be a comedy or a dark comedy primarily.
Scott: definitely definitely.
Rym: But I'm just saying just had it been a musical.
Rym: I think it also could have been good.
Scott: Oh, yeah, that could have helped too.
Rym: And I but at the same time I really did like it for what it was because What it was like it I don't know the mediocrity of the production in many aspects and the fact that the music was kind of bland.
Rym: I don't know kind of works for what it was.
Rym: It made it feel low-budget.
Scott: Yeah, it's sort of a charming like.
Rym: It's like almost like charming is the word you're trying to.
Scott: it's like you're trying to make a cult classic on purpose.
Scott: It's like, you know something like Rocky hard cannot just you can't do that on purpose?
Rym: Yes, like they tried Transylvania 69,000 anyone.
Rym: that movies terrible exactly, right?
Scott: It's like you can't do that on purpose.
Scott: It just happens, you know cult classics happen, right?
Scott: This is like someone's trying to make a cult classic and they didn't succeed in making a cult classic.
Scott: It's not but they succeeded at something else Which wasn't?
Scott: you know poop?
Scott: But yeah, it was also not platinum.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: what else we have here was perhaps silver?
Rym: Well kind of cut this short cuz Scott's a sniffling a little bit and I'm kind of hungry and it's a Thursday, but don't worry Websites coming along.
Rym: We're gonna have a lot of stuff from the New York Comic Con and Yeah, that's it.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know kind of kind of peter it out here.
Scott: All right, whatever Go to bed early good.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at www.frontroadcrew.com where you'll find show notes links our awesome forum a link to our frapper map and Links to all the RSS feeds.
Rym: we say feeds plural because GeekNights airs four nights a week covering four different Brands of geekery.
Rym: Mondays are science and technology Tuesdays.
Rym: We have video games board games and RPGs.
Rym: Wednesdays are anime manga comic nights and Thursdays are the catch-alls for various rants and tomfoolery.
Scott: You can send us feedback by email to GeekNights at front row crew comm or you can send audio feedback via Audio, just click the link that says send me an audio on the right side of our website If you like what you hear.
Rym: you can catch the last 100 episodes in iTunes or in your favorite podcatcher.
Rym: for the complete archives visit the website which has everything.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution non-commercial share alike 2.5 license.
Scott: This means you can do whatever you want with it as long as you give us credit don't make money and share it in kind.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.