Rym: It's Thursday, February 4th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight's The Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy.
Rym: in case you somehow haven't already read it.
Rym: Hopefully you did read it because it's the book club book.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Scott, I'm really impressed.
Rym: Not five seconds before we start recording you burped and farted simultaneously.
Scott: That was not a simultaneous burp and fart.
Scott: There was one after the other.
Rym: There was definitely, in the very least, a sort of crossfade between the two.
Scott: Crossfade, perhaps.
Scott: But that could have just been due to the delay of the sound traveling across the room to your ears.
Rym: As opposed to the speed of light of me seeing it.
Scott: You know, you didn't see either one.
Scott: You only heard and perhaps smelled, but you know, the speed of smell is way slower.
Rym: Now you tend to make very obvious physical movements when you fart.
Rym: It's kind of like you build up to it a little bit.
Rym: Like you clench your fist just a tiny bit and you kind of just shoot it right out there like BAM.
Scott: Well, it builds up very quickly because I have a gaseous problem.
Scott: I need to go to a doctor.
Scott: He'll probably just say you have gas.
Scott: What the hell?
Scott: See, at least I can save mine up.
Scott: And be not helpful in any way.
Rym: Like if it starts building and I feel it in there, I can wait a while before I let it out.
Rym: Mine builds up basically from nothing to a whole lot and it basically instantly, you know, often I'll walk into someone else's office and just kind of leave it there and then go somewhere else just because I don't want to deal with it.
Scott: Like basically it builds up as fast as I can inflate a balloon with my lungs like well.
Rym: Well, that depends on how fast you can inflate a balloon very quickly.
Rym: But I do have to issue a brief retraction from yesterday's show or not?
Rym: yesterday's two days ago.
Scott: Rym sucks.
Rym: Yep, so I said that Emily did not know a lot about paranoia, the setting.
Rym: She had actually not that long ago, because we talk about paranoia more often than you'd think, researched all about the setting because she thought it was cool.
Scott: So she didn't research it in preparation to play in a game she knew she was gonna play and she didn't know she was gonna play or what?
Rym: She researched it long before the recess.
Rym: She just knew quite a bit about the system, but she did not grock it, I guess.
Scott: Well, I have the book and people, you know, can read the book.
Scott: I have it.
Rym: Yeah, I still- we had to get a bunch of copies of just like the red part of that book.
Scott: Yeah, that's the thing.
Scott: You gotta get the red book.
Scott: You can't, you know, for the players.
Rym: Even though it was still weird to play the game at blue.
Scott: That is very weird.
Scott: I definitely want to play it for serious starting at the low.
Rym: Wait, wait, wait.
Rym: Play it for serious or play it serious?
Rym: For serious.
Scott: Serious for serious.
Rym: Oh, man, that- not many people have done that.
Scott: The dystopian version.
Scott: No silliness, no soda.
Scott: You know, it's actually- So basically Logan's run.
Scott: Yes, I want to play Logan's run.
Scott: For real.
Rym: So, uh, let's just get right into it.
Rym: It's Thursday.
Rym: We're lazy.
Rym: Go skiing this weekend.
Scott: Do you want to do news and thing of the day or just want to do the show?
Rym: I don't know, just jump right into it.
Rym: It's Thursday.
Rym: We used to call this the lounge, remember?
Scott: We kept saying- You called it the lounge.
Rym: The whole goal was that we won't do a normal show on Thursday.
Rym: We won't like, "Well, my news is
Rym: blah.".
Rym: Looked up this thing on Fark five minutes before.
Scott: We failed and I'm lazy, so I got some news.
Rym: Alright.
Scott: Alright, the news I have is that the Superb Owl is on Sunday.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: The Superb Owl.
Rym: Isn't there something on a website for that?
Scott: Superb-owl.com.
Scott: Ah.
Scott: It's on Sunday, February 7th, 2010.
Scott: Will be Superb Owl
Scott: 45? 44?
Scott: Yeah, screw that.
Rym: Meanwhile, one of my coworkers is going with one of my bosses to the Rangers game tonight.
Scott: Oh, very nice.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The Rangers are sort of up and down.
Scott: They win a whole bunch.
Scott: It's 44.
Rym: You know, I'm proud of New York.
Rym: I feel like New York City is my home city now.
Rym: I identify with it.
Rym: This is my city-state, but I still root for the Red Wings and not the Rangers.
Scott: The Rangers win a whole bunch and then they lose a whole bunch, and then they win, and then they lose.
Scott: That's how they go.
Scott: At least they don't have the problem they used to have, which is where they would basically fill the team with a bunch of big names who are all old and past their prime, not win at all.
Scott: Right?
Scott: And now, this year, it's actually not full of old Yeezers, so...
Rym: But very tactically, I decided to ski this weekend because I'm hoping... It's tricky because maybe fewer people will go up to ski because they want to go see the Superb Owl.
Rym: But maybe the kinds of people who ski are thinking, "Man, I hate the Superb Owl.
Rym: I'm going to go ski while all the idiots are watching the Superb
Rym: Owl.".
Scott: I think you might see a lot of skiing on Saturday, and then you might actually see a lot of Superb Owl watching in the ski lodge on Sunday.
Rym: Yeah, I'm only skiing Saturday, though, because I don't want to take Monday off work.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: This old man can no longer ski one day, go to work the next day.
Rym: I just, I can't.
Rym: I wake up the next day, and they just don't go.
Scott: So for all you nerds out there who might end up watching the Superb Owl and not understanding or caring, allow me to spend a minute to tell you the story of this year's Superb Owl that maybe you will have a slight greater appreciation for it than you otherwise would have.
Scott: So from the NFC are the New Orleans Saints, and the reason that the New Orleans Saints are hyped up is because, A, they have shit tons of offense.
Scott: They get touchdowns like crazy.
Rym: Think of football like a board game.
Scott: Yes, because of their quarterback, Drew Brees.
Scott: And that is how you say his name.
Scott: Really?
Scott: Drew Brees.
Scott: Okay, so the opponents from the AFC are the Indianapolis Colts, who have Peyton Manning, who is pretty much possibly the greatest ever.
Scott: Brother of the Giants quarterback, Eli Manning, who didn't even make the playoffs this year.
Scott: But he won the Super Bowl in '07, which is okay.
Scott: And basically, he's the greatest ever.
Scott: So it's sort of like the greatest ever versus the young punk kids who have crazy offense.
Scott: And, you know, if you want to add some suspense, right, to this mix, the Indianapolis Colts, one of their very important players.
Rym: Killed the mother of the other coach and stole the baby.
Scott: Is injured, right?
Scott: And at the same time, a lot of people are rooting for New Orleans because there was a hurricane there, so the city is a very sad city.
Scott: And the football team is pretty much the only thing they have that is not sad.
Scott: So if they win, it is like a happy, feel good story.
Scott: But really, it's kind of bad for me because all the teams that I hated, like the Cowboys and the Vikings and the Eagles and the Jets, they already lost.
Scott: And the only teams left were the teams that I liked.
Scott: So it's pretty much like team I like versus team I like.
Scott: And I'm like, oh, whatever.
Rym: I don't get you New York sports fans because I see this happen a lot.
Rym: It's not just you where there's a lot like.
Rym: you have this whole list of teams you hate.
Rym: And anytime there's a game that doesn't involve your team, you're looking at all the other teams like, well, I hate them more than them.
Rym: So I hope they lose, but I hope one of them gets injured.
Scott: Yeah, because I mean, there's no other team you like.
Scott: You only like one team and then you hate like a fistful of teams.
Scott: And then the rest of the teams are just teams in hockey.
Rym: As a Red Wings fan, we have the rivalry.
Rym: There's only one team at any given moment that we hate.
Rym: Every other team we are 100 percent neutral toward.
Scott: Oh, see, this is why the reason for this is because if you look in hockey, really, you know, I only hate maybe a couple hockey teams like the Flyers.
Scott: I hate the Flyers.
Rym: I'm indifferent to the Flyers.
Rym: You stay at the Avalanche because they were the rivals.
Rym: But then the Devils with their fucking trap.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And, you know, the Islanders, but the Islanders are so shitty.
Scott: It's like whatever.
Scott: But if you look at, say, baseball, for instance, right.
Scott: You are a Mets fan in the Mets division.
Scott: Right there.
Rym: You know, I thought you were going to say in the Mets universe.
Scott: No, no, no.
Scott: In the Mets division.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Are all the hated teams?
Scott: because those are the teams you play the most and those are the teams you need to beat to get to the playoffs.
Scott: You know, if you're a Giants fan, you hate the Eagles.
Scott: You hate the Cowboys.
Scott: You hate the Redskins because those are in the same division.
Scott: You got to kick their asses.
Scott: It's the end of, you know, it's NFC East.
Scott: So if the team's not in your division, right, you know who really gives a shit.
Scott: It's the teams that are in your division.
Scott: You play them twice a year.
Scott: Fuck them.
Scott: Fuck them hard.
Rym: See, I guess hockey is a little weirder because one divisions matter a lot less in hockey.
Rym: Well, they still matter a lot in terms of how you get seated for like the Stanley Cup and all.
Scott: No, the only thing that matters for that is East and West.
Scott: And the thing is you in hockey, you only if you're in the East, you play each team in the West at most once a year during the regular season and vice versa.
Rym: So they still divide them up smaller and smaller.
Scott: And there are separate divisions, but they hardly matter.
Rym: But what hurts is that the people, the Red Wings play at that level.
Rym: Oh, pretty, at least while I was a kid, sucked and it didn't matter.
Rym: And all that mattered was the Stanley Cup.
Rym: It was never like, are they going to make it to the finals?
Rym: It was just, are they going to win the Stanley Cup or not?
Rym: Are they going to win the Stanley Cup or not?
Rym: Nope, nope, yep, yep, nope, yep, nope, nope.
Scott: Meanwhile, the Capitals have won like 12 in a row.
Scott: And I'm cool with them because their fans have style.
Scott: Caps fans are good fans.
Scott: And that's, you know, that's another thing that contributes to whether you hate or don't hate a team.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Like, for example, you know, Redskins, they're in the same division as the Giants.
Scott: I don't like them.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But the Cowboys and the Eagles are hated far more.
Scott: Why?
Scott: Because Redskins fans, they're OK people.
Scott: Cowboys fans are shitheads from Texas.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Nothing needs to be said more about that.
Scott: And Philadelphia sports fans are pretty much the worst human beings on the face of the planet.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So that's why Phillies, Flyers, Eagles are like the most hated.
Scott: One, two, three.
Scott: All these Philadelphia sports fans are like, like, you know, it's like Hitler, Philadelphia sports fans.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Right behind.
Rym: See, I only measure the how bad.
Rym: the fans are of a team.
Rym: I call it batteries per year.
Rym: How many batteries do those fans throw?
Scott: Did you see that video of the Eagles fans like like literally like drowning these people in snowballs who are not Eagles fans?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Like if you you know, there's even.
Scott: this isn't like something I'm making up either or something.
Scott: I'm just saying because I'm a New York guy.
Scott: If you watch like ESPN or something, all the sports writers will be like, yeah, when my kid goes to like a Philadelphia sports game, I tell him, you know, do not wear your Redskins jersey.
Scott: Do not wear, you know, because he seriously thinks he's going to get.
Rym: See, at the same time, I'm pretty sure that the media has contributed to nothing more than a legend of Krauser, that there is a kernel of truth, but there's primarily a gigantic Krauser fucking the Tokyo Tower.
Scott: OK.
Scott: All right.
Scott: The last, I guess, raping more precisely the very last time I was at Chase Stadium, which is the last time I'll ever be at Chase Stadium because it no longer exists.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Was the was the last game that the Mets played against the Philadelphia Phillies at that stadium.
Rym: All right.
Scott: And many, many Phillies fans showed up and they were all shitheads.
Scott: They were like the worst people imaginable.
Scott: They all bought their brooms.
Scott: They were like, sweep, sweep, because they had won the first two games of the series.
Scott: And of course, we won that night and there was no sweep.
Rym: I brought a broom to the the second set of Stanley Cup stuff when the Red Wings were doing really well when I was.
Scott: But I'm just saying is that these people were not pleasant people.
Scott: They were, you know, not.
Rym: Now, Scott, how about the corner crew at RIT?
Scott: We made the goalie cry.
Scott: It was a good natured ribbing as opposed to a.
Rym: He started crying.
Rym: Well, that's just because he was a pussy.
Rym: That's not because.
Scott: The corner crew was good natured ribbing.
Rym: It was not malicious, cruel, drunk and retarded through your thighs than your sister.
Scott: Yeah, that's not.
Scott: It was not malicious, cruel, drunken or retarded.
Scott: It was intelligent and good natured.
Rym: And also, I point out, as much as I love RIT, we stole half our chance from MIT and just said RIT instead.
Scott: What's wrong with that?
Rym: You know what most of our listeners just heard?
Scott: Sports, sports, sports, sports, sports, sports, sports, sports, sports, sports, sports, sports, sports, his name is Drew Brees, like B-R-E-E-S, like the cool island breeze.
Scott: Aha, Drew Brees.
Rym: OK, so I just I'm not going to talk about it much, but there's this.
Rym: It's funny because I just finished our Scott backers neuropath and it's quick geek bite.
Rym: It's no prince of nothing.
Scott: If you're you don't say the prince of nothing is the prince of something.
Scott: It's the prince king of something.
Rym: It's the prince of let's just do a bunch of really disturbing Ghost in the Shell kind of stuff and then end on a downer.
Scott: So it's Ghost in the Shell and it's not.
Scott: It's mind game.
Rym: You know, it really is.
Rym: It's Strange Days, except it ends in the exact opposite way from the way Strange Days ended.
Rym: But otherwise, it's almost the same story.
Scott: All right.
Rym: But it's funny because I just read this whole book and it really has a really, really, really depressing outlook on what humans are and what consciousness is and free will and all that.
Rym: And then just today, randomly, I click on the top story on like Google News in science.
Rym: And it's the story on the Telegraph that basically says 80 percent of what neuropath says.
Rym: But it's a science article saying, check out all these scary things we've learned about the brain in the past year.
Rym: And it's basically, wow, neuropath is wild.
Rym: I'd say like half the book is definitely all right.
Rym: We're speculating and sci fi and whatever.
Rym: But half the book is pretty much hard science at this point.
Scott: I you know, it's it's.
Scott: the one thing that just fascinates me more than anything is that when I was a kid in school, like elementary school, right, you would ask, like, how does a brain work?
Scott: And we knew that, like, the brain was the brain.
Scott: And that was about it.
Scott: And I'm sure that scientists knew more.
Rym: I knew about the hippocampus in high school.
Scott: Yeah, but I know a lot about that, you know, and you knew the different parts of the brain different things.
Scott: But like, if you ask people like, how does the brain work?
Scott: Like, basically, nobody knows.
Scott: It was basically this land of mystery, you know, and now if you ask how the brain works or go on the Internet, there's any number of books and websites and papers about neuroscience telling you a scary amount of information about how the brain works down to excruciatingly small details.
Scott: That is very frightening and awesome.
Rym: And it's one.
Scott: if I could go back in time, I would have been a neuro doctor instead of a computer guy.
Scott: I'll raise two points that I had to get all A's in school, and that would have been unpleasant.
Scott: I would have played a lot less video games.
Rym: It's been a while, so I got to slip back into Friday night party line mode a little bit.
Scott: Oh, I got to bring up the things I bring up Admiral Nelson and his brain is so massive.
Scott: That's why he never got killed in war, even though boats were horrible places.
Rym: Well, I could go back to Emperor Constantine and how his brain was so small.
Scott: First, I'll go to Cthulhu and how he doesn't have a brain.
Scott: You just go insane whenever you look at them.
Rym: But how we're getting, you know, the whole idea of the Cthulhu, like that kind of mythos story is the idea that there is knowledge.
Rym: that is true, that you do not know.
Rym: that upon knowing changes the very fundamental nature of the way you exist because you cannot forget.
Scott: Once you know, you can't un-know.
Rym: Basically, yes.
Scott: You've seen it.
Scott: You can't un-see it.
Scott: It's tub girl.
Scott: It's the neuroscience paper.
Scott: And tub girl have something in common.
Rym: The FNPL point I always bring up is the zebra storyteller.
Scott: Oh, your zebra storyteller.
Rym: That these things would have been disturbing to me at a younger age, but because I've watched so much sci-fi that in many ways was worse than what reality is turning out to be.
Rym: Yeah, all right, maybe I don't have free will.
Rym: That's not nearly as bad as H.P.
Rym: Lovecraft World.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, it's funny that you mentioned the Cthulhu because Cthulhu is the antithesis of the zebra storyteller.
Scott: You know, no matter how many H.P.
Scott: Lovecraft stories you read, if Cthulhu shows up, you will go insane and die.
Scott: It does not matter.
Rym: However, I point out the people who are zebra storytellers hold out a lot better.
Rym: or maybe they found out about the yellow sign and hold themselves off for a little while.
Scott: They're the last to go, the cultists.
Rym: They delay.
Scott: Yeah, the cultists are always the last to go.
Scott: Yeah, or the first to go, depending on- If they want to or they get what they go in the order they want to go because they know.
Rym: Yeah, you pretty much trust Cthulhu.
Rym: If it eats you first or eats you last- You have no choice but to trust.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: I feel like I want to cross-pollinate for like the next month or so.
Rym: I'm never going to use a video game thing on a Tuesday and I can't really say vice versa because there's no other thing there.
Scott: Oh, you're always going to use an inappropriate thing.
Scott: today is what you're saying.
Rym: Yes, because that's the whole point of our show, to get people exposed to things they wouldn't otherwise be exposed to, like my hammer.
Scott: It's not a bad idea.
Rym: So my thing of the day is totally video game and it's from College Humor, which again, if you guys haven't figured it out, pretty much 99% of our things of the day are just a video from that day on College Humor.
Scott: I'm avoiding College Humor things of the day.
Rym: But there have been some really good ones lately that people don't watch.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: Every now and then- Go to collegehumor.com/videos and just watch any video you think is funny every day.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is- Instead of watching whatever crap you're watching on TV.
Rym: It's sad because even there, the signal-to-noise ratio is higher than almost any other like funny thing on the internet site.
Scott: And it's still less than half.
Rym: Yeah, I watch maybe a third, maybe, of College Humor videos.
Rym: Of course, you kind of get this gnosis, this like innate understanding of that one's going to be funny, that one's not going to be funny.
Scott: Is Jake and Amir on it?
Scott: Not funny.
Rym: Jake and Amir is awesome.
Rym: What's wrong with you?
Scott: They suck.
Scott: I mean, they're probably cool guys, but their show sucks.
Rym: Actually, I hear on good authority from multiple people that, you know, Amir is actually really awesome in person.
Scott: I'm pretty sure he is awesome.
Scott: His show sucks.
Rym: I hear that Jake in person is actually a complete douchebag.
Scott: That may be true also, but their show sucks.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: I think it's really funny because it- It says nothing about them as people.
Scott: Just like, you know, there are lots of cool people who make shitty shows and there are actually lots of uncool people who make good shows.
Scott: You know, your personality has nothing to do with the work.
Scott: No, I'm saying I don't know why- It's the Michael Jackson syndrome.
Scott: He plays little boys and he makes amazing music and dances.
Scott: Mike Tyson can beat the shit out of people, but he's a piece of shit himself.
Scott: You said rape play.
Rym: You didn't say rape or play.
Rym: You said rape play.
Scott: He does both.
Rym: Wasn't that the name of that game?
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Michael Jackson made that game.
Rym: So anyway, this is a Mario wrap set to a much less- I don't think a lot of people even know this Mario exists anymore.
Scott: Yeah, the Game Boy, you know, it's really weird because of the way things have turned out with Nintendo's portable stuff.
Scott: You know, the NES stuff, right, it seems to last forever because people can emulate it.
Scott: It's the most easily emulated thing.
Scott: and they got the virtual console, right?
Scott: And, you know, the GBA is sticking around because DS's have GBA slots and such and such.
Scott: But Game Boy and Game Boy Color games have really sort of faded into history and only people who were around and had those games remember them.
Scott: And especially if something is an obscure Game Boy game, there were a shit ton of regular non-Color Game Boy games.
Scott: A lot.
Scott: There was like a Hunt for Red October game.
Rym: I was about to bring that up.
Scott: There was a Star Wars game.
Scott: Who's played Star Wars to the original Game Boy?
Scott: I have.
Rym: That Hunt for Red October is one of the most underrated, underappreciated, and in desperate need of-.
Rym: There was a James Bond game for the Game Boy.
Scott: There was a Bomberman Game Boy game.
Scott: It was like Indiana Jones Bomberman.
Rym: Hunt for Red October was an asymmetric information hidden multiple screens to Game Boy games.
Scott: There were lots of old Game Boy games that people just don't remember at all, right, except for Pokemon.
Rym: So punk kids, watch this rep and that game you're watching is on par with Mario 1 in terms of gameplay.
Scott: And the best Game Boy game that is lost to history is Wario 2.
Scott: Play Wario 2.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: So someone was recently discussing, you know, how, "Oh my gosh, Avatar is the biggest movie
Scott: ever.".
Rym: It made like 30 million last weekend.
Scott: It made like a bajillion dollars.
Rym: It made double what like brand new movies last weekend were making.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And they're talking about like, "Oh, Dark Knight, Spider-Man, these are the biggest movies ever,
Scott: Titanic.".
Scott: And I'm like, "Uh, those no...".
Scott: You know, but people always talk about the box office gross, how much money it made at the box office.
Scott: And I'm like, "Dude, those numbers are not adjusted for, you know, number of tickets sold versus price of ticket, you know, because the 3D tickets cost a lot more.
Scott: They're not adjusted for
Scott: inflation.".
Scott: And someone was like, "Yes, they
Scott: are.".
Scott: And I was like, "Oh, really?
Scott: I didn't know
Scott: that.".
Scott: So of course I go on the internet and no, they are not.
Scott: I was 100%, I was 100% right.
Scott: Here is the real box office numbers on this website that has them adjusted for inflation.
Scott: Avatar is number 21.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Let's look at the real, the real list.
Rym: Of course, Scott, you're going back in the day to when there was only one movie.
Scott: Uh, wait till you hear this list.
Scott: All right.
Scott: This list has a wide variety of time periods.
Rym: It's not going to be on there?
Scott: What?
Rym: Welcome to Good Burger, home of the Good Burger.
Scott: I don't know what that is.
Scott: Number one, I know it's a restaurant.
Scott: Number one, it's a movie.
Scott: Number one is Gone with the Wind from 1939.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: You know what I'm going to say?
Scott: Adjusted for inflation, one and a half billion dollars.
Rym: You know what I got to say?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: That movie sucks ass.
Scott: Number two, right?
Scott: Star Wars.
Scott: Number three, Sound of Music, E.T.
Scott: Ten Commandments, Titanic, Jaws, Dr.
Scott: Zhivago from 1965, The Exorcist, Snow White, 101 Dalmatians, Empire Strikes Back, which comes after 101 Dalmatians.
Scott: I just want to point this out that 101 Dalmatians made, adjusted for inflation, 20, about 13 more millions.
Rym: Now Scott, you're forgetting something important.
Rym: Avatar is still making constant money in the box office.
Scott: It might be higher than 21 when all is said and done.
Rym: It's got to at least make it to Titanic level because people are rewatching this thing.
Scott: The point is, is that when you do adjust for inflation, all right, it's like, shut up.
Scott: Don't tell me a movie is number one gross when it's not really number one.
Scott: when you adjust, It doesn't count.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: So all these people hyping up Dark Knight, Spider-Man, Avatar, okay, as being number one, you are wrong.
Scott: Shut the fuck up.
Scott: It's number 21.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Call me back when it's really number one.
Rym: You're number 10.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: Number 10.
Scott: Not even number 10.
Scott: Number 10 is Snow White.
Scott: Until you beat Snow White, then call me.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Otherwise, you didn't break any records.
Rym: Seriously, have you ever actually seen Gone with the Wind all the way through?
Scott: I saw about half of it one time when it was on after The King and I on the classic movie.
Rym: Do you really think you saw half?
Rym: How far did you get?
Rym: Because I don't think you realize how fucking long that movie goes on.
Scott: According to the TV guide, I was halfway through.
Rym: Maybe edited for TV?
Scott: No, I mean, it was, you know, they don't show commercials in the classic movie channel.
Rym: When I was in high school, we had a party.
Rym: We had 10 people over a whole weekend.
Rym: Everyone could bring one movie and the rule was everybody had to watch it no matter what it was.
Rym: I would have brought, uh, one guy brought Debbie Does Dallas.
Rym: That was, that was horrifying.
Rym: I brought Dominion Tank Police.
Scott: That was not a movie.
Scott: That's multiple episodes.
Scott: You only have to watch one episode and we can turn it off.
Rym: But we did that.
Rym: Everyone really liked it.
Rym: You know, the third movie was Gone with the Wind.
Rym: Everyone went home about halfway through.
Rym: That was the end of the party.
Scott: Yeah, I would have brought that movie so much.
Scott: I would have brought Hard Rock Zombies.
Rym: I don't know if I could ever watch that again.
Scott: Or perhaps like Each of the Killer or something along those lines.
Scott: Ebola, you know, one of the, I would have brought something like that.
Scott: The kind of thing that no one will ever watch.
Scott: If they're Odin.
Rym: I believe you mean Odin.
Scott: No, maybe I'd go light.
Scott: I would bring, you know, Odin Starlight Mutiny instead of bringing Odin Photon Space Sailor Starlight.
Rym: So I believe, so we don't forget, we should at least do the meta Musel.
Scott: Do we have any meta at all besides conventions?
Rym: PAX East will be there.
Rym: We're doing four or five panels plus other stuff.
Rym: Anime Boston will be there.
Rym: We're doing between four and seven panels.
Rym: Nexus will probably be there.
Scott: Not doing any panels.
Rym: No, but we might, I'm going to try to get in as press.
Scott: Mocha will be there one day, walking around, looking at comics, buying comics.
Rym: Walking around, looking around, spending money.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: This is bad.
Rym: The last Mocha, I very consciously chose not to buy many things because I didn't want to carry them around in the city the rest of the day.
Rym: Now I'm done.
Rym: I'm just going to walk into every booth.
Scott: The thing is, like after the first year at Mocha, I decided that every year after I would just buy anything that was even slightly.
Scott: And the thing is, I've never actually done that.
Scott: I'm going to go this year, like totally uninhibited.
Scott: Just I'm actually going to buy anything that's quality.
Rym: I feel like I should just go to every booth that looks cool and be like, here's 100 bucks.
Rym: Give me whatever you think that's worth.
Rym: I haven't even read all the comics I've got from the last Mocha.
Scott: Yeah, we've got.
Scott: we've got, I guess, a new book club.
Scott: But this is a book club episode.
Scott: Oh, crap.
Rym: So I guess I have to pick the book.
Scott: Were we going to decide on a different method for picking or are you going to pick?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Let's decide at the end.
Scott: OK.
Rym: All right.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Yeah, that's it.
Rym: OK.
Rym: So the Hitchhiker's Guide, you know what I did not know?
Rym: What?
Rym: That book was published in the 70s.
Scott: I knew that.
Rym: I kind of assumed it was from the 80s when I was a kid.
Rym: I just didn't know.
Rym: I didn't I never cared.
Rym: I didn't think about it.
Scott: The first thing I want to say about the book is at least in my edition of it, there was a forward by Neil Gaiman.
Scott: I think it was by Neil Gaiman.
Rym: It has to be.
Rym: It was by.
Scott: All right.
Scott: But regardless of who it was by, it pretty much explains like radio show came first.
Scott: You know, TV series, this movie, that was based on this.
Scott: This is the order they came out in.
Scott: You know, we know that they weren't the same.
Scott: We don't care that, you know, the differences around purpose, yada, yada, yada.
Scott: And, you know, you can read that forward for yourself somewhere.
Scott: But the point is, I thought that was really good because you don't often get that that, you know, open, you know, no holding back explanation of adaptations and what order they came in.
Scott: And, you know, did the actual creator care about the differences or were they happy with them?
Scott: And the fact that they actually give you that, at least in the edition I had, was very nice.
Scott: I liked it a lot and it actually sort of helped me, you know, understand the book better and like, OK, I know there was a radio show and this is just a book of the radio show with changes made because it's not a radio show.
Rym: See, now, that's another interesting point.
Rym: I was exposed to the radio show as a kid way before I read the book.
Rym: And when I finally was like, there's a book, I'll read it.
Rym: And the whole time I thought, wow, it's cool to read the original.
Rym: And I did not know it.
Scott: You always think that a book is the original.
Rym: Yeah, I did not know until very recently that the radio drama actually did come first.
Scott: Yeah, it's even weirder now, like with animes and mangas, because you have those ones that are based on a light novel.
Scott: But then there's people coming out with like Full Metal Alchemist, the novel.
Scott: But there is no way.
Scott: that was first.
Scott: The manga was first.
Scott: You know, it's very difficult to tell what was first without looking in the front like flap of every freaking thing.
Rym: you are just going down to my news network and be like, what came first?
Scott: Yeah, even so, it's it's tricky.
Rym: Plus, you can usually tell if it's like I have a Sailor Moon manga that I picked up somewhere at a con and then I have a Sailor Moon novel and Sailor Moon novel is written by a cat's friend.
Rym: Yes, it was.
Rym: And I'm pretty sure the comic was based on the novel, which was itself based on the cartoon, which was itself based on the manga.
Rym: And none of them are really in any way similar to each other.
Scott: OK, so anyway, Hitchhiker's Guide.
Scott: Well, first thing I have to say about it is that it was very short, like it literally took me two nights to read.
Scott: But that's only because I barely read each night.
Scott: If I would have actually kept reading, you know, it takes almost no time to read.
Rym: Well, when I picked it up to read again, you know, I had this old collection of like the five books and I'd only ever read a few of them.
Rym: So I just had this book like beat up playing around and I didn't realize until I finished it how short it was.
Scott: Well, that's the reason that I picked it in the first place is because I'm like, OK, people don't read.
Scott: We need to get people to read.
Scott: Let's, you know, do the build up strategy like you do when you're trying to quit smoking with the, you know, Nicorette you build down.
Scott: I'm like, well, build up, read this freaking tiny ass book.
Scott: And next time we'll read a slightly larger book and a slightly larger book until you can read a big book like a grown up.
Rym: I get this feeling that most of the listeners are not reading any books we tell them to.
Rym: They're just if they've already read the book we talk about, they look forward to the book club shows.
Scott: Some people did say they were rereading the book.
Rym: You know, the thing is, it almost every time in my life until now when I've reread a book, I got something I didn't get before or like I got some.
Rym: Are you kidding me?
Scott: It was.
Scott: I just rewatched Macross, which I'll talk about in another episode.
Scott: But it was.
Scott: it was like 10 times the power of when I rewatched Ava.
Rym: Yeah, but even Ava, we rewatched Ava.
Rym: It was like a whole new thing, like, oh, right.
Rym: This is game changing.
Scott: I forgot.
Rym: But reading Hitchhiker's Guide, it was like, yep, this is exactly how I remember it.
Rym: This is this is everything I remembered it to be.
Scott: See, the thing is, I basically didn't remember, but I forgot some details like minor stuff.
Rym: But I realized like the only revelation I had was completely meta that in geek and nerd culture, like I know how ubiquitous the Hitchhiker's Guide is, like everyone knows of it in some capacity.
Rym: But I thought and reflected on just how amazingly frequently it is referenced to a degree that you don't even notice when it's referenced because it's referenced so often by everybody.
Rym: I mean, like even way back, like every time I do something in the database, like in a development environment, if I make a user, he's been called Ford Prefect my whole life and I continue to do that.
Rym: There's a Ford Prefect user and like everything I do at my current job.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Well, that's that's the only insight I had beyond what I had as a kid, that I didn't realize quite the scope of how frequently it is referenced in every nerd and geek media there is.
Scott: I mean, the one thing that really stood out to me in reading it is that, I mean, it's supposed to be primarily a comedy, right?
Scott: You know, it's supposed to be funny.
Scott: That's that's what it's all about.
Scott: It's all about being hilarious.
Scott: I mean, on the front cover is this green planet with his tongue hanging out and he's like thumbing is, you know, he's like, you know, nose at you or whatever.
Scott: It's supposed to be a comedy.
Scott: It's like, tada, here is comedy for you.
Scott: It's not funny.
Scott: Like, I didn't laugh at all.
Rym: I laughed out loud even rereading it.
Scott: Oh, really?
Scott: I don't think like it's completely not funny to me.
Scott: It's just, you know, I mean, any funny bits it has are just sort of like obvious sort of, you know, zaniness.
Scott: And it is not cleverly Monty Python humorous in any way.
Rym: See, they are, I think.
Rym: I don't think so.
Rym: Part of it is that it comes from the radio show.
Rym: And if you like listen to the radio show, when I read it, I kind of always hear it like all the dialogue in the same kind of cadence that the radio show had, where the timing of the like.
Rym: there are two levels of the comedy.
Rym: One is the timing of the dialogue, like listening to the dialogue at a spoken pace in your mind while you're reading.
Rym: it is half the humor of the book.
Rym: Not what's being said, but like the timing of who says what when and how people react to things.
Rym: And notice how people always kind of react to things by meeping or squelching or like very like the way the straight man in a Monty Python skit reacts when everybody around him spontaneously dies like it.
Scott: Yeah, yeah.
Rym: And the second half is it's kind of like I think Dave Barry wrote it Big Trouble, which is a more recent book.
Rym: I read it a long time ago, but I was reminded of it a lot again because it's the same kind of all the humor aside from the timing humor is the meta.
Rym: It's like in the dialogue and the phrasing and the writing itself is the humor, like the reading of it.
Rym: The humor is there.
Rym: The humor is not so much in the plot of the story.
Rym: It's in the meta of like the reading of it and the way it's written and the phrasing.
Rym: And it's in the humor of listening to the dialogue in your head.
Rym: The story itself isn't funny.
Scott: Just reading the book, I didn't laugh like at all, not once.
Scott: And, you know, I mean, there were things that I could see that were supposed to be funny, like, oh, he has a funny name or oh, that's so outlandish, it should be humorous.
Scott: But it was not humorous.
Scott: I was not lolling.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I just I don't think you pictured enough in your head.
Rym: If you listen to the radio drama again, I'll bet you'd laugh out loud.
Scott: It's possible.
Scott: I'm just saying, reading the book, I've got it laying around somewhere.
Scott: I'm sure I'm sure it's everywhere on the Internet.
Scott: If I want it, I got it.
Scott: But I'm just saying, reading the book, not funny.
Scott: I was not the only not funny thing at all.
Rym: that comes up is, again, 100 percent meta.
Rym: I have this problem where all the quotable lines from the entire novel and probably from the entire series, I'm so used to really boring nerds quoting them at me and pretending that is social currency that every time I read like every third or fourth paragraph, like the line about the pangalactic gargle blaster or the I don't know, the Vogons, anything.
Rym: It's just I picture the boring nerd who's quoting it at me to prove that he's read the same thing that I've read.
Scott: You know, I think that is true to some extent.
Scott: For example, you know, there's all the typical cliche things from this book, you know.
Scott: Oh, 42 is, you know, answer life universe and everything.
Scott: And, you know, all you know, all that stuff.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And the thing is, you read it and it's like they basically all the things, you know, are lined up one after the other.
Scott: Like, oh, there's that one.
Scott: There's that one.
Rym: In a way, it's that one.
Rym: It's a lot like rewatching a Monty Python movie.
Rym: I mean, you know, the whole thing by heart already.
Rym: It's just every memorable line one by one in a row.
Scott: But holy grail is still funny every time.
Rym: Just because it's been a long time.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: But basically it's like, you know, they show up as like there's that one.
Scott: I'm sure that if I had read this cold, I didn't know it already that it might be.
Rym: Well, there was a time when you did that.
Rym: Was it hilarious when you were a kid?
Scott: I don't remember.
Rym: Really?
Scott: I remember that I read like all of the ones in Future King.
Scott: But if you quiz me out on like Arthurian legend, I know like I didn't even know that Excalibur and the sword in the stone weren't the same.
Rym: So Scott, all right, Scott, question one.
Rym: Who was Arthur?
Scott: The king.
Rym: What was he the king of?
Scott: England.
Scott: Oh, no, Albion.
Scott: Albion.
Rym: Are you sure?
Rym: I'm not even going to.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: I was going somewhere else with that, but you kind of just went right off the track.
Rym: But it's got it.
Rym: The humor is really the Britons.
Rym: That's not that's that's right.
Scott: I think I'm funnier than this book.
Rym: The book is funny, though.
Rym: I think the next book club should be listen to the radio drama.
Scott: No, no, no.
Scott: All right, fine.
Rym: The radio club is now.
Rym: listen to the radio drama of the Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy.
Scott: If you have to do a radio club, you do the shadow first.
Rym: No, the shadow is good, but it's also really, really, really cheesy and corny.
Scott: What's wrong with you?
Rym: Have you listened to the shadow in recent memory?
Rym: Do you remember the one with the volcano?
Rym: No.
Rym: The magnetic volcano that was pulling airplanes out of the sky?
Rym: I have that on vinyl.
Scott: Oh, man.
Rym: It's I love the shadow, Scott, but I'm going to say straight up.
Rym: The shadow is the oral equivalent of I'll hit you now, you little guy.
Scott: Don't you agree?
Scott: But that actually works in a radio drama.
Rym: No, it doesn't.
Rym: Because you hear like, oh, no, you're not.
Rym: You're not also looking at a picture of him hitting the little guy with a line pointing in an arrow that says he is hitting the little guy.
Rym: That's right.
Rym: And then it cuts to Professor Xavier saying, oh, no, he's hitting the little guy.
Scott: That means that I'm using my psychic powers just to determine.
Scott: Oh, my God.
Scott: He's hitting the little guy.
Rym: But then you says, yes, the little guy has been hit.
Scott: Oh, Zoe.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: But it's like, listen to the shadow.
Rym: Oh, no, I am stuck to the wall of the volcano because everything is magnetic.
Rym: I know I'll take my belt off and then I'll be able to get away.
Rym: No, says the shadow.
Rym: If you take your belt off and blah, blah, blah, then you electrify yourself.
Rym: No, I will be fine.
Scott: Are you looking at a script of the shadow?
Rym: No, I just listened to this one like a million times as a kid.
Rym: Oh, no, he has been electrified and he is now dead.
Rym: That is what it's like.
Scott: Cool sound effects, though.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Okay, so Hitchhiker's Guide, regardless of its lack or presence of comedy.
Rym: I still say it's hilarious.
Rym: It's just it's blunted for a lot of people by the fact that nerds quoted at them all the time.
Scott: I actually think that the sci-fi part of it is actually like slightly interesting and above average, like, you know, this whole idea that there was a planet of people who made planets and doing this experiment.
Rym: Yes, by the way, spoilers, you know, it's the book.
Scott: God, we spoiled the incredibly tiny first book in a multiple series of books that you were supposed to read.
Rym: Oh, no.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Book that everyone already read when I was a kid has been around for 30, 40 years.
Rym: If you somehow haven't read it, you stop listening because I'm about to spoil the fact that the mice just fucking make up the answer in the end.
Rym: And that's hilarious.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Rym: You know, but just the whole the earth is.
Rym: the computer is one of those things that in a sci-fi like dead serious movie would be obvious from the start.
Rym: And when it happened, you like, oh, really?
Rym: But in this, because it builds itself as a comedy, I think the sci-fi aspects kind of slip under the radar and as a result, almost have more impact.
Scott: I think another reason that it has more impact is that, you know, in a sci-fi movie, like, you know, they'd be like, you know, at the beginning, they'd be like, oh, what is it?
Scott: And that at the end, they'd be like, it was this.
Scott: Whereas in Hitchhiker's Guide, it's like you're just on this adventure.
Scott: And then at the end, they're like, what was it?
Scott: It was this just at the end.
Scott: They don't go.
Scott: What was it at the beginning?
Scott: So you're not even looking for this mystery.
Scott: So it doesn't come out as obvious and cliched because they just throw it at you at the end and they can throw it at you at the end because they're not presenting themselves as serious and they're presenting it as serious.
Scott: You couldn't do get away with that.
Scott: It would just be a Dave's Ex Machina.
Scott: Fuck you throwing me complete softball at left field at the end.
Scott: But when you're presenting yourself as hilarious comedy, you just do whatever you want at any on time, completely spontaneous, zany randomness.
Scott: So the result is you can throw in spontaneous, random, zany, serious sci-fi ad in left field.
Scott: And it totally works.
Rym: Actually, when I think about it, the Heart of Gold reading it again, as soon as I like, I cut.
Rym: It's weird how I remembered the whole book, but I didn't remember a lot like the ship Heart of Gold.
Rym: Hyperion.
Rym: It reminded me of the ship they use in Hyperion for some reason.
Rym: And I kept thinking about Hyperion the whole time I read it as a result.
Scott: I didn't think about Hyperion at all.
Rym: But maybe that's just because you went full Hyperion in that thread in the forum.
Rym: And ever since then, I've been thinking about Hyperion every day.
Scott: Actually, strangely, I imagine the ship looking like the really silvery looking ship the princess has in episode one and two.
Scott: I don't know why I thought that way, but whatever.
Rym: Yeah, I will say I really like.
Rym: Zafar to this day is one of my favorite characters.
Rym: He is definitely an awesome dude because he has the perfect blend of awesome and Captain Tyler and doesn't give a shit, but also does give a shit, but tries to pretend he doesn't and is also not a moron.
Rym: What was the line?
Rym: It's one of the lines that no one ever quotes, but it spoke to me maybe because I just watched Tyler, but something along the lines of most of his success was probably due to the fact that he never quite understood the ramifications of what he had just done.
Scott: Yeah, I did that sort of thing is one thing that makes the book incredibly tolerable is the fact that, you know, there's no like retards in it.
Scott: You know, that's the one thing that bothers me about a lot of books is when you have a character who is just fucking stupid like they're just there things they could do that they don't do.
Rym: Wait, wait, Kaji, you gave him the thing.
Rym: Yeah, yeah.
Rym: Well, that was what you gave him the thing.
Rym: you gave him the thing.
Scott: Yeah, there are not like gigantic, you know, despite being zany, there aren't really plot holes or, you know, such.
Scott: it's like characters are doing what they can do.
Scott: You know, they're not doing things that are stupid.
Scott: They're doing the best they can with what they've got available most of the time, considering the circumstances and what they know and such and such.
Scott: And, you know, having Hitchhiker's Guide that tells you all sorts of stuff help make prevents you from being a moron in a lot of ways, as long as you remember to use it.
Scott: Too bad I have a hard time believing that looking at how much of the real world doesn't know how to use Google.
Scott: I don't have a lot of confidence that the real world would be smarter if everyone in Hitchhiker's Guide.
Scott: We already do.
Rym: Urban Dictionary plus Wikipedia plus WikiHow.
Rym: You've got it.
Rym: I've got.
Rym: my pre is basically the Hitchhiker's Guide.
Scott: And yet people are still morons and they don't use it.
Rym: Well, because it gives you information.
Rym: You see, but you do not witness.
Scott: Yeah, exactly.
Rym: There's not a lot to say about the Hitchhiker's Guide other than it's important.
Scott: Yeah, it's a book that I thought would be, oh, this is gonna be such a great book club book, but it's like, well, what, you know?
Scott: Sure, it was great for getting people to read.
Scott: Is it great for talking about?
Rym: Movies you should see.
Rym: whenever they talked about a movie that they love that was a comedy like Ferris Bueller or something, they descend into a quote fest.
Rym: But I almost it's weird.
Rym: I avoid quoting the Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy wherever possible because quoting it in public is often associated with the boring nerd who doesn't have anything more reason to quote.
Scott: Yeah, I think the other thing is that it's really.
Scott: it's one of those things where, you know, it's good.
Scott: It's not like, oh, my God, is the most amazing thing ever.
Rym: Well, it was.
Rym: it definitely had to have been game changing when it came out because I absolutely look at the absolute look at the ripple.
Scott: Yes, but, you know, I think part of it was, you know, right thing, right time, right delivery, right situation.
Scott: You know, it wasn't all, you know, the quality is not, you know, a plus.
Scott: You know, you judge it based on the quality of its if its innate qualities alone, it is like, you know, B plus.
Scott: what's really interesting is you also take into account the time it came out, you know, this and that and all these other things.
Scott: Then that's what raises it to that next level.
Rym: What's interesting is I just read the forward from, you know, Burke, the guy who did Bloom County and all that.
Rym: Yeah, he wrote the forward to the rereleased anthology and he basically admits straight up that it wasn't the greatest comic.
Rym: And the reason it was so popular and successful was that it was just before there was an Internet, really, and it was different at the time, just enough to break all these boundaries and be remembered.
Rym: But there was no Internet where everything was equally breaking boundaries and it would have just been one of a million.
Rym: That's true.
Rym: And then he says straight up, I was only a success because I just happened to do the right thing at the right time just before the Internet made what I was doing the norm as opposed to the exception.
Scott: And I think that something is that is absolutely true.
Scott: And I think that when something becomes sort of, you know, beloved and remembered and revered the way that Douglas Adams and the Hitchhiker's Guide is, it is very difficult to disparage in any way.
Scott: People will be like, oh, no, it's so beloved.
Scott: It's it's the best effort.
Rym: The thing is, I have nothing bad to say about it.
Rym: It's just.
Scott: it's not as bad to say about it.
Scott: It's just that it's the same as Monty Python.
Scott: I think, you know, yeah, if you judged it based on its merit alone as a book, you know, the book only and only the books merits on its own.
Scott: That's it, you know, independently of anything else.
Rym: Well, you can't do that if you have to also take into consideration when it was and what else existed at the time to consume.
Scott: No, no, but I'm like, look, if you're you know, we're talking about the present day, we're not traveling back in time here.
Scott: If someone's going to the bookstore to buy a book.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And there's like, which book will be enjoyable?
Scott: I'll be like, well, this Hitchhiker's Guide book, you might think it's funny and it's a quick read and it's kind of quirky, but you'll probably be far more entertained by these other books over here.
Rym: Well, that's just that.
Rym: it's the whole, you know, right time, right place.
Rym: Bloom County, if it appeared today as a webcomic, no one would give a shit.
Scott: It'd be.
Scott: it'd be an OK-ish webcomic.
Rym: Yeah, but it would.
Rym: it would be one a speck among millions.
Rym: It wouldn't be like the memorable thing that has these repeated reprints of anthologies and like it's considered an important part of 80s culture.
Scott: Even Penny Arcade.
Scott: I don't think they've reprinted any of the volumes.
Rym: Yeah, of course, Penny Arcade is the kind of thing where everyone who cares bought it.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.