Rym: It's Wednesday August 25th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights tonight Miyazaki the other Miyazaki's tales from Earthsea.
Rym: Let's do this.
Scott: You know how you know this happens to everyone in the world.
Scott: you get a song in your head But you don't know what the song You know.
Rym: it's even worse when you know what the song is no.
Scott: I don't even have the whole song in my head.
Scott: I've got like the tiniest piece of a single like bit from the song in my head.
Scott: Basically this is some song and I'm almost positive that it's gonna.
Scott: It's gonna end up being like some Britney Spears song or some bullshit like that, right?
Scott: But it's basically the only part of it that I can get in my eye.
Rym: This is gonna sing it well Kind of.
Scott: it goes like.
Scott: it's like a weird techno violin noise, and it goes like Kind of.
Scott: that's it or it?
Scott: maybe it goes do I forget exactly how it goes, but it's like these four like new kind of noises all together Something along those lines.
Rym: yeah, this is that song.
Rym: no is it?
Scott: maybe I can't.
Scott: I won't know unless I actually have the real recording of it.
Rym: Why don't you use that the iPhone app for your home in?
Scott: because that?
Scott: What I hum.
Scott: that isn't enough and things I don't even know.
Scott: if like is it?
Scott: is it Going down going you know is it Scott?
Rym: are you sure it's a song?
Rym: are you sure it's not nothing?
Scott: I'm 100. if it's not a song then if I can get the rest of it out of my brain I could make like a number one dance hit cuz.
Scott: I'm pretty sure that's what it is Is it?
Rym: you're sure it's just a violin.
Rym: do you remember anything else from the song like it?
Rym: was it a bass line?
Scott: I kind of kind of associate it with the kind of song that you would hear while you're standing waiting for a concert to start Like kind of.
Scott: you know that kind of song.
Rym: What kind of song is that?
Rym: the last concert?
Rym: I went to.
Rym: that wasn't pecs.
Rym: I think it was phantomas doing the music or the concert started.
Scott: The kind that they play on the loudspeaker while you're standing waiting for something.
Scott: you know That kind.
Scott: the kind to get you grooves.
Rym: That's not a kind.
Scott: That's a kind.
Scott: No it isn't.
Scott: it is.
Rym: Most concerts don't have that and they have a cover band in the front or the opening ad.
Rym: Anyway, that X does that.
Scott: I'm sure somebody listening will help me out.
Rym: Oh, yes, they're gonna help you out with a song that kind of comes down four times.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: it might go like.
Scott: I think it might go up down way up or down I don't know.
Rym: so here's what you've said.
Rym: it does something that might be up or down And maybe involves a violin.
Rym: well.
Scott: It's a techno ish violin ish noise.
Scott: I I like a digital violin At this point, and there's a piece of the song where it plays four notes And then the other song happens, and then it.
Scott: you know the thing happens if you wait.
Rym: so other stuff happens.
Scott: I don't know what the other stuff is.
Scott: I can't remember it at all.
Rym: so how is this playing in your head?
Rym: What does it sound like in your head?
Scott: I cannot reproduce it with my mouse because my mouth is not a digital violin, but any my head.
Rym: it plays back different ways So you don't even remember it.
Rym: you've got nothing stuck in your head.
Scott: Remember the sound of that kind of instrument.
Rym: so having a four note Riff kind of thing, but how does the riff go listen to this?
Rym: the first two notes of the riff?
Rym: It's in your head.
Rym: You can hear it right now.
Scott: No because it doesn't continue with that instrument.
Scott: that instrument only plays that little bit and the rest of the song does not involve that.
Rym: Can you name any other song that has a similar instrument?
Rym: no no no I Don't think you've got anything stuck in your head.
Rym: I do or I think you've got so little stuck in your head that you've kind of found an exception of the human brain.
Rym: It's so little that you will never be able to identify it.
Rym: and even if you do you won't be sure if it's it.
Rym: So you'll never get it.
Scott: if I hear it for real.
Scott: I'll be absolutely sure that it's it.
Rym: How do you know what if you hear something similar?
Scott: because the NP problem you can easily verify.
Rym: See the trouble is there are so many songs that are so similar that what if you hear a song And you're not sure if it's it, but it's the closest you'll ever get?
Scott: That'll be bad, but yes Even if I'm sure it's it and it's even if it's not it as long as I'm sure it's it I'll still feel alright.
Scott: You're sure it goes four times, and it's for definitely four notes.
Scott: that is for definite.
Rym: She said how long is each note?
Rym: not very long like a second.
Scott: Yeah, it's like maybe like one measure is like the whole thing.
Rym: one measure could last like 40 years.
Scott: You know what I'm saying?
Rym: no, I don't.
Rym: what's the time signature?
Rym: What key is it in?
Rym: That's a time signature is not you waving your hand at me.
Scott: It's like a Couple seconds of you know.
Scott: maybe one half seconds ish.
Rym: Wow Scott, I mean, I'll pick a song.
Rym: I know that you know too, and it goes dead to dip and I don't remember the rest.
Rym: What song is that?
Rym: I mean you're fucked.
Scott: Yeah, you know what.
Scott: someone's gonna find out the song and it's got the song.
Rym: I know the song I'm thinking of.
Rym: you know the song very well, but did?
Rym: it is not enough.
Scott: It would be enough if I heard the actual recording and not just you dead.
Rym: But no one's going to hear the actual recording of your thing.
Rym: They're gonna hear you going dead dead dead dead I you know.
Rym: I think someone actually will though post a link and I'll figure out what the song is of a violin going and Up or down at least four times and then another instrument that isn't the same techno violin.
Scott: I'm pretty sure it's a something we dancy song which limits it quite a bit.
Rym: not that much.
Scott: It's possibly a hit Scott.
Rym: I downloaded a torrent some years ago of every dance pop song from 1980 to 1989 Legitimately released in the United States.
Rym: I think that there are a lot of them.
Scott: I think that this is a 2009 tennis song.
Rym: so what do you base that on?
Scott: Just because the song that I never heard a long time ago, but I feel like I've heard it recently Aha, just feeling any idea where?
Rym: when did it get stuck in your head?
Scott: I think it got in my head a long time ago, but then reemerged in my head.
Rym: reemerge because So what triggered it?
Rym: you got to figure out what triggered it and that will lead you toward the answer.
Scott: brains They do things.
Rym: So I guess normally this is when we'd talk about anime news that being anime night, but there's only one anime news.
Rym: I didn't believe it.
Rym: Darryl Surratt Messaged me and I guess everyone else in the world that he knows on the internet in a panic.
Scott: Well actually before he messaged me I saw the tweet or a retweet from Murayama who was like someone important to the studio has died And I was like okay, and I just sort of ignored it until I got the message.
Rym: Yeah, the message I got and I think Darryl Surratt put it more eloquently than anyone else in the world.
Scott: What he said this is bullshit.
Rym: He said quotes.
Rym: Satoshi Kon is fucking dead.
Rym: That is some bullshit.
Scott: That is some bullshit indeed.
Scott: And that is not just some bullshit.
Scott: That's all the bullshit.
Rym: I can't even this is you know, what's bullshit?
Rym: It's actually take care on so many levels mainly because you know We myself Scout and Emily went to a retrospective of Satoshi Collins works in New York City Not that long ago and I know he had.
Rym: they screened paprika and then he came out and talked to us and he was really cool.
Rym: And he very pointedly said I'm paraphrasing because it was translated and I'm going on memory.
Rym: He said four notes played I think by a techno violin.
Rym: He basically said I feel that this is too much of an honor for me.
Rym: I'm just too early in my career for you to give me a retrospective.
Rym: Let me come back after I've actually done something Mm-hmm, and he never did anything else.
Rym: No movie of his came out after that.
Rym: That was it.
Scott: Yeah, I mean that was the first time we saw like a single still image of the movie that he's doing next Which you can see on the website for that movie the dream machine, which has a robot in it
Rym: It looks like the but
Scott: I mean they already spent.
Scott: there's a sunk cost fallacy.
Scott: They're probably gonna finish, you know, they haven't said anything but I can almost guarantee they're gonna finish the movie without him.
Scott: But is that really gonna be a good movie now?
Scott: I mean maybe part, you know, and then that's gonna be it, right?
Scott: That's it.
Scott: He didn't work on anything else.
Rym: So Yeah, it's just I know it bothers me primarily aside from every other reason I mean there have been directors and celebrities and people that I've seen die or I've known about and then they died and I was Sad.
Rym: but like how Miyazaki has had a full career I feel like he is trying desperately to die in the middle of his last film.
Rym: But he keeps going.
Rym: he keeps making things and I feel like while it would be sad if he died He has done a lot.
Rym: Tezuka did a lot.
Scott: I feel like he died when he was 60 though.
Rym: So that was still pretty early It was but he still did a lot.
Rym: I feel like Satoshi khan would have done twice.
Rym: again is more and and even more.
Rym: beyond that I can't imagine what he would have done if he had lived another 40 years.
Scott: It also doesn't help right that like.
Scott: really who else was you know?
Scott: Making the hits right in terms of anime.
Scott: They're really, you know in terms of like greatest living anime director I mean, okay, maybe Miyazaki is better in terms of his whole body of work.
Scott: But Miyazaki lately not really Mamoru Oshii lately not really Satoshi khan in terms of what have you done for me lately is Even in death probably the greatest current anime director, you know in terms of the stuff that he's done recently.
Scott: What other anime movies in any recent year in the past decade?
Rym: There is good.
Rym: I can think I get why I get.
Scott: no I guess decade does allow you to bring in like spirited away and stuff, but like piyazaki.
Rym: Yeah past few years We'll have to go to things like Mamoru Hosoda.
Scott: Yeah, right, which is Next level down from so she can at least.
Rym: What's really sad?
Rym: Well, I guess I keep saying what's really sad.
Rym: It's all really sad.
Scott: It's all said I was.
Rym: I mean It's rare that I'm taken aback by the loss of someone like.
Scott: I know right?
Scott: It's weird and it I think we're really says something is okay.
Scott: Look, okay He's made all these great movies and a great TV show right?
Scott: He was he was really awesome and beloved by anime fans.
Rym: He was also one of his of the like the successor series of anime directors and anime people.
Rym: He's one of those people who worked under a great did key animation things like that and worked up and became the great Yep, there aren't that many anime directors Right.
Scott: So having a big reaction in the anime community is kind of expected.
Scott: but his movies Honestly, at least outside of Japan especially are not that well known, you know, they're on DVD.
Scott: They go to a movie theater for a short run maybe But most people have no idea who he is or never heard of any of his movies.
Scott: But yet it wasn't.
Scott: just like anime news net where you know, a Crayon Shinshan crater died.
Scott: Remember he got like lost or fell off a cliff or something like that when he went into the woods.
Scott: Right, that's a big deal.
Scott: Crayon Shinshan manga crater.
Scott: That's a like an epic ultra famous manga with elephant dances in it.
Scott: You know, it's been going on forever You know, but they didn't.
Scott: the only place you heard about that was anime news network at least in English.
Scott: But Satoshi khan, you know at least 24 hours, you know this morning he died yesterday, right but this morning Kotaku boing boing Every freaking blog.
Scott: right, you know, that is, you know gaming.
Scott: everything was posting about it.
Rym: Not just the anime site speaks of how powerful his movies were.
Rym: I mean look at his entire body of work.
Rym: It's not just that he never had a miss or he never had a bomb.
Rym: It's that without exception Everything he made was brilliant.
Scott: and it's not just like I'm sure like he says his manga wasn't brilliant and haven't read it.
Rym: Yeah, I haven't read it either.
Scott: So aside from his manga all the all the things that he's known for, you know starting with you know Like rojansy perfect blue, you know magnetic rose and You know the paprika paranoia agent.
Rym: and it's not just us saying this.
Rym: It's not just like hardcore anime fans saying this.
Rym: his movies had a real Universal appeal and they were so different from everything else I watch and they're
Scott: like the only you know in terms like we grew up watching some animes like Akira and some leji Matsumoto stuff and that kind of thing, right and that's the reason we like to anime were those kinds of anime And he's really the only person who is still making those kinds of anime.
Scott: So it's not just sad for the death of him and the things that he will not create.
Scott: But also it's like the kind of anime that we like has died.
Scott: You know, where?
Scott: where is the kind of anime we like now?
Scott: It's gone.
Scott: There's no more who's gonna make it.
Scott: No one that no one that we know of is who is capable of making the kind of anime we like is either Passed on or is no longer making the kind of anime we like or no longer making anime period or is making anime We don't like.
Scott: So it just.
Scott: it's just bad though.
Rym: I what got me is I wasn't really moved to tears.
Rym: It takes a lot to actually make me feel that like watching Jim Henson's funeral again.
Scott: That is the ultimate crying weapon that brought me down.
Rym: but I was reading anime news network posted.
Rym: It was difficult to get to his site because it was just destroyed under the just the massive traffic.
Rym: But some of his final words are there for reading.
Rym: an anime news network is likely Translated some of them.
Rym: and in regards to his the new movie I'm pretty sure it's going to be finished and it's going to be what he wanted because it was written by him Right.
Scott: So he wrote it.
Rym: the screenplay everything was by him and the art director in the character design were someone else.
Rym: So I have a feeling they'll be able to finish it close to his vision.
Rym: But a quote from his some of his last words.
Rym: when I conveyed my concerns for Yumei Muru Kikai to mr Murayama, he said it's fine.
Rym: Don't worry.
Rym: We'll do whatever it takes.
Scott: Mm-hmm Yeah, Murayama is like a champ and the thing was Gerald pointed out in a tweet, right?
Scott: Murayama was at Otakon as he always is.
Scott: He never misses it.
Scott: Yeah, he's staff and You know people were asking him because he's the head of studio madhouse.
Scott: right who does all of you know Satoshi khan stuff and the people are asking him about Satoshi khan Of course because that of all of the stuff studio madhouse does.
Scott: that's the stuff we want the most Right.
Scott: tell us about the dream machine, you know, come on give it up.
Scott: But he knew at that point right that Satoshi khan was you know done for so it's like Gerald was like.
Scott: What was he thinking when people are asking him that at Otakon that must have been really tough.
Rym: Yeah, you know like whoa and and the worst thing is I mean it was pancreatic cancer.
Rym: It's almost no one survives pancreatic cancer.
Rym: It's basically you're.
Scott: it's like, you know talk about you know, oh my whoa.
Rym: Oh, I mean by the time you detect it, it's too late.
Rym: There's really nothing you can do.
Rym: even massive crazy treatment gives you like a 5% chance of living five years.
Scott: The biggest problem is simply that you don't really feel anything in your pancreas Right.
Scott: and like if you have cancer on your skin, you can see it even though that's really bad, too Right, but if you have cancer in the lung, it's like I can't breathe.
Scott: it hurts.
Scott: You know you have pains and things but when you have cancer in the pancreas You don't feel that.
Scott: and as long unless it makes such a giant lump that it sticks out or something You're not even notice that.
Scott: so Until it spreads to another part of your body where you can feel it and you know Then go to the doctor.
Scott: you're the doctor is not even gonna really check for it.
Scott: you go to a physical.
Scott: They don't check you for pancreatic cancer, you know, maybe if you happen to get a blood test They would see cancer cells floating around in there.
Scott: But even then you're and you're in big trouble if you're already that far gone.
Scott: So it's it's pretty much the worst.
Scott: Everything's the worst.
Rym: Yeah, and it's you know, like Emily I were talking about this a lot last night.
Rym: There are some people who are artists like Jim Henson where they did no wrong and they kind of were taken away Suddenly when they said a lot more potential.
Rym: and there are people who start out just as strong But either complete their career and just go down in history as legends.
Rym: Yeah or the one like the Michael Jackson who start out and they're weird when they die and something weird happens and it almost It doesn't quite have the same impact.
Scott: No, it's definitely far more, you know, cuz like we didn't.
Scott: you know, we met him once Right, the man lived, you know Too short, but 47 46 47 years, but he had such impact.
Rym: I couldn't help but think back to meeting him and I it was yeah, it was tough.
Scott: Yeah, it's that but it's like it does.
Rym: it hurts that he was so cool in person too.
Scott: He was just a normal guy.
Scott: It's like it wasn't like, you know.
Scott: Meanwhile, somebody like the niche who's all drugged up and whatnot and playing with guns is just fine, right?
Rym: What Was it?
Rym: someone on Fark.
Rym: they were talking about this and he basically said why couldn't it have been M night?
Scott: Well, and I was.
Scott: I went to 2chan and there was a gigantic thread with like thousands of posts in it Right and I pumped it through the Google Translator and the only one that I saw that was kind of funny and well Translated or relatively well translated was it was a short comment.
Scott: It said please instead of Satoshi.
Scott: Khan is Mamoru.
Scott: Oh she And it's like, you know, Mamoru she he made a lot of great animes probably more great animes that.
Scott: so she Khan is made but It's like he's sort of done ish, you know, it's like he made sky callers, which is pretty good But I would put sky callers below pretty much every.
Scott: she has the problem.
Rym: So she Khan is done as we always say where the things he's best at the things he at least seems to want to do.
Rym: Yeah, we want him to make action comedy anime.
Rym: He wants to make.
Scott: If Mamoru she died it's like it would be sad but it wouldn't be.
Scott: as Said I guess even if Miyazaki died, it wouldn't be.
Scott: as said.
Rym: there's just.
Rym: there's something.
Rym: there's a confluence of factors around Satoshi Kong that made the impact just universally felt among anyone who enjoys art.
Rym: Mm-hmm It's a dark day for anime - I mean look look at the entire landscape of anime and animation has changed.
Scott: probably.
Scott: I mean you look at just celebrity deaths in general and it's rare that you see one that comes so early in someone who is so awesome who is still a lot to go and Didn't have any weirdness at all, you know, even when you see something like a river Phoenix, right?
Scott: It's like well He was drugged up, you know, it's like there was you know, you don't you're not gonna you know Cry over someone who's all drug addicted and whatnot.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well you will but I don't know it.
Rym: just it feels different.
Scott: This is the other thing is that we weren't really alive when John Lennon was shot.
Scott: I think that's pretty much one of the only things you can compare it to.
Rym: yeah I'm pretty sure that people who live through that feel about the same way that we do now.
Rym: Yeah What really got me though was the final update on the website.
Rym: to quote Satoshi Kong It's basically his last public words with feelings of gratitude for all that is good in the world.
Rym: I put down my pen.
Rym: Well, I'll be leaving now.
Scott: That's pretty much it.
Rym: So one more lighthearted note things of the day All right, I'm gonna go.
Rym: you want to go.
Rym: so I had.
Rym: I have to.
Scott: You know, I got to.
Scott: I got this problem lately.
Scott: right where you know what an itch?
Scott: No Where you know, I want to go somewhere maybe on my bicycle or some such right, but I got to carry some things like wallet Phone keys, you know that sort of thing.
Rym: You could carry a purse, right?
Scott: So I put my bag, you know, and I take that's to match the shoes obvious My whole bag to work right on my back.
Scott: But that's a lot to carry.
Scott: and if I'm not going somewhere where I need to carry that whole bag Timbuktu bag what's you know, that's a big pain in the butt to carry the huge bags.
Rym: I'll admit the bag was much more useful when I had the long commute now.
Rym: I don't really care I carry nothing on me.
Scott: Yeah, but I still need to carry some stuff.
Scott: Now the thing is I could put in my pockets if I'm walking but if I'm biking Phone might just come out of the pocket land in the street get run over by a car pants.
Rym: Are you wearing?
Scott: Nothing falls out of pockets if I'm biking it totally good.
Scott: No, you got terrible pants, then I guess I'm not wearing tight girly jeans where everything is like right up next to my skin.
Scott: But anyway, I found this product which is not our existing product yet, but check it out.
Scott: this is the fit kit.
Rym: I've seen a million things like that.
Rym: You can buy them for like 10 bucks.
Scott: Look at this target, but look this one is like totally perfect and even has a metro card in the picture.
Scott: I mean And an iPhone 4. it's like that's for me, right?
Scott: I have a metro card and an iPhone.
Rym: It's one of those fancy things you wrap around your arm and it holds your wallet.
Scott: But look you can also wrap it around a water bottle or or yoga mat Cylindrically shaped object.
Scott: right now the here's the interesting more interesting thing than this awesome product itself, right?
Scott: Which is pretty awesome Is the website it's on is a website called the quirky Calm and the way quirky works is it's sort of like Kickstarter for cool shit All right.
Scott: so you go on here and you have a product and you put up images of this product you've designed and after you put up a price and You put up the discounted price and as soon as a certain number of people buy it Then it becomes a real product.
Scott: and if it never becomes a real product They never charge you because they don't charge you until it's ready.
Scott: So I basically made a promise to pay $25, but they didn't actually take any dollars from me.
Scott: So if it never happens it never happens.
Scott: But if it does happen, I totally get one.
Scott: and this site has a bunch of other cool products like here's some things to help you, you know, here's look at this a crazy Swiss Army knife thing.
Scott: and here's a dustpan that has Prongs in it to let you clean the broom more easily.
Scott: and here's a thing to help you cool Cool wine without getting water all over the place You know, uh-huh.
Scott: So that's cool.
Scott: Yeah is a whole bunch of cool stuff on here.
Scott: It's sort of like Kickstarter Etsy combo.
Rym: much more important is this mashup of the fuck you Song that has been making the rounds lately with the Shawshank Redemption.
Scott: That's a pretty good mashup.
Scott: I like.
Rym: I like this sort of thing.
Rym: I mean we see it every now and then.
Scott: That's the best part of this.
Rym: was it done with a violin?
Rym: four times?
Rym: no sure yeah, I Almost like when you have the idea for the enemy music video.
Rym: That's just perfect.
Rym: Like what if I just did Linkin Park?
Rym: Crawling to Dragon Ball Z like it fits so well that you just got to do it.
Rym: Well, this is a situation.
Rym: I mean look at this movie.
Rym: does this song?
Rym: had that song existed in the time and when the movie was made Would it not have worked?
Scott: You know, I forget the actual song that was used in the movie.
Rym: in my mind It's already rewritten as I wonder I think we're going to see more and more.
Rym: This is a total aside Mainstream ish songs that have such vulgar language in them that the radio really can't even get away with bleeping it out Like they do already.
Scott: This isn't a mainstream song.
Scott: There's like an internet song.
Rym: But what about when that becomes mainstream?
Scott: then of course people radio be gone?
Rym: What's the radio gonna play?
Rym: just 50s music forever?
Scott: Just be Internet's only.
Scott: Yeah, that's it.
Rym: So because that was kind of weak, I mean it's fun, but you can watch the first 30 seconds of this and you'll get it.
Scott: Yeah, and let you know unless you haven't seen the Shawshank Redemption I mean in which case what the fuck is wrong with you.
Rym: They get points for executing to complete V to the Netflix Because I will admit that the original born to be alive with horn was just a concept.
Rym: They're like, hey, here's the joke.
Rym: and they made like a 30-second music video, but this guy had the joke and made the full thing Mm-hmm.
Scott: So it wasn't much work.
Scott: You didn't even really have to edit the video.
Rym: Nobody edited the audio to make it fit with the scene changes very well.
Rym: He also modulated it.
Rym: It took some work Yeah, but to make up for the fact that that wasn't punchy I Present to you a video of a kid putting an egg on a skateboard and trying to launch it in the air as a catapult.
Scott: Well, isn't this just a freaking own video?
Scott: It is my key is on better than that.
Rym: So here's why I picked this.
Rym: over all the own videos that I could have picked one the kid Clearly thinks that something awesome is going to happen.
Rym: He puts the eggs not even aiming at anyone.
Rym: from what I can tell exactly I don't even know why he's filming this.
Rym: He's puts the egg on the skateboard stands in front of it and then stops on the skateboard.
Rym: now There is no possible outcome But this just hitting him in the face.
Rym: and it does in fact hit him in the face as you would expect Which is fine.
Rym: That would be an own video.
Rym: but then he pushes arms down and he stands there looking at himself with this look of how the fuck did that happen?
Rym: like he does not realize what he is wrought that he did not foresee and That the last second of this video is why it is my thing of the day.
Scott: Yeah, I wish that the Someone can make a video where they launch an egg into the air off the skateboard and then sort of catch it without breaking.
Scott: It's some awesome Parkourish trick.
Scott: or maybe we should start a new sub-genre of parkour where you have an egg with you But you're not allowed to put the egg in any sort of sling or holster or grab it.
Scott: The egg has to be free-moving as well.
Scott: You said I have to tap it or bobble it or whatever.
Scott: egg park or dribble it.
Rym: no egg park or use.
Rym: have a race First one or simultaneously first one to the top of the building with the egg wins.
Scott: But you can't actually grasp the egg.
Scott: You have to constantly.
Scott: egg has to be in motion, you know sort of like in basketball or bottle.
Scott: Yeah, that would be.
Scott: or like you could balance it on your head.
Scott: That would be okay.
Scott: like all the way Double egg all the way.
Rym: So we went to the theater not that long ago In fact this weekend and we saw a slightly older anime movie a Miyazaki movie that we had not seen Studio Ghibli movie.
Rym: Yes, Studio Ghibli Miyazaki can't lose right?
Scott: which uh Miyazaki was that was that high on.
Rym: Goro go to make good tournament schedule.
Scott: I'm sorry go to Goro nepotism give you job.
Rym: Ursula K Le Guin sadly probably said it best Because I've you know ghetto Sankey tales of Earthsea is nominally based on four of the Earthsea books.
Scott: Well, I think it's mostly based on the third one, which I read a long time ago.
Scott: But it says it's based on even really based on it.
Scott: It's based on them in that they use the same proper nouns.
Scott: That's pretty much it.
Rym: Yeah And even then they say get like once the title is ghetto Sankey and yet they refer to was sparrowhawk.
Rym: the whole time I think his name get get said.
Scott: Well, that's in the book.
Scott: You know, that's usually how it goes as well.
Rym: Well, yes, right.
Scott: You have never read the books.
Scott: You have no fucking clue.
Rym: Yeah, why why why?
Scott: and if Forget is in the title.
Scott: Why is the main character Aaron the prince guy?
Rym: Ursula K Le Guin first said and I quote It is not my book No, it is your movie it is a good movie.
Rym: But then later she said and I quote and this really really really puts it into perspective.
Rym: This was the result of quote when too much responsibility was shouldered by someone not equipped for it.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: This movie was pretty terrible.
Scott: Oh, well, you wasn't.
Scott: I wouldn't say it's terrible I would just say you remove.
Scott: I would just say was mediocre.
Rym: I will say this if you remove the fact that the animation is lush and beautiful if remove the beauty of the Animation the technical beauty of the of the film.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: It's not even mediocre.
Rym: the plot Consists of basically nothing.
Rym: I would argue that the vast majority of the scenes in this movie do not advance any plot or any characters Motivation whatsoever.
Scott: the ones that I think the scenes that really get me are You know scenes where maybe.
Scott: so there's two kinds of scenes that really bothered me.
Scott: right.
Scott: one is the kind of thing where you think it's an interesting scene and maybe they're setting something up and maybe something'll come of It and then they don't.
Scott: but then and it's useless like the scene where he gets like accosted by the drug dealer It's like oh that was kind of interesting.
Scott: The dealer is an interesting character.
Scott: Maybe something would happen there and no it was completely in the cold context of the movie.
Scott: That seemed didn't even mean it.
Rym: and the worst part is so later in the movie, right?
Rym: Dude gets poisoned and his lips turn the same color as that poison.
Rym: and because of the plot you think oh Maybe they're doing something up.
Rym: Not at all and nothing not related.
Rym: Neither scene was necessary.
Scott: other kind of scene that bothered me is the nothing scene like put the ox in the bar.
Rym: Okay, I will go put the ox in the barn cut to the barn.
Scott: He literally put the ox in the barn two or three times, but never did he actually put the ox in the barn.
Rym: Now the thing is.
Rym: a scene like that is fine, we love oshi movies where there's just long Stretches.
Scott: look at evangelical.
Scott: how many see?
Scott: awesome scenes are there where someone's just quietly walking down the street or looking at the window While you hear the cicadas and look at the trees in sky crawler?
Scott: remind you that it's summer and it's really hot.
Rym: I was in raptured by a scene where he sits there for a while slowly gets up turns around opens the fridge gets an orange Soda closes his fridge turns around slowly drinks it.
Scott: Yep,
Rym: but in all those movies Every time you see this, you know atmosphere is what makes anime good atmosphere is one of the things that's common in anime that we Like when they'll have scenes that set an atmosphere or a mood and those sorts of scenes are often missing from Western film.
Rym: but when those scenes add nothing to the movie whatsoever and literally are just boring.
Scott: and Well, I think what makes them boring right in this movie is that think about the cicadas from revenge alien, right?
Scott: It's just you know, nothing really moves.
Scott: There's nothing happening.
Scott: It's just cricket cricket cricket.
Scott: It's summer, you know, cicadas cicadas cicadas, right?
Scott: Well, you look at this in in in this movie.
Scott: What would you get instead?
Scott: you would get quiet?
Scott: Look, here is a building and you see one of the characters walking slowly and quietly.
Scott: They're just walking and they're doing something completely mundane and not symbolic in any way.
Scott: they're actually doing something like, you know plowing a field or Cooking something and there it's about.
Scott: it's not symbolic.
Scott: It's not setting it Mood, it's just someone doing something.
Scott: It's like you might as well show me hit this whole walk through the grocery store Comparing the cereals and picking one and then checking out one item at a time and then bagging the groceries.
Scott: It's like it's not symbolic.
Scott: I think it's not setting a mood.
Scott: It's just someone doing boring shit.
Rym: I think the trouble is even more fundamental than that because in movies where there are like a long slice of life scene like you All right, they're farming.
Rym: maybe the farming and the plowing is because they're bonding over something.
Rym: maybe there's some kind of implicit character development.
Rym: or Maybe they've already set up that you like these characters and now they're giving you this slice of life So that later when their their routine is ruined by the plot you feel sympathetic for them being pulled out of that.
Scott: Yeah, like you plow the field and then you plow the field again But then someone come something happens during that.
Rym: so or you call the field and you get all the screen time about plowing the field In the montage of them doing this or maybe The field gets destroyed.
Scott: or maybe they're giving advice about plowing the field and something about plowing the field.
Scott: Some sort of you know Like lesson some life lesson while about plowing like work hard or something in the later on Says the same thing again when he's got to fight the bad guy like remember the plowing of the field He's on wax off.
Scott: exactly.
Scott: That's exactly what.
Rym: there's a scene where the main character is plowing and gay.
Rym: it is helping him plan against blisters.
Rym: And he's like you have blisters and he looks at his hand and then they show us the blisters like oh he's got blisters now.
Rym: Maybe they're setting up some metaphor for he was nobility.
Rym: He'd never worked the land before he'd never lived a normal life.
Rym: Maybe they're setting up some sort.
Rym: There's all sorts of things they could have been doing.
Rym: No, then get says we should want to rest a little bit.
Rym: Okay, they rest they continue.
Rym: that never comes up again here.
Scott: You want to hear something?
Scott: Here's something that probably the worst thing in the whole movie, right?
Scott: So the opening scene of the movie the prince kills the king.
Rym: Oh, all right.
Rym: So I think we should just double away.
Scott: That's not the worst part of it for no, you know for a reason that's never explained or explored That doesn't come up at all.
Scott: But the real problem right was remember those two girls who were like appealing for the prince.
Rym: I forgot about that All right.
Scott: So there's these girls appealing for the prince and as if they're going to be important characters and there's something about them.
Scott: Movie at all ever not after that one scene and that means not it.
Rym: What about root?
Rym: No character from the beginning of the movie is in the end of the movie or even the middle of the movie.
Rym: Now you can if there was a Hitchcock movie I mean Pessacchio starts with a heist and this woman's getting away with the heist and then oh shit serial killer and no one saw that coming.
Rym: I guess I spoiled Pessacchio if you've never seen it.
Scott: Oh, no, as long as you didn't spoil psycho.
Scott: It is actually.
Scott: But This is no one really wants to see Pessacchio.
Rym: Imagine if I don't know the matrix started right and you meet all these characters.
Rym: What is the matrix?
Rym: and Neo and Morpheus and then it just kind of cuts to these other people and that's the whole rest of?
Rym: The movie.
Scott: and they never go back except except for one character who's still there, but that's it.
Rym: Yeah, but even then the prince is barely there.
Rym: He's not in the beginning.
Scott: He's not there at all.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: They just sort of talk about the Prince until he actually kills his dad.
Scott: he just sort of comes out.
Scott: No, that's it.
Rym: So you don't even know it's his dad at first.
Rym: So here's the movie right it opens.
Rym: so yeah.
Scott: So the movie would open with all the characters of the matrix and then some guy would stab Morpheus and the movie would be about the guy who stabbed Morpheus and none and Morpheus and none of the other characters that ever appear again.
Rym: So the movie starts right.
Rym: it opens, you know credits Miyazaki movie.
Rym: Let's go and There's a ship and it's all beautiful and there's dragons and the dragons fight and that never happens.
Scott: and you think they just did.
Scott: They just threw the dragons in their fighting's just so that they could open with an action scene.
Scott: with this stuff going on.
Rym: and you wonder What's this setting?
Scott: the dragons have nothing to do with the story at all?
Rym: Dragons basically don't come back until the end and they come back in a way that is unrelated to the Dragons Mm-hmm.
Rym: So dragon scene stops.
Rym: now We're in the kingdom and like there's all this political stuff in political discussions and the Kings asking root who I guess is the wizard of the court what's going on?
Rym: the world is shifting all this craziness and Then this kid runs out of nowhere and stabs the king.
Rym: Yep, that like that.
Scott: I don't even know you don't even really get that.
Scott: He's the prince until a little while later.
Rym: I Barely remember what happens after that.
Rym: and the next thing I know We've got GED Sparrow Hawk and the kid and they're hanging out with this woman in Taru this other girl who has a burn on Her face.
Scott: Well, you didn't.
Scott: you didn't read the tomb.
Scott: That's the thing, right?
Scott: They use they borrow all these proper nouns from all the Earthsea books.
Rym: See I'm pretending I know nothing about Earthsea.
Scott: Well, you've only read one book right?
Rym: I started the second one and then I got distracted.
Scott: Okay but I mean it's like so.
Scott: They give you all these proper nouns the characters of the same names and sort of the same roles.
Scott: But on the one hand they don't.
Scott: they really only take the proper nouns.
Scott: They don't take anything else about the characters really.
Scott: but at the same time the characters have a lot of discussions.
Scott: That will make no sense.
Scott: If you haven't read the books like.
Scott: they'll talk about the Wizards of Roke a bunch.
Scott: You have no clue who the Wizards of Roke are.
Scott: if you haven't read the Earthsea books You'd be like what the fuck Roke?
Scott: what?
Scott: but the worst thing is Roke All right.
Rym: So mentioning all these things adding all this side stuff in none of that matters.
Scott: No, it doesn't actually Factor into the plot you see in the movie in any way whatsoever, but they spend time having characters discuss it.
Rym: So I would argue that nothing factors into the plot of the movie.
Rym: the plot of the movie if I had to summarize it Is dude kills his dad Wanders off meets an old guy that hang out on a farm for a while.
Rym: Pedophile kidnaps him.
Rym: his shadow comes and gives a sword to a girl who turns out to be a dragon.
Scott: But she's not a dragon.
Scott: but she is.
Scott: yeah, but there's no reason why it did.
Scott: yet her name is Tohono Which is the name of the fourth Earthsea book?
Rym: Now Immediately after them alright, so I don't care if you've seen the movie or not.
Rym: We're just spoiling it because there's nothing you know You don't need to go see.
Rym: at the end of the movie the girl just turns into a dragon.
Rym: no foreshadowing whatsoever In fact, the pedophile old guy kills her.
Scott: no explanation whatsoever.
Rym: It does a funny dance.
Rym: He kills her and then he kind of goes like I guess she's dead.
Rym: She's dead.
Rym: She's dead And then she stands back up, and she's like I'm not dead.
Rym: and then she turns into a dragon and kills him.
Rym: Okay, Wow now you're thinking alright.
Rym: So maybe you know the dragons never fight with each other and they told us earlier that Teru's mother and father Had left her to die and burned her and that's where she got the scar and they were dead something like that.
Rym: So they set this up and in the beginning of the movie two dragons were fighting and one dragon killed another dragon or at least Injured it severely and that was supposed to let you know something's wrong with the world.
Scott: so the balance is fucked.
Rym: Imagine if the dragon that had fallen was her and she didn't remember she was a dragon until just then.
Rym: or What if she was the daughter of the two dragons that had fought and that was the plot of her real and the whole?
Rym: What if she was the protagonist?
Rym: that would have been an awesome movie?
Scott: Well this gives you something else right?
Scott: is that we watched the dub in the theater And you know what you know.
Scott: Disney's usually pretty good with the Miyazaki dubbing.
Rym: They definitely phoned this one in.
Scott: They phoned it in so bad.
Scott: There were some names in there that were pretty relatively big not as big as like the modern names.
Scott: They had a Mononoke and so.
Rym: Cheech Marin's in there.
Scott: Yeah But really this dub is so phoned in and I'm not sure if I can't tell because they didn't have any Subtitles or anything not that I could understand Japanese anyway.
Scott: But like the dub acting was phoned in.
Scott: but regardless the dub script was bad.
Scott: But was it the dub script that was bad, or was it a good script and just the original script was bad?
Rym: I am pretty sure the original script was bad.
Scott: I think I feel like it was a combination of original bad script and dubbed bad.
Rym: No, cause going back through the scenes I can think of no point where any different words said by any character would have made the movie better.
Scott: That's that's true, but even so it was.
Scott: some of the people said some pretty stupid shit.
Rym: What was with the pedophile at the end?
Rym: What did he?
Rym: even he comes out of nowhere?
Rym: He's just oh shit.
Rym: He's there.
Rym: Oh shit.
Rym: He poise.
Scott: We gotta go get the bad guy.
Scott: Where's the bad guy?
Scott: That's the bad guy.
Scott: We're suddenly showing you a bad guy.
Scott: He's obviously bad.
Scott: And even then what'd he do?
Scott: He was bad.
Scott: What'd he do?
Scott: He upset the ballad.
Rym: But how?
Scott: He was looking evil and casting evil Magic, you know his evil cause was purple so dark.
Rym: I like how he.
Scott: he wore black and lived in a castle where everything was black.
Rym: So here's where any hired guys who were slave really obviously starts to break down.
Rym: So he's pedophile.
Rym: I guess he acts like one talks like one looks like one.
Rym: He's kind of I don't remember exactly what happens.
Rym: but eventually the the heroes come to save everybody and He gets his head cut off or his hand cut off I don't remember.
Rym: and then Suddenly turns into a blob and he grabs the girl and runs away super fast as a blob.
Rym: and once he gets a little bit Away, he turns back into a slow old man and starts hobbling away like one mile an hour.
Scott: That is one thing that I've noticed in a lot of Ghibli movies, right is they really love to draw Anything?
Scott: that's sort of liquidy and swarmy even if it's not a Hayao Miyazaki movie, right?
Scott: Like beginning of Princess Mononoke the whole big wormy covered warthog beast, right.
Scott: and then you've got in Spirited away, you've got when the things are all splashing down in the crazy bathtub right the big black ooze thing that comes comes in.
Scott: they have to wash it right.
Scott: and then in Ponyo, there's all the water is always going Right all over the place.
Scott: and is there a movie in the middle that I was missing?
Scott: Oh How's moving castle?
Scott: I guess sort of had it.
Scott: I can't remember a specific scene Okay, but you know.
Scott: and then the black in this movie the guy turns into like a black slime and is all But only runs like a hundred feet with that.
Rym: then he turns back.
Scott: But I'm saying the Ghibli.
Scott: people love to draw that for some reason even better.
Rym: So they're chasing him.
Rym: He climbs up a tower So the main character chases him and they get to the top of the tower and they're gonna have their Great.
Scott: when the stairs he was climbing got crushed But there just happened to be two platforms just like a video game.
Scott: that happens to not be crushed so he could make the jump.
Rym: and then when they get to the Top and they're about to have their face off the bad guy just goes Around the corner and climbs up another flight of stairs and then they have the face off there.
Rym: Why?
Rym: And why does he kill Tara?
Scott: Why did it take so long to get up there?
Rym: By making his arm turn all blobby and muscly around her.
Rym: Yeah, like what was up with that?
Scott: just go stab or something?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I I'm at a loss to tell you what happened in this.
Scott: when you have the up the stairs chase You're supposed to have action like a guy throwing rocks at the other guy You know, there was.
Scott: where was the action?
Scott: there was no action scene choreography whatsoever.
Rym: It didn't matter because they did the top.
Rym: nothing happened.
Rym: It didn't matter what was going to happen because she was a dragon and she's just gonna kill him.
Rym: Yeah that there's nothing that could have stopped her from killing him.
Scott: It's really sad because you know the Earthsea books are so great and a good great movie great TV show great anime Adaptation great comic adaptation could be made of them easily, right?
Scott: It's not like some other fantasy novels where it's they're difficult to adapt.
Scott: These are pretty easy to adapt in my book.
Scott: in my mind Anyway, I can easily imagine it as an excellent movie that is faithful to the books.
Scott: However, we've had so far a TV miniseries that was horrendous and because of that TV miniseries This movie was delayed in its American release.
Scott: So this movie finally comes out in America when the you guessed.
Scott: the license for that TV miniseries That was so terrible is gone and it's also terrible.
Scott: What the fuck?
Scott: What the fuck.
Rym: but this movie was terrible in an extra special way because it was boring as fuck.
Scott: one guy in the theater fell asleep and some other guy kicked.
Scott: him was like hey, I Was just at no point was I excited or caring.
Rym: I was excited in the beginning Cuz our dragons fighting and then there's obviously this big political plot building and I'm thinking alright, maybe this isn't so bad Where's it gonna go this guy?
Rym: I mean, it's still a Ghibli.
Rym: It's got it up.
Scott: What you did in my movie Dragon, I don't know why like why did they feel the need to like rewrite the whole thing?
Scott: Why didn't they just take the first book and turn it into a movie?
Scott: Well, and that's it Alright.
Scott: So the thing is that has all.
Scott: that first book has all sorts of great Ghibli moments Like you go to the Isle of Roke and you got to enter you got to talk to the gatekeeper guy Right, and I mean, that's so awesome That's such a Ghibli kind of thing and then row it on the boat and the
Rym: end of the book That's like the Ghibli climax just already written ready to go.
Scott: Just you don't have to change shit.
Scott: Just take that book boom.
Scott: There's your screenplay and animate it and done.
Scott: You don't even worse.
Rym: This wasn't just an adaptation.
Rym: It's kind of like Goro just stole like random bits from the movies Like Aaron just happens to have a shadow following him.
Rym: That wasn't explained.
Scott: It was also supposedly based on something else that like, you know, Hayao Miyazaki had written.
Scott: so it's like he combined Four books that Ursula K Le Guin had written and then one thing his dad had written and mixed them together.
Scott: poop came out.
Rym: I Was it's hard to say like.
Rym: I don't hate this movie.
Scott: Yeah, it's not like.
Scott: I hate it like oh, it's terrible.
Scott: Never said.
Rym: it is one of the worst movies I've ever seen all the way to completion.
Scott: It's just bad Just don't.
Scott: and if I like oh god, it's the worst.
Scott: No, I hate this thing.
Scott: It can go die in a fire.
Scott: It's just like.
Scott: this is bad.
Scott: ignore Why does Aaron?
Scott: not?
Scott: even the thing is it's not even funny bad.
Scott: Like where's the funny?
Rym: There's nothing to make fun of.
Scott: it's not like an MD geist where you can be like other than the penis sword.
Scott: Yeah, the boob sword.
Rym: everyone called it something different But everyone laughed when the suit sort came out.
Scott: The thing is I really to be honest Emily told me the sword looks like boobs because in the hilt of the sword are too round.
Rym: who nuts and then it comes off Like a penis.
Rym: there's a hands at the bottom.
Scott: The thing is if Emily hadn't said anything.
Scott: I would not personally have noticed or thought it.
Scott: but she didn't sound like in any way that any other sword Say anything to me.
Rym: she told me it was a boobs and my first thought was if you take the blade off of that It's just a dick.
Scott: Well, she told me it was a boob sword.
Scott: So that's why I noticed.
Scott: but no if no one said anything I would not have thought the sword in any way strange I don't know.
Rym: I thought it was a dick.
Scott: Well, I mean every sword is is phallic But I mean it was not.
Scott: I would not have noticed anything's amiss about the design of the sword if she had not said it Was the boob sword.
Rym: so Is it just me?
Rym: or did notice no character of any actual motivation other than hair?
Rym: the slave guy?
Rym: Yeah, he was the only one he's like.
Scott: I'm evil But he was pretty much like a lot of the movie was just stolen from Nausicaa.
Scott: I like this lot of the clothing and character designs and he was straight up like totally based on those people who you know The the evil flying people from Lop to though the people that are flying men are no good, right?
Scott: I can't even remember which one of the ghibli movies.
Scott: It was.
Scott: they had the sort of people You know the the sort of group of of like four people who would fly around and we're not good But we're sort of like half good guys.
Scott: Oh, what the hell it was that Lop.
Scott: It's our.
Scott: was it Nausicaa?
Scott: I don't remember.
Scott: you don't remember either do?
Rym: I'm reading the summary of the plot of the part that I fell asleep through and I Didn't miss much.
Scott: Okay?
Scott: But I mean, you know what?
Scott: I'm you know, those people it's like there's a mom and like the the sons I guess and that's Lop to Scott.
Scott: Okay, Lop to yet.
Scott: He was totally a lot like those guys, you know Never turn good.
Rym: He was just evil.
Scott: I mean those people turn good and he didn't but another.
Scott: but in all other respects He's sort of like the the minion.
Scott: He was also boring evil He's.
Rym: his character.
Rym: motivation consisted of ha ha ha.
Rym: I am evil and a slaver and it's awesome That's it.
Rym: But like Ged his moat he just kind of wandered slowly and didn't really do anything.
Scott: I've only seen Lop to once.
Scott: I should probably watch that again.
Rym: Wow to Haru Basically is just pissy and then the very end is a dragon Mm-hmm and in between she has her moment when she rips the stake out of the ground and goes running.
Rym: Yeah, but why didn't she rip it out like three hours ago if it was so easy to do?
Rym: And Aaron the main character has zero motivation and just kind of sits there until the very end of the movie when Terror shows up and says here's your sword that you had before and then lost.
Scott: but that was that.
Scott: was that?
Rym: was the other Him right or was no?
Rym: the other?
Rym: him told her to give the sword to the real him and then disappeared But didn't rejoin with him or anything.
Rym: He didn't even kind of follow the Earthsea book there and then suddenly he turned out of it filed there.
Rym: See what he turns into a Miyazaki hero and suddenly he's all badass and active and motivated when up until that point He had never been and nothing had changed.
Rym: Mm-hmm I guess you could argue that because she knew his true name She spelled him into doing that but she was a total bitch to him before.
Rym: and then suddenly she changed And there was no reason for that.
Rym: The mommy character just kind of stood around being a mommy and never did anything.
Scott: Yeah, so I do want to wrap it up.
Rym: Oh you feel kind of bored with this.
Rym: We can't even make fun of it.
Rym: if this was like high-velocity wolf cannons, there'd be something to make fun of.
Rym: but this movie is just flat and Boring if you cut out every scene that does not directly advance the plot.
Rym: The movie literally is a 30-second clip of Someone standing on a roof turning into a dragon and killing an evil wizard the end man.
Scott: There's a bad guy.
Scott: We got it.
Rym: dragons kill him.
Scott: Yes There aren't even like really interesting designs of anything the dragons.
Rym: I liked.
Rym: I liked how the sparks and shimmering were coming out.
Scott: I can't even like interesting creatures or interesting magic spell other than the dragons.
Scott: Yeah, everything was so tame.
Scott: I Guess the horse had an interesting design.
Rym: Yeah, the horse camel kind of a chocobo camel horse.
Scott: Yeah, it was pretty cool.
Scott: I won't I'll take it.
Rym: But then again, why was it in the movie?
Rym: And why did they do stuff with it?
Rym: But it didn't matter.
Rym: they kept like oh they saved it, but it doesn't matter.
Rym: Oh, here it is.
Rym: It's happy to see them.
Scott: great I'm a camel horse.
Rym: Remember when Ged turns around with the ugly face and tricks hair.
Rym: Why was that scene even there?
Scott: There's a funny scene.
Rym: Why did he even bother having him lose the sword and get it back again.
Rym: that had no effect on the plot at all.
Rym: Cuz Ged just went and got the sword like right away.
Rym: Yeah, he's went to the pawn shop guy and bought it And they introduced that whole.
Scott: I guess in sort of it's in some ways You could view it as a people.
Scott: just do the smart thing movie, which is what we want, right?
Scott: It's like oh you lost the sword.
Scott: All right, I'll go get it.
Rym: So did Tara know she was the thing.
Scott: the problem is is that it's also boring because even though it's an always do the smart thing movie There's never any serious conflict.
Rym: I would argue anyone.
Rym: it is not a everyone does the smart thing movie because Ged doesn't do fucking anything.
Rym: No, he doesn't and Aaron doesn't do anything.
Scott: Well, that's another thing.
Scott: is that right?
Scott: Ged is is supposed to be like, you know He's like the Gandalf of that world, right?
Scott: He is the number one.
Rym: Wait, wait, is he the Archmage?
Scott: That was it as an example of a really bad dubbing part, right?
Scott: Someone says Archmage instead of Archmage But anyway, he's supposed to be the Gandalf of that world.
Scott: He is serious business and after the like the first book he you know Isn't really the focus even when he you know, he's in it all the time.
Scott: But like when he in the tombs of Atuan, he's sort of in the background They're mostly focusing on the girl who needs to be rescued from the tombs and then he sort of does the rescuing, you know He's sort of in the background character.
Scott: He's not ever focused on like that.
Scott: So the fact that you're already beyond the first book well beyond it, but you're focusing on him and it's it doesn't work.
Scott: That's not how it's supposed to be.
Rym: It doesn't you know, well, why was Aaron the main character?
Rym: He didn't do anything.
Scott: The movie was the main character was a third book.
Rym: Yeah, but This movie.
Rym: What did he do?
Scott: He did nothing nothing.
Rym: We.
Rym: this would have been such a good movie if they'd made to Harrow the main character and make the whole thing Leo Forget the kid or maybe he's there but he's a side character getting the kid come to her You know a little village and they disrupt and then she figures out that she's a dragon who saves the day.
Rym: They could have made a really good movie There.
Scott: I did it.
Scott: So, you know, it's a really good movie.
Scott: smarter than Goro Take the first Earthsea book and just read it and that's it.
Scott: Don't put any other shit in there at all.
Rym: Maybe maybe anime.
Scott: no touching no touching.
Scott: I Is.
Scott: I heard that Miyazaki said something along the lines of I don't want to give my kids any help, right?
Scott: They got to make it on their own.
Rym: Well, they got to make it on their own Directing but he'll have all the animators they want.
Rym: Yeah, right.
Scott: It's like these Ghibli animators.
Scott: they're like some of the best animators in the world and He basically because this guy was Miyazaki son.
Scott: Okay, maybe Miyazaki didn't help him direct but you know what he helped him by providing the team of the best animators in the world and Forcing them to draw really long boring slow scenes of a dude walking around.
Rym: really well It was animated beautifully, but nothing's like.
Scott: That is such a crime.
Scott: They could have been working on something else better But instead they were working on this that whole time.
Rym: What the fuck the movie won the bunsun raspberry award for worst movie in Japan?
Scott: Oh, and girl Miyazaki won worst director is definitely the worst studio thing studio Ghibli has ever made.
Rym: There is no question and it is in the list because remember I always say like something is one of the worst movies I've ever seen.
Rym: I do not finish movies that are worse than a certain line.
Rym: the worst movie I have ever watched to completion was Clifford with Martin Short playing a 10 year old boy.
Rym: the second worst movie I've ever watched to completion completion was the movie that M Night Shyamalan wanted to make about Avatar.
Rym: had he not unfortunately died.
Rym: This is in the top 10 of the worst movies.
Rym: I've ever watched to completion?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I mean you got to put things in there like great digital target.
Scott: There's a lot but it's definitely like great digital target I can make fun of.
Rym: there are things to say about it.
Rym: stuff happen in it.
Rym: I can make jokes about torsos climbing.
Scott: Yeah, it's definitely lowest 50 definitely probably lowest 25.
Rym: maybe I can make some pedophile jokes about Lord Cobb because he is totally a pedophile.
Rym: Yeah, that's about it.
Scott: That's it All right.
Scott: Don't don't spend money on it.
Scott: Don't even spend your time on.
Rym: I'll tell you why.
Scott: maybe you should like if you can get it Just kind of skip through it.
Rym: watch the first like five minutes watch it up until do get stabbed and then watch the last Like three or four minutes.
Scott: also read the fucking Earthsea books.
Scott: The first one was one of our earliest book clubs.
Scott: read them all hello Good books.
Scott: read eyeballs.
Scott: They're not long.
Rym: Why the fuck?
Rym: was she a dragon?
Rym: that wasn't for shouted at all.
Scott: because they gotta have dragons in the movie.
Scott: Otherwise, it would be cool.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Scott: You gotta dragons and swords.
Scott: Yeah, it's a fantasy movie.
Rym: start with dragons and with dragons and nothing in the middle really mattered.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.
Scott: You don't think I could do it, huh?
Scott: Come here.
Scott: I dare you.