Scott: It's Monday, May 24th.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: And this is GeekNights.
Scott: Tonight we will talk about the non-SQL, non-relational databases.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Oh Adobe, why do you have to do this to me?
Rym: So, Audition, I learned how to auto-tune, so watch out.
Scott: You're gonna auto-tune all of GeekNights?
Rym: I thought about it.
Scott: Didn't you have to put a song into auto-tune?
Rym: Nah, well, there are many ways.
Scott: Doesn't it usually work, like you put the notes in and then it goes...
Rym: What I didn't realize until recently was that the built-in functionality of Audition, I went back and you know what?
Rym: Cool that it can do it too.
Rym: I can just auto-tune.
Rym: I could have auto-tuned at RIT.
Rym: Just as good as the auto-tune now.
Scott: Just as well.
Rym: Yeah, just as goodly.
Scott: Just as well-y.
Rym: So I'm sad at Adobe for the fact that now I have the ability, if you couldn't tell, to auto-tune, which is not a power that should be put into hands such as mine.
Rym: But I'm also sad because Audition, just before we tried to do the show tonight, so I go to record and the input goes red line and then Audition crashes.
Rym: And I think, huh, that's fucked up.
Rym: That's awesome.
Rym: Let's try this again.
Rym: And it happens again.
Rym: So I'm trying to troubleshoot and poking around and Scott's getting impatient.
Rym: and then I see that, oh, somehow Audition has decided, you know what?
Rym: It doesn't want to record from the nice, you know, USB external sound card interface or even the interface on the sound card built into the computer.
Rym: No, no, no.
Rym: It found the speakers and said, you know what?
Rym: That is what I'm recording from.
Rym: And I don't even know what kind of signal it was getting.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Rym: So, you know what?
Rym: I think audio software should work 100% by now.
Rym: Fuck you, Adobe.
Scott: You know, I realized people, you know, the complaints about Linux.
Scott: audio are, you know, slightly bubbling again.
Scott: It sucks since, I don't know, the year 1990 and it still sucks, right?
Scott: Linux isn't that old.
Scott: So, but, you know, the thing is, I was looking at some other stuff and like audio sucks on pretty much every OS.
Scott: It sucks on OS X. It sucks on Windows.
Scott: This guy had a flow chart, right?
Scott: And the flow chart was like, okay, which, if you're making a game, what audio thing do you use on Windows?
Scott: And it was like a big flow chart.
Scott: And pretty much the only one that didn't suck was this one that cost a fuck ton of money.
Rym: Well, that's it.
Rym: I mean, a lot, like if you really want to edit Pro Tools, despite all the problems that I still say it has, it's not that bad.
Rym: What really bothers me is that way back in the day, like I would try to use something like, well, I guess the precursors to Audition, you know, before I learned Cool Edit.
Rym: And I would complain about the interface, like, ah, this interface is crap.
Rym: And experts would always say things to me like, well, you're just not an expert in the field.
Rym: You don't understand what a good interface is for this application.
Scott: Are you going to talk about how people psychologically like a complicated interface?
Rym: No, I'm going to go straight, I'm going to go in a slightly different tack because that was true about audio.
Scott: Because there was, someone figured that out, that basically, you know, like, let's say I'm a so-and-so engineer, right?
Rym: Well, the best example was the stupid Bloomberg terminals I deal with at work.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: Well, I have to remember, that's what the article is talking about, is why the Bloomberg terminal is complicated and silly looking with a fancy keyboard when it doesn't need to be.
Scott: It's because it makes people who know how to use it feel like they're special and feel like they're smart.
Scott: And, you know, it makes them feel like they have a valuable skill when really they just, you know, learn this arbitrarily complicated interface.
Scott: that psychologically makes them feel good.
Scott: And that's pretty much it.
Rym: But, you know, back in the day, I complained about, I'm trying to learn how to use CoolEdit to do stuff, and I complained.
Rym: I was like, "Eh, this interface sucks,".
Rym: and the expert said, "No, you just don't understand
Rym: it.".
Rym: And then I learned audio engineering, and I realized that the interface was actually freaking awesome for what I was trying to do.
Rym: It was great.
Rym: The interface was exactly what I needed.
Rym: And the interface in Audition is still exactly what I need.
Rym: The problem is, half the time, the interface just doesn't fucking work and things just break and crash.
Rym: So they finally got the front end of audio right, as far as I can tell.
Rym: It's just the back end is garbage.
Rym: So then, you know, I have Premiere, I have the whole production premium creative suite, Adobe, everything, and I had all these complaints.
Rym: Like, I tried to use Premiere, and I'm like, "You know what?
Rym: This sucks for
Rym: video.".
Rym: And I went to some video experts, and they're like, "Well, you're just stupid and don't understand.
Rym: It's just like you were with audio
Rym: before.".
Rym: But then I talked to people who do audio and video both for a living, and the uniform consensus among experts is that Premiere is a god-awful piece of shit, and no one worth any amount of skill or money would ever touch it.
Scott: It seems like everyone uses the really expensive Apple Final Cut thing.
Rym: Yeah, everyone said, "Why don't you use Final
Rym: Cut?".
Rym: And I was like, "I'm not gonna buy a
Rym: Mac.".
Scott: You wanna pay for it?
Scott: Think about how much that costs.
Scott: You get the cost of a Mac plus the cost of Final Cut.
Rym: Or Avid, but we're not going there.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know what that is anyway.
Rym: Regardless, and more and more I've been finding that as an audio engineer, audio software, it's really only back-end details and polish behind the interface that are the problems these days.
Scott: Oh yeah, I mean, think about it.
Scott: You're playing a game, right?
Scott: Or you're making a game.
Scott: The interface of interacting with the audio is not bad.
Scott: You get a little volume meter, right?
Scott: There's nothing bad about that.
Scott: The problem is, is like, the audio just won't work.
Scott: Or your surround sound won't actually be surround.
Rym: But here's the worst part.
Rym: The audio stuff itself is great.
Rym: Like all the direct, like this filter, that filter, all that stuff is great.
Rym: The problem really is that Adobe doesn't bother to finish all the kind of minor details like the program doesn't crash and the program can import all forms of audio correctly.
Rym: Anyway, I'm just, I'm feeling angry at Adobe lately because it fails me in minor, but...
Scott: And 'cause you paid a lot of money for crap.
Rym: Basically I paid a lot of money because it's the professional stuff and it does what I need, which, you know, the non-professional stuff literally doesn't.
Rym: Like CMYK and Photoshop.
Rym: And Photoshop is the same as Audition in my opinion.
Rym: Like the interface, like it is good.
Rym: It's a good application.
Rym: But it still fails in these subtle integration things.
Rym: Like the fact that the Adobe installer is not well integrated with Windows bothers me.
Rym: The fact that Adobe software does not talk to other Adobe software very well bothers me.
Scott: Well isn't that supposed to be what the Bridges thing is for?
Rym: Yeah, but the Bridge has issues and a lot of times when I import files, even if I use the Adobe Media Converter, it just fucks up.
Rym: And if I go to the Adobe support and say, "And open a ticket," their answer is basically, "Yeah, we don't actually really support that format like FLV or
Rym: MPEG4.".
Rym: Never, I'm not gonna get into containers and all that, but you get my drift.
Scott: Yeah, anyway.
Scott: So I got this new laptop here.
Scott: It's a Lenovo X201.
Scott: It was like a crazy sale.
Rym: I gotta say, if I could not make due with my current laptop and I needed to buy one right now, I would have bought pretty much the same one.
Scott: See, I could have continued to make due with the one I had, the Fujitsu P7230.
Scott: But it was getting a little breaky, right?
Scott: First of all, that's a technical term, breaky.
Scott: Basically, it had two batteries, but if I used both of them at the same time, sometimes it would just turn off.
Scott: And I could tell it was a problem with the extra battery, which, by the way, wasn't lasting all that long.
Scott: It was lasting 20 minutes.
Scott: It wasn't really boosting me very much at all.
Scott: So I got rid of that second battery and I put the plastic placeholder to reduce the weight.
Scott: And the big battery in the back was still all good because I had barely used it ever because I had mostly lived off the small one.
Scott: And, you know, it wasn't turning off randomly, but it was still getting a little eh.
Scott: The screen had a little scuffiness on it, you know.
Scott: And, you know, just generally the core solo was a little slow.
Scott: Like you go to YouTube and it'd be eh, eh, eh, eh, eh.
Scott: You know, you'd try to play like certain Flash games, it'd be like, "Uh, I can't really do this very
Scott: well.".
Scott: And we started working on, you know, like Project Dorf or whatever, and it'd be like, "Uh, I can't even do Project Dorf, I'm so
Scott: weak.".
Rym: Well, I remember way back when you started playing Dwarf Fortress and you were playing on that laptop and it was so slow and you were complaining about it.
Rym: And I turned it on my laptop with the Core 2 and it blew by just a million turns a second.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So, you know, I kept looking at the Lenovo site because I knew it wanted a tiny X series, you know.
Scott: And, you know, I kept checking it once in a while and I checked it, you know, one day a couple weeks ago and the price was like crazy low.
Scott: It was like $1400 for like the best X201.
Scott: I got like a 128 gig solid state drive and it's got like an i5.
Scott: They just announced like newer i5s and i7s for laptops.
Scott: But it's basically almost, it's only slightly faster than the one I've got, so big deal, right?
Rym: Actually, it worked.
Rym: They just, you know, I kept complaining my computer was slow.
Scott: And this one is so crazy fast.
Scott: This computer is like, you know, the video card and it's just some Intel poop, whatever.
Scott: So I can't do for real 3D gaming like I can on my desktop, but the CPU is the fastest CPU I own because my home theater PC has an i3.
Rym: You can probably get away with playing.
Scott: My desktop has a Core 2 Duo and this has an i5.
Scott: Oh, yeah, I could definitely play Civ 4, Civ 5, but I can't play like, you know, any FPSs or anything.
Scott: Not that I would with a laptop.
Scott: You know, it's got three USBs.
Scott: It's real quiet.
Scott: It's got really fast networky.
Scott: It's got, you know, awesome wireless.
Scott: It's got a really nice screen.
Scott: Everything about it is pretty terrific.
Scott: And the thing is, right, I remembered two things that I forgot.
Scott: Number one, oh, three things I want to discuss.
Rym: Number one is that fanatical devotion to the pope.
Scott: Number one is that Thinkpads have a little light in the top.
Rym: Oh, I totally forgot about that.
Scott: I totally forgot about those, but Thinkpads have always had those and they still have them.
Rym: Because I used to have a Thinkpad at IBM.
Scott: Other laptops don't have them and really they should.
Rym: Well, I have a feeling going forward.
Rym: we're going to get to the point to where backlit keyboards will be the standard as opposed to the option.
Scott: Maybe.
Scott: The second thing is that the keyboard on this has a whole lot of buttons.
Scott: It's like, whoa, way more buttons than regular.
Scott: I mean, look, you don't even have like F keys integrated in the numbers.
Scott: They're separate F keys and everything.
Scott: There's a lot of buttons on this keyboard.
Scott: The thing is, like the keys are really good, but the like positioning is not so great.
Scott: It's like I had the escape key is way far away from my vintage.
Scott: So I learned that control left bracket is actually escape.
Scott: Oh, so now I'm like I'm re muscle memory.
Scott: So I always use control left bracket instead of pushing escape and when using them.
Scott: So that way I don't have to reach all all the way over to F1 by accident.
Scott: When you hit F1 by accident, it opens up the help, which is not what you want.
Rym: I mean, looking at my Fujitsu, you know, the boutique ultra portable.
Rym: The keys are in a perfect rectangle and the F keys are separate, but they're tiny keys in a line.
Scott: These are tiny, but in the line across the top.
Scott: But it's, you know.
Scott: Anyway, the other thing is that this came with Windows seven professional already installed.
Scott: All my other Windows sevens are home premium, but I didn't, you know, a premium professional was the only choice.
Scott: Not that it makes a difference.
Rym: And so that means you could theoretically use the XP mode if you wanted to.
Scott: Theoretically, I guess not that I would.
Rym: You could run a cool added pro.
Scott: I'll just use virtual.
Scott: I'll just use virtual box.
Scott: Why?
Scott: Why would I anyway?
Rym: Because it's basically pair virtualized as opposed to fully virtualized.
Scott: It doesn't matter.
Rym: That matters.
Rym: Huge performance difference.
Scott: Yeah, but it's not not doing it for performance and doing if I'm doing virtualization, I'm doing it for, you know, virtualization and separation.
Rym: Well, the XP compatibility mode is primarily there for businesses who have like some old program.
Scott: I don't have any old program I need to run.
Scott: The thing I learned is that, number one, this doesn't have an optical drive, so it didn't come with any disks.
Scott: So how do I get like?
Scott: if I want to restore it to factory settings, how do I do that?
Scott: I got to plug in some sort of USB stick that's big enough and four gigs apparently wasn't big enough.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Or an external USB DVD ROM of some kind.
Scott: And you can there's a tool that lets you create the factory.
Scott: I have to do that.
Scott: And then there's like a factory restore partition on there also that I just left alone because it's so small.
Scott: I don't really care.
Scott: But it is annoying that they put that on there.
Scott: But I guess they have to.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But then the thing that really got me is just how much shit was pre-installed.
Scott: Like there was all sorts of Lenovo tools.
Scott: They installed on top of Windows.
Scott: Now, what was nice is that all these went to add or remove programs uninstalled and they went away, which was good.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The thing is, why are they on there in the first place?
Scott: I mean, some of them I could sort of understand, like there was one that like if you don't have the solid state drive, it, you know, controls the motion sensors to turn off your magnetic drive if you drop your laptop.
Scott: I could understand having a software tool for that and a driver for that.
Scott: That makes sense.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They also did some things that were just sort of, I guess, nice, depending on who you are, like they pre-installed flash.
Scott: So you don't have to go get it yourself.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So I guess that's nice for someone who doesn't want to go.
Scott: It wasn't like they installed some hokey flash.
Scott: It was the real deal.
Scott: The thing is, they installed a bunch of other useless crap, like something that manages the wireless card.
Scott: It's like Windows already has that.
Scott: Why did you give me this really shitty GUI that removes the wireless thing from the taskbar, puts a big ugly wireless thing, a replacement in the taskbar.
Rym: That's what amazes me.
Scott: And just makes it a worse experience overall.
Scott: And they did the same thing for the battery, like the power icon was removed from Windows, all the Windows power stuff, and they put in their own power stuff.
Scott: Luckily, it uninstalled nicely.
Scott: Even with Fujitsu.
Scott: But why did they put it there?
Scott: It's not, I don't even care so much.
Scott: Why does it, why did they even write it?
Rym: Why does it even exist?
Rym: I don't care so much that they put it there.
Rym: Like that, like maybe they're stupid, whatever reason they would have put it there.
Rym: Why do they always make the icons for that stuff so fucking ugly?
Scott: And big.
Rym: I mean, they look like they're out of the Windows 95 era.
Scott: They're so horrendous.
Scott: Really, if I was Microsoft, what I would do, right, is I would say, look, anyone who is shipping Windows pre-installed OEM on a computer, laptop or desktop, may not modify in any way whatsoever, except for these prescribed ways of modifying.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That is it.
Scott: You may not pre-install any driver.
Scott: You know, I mean, you know, obviously you have to have the drivers installed on there.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But you can't be installing like these separate gooeys and shit.
Scott: Just the driver.
Scott: You know, they need to heavily regulate the OEMs and tell them what they can and cannot do.
Scott: I think it's because I think that what's happening is Windows is a bad reputation.
Scott: It's always had a bad reputation.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And I think the vast majority of its bad reputation comes from two things.
Scott: Number one, stupid people filling up their computers with viruses and spyware because they're morons.
Rym: Which not much you can do about that yet.
Scott: Not much you can do about that yet, really, you know.
Scott: And number two, OEMs putting all this shit on Windows.
Scott: that just makes it worse.
Scott: And Microsoft really should put the foot down and say, look, you cannot put this on here.
Scott: You must use the built in Windows wireless thing.
Scott: You can put the driver for the wireless card on there, obviously.
Scott: But you can't go replacing the Windows wireless card controlling interface with your own.
Rym: The landscape of the industry has changed significantly.
Rym: I mean, think to back in the day when someone would go to like CompUSA and buy a computer.
Rym: There were revenue streams along the way for, you know, a company to preload software that some other company paid them to do.
Scott: You pay compact to put the AOL icon on the desktop and AOL would get, you know, money because you signed up for AOL.
Scott: And compact would get money from AOL.
Rym: There was a time when Microsoft basically, if they fought that, it would have been something like they couldn't have fought it too much or they would have really hurt all the resellers.
Rym: I think now we're at the point.
Rym: Microsoft is powerful enough to tell all the OEMs, fuck you, get in line.
Rym: And there's basically nothing they can do about it.
Scott: None of the things that were pre-installed were things that were going to make anyone money, right?
Scott: It's not like they make more money if I use the Intel Lenovo wireless card, you know, access thing as opposed to the one that's built into Windows.
Scott: It's not like I'm signing up for anything.
Scott: They're not making any money on that whatsoever.
Scott: Zero.
Scott: Nothing.
Scott: There was not a single thing that was installed that was a money making deal like sign up for AOL or anything like that.
Rym: Why do they even bother in the first place?
Rym: What is the addition here?
Rym: What do they do?
Rym: And why are they so ugly?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I don't know why they do it.
Scott: Even the worst part, they're paying someone to develop that.
Rym: My Fujitsu, right?
Rym: It came with, it had the window, Microsoft Windows power stuff works just fine.
Rym: It put another icon next to that, that did the same thing with an ugly Windows 311 interface.
Rym: And they had the software that turns off the hard drive and all that stuff, you know, that's the thing I wanted.
Rym: And that little software thing.
Scott: I don't even need it because I have solid state, but they put it on here anyway.
Rym: But it would show you like the pitch and yaw and all this information.
Rym: Then when service pack one came out, it just broke that.
Rym: And every time my laptop boots, it says no driver found for that thing.
Rym: And Fujitsu basically said, you know what, we're never going to make it fix.
Rym: We're done.
Rym: Your laptop is going to have this thing broken forever.
Scott: Yeah, well, at least, you know, what you could do, though, couldn't you just like?
Scott: if you just installed an actual clean windows that doesn't have any of their stuff in it at all, you wouldn't get the message, though.
Rym: Well, I'd have to turn off the service.
Rym: I don't want to get into the details of it, but basically they broke one of the fundamental functionalities and never fixed it.
Scott: Anyway, that's just something I got to complain about.
Scott: And anyone out there, you know, if you have a bad impression of Windows or you know people have a bad impression of Windows, don't judge Windows.
Scott: unless you're judging the clean Microsoft pure windows directly from the desk with no extra bullshit on it.
Scott: That is the only thing that you can pass a valid judgment on.
Scott: if you're judging windows based on some spyware infested thing or you're judging windows.
Rym: If you're judging communism by one or two poor implementations.
Scott: I'm just listen.
Scott: All right.
Scott: It's a totally different story.
Rym: Yes, if we just did it right from the start, it would work.
Scott: I'm not saying that Windows is like the greatest ever.
Scott: You know, I mean, you know, I hate all the OS's.
Scott: You know, I got something to hate about each and every one that's ever existed.
Scott: You know, it's funny.
Rym: It's the same thing with phones, with all the phone OS's and all the phone hardware.
Scott: Yeah, all the OS's are great and all the OS's suck, except OS X only sucks.
Rym: It's interesting, though, in the very least, something that sucks but doesn't have some sort of important redeeming quality fails immediately.
Rym: So all we're left in the situation where everything has one killer app you can't get anywhere else, coupled with one fatal flaw that is fixed everywhere else.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Why can't someone just it's like if one guy has the thing fixed, why can't you also have things that would be patents, patents, patents, patents, bullshit patents.
Scott: It's not all patent.
Rym: That's a big part of it.
Scott: We're going to talk about patents right now.
Rym: Yes, we are.
Rym: Let's get right into that, because I don't want to spend the whole show talking about stuff, because this is hopefully a good thing.
Rym: Back in the day, neuro-burning ROM was the almighty shit in the CD era.
Scott: Well, this isn't even the whole, this is like a sub-story here.
Scott: So the real, the big story is that, OK, we got the HTML5 video situation.
Scott: A bunch of people want to use H.264, but the open source people want to use like Ogg Fiora.
Scott: Thing is Ogg Fiora, technologically inferior.
Scott: H.264, patent encumbered.
Scott: What do you do?
Scott: Right.
Scott: Some of them are using H.264, but Firefox ain't going to do that.
Rym: The worst thing is that most times when this has happened in history, all the normal people and a lot of the techs go the third way of.
Rym: they'll use the patent encumbered stuff semi-illegally and basically make it the defacto standard, which then forces anyone who wants to make software to sell to deal with the bullshit.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Which is why we remember with GIF where nothing could legally use.
Scott: You don't even know the whole story.
Scott: You're like way, way off the full information's here.
Scott: So Google, right, bought that company that made like.
Scott: they bought basically the other video codec company that had made the original codec that like Fiora was based off of, which was like version three or four or something like that.
Scott: And but then now they just at their Google I/O, they released like version, I think, eight or nine, like the newest best version of this, this, you know, codec that I forget the name of.
Scott: It's like on something like on nine or something like that anyway.
Scott: And they released it out.
Scott: They're like, here, here's, you know, the the the open source patent free, awesome video codec.
Scott: Let's let's rock with this one that's, you know, far technologically superior and is not patent encumbered.
Scott: So the thing is, there's now this whole, you know, thing it's like, OK, if you want to actually use this right now, you've got to install this WebM thing.
Scott: If you go to WebM project dot org, you can learn all about it.
Scott: You can install it in Firefox or whatever and all kinds of stuff.
Scott: The thing is, you know, people are still discussing.
Scott: It's like, OK, you made this better codec.
Scott: The thing is, if I've got like a phone and I want to play some video, like the iPhone has a hardware H264 decoder in it, you know.
Scott: So if you're playing an H264 on an iPhone, it's going to be way better and it's going to use a lot less battery compared to even if you use this, you know, better codec.
Scott: That's not patent encumbered.
Scott: There's no hardware decoder for it.
Scott: And there's that whole situation.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So on top of that, right, there's the MPEG law.
Rym: Well, basically all that is, is a consortium of companies who all have basically they have contributed one or more patents to a pool.
Rym: And then collectively, they all share this pool of patents with a sort of not mutually assured destruction, but mutual.
Rym: We will not sue each other over patent infringement by agreeing to license these things all to each other.
Scott: And basically, it's not just that.
Scott: It's on top of that.
Scott: What they do is they charge people like a zillion dollars for the license.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So if you want to use if you're making a Web browser and you want H264 in there, you have to pay to be in the MPEG law.
Scott: So basically they have this.
Scott: it's like a huge racket, basically, to where people pay.
Scott: They're in.
Scott: Then they have this huge interest in maintaining, you know, the MPEG law situation.
Scott: It's like once you're in, you're in.
Scott: And they're basically you can't use anything else because everyone who's in is going to is going to use the thing that they paid for or have.
Rym: Now, here's where it gets really bad.
Rym: The way the laws are, it really comes down to the fact that software patents are even what little of them we have.
Rym: An algorithmic patents are way too powerful and long lived because they have so many patents in the pool that if anyone competed with them, even if you in a you know what, you know, a clean environment built a brand new video codec.
Rym: The odds are you have at least on the surface level infringed upon one or more of their longstanding patents because a lot of the patents are generic bullshit.
Rym: So they basically have a complete monopoly and the power to destroy.
Scott: It's not a real.
Scott: it's like a weird legal monopoly, but it's not actually a monopoly.
Scott: It's not like every it's not like H.264.
Scott: I mean, it's a very popular video codec, but plenty of other video codecs are being used, you know, like Divix and all kinds of other MPEG-4 codecs.
Rym: Of course, remember, a lot of the MPEG-LA owns a lot of codecs.
Rym: They do.
Scott: But, you know, they don't have every single codec.
Scott: There are many codecs being used that are not there.
Scott: So they don't have like a physical monopoly, but they've got this legal monopoly, at least in the
Scott: U.S.,
Scott: to where you pretty much you're doing video.
Scott: If you're not doing some one of their stuff, then you're probably they can sue you.
Rym: Now, they have also claimed that Theora and a lot of other codecs that they don't have an interest in actually infringed upon all their patents.
Rym: And this is where Nero Burningrom has stepped in.
Rym: I don't think they're actually called Nero.
Scott: They're called Nero AG.
Rym: Yeah, I just know them from their first greatest product.
Scott: Yeah, Nero is, you know, they're a pretty cool company.
Scott: I mean, they don't make, you know, too much open source stuff.
Scott: But they made Nero Burningrom, which is pretty much the only way to burn disks back in the day.
Scott: And the only reason they stopped using it is because all the operating systems sort of, the only time I ever used it was to burn an ISO, pretty much.
Rym: Or to burn, like, an overburn, which I don't need to do anymore.
Scott: You don't need to do that anymore, right?
Rym: Back in the day, I needed to.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So their product, you know, these Nero Burningrom is no longer useful.
Scott: But I do remember, right, a lot.
Scott: They pretty much had all this great stuff.
Scott: Like if I played an MP3 in Nero, like it just sounded way better because they had way better MP3 decoders.
Rym: I forget what the codec was that they used, but it was some special one because I remember pulling it out and using it in something else.
Scott: It was like I could do a double blind test on it like every single time because there was just something they did that just.
Rym: Wow.
Rym: I think I'm old.
Rym: I actually forgot the names of all.
Rym: Remember back there's the front offer like reference and then there are all these kind of other ones.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Because Lame used one and something.
Rym: It's all gone.
Rym: I'm old.
Scott: It's disappeared from my brain.
Scott: And then they made like Nero Burningrom for Linux in the days when burning a disk on Linux is really painful, you know, and I don't know what they're doing now.
Rym: Well, here's what they're doing now.
Rym: They've filed a straight up full on antitrust complaint against the MPEG LA.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Take that, bitches.
Rym: And they're basically saying.
Rym: Nero coming out of the booth.
Rym: Exactly what Scott said, that the MPEG LA has this kind of weird loophole legal monopoly that is preventing anyone else from competing in the market whatsoever.
Rym: And this is probably, you know, it might seem like a little thing like, all right, some people are fighting over these video codecs.
Rym: If this goes our way, few things do in the courts, guys, but if this goes our way, this is one of those game changers.
Rym: This should be like DMCA getting repealed.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Like Internet videos would be like, oh, snap, videos in the house, all those situations.
Scott: Like, you know, you have to jump through a bunch of hoops to get all your video codecs in line.
Scott: Right.
Rym: That's because of this bullshit.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: If Nero like wins this, then basically like every video player will play every kind of video.
Scott: You know, that's that's the best possible situation.
Scott: I'm not saying that's going to happen.
Scott: Here's the best possible case.
Scott: There might be a court ruling that's like every Linux can just come with every video codec installed.
Scott: You know, your every video player will play every video file, every audio file, just totally awesomely.
Scott: You won't have to install any weird stuff, no hoop jumping, no nothing.
Scott: You'll be able to have streaming video of any kind going to any device.
Scott: It'll be frickin crazy.
Scott: Awesome.
Rym: I'll say this.
Scott: This is the.
Scott: this is one barrier to that to reaching that golden paradise.
Rym: I have three kind of levels of optimism in terms of my prediction of what will happen.
Scott: I guess starting at the top, most likely Nero loses because they don't have as much money as everyone else combined.
Rym: Well, that aside, because, you know, because the MPEG law is everyone else combined, right?
Scott: It's Microsoft and Apple and Daylou and everyone, everybody.
Rym: But like one thing that could happen, and this is kind of the the most likely optimistic outcome I have, is that the courts would install or enforce some sort of statutory royalty to where the MPEG L.A.
Rym: could continue to force people to license, but it would have a statutory royalty that they would have no control over.
Rym: That would be much lower, which I could live with that.
Rym: That's kind of the status quo.
Rym: You know, don't rock the boat.
Scott: The thing is, even the one dollar royalty.
Rym: So, so, so, so, so too much is going to fix a less likely, more optimistic outcome.
Rym: Statutory royalties based on the sale price of whatever it is you're selling.
Scott: That'd be good, because if it's if it's not zero, right, then, you know, Firefox and whatever, you know, even if it's even even if it is zero, if it's not open source, Firefox and Linux's distributions might not include it.
Rym: Yeah, but at the same time, the non gnu neckbeard distros would if it was completely free and guaranteed and protected by law.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But, you know, statutory royalty based on cost be something I could.
Rym: But the real what we really need, but I basically have zero optimism for this whatsoever, is that I think the biggest hindrance to incremental improvement in all technology today is the fact that patents are too powerful.
Rym: And basically software and evolved so quickly that, all right, someone makes a slightly better codec.
Rym: If they can't step on the shoulders of the previous codecs, you know, take the MPEG L.A.
Rym: own stuff and incrementally improve it.
Rym: Everyone who has a good idea has to either pay out the nose, join the racket or start from scratch.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Well, think about think about it.
Scott: this way is is a good analogy.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So I'm making a car.
Scott: No, I say I'm making tires.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I'm Michelin.
Rym: Oh, but I got the patent on a round.
Rym: Yeah, exactly.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Because, you know, the thing is, the wheel is such an old invention.
Scott: The patent is expired.
Scott: Right.
Rym: So so if I may realize if Thog were still alive and he had sold those rights to Disney would be fucked.
Rym: Right.
Scott: So there's a way we'd have square tires on our Linux mobile on the wheel has expired.
Scott: So if I make like all sorts of different wheels.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That improve upon, you know, the default wheel or tire in various ways, the patent on the tire even.
Scott: Why did you do you hit me in the nose?
Rym: I bang down.
Rym: I'm sorry.
Scott: Don't do that anyway.
Rym: So we had an accident in the studio.
Scott: Even the patent on the tire is so even the tire much newer than the wheel.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's so old that it's expired.
Scott: So I can make all sorts of tires and improve upon the you know, the invention of tire in many ways without having to worry about patent infringement, you know, because it's just it's wide open.
Scott: Now, imagine if the tire straight up was invented like five years ago.
Scott: and I'm sitting here making improvements on the tire.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Because the tire was just invented, that hasn't expired yet.
Scott: So pretty much only one person in the world can make tires.
Scott: Or if I want to make tires, I have to pay them a boatload of money.
Scott: When, you know, patents were made in a time where the rate of invention was very it was relatively slow to what it is now, to where all the fundamental inventions were very old.
Scott: And the problem is computer science is so new, relatively speaking, programming is so new, software is so new that patents on these fundamental things like the tire of programming are still in effect.
Rym: The Amazon one click.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So there are these fundamental things to software that are pretty much in all software that are still patented and is bullshit.
Scott: And the thing is, I think this the if you're going to even argue that patents should even exist for software or for anything or for whatever, the thing is, if nothing else, the time of a patent needs to be relative to the rate of invention.
Scott: Right.
Scott: If we are making improvements upon things on a daily basis.
Scott: Then a patent really just be a few hours.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, if it takes a week to bring something to market and then something's obsolete a month after that, then a patent should be a month and a week.
Scott: You know, and the thing is, patents are still what, 17 years, I think they're there.
Rym: They're so long that basically if I get a pet, if I got a patent on some fundamental, like say I come up, there's a new video codec and I have the patent on it.
Scott: That video codec will be useful for maybe two or three years.
Rym: And then after that, for the next 15 years or so.
Scott: You're just obstructing the entire world into having shitty video for 14 years.
Rym: No one but me can take the thing I invented and perform what I think is obvious incremental improvement.
Rym: So and this I think this is one of the most far reaching issues in technology today.
Scott: Something else we can do is you can make an exception to where it's like, if you improve upon something that's patented, then, you know, if you just reuse something that's patented.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Like, OK, you made MPEG.
Scott: And I took MPEG and I just included it straight up in my shit.
Scott: No, no, no, no, no, no.
Scott: But maybe if I take your MPEG and I make it better, then your patent doesn't mean shit because I made your shit better.
Rym: I thought about the same idea.
Rym: Imagine if you applied it to just straight up copyright, not just patents, with the idea that, for example, like duplicating someone's work in its entirety with no substantial change and then just reselling it or whatever were still illegal for some short period of time.
Rym: But remixing, mashing up parody and all that.
Scott: The thing is, the only problem with this is you get the mega time, mega two, mega two, mega two situation where everybody will you read just infringe everyone else's patents and copyrights, but crook them slightly so.
Rym: But at the same time, if they can be crook slightly so, then there's probably the patent is a little too fundamental.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: It's hard to say.
Rym: I really don't know the solution.
Rym: All I know is that I wish Nero the best of luck because I can't not overstate how impactful this would be on the world if they won or even if there was a compromise.
Rym: There was 90 percent against them.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: But anyway, the the the fight over the future of video on computers is like full on.
Scott: And it's right now it's Nero versus the world.
Rym: I feel ready to take out the world.
Rym: Oh, and Google TV, but there's not enough info to really say much about it yet.
Scott: So the one thing that is interesting about Google TV is that, you know, if it's built into your TV, then you don't have the one extra box problem.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And what what Google TV seems to be able to do is you could hook in your cable and your DVR and your boxy and whatever other video, your Netflix and whatever other video sources you've got.
Scott: And then you can just instead of ever changing channels or specifically picking videos to play or anything like that, all you would do is turn on your TV and search for what you want to watch.
Scott: So if you want to watch Hokuto no Ken, you would turn on your TV and you type in Hokuto no Ken.
Scott: And if it found any Hokuto no Ken on your DVR, on Crunchyroll, on YouTube, on any anywhere, it would bring it up and you'd pick one and it would play.
Scott: And that's what.
Scott: so that basically it changes your TV by aggregating all your video sources and then allowing you to search.
Scott: it sort of like desktop does.
Scott: And that's that's Google TV now independently.
Scott: Logitech sort of does this.
Scott: And I think Google TV would actually be a good like front end on the boxy.
Scott: You know, if you just open a boxy and you just searched and then played.
Rym: Yeah, well, it's hard to say what's going to happen with the boxy and everything.
Rym: I think who's really interested in this is remember when Hulu blocked boxy because they don't want people to actually use the Internet to watch TV.
Rym: I think basically I think what Google TV is going to do now, we don't have enough details to know exactly like what video formats does it really support?
Rym: What does it really do?
Rym: Logitech's making a box that'll basically let anyone use it if they don't have one of these Google TVs.
Rym: Yeah, but this could be the device that basically is the death knell of cable TV for most techie people and young people.
Scott: Well, I hope right.
Scott: The thing is, it seems like a lot of people are probably going to still have cable and DVR.
Scott: They're just never going to watch channels.
Scott: They're just going to search.
Scott: So if it's time to watch Super Bowl, right, you go to your TV type Super Bowl and you push enter and then he just turns on the channel, whatever channel it is on that year.
Scott: And there you go.
Scott: People aren't going to flick through the channels anymore.
Scott: Right.
Rym: And also a lot of people, I mean, more people in our generation, I think studies show more and more dropping cable entirely because idle entertainment is trivially found on the Internet forever.
Scott: But hopefully what this will do is more people will, you know, the problem is, is that right now you can plug your computer into your TV for awesome, but not enough people do it.
Rym: And it's not super easy.
Rym: It's not drop in place for grandma to do it.
Scott: Well, some of it is, depending on what box you get.
Scott: Like if you do a Roku, it is.
Scott: But if you do like a computer like I have, it's not.
Rym: But it's not like the Roku is great for Netflix and all that stuff.
Scott: An Apple TV is, but it's useless.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I think multiple articles basically said the Google TV versus Apple TV.
Scott: The boxy box is not out yet.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But we'll see.
Rym: Google, they have a reputation for coming out with cool things like this and making it 80 percent there and then just not finishing it.
Scott: That's pretty much everything.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But lately they've been getting to like 85 percent with things like Google Apps.
Rym: So we'll see.
Rym: It's like 82 percent, maybe.
Rym: We'll see.
Rym: There's not enough information to say for sure.
Rym: But Google TV, for if it does what it what we think it may do will be a game changer between that and boxy.
Rym: That's going to scare a lot of the old.
Scott: I hope they give Google TV out for like free as software so I can just install it on a computer.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The way I install boxy, I could foresee them doing or they make up like maybe I can if they have an API for it, I can make a boxy app for Google TV.
Scott: Because the boxy guys said that like Google TV, they see it as complimentary, which I totally agree with.
Rym: Well, Logitech and Sony, I believe, are smart.
Rym: Sony will sell their new OLED TV with Google TV built into it.
Rym: And the people who will buy that TV are not the people who would go buy some separate box.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So that market, they'll basically make money anyway.
Scott: The thing is, they've got to set it up.
Scott: so we turn on the TV and the Google thing like comes out at you.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Because like, look at your TV.
Scott: Your TV has some Internet Yahoo widget thing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: But that doesn't just come out at you when you turn the TV on.
Scott: You have to actually do a bunch of stuff to make it appear if you even know it's there.
Rym: It's also slow as shit.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So the Google.
Scott: Right.
Scott: What they've got to do is they've got to make it so that if you have a TV with Google TV, it has to be a Google TV.
Scott: Like you turn the TV on and there's the fucking search box.
Scott: Boom.
Scott: Right up top.
Scott: You know, like as soon as you turn it on, it's good.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And the thing is, I think they'll actually get a lot of.
Scott: they're not competing with anyone, really, because what it does is it doesn't actually have any video sources of its own.
Scott: Other than the Internet.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So what it does, it brings in all these video sources the way that Boxy does, you know, is like greatest fear of the current content generation regime, because basically there's so much free content out there.
Rym: If it's all aggregated and easy to get, that really hurts their bottom line in a huge way.
Scott: I think it's just another example of the middlemen being eliminated.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Because you've got TV networks like some TV station, some cable network.
Scott: They buy productions from some, you know, production company that's making TV shows.
Scott: Then they put it on TV with some ads and people buy ads even if no one's watching.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Whereas now, if you remove the middleman of the network, it's just people watching videos direct.
Scott: Then it's pretty much all these production companies who make shitty shows, but managed to survive by selling them to networks.
Scott: They're going to die.
Scott: The networks are going to die.
Scott: And pretty much the only people left are going to be the consumers, the tech companies who are providing the technological services because the, you know, and the production companies can't do it themselves.
Scott: And the production companies who actually make shows that people actually watch.
Scott: And that's going to be it.
Scott: Everyone else is going to be dead.
Scott: It's the same in every entertainment industry.
Rym: The reason I think that they're going to let the software be free is that Logitech, you know, the people who would sell the boxes, I don't think the people who would use it on their own computer and then install it are competing for the same demographic as the people who will just buy the Logitech box and put it down.
Rym: Logitech box is for mom or for me because I don't really feel like building an HDPC maybe.
Rym: Maybe.
Rym: But I already have a bunch of PCs, so maybe I'll just throw it on my Mac or something.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: Something else that's interesting.
Scott: I was reading about, you know, how it's pretty annoying that, like, all the Android phones are sort of like different versions and you can't upgrade them and all this kind of stuff.
Scott: Basically, I read and the reason for this isn't because, you know, you think, oh, it's because Google's lazy, whatever.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But really, no.
Scott: What it is, is that Google just keeps improving Android constantly.
Scott: They keep upgrading and upgrading and upgrading and upgrading and upgrading all the time, constantly thinking about how many new versions have come out in such a short time versus how long it took like a new version of Windows Mobile to come out.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And the thing is, it's not like Windows Mobile.
Scott: If I'm a phone carrier, if I'm a phone maker, I license Windows Mobile to put it on my phones.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I'm paying Microsoft for this.
Scott: So, you know, it's up to Microsoft to, like, make sure the shit works and everything so I can upgrade and whatnot because I'm paying them with Android.
Scott: It's just like you just get it for free.
Scott: It's open source.
Scott: It's just out there.
Scott: If you're you can.
Scott: just if I start a phone company and I just start making phones from like, you know, I'm basically soldering soldering together old Nokias to soldering, not soldering soldering.
Scott: Oh, no.
Scott: I just start making phones in my garage.
Scott: I can just put Android on them without giving Google a second look.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But then it's up to me to make my phones have all the newer androids on it.
Scott: And the thing is, the shitty phone makers and shitty phone carriers can't keep up.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So some of them are better than others.
Scott: Like HTC is better at keeping up, you know, than you see.
Rym: I just I like them.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But, you know, like Samsung, they can't keep the fuck up.
Scott: They just suck ass.
Scott: They can't you know, the Google keeps updating the phone and Samsung keeps updating Android and Samsung.
Scott: We can't oh, we can't keep up with all these Android updates because we suck so bad.
Scott: That's the reason.
Scott: Don't blame Google for this.
Scott: Google's actually just upgrading as fast as possible.
Scott: It's the phone makers and the phone carriers.
Scott: You can't keep up.
Scott: And I see the same thing in like the HTC area.
Rym: Well, that went on for a while.
Rym: So I guess things of the day, about half the people I run into knew this.
Rym: The other half didn't.
Rym: So you guys have a 50 50 shot.
Rym: I did not know.
Rym: Mark Twain said that 100 years after his death, his autobiography, which was in escrow, should be published.
Rym: And it's now been 100 years.
Scott: Right.
Scott: OK.
Scott: They put it in escrow, but they didn't have to.
Scott: They didn't have to obey him for 100 years.
Scott: Well, they could have chose to not obey.
Rym: Now, here's the thing.
Rym: Had someone had the person who had it just released it against Mark Twain's wishes.
Rym: I would not have faulted him because I would never.
Rym: I will never fault someone morally for revealing truth.
Rym: But at the same time, if he chose not to reveal it, I will not fault him because he did honor the wish.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Scott: I'm saying they had to do it.
Scott: I'm saying they didn't have to not.
Rym: I'm saying it's interesting that I don't I wouldn't fault someone either way, nor would I fault the third party who broke in, stole it and revealed it.
Scott: Well, it was stealing.
Scott: property doesn't belong to you.
Scott: But at the same time, revealing truth through investigative reporting, investigative reporting doesn't include breaking and entering and stealing.
Rym: What what?
Rym: what if it wasn't breaking and entering?
Rym: It was digital breaking and not even breaking just digital copying.
Scott: Did they physically enter property that was not theirs?
Rym: Let's say no.
Rym: But they did trespass to Chateau's by breaking into like an email server, but they didn't cause any harm.
Rym: They just copied.
Scott: See what they would have to do to to make it totally kosher.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Is that?
Scott: use X-ray vision to see into the vault, read it and then type it into a computer while sitting out in the public street.
Scott: That would.
Rym: that would be because there's legal precedent that if it's like, for example, I can take a picture of your house and you have to be naked in the window.
Rym: Fuck you.
Rym: I can do whatever I want with that picture.
Rym: If I take a picture of your house through the window into your bedroom with a telephoto lens, not cool because you had a reasonable expectation of privacy.
Rym: So the inside of the safe.
Scott: Do you have a reasonable expectation of privacy?
Rym: If everyone has X-ray vision, but not everyone does yet.
Scott: Anyway, my thing is real quick.
Scott: Do you remember this flash game called the the codex of chemical engineering?
Rym: Yeah, it was basically teach kids the cool fun parts of coding version one.
Scott: Yeah, there's another game out.
Scott: It's called Manufactoria.
Scott: It's a lot less subtle than the codex of chemical engineering.
Scott: It's pretty much like, hey, kids, Turing machines, check it out.
Scott: But it's a good game and it's good Turing machines and you'll learn something.
Scott: So play this game.
Rym: So I don't know how long we'll talk about this.
Rym: Scott has a lot more direct experience with it than I do, though.
Rym: I've played with CouchDB quite a bit.
Rym: Basically, we want to talk about, you know, when people think databases, at least tech people, they think things like Postgres or MSSQL or.
Rym: Oracle or DB to, you know, they think of relational databases, which for most people, if you think database, you think relational database.
Rym: That is what a database is in most people's minds.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: But nowadays it's been really trendy lately to go with the non SQL databases.
Scott: You know, there's some of them are key value stores.
Scott: Some of them are documented oriented databases.
Scott: So, you know, they go by many different names, but no SQL is like the trendy term.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, even though it's sort of it's an accurate term, though, because I've seen some of these that actually can work with SQL, even though they're not relational.
Scott: You just can't do a join.
Rym: I mean, you can go all the way down to like an LDAP.
Rym: That's literally just a flat CSV.
Rym: And then you exactly.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So this is the first thing, right?
Scott: These are way trendy lately.
Scott: All right.
Scott: All these no SQL databases.
Scott: But the thing is, the original databases weren't relational.
Scott: They were flat databases is basically a blast from the past.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like they made.
Scott: we finally got to the point where we can make relational databases.
Scott: And we're like, yes.
Rym: Awesome.
Rym: Kind of like object oriented programing was a whole new paradigm.
Scott: Now, now people are like, oh, yeah, these relational databases.
Scott: It's so hard to replicate with them, you know, even though it's kind of.
Scott: it's not that hard, but it's harder than it could be.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And oh, you know, I don't actually need this relational bits or oh, my Web site is hard to scale.
Scott: You know, the database is totally getting crushed.
Scott: You know, what do I do?
Scott: You know, so they go back and they've made basically these modern non relational databases.
Scott: They're like the databases of old, but they're new.
Scott: And the replication is easy.
Scott: The load balancing is easy.
Scott: The partitioning is easy in many cases.
Scott: And the other thing is that many of them are schema lists, which is very, very useful for many, many applications of the modern days is not having a schema at all.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So the first thing that bothers me right is some of the people who are like zealoty about these no SQL databases.
Rym: That's just silly.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: For example, right.
Scott: Some people will be like, OK.
Scott: My SQL.
Scott: Yeah, yeah.
Scott: My SQL sucks.
Scott: Why?
Scott: Well, because if you use my SQL in the default mode with the default engine of my ISAM, then you don't get any of the foreign key constraints.
Scott: And it's all.
Scott: it's not acid compliant.
Scott: And you might it might screw up.
Rym: And let's translate that.
Rym: If you take a product off the shelf, make no customizations and don't read the documentation and don't configure it.
Rym: It doesn't perform exactly what you might have wanted it to do.
Scott: No, no, it's not even that it will perform exactly what you want it to do, but it won't be super hard core for database people.
Scott: They won't like it.
Rym: Well, those people shouldn't be using my SQL anyway.
Scott: But if you use my SQL in a DB mode, right, then it will do all those things.
Scott: just as you know, it's acid compliant and totally awesome.
Scott: But it'll be slow, but it won't be slow.
Scott: It is be slower than the non acid compliant mode.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it'll basically be as fast as Postgres is.
Scott: But the thing is, so these hard core people like, oh, you got to use Postgres.
Scott: Postgres is for real.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And the thing is, I used to be like, yeah, OK, Postgres is for real and my SQL isn't for real.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: I have yet to find someone who can actually explain to me why Postgres is for real and my SQL is not.
Scott: If you use my SQL, if you really need your data to be for real, then you can use the my SQL in the slow mode.
Scott: It'll be easier to use because Postgres is wicked user unfriendly.
Rym: That's for sure.
Rym: Right.
Scott: It'll be easier to replicate because my SQL slaving is way better than Postgres, even though the newest newest newest version of Postgres that might be coming soon apparently makes the slavings.
Rym: Yeah, I'm running the beta on my windows box.
Rym: I've been playing with it.
Scott: Nice.
Rym: So you can even do like.
Rym: as an example, you know, just to give a specific concrete in my SQL is actually very easy to set up master master two way replication.
Rym: You can have two database really want to do that.
Rym: Well, there are situations where you might want to.
Rym: However, you got to know what the fuck you're doing or you're just going to make a mess.
Scott: But master slave is way easy.
Scott: And most of the time, even if you don't need to scale or anything, you want to do master slave to have a warm backup.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: In Postgres, even that is difficult to do.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Just because Postgres is difficult.
Scott: So I I want to hear from the Postgres zealots out there.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Why?
Scott: You know, if I'm not a bank.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And I don't care about like data integrity, hardcore, like wicked hardcore.
Scott: I need everything to be perfect.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Why would I use Postgres?
Scott: It's just.
Scott: it's just like a blog.
Scott: Who cares?
Scott: I'll use my SQL with my ISAM.
Scott: There's no sure.
Scott: it's not as compliant.
Scott: Who gives a shit?
Scott: It works and it's crazy fast.
Rym: Well, here's here's my reasons for using it.
Rym: I basically am a bank and I do need that.
Scott: I'm saying that you are a bank, but I'm talking about people are saying like even for websites, like, oh, you got to use Postgres.
Scott: It's like, what the fuck?
Scott: It's a fucking website.
Scott: The only other.
Scott: why would I use something that's harder to use, difficult to replicate and whatever.
Scott: There's some under the hood differences.
Scott: Tell me what they are and why they matter to someone who is not a bank.
Rym: One thing I have found is that there are performance advantages to Postgres depending on what kind of reading it might.
Scott: it might be that Postgres.
Scott: You know, it being all compliant and super perfect.
Scott: Right.
Scott: On the database, low level is faster than the MySQL in the perfect mode.
Rym: But you know what?
Rym: If you're if you're at the point where performance matters that much, you should be doing your own benchmarking.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So anyway, the second thing.
Scott: So people these same people, right, will come to you and say, yeah, we couldn't scale any of those relational databases.
Scott: So we use the no SQL database.
Scott: So it's like, oh, wait a minute.
Scott: The no SQL day.
Scott: It's like we couldn't.
Scott: they couldn't use my SQL in the my ISAM mode because if you don't use it, you're not going to be able to use it.
Scott: It wasn't compliant and awesome, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So they used either my SQL, you know, DB or Postgres, but they couldn't use those because they were too slow.
Scott: But they could use like Mongo DB or CouchDB or Cassandra or any of these no SQL databases.
Scott: Like, ah, now we can scale and replicate.
Scott: And it's awesome.
Scott: I'm like, dude, that no SQL database that you're using is no more compliant.
Scott: In fact, it's much less compliant than the my SQL in the fast, crappy mode.
Scott: Why didn't you just go back to using my SQL?
Rym: I think my belief is that a lot of the people who are for this are not actually super good coders.
Rym: And basically, I've noticed like an IT, at least a lot of people shy away from learning about databases on the low level.
Rym: Like a lot of IT people, NCS people don't know much about, like, really using databases.
Rym: So real relational databases probably scare them, and they find it a lot easier to develop for and optimize for things that aren't actually doing well.
Scott: Here's the thing is that these no SQL databases, though, what I found through extensive research, including I went to the Mongo NYC like conference last Friday, and I learned all about Mongo and about this stuff in general, right, is there are two use cases for it.
Scott: One use case is if you actually need to scale big, right?
Scott: For example, I heard a talk from the guy who does the tech for Sluggy freelance, right, the webcomic.
Scott: And he basically just does it because he's friends with the guy, the webcomic artist.
Scott: And, you know, he's not getting paid for anything.
Scott: He's just doing it because, you know, he's, you know, he's not getting paid for anything.
Scott: He's a pal.
Scott: And basically, their servers couldn't handle it.
Scott: And their goal is to save money, right?
Scott: Because basically, tech is just a cost for them, right?
Scott: And the Sluggy guy's living off of it.
Scott: So they just want to be able to get the website to handle all the traffic, and it gets a lot of traffic comparatively to other webcomics, right?
Scott: But they need to like as few servers as possible as with as little hardware resources possible to keep the price down.
Scott: They want to use free stuff, right?
Scott: And in that case, right, using, you know, the NoSQL database definitely helps them out.
Scott: It lets them, you know, scale way bigger, right, with replication, with very easy replication, easy partitioning, easy load balancing, right, easy backups and all this stuff for way cheaper than even using MySQL in the fast mode.
Scott: So that is totally good reason to use it.
Scott: Second good reason, Bitly also, there was a guy from Bitly talking about how they use it for like one function of Bitly, not the whole thing, you know, just one function of it.
Scott: They apparently the actual Bitly part, the URL shortener is still MySQL, I think he said.
Scott: But there's like one part of Bitly that uses Mongo.
Scott: And they've got it like, you know, split between two machines that both have like slave backup things.
Scott: It's like they needed to be all reliable like that and also fast.
Scott: And it totally works for that.
Scott: Another reason to use it is you have lots of writing going on, right?
Scott: Because the fast mode in MySQL is really good for reading.
Scott: But if you're writing a lot to the database, it basically locks the table while it's writing.
Scott: So if a whole bunch of people are trying to read it, while you're writing to it, it goes ahh.
Scott: And you could use a slave and make everyone read from the slave.
Scott: But then there's some problems occasionally where you'll write to the slave and then read immediately, write to the master, read from the slave before the write is propagated, then it's wrong.
Scott: And if you care about that, then, you know, but that can happen in the NoSQL databases also.
Rym: It won't happen with Postgres, but then you need to know what you're doing to get at the replication.
Scott: You get a lot of writing going on, right?
Scott: For example, let's say you want to put your like your tracking, your like Google Analytics, right?
Scott: So every time someone hits your page, you're writing to the database, right?
Scott: That would be a good reason to use a NoSQL, right?
Rym: I guess one other case I've found, at least for me, is rapid prototyping of things.
Rym: I'll use Couch TV just as a quick backend to stuff stuff in.
Rym: Then I replace it with a proper database like interface once I'm done.
Rym: With like just getting my, you know, like the basic, basically the logical side of my code before I get to the actual like recoding it properly side.
Scott: Now, another reason to use a NoSQL database is because they don't have a schema, right?
Scott: So if you're using MySQL, even in the fast mode, you have to choose what columns are in your table.
Scott: And if you want to change something about your application that requires a database change, like, oh, I have to add a new field, then you've got to go to the database and add a new field.
Scott: That's a huge pain in the ass.
Scott: If you want to remove a field, God help you, right?
Scott: Most of these NoSQL guys are schema-less.
Scott: You can just add and remove fields willy-nilly.
Scott: Two separate like, you know, rows in quotes, right, are in the same exact, you know, table in quotes also.
Scott: Because, you know, sometimes it's like two different documents in the same collection or whatever they want to call it, right?
Scott: Could have completely different fields.
Scott: One could have like a name and a date field.
Scott: Another one could have like a time and a video field, you know, and they'll be right next to each other and it won't give a shit at all.
Scott: And this is really useful.
Scott: Like, let's say you're making something like IMDB, right?
Scott: So you put all these movies in and, you know, OK, most movies have like a year and a director, right?
Scott: But, oh, my God, this movie has like a sub director and no other movie had that.
Scott: If you're using a NoSQL database, you just be like, boom, sub director field on this one and not on any of the others.
Scott: Just do it, right?
Scott: But if you're using a MySQL database or a relational database, you have to go and explicitly add the field just because one fluke movie came along.
Scott: And that's a pain.
Scott: The sluggy guy actually talked about how for their e-commerce part, PayPal keeps changing like what fields they send you.
Scott: So basically he just stores every field PayPal sends them in the non-relational database, no matter what they send.
Scott: And it doesn't matter if PayPal changes what fields it's sending.
Scott: They just keep all of them and they only pay attention to the ones that they care about and it's all good.
Scott: And, you know, it totally just works out because whatever PayPal sends them, they can just store every single thing that PayPal sent them, no matter.
Scott: They don't have to keep changing their database to match PayPal's changing API.
Scott: Just always good.
Scott: And that's another good reason for them.
Rym: I would argue, too, now that I think about it, I think another thing that drives a lot of, I guess, less apt coders to this.
Rym: I found that a lot of serious tech people I know don't actually know SQL.
Scott: I know that's like I'm really, really good at SQL.
Scott: At least I think so.
Rym: So I'm no guru.
Rym: I've seen some queries that make me quake.
Scott: A lot of times, you know, people try to use these ORMs, which is where you can interact with the database by objects that having to write any SQL.
Scott: And the thing is, they always frustrate me because sure, there might be easy to code and I use them.
Scott: That's basically my job.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But it always frustrates me that they write such shitty SQL or they force me to create such shitty SQL when I know that I could write basically, you know, some page will do like 20 queries.
Scott: I know I could write one query to do the whole page.
Scott: I know I could do it, but I just, you know, there's an ORM sitting there.
Scott: And of course, you can always write raw SQL, but it's like, well, it's just more work.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, whenever I write stuff, you know, interfaces or things internally, like I got to grab stuff from a database and then send it via SOAP to some other thing.
Rym: I'll usually write, like I'll spend most of my time writing the query to get exactly what I want out of the database in the most efficient way possible.
Rym: And then that will be my point of interface.
Rym: So my actual code is very simple.
Rym: I'm not doing like a million transformations and like secondary lookups to figure out what, you know, this field say is defined in some other table.
Rym: So I'm not like doing multiple lookups or anything, just one awesome joined query.
Rym: That's the most efficient thing possible.
Rym: It gives me exactly what I need.
Rym: But a lot of coders, I just don't think can do that.
Scott: Nope.
Scott: I don't think they can.
Rym: And I think part of it is that I don't think most IT and CS education emphasizes, I think data access and data storage and SQL are actually very important subjects that are overlooked by a lot of programs.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I took one database class and it was kind of weak.
Scott: RIT forced us.
Scott: I didn't actually learn databases in that class.
Scott: I learned them later on my own.
Rym: See, RIT forced all IT majors at least to take one pretty hardcore intro to database class.
Rym: Like it got like in the beginning it was like, this is a database.
Rym: And by the end it was, you know, right complex outer joins from multiple heterogeneous databases.
Scott: So this is another thing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So if you saw a lot of Web applications out there aren't actually relational in nature.
Scott: So think about, say, WordPress.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You make a post and a post has a whole bunch of stuff in it.
Scott: It's got comments.
Scott: It's got body text.
Scott: It maybe has some videos.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But it's not related to anything.
Scott: Really.
Scott: You know, there's no reason you have to make that relational.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You could totally make that non-relational where each post is its own row.
Scott: And every single piece of data about that post is in that row.
Rym: Like think of CouchDB.
Rym: You've got, you know, your identifier for, if you use that as an example, identifier for my blog post, you know, X. And then say I have a video associated with it.
Rym: All right.
Rym: That's just in the database now.
Rym: You know, video and then the file or video and then the link.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So if you don't have a relational application using one of these, you know, it does you do lose some things in terms of data integrity and data safety and, you know, making sure your data is like always correct.
Scott: But you make up for it because it's so scalable.
Scott: Right.
Scott: If you need to scale, if you don't need to scale, I say don't bother.
Scott: But but, you know, it is also more flexible because, you know, the fact that you can just change the schema at any time is not restricted.
Rym: That's why I say it's especially good for rapid prototyping.
Rym: Like say like I'm I was writing I gave up on this.
Rym: I'm going to use something else instead.
Rym: Say I needed to make an application is going to track like panels for a convention.
Rym: So.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So I define define my database schema and figure out like all the data I need to track and make the database and then start writing the code.
Rym: Every time I decide like, all right, this logical flow is bad, I have to change it.
Rym: I either have to change all my database schema.
Scott: Alter table blah.
Rym: Or I have to work my code around the scheme I already wrote, as opposed to just solving the problem.
Rym: So like CouchDB is perfect to just have a back end that's functional while I'm figuring out the logic.
Rym: Because, you know, a good coder, you might get 90 percent through a project and then realize you made a fundamental flaw in your flow and you're better off kind of going all the way back and writing again.
Rym: Then you are writing around this problem with all this existing infrastructure.
Scott: The thing is, there are some applications out there that are inherently relational.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, maybe you've got something where, you know, like.
Rym: I don't know, you know, address books are a good example, keeping track of people, keeping track of inventory.
Rym: Yeah, these are things where you have a list of assets and every asset has a series of defined relationships to like who owns it and all that sort of stuff.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, OK, you know, who owned it?
Scott: This person.
Scott: What else does this person own when you want to start asking crossways questions?
Scott: Right.
Scott: Like, OK, what are the?
Scott: what are the tags in this blog post?
Scott: That's an upset.
Scott: That's a straight up question.
Scott: You can just look at the blog post object and see what tags are on there.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But a sideways question to show me all the blog posts with the tags of food.
Rym: Suddenly you're in a lot of trouble with these non-relational database.
Scott: Right now, you could do that very easily with a query or a join in SQL.
Scott: But using the non-relational database, you basically you have to do it yourself.
Scott: You have to write your own join.
Scott: What a pain in the ass is that?
Scott: And it's not really that fast.
Scott: You know, I mean, sure, you're still getting the scaling and load balancing and all those good things.
Scott: And maybe if you don't have to do it too often or you do in controlled cases with indexes and stuff like that, you'll be all right.
Scott: You know, but you have to do that a lot like.
Scott: that's what your application is constantly doing, that sort of thing.
Scott: Like show me all the movies directed by food.
Scott: OK, now for that movie directed by food.
Scott: Show me everyone who is in it.
Scott: OK.
Scott: All right.
Scott: You keep going cross ways and ups through the data in multiple different directions, joining and selecting across and also different or never mind data mining.
Rym: Like if you want to be able to use this data for some sort of complex analysis later on, you really want relational databases.
Scott: Yeah, if it's relational data.
Scott: So these people, like some of them are even suggesting, right, to use the NoSQL database when the data is highly relational.
Scott: And, you know, maybe I can understand these people, you know, they keep making websites that are, you know, so big they need to scale so big that they, you know, it's easier for them to just write a join themselves than it is to try to get MySQL or Postgres to scale in some way, which is somewhat understandable.
Scott: But really, that's not the right way.
Scott: You could just, you know, put the memcache out in front and, you know, get it going properly.
Scott: You know, think about, you know, even the Bitly people, right?
Scott: They talked about how they were using the MongoDB for this one like history feature, but they're using MySQL for the straight up, you know, URL shortener, which is far more trafficked and they've obviously made it scale and it works.
Scott: Bitly ain't slow, you know?
Scott: So you don't need, you can scale without using these things.
Scott: You know, scaling alone is not a reason to pick NoSQL, non-relational, over-relational.
Rym: So here's the trouble, I guess, for a lot of our non-technical listeners or the not super technical.
Rym: It seems like the only way to know if you need a relational database or not, or if you need scaling or any of this stuff, is to already be an IT or CS expert.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But the thing is, even a lot of experts, like they've totally drunk.
Scott: There were so many people there who drank the Kool-Aid on this, you know, like a lot of the people.
Rym: I can say that no one in the enterprise world has.
Scott: Granted, you know, it was the Mongo NYC.
Scott: It was about this one product, right?
Scott: And it was the company that, you know, supports it was there.
Scott: There was obviously, you know, you pay us to learn about our thing and we try to sell it to you situation.
Scott: And the thing is, a lot of the talks were straight up educational.
Scott: A lot of them were like really high quality people, you know, giving you the pros and cons of different setups.
Scott: You know, suggesting some best practices and all this stuff.
Scott: But there were like a couple people who were just totally Kool-Aid.
Scott: And I was just like, dude, not cool.
Scott: Not cool.
Scott: Like, whatever.
Scott: But yeah, you know, if you're out there and you want to, you know, learn some databasing or whatever, you know, it's worth playing around with these things because, you know, you can just sort of start them up and start poking at them and learn about some databasing.
Rym: Yeah, it's actually pretty straightforward.
Rym: In fact, if you really want, I would recommend if you're in like a corporate environment, you have access to it.
Rym: The IDE, the MS SQL like server management tool, if you have an MS SQL database installed somewhere at work is actually super awesome.
Rym: for, you know, if you have a tail, like you import a database for writing queries and seeing how they work.
Rym: And it kind of guides you in writing the SQL.
Rym: That's actually I've seen a lot of people learn how to do SQL with that.
Rym: So if you're in college, you can probably get a hold of that and just, you know, use the query analyzer, write some queries, find like some test database, just mess with it.
Scott: The other thing is that, you know, like if you connect to Postgres or MySQL on the terminal, I mean, MySQL is a lot easier to use on the shell than Postgres is.
Rym: Postgres is really easy.
Rym: You just type, you know, Postgres basically.
Scott: No, but the shell itself is kind of shitty.
Scott: It's got all these backslash commands, whereas in MySQL, you just be like, show databases, use this database, show tables.
Rym: See, I guess I'm used to that.
Rym: Never mind fucking Oracle.
Rym: I got to look at like the...
Scott: Yeah, I don't even know what the Oracle is like.
Rym: I've learned it again.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: But, right, if you use one, a lot of these know SQL guys, their shells are even easier to use, like Mongo, for example, right?
Scott: The one that I went to the conference about, their shell is basically a JavaScript.
Scott: You can just, any JavaScript, you can type in there, right?
Scott: And it's just, the whole thing is JavaScript.
Scott: So it's totally, it's like, you know, the Python shell.
Scott: It's like totally fun and awesome.
Scott: You can do all sorts of crazy stuff in it.
Scott: And it's great for learning how their stuff works if you just open up their shell and go nuts.
Rym: Of course, SQL too, a lot of people are afraid of SQL, but it really is very close to natural language until you get to more advanced queries.
Rym: I mean, anyone can understand the statement, select all from, you know, foo table where bar equals one.
Scott: Select name from, you know, shows dot people where name, you know, where age equals 30.
Scott: Well, that's going to give me all the names of all the 30-year-old people in the shows table, shows database, whatever.
Rym: I mean, it remains intelligible as a natural language further along than you'd expect.
Rym: Of course, once you have like 10 case statements thrown in, you're not going to really read so well.
Scott: I never use case statements.
Rym: I use case a lot when I, well, I won't get into the details.
Rym: We've gone on too long enough.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.