Rym: It's Thursday 11 11 2010.
Rym: I'm Rym And this is GeekNights tonight protest rallies and riots.
Rym: Let's do this.
Scott: Is it anything like a mistress?
Rym: What do you want?
Rym: It's armistice day 11 11 2010.
Rym: I like.
Scott: I like how you redid the the you you stopped recording so that you got correct.
Rym: your mistake of saying Our mistress incorrectly or didn't record as you can look at right now.
Rym: I said wait I have to restart it Uh-huh.
Scott: Yeah, cuz you didn't.
Scott: you're bad at pronouncing.
Scott: You're covering up your errors Okay.
Rym: Anyway, it is armistice day.
Scott: All right, so yeah exciting thrilling.
Scott: Wow, that's a that's an exciting start to the show there.
Scott: so Anything else going on?
Rym: Hey, I don't know you give me all this crap about saying the date and yet No one seems to have complained about the fact that I say the date in the opening.
Rym: you're so about it.
Scott: No one's even commented either way.
Scott: Yeah, who knows what they think?
Rym: I Think we should leave the date in and I'm gonna keep doing it.
Rym: You sounded so just Like I'm Rym.
Scott: Why can't you just say the date the way we've been saying it?
Scott: Why you gotta mess things up?
Rym: Why don't you?
Scott: just does name wasn't broken?
Rym: Why don't you just keep slaves like we've been doing?
Rym: Why do you guys set them free?
Rym: All right, got a change.
Rym: We got a progress.
Scott: Yeah, but if it ain't broke don't fix it.
Scott: you got to change what's broke but not what's not broke and I think it was Broke.
Rym: we didn't.
Scott: it was not broke not only as single person complained.
Scott: No, not a single person.
Scott: is that a problem with it?
Rym: So we should only fix things that people complain about even if they're wrong.
Scott: No, you should only fix things that are broken.
Rym: I mean 20 of the 2000 bug, you know, why 2k?
Rym: we know it was broken.
Rym: actually in a lot of places It wasn't but we had to check But it was actual breakage.
Rym: This is not breakage But we didn't handle the date rollover.
Scott: you're fixing a problem that does not even exist.
Rym: the fact that we didn't handle the date rollover.
Scott: No, the fact that would saying the date at the beginning of the show.
Scott: We don't even need to say the day to being a show we just leave it out entirely.
Scott: It wouldn't make a difference.
Rym: So we just not do the show would make a difference.
Rym: It's also true God.
Scott: So considering how inconsequential it is.
Rym: There's no reason to change But considering how inconsequential it is There's no reason to resist the change.
Rym: that doesn't cost you anything.
Scott: It does good.
Scott: I just think it.
Scott: I think it's worse.
Scott: It lowers the quality.
Rym: I think that's silly.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: I think it's silly spending the whole beginning of the show arguing about how we say the date in the show.
Rym: You're the one who started it.
Rym: Anyway, it's Thursday.
Rym: So, I guess zombies.
Rym: I mean isn't that the Thursday show we're gonna do?
Scott: no, we're never doing that show.
Rym: I don't understand why people to this day demand we do a zombie show.
Scott: We did that first zombie show in 2006 the same shallow people who will go to the comic book store and they'll buy anything with a zombie on it and they'll go See any movie where the zombie in it and they'll watch any TV show.
Rym: Why don't we farm out a zombie podcast?
Scott: Zombies if they go to if they want to buy anything, right?
Scott: They want to go to the store and buy a screwdriver.
Scott: if one of them has a zombie on the package They'll buy that one.
Rym: I gotta admit if I was buying a screwdriver and there were zombie brand and like normal brand and the zombie brand didn't Cause that much more.
Scott: I would evaluate the actual screwdriver in question based on price and quality.
Rym: Screwdrivers are pretty much all the same now.
Scott: They're made of different materials and the different sizes and some of them are stronger and weaker and for 90% of people It doesn't matter it matters.
Rym: Not really it does.
Rym: I have the cheapest ass screwdriver.
Scott: Yeah, I see a magnetic non magnetic.
Scott: Yeah, you know what handles there's grip.
Rym: There's no reason to not get magnetic.
Rym: magnetic doesn't hurt anything.
Scott: But there is occasionally a reason not to get magnetic.
Rym: Yeah, but rarely.
Rym: I mean a lot of people think that they shouldn't use them into their computer.
Rym: But that's not hurting anything.
Scott: No But it could be a problem.
Scott: say you're screwing something into something in this metal filings about that suddenly got metal filings over your screwdriver.
Rym: It's like ah fuck and then you just wipe them off.
Rym: I think the deeper problem there is why are you screwing into something?
Rym: That's covered in metal filings.
Scott: Maybe you're screwing into something that's metal and the filings are coming out because you're screwing.
Rym: then you're not screwing you're drilling.
Scott: What if it's already semi drilled?
Scott: but you're you know the tight fit.
Scott: Good guy, what do we know about screwing and drilling here?
Rym: quite a bit in fact If you can tell we couldn't figure out what to do the fucking show on.
Scott: no, not at all Let's do some news.
Rym: I do want to get out of this rut a little bit about this article because it's been making the rounds and internet people are talking about it and Everyone that I've seen so far is missing the base point.
Scott: the AP was reporting that that's because the AP writes something and everyone else writes the exact same thing with different language.
Scott: They just get the thesaurus and they put up a mark But even in comments in places people just don't get it.
Rym: So there was the study that showed that there's a strong correlation.
Rym: now, obviously, there's no causation proof of causation But there's a strong correlation between people who text frequently and use Facebook Well and or use Facebook.
Rym: this is correlated strongly with drug use and Sex.
Scott: Well, gee, if you are the kind of person who has more friends You're the kind of person who has people to text and Facebook with and as a result people to have sex and drugs.
Scott: with Drug, I mean sex is pretty much Explicitly a you know friend.
Scott: Multi-person activity and drugs are usually not too many people do drugs alone.
Rym: Yep, two two to four players four hours.
Scott: I mean try to imagine in your head stoners.
Scott: You don't think of a stoner in his room alone with weed.
Scott: you think of a bunch of people passing the bong around.
Scott: You know that right?
Scott: It's not a.
Rym: well, there is the stoner who's alone in this room.
Scott: That's a rare.
Scott: you don't think about that though.
Rym: Is that guy rare?
Rym: that guy is the same as the alcoholic who is also alone in his room.
Scott: someone who is lonely Is a lot less likely to do drugs and or an extremely unlikely to have sex.
Scott: so What's with the captain?
Scott: obvious,
Rym: but I think although especially in the mainstream news a lot of the commentary about it This has been really weird and they're trying to either say there's some sort of correlation between using this Social technology and being a deviant or whatever
Scott: about the correlation with having lots of friends.
Rym: I think it's even simpler.
Rym: I think it's a correlation with being young and the fact that society has been progressively more and more open liberal and generally cool with stuff.
Rym: as time has gone on and The generations coming up now, I mean when I was in high school for all the talk kids had about yeah I had sex and how worldly they pretended to be Not many of them were actually having sex or even they making out with each other and that became quite apparent when Someone I know had sex and suddenly all these very worldly people were very I don't know.
Rym: It was obvious that they had no idea what they were talking about And I think if I was in high school today, it's blowjobs aplenty.
Rym: I Get this impression and I think that the simple correlation causation here isn't even social.
Rym: people are more likely to have sex.
Rym: I think it's just the generation coming up is way more liberal.
Rym: on average.
Rym: I'm just about everything and if you're young you're more likely to use new technology.
Scott: You're just saying it's the times right?
Scott: Yeah, like hey in 2010 Kids are more likely to have sex and also in 2010 kids are more likely to use Facebook because Both of those things are on the rise that happen to be on the rise at the same time.
Rym: so in fact I would argue that the kids who don't send a lot of text or don't use a lot of Facebook are the kids who are Actually already behind the times Or ahead of way ahead of the times.
Rym: I'm not getting the sense that they're way ahead of the times But you don't know.
Scott: the times could revert.
Scott: it could be a sine wave go back and forth.
Rym: Thing is it never really has except for the Dark Ages I don't know.
Scott: I mean, you know, you look at something like the Victorian era right where everything was on the surface all very, you know modest but underneath much more lewd.
Scott: In reality, it was the ludest and then it was only after it that it actually got a little bit less lewd.
Scott: But there's always lewdness somewhere Everywhere.
Rym: I mean, I think this study can really just be summed up as kids who use technology are smarter and more social and more Likely to do fun things.
Scott: Yeah, it's due to I don't know whatever.
Scott: So I also read about this article about a study, of course You know, you never get the actual study and everything's always full of bullshit.
Rym: I got the actual study here, but it wasn't that exciting.
Scott: Oh, wow, very cool.
Scott: But anyway, this article has also made the similar rounds and it's typical science reporting.
Scott: But anyway, what it's about is it says spacing out half the day makes people unhappy in Harvard study and they're basically saying look People especially when they're at work their minds wander about forty six point nine percent of the time.
Rym: Ah, it's about right.
Scott: I'm mostly just kind of walking around looking around thinking about stuff and no less than thirty percent of the time during every activity except sex.
Scott: And apparently people who are able to focus on one thing for a long amount of time as opposed to having their mind wander are happier.
Scott: and it's like Here's another situation where it's like hello.
Scott: obviously, it's not the mind Wandering that is causing the effect of being bored.
Scott: It's their board.
Scott: They're unhappy because they're bored.
Scott: So when they got nothing to do their mind wanders if they had something to do or if they have this on that shit.
Rym: Or like my situation at work.
Rym: I have stuff to do.
Rym: It's just boring.
Scott: I'm in the same situation.
Scott: I don't want my mind to wander at work.
Scott: It wanders cuz there's nothing doing.
Rym: There's a reason.
Rym: I'm reading C sharp and XNA books and and cuz I'm bored and I want to learn.
Rym: I don't want to just And I can't.
Scott: I would do my own thing in my free time at work, but I can't.
Scott: cuz then they own that shit.
Scott: Yeah, I was at home.
Scott: I could get away with it cuz they would never know.
Scott: but at the same time I can't just be at home all the time.
Rym: My mind really only waters when I'm bored.
Scott: Yeah I mean if there are some days Rarely once maybe a couple times a month if I'm lucky where there's actually something to do and Focus on for the whole day because most days I could just do all my work in like ten minutes not be it.
Scott: You know, it's cuz it's so easy.
Rym: Sometimes I will pointedly daydream like I'll be like, I'm just gonna sit here and dick around.
Scott: Yes, but it's just like I'm not.
Scott: you know, it doesn't make me unhappy But you know that my mind is wandering.
Scott: my mind wandering is it's the other way around.
Rym: Whoa, whoa, go I want to go back to my study for a second.
Rym: You know what they define as a frequent texter.
Rym: All right more than a hundred and twenty a day Okay.
Rym: Yeah, cuz basically, you know kids they use it the way we used aim.
Scott: Yeah kids these days if you got friends, they have a you know, they have text.
Scott: They don't use aim They just use text messages.
Scott: They have their phones with them all day.
Scott: And if you're not in a class with They're bored.
Scott: They're not paying attention in class because they're fucking bored other minds.
Scott: So they just talk to people all day because you can't do anything else.
Rym: They're existing in this kind of meta universe where they're not bored.
Rym: Their mind is.
Rym: think of this in that study, right people's minds are wandering, but it's daydreaming like I'm bored thinking about potatoes.
Scott: Yeah I mean if you're the kind of person who has a friend that is gonna text you 160 times a day Then you probably have or even have enough friends to add up to that.
Scott: Then these people actually want to talk to you which means they're actually your friends and you access that to talk about with them Which means you have a lot of friends means you're very likely Person who gets along with people and that's very likely to have sex with someone.
Scott: and also if you're into drugs There'll be people to have drugs with.
Rym: But here's my point in that study.
Rym: people's minds wander within their own mind.
Rym: They're bored and their mind is just kind of thinking about potatoes.
Rym: Yeah These kids see potatoes their mind is literally.
Rym: well it is in a way Wandering as in they're.
Rym: they're physically in a place They're in class somewhere or they're like on the bus or their mom's talking to him or something.
Rym: But really their mind is out in this shared space with all the other people They're texting their mind is literally wandered and they're probably happier.
Scott: Well, I mean the thing is, you know, when I mind wanders at work, it's wandering on the internet, right?
Scott: It's not wandering.
Rym: Sometimes I can't wander on the internet or I've wandered everywhere.
Rym: interesting to wander.
Rym: That's usually.
Scott: my problem is I Wandered the whole internet.
Rym: Yeah when I worked at that old job in the hospital I remember there were days where all right.
Rym: I've read everything on Fark Nothing else to do.
Rym: Should they buy?
Scott: Tony really just need some sort of way for you know people to I you know to You know to take.
Scott: hey, I did all my work.
Scott: You must let me leave or give me more work immediately.
Rym: Ah, but here's the problem.
Rym: What if their resolution to that is to give you stupid work that is time-consuming that is unnecessary work.
Scott: Example as a software engineer I can automate all work.
Scott: There is no work they could give me that I could not automate.
Rym: I worked as Perhaps the worst pizza chef in the history of RIT at the Ritz in the bar downstairs yep, and I was the worst pizza chef because they paid me so little that I literally just didn't care.
Rym: and once I made a good pizza and they yelled at me because I used too many ingredients and I was like All right, fine back to shitty pizza.
Rym: I go but Anytime I was not actively making pizza or throwing away the pizza that no one bought because it was shady to replace it with new Shitty pizza that no one would buy.
Scott: you're just standing there.
Rym: I was just standing there and my manager.
Rym: one day I came up and she was like if you got time to lean You got time to clean.
Scott: But it's like we already just cleaned everything.
Rym: and I was.
Rym: I was leaning against the fridge.
Rym: So what you know what I did.
Rym: I stopped leaning and I stood there.
Rym: Okay, and she was like clean something.
Rym: I cleaned goddamn everything.
Rym: I was so bored I pulled back like the fridge and cleaned behind that shit.
Rym: All right, and then I leaned and she said it again and I quit.
Rym: That's how I quit the Ritz.
Rym: she was like if you got time to lean you got time to clean like a month later.
Rym: And I was like, you know what I quit.
Rym: And she was like what I was like, yeah, I quit.
Rym: I'm done.
Scott: It seems like people.
Scott: it's like whenever you have a job people act like, you know, you need that job.
Scott: Yeah Another job.
Scott: there's never been a time in my life where I could not get a job within a few days.
Rym: I think a lot of you cannot threaten me with fire either do need their jobs or They don't realize how easy it is to get another job.
Scott: If you are maybe really want it's hard for them to get a job because they have no skills.
Rym: No, all righty kids.
Rym: It's trivial to get a job somewhere in Rochester.
Rym: It's just people don't know how to look for a job.
Rym: They apply to like the obvious jobs like the local fast food or the on-campus jobs And they don't even think about applying to like the factory nearby to be like a maintenance guy at night.
Scott: Yeah, no one you know, that's that's a big problem is in the whole world Is it these non obvious jobs?
Scott: and no no career counselors, right?
Scott: You know, I would be a career counselor if it paid better because I would I would actually be able to find people you know the careers they wouldn't even think about like somebody underwater.
Rym: welder obviously Racer Mm-hmm f1 driver you can go for that.
Rym: You could race car driver things.
Rym: You got to start early on that Yeah, but if you got to go to elementary kids school kids and be like, you know what?
Scott: Right.
Scott: Here's a praise.
Scott: That's a good job, right?
Scott: So f1 driver.
Scott: That's a hard job to get right?
Scott: But you could be the pit crew guy.
Scott: Yeah, you could be the mechanic guy You could be the.
Scott: you could make racing helmets You can.
Scott: you could be the guy who's in charge of getting sponsorships for the cars.
Scott: You could be the race steward the guy who runs out with the fire extinguisher.
Scott: There's like a million jobs just in that one Small area that no one even thinks about.
Scott: you know one grows up says I'm gonna be a race steward I'm gonna be there who weighs the checkered flag.
Scott: No one thinks they're gonna be that guy.
Rym: Yeah, but I'd love as a kid if someone had said hey, but that's actually a really that guy That's a beat.
Scott: It's a damn good job.
Rym: You want to go for that go for it?
Scott: Go all around the world.
Rym: when I was a freshman in high school there was one of those, you know, what career you're gonna have aptitude tests like what careers you good at and I took it and Based on everything basically gave everyone else in my class like 10 or 15 options.
Rym: It literally gave me one option which was it said?
Rym: Market data analyst you're getting close.
Rym: Yeah, and I thought fuck that I'm going into computers.
Scott: and Well, you know I I never took one of those things but I always heard saw jokes about them and they were on TV shows And stuff, you know, there'd always be.
Scott: every sitcom would have an episode about them if there were kids in school.
Rym: And yeah, it tells the one kid he's gonna be a janitor and he's upset about it.
Scott: Yeah But yeah, I never took one of those.
Scott: but that's weird.
Scott: that what it would be.
Scott: so, you know accurate I guess you know if even if it's random it's gonna be scarily correct on some people and incorrect on most people.
Rym: but also if you're young and skilled generally like you have basic human skills and you live anywhere where there's a reasonable density of Population in a city it is trivial to get to.
Rym: even in a suburb it is actually pretty trivial to get a job that'll pay you enough to live.
Rym: and It it amazes me.
Rym: there were people I knew who couldn't like a job they hated and they never like realized they could quit and I always felt like I should have been the hero.
Rym: like that one college humor with the guy Who plays the spags are through stir stands up on the table rips off his shirt.
Rym: He's duct-taped I quit to his chest and runs around like screaming and quitting and eventually the cops get called.
Rym: But no when I remember when I worked at the Bellas one day they called me in the morning.
Rym: They're like Rym.
Rym: You didn't show up to work and I was like, yeah I guess I didn't.
Rym: and then the guy pauses and he's like are you ever gonna show up again?
Rym: Cuz he knew.
Rym: and I was like You know what?
Rym: Nah I'm done.
Rym: Or the Ritz I quit I'm done like this or the hospital.
Rym: Yeah, I was kind of hoping to be out of here by lunchtime.
Scott: The thing is when I was younger I always looked at people who couldn't stay with one job, but I'd like why can't you stay with one job?
Scott: What's wrong with you?
Rym: I this is the longest job I've ever held already Three years and I knew people at IBM who'd worked at IBM for 40 years.
Scott: What the fuck my life not even 40 years old.
Rym: So things of the day, I like otters.
Rym: I like cute otters.
Rym: I like cute baby otters being taught how to swim.
Rym: The babies they kind of know.
Scott: but basically the way like a fucking giraffe comes out and starts walking like right away.
Rym: Yeah, what an otter.
Scott: come out and swim right away.
Rym: otters walk right away But when their babies?
Rym: basically I've watched videos of this what otter moms do is one day They're like you're ready and they pick them up in the neck.
Scott: Aren't they born in the water now?
Rym: Okay, cuz they're basically like water land like dogs Like they go between the land and the water and act like dogs that they like to play with rocks.
Rym: So one day the mom otters like they don't play they don't pick up rocks in their hands like they catch with them.
Rym: So one day the otter mom's like, all right fuckers time to learn how to swim.
Rym: We shall pick them up throw them in the water.
Scott: Yeah, that's how you do it.
Rym: and they're like, yeah and they try to get out.
Rym: She picks them up and throws them back in the water until they figure it out.
Rym: So this is a human doing that because the otters don't have mommies or something is really cute.
Scott: take note people with human babies Same thing works.
Scott: Don't be afraid to do it.
Scott: You're standing right there.
Scott: if they start drowning you pick them up.
Scott: It's not gonna be the end of the world, right?
Rym: That's how I Learned how to sled and ski.
Rym: to a degree.
Rym: I got one lesson and then I was basically pushed down the mountain.
Rym: in both cases.
Scott: Yeah, it's you know, people are so afraid like I was so cruel.
Scott: It's like yeah, the kid might be upset.
Rym: You know how.
Scott: I learned how to getting upset never hurt anybody.
Scott: I learned how to solder as long as you don't drown.
Scott: It's all good.
Rym: I learned how to solder by fucking burning my fingernail off.
Scott: I had an Australian guy tell me.
Rym: I learned how to wire by shocking the shit out of myself.
Rym: All right, I learned about fireworks.
Rym: I hit myself in the face with a bottle rocket.
Scott: So check it out this one, dude.
Scott: He went and he took you know Megaman the sprite of Megaman and he drew pretty much every other character except for the really obscure ones the Rym likes to think of You.
Scott: basically he took the Megaman sprite is the base sprite and then he modified it into all these other care.
Rym: Oh a lot of people do that with Kirby.
Rym: Yeah, so is there uh, There a Kraid in.
Rym: there is Samus but no Kraid.
Scott: Yeah, I don't think he's gonna do Kraid.
Rym: How about the cheetah, man?
Rym: He didn't do any of the cheetah, man.
Scott: It's a little obscure.
Rym: Not one cheetah, man.
Rym: I don't think it's that obscure.
Rym: In fact, I think it's more well known than a lot of Relatively name something that's not obscured.
Scott: It's probably on here Something all right, Dick Tracy That's not a video game that is.
Scott: It wasn't originally a video game.
Rym: So it has to be originally a video game.
Scott: most of the things on here originally a video game.
Scott: There's a couple things that aren't video games All right.
Rym: So very briefly before we get on to the main bit the meta moment We're gonna be at magfest and PAX East and PAX West and anime Boston and all those conventions.
Rym: the book club book.
Rym: We'll be finishing it soon World War Z the next Thursday episode So two weeks from today with Max Brooks And that'll probably the last Thursday episode.
Rym: that is a book club book because after that they're gonna be their own feed.
Scott: Oh, did we decide then?
Scott: Yeah everything.
Rym: I mean the whole big like book club thing is done.
Scott: Yeah, but that doesn't mean we had to make it not on Thursday.
Rym: I don't think we should waste Thursday episodes at that point.
Scott: We don't have enough ideas for Thursday.
Rym: you have plenty of ideas.
Rym: they're just they're all half-assed and we're tired.
Scott: Also Tomorrow's board game night Nerd NYC.
Rym: board game night in New York City.
Scott: If you're listening to this on Friday.
Rym: It's tonight I probably won't be there because I gotta make some license plates at work.
Rym: We'll see.
Rym: I'll show up if I can.
Rym: Yeah, I gotta make some love but I'm going in at like 11 tomorrow.
Scott: I haven't played board games a long time Me either.
Scott: I'm going though this weekend.
Rym: actually in New York City on Saturday There is the chocolate convention.
Scott: I think it's all weekend.
Scott: Actually.
Scott: I think it's even Thursday.
Rym: I don't know I don't know, but I'm gonna go Saturday.
Scott: All right, I'll go and there's some sort of meetup with Robert coup Supposedly at a ramen ramen place that is basically directly adjacent to my office.
Rym: Yeah, I think I've been there before.
Rym: Yeah, it's alright Yeah, so yeah, I don't know.
Rym: I'm gonna show up.
Rym: All right, I'll go have ramen with Robert coup.
Rym: I've never talked to him outside of business like very specific like packs business.
Scott: I've never talked to him for like 10 seconds when he took us from a point.
Rym: I've had other email conversations with him But they've always been a very specific things related to packs like specific question.
Rym: any answers it.
Scott: or here's the flight We were on where we had two people because that's when you're when you're a blackberry guy like that and like Steve Jobs is an iPhone guy, right?
Rym: I'm not gonna be like hey Basically what they do is they only reply to emails they must reply to and they reply very shortly But at the same time they reply with exactly what they needed to reply with.
Rym: I was like, you know nothing extra as a question.
Rym: Like where are the Baffa dads?
Rym: I need to know for packs and he's like Baffa dads are at X. Yeah, that's all they say and you know That's the way I'm at work.
Rym: I don't respond with thank you or anything.
Rym: I'm not like what you doin?
Scott: All right.
Scott: Hey, let's get to know each other.
Scott: That doesn't happen.
Rym: Anyway, yep, so I'll probably be at that.
Rym: All right And the GeekNights store is gonna be coming online fairly soon.
Rym: All the tech stuff is sorted out.
Scott: Let's go see here.
Scott: shop 589 days, huh?
Scott: Will you beat the two-year mark?
Rym: I am holding in my hand.
Rym: Actually.
Rym: No, I'm not.
Rym: I'm holding.
Rym: where the fuck did it go.
Rym: Oh here it is.
Rym: Okay, nevermind I'm holding in my hand a certificate of authority to collect New York State sales tax The only state in which I am obligated to collect sales tax.
Scott: Well, you're you're getting close to you.
Rym: So I swear to God if no one from New York even bothers because you realize if no New Yorkers Ever buy a t-shirt from us.
Rym: I didn't need this.
Rym: I didn't need to go through all this bullshit.
Scott: What if only one does?
Rym: Then it was technically worth it Even though I have to remit the tax to New York and we're gonna charge you the goddamn tax if you buy from New York 8% or whatever plus the clothing tax.
Scott: Anyway, anyway, and not non clothing.
Rym: So we're gonna start by selling off the remaining stocks of our original get the pocketer off my internets t-shirt.
Rym: We've got two more t-shirts in the works and other things But those will come later and basically we're gonna take soft pre-orders for everything.
Rym: That might be expensive.
Rym: I'm not gonna order like five hundred hundred dollar hockey jerseys if I can't guarantee that at least one of you is gonna buy one.
Scott: all right the.
Scott: What's our show on?
Scott: so?
Rym: Rallies, well, I guess protest rallies and riots.
Scott: Oh, it's not car auto rallies.
Rym: Oh, man, that'd be a good show.
Rym: That'd be a real good show.
Rym: I really like rallies.
Rym: I also really like that because rallies are the only place we're drifting.
Rym: actually Works well kind of but it doesn't really work.
Rym: Usually when you see someone doing a crazy crazy drift They fucked up and that's just them recovering anyway.
Scott: Kind of rally.
Rym: So I'm gonna get right to the point.
Rym: then we can talk about rallies and protests and riots and everything.
Rym: I think in the modern world protests don't do shit.
Rym: Well, it's not in America Protests defined by people with or without sign standing in front of something.
Rym: yelling don't do shit.
Scott: Yeah, if you're just standing around and or holding signs and or just yelling That's not gonna do anything right.
Scott: if you want to actually have an effect You need to have a protest that involves some sort of action or hinders people in some way.
Scott: You know, like if you just stand there while people cut down trees are gonna cut the trees.
Scott: But if you're gonna be a tree hugger and tie yourself to the tree You might be arrested but you'll maybe have an effect maybe.
Rym: well I maybe.
Rym: it's the point that for a protest to be effective You have to have both an actual demand and an ultimatum.
Scott: But that you know, that's not to say that tying yourself to the tree is guaranteed to have an effect.
Scott: It's just if you don't actually do something you're guaranteed to have no effect.
Rym: But you need to demand an ultimatum and you have to actually be willing to follow through Absolutely, or you know, if your bluff gets called you have to be like, yeah, you called my bluff.
Rym: Never mind I don't want civil rights.
Rym: I Mean look at let's look at some Protests because outside of my building the Lincoln building in Manhattan for like months There have been protests by like the masonry whatever union at the rats outside my building this week Really?
Rym: That rat was in front of my building for like a month straight.
Scott: from what I hear The rat is actually a scam where this one company wants you to hire them.
Rym: So if you hire a different company They come with a rat outside your building and they say something like this company employs shitty workers to do shitty work at low pay.
Rym: You should hire us instead, but it's like.
Scott: did anyone ask those people that they hired though are in the building working?
Scott: So it's like when we ask them and they'll be like, um, I'm fine If they didn't.
Scott: if those people don't like what they're being paid.
Scott: How come they aren't outside with the red?
Rym: Because the rat doesn't do anything is not only does the rat have no effect and does no one care But usually the only people who pay attention to the rat are tourists because they see this giant inflatable rat and they think it's some Sort of attraction.
Scott: Yeah, they're like, what the hell is this?
Rym: Right?
Rym: I see people.
Rym: I see I've seen Japanese tourists taking their pictures with it.
Rym: Yeah for a while They actually stopped using the rat and they started using this coffin with a guy in it instead Because they were it was something about asbestos, but it was the same company doing the same thing.
Rym: They're like the company.
Scott: the asbestos union is right near my apartment and you know They actually just read model their entire little Union Air Center and it's actually pretty nice now.
Rym: Ah, but they kept protesting in front of my building with the coffin and they're like the same thing.
Rym: You know incompetent people hired to remove asbestos in your building.
Rym: evil evil evil evil evil evil.
Rym: Here's a coffin.
Scott: Wait, they hired non-union guys girl.
Scott: It's like alright, so they're saving money.
Scott: good on them.
Rym: Yeah, just I'm not a union Me either.
Rym: So zero effect.
Rym: or what about the peace protesters even though I like these guys?
Scott: Yeah, those guys they stand in the corner, right?
Scott: They're having a good time.
Rym: This was up in Hopewell Junction.
Scott: Everywhere in the US.
Rym: very specifically when we lived in Beacon we would often and until we realized it was stupid and stopped doing it drive up the road to the mall and the shop right and everything and Every weekend there were all these old people cool old people.
Rym: they'd sit on the corner and they were just protesting for peace.
Rym: they were like honk.
Rym: if you want the Iraq war to end bring Our soldiers home and I rocked for those guys.
Rym: They were cool guys, but they had no effect on anything.
Scott: No, it was completely, you know a waste of time.
Scott: They weren't changing anyone's mind Right.
Scott: They weren't, you know, actually achieving anything that they wanted to achieve.
Scott: However, all they were doing was having a good time and honking Getting people to honk their horns.
Rym: However to their credit.
Rym: They had nothing better to do and they looked like they were having fun.
Rym: They're like we have a message.
Rym: We're just gonna get our message out in the most effective way that we as old non-technological people not to get it out We're gonna sit here hang out and have fun and will.
Rym: at least you know people honk and will know that.
Rym: yeah They saw us.
Rym: Maybe they care a little bit.
Rym: maybe and I remembered the saddest day was Driving up the road one day and seeing the counter protest of angry old people who were against peace.
Rym: Literally remember those guys.
Rym: they were like support our troops.
Scott: fuck Iraq.
Scott: They also achieved nothing.
Scott: Yeah complete except for wasting their own except.
Rym: so we had a protest that was like honk if you're against the Iraq war and honk if You're pro the Iraq war and they're at the same intersection and it was just old people Yep with nothing better to do.
Scott: Well, I think that a lot of the protests you see nowadays are you know old people unemployed people and occasionally young unemployed people.
Scott: It's pretty much no one who has a job is Protesting, you know anything especially not during the week or during the day.
Rym: Yeah, that's why the John Stewart rally had such.
Scott: you know that rat if there's any.
Scott: you know The people who are in the building working when the rat is there.
Scott: they have a job.
Scott: They're doing it.
Scott: right now People are standing near the rat.
Scott: are standing near the rat because their company didn't get a job and they want you to hire their Company instead.
Scott: so because they have no work to do they're gonna Stand there with the rat to try to extort you into hiring them.
Scott: So they have work to do or like.
Rym: remember that one day I we're in Beacon and there was a family Mother and their kids standing outside one of those car dealerships with the sign that was like this car dealership ripped us off.
Rym: You don't remember that?
Rym: no, we drove by it.
Rym: We actually talked about it a lot.
Scott: I don't remember that really.
Rym: Yeah, so That's it.
Rym: I already said what happened.
Rym: But yeah, I wasn't.
Scott: you know None of those.
Scott: if those people who are at time to complain about you know, the car dealers you're ripping them off.
Scott: They obviously didn't have work to do.
Rym: I hate to say it but in the modern world if you engage in Physical protest where you don't have an ultimatum and the will to follow through then you're basically Just proving that you don't understand the term opportunity cost.
Scott: Well, I mean it's even even when you're not dealing with protesting right.
Scott: it's like I'll see people who will do all sorts of things that show that they don't understand opportunity cost.
Scott: for example I know people who will go to a comic book store and they'll buy comics.
Scott: They'll buy extra copies and You know they'll take extra to keep everything in mint condition and then they'll go and they'll like sell a whole bunch of stuff on eBay and Like speculate and try to make their money back right, you know, and they try to buy a comic.
Scott: They know the price is gonna go up or buy a variant cover and sell it for twice as much.
Scott: and it's like dude.
Scott: If you worked minimum wage at McDonald's for every hour you spent, you know buying and selling comic books that you're not reading You would probably making more money than you are on these comic books, right?
Scott: So, you know people just don't you know calculate like their time.
Scott: they don't factor in their own personal time into their monies.
Scott: You know, it's like if you are standing there protesting for five hours, you know, you could have been working at McDonald's for five hours.
Scott: They'll hire you.
Rym: Trust me See now a real protest would be like say this was about the gay marriage thing and a bunch of people got together and they Went to the White House and they had a march or a rally whatever.
Rym: that really doesn't have much effect.
Rym: But if they went and they're like we're not leaving until we get it Yeah, we're not leaving arrest us.
Scott: Yeah and block and you actually have to do so, you know, they're not good.
Rym: Oh, no, you don't necessarily have to block.
Rym: Well the thing is that often move moves your protests from peaceful legal protests to illegal.
Rym: They can arrest.
Scott: but that's exactly what the point is, right?
Scott: Is it you?
Rym: No, no No, it's only the point if by being arrested thorough style You can actually make a difference.
Rym: if I go smoke a joint to get arrested to then protest joint laws That's not gonna move my movement.
Rym: I'm just gonna be in jail.
Scott: No, but that's the whole thing.
Scott: It's like if you just stand there peacefully protesting without doing anything It's not gonna do anything.
Scott: You need to go and get arrested.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: you don't know that one guy smoking a joint isn't to do anything.
Scott: get 20,000 people to all light it up.
Scott: Yes, Al at the same time Right or one guy smoking a joint isn't gonna do shit.
Rym: or if you go and say you're not gonna leave and you literally Don't leave if you've got a hundred thousand people not leaving maybe even you know hunger strike Some of that action.
Scott: Yeah, you actually have to do something threatening.
Scott: that will make them, you know now they can't arrest you.
Scott: You know, all they can do is either a concede or B do something.
Scott: That is very bad.
Scott: PR like, you know massacre you.
Rym: I mean look at that's why Gandhi was able to win was that they were peaceful.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't just stand there.
Scott: He freaking took all the salt and dumped it in the ocean.
Scott: He would just not eat and people would be like, oh shit We better do what Gandhi says or he's gonna die from not eating.
Scott: and then what it's gonna be from us Oh shit, we can't have Gandhi.
Rym: see I know that the corollary here Protests don't work.
Rym: If the person you're protesting doesn't give a shit about you.
Scott: That's also absolutely correct, right?
Scott: So let's say you are protesting, you know against police brutality and then the police brutalize you But they don't give a shit.
Scott: They're like, yeah, we brutalize you.
Scott: What are you gonna do?
Scott: Come get brutalized again motherfuckers.
Scott: Then no amount of protesting as the police brutality is gonna work.
Rym: Yeah, your protest has to be aimed at the people who can do something about.
Scott: yeah The only the only public outrage.
Scott: Yeah, the only you know protest that's actually gonna work against something like that is probably violence.
Scott: You know.
Scott: see no no or voting if you can do that.
Rym: when I say where you are We say a threat because the threat doesn't imply violence necessarily not necessarily.
Rym: It's just an ultimatum, but we want X and You know there.
Rym: we will not compromise on that.
Rym: Yep, but I've never seen effective protests in America anymore Not in my life in recent times.
Rym: This is why John Stewart's rally headsets resonance because the first thing they said it's like look it's on a Saturday For a couple hours because we know that you have jobs and yet to do but it still didn't do anything.
Scott: It was basically a free concert for everybody.
Rym: Yeah, it was.
Rym: no we'll get to that because you know, the next step up from a protest is a movement or a rally.
Scott: Yeah, what's?
Scott: it's not really a different approach.
Scott: Yeah, I went to the rally protest with a schedule.
Rym: I went to the rally.
Rym: I kind of didn't want to go.
Rym: I bailed on it cuz I was like this is gonna fail and be a disaster.
Rym: But I went for the hell of it.
Rym: I got slightly optimistic and nah, it was a boring disaster.
Scott: It was the only thing I got.
Scott: I watched it on the Internet's and I was like, oh, that's exactly what I thought I was gonna be.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: The only surprising thing drive all that way Is that a lot of people showed up.
Rym: it gave me a lot of hope.
Rym: it proved to me that yes There are a lot of rational people and everyone there was totally chill, but it had zero effect on anything Other than it made the people who showed up feel good made them feel like they did something.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean if you felt like you did something then clearly you weren't that rational, right?
Scott: I mean, it's basically it looked to me when I was looking at pictures on the internet was like, okay It was it was a normal person.
Rym: It was like.
Scott: it was like 80% cool people showed up all at the same place at the same time.
Scott: And I guess it's cool to hang out with cool people just like it packs or whatever it is.
Scott: Everyone was totally cool, but it's like if you went to packs and there were no games.
Rym: However, that would have been fine because I could I could have a lot of fun Just going to restaurants and hanging out because you bring your own Games with you.
Rym: But here's the trouble.
Rym: Washington DC sucks ass sure does and the entire city was basically Make protests.
Scott: if Washington D. Imagine it'd be so easy and comfortable to protest in New York If you had to protest, you know the fact.
Scott: that's why they put DC in DC and not New York.
Scott: So that way it's like no one wants to protest is there for that long because it sucks.
Rym: but I basically all that rally taught me was that I will never go to a rally again in the rest of my life because they're pointless and Boring, but here is an example of some kind of protest that actually does something right.
Scott: so look at this recent news with Amazon And the pedophile book.
Rym: you see that I saw that I.
Scott: so basically is what happened?
Scott: there's some pedophile guy wrote a Guide for pedophiles, and he put it on the Kindle on Amazon Which he can do.
Scott: and Amazon at first was like free speech you know hey, whatever.
Scott: and I also agree free speech I mean it wasn't didn't have child porn in it.
Scott: It was just a book up.
Scott: You know it's no different than anarchist cookbook.
Scott: Just you know not like I would buy this book or that I agree with the book or I say pedophilia is good I wait wait But just like the anarchist cookbook.
Rym: so it gives you instructions that if you follow them will cause a small child to explode killing you.
Scott: It gives you lots of instructions on how to be a pedophile, and it's like It's pretty disgusting book anyway.
Rym: How do I even read it?
Scott: I don't know from what I I didn't read it either, but I read basically with the Discussion of it.
Scott: was that for example.
Scott: It's a book That's like hey if you're a pedophile.
Scott: Listen you should do this and you shouldn't do this that way you won't get caught.
Scott: and if you don't if you do get caught You get a lighter sentence in this way.
Scott: You know you won't hurt the children.
Scott: You'll just you know.
Scott: it's like oh Okay It's that kind of book you know.
Scott: very questionable, and I don't agree with the book.
Scott: But I agree that the book should be allowed to exist and be sold because freedom of speech But at the same time no store should be required to sell it.
Scott: no that's also true.
Scott: But these people on Amazon in the comments they protested, but they didn't protest just by going rabble rabble rabble.
Scott: They actually said we're boycotting Amazon.
Scott: is some lady was like I emptied my shopping cart when I saw this book on here.
Scott: The Amazon removed the book.
Scott: they actually did something they boycotted.
Scott: a an actual doing of something you have to actually do Something you know or you know a stopping of doing something that you were doing.
Scott: you know like you will go and protest Walmart.
Scott: It's like well stop shopping there And you know what if you can't get enough people to stop shopping there Walmart staying in town.
Scott: or
Rym: like I was in the the big Rally movement marched against the Iraq war when it first started by accident well I sure I was in New York anyway
Scott: happened to be
Rym: yeah I have to be in New York even
Scott: though it was going on and I and
Rym: then I see these street like I was walking around And then the streets got barricaded around me, and I was kind of trapped and like what's going on, and then I realized Oh, there's a giant protest against the Iraq war.
Rym: well I'm against the war and I'm already in and I just walked along with it.
Rym: I was just there.
Rym: he just walked down the street and what he walking down a street accomplish now had Those people who had all been there said and we're gonna stop paying taxes until the war is done.
Rym: Yep, that would have been a movement.
Scott: that would have been But it wasn't huh?
Scott: instead all he did was walk, and they got good leg exercise.
Rym: So I mean, but then again you could go too far.
Rym: the next step from a rally is of course riot.
Scott: Well, you know the thing with the right is that it only works in certain situations, right?
Rym: Only works if it leads to revolution.
Scott: Yeah, and you know the main thing the main problem we have in the u.s.. Right as Lee or at least in any you know Relatively stable democracy is that you can't really overthrow the government with just violence.
Scott: right like let's say something crazy happened And you know I mean and we managed to like do something ridiculous like killing all the congressman or something just out of control, right?
Scott: anyone Anyone managed to actually succeed at some sort of ludicrous violence, right?
Scott: The government even the government would stay in power.
Scott: you wouldn't be able to unseat it.
Rym: if nothing else It's like a chicken without a head.
Rym: It'll keep running for a long time.
Scott: Hey, you can't stop the US government with any amount of violence.
Scott: I'm gonna tell all the generals and all to everybody because the sheer momentum of bureaucracy at all levels Just be new elections, and they'll just appoint new representatives, and they'll elect a new president, and there's a big chain.
Scott: We know who the next president's gonna be.
Scott: it's gonna be the dogcatcher from you know some Kentucky or something you know.
Scott: no It's gonna be someone.
Scott: you.
Scott: there's nothing you can do Right, but meanwhile if you're in a tiny country right or some unstable country.
Scott: That's not a democracy layer.
Scott: Somalia That's perfect.
Rym: Yeah, all right can actually lead to Evolution.
Scott: if you're in Somalia, and you fucking kill all the warlords guess what you're in charge.
Scott: well It works.
Rym: I think it.
Rym: more fundamentally this can be defined is just the idea that The civil order of America is too strong to be overthrown and also violence.
Scott: We are it could be overthrown in other ways.
Rym: as a society We are very intolerant of breakdowns of civil order.
Rym: basically the moment you riot the entire country is against you.
Rym: yep No, and if something were big enough to where you write everyone's with you.
Rym: that means civil order collapse.
Scott: yep You know I mean like look you they had written.
Scott: like you know we do have riots here.
Scott: They're mostly out in like the West a bit There's like you know Rodney King riots.
Scott: right that was a long time ago was a long time ago But you know and they kind of work every now and then.
Rym: but what worked?
Rym: in what sense?
Scott: yeah?
Scott: I mean the LA police are still Racially profiling everybody, and it's still police brutality everywhere.
Rym: Yep, but just people have no patience for anyone who violently disrupt civil order on a wide scale.
Rym: I mean whenever a riot happens pretty much everyone just wants the riot to stop.
Scott: yep except for people writing.
Rym: Yeah, but even then I get the impression that most of the people riding don't care about the cause of originally sparking them.
Scott: No, I think that most of the people at least in the u.s.
Scott: Who riot are people who just kind of want to do rioting activities like looting and vandalizing and smashing and you know hurting and whatever.
Scott: And the riot is just an excuse.
Scott: It's like they're sitting there, and they really want to hurt people and break things But they don't right because no one else is doing it.
Scott: But if everyone starts doing it all right I can do it is that everyone's doing it whoo and they let loose which what they wanted to do anyway and No one else really wants to do that.
Scott: so then you basically all these people reveal their true selves.
Scott: you catch them And then the riot stuff.
Rym: so you know look at the anti-war protests back in the 60s.
Rym: those were much more like real Protests.
Rym: I mean Kent State.
Rym: they got shot.
Scott: Yeah, well they got shot, but what did you know?
Scott: They didn't.
Scott: what did they do to start it?
Scott: They've like pushed the police a little bit.
Scott: You know they weren't.
Scott: they were basically standing around yelling Just you know more angrily yeah, but nowadays people just kind of stand there.
Rym: They're boring.
Rym: But remember RIT.
Scott: we had a riot that wasn't much of a riot.
Scott: well riot police came that's true, but no one was rioting.
Scott: basically There was a party.
Scott: it was a very large party and then you know they call it was an organized flash mob party.
Rym: We're basically out of nowhere.
Rym: You know we lived in colony which was like this apartment complex Like on like right next to campus kind of isolated like by itself like connected but like across the street and away and suddenly all over campus these flyers appeared saying colony Palooza on x-date
Scott: yep
Rym: and Everyone threw a party.
Rym: it was the biggest fucking party RIT had ever seen and basically somebody called the police on this party.
Scott: So I remember it's like why did you just let the party go?
Scott: Why did you have to say you know if you didn't try to stop it?
Scott: It wouldn't have been an issue, but they wanted to stop it.
Scott: the party was actually going fine People standing out there party.
Rym: it was just a big frat.
Rym: So they call the campus safety.
Scott: and then it you know because campus safety tried to break it up.
Scott: Then a conflict began.
Scott: It's like if you just not done anything that wouldn't have been a conflict.
Rym: It was kind of hilarious, but went down.
Rym: apparently
Scott: I mean there were some people throwing like glass bottles at campus safety and or the police I
Rym: don't know what specifically happened was one we're hanging out And we're watching the party because we lived in in the middle of this and in fact the main body of the party was Directly outside of our first floor window.
Scott: Yeah, so we just watched the whole party.
Rym: We're watching the party kind of enjoying it and whatever and hanging out We're playing like D&D and whatever and then our friends leave and they call us, and they're like Yeah, every cop in the world is on their way to Colony.
Rym: so we're expecting fun.
Rym: What happened was campus safety showed up and they were you know telling the party to quiet down and someone in the crowd threw a Beer bottle and it hit a campus safety guy in the head.
Rym: So he retreated and riot police showed up and formed a battle line.
Scott: They just formed a big line.
Scott: They all had shields and armor and whatever and basically the party people kept partying and left a gap between them and the police and Didn't do anything which was fine.
Rym: the riot police didn't actually give an ultimatum yet They just stood there.
Rym: yeah And eventually the riot police like yell at the party to disperse and the party is like fuck you guys But no violence happens.
Rym: I'm just kind of standing there, and I decided to go out and see the party at this point.
Rym: You know watch the riot police see what's going on.
Rym: I walk around a little bit and as we're walking out Everyone starts screaming and running because the riot police Moved in after the crowd started chanting you can't arrest us all you can't arrest us all.
Rym: That's when the paintballs and the dogs came out.
Scott: It was mostly.
Scott: I didn't see any dog action.
Rym: I'm what are you talking about?
Rym: We have a show.
Rym: we did a long time ago where you talked about the dog Right outside our window.
Rym: we're sitting there right.
Rym: we're watching the riot police move in and this guy Directly in front of her window reaches down.
Rym: He's drunk picks up a bottle raises it to throw it at the riot police and the riot guide looks at him Signals the dog runs up takes him down by the neck and then they pepper balled him in the face.
Scott: Yeah, it's mostly paint balls full of pepper mace which by the way came into our windows.
Rym: that sucked ass.
Scott: I didn't really yeah, and it really sucked.
Scott: And you know what.
Scott: I think that that's actually become one of the most popular police weapons these days.
Rym: Oh, there's this great video in college humor of this crazy homeless guy.
Scott: I thought they used them on him.
Scott: I saw that.
Rym: yeah, it didn't slow him down.
Scott: No, but it's like tasers.
Scott: It's like tasers have a stigma, but like these pepper balls, it's like please love those fucking things.
Scott: Yeah, and why not?
Scott: It's like you can just shoot him at anyone and if you actually get hit with those Oh, man, you're like, oh you're out and it's like you can mace someone from really far away.
Rym: However, I was not pleased with the fact that the police provided covering fire at all the balconies while they moved in Filling our apartment with pepper.
Scott: Yeah, it was not cool.
Rym: Ah Anyway, that right the thing is there was such like faux outrage on campus the next day.
Rym: Everyone's like, oh my god There was a riot and the riot police came in.
Rym: fuck RIT blah blah blah blah blah.
Rym: And then everyone forgot.
Rym: no one on campus probably even remembers that.
Rym: yeah I don't know if anyone campus remembers it but at least people who were there and people, you know We remember it but there were people who remembered it with this like outrage and anger and I remember it as this dumb funny thing That happened on campus.
Rym: It didn't accomplish anything.
Scott: It wasn't a riot for anything No, but I think what it shows though is that you know a lot of protests and riots that have conflict like that.
Scott: It's really only because somebody went and opposed it.
Scott: It's like if you just if someone's protesting a riot or doing something you don't like Don't just don't go over there and pester them just let them do their thing and there won't be any fighting.
Scott: fighting only happens if Police or an opposing force appears to actually instigate.
Scott: it's like, you know, the police didn't show up.
Scott: People would have just gotten drunk until about 5 a.m And then eventually all passed out and vomited or whatever and then and then they could discard the fire department to come and hose everybody Down.
Scott: Yeah, what actually that would have been great.
Rym: The fire department should have just showed up and hosed everybody down.
Rym: That would end at the party.
Scott: Yeah, but you know, the thing is like there was no harm being done.
Scott: There was only an issue because you tried to shut it down.
Scott: if you would have just left it alone It would just gone away.
Scott: There's some crazy people protesting like the rat.
Scott: just ignore the stupid rat.
Rym: Here's the thing.
Rym: everyone ignores them.
Scott: Anyway, that's what I'm saying.
Rym: So you don't need.
Rym: that's not advice for anyone.
Scott: It's advice for the people who called the cops.
Scott: Don't don't do the head.
Scott: Just let it go.
Rym: I Mean, I don't know what else we can say.
Rym: it Protests are stupid now.
Rym: They don't do anything.
Rym: They're basically that there's.
Rym: they're like wearing a sign that says I have nothing better to do right now.
Scott: Yeah, very much.
Scott: You can translate every protest sign into I have nothing better to do.
Scott: Yeah So if you're gonna protest it is something you don't like.
Scott: it's something you want to change.
Scott: you have to.
Scott: you know Don't standing around with signs is not really gonna help right?
Scott: You need to do something.
Rym: I mean unless you're going you have to do something that cannot be ignored.
Scott: Yeah, I mean for example, right there is sometimes where you can help in some ways For example, when the anonymous you will protest Scientology, right?
Scott: They're not really gonna stop Scientology in any way with that But Sarah with science, but they might be able to inform people who don't know.
Rym: that's what I'm saying.
Rym: they were at least raising awareness about a thing that people do care about because I even know a lot of smart people who don't Actually realize the Scientology is a crazy batshit cult made up by a sci-fi author.
Rym: That's incredibly dangerous and takes all your money Yeah, but there are people who don't know that yeah, and anonymous does a good job of getting that word out.
Scott: But I mean spreading awareness isn't really protesting right?
Scott: I mean it might look like Yeah, cuz they might stand outside the Scientology place with signs.
Rym: they were there the other day.
Scott: So it looks like a protest but it's you know, it's not really a protest cuz they're not really.
Scott: you know.
Scott: Do this?
Scott: do this cuz?
Scott: I said so all they're saying is hey people who you know This thing is that you're looking at here.
Scott: Isn't what it appears to be.
Scott: It's it's more like, you know standing on a soapbox and Preaching than protesting.
Rym: Well, that's it.
Rym: It's something that can't be ignored because it gathers more media attention than Scientology can direct away from it.
Scott: Yep, you know and the thing also they have alternate utility.
Scott: they do it for the laws, of course And you know while there are many, you know, you could say well look, you know We stood out there and we protested for the White House for three days with our signs and we were getting awareness, right?
Rym: So, you know our protests, but if awareness doesn't lead to action, it's useless.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: But at the same time I think a lot of people protest things that they're not increasing any awareness Whatsoever.
Scott: like if you go protest in front of like an abortion clinic as many people do who have nothing better to do.
Scott: No, they're not increasing any awareness.
Scott: people people fucking know what abortion is.
Scott: You're not making anyone aware who is not aware.
Rym: I mean if I go stay even if well, we could try to resume it.
Rym: What if we go outside of you know, chiropractor offices and just hand out brochures pointing out his bullshit But what it signs and we could do that we could do that.
Rym: Maybe we should do that.
Scott: problem is you know We know why I don't do that because people are stupid.
Scott: I got something better to do.
Scott: Yeah Good types of protests, right?
Scott: Boycotting, you know.
Scott: actually, you know If like there's a Walmart and you want to protest it if that store is empty for a whole day They will be fucking.
Rym: but it only works if it can't be ignored.
Rym: if I boycott Walmart and no one else does no effect No Have to do something that has an ultimatum and a goal and cannot be ignored by the people who have the power to take action.
Scott: yep, or You know me, you know book burning doesn't really help right because it's just like whatever dude.
Scott: But you know if you were to don't you don't got a Quran.
Rym: now, you've got no Quran.
Rym: I love that guy.
Scott: if you made a meme right and thus we're able to You know get the the book.
Scott: so, you know They got you know a machine of death to the top of Amazon.
Scott: if you're able to get something to the bottom of Amazon Which I don't think I think it's kind of hard to do that because if you draw attention to it You're only gonna increase sales whether it's positive or negative attention.
Rym: cuz you are you know At least one crazy pedophile, but maybe news.
Rym: and they were like, oh there's a guy.
Scott: but maybe if you spam the Amazon Reviews to get it all the way down to zero stars Maybe that would you know, keep it away from getting high in the search results and would crush its sales.
Rym: Maybe we should get an organized movement of anti Pseudoscience bullshit people to just put bad reviews on Amazon for all the pseudoscience bullshit.
Scott: Maybe we could do that.
Scott: Yeah, but you know you had to actually do something that has some effect on some Saying the same thing over and over again.
Rym: I think we're done.
Rym: We're done.
Scott: I'm hungry.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.