Scott: It's Thursday October 14th.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Scott: I'm Rym.
Scott: And this is GeekNights.
Scott: Tonight, burgle, burgle.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: So, uh, how's that headache going?
Rym: Headache's gone.
Rym: I'm actually feeling pretty good now.
Rym: In fact, I feel fantastic.
Rym: Are you gonna, um... I actually feel fantastic.
Rym: I'm at the 96 hour mark.
Scott: Are you going to, uh, return or are you gonna, you know, stick with it?
Rym: Well, I'm going to continue to consume caffeine on a regular basis.
Rym: Don't get me wrong.
Rym: I very much enjoy caffeine and coffee and tea and everything.
Scott: I just drink the decaffeinated varieties.
Scott: It can't taste any different.
Rym: It tastes way different.
Scott: How does it taste different?
Rym: Because of the processes they use to make it.
Scott: Well, I mean, is the caffeine naturally in the cocoa beans?
Scott: Yes.
Scott: The ultra-rare cocoa beans.
Scott: Okay, so it's not, so they do have to do something to get it out of there.
Rym: Yes, they have to chemically remove it.
Scott: Is there, you know what we could invent?
Scott: We should invent a chemical that like bonds to caffeine and turns into something else so that you can like take a pill then drink coffee and it tastes like non-decaffeinated coffee, but it doesn't actually happen.
Rym: If I sell you this Hale and Hardy bean counter carb, you can get 10 ultra-rare cocoa beans.
Scott: Are you serious?
Scott: Buy 10 soups and get a free soup.
Scott: Yeah, I've got a. buy 10 burgers, get a free burger from the burger truck.
Scott: So far I've got two.
Rym: Oh man, I wish Good Burger had something like that.
Rym: I'd get a burger like every two weeks.
Scott: The thing is the truck only comes around like once a week, which is probably good.
Scott: Otherwise I'd have a burger every day and be fat.
Rym: But a lot of people, I posted in the forum.
Scott: They got this potato onion rolls.
Rym: Have an email in me and posting in the forum ever since I said I'm temporarily giving up caffeine.
Scott: I guess that's, it must be a hot item.
Scott: That's why we're talking about it again.
Rym: I got a lot of Twitter responses and everything.
Rym: And the biggest question was, Whoa, you actually did research.
Rym: Is caffeine hurting me?
Scott: Probably.
Scott: Yeah, actually now everything hurts you.
Scott: Water is hurting you in every way.
Scott: The air oxygen hurts you.
Scott: However, once you start consuming more than 300 milligrams of caffeine a day for an average body, you know, that's like 2000 calorie diet.
Rym: I mean, if you're a six year old girl, you probably shouldn't be having 300 milligrams of caffeine a day.
Rym: Chocolate bars probably too much, but teaspoon full of sugars and trouble.
Rym: But if you consume that much, you know, more than way too much regularly within about two weeks to develop physical dependence, 48 hours after you stop crippling headache.
Scott: So, I mean, physical dependence just means that your body will hurt you if you stop.
Rym: So it means that your body has increased the amount of adenosine receptors, which will slow you the fuck down because it makes adenosine more effective on you.
Rym: It slows you the fuck down.
Rym: So when you stop taking caffeine, now you've got, you know, everything else is low again and any little amount of adenosine, which normally would just make you a normal amount of tired, just knocks you out.
Rym: You're just done.
Rym: You can't even think straight.
Rym: Of course, you can cure that by drinking more caffeine.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, let us cure this caffeine like bonds of the adenosine receptors and prevent adenosine from doing its magic.
Rym: It's an adenosine antagonist, as far as I can tell, which as a result causes the body to upregulate and make more adenosine receptors to counteract the effects.
Scott: I thought you said it.
Rym: There is a mystery.
Rym: Well, this is why you can build up tolerance.
Rym: If you keep using caffeine too much regularly, then you build up this tolerance.
Rym: But there's something called the wall.
Rym: Once you get to a certain level of tiredness and you have already developed full caffeine tolerance, no amount of increased dosage will have any effect because there's no adenosine left.
Rym: No, they don't know why, because if it were just the adenosine receptors alone, then increasing the dosage of caffeine should cause the effects to resume.
Scott: It's like you only have a certain number of them total, right?
Rym: No, you get more of them.
Scott: You can have infinity of them?
Rym: Well, I guess you can have, I don't know, one per neuron or receptor.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: I'm not a biologist.
Rym: You've already extended all of my biology knowledge out of me.
Rym: I don't know anymore.
Rym: But suffice it to say, I'm glad that I'm past the 48 hour mark and I'm feeling good.
Rym: My goal was to get until the end of the day, Friday, and then it's Red Bull time.
Rym: Because one thing I haven't experienced in many months is the effects of caffeine on a non tolerance, built up body, which as I recall, is awesome.
Scott: Alrighty, so you know how we used to, you know, we know you, you and I know that the Sudafedrine is like the only medicine that will actually help you if you have a congestive cold nasal something something as a connoisseur of nasal problems.
Scott: I mean, like fucking regular old cough syrup just doesn't do shit.
Scott: In fact, scientifically, it really it doesn't do shit except make your throat feel good.
Rym: Scott can vouch for the fact that I have quite a bit of experience with nasal problems, blockages, mucus.
Scott: I don't know why you just don't like drill a hole in your nose.
Scott: That'll open it right up.
Rym: I got a hole.
Rym: I got two holes.
Scott: Yeah, but they could use a drill to make them bigger and then you would be all foot.
Scott: Everything would flow freely.
Rym: Regardless, Sudafedrine is one of the most effective decongestants in the world, and it has very few side effects.
Scott: It is.
Scott: It makes you a little tired.
Rym: It's the may or it makes you pumped up.
Rym: Yeah, depends on the person.
Rym: But regardless, it's an awesome drug.
Rym: It's like aspirin.
Rym: It's one of those bad ass.
Rym: Let's go.
Rym: Let's cure everything drugs.
Scott: It just so happens, though, that by a very dangerous chemical process, it is possible to use Sudafedrine as a key ingredient in the manufacture of crystal meth.
Rym: It's actually not that dangerous.
Rym: It's only dangerous, but if they don't know how to.
Scott: I mean, it's more dangerous than distilling like Vodac.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Which could explode.
Scott: You know, this is more.
Scott: this is more dangerous than that.
Scott: So true.
Scott: It's not as dangerous as, say, cesium and water.
Rym: I would argue that they're actually similarly dangerous if you know what you're doing.
Rym: But the thing is, point the first, you know what you're doing.
Rym: People who do meth moves not the smartest point.
Rym: The second, if you're smart enough to know good lab practices, you probably don't need to make math.
Scott: I know.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But anyway, so the thing is in the
Scott: U.S.,
Scott: they passed a law some years ago where if you want to get any drug that actually has the Sudafedrine in it, you have to get it over.
Scott: You have to, you know, sign a paper at the drugstore and write your name down and all this.
Rym: And at least in New York, I have to present my I.D.
Rym: and they scan it and they consult with the computer to see how much Sudafedrine I have bought in the last month and the last year.
Scott: And in fact, what ends up happening is bought too much.
Rym: I legally cannot buy more Sudafedrine.
Rym: And in fact, if Scott, if you bought some for me, that is a federal crime.
Scott: Oh, shit.
Scott: Oh, well.
Scott: But anyway, the the thing is, is that most people don't even realize this.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Because they just see, oh, it's Mucinex.
Scott: Oh, it's Sudafed.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And they have different letters like Mucinex D, Mucinex E.
Rym: Even worse, the people who buy Sudafed brand Sudafed, which doesn't even have Sudafedrine in it anymore.
Rym: At least the stuff on the counter.
Rym: It's fake.
Scott: In fact, the stuff on the shelf, the stuff behind the counter, behind the glass case is the good stuff.
Rym: I read many articles.
Rym: I don't want to try to find them again, basically pointing out that the drug they found to replace Sudafedrine, that is legal and not regulated because you can't make meth out of it, doesn't work any better than a placebo.
Rym: It's bullshit.
Rym: And also, apparently, the company that made that drug was a huge lobbyist for anti-meth legislation.
Scott: So there we go.
Scott: There you go.
Scott: But anyway, so CVS, right, one of the biggest chain drugstores in the United States, perhaps the biggest.
Rym: And I used to go to Perry drugs when I was a kid.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Apparently they didn't.
Scott: they didn't properly apply this law in the years of 2007 and 2008, as well as the other drugstores did so.
Scott: And they lost a case in court and they now have to pay seventy eight close to seventy eight million dollars to the government for failing to, you know, properly not sell people Sudafed.
Scott: And apparently they're responsible.
Scott: They're being held responsible for the spread of crystal meth in California and somewhere else.
Rym: Are you fucking kidding me?
Scott: The attorney, U.S.
Scott: attorney in L.A.
Scott: is basically like, hey, crystal meth spread all over Vegas and Southern California because they didn't follow the law properly.
Scott: Huh?
Rym: Yeah, it doesn't quite add up more like I can't I'm.
Scott: I'm like, you know, our police aren't doing a very good job of stopping the crystal meth.
Scott: Let's blame it on the drugstore and get a bunch of money.
Scott: Wow.
Scott: That's more money than like all the parking tickets we've got all year.
Rym: I'll tell you what would stop crystal meth right quick.
Rym: Legalize weed.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: It would maybe, but maybe not.
Rym: Not that many people are doing meth because they want to do meth.
Rym: They're doing meth because that's what they can get.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But I mean, do you think some of those people are doing meth because, you know, but the now they're both illegal.
Rym: You would be surprised outside of cities and areas where there's a bunch of hippies or nerds living or like college kids.
Rym: It's actually really hard to get weed and really easy.
Scott: But they're talking about Southern California and Las Vegas.
Scott: Those are easy places to get weed.
Scott: Depends on among the easiest.
Scott: If you don't, California is the number one easiest.
Rym: If you're not on the end and Vegas has fucking everything, you don't have a dealer.
Rym: It's not that easy.
Scott: OK, anyway, but you can.
Scott: but you're going to manufacture meth, but you're not going to grow weed plant in the very least.
Rym: I think teenagers who are doing meth would probably have moved to weed instead if we were legal and meth were still illegal.
Scott: They probably never would have started the meth in the first place.
Scott: The thing is, if you're already on the meth, you're already on.
Rym: You're already fucked.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's you're not going to switch.
Scott: It's just now.
Rym: I thought you were going to bring up a much scarier story.
Rym: I forget what state this was in, but a woman bought a bunch of Sudafedrin in like February because her husband was sick.
Rym: And then like way later in the year, she was at some other drugstore and she bought some more Sudafed unrelatedly for some other illness that someone had.
Rym: And she technically went over the limit, but the store didn't notice.
Rym: She got arrested.
Scott: Wow.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: She didn't realize it.
Rym: She didn't even know it was a law.
Rym: The store didn't realize it.
Rym: They sold it to her.
Rym: They're not in trouble.
Rym: She's in trouble.
Rym: And in fact, the law says it's the duty of the people buying it to make sure they don't break the law.
Scott: Wow.
Scott: It's just bullshit.
Scott: I just, we need to start some underground Sudafedrin.
Rym: See, we always talk about how the war on drugs is so mismanaged.
Scott: We'll end up in federal prison and we're not even doing crystal meth.
Scott: What do you think the judge would say if it was shown in court?
Scott: Yes, we had nothing, we don't care about crystal meth.
Scott: We were literally just trying to get cold medicine that actually works.
Rym: That's basically what the woman who was arrested did.
Rym: And that defense didn't fly.
Rym: Really?
Rym: Because the law's the law.
Scott: God damn.
Scott: This is why we, you know, at least in Britain, I mean, it's good.
Scott: It's a double edged sword of letting the judges use common sense, right?
Rym: I think there's a way around that.
Scott: because you got a common sense judge.
Scott: You'd be like, well, the law says this, but you know what?
Scott: I don't agree with that.
Rym: So I think a better way.
Rym: What if every law had to have a short, like you had a limit, you already, you said this before a thousand times, limit X word statement of intent.
Rym: And it's pretty much a viable defense to say, yeah, I broke the law, but the intent does not cover what I did.
Rym: And then the judge would have to sort that out.
Rym: Yeah, I think it's a good idea.
Scott: This intent of this law is to stop this flow of crystal meth.
Scott: Well, I had nothing to do with crystal meth.
Scott: So even though I broke that law, that doesn't apply to me.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Anyway, however, all that aside, we always talk about how the drug war is so mismanaged in such a disaster in America.
Scott: And yet Mo, usually when we say that people think maybe that's the dagger nature we need is the drug war.
Rym: I think that is one of the dagger nations we need.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But people think, oh yeah, because we lock up all these nonviolent offenders and you know, that whole side of it, but there's this whole other side of it of not only denying a perfectly usable drug, like pseudo federal and the people who really need it like me, but just the whole mismanagement of the situation regarding people on meth.
Rym: I mean, none of the policies seem to actually prevent the spread of meth.
Scott: I know Japan is even more strict, right, than the US, but even like allergy medicines, it's hard to get.
Rym: Japan has a weird bug up their butt about any sort of stimulant, unless it's tobacco or caffeine.
Scott: Yeah, they love those.
Scott: You can do them anywhere in the store, in the restaurant, you know, whatever.
Scott: But I wonder if, you know, there's all similar pseudo-veteran regulations in other countries, you know, like, can I go to France and just get pseudo fed?
Scott: That's for real.
Scott: No problem.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: I hope so.
Rym: I really don't.
Scott: Probably.
Rym: I would guess you could, but on a completely unrelated topic, this is something that came up when I was a kid.
Rym: You know, I was in middle school and the local mall was like, we're banning anyone under 18 on the weekends, unless they're with their parents.
Scott: That never happened to me, the mall near my house, but maybe it is now.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Well, it happened near me when I was a kid.
Scott: It's not a new trend, but in the last few years, I remember the mall in Poughkeepsie was like that.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Now even the, that big mall in Brooklyn is like that, but there, that mall is crazy.
Rym: You gotta be 21.
Scott: What?
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Whoa.
Scott: That can't be, how was that legal?
Rym: It's perfectly legal.
Scott: I mean, if you're 18, you're an adult.
Scott: So if you, if you're, if that was age discrimination, you could file a lawsuit.
Rym: They totally get away with it.
Rym: It's been that way for a while, but they're basically in the last few years, malls across the country.
Rym: I just have one article about it, have been jumping over themselves to ban teenagers from the mall.
Rym: If they can all the time or in the very least at night and on a weekends or when they're unaccompanied, this is only unaccompanied teenagers, right?
Scott: If I go with my mom, it's okay.
Rym: Well, every mall is different.
Rym: I don't know of any malls that just banned teenagers outright, but that one in Brooklyn bends, any group of more than X people, it's a small number that are under 21.
Rym: If anyone in the party is under 21, unless their parents are with them.
Scott: Well, what if there is like one person like me, I could just, can I walk in with all the kids?
Rym: No, cause you're not their parent.
Scott: I have to be the parent.
Rym: That's how a lot of movie theaters will say like, Oh yeah, you're the cool 18 year old kid.
Scott: What if they don't have any parents?
Scott: They have foster parents.
Rym: Well, they're fucked because this is a really sad situation.
Rym: It's the Atlantic terminal mall in Brooklyn.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Groups of five or more shoppers who are under 21 are forced to disperse and or leave.
Rym: Alrighty.
Rym: But what amazes me is that all the malls and all the anecdotal evidence, all the quotes are talking about how I'll summarize old people are afraid of the kids.
Scott: and because the kids are, did they ask any kids about this?
Scott: Oh yeah.
Rym: And the kids are like, this is stupid.
Rym: What the fuck?
Rym: But some of the other kids are like, I buy everything on Amazon.
Rym: I just go to the mall to hang out and they're right.
Rym: It's interesting how right and simultaneously how wrong the mall owners are because the mall owners argument is that old people feel threatened by youth.
Rym: True.
Rym: And they feel threatened and afraid because these kids are.
Scott: the guy who owns the mall actually said that.
Rym: Uh, yeah.
Scott: He knows, he knows what's up now.
Rym: They know what's up to a degree, but I think they're making a big mistake here.
Rym: So they also point out that, yeah, most of the stores in the mall are aimed at a teenage audience, but at the same time, the mall makes all of its real money from the department stores.
Scott: That's correct.
Rym: And all of the old people go to the department stores.
Rym: They're the anchor.
Rym: So keeping the old people around and getting away rid of the kids will increase sales.
Rym: And in fact it did.
Rym: And all these examples, sales went way up because the old people started coming to the mall again.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Now this is why I'm so convinced that they only understand half the story.
Rym: So they think punk kids come and hang out at my mall and don't spend a lot of money.
Rym: Old people come and spend all their money because this is where they buy all their shit.
Rym: Therefore, by kicking out the kids, the old people who are afraid of the kids will spend more money in my mall until the old people die.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: And I think when the old man will die, it's a great short term strategy, right?
Scott: You have all these people will spend more money in your malls and all the little tiny stores might go out of business in the midterm and the department stores will make more money in the midterm.
Scott: But in the long term, the old people will die and then your mall will be empty and your whole place will shut down.
Scott: That'll be it.
Scott: And then it'll be a dawn of the dead situation.
Scott: All the malls will be cool, empty places for us to play paintball.
Rym: I don't know if they realize it, but seriously, here's one mall after a month of banning kids.
Scott: The thing is they might have a chance though, after the old people die, they could be like young kids can come to the mall again and then the mall will be like a party town.
Scott: They'll re they'll rework the whole mall and we could turn malls into like, imagine after the old people die, we can rework the malls in the party towns.
Rym: No, it's, it's almost a situation.
Rym: You've got a mall, right?
Scott: We can turn them into convention centers.
Rym: Imagine if every storefront in the mall was like that Greek society center, but it was for a different culture.
Rym: Like here's the Jersey shore room.
Rym: Here's the star galactic.
Rym: We could buy an old the board games.
Scott: We could buy a hippie mall and do it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It has just been a really nerdy place.
Scott: It'd be an convention in a mall, right?
Scott: Each department store.
Scott: One department store is the dealer's expo hall and the other one is like the artist's alley and the other one is like a dance party.
Scott: And then the other one is like a concert hall.
Scott: And then every store is like a different awesome thing at the convention.
Rym: But like sales were up 10% and like people coming to the mall was up 5% after like a month at one of these malls because the quote generally unruly horseplay heavy crowds of children concentrated in the food court and movie theater entrances.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, I mean what they should do though is like a lot of malls at.
Scott: the movie theater has a door directly to the outside and they can basically just say, look, kids come in the movie theater through the outside door.
Scott: Don't go in the mall.
Rym: Every movie worth seeing just about as rated R and the movie theaters won't let them in anyway, which as another aside aside kids, so you know, there is no law saying a movie theater can't sell you a ticket if you're under 18.
Scott: No, but it is the movie theater just decides and they're perfectly, they're allowed to just decide not to sell you at the same time.
Rym: One, you should raise a stink.
Rym: And two, there are movie theaters.
Rym: I don't know if there still are, but there were when I was a kid.
Rym: that totally just would sell anyone to take it to anything.
Rym: I saw a lot of R rated movies when I was like 14.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, I have my parents just buy tickets to the R rated movie and give them to us and then we'd walk in and they wouldn't question it.
Rym: But here's a, here's a direct quote from the director of one of these malls.
Rym: The problem a developer has is if it becomes a hangout for kids, it becomes scary for old customers.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Like literally they're like old people are afraid of these children.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I think malls are going to go away because I, I don't, I realized the last time I went to a mall, there is nothing, absolutely nothing I would ever need from a mall again for the rest of my life.
Scott: I'm in New York city.
Scott: I can go to a store that's just on the street.
Rym: Even in Poughkeepsie when we lived upstate, when we went to the mall for no reason.
Scott: Once we realized we went to the mall a whole bunch and then we didn't go to the mall at all.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But remember we went to the mall and we'd like played DDR and then I realized we never really bought anything.
Scott: I got a haircut a few times.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But I bought a few things.
Scott: And
Rym: there's this whole funny bit about the end where they're like, part of the reason teams are not able to converge in mass at the mall instead of simply running into a friend or two there is because they have never seen technology like their cell phones and social media like Facebook and Twitter and four square.
Rym: Like, yeah, really?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: You need a whole paragraph about this.
Scott: Anyway, the thing is, right, is it's weird?
Scott: is that we have these societal problems because each group that's causing the problem looks out for themselves.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So the mall is looking out for money, at least short term money.
Scott: The old people looking out not to be scared.
Scott: The young kids have no power.
Scott: So it doesn't matter what they're looking out for.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But the young kids don't care.
Rym: They'll just go do crystal meth because they can't hang out.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: The mall is part of this problem of kids have nothing to do.
Scott: Right.
Scott: We kids we always say kids don't do drugs.
Scott: Kids don't do bad things.
Scott: Kids don't join.
Scott: Wait, wait, wait, wait.
Rym: To be fair, because we got to qualify that people will argue against you otherwise.
Rym: It's not.
Rym: the kids don't have anything to do because as a kid, like in New York City, they have something to do.
Rym: Even in the in Bumfuck, kids have plenty to do because I got video games.
Scott: I had all this.
Scott: But that's all they have to do.
Scott: So hear me out.
Rym: I have infinite entertainment media at my hands, even if I'm like a punk kid in the middle of nowhere.
Rym: What I don't have is a place to hang out with my friends where my parents are not there.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: I mean, they have like teen community centers, but those are all policed by churchy people and shit like, you know, townie people or whatever.
Rym: And half those places, like Rochester.
Scott: Only dorks go there.
Rym: Remember at RIT, there's that big community center with the Pump It Up machine?
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And that place got shut down because there were like riots inside of it.
Scott: Well, that was because they had a dance party there one night.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And there was a. there was like a riot or something.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But yeah, it's they take away all the places for kids to go because each individual place is better off getting rid of the kids or shutting down.
Rym: I mean, even in my hometown as a kid.
Rym: Right.
Scott: It was.
Scott: So what do kids do?
Scott: They stay home.
Scott: They get drunk.
Scott: They throw drunken parties in their back.
Rym: It was against the law to be outside at night.
Scott: If you were under 18, where I grew up, you know, if you would just let the kids make trouble.
Scott: That was Dennis the Menace trouble.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Which is easy to shut down, which is why they shut it down.
Scott: Then they wouldn't make trouble, which is fucking Al Capone trouble.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So instead, you shut down the Dennis the Menace trouble because you can.
Rym: And while we have a kids doing drugs, I think there's also a secondary point that people don't seem to realize that a lot of the institutions of our society are not in any way valuable to at least the techno Roddy, like modern generation of people like us.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, a ball to anyone who's even remotely like me, culturally, there is fuck all reason to go to a mall unless you're going to the movie theater attached to them all, because that's where the fucking movie theater is.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It just happens to be there.
Rym: And maybe you'll go to the GameStop, but you know what?
Rym: GameStops are going to go away because they're just pawn shops and our first sale rights are going away.
Rym: So you can see what's happening here.
Rym: I think within 10 years, more than half the malls in America are going to shut down.
Scott: I mean, scary thing is some places have like newer malls.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So this video was on CollegeHumor a little while ago.
Rym: And while it's crazy awesome, the video alone wasn't worth being a thing of the day because there's no context.
Rym: It's just kind of intense, sort of scary music as a dude is set on fire and literally jumps out through the window of a skyscraper and lands on a mat with no parachute.
Scott: and a parachute wouldn't help because he was on fire.
Scott: So the parachute would have also been on fire.
Rym: I mean, I watched the video.
Rym: I'm like, all right, what's this guy going to do?
Rym: All right.
Rym: Some sort of stunt.
Scott: So holy shit, actually jumped out of skyscraper window on fire, on fire.
Scott: It wasn't like tricks or cameras or anything.
Scott: He actually was on fire, actually jumped out the window, actually had no parachute.
Scott: Parachute actually would not have helped because he was on fire.
Rym: So I dug around and I figured out what the deal was for a movie.
Rym: No, it wasn't for a movie.
Rym: It was a stuntman, Bob Brown.
Scott: Was he promoting himself to get more jobs?
Rym: I believe.
Rym: I'm not sure.
Rym: I believe he's promoting brand X, a kind of airbag that you can land on like what he landed.
Scott: Oh, so he's trying to sell stuntman equipment to other movies or something like that so they can do crazier stunts.
Rym: Mostly this article talks about how they did the stunt, who the guy was.
Rym: He's like forty three to so badass dude.
Scott: They set him on fire in the usual movie way.
Scott: It was a fake window that he broke through so he wouldn't cut himself up with shards of glass.
Scott: They had an incredibly big mattress at the bottom with fire extinguishers, you know.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: It's just.
Rym: it's quite a thing to see.
Scott: So there you have it.
Scott: My thing of the day.
Scott: So, you know, we mentioned Dagen H, at least we referred to it earlier in the show, but we've talked about that before.
Scott: It was the thing of the day.
Rym: We should probably explain briefly again what it is.
Scott: Dagen H was the day.
Scott: What country was it?
Scott: Norway, maybe?
Rym: I don't remember.
Rym: I think it was Denmark.
Scott: It was one of those northern European countries.
Scott: And what they did is they had the roads.
Scott: Sweden!
Rym: I'm sorry, every listener from Scandinavia.
Scott: So they had the roads on the left and they switched them to be on the right.
Rym: You know what the H stands for?
Scott: It's because they... Hogertraffic.
Scott: Oh, I thought it was because, you know, if you think of a road and you think of an H and it's like, aha, we're switching the roads.
Scott: The shape of an H really makes it seem like a road switching.
Rym: I can see how you would get that from the picture of the reminder, you know, the logo for Dagen H. But Wikipedia right away, the H stands for Hogertraffic, the Swedish word for right-handed traffic.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So basically they had the cars drove on the left like England and now they drive in the right like the US.
Rym: Like the civilized world.
Scott: And they had a day that was Dagen H, which is a day they switched it.
Scott: And now what I say is when I say something is a Dagen H, like because I referred to a Dagen H for the drug war, is basically in the US.
Scott: they really, really, really don't like sweeping and rapid change.
Scott: Everything we have to do gradually, right?
Scott: If we're going to change some rate, we have to change the rate a little bit each day.
Scott: We can't just make change the rate a whole bunch in one day.
Scott: They got to do everything slowly, right?
Scott: If we're going to increase something, we got to increase it slowly.
Scott: So there isn't this rapid, you know, and drastic sweeping change.
Scott: that is, you know, instant.
Scott: So when I said we should have a Dagen H for the drug war, I said I was meaning we should just turn it off one, you know, immediately.
Scott: And instead of being like, OK, well, this year it'll be OK to do pot like this and next year we'll allow a little more pot.
Scott: Fuck that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So I'm trying to find examples of Dagen Hs from around the world.
Scott: Drug war.
Scott: To show Dagen Hs that actually happened already.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You could almost argue that.
Scott: Didn't Portugal do a Dagen H for drugs?
Rym: Czechoslovakia did for Dagen Hing for driving.
Rym: OK,
Scott: yeah, but anyway, the thing is trying to find examples of Dagen Hs from around the world to show that, look, if you do it right, you can do a big change that and that succeeds for a whole country or even a bigger area all at once and do a big fix to the world quickly and effectively.
Scott: And it's not something to be afraid of.
Rym: I think there's a much more fundamental idea here that Dagen H proved that a society as a whole can agree this is worth doing.
Rym: We're all all going to pitch in.
Rym: I mean, this isn't something that a government could just say, yeah, on this day we're doing it.
Rym: It just happens.
Rym: Every single goddamn person in that country had to be ready for it, had to be prepared, had to know about it, had to be educated.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: And I mean, the U.S.
Scott: sort of did it when we cut off the TV broadcast.
Scott: That was sort of a Dagen H. Yeah, we kept delaying it, but we did.
Scott: It's done.
Rym: We Dagen H'd away alcohol and then we Dagen H'd it back.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: That was a bad Dagen H. Anyway, so I found about this this Dagen H I had not heard of before in Brazil.
Scott: that was very successful.
Scott: And basically you can read the article and listen to the NPR audio to get all the details.
Scott: But here's the story.
Scott: Brazil had crazy inflation, the kind of inflation they have in Zimbabwe, where eggs are a dollar one day and a dollar two cents the next day.
Scott: And by the end of the year, they're a thousand dollars an egg and it's out of control.
Scott: And this is like in the 90s.
Scott: So every politician who came along was said, I'm going to fix the inflation.
Scott: And they tried everything and nothing worked.
Scott: And every time they voted for someone new, they were like, OK, what are you going to do to fix the inflation?
Scott: So eventually what happened was a new president came in and he had a finance minister and the finance minister was stupid.
Scott: He wasn't completely stupid, but he knew it was one of those situations where he didn't know, but he knew he didn't know.
Scott: He knew that he did not know about economics.
Rym: That is a rare person.
Scott: How did he become a finance minister?
Scott: I don't know, but I don't do what Donnie Don't does.
Scott: He knew that he didn't know anything about economics.
Scott: So he went to to the university and he found the smart guys who were always hanging at the bar talking about how to fix inflation.
Scott: And he said, you smart economic types, fix inflation.
Scott: And they fixed inflation with a Dagen H. What they did is they said, OK, starting today, everyone's going to keep using the Crissero, the currency of Brazil, but we're going to change all the prices on all the shelves, right, to be in reales, URVs, units of real value.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So if went to the store, eggs would be one real.
Scott: Now, when you went to the checkout counter, right, the guy would have a little chart and the chart would say, yeah, today one real is 20 Crisseros.
Scott: And because of inflation, the next day one real might be 40 Crisseros.
Scott: But the price on the shelf was always one real.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So nothing really changed.
Scott: Just people's perception changed.
Scott: People began to value money.
Scott: And the problem with inflation is money loses value.
Scott: So psychologically, people are now valuing money or at least they're valuing the real.
Scott: They're not valuing the Crissero.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Because the real is stable.
Scott: It stays at one all the time.
Scott: Eggs are always one real.
Scott: Real must be real.
Scott: And then on the Dagen H, he said, all right, today we're going to take all the Crisseros and throw them in the trash and we're going to distribute reales.
Scott: And everyone went to the bank or whatever.
Scott: And, you know, during the whole period, right, they weren't using reales, but their paychecks were listed in reales.
Scott: And every everything was on paper was reales, but they physically used Crisseros and just exchange them all the time on this Dagen H. Everyone threw away the Crisseros and exchange them for reales.
Scott: And they printed up the reales and gave them out.
Scott: And ever since then, Brazil has been just kicking everybody's ass, going up and up and up.
Scott: Economy is awesome in Brazil ever since they did this.
Scott: And it's an awesome Dagen H. And I think the rest of the world needs similar Dagen H's.
Rym: I think we'll do a show on some Dagen H's in the future.
Rym: So if you know of any that we do not know of, let us know.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I want to make like a website like Dagen H's like plural and talk about all of them because they are they're awesome, especially if you find like a really old historic one.
Scott: That'd be awesome, too.
Rym: So I suppose briefly we should have the meta moment.
Scott: So the next convention we're going to is Magfest.
Scott: Magfest in January.
Rym: And then PAX East in March.
Rym: Hotels are live.
Scott: Yes, get your PAX East hotel now.
Scott: Otherwise, you're going to be in a hotel that you're going to need like a shuttle or a taxi or the take the transportation of some sort.
Rym: The fuck now I'm going to get to the convention center right now.
Rym: If you want to go to hotel is the Western Boston waterfront is connected to the convention center.
Rym: It is the closest hotel you can get.
Rym: And it's cheaper than the Renaissance.
Scott: The food might be far away, but the convention center is close.
Scott: And that's where you're going to be most of the time.
Rym: However, there there is the benefit of look at Connecticut, the situation where the food and the cheap hotel are way far away from the convention center, which is good.
Scott: But you don't really see the difference is a Connecticut.
Scott: It's OK if you get to the convention a little late.
Scott: You're not in a rush, but it packs.
Scott: You don't want to fucking miss one minute of packs.
Scott: So you want to be close.
Rym: Don't want to close my eyes.
Rym: Anyway, the book club book is World War Z by Max Brooks.
Scott: It's about zombies.
Scott: You indirectly asked for it independently.
Rym: I saw the movie or the TV trailer poster things and everything for Walking Dead, the series.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, I knew they were making it and I saw that was promotional stuff.
Scott: It's actually a good poster at the image booth at the comic.
Rym: It's like the freeway all shut down, like all the disaster and just one guy walking toward the city on the empty road on a horse.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Additional meta.
Scott: You should follow GeekNights on Twitter and it'll tell you about old episodes and also new episodes that we're treating out random episodes every day.
Scott: You should come to the forum at forum dot for a great outcome forms.
Rym: Pretty rocket.
Scott: You should also just go to front row crew dot com.
Scott: And, you know, because that's the Web site for this podcast and you should go to it instead of just looking at iTunes and never going to our Web site.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: The stuff on the Web site.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Jerks.
Scott: Not that much.
Scott: There's news there and shit, but there's going to be more there soon.
Scott: A lot.
Scott: It's coming.
Rym: OK, so, Scott, something happened not that long ago.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So a week from yesterday, so eight days ago on Wednesday.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I came home from work and it was, you know, I was planning to do with Scott's box because the box was arriving that day.
Scott: So, of course, it was after a podcast.
Scott: I was actually Scott's box the next day.
Scott: I didn't end up doing it until yesterday.
Scott: So it was delayed like a whole week.
Scott: And then the recording on Ustream totally failed.
Scott: I'm sorry.
Scott: Nothing I could do about that.
Scott: It was their fault.
Scott: And I get home and I go to my front door and on the floor is Scott's box.
Scott: I pick it up and then I look to go put my key in the door.
Scott: And I noticed that right near the handle for my door, there is significant physical damage to my door.
Scott: And I push the door without even putting the key in.
Scott: And it just opens.
Scott: And I'm like, oh, as soon as I saw the damage, I was like, all right, I got burgled.
Scott: Let's let's see what's missing.
Scott: And I opened the door and I took my TV and my Xbox and my Wii.
Scott: Those are the obvious missing things right away.
Rym: I just can't believe.
Rym: you called me and you're like, I got robbed.
Rym: I'm like, what do you mean?
Rym: he got robbed?
Scott: Apparently, I found out even more recently the guy upstairs also got robbed, but no one else.
Scott: Oh, or at least he got broken into.
Scott: He didn't.
Scott: He just wrote a note.
Scott: I didn't.
Scott: I don't know what was taken or anything.
Scott: It doesn't matter.
Rym: Maybe he robbed you.
Rym: This cover story.
Scott: No, I don't think so.
Scott: I'm pretty sure what it was.
Scott: There was this guy, you know, those guys who go on the street and they're like from Greenpeace or whatever.
Scott: This guy was from U.N.
Scott: something, something.
Scott: And they're always trying to get you to give money to some charity or something.
Scott: And they have those clipboards full of paper.
Scott: And they're really annoying and pushy.
Rym: Yeah, I like that.
Rym: I don't speak English at this point.
Rym: There was a guy.
Scott: there was a guy like that in our building walking around.
Rym: Yeah, that seems suspicious.
Scott: How did he get into the building?
Rym: I mean, your building's locked as fuck.
Rym: My building is a doorman.
Rym: You can't like people can't just walk in.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But anyway, he was in the building the previous night and I basically, you know, was like, screw you, go away.
Scott: So maybe he was like, aha, that guy's a jerk.
Scott: I won't give to the poor, flooded people in Pakistan.
Scott: It's OK to rob him.
Scott: But, you know, whatever.
Scott: See,
Rym: I think because I have it seems obvious that if I were going to rob a little apartment building like that, I would send someone in with some nice excuse who would never go back to the place to basically case it out and see whoever has the most expensive TVs, rob them
Scott: and no one else.
Scott: Yeah, probably.
Scott: The thing is, they didn't take any of my computers.
Scott: You know, they didn't take out.
Scott: There's a whole bunch of valuable things they didn't take that they could have taken.
Rym: They're probably in a hurry.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: They're in a hurry, but they took a TV.
Rym: They stole your stinky blanket.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: It's like after I, you know, when the police showed up pretty quickly and then detectives and then the evidence people showed up at two a.m.
Scott: and they didn't find anything.
Scott: But the thing was is like as time went on, I discovered more missing things.
Scott: It's like my DS and a whole thing full of games.
Scott: And actually, I was lucky that Emily took a bunch of my DS games from me.
Scott: So they didn't take as many as they would have otherwise taken at random aside.
Rym: So after you got robbed, I realized I didn't know where my DS was.
Rym: I hadn't seen it in months.
Rym: So I found it today.
Rym: It was rainy, right?
Rym: I put on my trench coat that was in the trench.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And I feel something heavy in the pocket.
Rym: I'm like, what the fuck?
Rym: And there's my DS still on on suspended.
Rym: I opened it.
Rym: There's two months.
Rym: Whoa.
Scott: Anyway, so but yeah, it's weird.
Scott: It's like they took the HDMI cables, but they didn't take the Wii cable.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then.
Scott: Like a day later, they actually started spending my Xbox money that I can't believe this.
Rym: This is one thing that bothers me.
Rym: I mean, I don't care, you know, from because you don't care if the guy gets caught or not because you got insurance.
Scott: It doesn't yet.
Scott: Whether the guy is caught makes no difference in my life whatsoever.
Scott: But I still unless he's planning a repeat.
Rym: But I want him caught for, you know, obviously social justice reasons.
Scott: Yeah, but that doesn't matter.
Scott: You know, it doesn't make a difference.
Rym: It does in the long run.
Rym: I mean, people who get away with crimes are more likely to commit more crimes.
Scott: Is that true?
Rym: Probably anyway.
Scott: But that aside, recidivism is pretty high.
Rym: The fact that he bought shit with your Xbox as an IT professional.
Rym: There is nothing between you, the police and knowing where the fuck the dude is.
Rym: But bureaucracy from Microsoft.
Scott: Yeah, like Microsoft.
Scott: You know, I told that, you know, I called the detective and I called Microsoft and Microsoft, you know, they're doing that whole thing, I guess, where they find the IP and then they peed at the ISP and, you know, I guess they're going to do that thing that you always hear about them doing.
Scott: So, yeah, whatever.
Rym: I look forward to them because the dude must not be that smart or he must have already sold the smart.
Scott: Why did he take my computers?
Scott: Why did he not take the cable?
Rym: Because your computers are weird and custom and those difficult defense.
Rym: Maybe he took.
Rym: Look, he took very generic stuff that's easy to reset.
Scott: But he didn't want to resell it all because he didn't resell the Xbox.
Scott: He used it or maybe he sold it to somebody.
Rym: Maybe he did resell it, which is fine, because you know what?
Rym: If they find the Xbox and it isn't the thief, guys still loses the Xbox.
Rym: It doesn't get any money back.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: But your antenna DVD was in the Xbox.
Rym: I know.
Rym: I want you to find the goddamn Xbox.
Scott: The thing is, you 10 is getting re-released.
Rym: So I know.
Rym: But that was the.
Rym: I bought that, you know, all 13 episodes of season one on two disks.
Rym: I bought that back when money was not something I had.
Scott: I mean, the only real major loss is like there are Pokmon that I had in Pokmon Red back in the day that I traded up and traded up and traded up were in the Pokmon Diamond.
Scott: Oh, shit.
Scott: But it's like, really?
Rym: I'm going to get upset about if Nintendo were smart and nice and had the Pokmon MMO and the Pokmon.
Scott: That wouldn't be an issue.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Pokmon Cloud, my Pokmon or my Pokmon forever.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Let's do it, Nintendo.
Scott: They're failing at all internets.
Rym: There's a reason.
Rym: we did a whole panel at PAX on why Nintendo is full of assholes.
Scott: I mean, there's not really much to say about getting burgled because it's not like it was an adventure.
Scott: I was there and fought them with or anything.
Scott: But I did think about like, what if I had to fight them?
Scott: And I realized the knife would have been a bad idea because more likely to hurt myself and also get blood everywhere.
Rym: if I actually succeed, you know, large like weird bludgeoning instruments like a steel folding chair just kind of whipped at someone will take them out enough.
Scott: But also, they obviously broke in with a crowbar so they would have had a crowbar.
Rym: Anyone who tries to wield a crowbar is not going to do that well.
Scott: You think so?
Rym: Against a baseball bat?
Scott: Oh, I don't have a baseball bat.
Rym: You don't have a baseball bat?
Scott: No, but I bought a rolling pin recently, which I bought it to.
Scott: actually, I bought it to roll, not to hit.
Scott: And I do have the honing steel that goes with the knives.
Rym: That'll hurt someone.
Scott: That's a pretty good whacking stick, right?
Rym: I would say taser, but they're illegal in New York.
Scott: Are they really?
Scott: Yeah, which sucks.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, there's, you know, pretty much here's, I'm going to get, since there's not much adventure story to tell, right?
Scott: I got robbed.
Scott: I'm buying new shit.
Scott: I have insurance.
Scott: End of story, right?
Scott: Here's my advice for what you should do pre and post getting robbed to make out.
Scott: well, right?
Scott: Number one, renter's insurance is like, usually I'm anti insurance, right?
Scott: You know, and because insurance is usually a rip, right?
Scott: I mean, by definition, it's gambling and the house always wins.
Scott: But renter's insurance is actually, even though the house always wins, the bet is so low.
Scott: It's like a hundred and something bucks for a year.
Rym: Homeowners insurance, the, the, the, the value of saving you a pain in the ass at a bunch of, basically it's a losing bet, right?
Scott: Odds are you're going to lose that money, but it's such a small amount of money and the potential payoff is so big.
Scott: It's like, imagine if there was a lottery, right now, the lottery is a losing bet because it's $1.
Scott: I mean, you're only spending $1 and there's a multi-million possible payoff, but the odds of winning are like one in a billion almost.
Scott: So it's really bad idea.
Rym: What if the lottery ticket was a 10th of a cent?
Scott: Yeah, the lottery tickets, basically a hundred dollars.
Scott: The payoff is like tens of thousands possibly, right?
Scott: But, uh, the odds of winning are like one in, you know, thousands.
Scott: So it's still a losing bet, but it's such a small bet with a big payoff and the odds aren't all that bad.
Scott: It's like, they're okay.
Scott: Better odds, but okay.
Rym: Every year I consider and then decide wisely not to buy one of those thousand dollar raffle tickets for the Lamborghini.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So you mean the Maseratis and whatever.
Rym: There's only 400 tickets.
Rym: I actually got a decent chance of winning.
Scott: Real decent, but you're probably throwing away a thousand dollars.
Rym: The thing is if I win it, I'm fucked.
Scott: You sell it immediately.
Rym: Yeah, but then that's not my income tax.
Scott: I think.
Scott: Yeah, but you only, you can take half.
Scott: So if it's $200,000 car, you get $100,000.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Which wouldn't be that bad.
Scott: But you spent a thousand and you had a one in 400 chance of multiplying the money by a hundred.
Scott: I'd really want a roulette table is a better idea.
Rym: I really want to keep it, but insurance alone would cost more than my apartment.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Anyway, so here, here's my advice, right?
Scott: Homeowners and renters insurance or homeowners insurance or whatever is actually a good idea, depending where you live, right?
Scott: If I lived in the boonies, when I was in beacon, I didn't buy the rent just insurance, but in New York city, I bought the renter's insurance.
Scott: It was so cheap, right?
Scott: Um, second thing, right?
Scott: It's good to buy everything on the internet because that renters insurance they're going to make, they're going to want you.
Scott: It's not necessary, but they're going to want you and they'll like it.
Scott: If you can prove you actually own the stuff.
Scott: So I was like, here's the printouts of all these invoices from Amazon.
Scott: I own it.
Scott: I bought it here.
Scott: Proof.
Scott: You don't have to save receipts in a folder or anything stupid like that, right?
Scott: Like you did in the olden days, you can throw your seats all away.
Scott: Cause it's all recorded on the internet in stone for all eternity.
Scott: I could, I could show you everything I've ever bought an Amazon ever.
Scott: It's all there.
Scott: Right?
Scott: So I owned it.
Scott: Screw you.
Scott: Other advice.
Scott: And I, you know, I've told people before I've known this advice already.
Scott: You should use a credit card for everything in your entire life that you possibly can.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: There's no reason not to use a credit card.
Rym: Aside from all the benefits of the credit card, it's a huge buffer between your money and your stuff.
Scott: Right?
Scott: So here are the reasons to use a credit card that we already knew, right?
Scott: Reason number one, it's easy.
Scott: You don't have to carry cash.
Scott: If someone steals it, you just change the number.
Scott: It's really safe, right?
Scott: Uh, reason number two, increased liquidity, right?
Scott: You can keep your cash till the end of the month.
Scott: And then you're totally, you know, so if any emergency happens, you actually have more money on hand.
Scott: It's, it's a safer financial bet.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: It's like, it's like a free temporary no interest loan.
Scott: That's 30 days.
Scott: And you should always, you're always paying off every month.
Scott: If you don't pay it off every month, you're a moron or it was an emergency, which is justified.
Scott: Uh, another reason to use a credit card for absolutely everything is it's really easy to stop payment or dispute a payment.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Do you know how many times someone's given me trouble and I'm just like, I'll charge back the credit card.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: We're not just talking about column right.
Scott: The we're not just talking about fraud.
Scott: We're talking about just people were a jerk, right?
Scott: If I call the plumber and I pay him with my credit card and then the plumber like doesn't do a good job, I'll just unpay the plumber.
Scott: You just take the money right back.
Scott: If I paid him with cash, that's a lot harder to do, isn't it?
Scott: Yep.
Scott: You know, uh, but with the credit card, yoink debit, it's even harder to do, but credit card yoink, right?
Scott: You know, people think credit cards are evil.
Scott: They're only evil to businesses.
Scott: They're awesome for you swiping the card.
Scott: All right.
Scott: In every single way.
Scott: Now here are additional reasons to use a credit card for absolutely everything in your entire life that we didn't already know.
Scott: And these are.
Scott: this is just two things that I learned about my American Express card.
Scott: But many other credit cards have similar things.
Scott: Look up your credit card policy information, whatever.
Scott: Here is two things about American Express card.
Scott: The one I have, I didn't know.
Scott: Number one, apparently, if I buy something as a manufacturer's warranty, it's like automatically extended like American Express just extends it.
Scott: So if I have something that, say, has a 90 day warranty and it breaks like 100 day, I just call American Express.
Scott: They got covered.
Scott: It's all good, right?
Scott: It's as if the warranty was longer.
Scott: Just got to call the credit card company instead of the manufacturer first or whatever.
Scott: And it's just take care of something else I learned.
Scott: Let's say I buy something and within 90 days it's lost and or stolen.
Scott: So I buy DS and 50 days later I lose it.
Scott: Oh, shit.
Scott: American Express just buys me a new one.
Scott: Boop, boop, boop, boop, boop.
Scott: Just because I used my credit card.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That's all you got to do.
Scott: Nothing else is going to give you that kind of benefit.
Scott: And this doesn't even count.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I didn't even bother to mention, you know, the default credit card benefits of getting miles or points or whatever the fuck, you know, because those are really insignificant.
Scott: Like I get cash back.
Scott: It's barely any cash back.
Scott: It's like a few hundred a year, but it's more than nothing.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, you know, it's you know, the whole miles and stuff.
Scott: It is a big scam.
Scott: You're getting almost no points.
Scott: You know, it's such a small fraction.
Scott: Also, when you're trying it's more than zero.
Scott: It's free stuff.
Rym: When you're traveling overseas, using your credit card gets you the best exchange rate of the day.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: You don't have to worry about hunting around the different exchange rate places.
Rym: Some crappy credit cards have fees, but mine don't sell.
Scott: Yeah, mine doesn't either.
Scott: So, yeah, you should use a credit card for absolutely everything and you should buy as much as you possibly can.
Scott: That's, you know, at least durable goods that are going to get stolen online.
Scott: So you have records automatically.
Scott: Alright, here's some more advice.
Scott: If you have expensive things, right, like Xboxes and TVs or whatever, you know, there's not really much you can do to like secure your house.
Scott: Even if you're crazy with a bunch of locks and stuff, anyone can break into your house if they really want to.
Scott: I can go to Home Depot and buy like a saw that'll drill a hole in your door and put my arm right through and open your door from the inside with my hand.
Rym: That's when the auto shotgun takes you out.
Scott: If you got one.
Scott: And the dags.
Scott: If you got them, right.
Scott: But if you don't got those, right, no number of like even, you know, the strongest, craziest locks is going to save you.
Scott: They're those dudes who open bank vaults with their ear, right, and a few tools, you know, in a matter of minutes, right?
Scott: So nothing you can do to your house is going to keep someone out who really wants to get in.
Scott: As the locksmith said, locks keep honest people honest, right?
Scott: That's pretty much all they do.
Rym: They also keep hobos out.
Scott: They keep hobos out and they keep stupid people out.
Scott: But they're not going to keep a determined burglar out.
Scott: Right.
Rym: If you have something really good, of course, in your case, it was just crowbar.
Scott: It was just crowbar.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But, you know, that's not to say that a crowbar defense mechanism would have actually sufficed.
Scott: You know, they might have gotten in.
Scott: There were any of 100 other ways to get in climbing up to the balcony, breaking the glass.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But anyway, what can you do to actually help out?
Scott: Well, if I had like a camera, it actually probably would have helped.
Scott: It wouldn't help keep them out or save my stuff.
Scott: But the person would probably be in jail now.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So getting one of those like babysitting, if you're really worried about it, you know, it's pretty cheap to get a webcam and a little recording thing.
Scott: And, you know, it's like, OK, it could actually prove useful in many other cases, even when it's not burglars.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You can make sure that, like, the superintendent isn't watching TV in your apartment on the off days, if you care.
Scott: Or you can if you have friends over for a party.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: In the apartment black box where you just, you know, you have your cameras.
Scott: You're going to catch like some YouTube moments that are going to be totally awesome.
Rym: Or they'll just they'll catch, you know, the last 48 hours and then you have to go back and say, like, keep whatever's good, because then you could even hook it up to a motion detector.
Scott: So only records when there's motion.
Rym: But then if anything weird happens, either good, bad or awesome, you've got a record.
Rym: I've thought about setting up something like that in our apartment.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, it's what we don't have anymore, because James, who is like the best photographer in the group, at least in terms of being good at taking pictures of everyone, actually using the camera.
Rym: It's still in Texas.
Scott: Well, you know, it's not like, you know, what's his name comes over enough.
Rym: So we don't have enough photos of us hanging out in parties.
Rym: We've had cameras just filming the whole apartment all the time.
Scott: What's what's tall?
Scott: John's name.
Rym: John.
Scott: No, no.
Scott: You know, John.
Scott: Who lives with Yuka.
Scott: What's John's last name?
Rym: I don't know anyone's last names.
Scott: The tall guy who lives with John Kelly.
Scott: John Kelly.
Scott: God damn it.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: I was like, John, a tall John who takes photos all the time.
Rym: You're like, what's tall?
Rym: John's name?
Rym: I'm like, tall.
Rym: John Kelly.
Scott: He's the only other person who actually takes photos, but he really knows what he's doing.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: He took a really good picture of me in that linen suit anyway.
Scott: So don't if you're if you're worried about sending up a camera because you feel paranoid about it, don't feel paranoid.
Scott: It's totally.
Scott: why not?
Scott: You know, just one is all you need.
Rym: I was really that's one of the DIY projects I was thinking about doing is rigging cameras around the apartment that I'm going to use for parties.
Scott: You should get some like if my computer was stolen, it's not really a big deal.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And they didn't take them.
Scott: But if they did, it's not that big a deal because all my important stuff is in the cloud and on USB sticks and stuff like that.
Scott: And my laptop.
Scott: I'm good.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I got SSH keys, even though the private keys are on the computer.
Scott: They need a password to unlock the key.
Scott: So it's not doing them any good.
Scott: All right.
Scott: But I do have a lot of media MP3s on the hard drives and I have to redownload them if it was stolen.
Scott: So if you're worried about that, external hard drives, hide them somewhere under a bed or some shit like that.
Scott: You know, I'm probably going to get one just mostly because I'm going to hook it up to the camera.
Rym: Actually, as a kid, especially in high school, not that it ever was necessary or helped me out in any way, but I always kept a tiny flash drive or back then, even like way back floppies with whatever, you know, whatever I thought would be important or incriminating or whatever.
Rym: And I hit it in the cold air return.
Rym: I think those floppies might still be there because I didn't take them when we moved.
Scott: Another advice, right?
Scott: Those, you know, those Kensington locks, those little like basically the thing that lets you hook up a steel cable to your computer to tie it down to the desk or the furniture or whatever.
Scott: They're pretty much useless because some we just do as a clipper of any kind.
Scott: You can cut right through that cable, no problem.
Scott: But if you had enough of them, right, it might slow down or deter, you know, a robber.
Scott: Like if your Xbox was tied to the TV and was tied to the Wii and was tied to a computer and was wrapped around like a like a like a steam pipe or something like that, they're probably just going to go, fuck it.
Scott: You know, they didn't bring a clipper.
Scott: They brought a crowbar.
Scott: So what the fuck are they going to get?
Rym: You got to watch out.
Rym: I remember learning this from a cop friend when I was a kid because my dad's a fireman.
Rym: So thieves who fail or run into difficulty might start breaking.
Rym: We'll just trash the place before they go.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: That is also quite a possibility that they will just break stuff.
Scott: But in some ways, breaking stuff is good and bad.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Insurance still covers breaking stuff.
Scott: But breaking stuff is almost more annoying because you have a bigger cleanup.
Scott: I had almost no cleanup because they didn't.
Scott: They just took stuff cleanly, you know, but they also the cops.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They were like, God, did they drink a soda?
Scott: Did they do anything?
Scott: You know, because that's how they can find DNA evidence and fingerprint evidence.
Scott: A lot of people apparently are really stupid and like, they drink a glass of water or they sit down and watch the game.
Scott: I mean, you've seen it on YouTube, right?
Scott: All these people, they robbed someplace and they stopped to play Wii bowling.
Rym: My favorite is the story about the guy who was locked.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: There was just a story about a guy today who got because he robbed the place and he we bowled for an hour and got caught and he went to jail for X time.
Scott: Right.
Scott: He just got sentenced recently.
Scott: So, yeah, you know, watch out for stuff like that.
Rym: Of course, you can't go too far because I remember there's an episode of Dragnet when I was a kid and it was this like fancy clothing store that got knocked off.
Rym: And the dragnet guys like, all right, we're going to help you deal with thieves to make it more difficult for thieves to get you in the future.
Rym: And he goes to the rack of clothes and they're all racked on hangers facing the same way.
Rym: And he's like, look how easy it is for a thief to grab all these clothes.
Rym: You should alternate all your hangers and make it really annoying for the customers to make it really impossible.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Notice how I haven't.
Scott: I haven't suggested you do anything that actually makes your life inconvenient.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I mean, tying all your stuff down with cables basically cost you some bucks and you do it once and then you just leave it that way because you don't move your stuff around that much over the TV.
Rym: Like, I didn't set it up, but I have some anchors for my TV because it's a big TV.
Rym: If it's on a stand, you can basically anchor it to the wall so that if someone bumps into it, there's no way they can knock it over.
Scott: That's a good idea, because TV falling over is perhaps infinitely more likely than it being robbed.
Scott: And if one device can stop both of those, that's a good device.
Rym: I bumped into my TV once and there's this moment.
Rym: It wobbled.
Rym: I was worried the stand was going to break.
Rym: I just stared at it like, oh, fuck, oh, fuck, oh, fuck.
Rym: Oh, OK.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But yeah, you know, any you know, adding more locks to your door does make your life more inconvenient.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Now, you've got to get all these different keys and unlock them all and lock as a pain in the ass.
Scott: But having a camera in your house that is just there, you set it up once and that's it.
Scott: It just doesn't bother you in your life at all.
Scott: Maybe you get some sex tapes out of it.
Scott: You know, it could be good times.
Scott: I mean, other than that, I mean, really, you know, if you show up at your house, you come home and it's burgled, don't touch stuff, especially if it looks like it doesn't belong to you, because the evidence people are going to want to be grabbing that before you grab that and just call the police immediately and chill, you know, just do whatever they say.
Scott: All right.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: It's not really, you know, could have been worse.
Scott: Maybe it would have been better.
Rym: Maybe it was one of those listeners who had your phone number and figured out where you lived.
Scott: I mean, anyone on the Internet knows all that stuff.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And if it's someone on the Internet who knows me, who robbed me.
Scott: They're a jerk.
Rym: Well, we were thinking because Adam, you know, we're waiting to see.
Rym: It'd be funny if the guy had logged in again with your Xbox profile, because he was like, why don't I just message and be like, hey, man, I got the weed.
Rym: You want to meet me to get it.
Rym: or hey, man, do you remember my credit card number?
Rym: You know, I'd ask you to buy that thing and just try to like stream along.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, my credit card number was stored in the Xbox, but you can't actually get it right.
Scott: So you can buy stuff using the card that's for the Xbox like games and downloads or avatar shit.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But you can't actually, you know, use my credit card to buy stuff on Amazon or whatever.
Scott: This does no help.
Rym: Well, apparently they bought some shitty Xbox games.
Scott: They bought two human and fight night something and two other crappy games.
Scott: And then Microsoft gave my money back.
Scott: So whatever.
Scott: All right.
Scott: It's all good.
Scott: Nintendo wasn't much help.
Scott: I basically had to go get a new Wii before they'll help me.
Rym: So we've had.
Scott: But I mean, they couldn't really add any points to my Nintendo without my credit card.
Scott: What they could do, though, is spend the points that were already on there, which I had some points.
Scott: So they're going to buy a virtual console game.
Scott: I didn't want.
Rym: So we've had Bargo, Bargo, Boggle, Boggle and Bargo, Bargo.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: What's next?
Scott: Bungle, Bungle, maybe Bugle.
Scott: Well, there is an anime called the Bungle.
Rym: There's also which is a bungling bay.
Rym: OK.
Rym: You don't remember that game?
Rym: No.
Rym: Really?
Rym: You don't remember bungling day?
Rym: No idea.
Rym: Wow.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for Web Design and Brando Kay for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Scott: But you know, nowadays.
Scott: The old man got all the money.
Scott: And the young man ain't got nothing in the world.