Rym: Hey, it's Tuesday July 27th.
Rym: I'm Rym and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We have two Jareds Luke crane and Jared Sorenson to talk about role-playing games.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Due to what I can only assume is magic I happen to know how long this interview is going to take so we're going to just get right into it.
Rym: So it looks like we've got some Jareds in the studio.
Scott: Oh snap.
Scott: We have a return Jared and a new Jared.
Scott: These are the first return Jareds to GeekNights, maybe possibly I mean not counting people like Emily.
Scott: Yeah, I'm trying to remember It's been.
Scott: it's been how long Luke since you've been on the show.
Luke: Oh, wow.
Luke: It's uh, it's been four years I guess and I'm only back here because you paid me.
Scott: I didn't.
Rym: I didn't contribute Since we basically cornered you at a convention and forced you to do an interview with us.
Rym: I was drunk during it.
Scott: I was so drunk.
Scott: If he's the one selling stuff shouldn't he be paying us?
Rym: because we were going to like wait in the bar and meet everybody and hang out with some people in Our K?
Rym: and then that didn't happen and I was the only one who got my drink.
Luke: He had it.
Luke: You had a mixer Like.
Luke: I'm not a drink.
Scott: You have both guys.
Rym: Mostly the problem was I ordered a. I think I wrote like a Manhattan and they just gave me a gigantic water glass filled with.
Scott: So, yeah, do you want to introduce yourself properly?
Luke: I guess hi, I'm Luke and I'm Judd.
Jared: Nobody's gonna get that joke.
Jared: It's too long.
Luke: It's too long.
Luke: It's it's dead.
Luke: So yeah, hi Rym.
Luke: Hi Scott.
Luke: Thanks for having me back.
Luke: It's been four years.
Luke: I've made a lot more games and books since then but I miss you guys and people always miss you.
Luke: We saw you like up to me a few weeks ago But in radio land People come up to me today still and talk to me about that GeekNights episode And tell me that they heard about burning wheel through GeekNights.
Luke: Well, hopefully they'll do this day.
Scott: Hopefully this will I guess, you know increase the frequency of that.
Scott: maybe they'll be like, oh which you'll be like which episode?
Scott: the one?
Luke: But we're here with my my friend and partner Jared Sorenson, hi I Tell the listeners who you are what you do.
Jared: My name is Jared Sorenson.
Jared: I'm a game designer and writer and publisher and I do a bunch of games.
Jared: They might have heard of might like action castle Made famous by the action castle incident at PAX.
Scott: You're on a podcast.
Scott: There are four people here.
Luke: There are no exits.
Luke: I There's a microphone.
Scott: here dude is an elevator.
Scott: dude, we need an.
Scott: we need a parsley game with the elevator in it.
Jared: It's the next one Station, definitely.
Jared: It's a turbo lift.
Scott: Oh shit.
Scott: Yeah, I gotta get that.
Jared: It's out.
Luke: What brand new it's out.
Jared: It just came out.
Scott: Yeah, you have one.
Jared: I didn't bring one.
Rym: So rapidly we get behind.
Scott: Clearly he's making games faster than I can play them.
Rym: So, I guess we should get started with kind of the obvious topic because it's a. it's a point of debate among our listeners among Us sometimes at panels between awesome people in the audience.
Rym: What is a role-playing game?
Scott: There's a question like mean something different when you say it like that?
Rym: Yes, it's like a game show.
Rym: question then like who is the father?
Luke: Not any of us I don't think trying to tell us something.
Jared: I don't think that game shows been invented yet.
Jared: Although that's gold.
Jared: that is fucking gold We don't know.
Luke: Wait, I saw an episode of it when I was in Japan.
Rym: Oh So, what is a role-playing game?
Rym: I guess we should actually talk about it.
Jared: really do we care?
Jared: does anybody care?
Rym: I think people do because a lot if nothing else it will.
Scott: it will spawn us into discussing something else more interesting when we find Tangents.
Scott: that is interest, you know quality.
Luke: Okay, so Talisman, that's the best role-playing game ever design.
Jared: It's a role-playing game talisman.
Scott: I don't even what is talisman games workshop Game from the 80s?
Jared: from the 80s you play a character you get magic I roll as it were you get you fight you have stats you have hit points you have gold you find explore the labyrinth you do and You win lose or die.
Jared: There's even alignment in it.
Scott: Really?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Oh, wow So do you have to paint the managers?
Scott: this is a games workshop game.
Jared: no Do have some lead figures that you can buy for it, but it comes with little hard stock counters.
Scott: Make this game because I know like they reissued it.
Jared: fantasy flight games maybe last year.
Scott: Oh fantasy advertisement.
Jared: It is.
Scott: they change they change the name of it.
Jared: It's canal called talisman by fantasy flight.
Scott: Sometimes you'll get like a reissue of a game and they change the title of it.
Jared: But it's really strangely enough in the 21st century.
Jared: I think it's still cost the same as it did in a 1980 Possibly one of the worst gameplay experiences I've ever had or the best Which defines it as a role-playing like a hero quest type of thing.
Scott: Does it differ from hero quest?
Luke: I was very similar very similar or Warhammer quest or Dungeon dungeons actually the first role-playing game dungeon also.
Scott: What's what's dungeon?
Jared: Is that talisman light?
Luke: Designed by Gygax and Arneson board game levels.
Scott: Did they make that before D&D or after after?
Scott: so you're so.
Scott: so wait.
Scott: You said that that was like the first role-playing game.
Scott: So D&D original D&D was not a role-playing game.
Scott: Is that what you're saying?
Jared: Correct?
Scott: So what?
Jared: it is a simulation.
Jared: It's a tactical tactical simulation skirmish based man-to-man fighting.
Scott: So what is what about it?
Scott: makes it not a role-playing game?
Jared: No kissing.
Scott: There's no kissing in talisman.
Jared: there is kissing.
Scott: yes, how do you how?
Scott: you said it's a lot like hero quest.
Jared: There's all sorts of stuff in talisman But you've changed.
Scott: it's not no longer the hero quest anymore.
Scott: It's not a different game.
Scott: because you've changed the rules.
Scott: like if I play monopoly with money on free parking It's not monopoly.
Jared: It's your request in a pink box.
Luke: yeah, so wait what if I Every time I get a hearts card in poker if I kiss you?
Luke: doesn't make it a role-playing game.
Jared: Makes it more disturbing game.
Luke: How do you turn poker into a role-playing game?
Jared: God I actually played that game.
Jared: WIC had a game.
Luke: John WIC John designer of legends of the five rings.
Jared: He had this really cool game.
Jared: I don't think he ever.
Scott: You played that game.
Rym: I played that game.
Scott: scary people.
Rym: I played that game with perhaps the scariest people we've ever known I've ever encountered in my life.
Scott: I'm pretty sure he never actually raped a child, but otherwise Wow, this is a dude where if you just if he brought up a conversation He basically he would brag to you about he how he knew and memorized the age of consent in all 50 states.
Jared: Yeah, I think I know that guy too.
Jared: But someone like him someone with his gene line.
Rym: Basically I spent like four hours making this character with this long introduction And I was killed in one hit by the first thing we encountered and that was the end It's Bushido played of role-playing games.
Jared: What's that's that's good?
Jared: We need more of that.
Jared: We need more one-shot kill.
Rym: What makes a good role-playing game?
Jared: Oh now our names on the box Boom.
Luke: that's completely different.
Luke: So what is a role-playing game versus what is a good role-playing game?
Jared: I mean a good role-playing game is very different.
Luke: different question exactly.
Rym: So It makes a good role-playing game.
Rym: like for you, like what do you say Luke is a good role-playing game?
Luke: Oh Oh my like.
Rym: what are the elements like?
Rym: what makes it good versus bad?
Rym: Like why is D&D so unsatisfying?
Rym: Well, I say all right.
Scott: So if I'm if I'm a if I'm if I'm some punk kid who thinks he knows how to write a role-playing game Right, you're wrong and you are all right.
Scott: Okay, so you're wrong.
Scott: So so I write a game and I say, you know, let's say you were it was like, you know You're in like a the way comic people like look at people's portfolios.
Scott: I give the game to you and I'm like, oh you will you critique my game and tell me where I went wrong?
Scott: You know, what would be like the things that you look for first?
Jared: We have a list.
Luke: if you're a role-playing game had creation myths in it and a fighting system and Character creation and a magic system.
Luke: I think that would be where at the point at which I'd tell you you steered yourself a little.
Luke: Perhaps you might want to go back to the drawing board.
Luke: For me a modern role-playing game has to have Some form of mechanical resolution for well it needs.
Jared: it needs player agency.
Jared: It needs.
Scott: so what I say for what is player agency?
Scott: because people listening probably have no idea.
Jared: the player has to be able to make meaningful choices and have a have a right effect on Events in the world.
Jared: Well, that's that's a. that's a choice.
Jared: that's good.
Jared: It's better than no choice.
Luke: It's but it's not.
Jared: but it's not really.
Luke: It's not enough.
Luke: It's it's.
Luke: it's not enough for for a contemporary role-playing game.
Jared: You have to make emotional.
Jared: Well, basically what you have to do is you have to make irrational decisions.
Jared: that's kind of the difference between a role-playing game and a war game is if I'm playing with my Napoleonic miniatures and I decide this guy's gonna kill this guy because he's closer and it's an easier shot That's a lot different than saying this guy's brother was killed in the war by this guy.
Jared: now He's out for revenge.
Jared: then it's a role-playing game.
Jared: You have emotional context You're making.
Jared: you're making suboptimal decisions based on emotional responses.
Luke: I call it player priorities to like.
Luke: I feel I feel stupid playing a role-playing game in 2010 if I do not have a place to insert or choose a Priority as a player meaning something that I am interested in as a person that I want my character to do.
Luke: I don't give a fuck about my character, you know, I don't give a. I don't care what Rym wants to do.
Luke: I want to be able to say Right.
Luke: I'm playing a dragoon or us a dirty French hussar.
Rym: I Thought about that stupid like.
Rym: what's a game?
Scott: that the rail shooter with the dragon is like Legend of Dragoons, I think it's Anyway.
Luke: if I'm or is Starcraft or Grune, you know, there's no Shogun warrior named Dragoon.
Jared: I'm gonna say there was all right.
Luke: I don't think so.
Jared: Yeah, I'm gonna say there was shut up.
Jared: How dare you don't have the right to dream?
Luke: So, I mean a game should have a role-playing game needs to have not just like Mathematical mechanical resolution But it has to have choices that the player is making based on the emotional content of their character based Plus the situation plus what's going on in the game.
Luke: right if you're not factoring in What you know what the GM has said, you know What the other players have done and presented like basically where what what's going on in this in this space between us like where?
Luke: All the characters, you know, why am I doing this if you're not factoring factoring that into a role and the game isn't reinforcing that decision with okay if you go this way if you make this decision Then this thing happens.
Luke: you make this decision.
Luke: this thing happens If you.
Luke: if you make no decision this thing happens, right like a nun like if you choose to stand null whatever the game has to insert itself into the situation and Either there has to be an instruction for another player or there has to be some kind of consequence for those actions.
Jared: Well, the game has a philosophy and it should either coincide with or conflict with your own philosophy.
Rym: Your own philosophy is a player or your characters philosophy.
Jared: There's no character in a role-playing game.
Jared: There are no characters.
Jared: They're only players.
Jared: Anybody who says that's what my character should that's what my character would do is weird.
Rym: It should probably go to a hospital that I've noticed that a lot and you always talk about like turtling.
Rym: I got a break hit like someone who's like they're starting to roll play and then they like turtle and just sit there and like Let all the events pass by.
Rym: but I found that almost the opposite situation happens I don't know what to call it.
Rym: where someone starts to internalize all the role-playing to the point that they're kind of being quiet.
Rym: It looks like they're turtling but really they're like role-playing all this BS about their own character out in their head and then they have some sort of rationale like suddenly they jump in like I stabbed that guy because that's what my character would have done and they use my Character would have done it as an excuse to just be obstructionist.
Luke: Yeah We have less nice names for those guys.
Jared: Is it a troche?
Luke: no, no that no.
Luke: the turtle just sits there and does nothing.
Luke: the roach.
Luke: Like when the spotlights not on the player, they're running around doing everything.
Luke: you're talking to that player.
Luke: next to them There's oh, oh, oh, they look like they want to do something and then as soon as the the whatever the spotlight of the game Turn they got nothing.
Luke: Yeah, they just cuz they're a roach.
Scott: They run or they scurry into the darkness as soon as the light is On them.
Luke: Yes.
Scott: Yes, but when it's dark, they're moving around getting all busy.
Scott: Yeah.
Jared: Yeah.
Jared: So word for the.
Scott: so this is a word for the player who just internalizes everything they're playing but only in their own mind and they're doing The guy who comes and he's got like a whole book of backstory written and like as you're playing he's like writing even more.
Rym: The first gaming kind ever went to Michicon.
Rym: I was like 11 I think and I went to this gaming kind of played D&D like for all night with all these old guys and one guy like runs Into a god and the gods like what is your desire?
Rym: and all the players are like tell like tell him like out of character You should do this.
Rym: You should do this.
Rym: No, we're trying to win this thing.
Rym: It's a competition.
Rym: Let's go and he goes through this big notebook He brought with him finds a piece of paper like flips through.
Rym: it finds like one paragraph Circles it hands it to the game master and the game master reads it and just looks up to him Like what is wrong with you?
Luke: And he had it all planned out like if my character should ever meet a god ask for this.
Rym: and it asked about all this stuff about his character's backstory and all this Fulfillment and all this.
Rym: it looked like he had a great story in his head.
Luke: But so wait, so let's back up.
Luke: I actually think it's a little disingenuous to say that there's no character.
Luke: I will often Like I will toot that horn and say, you know, there's only a player there's no character.
Luke: I also think it's very dishonest thing for a for a player to say Well, that's what my character would do and to not recognize that there are three or four other people at the table all with their own needs priorities desires.
Luke: But I mean you can make decisions within the framework of a character that you've built.
Luke: Sure, right.
Luke: You can you can say hey I have made you know, I have built this little mask this this structure here and Most appropriate response.
Luke: Right, that's what my character would do.
Jared: Yeah.
Jared: What would I do in a fight?
Jared: I'd run.
Jared: what would my character do?
Jared: He'd probably fight because he's trained or something.
Jared: So yeah, I mean, of course there's that but there's no There's no Schizophrenic kind of.
Jared: oh, I'm gonna make decisions based on this fictional character.
Jared: That's gonna not only clash with the other players But also clash with which is with with what I want to do as a player.
Jared: Because oh that was my character would do.
Jared: my character would do something.
Jared: That's not fun It's the classic.
Jared: my character would go home.
Jared: My character wouldn't be an adventurer.
Jared: Yeah, but you're playing a game.
Jared: Yeah, you made a character.
Jared: He's going to be an adventurer.
Jared: deal with it.
Jared: Yeah, but he's a cook.
Jared: I always got this in games.
Jared: in D&D games that one guy who's like I'm gonna be a cook Rym those are in once and I'm gonna carry a frying pan instead of a Pacifist.
Scott: I don't want to do the boring combat Because I hated the combat.
Rym: so basically combat would start.
Rym: I would go over to the other apartment like counter-strike for like four hours Which is it's.
Jared: that's a bad game because you as a pacifist you you made a decision.
Jared: You should have consequences for that decision.
Jared: You shouldn't be able to just disengage with the game pull out and go.
Jared: well this part's not for me Right.
Luke: if the game lets you make a pacifist character the game should speak to you as a pacifist Player.
Luke: as a player of a pacifist character the game should say it should say oh well Then if you're going to do this This is what's going on the game should not exclude you for four hours at a time of play.
Jared: the same example same example Same same condition different example the decker in a cyberpunk game same thing as a pacifist player.
Jared: well This isn't about decking so I'm gonna leave.
Luke: aggressive player.
Jared: Yeah, this isn't about decking so I'm gonna leave.
Jared: and meanwhile the decker is like well This isn't about decking so I'm gonna leave I'm gonna go you know catch up on my sleep.
Jared: those games are broken.
Rym: So at what?
Rym: what's the line between it being the game masters responsibility to address that versus the game?
Scott: Yeah, what is the game Dean right?
Jared: Well cuz the game tells the game master what to do right?
Scott: I mean, but like look at D&D right the the book doesn't really the players handbook.
Scott: at least It doesn't really give the GM that much instruction right, but if you were a pacifist player in D&D right the game master could Force upon some monsters on you forcing you to do something even if you were running away from combat.
Scott: He'd like a crazy fast cheetah is coming after you or there's a displacer beast.
Scott: It's faster than you would caught you.
Scott: now What are you gonna do?
Jared: pacifist World of Warcraft?
Jared: Allows you to play a pacifist character.
Scott: How do you level up then?
Jared: it's hard, but you do it.
Jared: In a week I got to level 20.
Jared: No, the only thing I was allowed to kill.
Jared: I gave myself the concession I could kill undead But still there's not a lot of undead in the zones.
Jared: I played.
Scott: I played the World of Warcraft demo.
Scott: I've never played it beyond like a day and I was I don't know.
Scott: I think I was a paladin so pretty much everything was undead.
Scott: It was like scale.
Scott: It was like kill 10 skeletons.
Scott: Okay, kill 15 skeletons.
Scott: I was like great.
Jared: It's I was doing a.
Luke: Let's back up to the question.
Luke: like Jared said the Right in D&D.
Luke: There's.
Luke: there is this kind of void space where you can make anything.
Luke: You can have any philosophy because D&D won't come out and just say no you have to be this.
Jared: This is because there is somebody who can fight and be going adventures be an adventurer.
Luke: according to them the mechanism that is D&D.
Luke: there are only certain things that you can be that will Allow you to function within the game.
Luke: right you have to kill shit and take its stuff.
Luke: And and if you're not gonna play a character who's gonna kill shit and take its stuff.
Luke: You're going to be miserable.
Luke: And you're.
Jared: it's like playing a shadowrunner who won't break the law.
Jared: I'm not gonna break the law.
Jared: well You're going to be staying home.
Jared: Well.
Luke: I want to play a cop screaming shadowrun.
Luke: You're the only one.
Rym: I've seen that as the opposite problem too where we'd often you know before we found burning wheel and even any other game that wasn't D&D or basically GURPS.
Rym: you know just D&D with different numbers.
Rym: we would try to play these very like politically driven intrigue like we're all diplomats, and we'd use the D&D rules and Obviously that didn't work, so we basically roll diplomacy all the time.
Luke: well right because the game won.
Luke: The game won't come out and just tell you what it's about Right and say this is the best way to play this game and also the players.
Jared: a lot of players refuse to admit that the Game, they've loved for so many years It's probably kind of bad and that they've turned into a game that they love.
Jared: the game itself is written.
Jared: It's not a good game, but they're like no.
Jared: I love this game.
Jared: I've been playing it since I was 13. no you've been playing your own hack of it with all this crazy intrigue and political Machination mechanics, it's like monopoly and free parking.
Luke: right yeah.
Scott: So I guess you wouldn't consider Final Fantasy in RPG right because you don't make any decisions.
Scott: You just basically you know this combat, and it's just a strategy, and if you lose you just start over you don't you know?
Rym: There's?
Scott: no there's no decisions.
Jared: That's a computer game.
Jared: I don't know if I think computer RPGs are inspired by RPGs, but they're.
Jared: who knows?
Luke: that's a tough one.
Luke: I mean you're.
Luke: I mean is there any embodiment in any identification avatar identification?
Luke: there I feel like you're that person.
Rym: you feel like you're making no Trigger which is a very separate example.
Scott: You're supposed to be chrono and the other.
Scott: the other characters are supposed to be sort of supporting characters.
Scott: Right and there are multiple endings based on things you do In different parts of the game though the rest of it is largely extremely similar to Final Fantasy.
Jared: well I mean if you look at some popular and successful well-made games There is an element of embodiment.
Jared: I mean when you're playing half-life You are not a badass.
Jared: you are a physicist and up in a suit.
Jared: if you're playing thief, and you're playing this is name Eric I forget God begins with a G whatever, but um you are not a badass swordsman.
Jared: You're a dude who hides in the shadows and waits for people to walk by and then you club them in the back of the Head.
Jared: that's great because it enforces you to play a certain way, which mirrors the character however.
Jared: Are you feeling?
Jared: You know loss or longing or any of these emotions that the that the characters feeling I Mean maybe in the way that you you feel for a character that you're reading about in a book.
Rym: Well the argument I get most from people who say that our role-playing games and a lot of people in panels will ask this question They say that you couldn't just make it a movie You know even though it's just a single narrative because the time invested alone Makes you identify with the character and feel like you're making these decisions even when you're not
Luke: the sunk cost fallacy.
Rym: It's hard to argue with you guys, let's let's.
Jared: uh let's actually let's call Roger Ebert so we can get him in on this conversation.
Scott: I don't even know.
Scott: he's never played a video game right, so I don't really.
Scott: I don't even knows a tabletop RPG exists Or how it works.
Jared: He actually has a copy of one of my games really.
Scott: How do you know this?
Jared: I gave it to him.
Scott: really We need to start.
Scott: so when did you?
Scott: when did you meet him in person?
Scott: or was it?
Jared: no is it person?
Jared: I went up to him.
Jared: I was on a cruise ship, and he I was at his uh his Festival film festival at sea with uh him in a Richard Roper, and I went up to him.
Jared: I was like hey I did this.
Jared: I know you're a big into pulp and and stuff like that and Here's a copy of octane and against the Reich.
Jared: you know you know I signed it for him and everything I was like you know.
Jared: I think you're a great reviewer.
Jared: I really you know admire you blah blah blah and Richard Roper looked at me and said hey, where's mine?
Jared: I said hey, you didn't like sky captain and world of tomorrow.
Jared: Yeah, yeah, you'd like.
Jared: Ebert likes anything that has a bold vision.
Jared: It doesn't matter if the story's a little weak as long as it shows him something.
Scott: Yeah, that's I was gonna say is like that's.
Scott: that's basically my opinion of the sky captain is that the story was a little weak But it was like he always.
Jared: he always quotes the the quote about the world is starving for new images Which I always like.
Jared: that quote mm-hmm.
Jared: But anyway, yeah Ebert suffering the same the same slings and arrows from his readers about our games are in our games better than movies or the same as movies or Whatever, I don't think we're gonna.
Luke: So it's tough.
Luke: a role-playing game like a tabletop role-playing game allows You know one as simple as D&D allows for such a greater degree of avatar identification for embodiment.
Luke: Then partly because you make up the character yourself well you make up the character right.
Luke: you were created And you get to.
Luke: you get to form this vision in your head.
Luke: but also part of it like this the sunk cost fallacy is involved in this a little bit to the Number of decisions that you make even in D&D the small just micro decisions that you're constantly making huge like you know Exponentially greater than the decisions that you make in a Final Fantasy style RPG Final Finis because Final Fantasy processes all of the game information for you.
Luke: So it's just presenting you with like these really easy like spell or weapon.
Luke: You know this way or that way whereas you know I have to be.
Luke: if we're playing D&D I have to constantly negotiate with you guys where we're gonna.
Luke: Go.
Luke: We're gonna.
Luke: Do I got it?
Luke: Oh, well, what kind of?
Luke: what do I get from this Hall of Treasure?
Luke: We what am I gonna write down?
Luke: We're gonna share with you.
Jared: a D&D character has memories and history associated with it And I tend to think of our computer RPG characters as having levels and like goals and quests that they've accomplished.
Scott: Do you think do you think there is a video game that has memory and history going on?
Luke: Why not World of Warcraft?
Luke: I mean why is that not an RPG?
Luke: I don't know.
Rym: none of that is attached to the character.
Rym: It's all kind of the meta.
Jared: It's just there.
Jared: It's just there and you're unlocking bits and pieces of it.
Jared: There's no, but I the more you.
Luke: but you're.
Luke: you talk about that pacifist character all the time.
Jared: well That's cuz I'm using it to bring up an exit.
Jared: to make an example.
Jared: I mean no I I. I have memories about the character But it does.
Jared: it never feels like the character has memories.
Jared: the characters a cipher.
Jared: the characters a cipher with some numbers.
Luke: This is the case I mean for everything you said it before.
Luke: the character doesn't exist in an energy correct, but but The character.
Jared: well the character, I'm getting flustered.
Jared: cuz Luke's pushing a big button of mine.
Luke: Go let's go Come on Come on.
Luke: I'm pushing the big red button.
Luke: so the care come on.
Jared: Which is it I think for an RPG?
Jared: the players memory of the events and The characters memory.
Jared: the events are Are Similar, but disparate things.
Jared: The events that happen in the character not the events that happen to the player.
Jared: There's a lot there's a lot.
Jared: There's.
Jared: there's emotional resonance in this emotional context.
Jared: It's not there.
Luke: You are twisting yourself around this point.
Luke: I mean yeah Yeah, I agree with you, but so I don't post on forums anymore.
Luke: I agree that I think it that counteracts or contradicts rather your earlier statement.
Luke: the character doesn't exist.
Jared: Well I guess I would I said that to be some provocative.
Rym: You know the character sheet of World of Warcraft only writes down the kind of these tasks You've accomplished that.
Rym: everyone else who played that same You know class and race basically is also accomplished once they get to that level And doesn't write down all the personal like everything else.
Rym: all the decisions you made there were interesting.
Jared: It'd be interesting if it if it took into account like oh my god that know that one.
Jared: No took me so many times To go back and to kill him and eventually he did and I had to kite him and I had to get this weapon.
Rym: Using the lingo.
Jared: you're really good.
Jared: I'm a professional, dude.
Rym: But like look at D&D or not?
Rym: Do you look at a role-playing game where you have the paper and you and your record like you're writing down like I got this And you're kind of the filter of the stuff you remembered you care about Gets onto the character sheet at least in a role-playing game.
Rym: that does that.
Rym: I mean he doesn't do that by default But some games do?
Luke: when you guys play role-playing games Do you make little side notes on the care sheet about things things people said or characters you met or stuff like that?
Scott: Just because I'm really I'm forgetful.
Scott: like even if I'm like GMing I'll try to write everything down and then I'll forget just because I don't.
Luke: what about when you're playing when you're forgetful when you're Playing so you don't write things down.
Rym: Scott basically will say things in role-playing games like I use the proper noun to attack the bad guy.
Scott: Alright, you know even if I'm playing like I'll write down something like in D&D Write write down if there's like we got some crazy item or something or if there's a puzzle I'll try to figure it out, but I don't you know.
Scott: I just don't have the instance.
Scott: the same problem I'll bring a camera with me everywhere And I'll never take a picture even though I really really mean to Just because I don't have the instinct to actually pull it out and actually use it.
Rym: Don't look at me with the same pity.
Rym: you're looking at Scott with.
Rym: I write down the names every character I run into and like stuff about him and how much I care about him, and I remember it.
Rym: I actually use NPCs first names when I talk to them.
Jared: I'm more like Scott.
Luke: I guess I'm in the middle, but I'll like.
Luke: I'll make a note on the character sheet itself.
Luke: like just like you know We meet somebody like you know Vanya.
Luke: I'll just write down Vanya like I have no context.
Luke: I also I also will write down funny things that Scott says or that from Rich will say.
Luke: like I'll write down quotes Often, but my point here is that the character sheet?
Luke: Just as you're talking about in World of Warcraft your physical character She definitely becomes an artifact and it becomes almost like a totem.
Luke: like how many how many?
Luke: Times you see character sheet that's got coke stains on it and eraser marks rip through it.
Scott: That's Rym won't even replace a book if the covers come off.
Scott: what I do is all like if my she gets messed up is Like I reprint it and re do it.
Scott: I gotta be on.
Scott: it's got to be all clean.
Rym: even when I refresh like the character is unreadable I keep the old one is backup.
Scott: Maybe oh, man.
Rym: I doodled there when I fell asleep during that combat.
Luke: interesting I'm like that.
Luke: I'm very much like that.
Jared: I'll reprint a character sheet and then Photoshop it so it has the coke stain back on it So you can just make a watermark that will automatically add a different like randomized coke stains.
Scott: the problem is some are Besides I have their character flash already has like you know coke stains like built in to the character sheet like the PDF.
Scott: on Their website there's a.
Jared: there's a couple books that inspect.
Jared: the German version of inspectors is like that.
Scott: There's a German version.
Scott: Yeah, how many?
Scott: how many languages are there for right now?
Jared: There's Two and Polish is in the works.
Scott: Oh wow awesome.
Scott: How about never like they're burning wheels that and any other non-english?
Luke: No, I tried to get a contract.
Luke: I don't understand.
Luke: I tried to get a. these guys offered to translate to Spanish and Catalan and yeah To like two more languages, and they were only gonna print 80 copies, and I said right.
Scott: So it's just for you and your friends.
Luke: Yeah, I'm like what the hell they're like.
Luke: the markets very small.
Luke: We'll put like 80 Catalan and 100 Spanish whatever and I'm like 100 Spanish.
Luke: really are you like?
Luke: I don't either.
Luke: I was like.
Luke: I don't think that's enough.
Luke: I think you could probably sell a thousand in Spanish and so we couldn't work out the deal And I and they wanted to take three years, and I wanted them to do it in two.
Luke: So I'm pretty much just a bastard who ruins all things that are good.
Scott: Would you would you be opposed to like a fan translation?
Luke: fanslation uh Yes I Mean whatever.
Luke: if somebody's gonna translate it at home for their group or whatever that's fine, but once you post Changing hands.
Jared: That's when it's I mean.
Scott: what if it wasn't money?
Scott: It was just you know we put on the Internet's.
Luke: if you post my shit for free on the Internet I will ask you to stop.
Luke: I hate it.
Luke: I really hate it.
Scott: I Guess we don't.
Scott: I guess we don't want to go into that topic.
Scott: we could do a whole show on there, right?
Scott: So so you know you guys I guess you know you're mostly here to talk about making games.
Scott: What are there any games?
Scott: You've like played a lot recently or that you're really?
Scott: You know having fun with.
Jared: this is the shout-out section.
Scott: no No, I mean like you know like I wanted.
Scott: I don't want you to like just shout out.
Scott: Oh these are the games our friends make or the.
Jared: you know I'm not gonna do that because I don't Like actual.
Scott: like recent game experiences that were awesome.
Jared: pandemic is awesome.
Scott: I make really the the like you know the the everyone versus the game game.
Rym: yeah Yeah, it was pandemic a role-playing game because a lot of people treated as one.
Jared: oh I was totally playing it like a role-playing game in fact.
Jared: I was told Jared don't roleplay Don't roleplay.
Jared: I was playing the crazy guy.
Jared: Who's like.
Jared: I'm gonna solve the world's problems.
Jared: I'm gonna cure this disease.
Jared: But it's an emergent process crazy.
Jared: It's totally emergent.
Jared: It's not like.
Luke: there's not a.
Jared: you don't need to do it.
Luke: You can talk back to you if you start talking to it.
Luke: essentially right the game does not and further encourage you to make Moral ethical decisions in the framework of the character the game.
Scott: I think the game pretty much has a pretty straight moral of save the world.
Scott: Yeah, it doesn't say don't save the world or decide.
Jared: there's no size for being the guy who discovers the last cure.
Jared: There's no prize.
Luke: There's no.
Luke: there's no prize for making a heartfelt decision.
Luke: Do I save my wife or do I save the whole world?
Luke: right like like you never make that decision.
Luke: and where were you brought?
Jared: Up?
Jared: yeah, Atlanta.
Jared: Well guess what it's just been overrun.
Luke: Yeah, how do you feel about that?
Rym: But I mean you like Value in these emerging experiences where the game was not intended as a role-playing game and yet those same Maybe this is why D&D is still so popular.
Rym: D&D You know the game doesn't really intend kind of their kinds of role-playing we do and yet it comes out anyway Just because that's what people innately want.
Rym: what will they do?
Rym: the same thing to pandemic?
Jared: What we call role-playing which is talking in funny voices and making weird decisions based on what this is.
Jared: what my character would do is Totally an emergent property from D&D.
Jared: It's not anything.
Luke: I right D&D doesn't tell you to do that.
Jared: It's not the act.
Jared: Yeah, D&D is not a theatrical experience.
Jared: I think if it was written like that Dave and Gary's friends would be like I'm not gonna do that I'm not.
Jared: what do you want us to do?
Jared: dress up in robes - but that's the other thing.
Luke: you don't say it Except it emerges natural happens.
Luke: It's just.
Luke: it's kind of how we embody media.
Luke: We like how we come out of a movie theater and we're talking about the characters like they're real.
Luke: Right the movie that we just saw.
Luke: we quote lines incessantly like we talk about a character as if the character did something.
Luke: No, nobody did anything.
Luke: Leonardo DiCaprio didn't do anything either.
Luke: He was told to do something.
Luke: He was instructed and he followed a very Strict formula.
Jared: He didn't really do anything period he just talked a lot.
Jared: He just told you what he was gonna do.
Scott: We saw it yesterday.
Scott: I noticed some similarities with like lacuna in there.
Luke: It's really it's really scary.
Jared: Yeah.
Jared: Yeah Luke made you made the list right of.
Luke: yeah, there's a list like it's static levels Hostile personalities personalities Diving slut the slab.
Luke: Jared already wrote the Inception role-playing game, which is really eerie for those of you at home.
Luke: 2006 yeah, so apparently he went into Christopher Nolan's dream state and did an Inception Traction.
Scott: Marvy Christopher Nolan's played lacuna.
Jared: We don't know he could have possible.
Jared: There's I know a bunch of screenwriters who have played my game.
Scott: Yeah, I mean it was But I thought that it was you know Just incredibly like welcome that they would had something so complex and off the wall.
Scott: They usually went.
Scott: other movies and TV shows try to do the same thing.
Scott: It's like, you know, they go into the realm of even comprehensibility, but you don't know what's going on.
Jared: It wasn't complex or off the wall pretty straightforward If you compare it to like standard fare.
Jared: you want to see something complex and off the wall.
Jared: see Rafifi what's your?
Jared: Just go see it.
Jared: Oh, it's just go see it.
Jared: Oh, yeah, it's a movie.
Scott: Is it on DVD?
Scott: What country is it from DVDs on Netflix?
Scott: What year is it from?
Luke: 1957 no 60 no, no, no, no early much earlier.
Luke: It's like 49 or something.
Jared: Oh tub copy is the one that came after.
Jared: That's what.
Jared: that's what I'm thinking.
Luke: But but copy so that's the see.
Jared: either one of those.
Jared: actually see them back to back and your mind will be blown.
Rym: We'll have to trade them some.
Luke: ma chareau They're heist films.
Luke: They're they're.
Luke: they're really actually pretty grounded high school Right.
Luke: Yeah, exactly.
Jared: And that's why we're suggesting these and The.
Luke: the heist in Rafifi is has no Music, no dialogue.
Jared: No music And it goes 20 minutes long 20 minutes long.
Jared: It will blow your mind.
Jared: You will be biting your friends.
Luke: Dude I could.
Luke: I have never been able to conceive of how to get you fucking monkeys to behave like that.
Luke: That's one of the reasons I won't write a noir.
Luke: role-playing game is because in noir You have to behave in a certain way.
Luke: You cannot goof off.
Luke: You can't eat Cheetos You can't crack jokes that are outside of like, you know, the weird noir like underworld code like like.
Jared: There would have to be people behind you with guns in order for a role-playing game.
Jared: New aren't role-playing him to work.
Rym: So the box comes with a couple of zip guns.
Jared: It comes with a couple large men with zip guns.
Jared: It's like hey, I don't think you want to be making no money Python jokes.
Luke: It's not a mafia role-playing.
Luke: I love noir Holy passion and it just I've never been able to conceive of the tone.
Luke: and if you look at all the modern Role-playing games boat noir.
Luke: They all incorporate some gonzo element that just destroys it.
Jared: Just here's noir with fairies.
Jared: Here's noir with Cat.
Scott: people are with spider-man.
Rym: So to bring it back hey, wait a minute.
Rym: It's just like this natural emergent behavior that we do just when we play games like emergently we will play.
Rym: Yeah What's the purpose of a role-playing game as opposed to just role-playing to reward that?
Jared: if you reward that you've made a role-playing game Oh my god.
Jared: I just answered.
Jared: What is a role-playing game?
Luke: Yeah, I mean it's different.
Luke: when you know, I'm playing memoir 44 and I'm talking to funny German accent and I'm you know, I'm You know driving toward my evil axis goals.
Luke: it's.
Luke: it's just very different than when I play a World war two role-playing game and I'm playing a German commander who's doing awful things and just that like it's just well Here's the quality of the experience is just very very different when right when it's something that I'm just kind of goofing off doing versus when I am suddenly kind of in the Boiling pot having to make these horrible decisions and say and thinking well, but I don't like not I don't want to make this decision.
Luke: I don't want to be this guy.
Jared: So you just said, you know evil decisions in the memoir game.
Jared: There are no evil decisions.
Jared: There's no evil axis Plans.
Jared: in memoir 44 there's pieces on a board and you're trying to eliminate the other pieces.
Jared: There's no There's no good.
Jared: There's no evil.
Jared: There's just side a and side B. as soon as you start ascribing motivation and philosophical Ideologies and intent and good and evil and emotion.
Jared: That's when it becomes a role-playing game, right?
Luke: I never weigh like.
Luke: I'll play the the the axis in memoir without really thinking about it.
Luke: I mean, I you know, I grimace a little bit.
Jared: There's a historical context you're aware of but it's not.
Jared: it doesn't really factor into the game, right?
Scott: But I'm you're not gonna pick.
Scott: you're not gonna pick the axis in axis and allies and just say yeah We're not attacking.
Scott: I'm just not I'm just sitting still.
Luke: Yeah Please take the concentration camps.
Scott: Yeah, you just it's backed like his new infantry.
Scott: it's made of Jews.
Scott: they rose up.
Scott: there we go.
Luke: It's just different.
Luke: It's it's a different quality of experience because the game is Opening up this other space now saying hey think about this from this perspective make decisions from this perspective When but also that the quality of the mechanics are very very different from a role-playing game to a Boardgame.
Luke: and as Jared talked about it like you're right you're manipulating pieces and resources and and betting on randomization Gambling essentially in a board game.
Luke: when Jared and I made free market We went through a lot of iterations of the the card mechanics in the game.
Luke: Yeah, card based role-playing game.
Luke: and at one point Jared was like yeah, I don't know Can we tighten this down you know because it's a little it was a little loosey-goosey at that point and We did we.
Luke: we spent a weekend and we really ratcheted down the card based mechanics to where it was this very intense Card game and had a crazy like it had a weird Mechanic where you didn't see.
Jared: some people could see your cards and then some cards were hidden.
Jared: and right.
Jared: is that what you're yeah?
Jared: Yeah, it was really like.
Jared: it was a crazy cool like.
Jared: it was totally like memoir Inspired actually because you had certain resources that you were privy to that your opponents weren't in certain.
Jared: Oh, yeah, resources that they knew about.
Jared: that you didn't.
Jared: it was really weird.
Luke: Yeah, you had to show your opponent's cards that you couldn't see and stuff like that.
Luke: What happened there is it became a card game.
Luke: It was a cool card game But it stopped being a role-playing game.
Luke: it became like the decision-making for the card and tactical element became so intense That we stopped talking in funny voices and making important Ethical decisions.
Luke: in the game.
Jared: it was the equivalent of that that tower defense game where you only build that one tower because it supersedes everything Else.
Jared: it's the same idea.
Jared: It's it's.
Jared: why would I roleplay when none of that matters?
Jared: All that matters is I you know get four points more than my opponent and that's what I'm concentrating on.
Jared: That's what I'm putting all my effort and energy into right and the role-playing game game Just kind of falls apart, and you just don't think about it because it doesn't really matter.
Luke: I mean I'm actually really bad at RTS games like Starcraft whatever because I try to make a story out of them.
Luke: as I play I try to have kind of a Complete narrative.
Luke: I like you know I like there to be a beginning middle and end to the whole game.
Luke: And I'm so poor for I I'm that's it's too much for me.
Luke: I'm also.
Luke: I love the idea of dwarf fortress.
Luke: I'm just not capable.
Jared: Loose mind hasn't cracked.
Luke: but also in memoir and Commanding colors I played recently the basis of memoir.
Luke: I have I have the same instinct But I've actually gotten good at playing memoir because I can understand the the the games a little bit.
Luke: You know it's easier.
Luke: There's basically less less complexity than like Starcraft or an RTS whatever, but so in memoir like I Can play for points even though I want my army to win even though I want this unit to survive.
Luke: You know I want to keep my battle lines neat.
Luke: You know I want to.
Luke: I want to run my tanks behind you and be like true I want all these things to happen, but I know the way to win is to score points right.
Luke: and so I've You know learned through Ten or twenty years of hard lessons that I should just win the game And stop goofing off.
Luke: I played risk a couple years ago.
Luke: We were in Boston.
Luke: It was one of my very best friends in the whole world.
Luke: He loves risk.
Luke: He absolutely loves it, and he was winning.
Luke: And he was having a good time winning.
Luke: and he.
Scott: everyone else was not having a good day.
Luke: Everybody else was out and watching right nobody else having a good time.
Luke: I was still in the game I think.
Luke: hold up in Australia.
Luke: I was holed up in Australia, and I think my friend was holed up even like it If you can be.
Luke: but he was a holed up in in South America - you can do that yeah, so and you know my friend was just like you know cashing in the cards And he was just like dumping units all over the board.
Luke: and we're like what the hell you doing man.
Jared: He could win immediately.
Luke: He had us walled in.
Luke: we couldn't go anywhere And he's just.
Luke: he's just playing and like picking at us or whatever and getting cards get my armies into the triple digits Right and just like.
Luke: and we're like dude We gotta get mad at him.
Luke: We're like what the hell he's like.
Luke: We're like just attack because we can't get out or anything.
Luke: He's just like no no no He just would not win and in the game nothing in the game and forced him like to take the winning move like nothing like.
Luke: There was no balancing mechanic.
Luke: No nothing going on.
Luke: There's no.
Jared: once you have this many troops on the board you win.
Luke: Yeah, yeah, no endgame mechanic nothing.
Luke: It would just pure hate and frustration talk about that a lot.
Scott: the games are that are over when they're not over.
Scott: Yeah, it's like we played Chicago Express.
Scott: We just did a show.
Rym: I was mathematically eliminated from victory two turns in right.
Scott: this is a train game called age of steam and the way age of steam Works is every turn.
Scott: it beats the crap out of you.
Scott: It takes all your money.
Scott: So if you're not doing well enough to win like you're after like three turns.
Scott: It's like you're out.
Scott: leave you're done You can't.
Jared: you're not even in it and the game tells you to leave right here.
Scott: You just stop playing and the game tells you to stop playing, but Chicago Express leave implicitly when someone flips the board over.
Scott: But you know the the Chicago Express.
Scott: we were mathematically eliminated from victory.
Scott: the only thing we could have done to maybe you know The only thing that matters in the end is how much money you have.
Scott: right and the only way to get more money is to More shares, but if anyone bought a share that would have ended the game And we already had a guy who was way ahead so he would have won.
Scott: But if we don't buy a share he would have continued to get more money.
Scott: So it's like and a share costs money.
Rym: so someone's got to take one for the team and end the game and guarantee loss.
Scott: Yeah so otherwise you just keep playing and there's a lot of games role-playing and otherwise.
Scott: where there is there's a victory condition and that Victory condition is somehow set like we already know who's gonna win.
Scott: right there is no changing that.
Scott: But that victory condition actually reaching it is some way in the future and at the present time we already know you know Our destiny.
Scott: it is it is locked in stone But the game isn't over because the victory condition is poor.
Rym: Is that a problem in a role-playing game?
Rym: because you can play out the scenario and try to make decisions as to like how the bad Ending or good anything is gonna roll out.
Jared: well there there are.
Jared: I mean there are games that that start off the bat saying You're gonna die Mmm.
Jared: It doesn't matter your life's a joke.
Jared: Now what I mean right off the bat?
Jared: character creation, how are you gonna die what's gonna happen to you and
Rym: How your character will die on the sheet at creation,
Scott: but 2001
Jared: schism yes
Scott: to say it a different way I guess it's that there might be a game that has meaningful decisions and at a certain point before the game is over you are You're.
Scott: there are no more meaningful decisions that can be made.
Jared: You know you can role-playing game though There's always a meaningful decision.
Luke: That's not true.
Luke: necessarily like it.
Luke: burning wheel has a problem where it like a fight can reach a point where they're very Like.
Luke: there's really no meaningful decisions like and I'm not saying a fight.
Jared: I'm saying a game.
Jared: I'm saying an actual game, but it's In the.
Luke: in the process of this mechanic you reach the point where you just need to end the fight.
Luke: true And make sure and the instructions running wheel are lacking.
Luke: in this case We fix that in the new book, but the where they're like the game doesn't come out and say hey Hey dumbass just stop and move on like right Which?
Luke: Because I made an assumption that it's a role-playing game.
Luke: You'll figure this out.
Luke: That's what you do you you you are talking to each other as players, and you know okay?
Luke: Well this we're done with this we move on but the actual procedural instructions Don't tell you that's that I mean in free market.
Jared: We have a specific action which is and the challenge Right that's it's.
Luke: I think it's to solve some of that, but it's really interesting though because the end the challenge can some.
Luke: It's kind it's it's almost broken.
Luke: the end the challenge mechanic because It can be a foregone conclusion who's gonna win who's gonna lose?
Luke: I can force the decision onto your shoulders.
Luke: if you're losing I can say here go ahead you can take an action a futile action or You can end the challenge.
Scott: you know what I just realized.
Scott: you're explaining His way.
Scott: this might seem like it's out of nowhere, but this is gonna make sense.
Scott: you're explaining the rules of roller derby to me.
Scott: The last time we were at ConnectiCon eating right and you told me that the per the first jammer that passes through gets to Choose when it's over mm-hmm.
Scott: all right.
Scott: It's like the same thing.
Scott: It's like you know you're.
Scott: you're in this position.
Scott: You can choose to end it at any time.
Jared: Yeah, I mean the.
Jared: the jam will end at two minutes regardless, but they can end it early right.
Luke: That's a huge tactical decision right.
Luke: There's a double.
Luke: It's double jeopardy.
Luke: right you have two minutes or Up until this certain condition and free market it you know.
Luke: so you can choose not to end it And if you don't well, then I get the choice I can continue on you know and choose to end it or push.
Luke: Yeah, I don't know.
Luke: It's it's it's interesting It's a whole other discussion.
Luke: you know that you guys talk about it in your panels.
Rym: But right and conditions essentially for a game win conditions Actually because you brought it up and burning will we have?
Rym: actually this very distinct problem has occurred in every game.
Rym: We played today with duels of wits always ending in a tie to the point that it gets frustrated.
Rym: Really, they always end in a time.
Luke: I think it's my guy just going point point point point.
Scott: no What happens a lot is people don't have very powerful?
Scott: Dueling skills often, so what will happen is they'll they'll chisel down and maybe defend a little bit.
Scott: It's down to the wire, and then they'll always go over on the same action.
Scott: We could I mean if we looked at negatives like maybe one person would be negative three and one would be negative one.
Luke: There's a reason why that doesn't count.
Luke: it's still a tie.
Luke: so why isn't somebody just rebutting then at that point and winning?
Luke: How are like you guys?
Scott: just like showing you Don't have people don't have a lot of.
Rym: There is a hive mind and we know each other well and also The first time we ever played burning wheels the three of us And we you show us how to combat work.
Rym: and there are duel of wits.
Rym: first round Second round we all point.
Rym: third round.
Rym: We all okay.
Jared: Let's see some rock-paper-scissors right now ready.
Jared: one two three oh Scott once that's right.
Scott: I won.
Scott: I don't know I Rym didn't do the fistful of dollars because you expect me to do the fistful.
Luke: So how do you do the fistful of dollars?
Scott: rock rock paper?
Scott: Oh, no is it rock?
Scott: two papers or two rocks, and then a paper full of dollars.
Scott: Yeah All right, so you do you do rock and then you on the second round the second go you do rock again And then in the third go you do paper, but you only did one go.
Scott: well Yeah, but we did three goes it would have been two rocks and then a paper.
Jared: I see so it's kind of a Emerging predetermined.
Scott: you know that was
Rym: a media virus that was like infected into the group by Luke
Scott: Different Luke
Jared: I was speaking of I just lost the game, okay?
Rym: I mean you play World of Warcraft.
Scott: you just admitted you're on 4chan a lot.
Rym: I mean the game is the fortune Dude.
Scott: 4chan the game that will sell free market.
Luke: Jared's actually working on YouTube the game.
Luke: come on don't tell people.
Luke: come on come on come on Spur.
Luke: you like a mule like a rented mule.
Jared: take me and I'll be like action castle.
Jared: three years.
Jared: I'll have it done.
Jared: I upload the video, and then I'll complain about it.
Scott: video is uploading.
Scott: please wait.
Scott: And if you're at my house at Time Warner, please wait even more.
Scott: yeah wait till tomorrow.
Scott: You making YouTube the game.
Scott: are you really making YouTube the game?
Jared: Yes, I want to talk about it.
Scott: Is he stuck?
Scott: wait wait.
Scott: So is it so like you don't want to talk about?
Jared: I want to talk about done like Google.
Scott: no comment for Google Cuz.
Scott: I mean you know all right here.
Scott: I'll say this we were at recess to reset the big double recess and someone actually brought eBay the game And it was like this electronic game with cards, and I was surprised.
Scott: It was actually a good game like you know.
Scott: so if you made if you were to make YouTube the game Which you're not commenting on.
Scott: you could make it, and it's actually possible for that to be an awesome game.
Jared: It is very possible.
Jared: It is extremely possible.
Luke: You can really make a game out of anything.
Jared: You can make a game out of anything.
Jared: We had guys that have one of our seminars do a tattoo game.
Jared: Oh Being at a tattoo shop.
Rym: I thought it was a game where you have to collect tattoos.
Luke: It could be that but they chose.
Luke: they ultimately chose you had to draw tattoos and put them on people.
Luke: yeah Tattoo artists keep a portfolio of tattoos or something.
Luke: I don't know.
Luke: the game is called like slut mark or something tramp stamp tramp stamp Slut mark.
Jared: that's my game.
Scott: That's the 4chan remix.
Rym: that's Jersey Shore.
Jared: the game punch Snooki in the head the RPG.
Jared: It's got trust mechanics.
Rym: so Obviously we all dogs in the vineyard hack what we like about role-playing games and we try to get people to play these games.
Rym: and a Lot of people just only know about D&D and just play D&D.
Rym: How do you trick someone into playing a different game other than going to one of our panels?
Rym: Are you like grabbing them at a convention and tricking them into playing with you?
Luke: Well people are.
Luke: I found it.
Luke: conventions are usually pretty open-minded.
Luke: They'll like they'll definitely do.
Luke: they sit down and yeah I'll give this a try.
Jared: yeah, even the people who really don't want to play will still say yes It's alright.
Scott: So so I think more a more direct question that would be more helpful is a lot of people out there.
Scott: They've got a group of gamers already and maybe they hear us and they they're excited about whatever game And they want to switch their people over to.
Scott: this should right.
Scott: But they can't convince their part their group of people who have been playing D&D or playing something else To play something else instead.
Scott: They can't even convince them to try it.
Luke: There's a I mean, there's kind of two sides to this and there's.
Luke: there's a lot of bad behavior that goes on.
Luke: one You can't like you can't burn the books.
Luke: You can't throw a tantrum You can't you know move and that you know.
Luke: and the other players they can't just sit there and be like nope No, no, you know, you got to kind of ask politely and say hey, you know this week I'd like to try this one thing and you have to make it as
Jared: low
Luke: commitment as Possible this one week for two hours.
Luke: We're gonna play this other game and you guys are gonna actually give it an honest try.
Luke: Okay, really?
Luke: Okay, please.
Luke: I'll bring chocolate like right like bribe chocolate.
Luke: Yeah, I didn't.
Luke: So donuts.
Jared: so the problem the problem with the one of the problems with role-playing games is there's this Right off the bat huge like the idea in your brain when you hear role-playing game is at least the classic model is Role-playing game.
Jared: we're going to be playing this for seven years.
Jared: everybody Grab a lunch.
Luke: Hell, yeah.
Jared: And when you really need to do is just make some characters throw them down and say, okay We're gonna do one thing We're gonna do one cool thing in this game that this game does well.
Jared: That's what I'm needs to show you the game.
Jared: I mean when Luke does his demos.
Jared: He's not running a five-year burning wheel epic campaign for these people.
Jared: He's doing sadly.
Jared: No a Scenario, which is essentially.
Jared: it's usually a situation.
Jared: There's something going on.
Luke: There's something wrong.
Scott: Inception, right?
Scott: What did they say?
Scott: It's like five times, right?
Scott: We go like two levels down and run like six campaigns and come back except be like a minute.
Luke: That would be amazing except that doesn't actually happen.
Jared: I know it sucks Mm-hmm That's why you have the sword.
Jared: You have felons rift.
Jared: It's like okay Here's the situation.
Jared: go and you play it and you're done, and it's satisfying.
Luke: well I mean one of the great things about contemporary small press role-playing games.
Luke: They're so low commitment like you can grab inspectors or lacuna And that's that's.
Jared: that's one of the whole Hallmarks of the the genre because it's pretty much a genre over the past 10 years is you'll learn it that you'll learn the rules Tonight and you'll play it in two to four hours, and it'll be a fun story.
Luke: I mean it's just one thing that you kind of have to acknowledge is that people play role-playing games for a lot of different reasons.
Luke: there's a lot of different ways to to have fun playing a role-playing game and Roll.
Luke: each role-playing game brings a different kind of fun to the table.
Luke: I mean or focuses on a different kind of fun.
Luke: You know obviously people who have different priorities can play the same game and still have fun within certain tolerances, right?
Luke: Not everyone plays D&D for the same reason, but a lot of groups can get together and and agree We'll play D&D.
Luke: It's cool even though It supports more this style play than the style than this other style of play.
Luke: So one you have to agree when you're starting a new game, that's try something different, but also you have to recognize that there People's like emotional fun is wrapped up in this and so there's gonna be some reticence to try something new some some skepticism and you're kind of fighting against a long history.
Luke: because The how we have fun is we sit down and we play riffs every week, and that's it like we.
Luke: there's no other game There's no other like hey still play riffs.
Luke: Oh hell.
Luke: Yeah.
Jared: What's like the poker game right?
Jared: Nobody says hey guys instead of poker this week Everybody you know looks at you like you have three heads.
Luke: Yeah, let's play jungle speed instead of poker.
Rym: They're like jungle speed is a much better game.
Jared: Yeah Certainly dude, let's jungle speed jungle speed jungle speed be a lot more interesting with betting.
Scott: Let me tell you dude Especially if you put the money near the Scott thought he broke jungle speed because we're playing together.
Rym: He just holds his hand like around the thing.
Rym: He's like what are you gonna do?
Rym: I'll grab it no matter what.
Rym: so he goes to the guy like the guy who's demoing the game at PAX and the guy's like All right, show me your trick.
Rym: and Scott's like yeah, what are you gonna do?
Rym: I think I just punches his hand.
Jared: Yep That's like jungle speed 101. come on 101.
Scott: we needed it to get going.
Jared: what you do is you bore out the totem and you start stuffing dollar.
Jared: You have a wooden totem.
Scott: Oh, yeah I'll trade you my plastic.
Scott: It's not even solid.
Luke: it's like yeah, it's like a dog toy.
Jared: Yes.
Jared: My totem is stained with blood.
Scott: Can I see your totem so that I can like make my own?
Jared: That's what she said, yeah, that's my screen name.
Scott: your screen name is can I make it?
Scott: can I see your totem?
Luke: Can I Can I see your totem anyway to get back on track here?
Luke: So that's a great example.
Luke: is you know sitting down for poker night and saying hey, let's play jungle speed?
Luke: You know, you're basically offering that much of a culture clash to people.
Jared: So you're upsetting their their their boat that they've been paddling in for a while, right?
Luke: You know most people play role-playing games.
Luke: I think want to sit down and play the same character.
Luke: Most people who play role-playing games don't want us don't think about playing role-playing games Like they think about playing a board game.
Luke: right playing a board game.
Luke: Okay, how am I gonna expand?
Luke: kind of win this?
Luke: how am I gonna get into these mechanics and and Win the game.
Luke: you don't think about a role-playing game as a set of mechanics.
Luke: You think about a role-playing game as a setting and a character and the stuff that comes Behind.
Luke: it is a pain in the ass that gets in the way of you Exploring the setting and playing your character, which is completely and utterly fucking wrong Since the rules are the setting.
Luke: there's nothing else in a role-playing game, but the rules and the.
Luke: the rules create the setting.
Luke: No matter what the Annie's say There's nothing else in a game but rules nothing.
Jared: games are rules.
Jared: games are instructions.
Luke: you cannot have a game without rules.
Jared: Sorry, but what about flux Luke?
Jared: that has no rules.
Jared: But what about flux Example?
Scott: I mean, yeah, they just say they just say what about.
Rym: but junker most people don't know how to argue.
Luke: This is also true.
Jared: Just yell louder than everybody else.
Jared: right most are typing caps.
Jared: We make arguing the game.
Scott: That would be good.
Scott: Well internet arguing the game BBB the game are also bad at following instructions, too.
Luke: So that that's another thing to acknowledge.
Luke: when you're you sit down with a new game You kind of want to make it as easy as possible.
Luke: You are essentially the ambassador for a fun time when you sit down with a new game with your friends But I actually wrote a whole chapter on.
Luke: this is my new book for the burning wheel for the inventor burner is like hey You know you you've got to be cool and everything.
Luke: But honestly the main responsibility in this is on the group.
Luke: if someone in the group is is Sucking it up and playing rifts or D&D or whatever Every week and they're not having a great time wants to try something different.
Luke: You know what you're.
Luke: all friends Say okay, we'll try your game this week We'll try it and we'll give it our best shot.
Luke: the thing that drives me crazy is the is the passive-aggressive.
Luke: You know we'll try this and and the arms folded Already decided before you started.
Luke: Yeah, and they just sit there for a couple hours.
Luke: being like this is stupid.
Luke: What the fuck?
Luke: how hard is it for you to open up and you know what and say you're my friend?
Luke: I'm gonna make sure this is fun for you.
Rym: I don't think they're really friends.
Scott: I don't think they're.
Rym: yeah I think a lot of these people who have these gaming groups and all these like all the drama like every time we do a It's the person who happens to live close enough to you geographically that also wants to play.
Scott: it's always high school kids.
Jared: again You feel bad about kicking people out Like they know.
Rym: like like those are the other five guys.
Scott: It's so difficult to even get this many nerds into a single room in the middle of nowhere.
Scott: I mean that to lose that is like we got nothing.
Scott: You know it's either this or nothing.
Luke: fuck What's up with the disconnect between?
Luke: What you two and we to see once a month where thousands upon thousands of these nerds are getting together Hanging out at these cons?
Luke: right we know there's this giant nerd underground.
Scott: because well, okay.
Scott: So first of all we're in a city where there's a lot of nerds.
Rym: Yeah, we're a beacon when you're if it weren't for the fact that we brought our own crew with us to beacon There's no gamers there.
Scott: Yeah, and the second we gotta find him.
Rym: Yeah, we found it and I think four of them 40 they wanted to play war games.
Scott: right.
Scott: so the other thing is that you know the Conventions are this one-time thing that gather from a greater geographic area there, maybe that's why conventions exist.
Scott: Yeah, they're dry exactly.
Scott: there may be thousands there, but you got to realize that any one of those people goes home to their town.
Scott: They're probably a teenager with no car and the number of people that they actually have to game with on a regular basis is like Four if they're lucky, but at a convention It's.
Rym: it's always gonna make a much simpler point.
Rym: every time there's a panel that I'm involved with in any way There's something like how do you a GM or like tell your stories or like you know tell us what's wrong with your game?
Rym: And we'll fix it.
Rym: It's never about the game.
Rym: It's always just this personal crazy bullshit.
Rym: drama is nothing to do with gaming.
Rym: that seems to be in everyone else's lives, but ours.
Luke: yes Yeah, I don't understand.
Luke: It's like.
Luke: well.
Luke: I don't know.
Luke: I guess we have personal drama in our games.
Luke: I've had my friends storm out of my apartment being like I'm not fucking playing a game with you again.
Jared: Sure Luke will never let me play burning wheel.
Luke: no Jen Jared and Jared isn't and I are never playing burning wheel together.
Luke: Yeah, I'll run burning wheel for Jared.
Luke: That's fine.
Scott: Yeah burning wheel for me because a pain in the ass to Luke.
Jared: Luke put out his welcome mat, and I might have shat upon it.
Jared: shat upon it not not intentionally.
Rym: You're like you see the sword.
Jared: I defecate no the sword.
Jared: I played and I really liked it.
Jared: I played the elf.
Jared: it was awesome.
Scott: Yeah, the elf is a good choice.
Scott: the human is the only one.
Rym: Was my last choice?
Rym: oh really Yeah, the elf is tricky because I feel like the elf.
Rym: you feel like you can kick everyone else's asses, and that is not true.
Luke: That's like.
Rym: the best part about the scenario is that the elf always tries like just I'll kill the dwarf and it'll be great.
Jared: And then he's like I'm an elf you're all fucked.
Scott: The reason I like all of them except the human because it feels like the human.
Scott: It's hard for him to make a friend because he just he just wants to steal it for his personal reasons Right and so he could try to be friend.
Scott: the elf for the dwarf right - right But and he can't afford to pay the rat.
Scott: no one can afford to pay the rat.
Scott: So he's sort of on his own there, and he's just a jerk But he's not strong enough to actually do anything as any one of the other characters can probably kick his ass.
Rym: Oh, he's a jerk.
Rym: You just always play him as a jerk.
Scott: I think the human is a jerk.
Jared: well They all want to see the sword.
Jared: He just doesn't have this like family legacy to like back it up He has no.
Jared: no it's like, but I just want it every.
Luke: no no he has to repay a gambling debt.
Luke: He has no nobility to his claim.
Luke: right, right, it's very So.
Rym: you gotta be a noble or you're a jerk.
Scott: no, it's not being a noble.
Scott: is that his?
Scott: He only wants the sword for selfish reasons.
Scott: He doesn't.
Scott: you know he doesn't even have the illusion that they all want the sword for self But they have the illusion of a valid reason.
Scott: Loud the human has nothing he can say out loud.
Scott: He can make.
Scott: that is truthful.
Jared: well for my wife, right?
Scott: Lying jerk right there's nothing truthful that he can say.
Scott: that would be a valid External claim for the sword that anyone else would.
Rym: is you know the dwarf and say we can take these assholes.
Rym: Let's go.
Rym: That's what you do.
Scott: Yeah, but then the dwarf is on you after you take out the elf the.
Luke: so well I'll grant Scott this the human is the hardest Character to win with.
Rym: so hold me the rat was the hardest one to win.
Luke: No.
Luke: I changed my mind.
Luke: I actually that I After further analysis of the sword the human is the hardest to win with the human wins the least and often because.
Luke: Well I think one because of the reasons that Scott is is pointing out that he you know he he it's hard for a player to sit down and jump in and make him sympathetic or And he's not powerful enough like the dwarf who just come out and be like fuck you all.
Luke: I'm gonna Just do it the rat it turns out.
Luke: I Just take on all the other characters and beat them down.
Jared: the rat at uh at packs Oh my god was it.
Jared: packs packs.
Jared: Easter packs packs packs packs packs.
Jared: Oh my god.
Luke: Yeah, dude crazy crazy, but the best actually the best Robard the best cute gambler.
Luke: I saw was at PAX Prime to where the kid Had used his falsetto shit.
Luke: Yeah had everyone coming and going.
Luke: he's.
Jared: he did the forgery right.
Jared: he had the forged coins.
Luke: Yeah, he made an unskilled.
Scott: He paid the rat with fake money.
Scott: Yeah, he clipped.
Jared: he clipped the coins.
Jared: It was awesome.
Luke: And then but he's.
Luke: and he got.
Luke: and then he he paid the rat with fake money and then used his falsetto abilities to Convince the rat that it was the dwarf that did it because of the dwarfs greed.
Luke: And there it's perfect as the rat is a low will he was a perfect mark for the scam.
Luke: and then the rat who is a Badass bad as a knife.
Jared: when house The dwarf ended up running off into the caverns, and we never saw me again because we had to end the game.
Jared: But it was like okay the dwarf kind of got away Lost in the caverns.
Scott: hungry Story I have is when I did the circles as the rat and I got more rats You know, but that was you know, I guess that's a little bit better with the forgery.
Scott: That's that's clever.
Luke: Yeah, he's a combo attack.
Jared: That was a kick-ass game.
Jared: That was like everybody was just bringing it.
Luke: That was really fun.
Luke: But yeah, the I have seen I think the human wins the least out of everyone in the sword.
Luke: So if you're listening to this and you're burning will player and you have won with the human if you have played the sword And Robard has come out on top.
Luke: I want to hear about it.
Scott: Mmm.
Jared: Give yourself a round of applause.
Luke: burning We'll burning wheel.
Scott: calm you get.
Scott: you should get a. you should be rewarded for winning with.
Luke: if you and if you're an experienced Pretty well player and you've played the sword and you've won with the dwarf Play again and play with the human play with Robard because the dwarfs the easiest to win with because the dwarf can just take on like nightmare level.
Scott: Thing is I've seen the dwarf get dwarf get freaking stabbed, you know, pretty bad by the elf, you know He's not all you know, he's the strongest but he's not always gonna know.
Luke: I mean everything.
Luke: every character in burning wheel is vulnerable and which I love about the game.
Luke: Well, you know they can all be brought down but just in the burning wheel.
Jared: Everyone has a groin.
Jared: That's what Luke's trying to say.
Scott: I Have a specific burning wheel question.
Scott: Do the dwarven females?
Scott: because there is a. there is a question.
Scott: Yeah, it says in the in the character burner dwarven trait bearded.
Luke: So do the female dwarves have beards cannot play a female dwarf from burning wheel.
Scott: You can't.
Jared: oh, oh, yeah, it's there's no life path.
Luke: You cannot play a female dwarf from burning wheel.
Jared: We're wrong this is?
Rym: we just assume that men and women were all bearded.
Luke: Well, I mean you can be a bearded women.
Jared: and this this came up at the at the the.
Luke: yeah We were joking about a company.
Luke: No, the series.
Luke: All right, then a serious answer is dwarfs have a conservative society to the point of fascism and you can only.
Luke: The only dwarves in matter are male dwarfs.
Luke: essentially in dwarven society doors are assholes, they're giant greedy assholes.
Rym: They're not that giant.
Luke: Well, I mean I ride there.
Luke: They're meta asshole.
Luke: property is giant.
Luke: I'm sure a dwarven asshole is quite giant.
Jared: We just lost the Poughkeepsie.
Jared: I Was thinking somewhere in the Midwest.
Luke: that's like the kids.
Luke: he's right upstate.
Luke: Yeah, that's.
Luke: I've been to the Polish men's club up there.
Jared: I'm sure you have.
Jared: They have China's holes the Polish men's club.
Scott: They like to.
Scott: they like to play role-playing.
Luke: I was some rock and roll.
Scott: Okay.
Jared: Oh I remember when you went to that show.
Jared: It's a jay-zoo, right?
Rym: So, yeah, I suppose we can wrap this up But I guess now's the time.
Rym: what games should people out there be playing?
Rym: because people always come to us?
Rym: now You know because we talk about burning wheel a lot.
Rym: We play burning wheel we do the panels and they come back and they're like I played burning wheel and I played inspectors.
Rym: What should I play now?
Luke: Well, if you saw inception and you want a legitimate inception experience one of my favorite role-playing games ever happens to be by the guy Who's sitting next to me?
Luke: I know I'm a big suck-up.
Luke: but lacuna It's a few years old, but it's uh, it's doing well.
Luke: It's so aged very well.
Jared: Well all these Inceptions threads have been like driving sales.
Jared: It's so yeah, that's actually that and the parsley games are my best sellers by far.
Scott: I mean like I. when I first saw lacuna I bought it cuz you recommended it at the uber con.
Rym: We even did the thing like I didn't read the book.
Rym: Yeah, I tried to like follow it.
Scott: I read I read them.
Scott: I was the only one who read the book.
Scott: Alex I think also read it but I Didn't.
Scott: when I saw the book I didn't think it was a game that could be played sort of like one of those games.
Scott: That's just they make a game.
Scott: Yeah, like all right It's a game.
Scott: someone makes a game book, but you're not actually supposed to play this game.
Scott: I mean kill puppies for Satan is almost one of those, you know, it's like.
Scott: you're not actually supposed to play this.
Scott: It's just a humorous book that happens to be in the form.
Luke: You can really kill puppies.
Scott: But yeah, I know you can't.
Scott: but I thought lacuna was unplayable.
Scott: But actually we played it and it was like it was like completely the opposite.
Scott: It was extremely playable.
Scott: I was I was quite surprised.
Luke: Yeah, I mean one of the Jokes in lacuna.
Luke: Is that right?
Luke: It's an unfinished game.
Luke: Well, all role-playing games are unfinished right?
Luke: all role-playing games or you know the vast majority of them require you to make up some rules and Sit down and kind of fill in the last.
Jared: there's huge.
Jared: There's three things I can think of off the top of my head in lacuna which are not explained in the game which are Necessary to play the game.
Jared: if you don't answer those questions It's impossible to plays.
Jared: they play the game but it's.
Luke: but the part of the game is just answering those questions.
Luke: That's that's the important Aspect.
Luke: it's not that you Can't answer them or whatever you.
Luke: you will answer them and you have to answer them in order to play the game.
Rym: Somewhere I have in the archives.
Rym: I recorded the entire game that you guys played of lacuna and Wildwood.
Scott: Oh, yeah That's gotta be somewhere in the archives.
Luke: That's an ancient ass recording so more more modern like my.
Luke: my current pick from last year was kagamatsu by Daniel Luan.
Scott: Let me write that down Tell me tell me all about it.
Scott: So kagamatsu is it k a g a ma tsu.
Luke: Yeah, okay kagamatsu by Daniel Luan and Full disclosure.
Luke: I designed the cover for it after she asked me to Her other cover artist punked out The.
Jared: The cover is also nominated for a day.
Jared: No, it's not.
Luke: No, I'm not a for Dan and Jones Ward, but it is nominated for Dan and Jones Ward and it's a game about medieval Japan.
Scott: and oh, is that it?
Scott: That's it.
Scott: Wow, that's a fantastic cover.
Jared: Holy crap The book itself is really really beautiful.
Jared: Yeah,
Luke: you play women of a village that is in peril in kagamatsu and a Samurai a wandering samurai, maybe Ronan or whatever wanders into the village and you each have your own reason to try to lure him over to your side to ally with him or romance him or whatever and The.
Luke: the game is just really elegant like very simple mechanics Like and it's high concept, right?
Luke: It's a samurai romance and the.
Luke: it's got gender-bending rules.
Luke: the if you have a woman in the group She plays kagamatsu and the boys all play the women and That's a correct assumption.
Luke: It's probably a fair assumption, but it says like adventure has similar assumptions.
Luke: that is also true if it just says basically if there's an if there's an imbalance make sure that the the girl plays Plays the voice samurai, which is cool.
Luke: It's you know, it's it's.
Luke: so it's a bit of a thought experiment there it but it also It makes you conscious of the gender roles and it makes it a little less skeevy When the boys are trying to romance the girl.
Luke: in that case I mean, I can see you playing it the other way, but I like the fact that's a conceit in the game.
Luke: Yeah, the actual mechanics are very simple.
Luke: It has an endgame mechanic.
Luke: It has priorities Player priorities which are important to me as a player and a game designer.
Luke: Yeah, and it's just short.
Luke: It's just short and sweet.
Luke: And I mean, I kind of think it's the state of the art for like games.
Luke: At this point in our like history as a community of small press games producers Like this should be the bare minimum of quality that we should be producing.
Luke: They should be you know, well-designed simple You know with you know, nice mechanics that play to the concept.
Luke: I don't think we should be designing D&D over and over again and fucking that's like The human.
Luke: Oh to me that's like you've curled into a ball and are jerking off into your own mouth like Like what the fuck it's a human centipede.
Rym: I Have not seen that yet.
Luke: I'm not never going to see that.
Luke: really I can't do it.
Luke: I don't like movies like that.
Rym: I've seen each of the killer.
Scott: I don't know what I don't know you're talking about.
Luke: I have seen if I've seen each of the killer with you.
Jared: I have each of the killer.
Jared: We haven't watched it.
Scott: You have the like the fully uncensored one though I got.
Jared: I got on Netflix instant download.
Scott: I'm probably not the real.
Jared: no cuz basically oh, I've heard.
Jared: I've heard Something about swimming pool right now.
Rym: I'm talking.
Rym: Well, there's there's a pool of hot.
Jared: Yeah There's a lot of stuff.
Scott: There's a lot of stuff.
Scott: There's a lot of.
Scott: that's not even the worst movie Ebola syndrome.
Scott: That's the worst.
Scott: Ebola.
Scott: It's the worst I've seen.
Rym: the killer is the worst like direct well-done violence.
Rym: Ebola syndrome syndrome is the worst Concept that actually made it to execution.
Jared: How about a cannibal furrow?
Scott: never heard of it?
Jared: Cannibal frocks fe ro X.
Rym: I'd be surprised if that one's a classic if it could not be Ebola syndrome.
Rym: all the syndrome is.
Scott: I'll tell you about Ebola syndrome after we're done here.
Rym: Yeah, we don't want to.
Rym: that might change the demographic of the show.
Jared: Well, we don't know.
Jared: we've been talking about some interesting things.
Luke: I didn't see Valhalla rising.
Luke: I've seen.
Luke: I saw it at the IFC.
Luke: Yep.
Luke: Ah, it's like apocalypse.
Luke: Viking nice like there's.
Luke: there's even this the the the scene in the Hotel and how no apocalypse.
Luke: scald With the.
Luke: you know where the Viking is drugged out and walking around punching the mirror and there's a helicopter early.
Jared: That's awesome.
Jared: Yeah, are they playing Ride of the Valkyries or Flight of the Valkyries?
Luke: Like Whatever the big musical number in it like that with the montage or that is actually like.
Luke: it's awesome.
Luke: It's like the intro to like an inflames album or something.
Jared: The guy did that he did Bronson.
Jared: yes, and the guy Bronson is in is with Inception.
Jared: He was in the direction totally did so.
Luke: if you if you'd like the Eames character in Bronson studio audience You are sorry.
Luke: the Eames character in Inception see Bronson see Bronson.
Luke: He is the lead in Bronson, which is an interesting see Bronson.
Jared: So aside from the what was the other double feature I recommended?
Jared: Oh, I can't remember now Rafifi Topkapi if you took copy and after that more crime you do chopper and Bronson.
Jared: chopper Ron.
Scott: So we're asking for RPG recommendations and we get a few.
Scott: we're again mostly movie recommend.
Jared: Hey, you know, it's all the same It's all the same cloth.
Luke: I'm trying to think what else.
Luke: I'd say the same.
Jared: Well, I played Mouseguard.
Luke: I like my skirt a lot.
Scott: Mm-hmm We tried to play Mouseguard like once right?
Scott: It was all right.
Jared: I wanted to play Your role-playing game ever written, you know what I want to play which I haven't Mm-hmm, and I'm going to.
Jared: I'm gonna try to play at Gen Con or at least buy it because it's actually the first role-playing game I've wanted to buy in a long time.
Jared: Dungeons and dragons.
Jared: Let me tell you about Dungeons and Dragons.
Jared: It's fascinating.
Jared: It's called.
Jared: you guys know about a fiasco.
Scott: Oh, I believe that yesterday.
Jared: It was awesome.
Jared: It was well I'm not buying it then.
Scott: Okay,
Luke: we only played it once,
Scott: you know, did you
Jared: have a girl in your group?
Scott: Yeah, we had.
Scott: That's just not natural, okay, so Basically, I mean we kind of want to do a show on.
Scott: if we can make this the show on fiasco.
Luke: It would take a lot of time, but basically Didn't give the care.
Rym: like basically our people got to into the role-playing so the game went on way too long Because it was the reverse of it.
Scott: basically the game told us that the whole game should have taken two and a half hours right and By like an it was already like an hour and a half and we weren't even half done with the first act and there were Two acts right?
Scott: So we were 25% done when we should have been three quarters time play with like an egg timer or something.
Jared: Well,
Scott: the thing was is that the mechanic of the game is that you go around turns to making scenes right right and the scene and then everybody should You either establish the scene or resolve the scene right
Rym: you're establishing because that's like most people would establish that you establish the scene And then as you roleplay it out And the weird part is a lot of the scenes will end up being you just kind of monologuing or explaining.
Jared: Wow So it is one of those.
Jared: it is like the movies that it's.
Rym: yeah Or you can bring like other characters in and interact but then the other players kind of wink and nod at each other.
Rym: eventually They pick up a black dye or a white dye to tell you the scene is gonna go badly for you Or it's gonna go.
Jared: well, so it's a. sit around a table make shit up game.
Jared: Yes Okay, I don't want to get any more Morningstar.
Jared: You suck.
Rym: It is very It's very.
Rym: it is very good mechanics for building the world and building the relationship with the characters.
Rym: Well, it's very mechanics light for everything else.
Jared: The play sets are really cool.
Jared: I really like the place.
Scott: I also like the place.
Scott: that's a whole lot.
Scott: The problem was is that when we actually when it's time to do a scene We might roleplay way too much and I'm like I was like, whoa.
Scott: Okay I mean, this is awesome role-playing going on But we have to shoot to do.
Scott: we have to pick a black or a white dye and this is only supposed to take two and a half hours even work.
Rym: because because the way people role-playing Four characters are involved in this scene and the result is good and bad and vividly.
Rym: for yeah It's like it's supposed to be on the Apache skeleton in the cellar, but the Apaches are now.
Scott: Yeah, if it's my turn and it's my scene the black or white dye is supposed to say whether it's good or bad for me In terms of the conflict of the scene.
Scott: but if the scene has a Reconflict or maybe black or white actually might be a bad or good consequence for the other person.
Scott: It's not even their turn.
Scott: So it's not you're not.
Scott: I was like, is that even right?
Scott: Can we do that?
Scott: like a white dye on my turn when I'm resolving kills that kills Rym on his when it's not his turn and he's not the Spotlights not on him.
Scott: and I was like, is that right?
Scott: The book didn't really give a lot of help there.
Jared: So I'm gonna assume that you just played it wrong.
Scott: It's pie.
Scott: It's very possible very possible that we have played it wrong.
Scott: We're going to try it again for sure.
Rym: give up on things.
Scott: I mean don't count this as a review of a game that we played once and didn't even finish playing.
Jared: So because who would do that?
Luke: We got a plane we never have to us.
Scott: We got to play it more times and finish it to have an accurate assessment.
Scott: But that was.
Scott: that was just well, that's.
Scott: that was what happened the first time we played.
Jared: that's one of the games I'm interested in.
Jared: I haven't played it yet, but I'm very I'm very curious.
Scott: Yeah, just reading the book It's it's interesting and the playsets are awesome.
Jared: It looks great.
Rym: Just every individual scene.
Rym: just Let make it end quickly like get to some sort of conclusion.
Jared: That's I think that's good advice for any game for any role-playing game.
Jared: Yeah, get it done.
Scott: I think the problem is that was unnatural for our group.
Rym: our group people like to really like it in character and start act Cuz.
Rym: people are because we have some actors in the group.
Rym: So people
Jared: start actually well, there's your problem
Luke: Actors the worst role players ever.
Scott: Okay, so why don't we?
Scott: why don't we wrap this up and we'll discuss?
Scott: I guess just pimp whatever you you want to pimp You know.
Rym: for for people to spend money right now, what will make you money?
Luke: Well The adventure burner.
Luke: Oh, what's that?
Scott: What's it?
Luke: What's in that for burning wheel?
Luke: It's book five out of five books.
Rym: Are we gonna get Options and skills.
Scott: That's a definitive.
Scott: I mean when the magic burner came out, did you say that it was four of four?
Scott: or did you sit?
Luke: No, it's burning match burners four or five.
Scott: Okay, so it is.
Scott: No, that's it.
Scott: We're done.
Luke: core books.
Luke: Okay, burning will core books like folks.
Scott: All right, so blossoms are falling doesn't count.
Luke: blossoms and jihad don't come.
Luke: Serpent Sun doesn't count paths of spite, but a dark elves doesn't count, right?
Luke: So we'll do more stuff like that.
Luke: But as far as like core book mechanic stuff that's done.
Luke: so adventure burner contains adventures advice on setting up Situation or adventures in burning wheel and then commentary about a hundred and fifty pages of commentary Like basically the majority of the book majority of the book Make an audio commentary version of that or reading.
Jared: Sure.
Jared: That'd be awesome.
Scott: Yeah, cuz I mean, you know burning wheel itself doesn't really work as an audiobook so much.
Scott: But if the adventure burner would the adventure burner probably would work as an audiobook and you don't have to like go through audible.
Scott: Whatever, you know, you could just be like here.
Scott: buy the mp3 on my site.
Luke: That's cool.
Luke: Sure.
Luke: So yeah, 25 bucks.
Luke: It's got a green cover.
Luke: It has the sweetest wheel.
Jared: It's sweet.
Luke: It's a wheel of skull and skulls and weapons.
Jared: Oh Anybody.
Jared: Yeah, you gotta say I gotta say I helped Luke with the the final editing pass that we did a big party and so I Got to read the whole thing several times.
Jared: and I gotta say anybody who's interested in role-playing games should really check it out.
Jared: Anybody who bought Robin laws is a guide to good Robin's laws Game mastering book.
Jared: I can't remember the full title, but Anybody who's into that kind of stuff should should read adventure burner because it's a lot of good advice about any game Which is hilarious because I specifically wrote against that.
Luke: I made sure the instructions in the adventure.
Luke: It's very specific only for burning wheel.
Luke: I know it is not the instructions.
Luke: the adventure burner not apply to any other game.
Luke: They don't apply to mouse guard.
Luke: They don't apply to burning empires.
Luke: They don't apply.
Jared: having read it as a player else as a player with problems.
Jared: I Found it you very useful.
Scott: I found a lot of problems.
Scott: So that would help.
Scott: if you
Jared: have problems if you have a player
Luke: coming out of Gen Con Jared What?
Scott: uh, we have the part of Gen Con Two weeks on.
Jared: you should notice.
Scott: I don't we don't do that.
Rym: Remember where we do because we dropped Otakon So where we have a spot free in the schedule now.
Rym: No, we're kind of backing away from a lot of the anime cons move more toward the weather.
Scott: So you're going to Gen Con?
Luke: Gen Con is in two weeks.
Jared: Gen Con.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, all right and what are there?
Scott: what are the conventions?
Scott: are you doing?
Luke: well, hold on Jesus Christ.
Jared: Wow right over just I'm done.
Scott: Conventions on the brain.
Luke: It's convention season Facebook.
Luke: No Gen Con.
Luke: Why are we here?
Jared: Yeah, are you guys actually recording this?
Jared: or is this just elaborate puppet show?
Jared: These are just soup cans that you just modded aren't they?
Scott: Just go.
Jared: no, it's just gonna say it at Gen Con.
Jared: We got I got my parsley games.
Jared: so action castle and it's sequels all not sequels, but Additional games.
Jared: there's four of them now.
Jared: Holy crap for last year I had one.
Jared: now I have four and I'm actually selling them in the parsley bunch, which is Action castle Jungle adventure spooky manor and space station.
Jared: spooky matters.
Jared: the one No, but because I need to make my rent.
Jared: but I'm going to be selling them in like little envelopes.
Jared: so It's a bunch and it's it's I'm working on the graphic design an envelope.
Jared: We'll see how it comes out.
Jared: Yeah, you know it could suck.
Rym: You should include some parsley like dried parsley.
Jared: Yeah.
Jared: Yeah, I'm gonna do that.
Jared: and awesome idea.
Jared: I'll also have lacuna and inspectors have some heroin and heroin.
Jared: And there's what is this other game that we've been working on for three years.
Jared: so finally Finally project donut is done.
Jared: free market will launch at Gen Con.
Jared: This is excited.
Jared: I can't wait.
Rym: Oh snap Scott got to play.
Scott: Yeah, so if you if you I did play it once.
Scott: that was actually pretty great.
Scott: when we played it at recess I was I was very impressed With the with the free market if someone pre-ordered it When would they expect to get it?
Scott: then if it launches at Gen Con you're gonna mail it like when you get back from Gen.
Luke: Yeah, probably be shipping after Gen Con.
Jared: Sorry kids, but they will get a groovy patch.
Jared: We had got the patches in in there.
Jared: They're groovy.
Jared: Yeah.
Scott: Oh, it's like iron-on.
Jared: It's like a mission a little.
Jared: so you got to sew it on mission patch.
Scott: Oh snap, I have to put that in my bed.
Scott: I don't have any.
Scott: I don't do patches really.
Scott: Maybe I should start.
Rym: you should do patches.
Scott: I wish they had laptops made of cloth.
Scott: I could I could sew it on Alright.
Scott: so so for people who aren't you've never heard of free market or maybe don't know like what the deal is like can You said it's fortune the game.
Scott: We did say that that's not real.
Scott: I don't think that's enough to make anyone buy it.
Luke: No Transhumanist science fiction role-playing game in which you cooperate Donate and And friend and friend make friends and make friends.
Jared: It's not nearly as hippie-dippie as it sounds.
Luke: It's actually rather cutthroat.
Scott: It's very ruthless and Violent and Frowny face and I was violent.
Luke: well It hurts when you get a little frowny.
Scott: I didn't even see it coming and he gave me a frowny face, and I was just like So yeah, it's.
Luke: We tried we really really tried to make a science fiction role-playing game.
Luke: That's not just about pirate romance and shooting guns Pirate romance.
Luke: Yeah, I love my pirate romance too, but it's in this case the game is much more about As Jared has said many occasions time space and identity rather than Exactly.
Jared: we took a lot of the the themes.
Jared: we did a lot of research both science fiction books like Schismatrix and snow crash and Neuromancer and down out in the Magic Kingdom and Which was a huge inspiration and then also stuff like Malcolm Gladwell's books tipping point tipping point link and Books on astronomy and books on pirate utopias by a that guy can never remember his name
Luke: Pirate opens a big
Jared: enough that books insane.
Jared: We did research on Facebook.
Jared: We did research on Burning Man.
Jared: We did research on this is true.
Jared: I forgot about that physics and medicine and and It's a crazy game We did some research on space too.
Jared: Yeah.
Jared: Yeah, we did The Grange points and All sorts of stuff.
Jared: travel time from Earth to Saturn.
Luke: So yeah, so $60 for a box set.
Luke: you get chips and cards and box.
Luke: Whoa.
Jared: Oh, yeah box set.
Jared: Have you not seen the box?
Scott: I've seen it.
Scott: I'm trying to hype it up to.
Scott: So unlike burning wheel, which is a pile of books there's other there's goodies in there.
Scott: Yeah, this is kind of a trick.
Scott: It's like it's like you can bring out the box like hey guys So I'll use all those D&D people who are used to buying planescape boxes.
Scott: Like oh, yeah, this is for them.
Jared: It's basically somebody called it future planescape Which I thought was kind of funny because it's it's.
Jared: you know, the single is shaped like a doughnut too, which I don't Build.
Jared: this is you have a little social group you have your with your philosophy and your ideal Ideology and then you go and you do stuff against other groups.
Luke: It is really funny.
Luke: But yeah $60 for the box set.
Luke: It's a very pretty box set and it's also hilarious that for some reason people will pay $60 for a single Single hardback book single hardback book like road trader, but they look at our box set for $60 and they go That's too much.
Jared: Somebody said on a forum.
Jared: Oh, yeah, I'd pay 20 bucks for that.
Scott: Yeah, how much is burning?
Scott: empires bring empires gigantic hardcover?
Scott: That's like fully crazy color and awesome paper on 40 or $45, right?
Scott: So they so they understand.
Rym: what stuff is?
Scott: this comes with cards and ships, right?
Jared: It comes with five decks of cards.
Scott: I mean six decks really.
Scott: I've bought board games will not board games card games that are a single deck for like ten bucks.
Scott: I mean, what's the starter deck of Magic cards?
Jared: It's like it's like 12 bucks, right?
Scott: five decks and a book and it's an infomercial chips Free.
Scott: so on patch you got a patch will include the patch for free.
Rym: I was gonna say like a dicking or something.
Rym: It's just gonna go.
Jared: you'll get those two and there's a ShamWow and box.
Luke: We're also gonna try to get the cover illustrator out for the pre-order fulfillment, so she's gonna be sitting there Sketching in the Oh snap in the books as we're numbering them.
Scott: Usually you just get something like, you know, you know burn on Luke.
Luke: Not everyone is gonna get sketched but we're gonna try to get her out there to sketch as many of them as possible.
Luke: Mm-hmm.
Luke: So anyway, that's our.
Luke: that's enough pimping.
Luke: I think yeah.
Jared: And if anybody's uh, anybody's coming to Gen Con stop by the booth.
Jared: and we're also doing a this Thursday.
Jared: We're doing a seminar.
Luke: We're doing many seminars.
Luke: So Thursday.
Jared: We're doing inside the doughnut, which is basically a. how the hell did we make this thing?
Jared: Yeah, it's first conception about what was it gangsters and its space station Korean Korean gangsters and a space station all the way to what it is now and the pitfalls and the hurdles and the Design process.
Jared: we followed the the one that we espouse that we actually followed for this game Where we actually sat down and went wait a minute.
Jared: Are we doing what we say we do?
Scott: and mmm Yeah, I noticed that we do that a lot too.
Scott: is we'll like you're doing the how to run a panel panel and we're basically We we like do as we say don't do as we do because we didn't do anything.
Scott: we said Right.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: it's like because once you're the expert you don't need to follow these rules.
Jared: But trust me if you follow these rules that I don't follow for this game We actually went back to our core kind of guidelines and went.
Jared: Okay.
Jared: Is this is this really what we're doing?
Jared: Yeah, we actually because we were nervous We had a lot of people looking at us going.
Jared: What are you doing?
Luke: And we at one point did not really know We actually used our process that we push on people.
Rym: This is like proof that it is a good process.
Luke: Well, you'll be the judge of that.
Jared: actually Vote with your dollars.
Luke: All right with your forum post.
Scott: I'm not gonna have you like say websites are out loud.
Scott: You can just you know, we can put them.
Scott: websites.
Scott: You
Luke: can see our Gen Con schedule on burning wheel calm
Jared: and on my website memento - Maury calm
Scott: There will be linkage in whatever.
Scott: so I guess I guess we have to put this up before Gen Con.
Rym: I'm gonna put it up on Tuesday and I'm gonna cut that part out.
Rym: So when people don't know that we recorded ahead of time, that's fine.
Scott: Cuz I was like, wait a minute.
Rym: we were just recording this for rainy day And then on Tuesday, we're gonna record our show and that show is gonna be the rainy day.
Rym: We're gonna.
Rym: we're gonna talk about our failure playing fiasco.
Rym: Yeah So you can be a writer for us.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.