Rym: Hey, it's Wednesday, May 12th.
Scott: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights tonight anime that Scott fell asleep watching.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: I don't know if I discussed this, but I ordered a new laptop because the one I have I mean it's awesome.
Scott: It has served me well.
Scott: It's still pretty great, but you know it's kind of old core solo.
Scott: I guess it's more Monday stuff, but whatever the point is already a new one.
Scott: and I also ordered of course an extra power adapter and a little you know a zipper Sleeve to put it in like you do and So Lenovo is totally a cock tease.
Scott: They haven't finished putting together the laptop yet because I you know I customized all the parts got the SSD and everything But they shipped me the sleeve and the extra power adapter.
Scott: They showed up today at work.
Scott: So you know that's cool because I won't have to worry about signing it for signing for it when I'm not at home.
Scott: but The thing is right.
Scott: I take the sleeve and I put it in my laptop bag.
Scott: It sort of sticks out about a couple inches You know because this thing is like a 10.2 inch sort of widescreen, but the one the laptop.
Scott: I got is like a 12 inch Squarish screen.
Rym: see that's the trouble.
Rym: It's like it's an ultra portable technically But it's still bigger than like the tiny tiny laptops that we really like.
Rym: you know what I want is I'm willing to pay for it a crazy powerful laptop.
Rym: That is the size of a netbook.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is right, so what am I gonna do about this bag?
Scott: I can't get a new bag.
Rym: this bag is like the awesome, but you could get the bigger version of that bag.
Scott: That's too big and I'm not gonna replace this bag.
Rym: I gotta find some other bag.
Rym: gotta find some other custom place that makes bags and get them to make like.
Scott: I Don't want to get another custom bag to replace my expensive custom bag that is in perfect working or you can go ultra custom find Like a tailor.
Rym: you know someone who makes bags and be like look I want you to make me a bag for me to carry this list of items.
Rym: here are the items.
Rym: Uh-huh, you know spend like a thousand dollars and get like the perfect, okay?
Scott: And then what happens?
Scott: why I get another laptop a few years or now you have money and you do the whole thing again.
Scott: No, I'm not buying a new bag Another laptop yeah anyway So that that was your day.
Rym: that was your exciting.
Scott: that was just annoying that I put this.
Scott: you know I'm like ah fuck I can't close my bag all the way really sorta.
Rym: yep, not really a to our Wednesday thing either, but I Just bought an Xbox.
Scott: all right.
Scott: basically watch some animes on it.
Rym: I guess it's a Street Fighter 4 machine.
Scott: No, there's some other stuff.
Scott: We'll play some Tecmo Bowl.
Rym: We will we will.
Scott: we can play Castle Crashers remote.
Rym: I mean my policy is still going to be anytime.
Rym: There's a game that I could get on the Xbox that I could also get on the PC.
Rym: And if I don't care about not being able to play with Xbox people on the PC PC 100% really see.
Scott: my policy is similar.
Scott: However my policy is this I will get the game for Xbox if it is a game I want to play with controllers on the TV.
Scott: I will get the game on the PC.
Scott: What's the game?
Scott: I want to play with the mouse and a keyboard.
Rym: the thing is if I get even if I get a game on the PC I'm gonna have an HD PC That's fast enough to play my steam games.
Rym: And I got a USB.
Scott: my h2 thing is the HD PC I have is you know fast enough.
Scott: the thing is right.
Scott: take this for example, okay, so Street Fighter 4 right yeah the home theater BC can totally do it.
Scott: the thing is is The home theater PC wants to do a vertical sync at 1080, but you know 1080p at 60 Hertz.
Scott: Yeah, right the Xbox to the 1080p doesn't do 60 Hertz But it vertical sinks at a lower hurt.
Scott: right.
Rym: so just get a more powerful HD PC.
Scott: No The thing is the HD PC right.
Scott: the graphics that it makes it 60 Hertz are way better than the ones the 360 makes cuz It's so much more powerful.
Scott: But I can't get it to vertical sync at a lower hurt cuz.
Scott: then I had to get the TV to go to a lower You know vertical refresh rate, and that doesn't happen.
Rym: I'm sure you come up with something But I guess I saw.
Scott: the problem is is that it looks better when I play Street Fighter 4 on the PC But it gets a little bit air because there's no vertical sync.
Scott: and you get the scan line.
Scott: well I think the operative, but if I plan the 360 is just perfect But the graphics are less quality.
Rym: the operative point there is just that with an HD PC There's a little more fiddling involved in everything and you'll never get it just working like an Xbox will.
Rym: yeah.
Scott: The other thing is that most of the games that I can play on the TV right with the Xbox the multiplayer action is gonna Be on Xbox Live and not as much on games for Windows Live.
Rym: yeah However, you're not gonna play a Civ 5 on an Xbox.
Rym: if you'll even be on I don't think it'll be on the Xbox.
Rym: I have no idea.
Rym: Yeah supreme commanders on there.
Rym: I can't imagine how that works.
Rym: Yeah, I would never buy that for like Left 4 Dead it always all my co-workers have Left 4 Dead.
Rym: I would have played with them.
Rym: They all have it on the Xbox.
Rym: What's the fuck?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I don't know I I just can't imagine that.
Rym: But it's Wednesday, and we're not gonna review it yet because obviously it's still coming out.
Rym: But I'm watching the door our.
Rym: uh it's pretty fucking awesome.
Rym: It's all right.
Rym: I've kind of blown.
Scott: I think I finished watching Captain Harlock.
Scott: I'm now watching that 13 episode Co-production with PBS the Phoenix.
Scott: Oh Jessica Phoenix.
Scott: yeah, I forgot.
Scott: you know I just didn't watch it.
Scott: when it's I'm watching it now.
Rym: that had a good opener.
Rym: I recall like I like the opener.
Scott: yeah That's it.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I don't know Dora.
Rym: We'll do a show on it as soon as it's all out because Obviously, there's some sort of twist coming at the end like some big things gonna happen.
Scott: Watch nothing happens.
Rym: Yeah, it just kind of stops.
Scott: That'd be cool.
Rym: I don't know it.
Rym: You were right though.
Rym: one Scott predicted something.
Rym: We're not gonna spoil anything that I did not predict.
Rym: I Realized it probably like I don't know two minutes before in the course of the show.
Rym: it was revealed straight up.
Scott: I did it in like episode two.
Rym: yeah That was one of those meta predictions.
Rym: like me and Alex's D&D games He introduces the character, and I'm like that guy's clearly the whole villain for this whole campaign.
Rym: Alex wrote No, no, but there is some news.
Rym: Scott's gonna tell me that this is old news because he knew about it, but I didn't know.
Rym: I don't pay attention to Philly Wizard world or well, I guess star wizard world basically wizard world right is a you know wizard magazine Which is right?
Scott: They like they had some conventions and they reworked them and they rescheduled them.
Scott: No,
Rym: no wizard world conventions are comic conventions in the older school sense so they seem to be trying to Appeal to the demographic that goes to like SDCC in that they bring like movie actors and kind of all these Ancillary pop culture things just trying to get a bunch of bodies there.
Rym: But the majority of the bodies there other than those kind of pop culture people who get sucked in are Dudes looking for silver age fucking spider-man, and that is all they want.
Rym: they got the little rolly-wheelie bag filled with all I remember looking for the new Green Lantern.
Scott: ish shit that they love those nodes.
Rym: But the same kind of people.
Rym: they're going primarily to buy comics and pay for autographs.
Scott: Yep, so anyway the These conventions like they've kept reworking them and moving them and they close some in some cities and opened up in other cities and Whatever and they keep doing a whole bunch of stuff.
Scott: and basically their new strategy Which well, it's just not so new Rym Just discovered it recently is that they basically when there's a big comic convention in town They have their comic convention at the same day same weekend as the big one and their logic is okay.
Scott: If we just have our Scott.
Rym: we're talking about comic cons.
Rym: You could have said same bat time same bat play okay, whatever.
Scott: so you could have their their strategy here, right?
Scott: You think that's a stupid strategy.
Scott: who's gonna go to their convention?
Scott: right if there's another better bigger one in town and the thing is Okay, so let's say the newer comic-con right.
Scott: a ton of people show up for that shit Especially since it's now combined with the New York Anime Festival.
Scott: It is a mega double con alrighty.
Scott: So now if they just had it on their own weekend in New York some people would show up Maybe.
Scott: but if they have it on that weekend that bigger convention is is so big.
Scott: It's drawing people from a wider geographical area to come into New York.
Scott: those people wouldn't come into New York from Massachusetts Or Pennsylvania for the wizard con especially because there's a wizard con probably near them at some other point in maybe.
Scott: But even if not it's not a big enough con to draw from such a large area.
Scott: It pretty much only draw the Manhattan nerds right so or the New York City nerds And maybe a slight maybe some northern Jersey nerds too, right?
Scott: But if this is bigger con in town that draws this big geographical area worth of people into the city and there happens to be Another nerd con down the road that is within you know ten five ten minute walking distance They're hoping that they can actually get more people to come to their con than would otherwise Because the mega nerds will go to both cons.
Scott: now They get a few key like guests to go to their con instead of the New York comic-con or whatever.
Scott: the other Con in town happens to be in the other city that they're doing this in.
Scott: and You know I just got to go see this guest, so I'll go buy a badge to the other con also.
Rym: now I don't see this working so well at least in this New York situation because one I know we couldn't figure out.
Rym: I actually look In the map to see where the hell this thing was.
Rym: the only convention center in New York City is the Javits Which is not.
Rym: it's big.
Rym: like it's one of those convention centers that can only be used for Gigantic gigantic events and like it's the kind of thing that like the New York Auto Show is in there.
Rym: You know giant show floors Tens and tens and tens and thousands of people hundreds of thousands of people over the course of a weekend.
Rym: You know big iron big deal stuff.
Rym: Where the hell are they gonna have their comic-con?
Rym: and apparently they're like 20 blocks north of the Javits.
Scott: I thought they were like 10 15 blocks Depends on where you count the Javits.
Rym: the Javits span as many blocks But it is at like 50 something.
Rym: it's Street at Pier F uptown which isn't that far.
Rym: It's probably like a 20-minute walk.
Scott: Yeah, it's not like there's no crosstown action.
Scott: It's just straight north base.
Rym: However, it's straight north through an area of Manhattan that for those of you who aren't from New York It's basically empty.
Rym: there aren't even hobos out there, nor are there pigeons because there's nothing for the pigeons.
Scott: It's basically just a concrete walk.
Rym: There's nothing.
Rym: There's no transit.
Scott: You're lucky if there's a street vendor.
Scott: There's usually one outside the Javits.
Scott: So anime con goers generally more energetic, you know running around.
Scott: They're not going to the wizard con.
Rym: They're not going anywhere near that thing.
Rym: There's probably nothing in the world.
Scott: They might go up there.
Scott: They want to see up there comic nerd guys one at least demographically.
Rym: I don't think have that much money.
Rym: I don't know if they're gonna pay 50 bucks to get into two conventions.
Scott: It's weird I think that there's like a huge spread in terms of how much money the common people have right?
Scott: It's like you get some people.
Scott: it's like they love comics so much, but they have a very little money.
Scott: So every month they just buy spider-man for like four bucks and that's it.
Scott: And then there's the guys who are like his 20 G's give me that silver server number one.
Scott: Oh, yeah Oh shit, the quality is not high enough.
Scott: I need to trade up.
Scott: I will sell you this silver server number one and give you five thousand dollars for that mint or condition silver server number one.
Scott: Those guys those guys exist, right?
Scott: So the thing is I will pay $500 for my con badge, so it's a VIP badge so I can skip all the lines.
Rym: Yeah, they I think they both have that sort of stuff going on.
Rym: but yeah, the tricky part is without transit short of taking a cab.
Rym: a Stereotypical comic book guy now there are exceptions is fat.
Rym: a stereotypical one might be carrying a lot of comic books is not gonna make it To that other con let alone back.
Scott: They might do one site name, you know, these people are just the kind of people were diving in the bins to buy stuff.
Scott: They're not going to the panels, you know, they're not doing all the other stuff, right?
Scott: They go to one.
Scott: they hit up all the bins sad Friday.
Scott: They go to the other.
Scott: one hit all the bins Saturday and they go home.
Scott: then maybe they hit them both on Sunday You know, maybe they go home.
Rym: Who knows see now if that if Wizard World were smart I don't want to give them good ideas because I'll be pretty much straight up, you know We're in the New York comic-con New York anime festival camp at this point.
Rym: We're gonna be there at both, you know same day and everything doing a bunch of panels all the kind of stuff We usually do.
Rym: it's read expositions.
Rym: We work with them on stuff positions expositions.
Rym: So we're not going anywhere near Wizard World and I guess unless they let us in free and they send us a car or something I don't know.
Scott: Why would I go there if I were them?
Rym: I Would set up and pay for a shuttle and I'd get a dealer's table at the read-con and Basically be like but they could refuse to give them the table.
Rym: they could I don't know if they would and also the Javits Unions law rules.
Scott: They might not be allowed to have a shuttle to go to a competing event like that.
Rym: Yeah, I would set the shuttle up, you know on the public street right there.
Rym: You can do that with New York City.
Rym: I guess I would set something up have a shuttle back and forth all day.
Scott: You could probably rent the Chinatown bus.
Scott: make them do it.
Rym: and what I would do is I would offer to You know Nick Niaf, they probably wouldn't accept it.
Rym: But then I would just do it.
Rym: anyone my own anyone who comes to my con wizard con with a New York anime festival comic-con Badge gets 50% off the badge.
Rym: Hey, yeah, that's what I would do.
Scott: You basically making your it's like hey, we'll make a you know leech con.
Scott: It's like well, there's nothing this beat.
Scott: Let's just make a leech event.
Scott: It's like if there's a music concert and I have a concert that has nothing to do with them an hour before that Concert starts and I say if you got tickets to the big concert you can get into my concert for a dollar.
Rym: You know, what's funny is that this is the sort of thing that Unnamed staff at certain anime conventions we work with will say, you know Reed they always say yeah Reed's trying to destroy us.
Rym: They always try to like steal all our stuff and steal our secrets.
Rym: that the how to run, you know, poorly managed cons.
Scott: But yeah, they want your secret.
Rym: so bad the anime con staff are so afraid of Reed and yet Reed doesn't do the shady stuff.
Rym: It's wizard world doing the shade.
Scott: But wizard world is not something to be afraid of now.
Rym: because we went to Philly wizard world Let me tell you many years ago.
Rym: I walked around trying to interview people at that thing and It was amazing.
Rym: one people were afraid of the microphone like, you know I or even without the microphone.
Rym: it started hiding it because when I headed out or my press badge people would like stay away from.
Rym: But if I hit it and I just talked to a random person They seemed aghast that I had said anything to them and the only person who consented to be interviewed Basically talked at length about how they were there to buy Silver Age spider-man.
Rym: they had a list of silver age spider-man comics they needed.
Rym: they spent all day looking for them and then they went home.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: It's a different experience But yeah I'll take this opportunity to to point out that the New York anime festival comic-con is October 7th 8th and 9th Or sorry 8th 9th and 10th in New York City.
Rym: Manhattan will be there if you want to see us.
Rym: We'll be doing awesome stuff And now that we live in the city We will probably be able to hang out pretty late and not you know Any of you tried to see.
Rym: it's the New York anime festival last year might have remembered that We appeared did our panels and then like the wind.
Rym: Yep None of that anymore.
Rym: We're gonna be there all three days.
Rym: Yep Okay, so how's that anime industry doing?
Scott: Oh, it's doing just as well as it's always been doing for the past X years, which is horribly bad.
Scott: So what was it like 2002 when the anime boom was like, so this isn't animated is manga related?
Scott: So Viz has laid off 60 people.
Scott: they closed their knee.
Scott: They closed their New York branch, which is five people.
Scott: They laid off 55 people at their headquarters in San Francisco, and we've determined that they have 90 people remaining.
Scott: Right, so actually that's pretty impressive to have 90 people, right?
Scott: That's a lot of people.
Rym: What do they need those 90 people for?
Rym: is what I wonder?
Scott: yeah, I mean well I mean Viz does publish a lot of stuff, you know.
Scott: And they said ahem and this is from the animated news network.
Scott: Obviously be assured Viz media remains connected to its obligations to you.
Scott: They have no plans this time for drastic measures such as product cancellations or business line closures.
Scott: your favorite series are not going away.
Scott: So as long as they finish like 20th century boys in Bocorano, it's all good, right?
Scott: I mean you reading anything else from Viz?
Rym: What's so sad is that four kids reported I think 3.5 million dollars in losses.
Scott: Well, that's a good.
Scott: four kids mostly made their money by getting shows like, you know One piece of whatever get out on TV and butchering.
Scott: nobody's putting them on TV anymore.
Scott: So, of course, why did four kids?
Scott: I'm surprised they're still in business.
Scott: I know but what business are they doing?
Rym: What amazes me is?
Rym: All right, 3.5 million dollars in losses.
Rym: the fuck are they doing with 3.5 million dollars?
Rym: I could have made an entire company and put out an anime.
Scott: Yeah, what are they spending that money on?
Rym: I mean Well, they apparently they got 12 properties now and they're how many of those are on TV?
Rym: They're gonna put them all on TV They have a new TV block and they're basically spending all this money.
Rym: for here's my non educated non insider personal opinion Not based on anything.
Rym: I have a no secret or whatever.
Rym: I think four kids is gonna have this last gasp and then they're gone.
Scott: Yeah, I mean wasn't someone gonna buy them or something?
Rym: They said recently that they have a buyer possibly lined up or that someone expressed interest in buying them.
Rym: I think they're on the way out.
Rym: I think they're done.
Scott: Well, what?
Scott: what are?
Scott: if I you know?
Scott: I mean if I just had that the money that they lost which means that they had it and spent it right because you can't Have a loss if you didn't have the money to begin with, right?
Scott: So if I had three and a half million dollars and my and I had to basically be in the anime business I could buy one anime that was guaranteed to be a hit market.
Scott: it make it a hit and Make a profit and then I would just repeat over and over again.
Scott: And I how could I fail at that?
Scott: I know what shows are gonna be a hit.
Rym: Also.
Rym: Look at those three.
Scott: I would just buy Dora.
Rym: I win if I was running one of these, you know anime companies or manga companies which I still believe the main reason there are so many problems in this so-called industry is that By and large everyone involved in it is just terribly unprofessional Like surprisingly so.
Rym: but why do they need all these employees?
Rym: I would have the tiniest footprint ever and I would literally outsource everything, you know I'd have a shell company a couple of employees You know doing sales and all the kind of basic stuff and every time we wanted a new property We'd get it and then I would basically Contract people to translate.
Rym: if I needed to dub I'd contract people to dub.
Rym: it would be nothing.
Scott: Well, if you're five your viz right.
Scott: so viz 90 people that's what we're talking about.
Scott: Yeah, so viz does manga Okay.
Scott: So first I basically need someone to go and get the licenses to things.
Scott: But this doesn't need that because viz basically has a lock on the licenses.
Rym: You needed that get like, you know a 10 person team plus a lawyer and that's it.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So, okay, so you get the licenses which viz already has.
Scott: Yeah, you need translating you need printing you need Marketing and then you need to actually everything but marketing.
Rym: you can just contract out every time you have a new property.
Rym: There's no reason keeping people around.
Scott: quality doesn't matter.
Scott: the only thing you need quality on is like the the book cover designs and stuff like that.
Scott: so you hire what like one or two awesome designers and Everything else like.
Scott: okay.
Scott: Yes that you you should have high quality translations.
Scott: You're gonna sell the same number with or without let's be honest here, right?
Scott: And even the translations good enough.
Scott: small staff.
Rym: you keep like what like a head of translations you basically keep one or two awesome people for each division or each like part of the business process and They're the ones who oversee the contract.
Scott: you have like one HR person who's also the office manager.
Scott: Yep, and What I mean, what do you need?
Scott: an accountant?
Scott: You know, I guess you could probably run it with less than 20 people.
Scott: the whole thing I think.
Scott: so I think easily so and outsource everything else for wicked cheap like, you know You wouldn't get some interns up ends.
Rym: You might not necessarily be super profitable But I think you could have a business that may make more money than they're making because you have less employees.
Scott: 3.5 million dollars Kids is the one with three and a half million dollars.
Scott: Yeah, my biz you're getting a mixed up here.
Scott: You can't be doing that.
Rym: how much money is making though?
Scott: We don't know.
Rym: Yeah, that's the other problem.
Rym: None of these companies are public.
Scott: Yeah, well, you know, that's how it is.
Rym: So things of the day.
Rym: What do you got for me Scott?
Scott: It's basically it's just this funky animation called love and theft.
Scott: It's seven minutes long and it's just so Frickin funky and awesome and you should watch it.
Scott: probably it's it's a. it's like a much better thing if you watch it like full screen or Like on your TV full screen or something.
Scott: just because the way it is If you watch it in a little YouTube window, it won't be as quite as cool.
Scott: So it's just an animation.
Scott: It's fun I like it.
Scott: That's it.
Rym: Well, I'm glad you have something good because this isn't the best thing in the world.
Rym: but I think it's cool because I would actually like to see this.
Rym: just for the sense of scale.
Rym: a life-size bust of Ava zero one was made in Japan or is in the process of being made some amusement park near Mount Fuji and it's basically that scene where Shinji, you know sees Ava one for the first time and It's life-size, but only the top of it and I don't know.
Rym: I think that's pretty cool.
Scott: That's all right.
Scott: There's a big thing going on over there.
Scott: It's like it's weird.
Scott: It's like they can't get people to watch.
Scott: You know, it wasn't like Mike tool talking about this anime Boston.
Scott: how like.
Scott: they can't get people to like, you know watch animes.
Scott: But then again, there's like this huge Nostalgia, right?
Scott: So when they make a big life-size Gundam statue like a zillion people show up.
Rym: Yeah, if they build stuff about nobody goes to on TV to watch anything, you know, I don't know of course Is it not the same way in America?
Rym: look?
Rym: 26,000 nerds will go to Otakon including us and have an awesome time, but none of those people buy or watch.
Scott: General public goes to see the giant Gundam robot.
Scott: Yeah, but the same general public that might have memories of Gundam But they're not watching new Gundam double-o, right?
Rym: Of course Gundam double-o wasn't that good.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I didn't watch it.
Rym: I watched the first one episode.
Rym: I wasn't impressed.
Scott: I mean the thing is I watched the first one episode and it was Gundam.
Rym: I mean it was yeah, well, it's tricky because the first four episodes of any Gundam are the same thing.
Rym: Yeah, so before we get on to the main bit We got the meta moment that we forget to do every now and then.
Rym: but we're remembering now quite often book club is still cosmos The coding club is still project Dorf and I imagine will be for a while.
Rym: We're gonna be at the New York Comic Con New York Anime Festival.
Rym: We're gonna be at PAX East PAX West Connecticut, yep, Connecticut.
Rym: Okay, not much else going on right now.
Scott: That's all I got.
Scott: That's oh there's that you stream is happening.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, we should probably talking like this.
Rym: second Yeah, we're streaming the video of us doing the show live Mostly as a promotional tool.
Rym: I'll tell you straight up reason.
Scott: It's a promotional tool is because people who go to you stream Hopefully will you know see Oh GeekNights is live now and maybe some new people who don't know about us We'll find us on you stream.
Scott: That's pretty much the the idea.
Rym: Yeah It's literally just a camera from a different angle every now and then showing the studio and how we actually record the show.
Rym: So it's a lot like watching Howard Stern.
Rym: He sits there.
Rym: There's a microphone in his face.
Rym: Yep It's not exciting to watch.
Rym: so I wouldn't necessarily Recommend that you bother with it.
Rym: I guess the only thing it really has going is that one there is the chat room.
Rym: So I guess you could talk to other listeners about it if you wanted to.
Scott: in real time You also see a few minutes of stuff that doesn't make the show.
Rym: So yep, like when we stop recording and do stuff and when we try to figure out what to do the show on Usually get to see what I were to work.
Rym: That's exciting.
Rym: I guess okay right now You can see the fact that the door on the closet in the studio fell and it's kind of Hang in there.
Scott: Yeah, you pay us so much money for this apartment.
Scott: They can't even have doors that work.
Rym: Yeah well the thing is and people in apartments like this from what I can tell actually Tend to take all the fixtures out and put them in storage buy their own fancy fixtures and install them.
Rym: Mm-hmm I I'm cheap.
Rym: I didn't bother with that.
Rym: So I have the plain white generic fixtures.
Scott: Anyway, yep.
Rym: So back to the show.
Rym: We were trying to come up with something to review.
Rym: I mean Scott's watching a bunch of anime.
Rym: I'm watching a bunch but we haven't both finished in anime together recently and Dora was not done yet.
Rym: So I don't want to talk about it now.
Scott: I mean for all I know we don't want to do repeat shows.
Rym: There's a tiny chance.
Rym: It's gonna pull a gonzo
Scott: maybe but anyway, the thing is is that I said hey We should do a show cuz we watched a ton of anime back in the day, right tons We're
Rym: talking RIT days when we would you
Scott: know, you know even older than that, too but I watched a ton of anime back in the day and we really never did shows on most of it because Mostly because we haven't rewatched it.
Scott: So we barely remember it.
Scott: So there's not that much to say about them.
Scott: and at the same time You know we well basically we.
Rym: these are shows that we liked back in the day But I forgot that I had watched.
Rym: in fact, I forgot they existed because you know, I'm so hard up for anime.
Rym: now I mean, there's good anime like Dora and there's old good stuff.
Rym: I haven't finished yet like Hokuto no Ken.
Rym: But while I'm watching all of those I'll totally forget about a show like saber fucking marionette J.
Scott: I just remembered it two seconds ago.
Scott: Yeah, and don't ask me what I remember about it I remember that it's a show and it exists.
Rym: So we didn't know what did the show honor like?
Rym: Yeah, what anime?
Rym: if we both watch maybe we should show on like some anime that we haven't finished yet I don't know.
Rym: and then I was thinking about coup and then I thought about anime that we haven't watched in a long time.
Rym: and Suddenly, you know when you have a memory and you tug on that little string and suddenly you remember all these things that just weren't In your mind,
Scott: so if we only have like one minute worth of stuff to talk about any individual one of these shows Let's just remember a whole bunch of these old shows and then we can Make one show about all of them together because there's no way we're gonna rewatch all these things.
Rym: So a disclaimer We may or may not have remembered these shows as being good.
Rym: That was a long time ago.
Rym: they may not be good now, in fact I don't remember the characters names from half of these.
Rym: I don't remember hardly anything which is scary because some of them I watched Almost all the way through.
Scott: Yeah, that's scary.
Rym: Are we gonna be this way with like Hokuto no Ken 20 years from now?
Rym: No, no, no, maybe these shows really weren't that good as a result.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: What's weird is some of these shows now that I remember them were Stupidly popular at the anime club back in the RIT days.
Rym: like everyone's marathoned him everyone talked about him all the time and I don't remember shit about him.
Scott: I Barely, I remember like the barest of details about any of these things But I can still probably talk for each one about each one for a few minutes.
Rym: It's almost there's like this curve where a show that is great like you remember forever It's like at the top of your cube and then on the far end shows that are really bad like Odeon are So bad or
Scott: that you don't forget them or
Rym: shows like this is the North Star that are so bad and so good Simultaneously that they're better than good.
Rym: Like all those shows are kind of like and around this crater like in the Rym They're very high up there and memorable our.
Rym: I am like the Rym of the crater.
Rym: So the Rym of job, yeah, that was a clever joke right there you had coming out.
Rym: that was fantastic.
Rym: I think you could have made a better joke.
Rym: You should have made a goatee joke, you know Rym's craters of gaping.
Scott: It was a slam dunk Dunk.
Rym: it's so big.
Scott: I broke the Rym.
Rym: So everything around the Rym of this crater is awesome or memorable in some way most Memorable, but then in the middle are all the shows that you watch just because everyone else is watching it.
Rym: I mean, I remember this whole era of anime when like I'm trying to remember the Nate like Ravemaster and all that stuff was coming on.
Scott: that was later on.
Scott: that was like the Full Metal Panic days Yes, but those like.
Rym: Ravemaster was not a good show but Everyone was watching it.
Scott: Rave master was a kid with a big sword that looked like Final Fantasy 7 and he had this cute monster friend and like the First episode was like hey, there's something going on here and it was a little bit cute and funny.
Scott: So I watched like 10 episodes.
Scott: then at a tenth episode.
Scott: I was like, huh?
Scott: This fight has been going on for seven episodes.
Rym: That was back before we could tell that a show was just a fighting.
Scott: I didn't even realize it cuz I'm just sitting there watching these short, you know, and I was like, oh shit I got what the fuck is this show?
Rym: I mean Naruto did that to us.
Rym: I was like, this is awesome.
Scott: This is four episodes of Naruto.
Scott: awesome ninja school.
Scott: This is so hilarious But it took me like most funny ninja school ever.
Scott: It took me like ten episodes episode 13 of Naruto that fight against the guy with the big sword Ten episodes.
Scott: I've been watching one fight ever since like episode six and done with this.
Rym: Yep, so these are not obscure shows.
Rym: They're just shows that I don't know if too many people remember and I imagine it would be harder to find some of these Than it would to be finding really old really obscure.
Scott: The difficulty of finding these varies greatly.
Rym: Yes, right We got to start right up though with one that is actually as far as I can tell difficult to find.
Rym: I never actually saw it but coo.
Scott: So there's a so in the RIT anime club, right?
Scott: They had a library of VHS tapes and we have found that they are in good hands because we met.
Scott: the newest Librarian of the RIT anime club at anime bar was an anime Bostoner packs.
Scott: It was the same buildings Boston.
Scott: so we met him there and you know, we got we figured everything out with him and it's in good hands.
Scott: Scott Johnson no worries.
Scott: and Basically, you know he had like me gone through the library and watched some of these old Classic tapes that you know, basically no one knew what the hell they were.
Scott: Like you pick up a tape and it says something on it like Horace Prince of Sun and you're like what the fuck is this?
Rym: It says something about the culture of a club like that.
Rym: I mean, it's you know I see other anime clubs But I got to say the RIT anime club like the culture was there because as a freshman, you know I'd go up to the library and I'd pick up a weird tape and it says something weird on it like k?
Scott: o No one knows what it is, but I look at it.
Scott: But there's no anime news network encyclopedia to look it up either.
Rym: but the old guard like the eboard even if they didn't know what a show was and I did this when I was the president like If I saw a kid standing picks up a tape and I have no idea what the show is I'd be like I'd look at him be like, oh you should watch that.
Rym: Even if I couldn't see what the tape was and people did that to me all the time I picked up k o century beast and the librarian at the time was like, ah That's an old classic.
Rym: Nobody in this club has seen that.
Rym: you should watch it.
Rym: I don't know if you'd seen it or not.
Scott: Okay, so I found it on anime news network, right and it's called ku tui umikara.
Scott: Kita ku.
Scott: Yes, it's a movie directed by Tetsuo Imazawa, it's from the year 1993.
Rym: Wow, like that's newer than I would have guessed.
Scott: Yeah, it was.
Scott: it's hard.
Scott: They actually have a screenshot a picture from it, which is kind of amazing.
Scott: And it also seems like.
Scott: there's a movie called summer days with ku about like a kid with a kappa named ku.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Whoa 2007 movie.
Scott: I don't know if it's related to the original in any way whatsoever.
Rym: I think of the entire crew.
Rym: It's funny because you fell asleep through a lot of anime.
Scott: Well, because what happened is you'd watch one in like the lounge at night and we'd all be laying You know around watching anime and I would just fall asleep.
Rym: Yep, because I did that a couple of times.
Rym: but did you just watch ku by yourself?
Scott: because I don't think I watched it by Myself on VHS.
Rym: I did that with all the slayers OAVs back then but basically ku right.
Scott: for those of you Don't know which is probably almost all of you right?
Scott: Is this really old anime from 1993?
Scott: It's a movie.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: And basically this movie is Free willy the movie.
Scott: I'm gonna look up the year.
Scott: Free Willy was also 1993, huh?
Scott: I wonder right, but I don't know anyway.
Scott: So basically what it was about is it was his kid who finds basically the Loch Ness monster.
Scott: It's like a cute little baby Sea dinosaur.
Scott: it's got you know, like flippers in front but a long neck.
Scott: so it looks like you know One of those sea dinosaurs, you know, I'm talking about.
Scott: I forget the name of that dinosaur If any paleontologist would like to hook me up with the name of the.
Scott: you know The ocean e dinosaurs that have the flippers but the long necks right like the non-existent brontosaurus.
Scott: Anyway, it's one of those.
Scott: it's a sea monster.
Scott: He finds it when it's a baby.
Scott: I think it sort of grows up and the movie is about like setting it free.
Scott: right, you know.
Scott: And he lives, you know, he lives in a tropical island.
Scott: There's not too many people around.
Scott: he discovers it He befriends it sets it free.
Scott: the whole right guys come looking for it.
Scott: It's kind of an ET Free Willy situation and it's actually a really high quality movie.
Scott: That is pretty much completely unknown.
Scott: I remember it being like surprisingly good.
Scott: better than Free Willy, right?
Rym: I never saw Free Willy.
Scott: It's the same thing only better And I don't know where you can possibly watch this.
Scott: Good luck finding a fansub.
Scott: We're working on it.
Scott: Good luck.
Rym: We'll get it out there.
Rym: if anyone can get it out there We can do it.
Scott: the only copy that I know of is at the RIT Anime Club on the VHS tape.
Rym: We're gonna do something about that.
Rym: I got a VCR right over there.
Scott: Yes, so that's that What I remember.
Rym: let's just go right down this list.
Rym: Surprisingly, this is a bad one.
Rym: I mean, you know You all know Odean because Daryl Surratt masterfully keeps reminding everyone that that movie exists when we really should Think it's because they keep reminding everyone of Odean because of the niche.
Rym: true But I feel like we'd be better off if we just killed everyone involved who had knowledge of it and just buried it.
Rym: that was the end.
Rym: but I The only reason great digital target is not worse than Odean is because Odean is like 80 hours long.
Scott: Yeah, so great digital target.
Scott: That's another one.
Scott: We just saw it in the library We picked it up and we watched it right.
Scott: and usually when we watch stuff like, you know, there wasn't much that was bad.
Scott: You know everything tended to either be okay average good mildly entertaining, right?
Scott: There wasn't anything that we would all be like, oh god, this is terrible.
Scott: turn it off.
Rym: Plus we were watching anime kind of always like every Saturday.
Rym: We'd all get together.
Rym: We had a pile of like ten tapes.
Scott: We'd pick not even on Saturday like just turn a week.
Rym: Well Saturdays were the days we like play D&D for four hours and then we'd watch anime and then we'd watch.
Rym: we'd always watch like One show and then it'd be like two of them or like one in the morning or something.
Rym: We're like, alright That's why I was asleep during let's watch another show and no one ever remembered what that second show was.
Scott: yeah, but you know, we watch great digital target.
Scott: once is a movie and It's a sci-fi about a dude and I'm trying to go completely on memory here, right?
Scott: There was some evil Empire that had like a big tower of machinery.
Scott: that was evil and ruling the world and this guy was and he had to go Target, he was the digital target and he had to fight it and he had a friend who was like a robot torso.
Rym: He wasn't a torso the whole time.
Rym: He got.
Scott: no there was a woman.
Scott: So here's what this movie is about and I don't know what's up with the movie.
Rym: I think you see your boobs once with a guy who is like a cool kind of hip normal guy like.
Rym: well He's basically the protagonist type and a girl randomly becomes naked and just hanging out with him.
Rym: and then not too long later There's a robot who is a torso and this one arm and a face this every somehow Climbing a cliff.
Scott: that happens at the end.
Scott: Everything in the movie is really quiet and slow except the robot who actually talks more.
Rym: as far as I can help.
Rym: Nothing fucking happens in this movie and it is notable primarily for the fact that it's building up to the so-called climax.
Rym: They're gonna go fight the tower literally freeze-frame.
Rym: The freeze-frame starts to like shake and text appears that says five minutes later The signal stopped coming out of the tower and then the credits roll.
Scott: Yeah, basically the dude goes to the tower Right and they don't.
Scott: there's no cool action scene of getting into the tower fighting anything in there.
Scott: It's basically just like he goes to the tower Going to the tower.
Rym: if it was me or if it was our friend Pete or if it was Alex Maybe it was Greg.
Rym: but someone at the end said what we all felt which was what the fuck was that bullshit?
Scott: Yeah, there's basically no ending.
Scott: It's just like here's a picture of the bad guy bad guys lair.
Scott: Okay, he went and then some text scrolls by and there's a picture of some fire and they don't tell you if he lived or Died.
Scott: they don't tell it.
Scott: There's no animation.
Scott: There's no nothing.
Rym: I guess like in in our culture like In college.
Rym: great digital target was to all of us what Odine is now to the greater anime community.
Rym: Cuz we'd like.
Rym: we had all seen many of us Odine, but we had all mercifully seen these sci-fi cut Mmm cuts.
Rym: what like two hours out of that movie?
Scott: Yeah, I mean there is that there is a manga for great little target that I've seen in some places.
Rym: I have it somewhere.
Rym: Do you?
Rym: yeah, I bought it and the MD guys.
Scott: Let me see if it's up on that shelf there I'm trying to look with my eyeballs.
Scott: I think it's in a box.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Yeah, have you read it?
Scott: I mean, what's what's now?
Rym: I don't even I don't even know if I still have it.
Rym: I might have given it away possibly.
Scott: Anyway, great little target like before.
Scott: we knew about things like Odine.
Scott: like that was our go-to Example of bad anime.
Rym: Yep, of course not to be outdone by Legend of Lemmyre, which I can't remember much about it Except there were boobs all over.
Scott: Well, there's me this Legend of Lemmyre Legend of Chris Tanya and all I remember about either.
Scott: one Well sucked was that there are both really shitty Fantasy OAV slash movies, I guess I don't even remember and they were just generic fantasy crap with boobs.
Scott: That really reminded me of that, you know, big big boob fantasy art.
Scott: You see it like different conventions.
Rym: It's always like the big breasted woman straddling a sword that itself is on a snake.
Scott: With a chain mail bikini.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: That's all I remember about both of those.
Scott: My memory could be completely inaccurate But that's all I remember.
Scott: But Lemmyre and Chris Tanya.
Rym: But I think right around that time I think what had happened is we at some point saw a bastard So bastard, oh man, that's a sort of one that's like so forgotten.
Rym: But it's so fucking awesome.
Scott: It is quite awesome.
Scott: So bastard is a fantasy anime and it's one of those situations where it's like the bad guys the good guy, right?
Scott: It's like there's all kinds of evil demons and there's one evil demon who is like the fighting for the bad the good guys But he's still bad.
Scott: But he's you know on the he's fighting against all the other bad guys.
Scott: So the good guys are with him and the thing that got us immediately hooked us on bastard, right?
Scott: Besides the fact that it was called bastard and besides the fact that there are funny jokes and also the same kind of boobage you Get in Chris Tanya and Lemmyre was that every.
Scott: the name of everything was a metal reference.
Scott: Metallicana.
Scott: Yeah, Metallicana and Thraxia You know every single thing in the show was named after some 80s metal band.
Rym: It's good stuff.
Rym: And I think as I recall it's actually a good show like it's worth watching.
Scott: Yeah, so Bastard like there's a manga - I don't know how much of that if any is out in English or how hard it would Get the bastard anime.
Rym: I didn't even watch all of it.
Rym: I want I think I fell asleep.
Rym: We watched like a bit of it and then I remember watching like three like multiple.
Scott: It was epilogue episodes.
Scott: It was either an OAV or a show, but we were watching it But I only I watched less than five of them.
Rym: I think we all watched bastard.
Scott: complete collection on Amazon 1660 bucks, uh, I pay like 20 volume 1910 bucks.
Scott: So there's at least 19 volumes in English It's just not the manga.
Scott: Yeah, that's though the manga 19 volumes, but the complete collection on DVD $60 I'm pretty sure what?
Rym: BHS boxset $13, I think we watched like the crew watched the first bit of it like one tape and then like half of us watched more Individually on our own.
Rym: Mmm Bastard and berserk.
Rym: we watched both of those and then I think we were looking for more stuff Like at least 20 manga volumes out in English.
Rym: But I think we were looking for more stuff like bastard and berserk and then we got fucked by a legend of Lemnier and all That.
Scott: yeah, but you know, if I go watch the legend Lemnier today, maybe it'll be good.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I Don't think so.
Scott: I don't think so.
Rym: I have this feeling.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So we're coming up on some of the things that are remember as much.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well Goku doe I don't know.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: if you listeners let us know if you ever heard of or seen Goku doe.
Rym: It's basically it's a slayers like but everyone's jerks, especially the main character And I just remember being really really freaking funny.
Scott: Yeah, there was something like me.
Scott: I remember Goku was like a show and Like they were TV the DVDs for it were everywhere Like someone had printed a whole bunch of DVDs for it and tried to sell it and I don't think anyone bought it.
Rym: But we watched it at some point and like the early episodes are wicked funny Halfway through it looks kind of thing where the main character doesn't want to do the.
Rym: you know The magic thing where him and his brother have to combine their swords.
Scott: I don't even remember.
Scott: I remember there was a funny genie and some other father.
Rym: He's awesome.
Rym: So is the Sphinx.
Scott: Yes Yeah, there was just these funny characters.
Scott: You too doing funny stuff catchy opening and ending music.
Scott: And it was.
Scott: it was a comedic fantasy show.
Scott: That's all I remember.
Scott: But we started watching it and then we stopped watching it.
Rym: think at one point that the demon guys like Goku doe I'll make you King for your soul and he's like, can I just give you that guy's soul?
Rym: And he's like, I don't think it works that way.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: Why not?
Rym: Let's go for it.
Scott: Yeah, but it was just a show like that.
Rym: That was the show where he eats the soul.
Rym: He's just like oh, yeah.
Scott: That's why I always thought that Akamaka was from that show instead of ko beast because that's all eating and the sort of comp comedic Demonish stuff not to be confused with soul eater.
Scott: No, not at all.
Scott: but yeah, I mean Go kiddo, they printed so many DVDs.
Scott: I can't imagine.
Scott: it's gotta be cheap to get them all.
Rym: I don't remember when it came out.
Rym: I think we were watching it like circa 2004. just went to Luke's house all the time.
Rym: Remember we watch it with him and Gabby.
Scott: Yeah, someone's got to go and like resurrect that show but not like for reals.
Scott: just someone get all the DVDs Dude, put it on crunchyroll.
Rym: I'm sure people would watch it.
Scott: Maybe it is on crunchyroll.
Rym: Oh if it is I'll watch it again.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: after I finished doing is people?
Scott: I never watched that many episodes of it.
Scott: people told me that towards the end It's not funny anymore.
Scott: Yeah loses what it had.
Rym: I heard that too.
Rym: Of course, I don't know if this is obscure or not, but I think it's obscured.
Rym: now again Dragon half.
Scott: there's a manga.
Scott: Do you want to store that the story of dragon half which is probably true?
Rym: I don't.
Rym: I don't think we should because I got to research that because I don't know.
Scott: Yes, mostly just hearsay that.
Rym: so what the rumor was?
Rym: back at RIT I searched.
Rym: Okay, there was that there was a manga dragon half and the guy who made it got in trouble for some sort of perverted thing.
Rym: And then the manga stopped.
Rym: but they made an anime about it, but the anime only covers the first bit of the manga.
Scott: Yeah, but basically anime is two episodes right now.
Rym: Yeah, I Think that shows hilarious.
Scott: It is the I don't know what the manga is about.
Scott: I think at the amount heard the manga is more perverted and that doesn't surprise me with the story of the guy being perverted.
Scott: But the anime is significantly less perverted and is really hilarious even though there's only two episodes.
Scott: It's really funny.
Scott: It's about this girl whose mom's a dragon and dad or dad's the night who went to slay the dragon as a Connecticut and then Funny shit.
Rym: They got it on.
Rym: yeah dragons are all cute.
Rym: There's so many like jokes I could make about the show, but it's so short I can't spoil it for you.
Scott: Just watch it and it's got the bad guys a little slime jelly thing.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: You're good.
Rym: slime half.
Rym: There's a reference to about dragon half.
Rym: for any of you?
Rym: So old anime stuff with slayers.
Rym: So In the slayers movie in the dub they make a reference to a slime half Which is actually a reference to dragon half because there is a slime half in dragon half.
Rym: Yeah It's just great.
Rym: and watch the closing animation.
Scott: Yeah, the closing animation is the way.
Scott: neither the opening animation is bad either.
Rym: So let's go way back to before.
Rym: I was RIT.
Rym: I was an anime fan.
Scott: I already watched everything in blockbuster Except they added a tape and it was called the lens man, you know I can't even remember anything about the lens man anime other than we joked about it a lot.
Scott: So I actually read a lot of the lens min books relatively recently like a year few ago.
Rym: it was on the sci-fi channel and I watched it and all I remember is that it was sci-fi.
Rym: and then I fell asleep and I woke up and He was flying with the green guy through this crazy scene and then the movie ended and I missed I guess all the plots.
Rym: I had no idea what happened and they never showed it again.
Scott: And meanwhile Pete had the tape too, right?
Scott: So it's like we weren't alone.
Scott: like lens min was like within our group I had like multiple people who had knew about it and had it.
Rym: there was a weird point.
Scott: I had a tape around here somewhere.
Rym: Yeah, I got the tape later in my life I was at a blockbuster and I want to see the tape from where I'm sitting.
Rym: I wanted yes right over there I wanted to see it again and I was looking for it with my mom.
Rym: I had like a blockbuster sale and this anime nerd was there, you know I'd never run into an anime fan other than myself before and you know my crew of people and he was like the lens.
Rym: min is difficult to get because it were.
Rym: there was a problem with The licensing and it was pulled from the shelves.
Rym: So if you find a VHS tape is actually valuable I'm sure and I was like fuck.
Rym: so I'd forgotten about it.
Rym: and then we watched it again at RIT and I fell asleep at some point and I remember ever watching it at RIT.
Rym: I don't know if you were there But we like you like.
Scott: I remember certain things that we tried to watch them and I fell asleep.
Scott: Right, for example, like I think we tried to watch kotocha and I fell asleep.
Scott: Yep, and certain Lupin movies.
Scott: I fell asleep Yeah, but I don't remember ever trying movies are dangerous to follow.
Scott: I don't remember ever watching or falling asleep during The last.
Rym: the last time I fell asleep during a Lupin movie.
Rym: It was normally upon action.
Rym: I fall asleep I wake up and there is a brain in a rocket like a gigantic brain.
Rym: I was mama flying out into space.
Rym: Yeah Don't fall asleep during the pond movies.
Rym: I don't think you were there but I remember us watching Lensman and all I know is that I fell asleep and I woke up during the same fucking scene where he's flying with the green Guy through some crazy scene and that it ended.
Scott: and I still don't know what happened I think is why did I always wake up at the end of things miraculously somehow?
Rym: maybe because the energy of the room You know, they only those old movies always played.
Scott: that kind of early 90s synthesizer rock would have happened If everyone fell asleep during the movie.
Rym: We just wake up like four hours later static on the TV the next day.
Rym: that would have been awful.
Rym: I'm so glad that never had imagine this.
Rym: it's Sunday night where it's like 4 in the morning.
Rym: We're watching some anime and you just wake up.
Rym: You don't know what time it is.
Rym: You're probably late for class.
Scott: There's just static on the TV, you know, everyone else is still there sleeping.
Rym: You don't even remember what you watched.
Scott: No, everyone fell asleep during it.
Scott: that never happened.
Scott: No, luckily.
Rym: Yeah, but there but there but for the grace of God when we But yeah kotocha we didn't even we watched the summary movie as far as I can tell
Scott: and we fell asleep during it We thought not because it wasn't, you know I've seen a lot of clips from kotocha and it seems like it's a totally hilarious
Rym: fell asleep because it was 4 in the fucking Morning,
Scott: it's a totally hilarious silly kind of show.
Scott: I kind of actually want to go back and see if I can watch it again.
Scott: Yeah, but I fell asleep the one time we actually watched it.
Scott: So I don't remember shit.
Rym: It was like that and Kimigurri orange road and marmalade boy.
Scott: Well, those are a lot of the shojos that were fans that the people who were running the club before we got there were big Fans of those, you know those shojo series so they had them all in the library.
Scott: I never really attempted to watch them, but I think you did right.
Scott: there was like please save my earth was another one.
Rym: Oh my god, please save my.
Rym: I Both loved and hated.
Rym: please save my earth.
Rym: when I watched it like I was fascinated by it But I couldn't figure out if it was good.
Rym: Yeah, but yeah No, no one in the crew watched.
Rym: that put me back then and like marmalade boy and kor Especially we're really really popular like in the club, but I don't think they were that popular Outside of the club in America.
Scott: You don't hear anyone mentioning Kimigurri orange road or marmalade, right?
Rym: You hear more mentions of touch than you hear of those Joe Yep, except you hear about those shows in the club and among the people in our crew who like no show.
Rym: Joe Mmm, like Laura remembers all those shows.
Scott: It seems like it's like just the people that were like, you know, like Networking Lee close to us right and spread out for the right date like no those shows but no else.
Rym: Wow, you reminded me of please save my earth.
Rym: that came out of nowhere.
Rym: There was the show where.
Rym: so here's the plot of please save my earth because it's really cool idea.
Rym: Right, you got a bunch of people and they all have weird like individually have weird dreams all the time and one of them puts an ad like in the newspaper like hey, do you have dreams about this?
Rym: and Like this group of people because of this ad come together and they none of them knew each other but they all realize that they're all having the exact same dreams and the dreams involved like a future past and a base on the moon.
Rym: and You know, they do some telescoping and they see the fucking base on the moon.
Scott: So the base on the moon is giving them dreams about self.
Rym: They had a past life of some kind.
Rym: they have all these memories of it and It could just be a loose nation or something crazy.
Rym: But then they find kind of real evidence that no something really happened.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: And that is a cool premise.
Rym: I think for a show.
Rym: It goes way off the deep end from there and I have no idea.
Scott: Cool premise.
Scott: I didn't even know that and what the show was about until just now.
Rym: we should watch it again.
Rym: I got it somewhere.
Rym: I got a VHS tape it off it.
Scott: I'm sure thing is you've already told me the premise.
Scott: So what do I need to watch it for?
Scott: Discovering.
Scott: I think the awesome part of the show would be discovering.
Scott: Oh shit.
Scott: You actually did have a secret.
Scott: pass the end.
Rym: Yeah, but there's more to it than that.
Scott: and I there was a radio drama, but it goes on the deep end.
Rym: Yeah, but I don't know if that's just because the anime was like compressing and then stops.
Scott: Was there a manga?
Rym: I don't know, but there's a radio drama.
Rym: I don't know anything about this show except that had a really good soundtrack.
Scott: I mean that there were a lot of shows that like they were just Constantly like I kept seeing the shows or seeing characters from the shows when we were in the anime club But I never watched them or knew anything about them like Sabre Jay and such.
Rym: Sabre Jay was kind of like a poor man's Tenshi, it has a bullshit ending like I didn't watch it I don't even know.
Scott: imagine a show that does about like catgirl nukunuku or oh man Video girl.
Rym: I Video girl.
Rym: I was really popular.
Scott: Not dnangel but DNA Squared.
Rym: Adam fucking loves that show.
Rym: Yeah, it was cute.
Rym: or uh, Birdie the Mighty, but I think after Gerald reviewed it.
Rym: I think it had a resurgence.
Scott: Yeah, that's that was at a sequel even.
Rym: Yeah, I really like the sequel actually.
Scott: I haven't watched it.
Rym: It's worth watching.
Rym: It's really fun.
Rym: Yeah, but oh god, so you see what happened.
Rym: suddenly remembering all these shows I'd completely forgotten about.
Rym: but Sabre Jay has just the bullshit is ending ever.
Rym: imagine ending Where you.
Rym: the entire plot point involves some huge sacrifice.
Rym: All right, and then in the credits just don't do that for no reason.
Rym: Just undo all the sacrifice would keep the rest.
Scott: Yeah, man.
Scott: I just I mean there's even shows that were like, you know more recent than that.
Scott: You think no one would forget them like great teacher onizuka, but that shows been forgotten, right?
Scott: Yeah, who's remembering that?
Rym: Like video girl I was popular as far as I can tell like it seemed really popular and anime cons.
Rym: But no one I know has ever actually watched more than like a few minutes of it.
Rym: I've never actually watched it, but it seems like everyone I met at cons knew what it was.
Rym: now No one at cons knows what it is.
Scott: Yeah All right.
Scott: Do we want to keep going here?
Scott: Memory is sorry.
Scott: I'm trying to like a picture like the sea of tapes and like to remember individual things.
Rym: There's that a SMAP concert we had on tape.
Scott: Oh, yeah No I do and I did mention early in the show Horace Prince of Sun.
Scott: if you can find Horace Prince of the Sun it might Also be holus Prince of Sun.
Scott: Basically.
Scott: This is an old Toei movie and like Miyazaki worked on it.
Scott: He didn't direct it, but he worked on it.
Scott: It's like you can think of it sort of as like the first Miyazaki work is it?
Scott: You can see a lot in common between it and the things he did later and it does show its age.
Scott: You know, it's an old, you know old the oldly styled animated thing, but I really liked it when I watched it.
Scott: I kind of really want to watch it again.
Scott: It's you know, that quiet watch it at night kind of thing.
Scott: It's pretty awesome.
Scott: I wish they would release a DVD.
Scott: like they don't have to release a DVD of just that but they should Like, you know Take that and package it with a bunch of other things all together, you know That's not a bad idea.
Scott: Horace Prince of Sun and a bunch of other similarly old Toei movies all together on one disc.
Scott: That would be pretty cool.
Rym: I think a lot of the shows we talked about would do really well.
Rym: on crunchyroll Probably.
Rym: yeah, I don't know so much about things like marmalade boy.
Rym: I don't know if the demographic is there anymore.
Scott: I don't think so.
Rym: It's hard to say though.
Scott: Let's see which one of these could do.
Rym: Well, I think that I think dragon half would be like a one-shot like wonder if it was just on crunchyroll.
Scott: Yeah, it might be hard to just sell the two episodes For free and then people would like it.
Scott: I think if you did a remake of bastard that removed the porniness but kept the awesome hilarity metal references Yeah, I think that you could definitely do some koto cha Sort of remarketing to get that out there polish it up.
Rym: I think kimigiri orange road could be read.
Rym: I think.
Scott: who could be sold as a movie?
Scott: if you write something like that easily great digital target would probably burn really really.
Scott: These I think pretty much have no marketable value.
Rym: It depends.
Rym: Gokudo is one thing where I think if you put it on crunchyroll It would get popular among the people who like things like slayers.
Scott: It's it's hard though.
Scott: How many you know?
Rym: the thing is slayers should also be on crunchyroll.
Scott: Yeah slayer should be on crunchyroll.
Scott: you're right.
Rym: I think it would cause a whole resurgence of that kind of anime actually in America at least.
Rym: yeah I don't know.
Rym: we're petering out.
Rym: Let's just kick it off right here and kick it under.
Scott: we're done.
Rym: kick it out Devil doll.
Rym: I Think it's time to kick it.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and brand.
Scott: ok for the logos be sure to visit our Website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: remember GeekNights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.