Rym: It's Wednesday December 15th 2010.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight the terrible anime apocalypse.
Rym: zero.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: So my co-worker today he used to work more downtown ish in the Union Square area.
Rym: I'd like to work down there.
Rym: I kind of I really am sick of working in Midtown just for the fact that I can't get lunch for less than like 10 Bucks.
Scott: I also hate Midtown But anyway, he really wanted to go back down there to eat lunch like at these places.
Scott: He used to eat lunch yet, right?
Scott: Cuz he doesn't come to the city every day.
Rym: Oh, is this one of those?
Rym: the place he remembered being good wasn't good.
Scott: No, the place He remembered being good was too good.
Scott: So Trouble.
Scott: we went down to this burrito place.
Scott: I forget the name of it, but I know exactly where it is so I could take you there.
Rym: and it's basically So if on a scale of if zero is Baja Fresh and five why is Baja Fresh zero?
Rym: Baja Fresh really it's real.
Scott: Maybe the I mean Baja Fresh is way better than Qdoba.
Rym: I actually prefer can you know what?
Scott: Qdoba's way way better than Taco Bell?
Rym: So I would all right I was saying if we set the scale zero being the minimum acceptable as Baja Fresh All right, and five is like a Chipotle.
Rym: All right, where is this place?
Scott: Well, I mean, it's.
Scott: I would compare it to cafe Maya.
Scott: But the problem is is that cafe Maya is almost like a different kind, right?
Scott: Kevin Maya is like a sit-down meal and this is clearly a lunch burrito kind of place, right?
Scott: but in terms of lunch burrito kind of place So far number one in New York City.
Scott: Absolutely Really?
Scott: No question at all.
Rym: I am intrigued.
Scott: the burrito though.
Scott: I got the California burrito Was so ginormous Right that I was unable to finish it and a good 15 to 20 percent of it was left uneaten.
Rym: So where where did this end up?
Scott: It ended up.
Rym: I don't know you threw it away.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much Say I didn't want to but it was pretty much like there is no way I'm gonna eat this ever Because it's just so big and my stomach was so full.
Scott: I've pretty much done the mushroom and pretty much the refrigerator at work is Ho ho rendus.
Rym: I've pretty much wandered in every direction that I can reasonably walk to eat somewhere and walk back within an hour or so Mm-hmm, and I'm running out.
Scott: Actually we places the subway going taking the subway down to Union Square.
Scott: It actually took surprisingly not much time.
Rym: I've done that a couple of times never to eat always till I go to a particular store or something.
Scott: Yeah, because we just pretty much went down eight and came back.
Scott: It didn't take much time at all.
Scott: and we sat down and ate, you know, and there was a Muji store down there I didn't know about and he would know that.
Scott: that's how I know where the burrito place is cuz they're right next to the Muji.
Rym: Let's go check this place out.
Scott: However, after we ate at the burrito place We went to a place I think was called City Bakery Because he had remembered the best hot chocolate being there.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So we went and got this hot chocolate and they had two varieties regular which is dark chocolate But that's the default and milk chocolate which is not the default and for 50 cents You can get a marshmallow.
Scott: which was?
Scott: they made the marshmallow and they cut a big marshmallow cube.
Rym: What's the marshmallow made out of marshmallow?
Scott: I don't know what it was made.
Rym: or was it a fake marshmallow?
Scott: like most marshmallows It was a real marshmallow that they made.
Rym: if they made it then it's not a real marshmallow.
Rym: Whatever marshmallow is a plant anyway, anyway, uh How was this hot chocolate?
Rym: You're leaving me in suspense.
Rym: It was basically.
Scott: I don't know if I would really qualify it as hot chocolate right because it was so insanely delicious.
Rym: It was basically a candy bar in a cup.
Scott: Yeah, it was a melted Chocolate bar in a cup.
Scott: that was like the best, you know Like an ultra high quality bar of dark chocolate melted in a cup.
Scott: just the right temperature not burning you not cold Right, and it was thinned out.
Rym: It was just right.
Scott: It was thinned out, you know just enough that it you know Wasn't?
Scott: it was like on the border like any thicker would have been undrinkable But it was just on the drinkable side of thickness.
Rym: see.
Scott: and then the giant marshmallow cube was amazing But I could only eat like two bites of it because by this point my stomach was still 100% full.
Rym: You're the one who made the choice to get that after having not finished the burrito and it's still 100% full.
Scott: So I'm pretty full.
Rym: I'm curious because Le Cafe Henri has some pretty damn good hot chocolate.
Rym: We'll have to go and check.
Scott: But basically this bakery place not only they have this hot chocolate But pretty much everything else they had in terms of cookies and muffins and all that stuff Like.
Scott: this is the kind of place that I could go and eat a different thing every day and never get bored and it was Wicked crowded.
Scott: So yeah, and they had a. there's a little tiny room in there.
Scott: That was the chocolate room and it was like this little closet of chocolate.
Rym: It was like it was made out of chocolate.
Scott: No, it had chocolate for sale in it.
Scott: It was a little tiny closet and you would go in there and get a chocolate and it was it.
Scott: you'll see it if you Go down there.
Scott: All right.
Rym: So in a geek bite an anime geek bite I happened to watch with Emily last night the professor Layton movie professor Layton and the eternal diva.
Scott: I'm still playing the third video game Layton.
Rym: Kyoju toy and no Otahime.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: It was okay.
Scott: It was it was beautiful.
Scott: It was like the video games.
Rym: Not to spoil.
Rym: there is a point not that far in where an evil voice appears and a projector Projects the zero zero one on the wall and the voice says your first puzzle is this It was okay, it was fun it was beautiful.
Rym: I'd recommend watching it, but it really just made me want to watch Lupin and the castle of Cagliostro again Because it seemed to homage that a couple of times.
Scott: Yeah, I could definitely see that.
Rym: the similarities there Yeah, but Luke kegliostro is a thousand times better than this which means this.
Scott: That makes me really wish they were new good Lupin's.
Rym: We haven't watched the last like five or six or not, but they're not a quality, you know It's not like Fuma conspiracy All right, you know Fuma as good as it is doesn't really hold up as well as say Cagliostro.
Rym: Oh, yeah, that's like mom.
Scott: Oh gee, man.
Scott: This bar of gold doesn't hold up as well as that bar of platinum.
Rym: I believe you mean the bar of Babylon gold.
Rym: So, yeah, it's no K like a - B plus animated movie and you know our thing.
Rym: it's an anime movie There aren't that many watch it.
Rym: God damn it.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Also, it's on pirate thing.
Scott: Is it anywhere legally?
Rym: I have.
Rym: no I guess.
Scott: is there a Japanese?
Scott: there must be a Japanese DVD.
Scott: that's legal.
Rym: Actually, it was released within theaters in Germany in Spain interest and Singapore.
Scott: very interesting.
Scott: Is the game a big seller there?
Rym: I have no idea.
Scott: All right good to know.
Rym: one thing though, uh the weird kind of almost romantic homosexual odd Undertones between Layton and that kid.
Rym: they're still there.
Rym: Yeah also Layton's dot eyes.
Rym: I realized he's the only one with dot eyes.
Rym: There's this one scene where someone like he notices something like someone's talking and that scary blank expression dot Face slowly turns Regards this and then slowly turns back.
Rym: That was the closest thing to a Layton rape face I have ever seen.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: So anyway, the biggest news in the anime world right is that the Tokyo Assembly passed this bill.
Scott: that was the Youth Ordinance bill and The summary of what this bill does at least one of the things it does from the anime news network Right, which is the really the only place to get any news about this in English Basically the anime news AP wire.
Scott: it prevents the sale and renting of quote harmful publications materials that are Sexually stimulating encourage cruelty and or may compel suicide or criminal behavior.
Scott: the people wait wait wait.
Scott: people under the age of 18.
Rym: I've got a real translation of that law.
Rym: it hereby bans the majority of Japanese media.
Scott: It would require the industry to also regulate manga anime and other images except for real-life photography That unjustifiably wait wait wait or if I or exaggerate certain sexual or pseudo sexual acts.
Rym: so Except for real-life photography.
Rym: That's a very specific exception.
Rym: and if I go back to sell animation Can I not just say that it is that my movie is a collection of thousands upon thousands of still photographs of paintings?
Scott: Good question.
Scott: another section of the revised bill allows the government to directly regulate above images if the depicted acts are also Considered to be excessively disrupting of social order such as rape.
Scott: and that's pretty much.
Scott: I read almost the entire Anime news network article.
Rym: so much for rape man, right?
Rym: How's it ok?
Rym: Ok, or so?
Rym: Yeah anything I like the other additional news that I like rape man.
Scott: No, the additional news about this right is that Many many manga publishers are now basically boycotting the Tokyo anime fair Including the big boys like, you know, Shueisha and such and such damn.
Scott: Yeah, so, um Yeah, I mean it just sort of reminds you that hey look Japan is loaded with censorship.
Scott: You know people always, you know We're always complaining about when there are censorship sort of things happening in the u.s.
Scott: And there are some.
Rym: there are in fact quite a few but we have that test by first amendment.
Rym: That means we always get in here.
Scott: Remember the thing is we still Censorship wise?
Scott: have it a lot better than a lot of other places.
Scott: It's not the best in the world I'm pretty sure.
Scott: like didn't Iceland win the award for best freedom of the press?
Rym: Scandinavia pretty much has freer press only because the United States is really bad about boobs Yeah, but even so as obsessed with them and we don't like anyone to see them on TV The United States is still doing pretty good.
Scott: And while this Tokyo ordinance probably won't affect us in any way really and while you know Just you know to anyone out there who's like listen Japan's loaded with pedophiles and all this shit.
Scott: So because there's societies that way they got to do something like this.
Scott: and to that I have to say well You know if you believe in freedom of speech in freedom, right while you might be banning nymph et you're simultaneously Banning say Akira and that's not cool.
Rym: I don't remember that scene where Akira rapes a little girl though There is rapes in Akira.
Scott: Oh, yeah The manga and the Animes, but not pedophile also attempted rape and boobage and violence and suicides and pretty much everything That is made.
Scott: Akira would not be allowed to be sold to anyone under the age of 18 by this law.
Scott: Well, that is the most famous Most significant manga is ever created.
Scott: In fact a great many Tezuka mangas would not be allowed Right.
Rym: I'm pretty sure we could still get ambassador magma.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: But anyway, I if this kind of thing, you know Repulses you right to your representative and also send money to the comic book legal defense fund.
Rym: The comic book legal defense fund is one of the pretty much pure good charities that there is out there.
Scott: Yeah, so, you know, I send the monies you send the monies too.
Scott: And then the next time something like, you know, what was that guy Handley who who got arrested for Canada?
Scott: Yeah, well no it was.
Scott: it was in the US wasn't it?
Rym: There's a bunch of that going on in Canada because Canada has weird laws about.
Scott: yeah so the next time someone gets, you know busted for having hentai's they'll have lawyers.
Scott: and You know, we if we all chip in it won't be one person paying a zillion dollars for lawyers But everyone else everyone who cares paying $20.
Rym: But anyway things of the day, so I this video has been stuck in my head in the song, you know ignorance is bliss.
Rym: It's this animation someone made to a song that has to do with Mario and Luigi in the Mushroom Kingdom.
Scott: I'm pretty sure this is already a thing of the day.
Rym: I searched the archive.
Rym: It is in fact not So just to be sure.
Rym: Ignorance is.
Rym: bliss is a good video.
Rym: You should watch it, you know, like all those internet videos.
Rym: It's good.
Rym: but my real thing of the day is The story behind that white knuckles scoring.
Rym: What spelled with an apostrophe at the end white knuckles scoring was a comic book and CD put out by Nintendo and I believe 1991. all right, and It's awful.
Rym: It's awesomely awful.
Rym: but if you watch that video to ignorance is bliss.
Rym: that was a song done by a band called the jellyfish which no longer exists and No other song on the CD that that song appears on has anything to do with Mario Luigi the Mushroom Kingdom or even Nintendo.
Rym: as far as I can tell and As far as the internet says they're all terrible songs except for ignorance is bliss.
Scott: It was pretty terrible.
Rym: Also, I thought it was a good song.
Scott: It has like a good part, but it's it.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I like it.
Rym: I like it in in conjunction with the animation.
Rym: So if you wondered what the hell the deal was with that because the kind of had like the animation which was Not made by the band and has nothing to do with the album Kind of tells a story that fits with it.
Rym: The actual story is told in the comic that I have all the scans for you here.
Scott: Oh, how about that?
Rym: It's pretty terrible go figure.
Rym: So there you go.
Rym: Ignorance is bliss great.
Scott: So there's this video.
Scott: It's also Mario related, you know, we used to do a ton of Mario.
Scott: It's weird that Mario is so heavily used, you know in pretty well.
Scott: I guess it's not that much of a surprise.
Rym: at one point Bowser tries to cast a spell but because he's ignorant and he Can't read he gives it to Lenny Koopa.
Rym: Anyway, so Lenny Koopa's cast.
Scott: You don't need to tell this story and turns Mario Luigi into night.
Scott: We used to do things of the day and it felt like in the olden days of GeekNights that the things of the day Would be like it would be a Mario related thing.
Scott: almost every other show, you know.
Scott: So is a double dose of Mario.
Scott: why the fuck not?
Scott: it's his anniversary.
Rym: It's top-favored it on YouTube right now.
Rym: What the your thing of the day?
Scott: Yeah, this thing is all over the internet.
Scott: if you haven't seen this already I mean, you're just not on the Internet's but it's got about half.
Scott: so it's so good.
Scott: You know that it's.
Scott: it deserves all those views.
Scott: It's got.
Rym: it's got about half as many as the yo.
Scott: So I want to make sure that every last person who might want to see it does not miss it while it's big on the Internet's.
Scott: basically what these people did is they basically mashed up the Mushroom Kingdom with a generic gangland violence movie and Created sort of like this trailer ish Short movie kind of.
Scott: it's more like a montage of an entire.
Rym: what it is It's what the Mario Brothers movie should have been.
Scott: Yeah, the the really bad way and that's the thing that's so great.
Scott: That's so shocking about this short.
Scott: Well, I guess the machinima right, you know is that whoever put this together did a better job times a thousand.
Scott: then a Big full-budget Hollywood production was able to do right with Mario.
Scott: They did it with like a video game and some doodling and some voice acting.
Rym: You gotta watch YouTube all the way to the edge.
Rym: It's me body.
Rym: It's a me my.
Rym: That's pretty high quality.
Scott: It's very high quality.
Scott: It drops jokes.
Scott: It's it's.
Scott: it's all around a plus.
Rym: So the meta moment, we're actually running out of the first series of GeekNights t-shirts.
Rym: So if you did want one, I'd suggest ordering it soon.
Scott: I see like eight or nine on the floor there.
Rym: Yeah, but we're almost out of mediums.
Scott: Oh Yeah, are we out of any other size?
Rym: We're out of smalls already.
Scott: All right, you know It's funny all this is a medium large and extra hard.
Rym: If you look at the listeners the people who are asking for xxx L's and up tend to be Tuesday listeners And It's all Rym.
Rym: but as I got nothing to do with this, but I know patties That we got more than three times as many requests for baby dolls as we did for xxx L's That's good.
Rym: I'm going to cater to the girl demographic before I cater to the xxx xxx xxx L demographic.
Scott: I agree.
Rym: So if you want to get night t-shirt buy them before they sell out or else you have to wait until we reorder them because we Promised that will order another run if they sell out.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So you'll get them no matter what that doesn't mean, right?
Scott: So the thing is don't go don't go.
Scott: Oh, they're gonna reorder them.
Scott: So I don't need to order one now I'll just wait till they reorder and no matter what I'll get one.
Scott: The thing is it is gonna take a while for that reorder to come through, you know me.
Rym: So if you do shit and also it's in my queue, I just don't do it for like a year.
Scott: Yeah And also you can help us out a lot.
Scott: if we know how many we need we can do a better job of ordering the right Number on the reorder.
Rym: We've also got a couple more t-shirts coming but we're not gonna order them.
Scott: if you want to help us out order a SCP.
Scott: if you just don't care then or if you Don't even want one just don't even bother.
Rym: but you know I think you're gonna like it.
Rym: the two more t-shirts we got to come in.
Scott: We got to do my t-shirt somebody.
Scott: All right What other?
Rym: Meta moments we got the book club book is Michio Kaku's hyperspace.
Rym: a fantastic journey through hyperspace.
Scott: All right There any conventions are going to.
Rym: we're gonna be at MAGFest.
Rym: We're gonna be at PAX East.
Rym: We're gonna be at probably anime Boston.
Rym: We're gonna be a ConnectiCon.
Rym: we're gonna open panel submissions to ConnectiCon pretty soon The new website's coming along.
Scott: We're gonna go to zinc icon.
Rym: We're gonna be a zinc icon doing anime panel.
Scott: I think it's the week after PAX East.
Rym: we're gonna submit panels to Otakon.
Rym: We'll see if they.
Scott: that's a long time for now forget that we're gonna see if they can only worry about through like April May.
Scott: Here I do one quarter at a time.
Rym: the most upcoming ist panel con thing.
Rym: We're doing is at mag fest Yeah, which is very soon.
Scott: actually I gotta do something about.
Rym: I gotta remember which panel we're doing and then make sure I got the slideshow ready to be fun, I believe.
Scott: Also, if you're not going to mag fest, but you're in the New York City area the double recess is that same weekend.
Scott: So if you miss out on music and gaming down in Virginia You can get plenty of gaming up in New York City recess being the nerd NYC recess Which is RPGs in two sessions for an entire day.
Rym: Yep, and then another day.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Is this the double recess indeed?
Rym: I'm sad we're missing that one.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Oh, well any any other things you can think of for meta?
Rym: Fucking apocalypse zeroes.
Rym: I swear to God Alright, so I just yeah.
Scott: I want to say you know pretty much every other anime podcast in the world has already discussed apocalypse zero.
Scott: and because they discussed apocalypse Zero to such great hilarious You know just hilarious We're not up to the level of doing the.
Rym: Dave and Joel talk about 24 for an hour and somehow have reviewed apocalypse zero Right.
Rym: Well, nor are we the Daryl Surratt talking about the history of the manga.
Scott: no, but Basically because of those people like that Scott Johnson Downloaded apocalypse zero.
Scott: he or he acquired it.
Scott: right now He'll watch because we were at his house and bored in his basement We're looking for an anime to watch.
Scott: somehow apocalypse zero got turned on.
Rym: I believe he came down He's like you should watch this and he had only seen a little bit past the tit bear.
Rym: And he was like, yeah, most people don't make it past the tit bear.
Scott: so anyway somehow You know, it's only what a three episode OAV to To 240 minute episodes.
Scott: Wow, so because it was only 240 minute episodes We watched the entire thing in one go.
Rym: well it was on the TV and Everyone was watching it and kind of making fun of it and Everyone agreed.
Rym: Yeah, this is terrible.
Rym: We should turn it off.
Rym: We should watch something else.
Rym: They were like, I don't know eight or nine of us down there.
Rym: Everyone else was upstairs basically shouting down to us Why the fuck are you watching that?
Rym: Just turn it off.
Rym: What's wrong with you?
Rym: So We never turned it off.
Rym: In fact at one point when we said hey, we should turn it off.
Rym: I don't know who said this but someone said and I quote You can't turn it off until I find out why that chick is a dude in the flashback.
Scott: Uh-huh, so we watched it to the end and we found out why the chick was a dude in the flashback.
Rym: That was kind of disappointing.
Scott: That was like the only thing we found out.
Rym: I regret nothing However, because apocalypse zero was bad bad enough to where.
Rym: normally when we review an anime right on the anime news network I'll like pull it up to remember like who the character designer was or whatever and I'm always surprised that the ratings are Overwhelmingly positive even on shows that I think are terrible.
Rym: apocalypse zero Almost all bad reviews.
Rym: the worst possible rating is the most used rating for apocalypse zero.
Scott: I now see the thing with apocalypse zero.
Scott: right.
Scott: is that it's not so bad It's good, and it's not so bad like odeen like where you're just like kill me now.
Scott: This is so.
Scott: it's painful to watch right brutal.
Scott: It's just brutally like.
Scott: it's just you know, it's.
Scott: it's painfully bad.
Scott: It's not boring.
Scott: Oh my god.
Scott: When is it gonna be over?
Scott: It's just like oh, that's so terrible.
Rym: Oh, that's the worst thing I've ever seen like each of the killer was horribly violent.
Rym: It's bad.
Scott: It's like you don't want to watch apocalypse zero the way you don't want to be stabbed in the face.
Rym: But yet at the same time as you're being stabbed in the face, you're fascinated by the with a rusty spoon.
Rym: You're like you cannot help but be fascinated by what has been wrought onto your eyes.
Scott: Yeah, apocalypse.
Scott: I imagine like if I was like if I was stabbed in the gut right like most of my brain would be like.
Scott: But at least part of you is like.
Scott: This is like exactly a very small part of my brain to be like.
Scott: that's what stabbings like.
Scott: That's what being stacked is like right, and that's apocalypse zero is basically.
Scott: it's like oh god damn.
Rym: now I know what being stabbed in the eye is like exactly so If you've read the prince of nothing which is one of our first book club books The sequel you know the second set of books.
Rym: They're the non-manor addicts.
Rym: This is obviously.
Rym: you either know this you don't.
Rym: Apocalypse zero is most Memorable and I have decided that if something is bad, but memorable it is not actually bad because if something Writes itself into your memory
Scott: There is something to learn from apocalypse zero while it is not you know an entertaining It way to spend you know 80 minutes of your life
Rym: at least.
Rym: I've learned that if you cut a guy's karaoke dick off That is most of the way to killing him.
Scott: Yes, it is educational.
Scott: So basically let me sum up apocalypse zero right.
Scott: so this basic story Is that you have a guy and?
Scott: It's an anime.
Scott: so he has superpowers And he puts on a metal suit of armor.
Scott: that gives him wicked powers of fighting even though he's good fighting without it But he doesn't.
Rym: he's ultra fighting when he wears it, but he doesn't wear it all the time.
Rym: He fights without it.
Rym: sometimes in fact he fights the tit-bearer without it.
Scott: Yeah, he doesn't need it.
Scott: He doesn't wear it for all.
Scott: he's good with fighting without it, but he puts it on for super fighting.
Scott: You know it's like a transformation kind of thing yeah And basically he goes to it's.
Scott: it's like a post-apocalyptic world But for some reason right.
Scott: kids just walk to school in a group like normal.
Scott: It's like there's a normal school.
Rym: They're walking through the North Star landscape, right?
Scott: It's like they think school is normal and the places the houses they live in are normal But in order to get from one to the other they have to walk through the fist of the North Star world.
Rym: now the schools Have guards who are highly trained to keep people who aren't students away from the school, but they do a very bad job.
Rym: Oh, they do a really good job until tactical evil shows out.
Rym: you're right.
Scott: and basically They're.
Scott: every day when they go to school They're harassed by some horrible monster and this guy fights them and basically the course of the two OAV episodes is pretty much Him fighting multiple evil monsters and the thing is that really makes this show stand out.
Scott: It's like is that all of these evil monsters are horribly You know, they're obviously from the same dimension as the Overfiend, right?
Scott: They are.
Scott: they are as sexually charged as they are violently charged.
Rym: Now what is funny is Scott Johnson who you know told us he turned this on and left it for us to watch continuously says it's not sexual as the dude with the dragon dick.
Rym: I Think that was the third day.
Scott: Okay, so there was a bear with like 20.
Scott: There's a bear with 20.
Rym: It was not a bear it was a tit bear.
Scott: Okay So there's a bear whose body consists entirely of tits filled with acid relative of the dick wolf same same genus.
Scott: And then he fights against you know, the the famous, you know, anime's craziest deaths.
Scott: Gigantically large fat woman with the incredibly scary, you know body parts.
Rym: the woman who?
Rym: Apparently we didn't get to see this from anime's craziest deaths.
Rym: She rapes young boys and then rips their faces off by kissing them and then eats them
Scott: Yeah, and then
Rym: makes pasties With their faces and
Scott: she basically uses like their entire body as you know Hey dildo,
Rym: which is pretty great,
Scott: which is what you have to do if you were so gigantic.
Rym: So this giant woman shows up and she's you know harassing these kids.
Rym: She's basically gonna kill them all.
Rym: and then one of them looks up and kind of zooms in on her nipple and you see this Vaguely face-shaped thing and they're like Tanaka.
Rym: No Like how could you recognize someone's face?
Scott: I Don't know but it's horrific.
Scott: And then what's the next thing he fights?
Scott: Was it the dragon dick guy?
Rym: No, that was the third guy the next one.
Rym: There's the there's the scary nurse.
Rym: But before that there's the big guy with the karaoke dick.
Rym: Remember this karaoke dick and dragon.
Scott: I watched a lot of this show from my mind.
Scott: You understand I tried pretty hard.
Rym: So let's zoom back a bit because you know, there's flashbacks all the time.
Rym: and what?
Rym: what's weird is that in the flashbacks There's this these two guys who are learning to fight with these suits or whatever, but in the rest of the show One of them's a woman.
Rym: There's no explanation.
Scott: Basically the guy has like what's a sister or a cousin or something?
Rym: They keep calling him mister.
Rym: I forgot everyone's names in this, right?
Scott: So the main character guy has some sort of sister.
Scott: who is the big bad guy, right?
Scott: You know who all has another suit of armor.
Rym: that's the same kind of suit of armor and he or she is the head of Tactical evil.
Scott: I think it used to be a she.
Rym: now it was a guy first.
Scott: It was a guy first.
Scott: then it became a Woman's body, but it's still a guy.
Scott: Yeah, and like it got tits, but it didn't cut off the dick.
Scott: Well, we don't know about it's a futanari.
Rym: Ironically, we never find out because toward the end when they're fighting the dragon dick guy when the dragon dick gets cut off Which mortally wounds him He or she then takes over that guy's body to fight the main character and notes the fact that the dick is missing Yeah, and that this is really inconvenient.
Rym: The show's.
Scott: I guess if you're your best attack was the rape attack then it would be pretty inconvenient.
Scott: It's not a rape.
Rym: you don't use dicks for that.
Rym: the one dick is just a dragon and the other guy whiffs it off and Actually sings karaoke into it because it is in fact a microphone Mm-hmm.
Rym: There's also the nurse who has the two dick tits, I guess.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know what's up with me Doesn't the nurse like tries to befriend them and then it's like oh my god.
Scott: It wasn't actually a nurse.
Rym: Well, she's trying to eat them with her vagina.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, this shows not safe for work.
Scott: It was not safe for anything.
Rym: No one should watch apocalypse zero.
Rym: You should just read all the reviews about it.
Scott: I think what you need to do is you need to see it.
Scott: You should look at a still picture or a short video of any one of the horrific monsters in the show.
Scott: Right, and then once you see the style of any of these horrific monsters, you'd be like, oh I see that style.
Scott: Okay, then you're good.
Rym: The character design is pretty awesome.
Rym: Everyone has this continuously surprised look on their face.
Scott: Yeah, I mean like it is an OAV and that the production quality in terms of like animation is actually surprisingly high.
Rym: The karaoke dick is really well animated.
Scott: Yeah, it's like woes Animated, you know, I don't know.
Scott: the thing is is no AV.
Scott: So this is not on TV.
Scott: It was not in movie theaters, right and someone wanted to watch this.
Scott: That means they had to go to the store and buy it on I guess DVD.
Rym: if you watch this You must have already been a fan of Taka Yuki Yamaguchi's manga apocalypse zero.
Scott: Yeah, it's like who actually went to the store and bought this right intentionally?
Scott: And then I guess it became big in the US because of the.
Scott: you know The 90s when it was all about, you know violent.
Rym: Oh my god, ultra violent anime was like the marketing technique.
Scott: Yeah, they just they're like, oh my god, you gotta watch this anime.
Scott: It's so violent.
Rym: so people in the US bought it and that's the thing is I feel like, you know Watching vampire hunter D or ninja scroll.
Rym: Those were ultra violent but more in the ichi the killer way.
Rym: Apocalypse zero is this brand new kind of violent.
Scott: apocalypse zero is not in the same category as each of the killer.
Scott: What are you talking about?
Rym: I don't think it is.
Rym: each of the killer is realistic.
Scott: How is it not in the same category as Ebola syndrome?
Rym: I for some reason they feel different.
Rym: the the way the violence is presented in apocalypse zero is so Just fucked up.
Scott: How is Ebola syndrome not fucked up?
Rym: because at least Ebola syndrome in the end the guy shoots the guy and I don't know Ebola syndrome kind of made sense from a plot perspective, right?
Rym: There was a plot.
Rym: Okay, the guy went around infecting people with Ebola because he's a dick.
Rym: Yeah, that was the plot.
Scott: So is the plot of apocalypse zero?
Rym: No The plot of apocalypse zero is that this dude trains his two sons to wear this armor.
Rym: to train them He basically makes them badasses by fighting the tit bear and then he locks each of them in a room Naked with the armor and before he locks him in there.
Rym: He's like, here's the armor You'll figure out what to do.
Scott: and the armor hurts really bad.
Rym: So we thought but there's this long scene where the guys laying in there in this room just naked and the armors just kind of Laying there next to him in the room and he's like, all right.
Rym: I don't know what to do now.
Scott: And yeah each piece of the armor he puts on causes incredible the whole time You're thinking is he gonna have sex with the armor?
Scott: You could say that he does metaphorically but then he's like I don't know where is a piece of armor that applies to the crotchal area.
Rym: I don't know what to do.
Rym: armor What do you want for me?
Rym: And then he touches it.
Rym: He's like you're so cold.
Rym: Should I should I warm you up and he starts hugging the armor and then the armors arm falls off.
Rym: He's like should I should I stick my hand in the hole where your arm just fell off.
Rym: Oh, you're nice and warm and it's You see what I mean?
Rym: There's nothing like that.
Rym: and you see the killer.
Rym: each of the killer made me cringe because it was realistic this I couldn't even look Away, I was just like what's gonna happen next.
Rym: All right his dicks out.
Rym: Oh, it's a karaoke microphone.
Rym: He's singing.
Rym: I guess that's his power singing into his karaoke dick.
Rym: Like you.
Rym: just everything that happens is so much more over the top than the previous thing that happened that you cannot help.
Rym: But just you have to know what happens next.
Rym: Our doubt it goes.
Scott: who thought of this right?
Scott: because like no matter how hard I try I told you who did the Right, but it's like imagine if you're sitting there and you're like, all right I need to think of the most fucked up thing I can think of.
Scott: right you're not even gonna come close to this Right.
Scott: I mean like.
Scott: I don't care how creative you are.
Scott: Find me the most creative person Like I don't know if I can you know, even something like the boys or preacher I get Garth Ennis.
Scott: be like Garth Ennis.
Scott: Think of the most fucked up thing you can think of the most fucked up thing in any Garth Ennis comic I've ever read.
Scott: Apocalypse zero beat that don't even come close to even the tit bear, right?
Rym: So it's like, you know You're probably thinking much like with utana when we said the utana movie that yeah at the end It's just there's a naked car and you're like naked car.
Rym: What do you mean?
Rym: Yeah, that must be some sort of metaphor or allegory.
Rym: now naked car.
Rym: This is a tit bear.
Rym: yep But I Don't know even god damn it apocalypse zero.
Scott: Okay, like god damn All right.
Scott: So, you know, I don't know like I don't know if there's much more to actually say about apocalypse zero itself other than I'm glad it was only - oh, it's interesting.
Rym: had it been longer.
Rym: I would not have watched it.
Rym: I mean if this to the North Star were like that I would not have watched it but because it was so short It was like an achievable goal.
Rym: I looked at it and thought you know what I can without much expenditure see the entirety of this train wreck.
Scott: Yeah, it's less time than a movie and you're watching it with other people in the room.
Scott: So you're all suffering together.
Rym: and cool enough people were in the room who I would not have expected would have watched it.
Rym: There were people in the room who I thought would have been disgusted and walked out.
Rym: Nobody walked out.
Rym: No, some people came downstairs and then went back upstairs Very quickly.
Rym: One person who will remain nameless walk down.
Rym: Like what are you guys?
Rym: Whoa, my god.
Scott: and just walked away And that was the tit bear God, they didn't walk down for say karaoke, dude Or dragon dick?
Rym: or when he punches that the woman who eats the boys in the stomach and all those skeletons come out.
Rym: Yeah One of them is still kind of alive.
Rym: I don't know how that works.
Scott: Yeah, they knew who it was.
Rym: It was Tanaka again, whatever.
Rym: I couldn't tell you the name of any character.
Scott: I could not tell you they have a single character in this show but there's I couldn't even tell you the name of like the hero guy.
Rym: there's something to it because it was shorts and Because it was crazy and it.
Rym: we know a lot of anime that do crazy stuff.
Scott: It's like going to Ripley's believe it or not.
Rym: You're just staring at some ridiculous thing But they Peter out like if they're long or if they're not always getting more crazy you get bored with it.
Rym: You're like, alright, this is stupid But because this trumped everything that came before every scene trumped the previous scene.
Rym: If you start watching you're gonna see it to the end.
Scott: and but because it was you know They it's like it's weird because usually you start quiet and build up to ridiculous.
Scott: This starts out ridiculous builds up to ultra ridiculous in 80 minutes and then it's over.
Rym: I Have no desire to ever see more.
Rym: I've no desire to even look at the manga.
Scott: Nope None keep it away.
Scott: I Know all that needs to be known and more will not be will not be investigated.
Rym: Oh my god that the woman is On the cover.
Rym: I'm thankful.
Scott: This is an obscure OVA from a foreign land that will never see.
Scott: It will never be widely known across the world.
Rym: I have this sinking feeling that we're helping make it much more Well known.
Scott: it doesn't matter.
Scott: My only warning to you are they need to be warned.
Scott: you can't just you know What if they watch it by accident?
Scott: We're saving someone You.
Rym: well, actually there was a point that was made that was interesting.
Rym: while we were watching to a nameless person said and I quote Stuff like this is what made anime good in the 90s.
Rym: No, it's not now.
Rym: Argument actually made sense that yeah apocalypse zero God damn it, but it was crazy.
Rym: It is different.
Rym: There is nothing else like it.
Rym: and What got me into anime was that it was crazy.
Rym: It was different.
Rym: There was nothing else like it.
Rym: So there is a place in the world for things like apocalypse zero because you have to delve all the depths You have to go in every direction with animation.
Rym: You have to make every possible thing.
Rym: Otherwise, we're gonna have a million moe shows and nothing else.
Rym: I Mean that that's the best argument I can possibly pull out of my ass for why apocalypse zero exists to prove to you that It can exist.
Scott: That's a that's a great argument.
Scott: You got there.
Rym: It is in fact the apocalypse.
Rym: All righty, I think we're done.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat Lee for web design and Brand-okay for the logos.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.
Scott: Play some burning wheel you wanna play.
Scott: well, we play free market instead.
Scott: It's easier to do one shot.
Rym: I just want to do the sword first.
Scott: That doesn't.
Scott: that takes 20 minutes.
Rym: Yeah, maybe felons rift - you want to play anything I could do.
Rym: felons are gonna make it past.
Rym: problem is I know Everything already, you know, I got a roll the dice.
Rym: All right, you know what the bridge of death does.
Scott: I refuse to go on the bridge of death.
Rym: It's the bridge of that belief one it's aptly named.
Rym: I want.
Rym: I want the orb.
Rym: I'm gonna change your belief now.
Rym: change of leaf.
Rym: it.
Rym: belief is now I'm gonna go.
Scott: I'm gonna go back and see if there's another way to get there without using the bridge of death Because really it's the bridge of death.
Scott: It's not the bridge of happiness or the bridge of long life.
Scott: It isn't quite the opposite and I refuse to go on it.
Rym: I love how even in the module it says the players will likely not make it past this point.
Scott: It's rage of that.
Rym: those rooms even tell you stay off the bridge of death.