Rym: Hey, it's Tuesday April 6th.
Scott: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: after a long Boston hiatus We are back with the PAX East 2010 show.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: It's so weird to be back in my real life.
Scott: Yeah, it's all right.
Rym: after that whole week You know we were in Boston for our packs And we had a week going around with the fun spot and everything and then anime Boston and then a flight home.
Rym: And now here we are on Tuesday.
Scott: It's actually weird.
Scott: it's like I've almost come back to a new life you know because like Everything's different now that I'm back here like all these things changed while I was away I know think of that we went out and the weather was shitty.
Rym: It was just rainy and cold and miserable.
Rym: And we came back and the weather's beautiful and it's sunny and the sun's out.
Scott: It's like I can ride my bike to work now Which I wasn't doing before.
Scott: and then also there's a. there's a little space in our office where this other I'm not gonna explain all the details, but basically all these people moved out of our office somewhere else.
Scott: There's a whole bunch of empty desks in this one area And you know this is all you know.
Scott: and then the new guy.
Scott: we have a new guy on the tech team.
Scott: So he started working the Monday after PAX East.
Scott: so it's like oh, it's like a completely different world I came back to.
Rym: it was actually weird.
Rym: You know getting back to work I kind of like on this visceral level forgot what it was that I do.
Rym: I mean I get there and I sit down.
Rym: I'm like all right this shit.
Rym: Yeah, I remember this.
Rym: I almost forgot one of the passwords.
Rym: Yeah But how we're back what kind of way.
Scott: you're like this super professional place And you've got a situation where there's like a shared password.
Rym: No no one of the passwords of my own Uh-huh because I have a lot of systems and a couple of them use different passwords for certain reasons.
Rym: Yeah, hmm, but anyway all that aside We're back and the show be a little odd because we're experimenting with video as you all know.
Rym: So we actually during the week between PAX and anime Boston recorded a series of five to ten minute segments about packs.
Scott: We thought would be podcasting that whole week.
Rym: Haha.
Rym: Yeah, we thought we'd stream stuff out of packs.
Rym: that Sprint card And that Verizon card laughed at us.
Scott: Yeah, it was all right, but we learned We still uploaded a bunch of youtubes and stuff and other things.
Scott: with those it was.
Rym: it was a good deal Yep, but basically this show is a little weird.
Rym: because we have all these segments I'm gonna kind of string them together.
Rym: so if you hear any Discontinuities where we kind of start up again or start up again or talk about something twice That's just because we suck and we're complete unprofessional at this point.
Rym: lol.
Rym: Because we were trying this new experiment and now we're recording the kind of the rapper to the pack show.
Scott: Yeah, I think it was later.
Scott: I think it was good because we talked about packs while we still remembered it.
Rym: Yeah, so everything in the kind of the beginning of this and the end of this is only the memories that shown through.
Rym: I mean, you know kind of the longer you wait after event only the strongest Impressions are the ones that you actually remember enough to talk about.
Rym: So it'll be interesting if we do end up repeating anything, but hopefully not so.
Rym: PAX East 2010.
Scott: So here we are lazy asses.
Scott: we were supposed to make podcasts and videos all week between packs and anime Boston But we didn't.
Rym: yeah, well Monday.
Rym: I was basically dead and Tuesday.
Rym: I was almost still.
Scott: we were in New Hampshire And Wednesday, we're coming back from New Hampshire and eating dinner.
Rym: and now it's Thursday.
Scott: Thursday We went to MIT and tomorrow's anime Boston.
Scott: So we really didn't make the podcast and videos We thought we would make while we were sitting around in hotels doing nothing because we didn't really sitting around hotels doing nothing.
Scott: all That much until now.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Hey, it's anime Boston's tomorrow and so excited.
Scott: Yeah Can really easily hide it.
Scott: We're gonna do our packs.
Scott: wrap up review ish PAX East.
Scott: review a show While it is fresh in our minds because come Monday will have a brain full of anime Boston.
Rym: Well, I feel like it's weird doing this.
Rym: I'm so used to doing like the show with like a microphone like up in my face doing the like.
Rym: I don't worry about the I don't.
Rym: I feel like we're a little stilted right now.
Scott: We are quite used it up.
Rym: So packs.
Rym: Holy shit we were at PAX East 2010 the first PAX East and The amazing thing about is that you know We were we did the like preview show and we kept having that disclaimer that if it's not as awesome If we've been making these packs is out to be.
Rym: it's not our fault.
Rym: You know, it's a new packs new location.
Rym: we don't know a hundred percent what it's gonna be like.
Rym: for all.
Rym: we know they're gonna cock it up and I'm pleased to report that they did not cock it up.
Rym: In fact, I would say it was like it was 95% packs.
Scott: It was definitely 95% PAX West.
Scott: I mean what was different?
Rym: The only difference was that the convention center in Seattle lets Joko sing for like an extra two hours.
Scott: Yeah, I mean They're really everybody fits in main events pretty much.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So PAX East it was PAX West.
Scott: if you're worried about what PAX West was like and you've been to PAX East you pretty much know It's the real deal.
Scott: PAX is PAX is PAX.
Scott: I'm pretty confident.
Scott: they can pull off packs anywhere in the US that they want probably maybe anywhere in the world probably anywhere in Canada.
Scott: You know other countries is still yet to be seen, you know language barrier cultural differences, you know.
Scott: I mean, I don't think packs China would work really or I think the back Scotland would go pretty well.
Rym: There's a lot of Scottish people at this guy.
Scott: I think a packs in the UK anywhere in the english-speaking world.
Rym: They could probably rock a packs, you know, they could do like a French packs But they'd have to get like all local enforcers They could probably do a.
Scott: German packs would probably do equally the same.
Rym: I think so.
Rym: I think so All right, yeah, but I mean it was great.
Rym: The only problem with packs that anyone is that a real complaint about this is a legitimate concern Is that the main events hall was tiny like you did.
Rym: it was crazy.
Rym: at PAX West, you know The room doesn't fit everybody for like the concerts and everything But people if you wait like 20 minutes after the concert starts you can just get in and like the keynote
Scott: you could just get into the concerts at PAX East -
Rym: well the Friday concert definitely the Saturday concert was actually Almost like.
Rym: it was pretty much almost at capacity the whole time.
Scott: Yeah, but people are still walking in and out that you could go to the bathroom.
Scott: You can come back.
Rym: Yeah, you know, it was notice how the omega-thon finale and especially the keynote and the opening.
Rym: sir You know the stuff people really wanted to go that Every single person going to the con no matter what wanted to go to the keynote and the Q&A.
Scott: Well, those are those are times when there was.
Scott: there were seats in there.
Scott: Remember closing ceremonies had no seats.
Scott: Yeah, right So everyone can fit in and the doors were still well luckily because not everyone who was at the con went to that But the keynote and the open the queue and the first Q&A panel.
Scott: right they were at capacity.
Scott: I'm pretty sure I don't know this for certain cuz I didn't go to them.
Scott: that Q&A to you know Make a strip panel etc.
Scott: Were also capacity.
Scott: Yeah Cuz those were.
Scott: those are events in main events where the receipts and not just openness cuz that's the one thing about packs that anime Cons don't have.
Rym: the culture is definitely You go to everything in the main events or at least everything you want.
Rym: Like the main events kind of are the anchor of the whole con like they're the biggest things.
Rym: they're so big that like the majority people go to many of them.
Rym: and The trouble is just that that main events hall in this convention center is way too small.
Rym: Yeah, it has an upper deck, which is really nice, but it doesn't seem that many people up there I think they said the total capacity upper and lower was fifty five hundred people not enough.
Scott: No, they need like seven thousand.
Rym: cuz they were what there were I think about sixteen thousand people at PAX East.
Rym: Yeah They need a seven or eight thousand capacity main events or they need to move somewhere where they could fit the entire con.
Rym: Like Otakon does that well with the mariner arena they can fit the entire con into the cosplay thing.
Scott: Is it an anime convention?
Scott: The only main event anyone wants to go to is the cosplay?
Rym: Yeah, I feel like we could fix that.
Rym: I mean we gotta have more keynotes like the New York anime festival.
Rym: They did that.
Rym: they had a keynote and I think more compact.
Scott: they packed the room.
Scott: Yeah, it wasn't a big main events room, but it was the biggest room they had and they tried.
Scott: They were originally intending to put that in a smaller room.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, so it was.
Scott: it was good.
Rym: It proves that you can do it, but you know official news.
Rym: This is I'm sure it's out there.
Rym: It was announced at PAX to us by many people But PAX is moving and PAX East is not going to be at the Heinz Convention Center because the heinz is way too tiny.
Scott: We're gonna be it's still gonna be in Boston at a convention center We did not know existed called the BC EC and I have done a cursory amount of research.
Scott: The BC EC appears to be about as big as the Baltimore Convention Center, which is Otakon.
Rym: that but it's 20.
Scott: It might not it might not be exactly as big I think it is smaller, but it is still in that same size category.
Scott: You know gigantic rooms with hundreds of thousands of square feet with really tall ceiling But also many whole bunch of small rooms, you know the same sort of deal.
Scott: So PAX East will be in Boston in the BC EC Probably next year and probably for the next three years after that.
Rym: We'll see how that works.
Rym: I mean on one hand the convent that's bigger.
Rym: I mean even if it's the size of the BCC in Baltimore.
Rym: So 25,000 people packs could grow another 10,000 and then be at capacity again.
Rym: It's quite possible.
Rym: I think it'll sell out there no matter how many people they can fit.
Rym: Oh, I honestly think that the PAX East could have if there were no limit on registrations Forty to fifty thousand bodies not the bullshit turnstile They can see.
Scott: what I'm worried about mostly is that you know there because an enforcer is so great You know, they can have a very low ratio of enforcer to attend 80 enforcers to 16,000.
Scott: I don't think it was an 80 enforcers.
Rym: That's what they said.
Scott: Yeah, we'll see but there were about 80 enforcers.
Scott: We'll have to look that up.
Scott: Anyway, the thing is If you have if you spread the geography a gigantic convention center where covering ground is not trivial, right?
Scott: You're gonna need a lot more enforcers and they might have to accept every every person who applies.
Scott: It's gonna be pretty interesting.
Rym: Yeah, I don't think they should tear it.
Rym: If anything like even the lowest lowest like if you're just volunteering and all you're doing is directing people.
Rym: You're still an enforcer.
Rym: Yeah but they might have to tear up as opposed to tear down when you've got enforcers and Not totally committed enforcer but like arch enforcer they give them some cool title I don't know, but they're gonna need.
Scott: they're gonna need a lot of enforcers And if that's what you want to do, you should sign up.
Rym: Yes However, I point out a lot of the front row crew were enforcers.
Rym: a lot of people we know were enforcers.
Rym: Every single one of them said that they had an amazing time.
Rym: Yeah, it's totally awesome.
Scott: The only thing is like, you know, occasionally someone would be an enforcer and I'd be like, hey, let's go to dinner tonight.
Scott: They'd be like.
Scott: I got my shift, you know, but they didn't skip their shift.
Scott: They did not want to do it.
Scott: They went to the shift and enjoyed the shift.
Rym: Yeah, they row lost her voice as an enforcer teaching people how to play games.
Rym: That's not even she doesn't have to do that.
Rym: It's not like the enforcer like you have to spend four hours teaching people to play games.
Rym: She did that.
Rym: cuz it's fucking awesome.
Scott: Yep, and you know, it's like I can't do these other things you're doing cuz.
Scott: I got a shift for a part of the day But they didn't care.
Scott: they'd probably do it again.
Rym: Plus all I mean the PAX party for the enforcers I mean, I saw the tweets.
Rym: people like oh my god.
Rym: I got coup to sign something.
Rym: I got you know, Mike and Jerry to sign stuff.
Rym: Apparently was badass time.
Rym: No.
Rym: All right I was asleep.
Scott: So we got a list of things that went down at PAX.
Scott: you want to go down this list or we could go semi Chronologically.
Rym: go through our.
Scott: my list is not chronological.
Scott: So it's gonna be tough.
Scott: How about your list?
Rym: My list is not in any way chronological.
Scott: So let us just go down the lists and pick stuff.
Rym: All right, let's start right away with the main events because we know we get to PAX.
Rym: Well, no, let's go even further out because we got to do the meta about other cons.
Rym: So you get to PAX and there's no line because they mail out the badges.
Rym: Seriously any convention that's more than a couple thousand people.
Rym: You've got to mail out these fucking bad.
Scott: Yeah, I just I just picked up my badge for anime Boston like a couple hours ago, right?
Scott: There was basically no, you know, not much of a line.
Rym: It was like a 10-minute line But even then we had to wait and it was a little bit of trouble anyway.
Rym: Obviously they need look at all that they had like 20 staff and this is the Thursday badge pick up.
Rym: I don't know what the Friday is gonna be like but like 20 staffers have to sit there Thursday night for like five hours Doing these badges.
Rym: what if they just didn't do that at all and just mailed them at PAX?
Rym: every PAX We've walked up to zero line usually even like one staffer who's like, oh Here is says badge.
Rym: Shall I warm says crock pipe.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: I like a warm crack pipe Let me tell you and hacks is the only con that provides.
Rym: Yep So everyone already had their badges and that you know, the thing was gonna open.
Rym: we got in an hour early So we walked around all the stuff but there wasn't much to do.
Rym: basically all we did was wander around and look at all the stuff and Check out like, you know, like the steel battalion room.
Rym: We'll talk about later.
Scott: Well, yeah, there's a you know, basically here Here's all the rooms that they have at PAX.
Scott: They got the main events room.
Scott: Yeah, I got three panel rooms Naga wyvern and Naga wyvern was or was the serpent.
Scott: it wasn't serpent.
Scott: serpent was at PAX West manticore manticore.
Scott: There you go.
Scott: All right, they got three panel rooms.
Scott: We were only.
Scott: we were only in the wyvern theaters Sort of medium-sized, you know, the Naga was the biggest.
Scott: I didn't go in the manticore.
Rym: one I thought the manticore was the biggest.
Scott: was the matter remember at all?
Scott: Yeah, sure.
Rym: Awesome doesn't matter.
Rym: every panel filled up with rare exceptions.
Scott: There was the Tabletop gaming areas.
Scott: There are many of them.
Scott: There was the watsy areas, of course.
Rym: Yeah, there was like role-playing.
Scott: There are hallways outside of tabletop had stuff in them Like, you know watsy had a little thing going on and the.
Scott: there was many board game vendors out there You know selling dice selling games.
Rym: They had the new school console free play and the old-school console free play.
Rym: They had fun spot provided the old-school arcade and old-school a tiny old-school arcade.
Scott: That was pretty happening.
Rym: while it was pretty awesome I got to admit it wasn't even close to as awesome as the one that Katsucon used to have with video told me.
Scott: there was the Jam space provided by magfest where you can go and rock some music.
Rym: magfest, by the way We're going to.
Rym: just you guys all know I'm gonna announce it right now.
Rym: We're going no matter what.
Scott: Yeah, even if it's his attendees and we don't do anything.
Scott: Yeah, they hate us.
Rym: See we realize I you know, we met the people who run magfest.
Rym: They were like, hey you guys got to come our comms Awesome.
Rym: Well, no, they more they approach us.
Rym: They're like, would you guys be interested in coming?
Rym: It's not that big.
Rym: I were like magfest.
Rym: Hells.
Scott: Yeah Yeah I had heard of the magfest but I did not know.
Rym: you realize the.
Rym: the official yell of magfest is the colossus yell from the x-men arcade game.
Rym: Oh Yeah, man, if you're the blob nothing moves you don't go anywhere near magfest, yeah The expo hall which wasn't, you know, we peaked.
Rym: we could look in but they didn't let us in early.
Scott: Yeah, we did walk around the expo hall.
Scott: It was not really as it had the same sort of level of you know Big-time companies, but I didn't have the quantity that the PAX West Xbox West had the turtle van.
Scott: Yeah, I mean I walked through the PAX East expo hall basically once looked at a bunch of stuff and that was it.
Rym: I know there was no line to get in.
Rym: We just walked right in the whole con.
Rym: You just walk right in walk around.
Rym: Yeah, I think part of it was there weren't that many crazy new games being I mean what there was Starcraft 2 but everyone cares about it like really there's a tournament of it.
Rym: Yes, but everyone who already cares about it already has a pirated cop or the beta or yeah They're playing like they're hacked beta like they've got their thing a big thing in the expo hall.
Scott: number one above everything else is sim 5 Civ 5, Civ 5.
Rym: See Civ 3 was a revolution like they changed everything they made like they added culture like it was a brand new game.
Rym: Civ 4 was Civ 3 Perfected in my opinion like they took everything that was good in Civ 3.
Scott: Civ 5 is a brand new game again.
Rym: Yeah, so this is Thing is?
Rym: I jumped on the Civ 5 bandwagon.
Rym: I was sort of mad.
Scott: on Civ 5 I was like, all right another Civ.
Rym: I knew some of the change but then you saw the same thing.
Rym: I saw that poster of George Washington like he's like.
Scott: And I'm like, yes, George.
Scott: I'll play Civ 5.
Scott: Take me take my money.
Scott: Here you go.
Rym: Well, the thing is I'm walking around the revolution.
Rym: I saw that poster.
Rym: I was like, oh shit There's another one for Bismarck with his pointy hat just looking at me like I will disapprove you do not play Civ 5.
Rym: But then I saw this other poster of this hex board.
Rym: I'm like, oh is this like a settlers game or something?
Rym: Then I realized that's Civ 5 Hexes.
Scott: Civ 5 is the win.
Scott: actually you could have.
Scott: the reason there was a big line was not to play Civ 5.
Scott: It was to sign up to go see the Civ 5 demo which is sort of private.
Scott: our poor friend Scott Johnson God Johnson got to go see the Civ 5.
Rym: However, he got shafted out of it like twice before he got it Like.
Scott: he did eventually get it though and he told us about a whole bunch of awesome shit in Civ 5.
Scott: We'll have to maybe interview.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: thing is what am I gonna do?
Rym: We could do like a preview of Civ 5, but here's the deal.
Rym: This is like NS2.
Rym: I'm buying it pre-order sight unseen.
Scott: Yeah, I'm putting all my eggs in that that might even buy the retail if it comes with a big book.
Rym: You know some get some games, you know, like when Smash Brothers Melee came out you're like, you know what?
Rym: I'm gonna be all in from the start.
Rym: I'm gonna buy this game today.
Rym: I'm gonna play it that entire day.
Rym: Yep, I'm not taking a day off at work for Civ 5 because it's gonna be a single-player.
Rym: It's gonna be a single-player experience for a while before we multiplayer it.
Scott: You want to talk about the other expo hall stuff?
Rym: Yeah, there was some cool stuff in there actually like Monday night combat.
Scott: I'm actually well thing is Monday night combat.
Scott: It looks like a Team Fortress kind of game, right?
Scott: But it's third-person Xbox kind of situation.
Scott: Well, there's a class.
Rym: it looks and like the play looks and feels just from watching other people play it Exactly, like all those awesome old like quake 2 mods felt.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: The only thing it is not an FPS There's a sport.
Scott: The only thing with it is as one of those, you know upgrading things.
Scott: But the thing is right the upgrades.
Scott: They sort of validate them.
Scott: like the way it works is if you're good at playing Monday night combat Which is a sport right a sport.
Scott: you get people Virtual people to sponsor you.
Scott: like Tiger Woods is sponsored by Nike and they being your sponsors, you know And you know you endorsing their products they give you their better products.
Scott: you get better endorsements as you get better.
Scott: So they actually have a metaphor for the upgrades that make sense.
Scott: That doesn't make them feel like cheating.
Scott: I mean is Tiger Woods cheating when he gets better golf clubs from Nike?
Scott: No, so am I cheating if I get plus three guns from gun soft in Monday night combat?
Scott: It does it, you know, it doesn't feel like it's unfair.
Rym: Well part of it It'll depend on how because they explained it.
Rym: so it'll depend a lot about how the game actually is.
Rym: I mean we watched it and the gameplay looked right up our alley.
Rym: It looked twitchy.
Rym: It looked like control mattered.
Rym: It looked like there was some asymmetry like the classes and everything.
Rym: it had all the look of like a weapons factors.
Scott: I didn't actually play it though.
Scott: So we're gonna see when it comes out.
Scott: I'm gonna try out some demo if they have one and then I'll buy it.
Rym: maybe I think it's a game that could foster a Community like a community of players like I really get into it.
Rym: if they start like.
Rym: if they made like videos of games and highlights Like what if they made a show for this game that was like the highlights this week from all the servers?
Rym: That'd be cool.
Rym: They could really do something with this all points bulletin.
Rym: I heard tell that this might be a subscription model game in which case I'm almost done with it.
Rym: Yeah, I just give.
Scott: well, there was a very old game called all points bullet and actually played it at fun spot.
Rym: Yeah, I used to play a game at tilt when I was.
Scott: yeah, it's basically a driving game where you pull up behind Criminals and pull the your cop and you pull them over your driving guy litters you pull them over.
Rym: Oh, no, really You know what that game was.
Rym: you crash into every wall because it's really hard then you lose and put another quarter And when you crash you get demerits and too many demerits you get fired and that that cop with the big fat gut and the Cigar yells at you.
Scott: Yeah, so there's a new game and it's basically it looks like Grand Theft Auto, right?
Scott: except it's versus.
Scott: some people are enforcers and some people are criminals and the criminals are trying to crime and the enforcer people are Trying to enforce to uncry man.
Rym: I cry.
Rym: Yeah a bite.
Scott: So it's like a versus multiplayer grant team Grand Theft Auto and that is cool.
Scott: But if it's a subscription game screw that it depends it.
Rym: What if it was what we always wanted like a large Persistent actually massive actually multi.
Rym: It's not.
Scott: it's like a four-on-four instanced kind of game.
Scott: Yeah, that's what it looked.
Rym: You know, we got to see we.
Rym: I mean literally all we saw of it was we watch people play it from online.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, those people all sucked at it.
Rym: Yeah, I watched one guy like he's.
Rym: he gets in a car He's like chasing a criminal and he literally gets in the car drives about two feet and then just like swerves right into a pole We played what was the game called afro bot or something like that?
Rym: It was basically robotron.
Scott: It was basically robotron, you know, then we played the multiplayer which is versus robotron.
Scott: Which was?
Scott: it was?
Rym: obviously it was a beta like it was on like the Nintendo dev.
Scott: It was on the Wii on a Nintendo dev kit, right?
Scott: It was okay.
Rym: We spend more time looking at the dev kit like oh, we've never seen one in person.
Rym: Check this out.
Scott: Yeah, but this the the single player is robotron Zelda.
Scott: like you walk from room to room getting items that let you go to new Areas and you get you know open up secrets.
Scott: But you know, I'm just imagine if Zelda Zelda 1 instead of stabbing a sword You use two sticks one to move and one to shoot just like robotron style.
Scott: That's what this game is and that's pretty freaking cool.
Rym: I'm excited for that single player and while I would prefer the kind of you know Two sticks they actually did pretty well with the idea that you move with you know The stick but then use the wiimote to kind of like turn and it works.
Scott: Yeah, it does the control work just fine.
Scott: It was.
Scott: the versus was fun.
Rym: It was broken because you know It was like this demo obviously and Alex was like in the upper corner and I just kept shooting bouncy balls at the corner And he's gonna leave.
Rym: I blew myself up.
Scott: You know if Atari combat had better controls than it does on the Atari combat We were the best fucking games ever it does.
Scott: But if it had perfect controls You could just lock someone into a corner and keep nailing him and nailing him and nailing him and it be over.
Rym: now because you make The maps different.
Rym: you put constraints in.
Rym: the map we played on was not complex enough to offer an interesting sort of game But what this proves is that more and more what I like are these games that are very direct distilled combat between people.
Scott: Well combat.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Oh, so what was the name of that Yakuza game?
Rym: We were looking at Yakuza because we'd heard.
Rym: I heard about this game, but I didn't really think about it.
Scott: Yeah, I knew there was a game called Yakuza.
Scott: I knew it was popular.
Scott: I knew people liked it, but I never played it and they had it at the Sega booth and I played it.
Scott: I didn't realize that it was.
Scott: you know At least the newest version is a full Yakuza simulator 100%.
Scott: every aspect of Yakuza life from drinking alcohol to playing pool to driving cool cars to everything Yakuza does is fully simulated.
Scott: there is the when you play pool.
Scott: it might as well be a full-on billiards game like 100%.
Scott: you could take that out of the game and sell it on its own as a billiards game.
Scott: that is better than most.
Rym: I Mean I think the moment where I realized I didn't like I was wrong about this game is when Scott You know he plays and he walks into his Hawaiian shirt like you do Yakuza.
Rym: then he walks into a fancy bar and he goes up to the bartender.
Rym: the bartender's like, you know He says some things and they sit down and then it gives you this menu of like a hundred different kinds of beer and sake And wine.
Rym: so we go down.
Rym: Scott buys like this heap of sake and then it gives you like this Multiparagraph explanation of like.
Rym: well, this is this kind of sake.
Rym: these kinds of people drink it It tastes like this.
Rym: and then a little bit about the history of like Yakuza drinking.
Scott: and after I drank it I got some experience points.
Rym: You're leveling up yours that Yakuza ways.
Rym: I kind of want to be a Yakuza now.
Rym: Yeah, that was a good game or the very least.
Rym: I want to go to Japan.
Rym: We're like a Hawaiian shirt.
Rym: Maybe you have like a big fake tattoo and just walk around like the guys in Yakuza and scare everybody.
Scott: The only other thing I remember from the expo hall because I didn't spend too much time in there was that Nvidia actually dimmed live demos of its 3d stuff.
Scott: Yeah, which I mean I could do with my video shuttered glasses that are wired into the thing and then the screen.
Rym: they were wireless Polarized that wasn't.
Scott: I thought it was the shuttered ones with the battery But they weren't wired in anything.
Rym: that was the don't steal me wire.
Rym: Okay, and it's 3d.
Rym: It's just I don't know It's not worth the money yet.
Rym: I mean a weighty.
Scott: it goes deep in but it doesn't pop out.
Scott: but that was a Apparently a decision of the game developer not a decision of you know You could make a game where the 3d comes out of the screen But people seem to only do it where it goes deep into the screen.
Rym: I can see why cuz pop out is really disconcerting.
Rym: if pop out and then you change your angle and then like goes off the edge Of the screen it disappears.
Rym: Yeah, and it looked great.
Rym: It's just My opinion as a gamer is that if you just wait like a year, it'll be ubiquitous.
Rym: Just wait until you buy a new computer and the video card has the two DVI outs for 3d and just comes with the glasses.
Rym: Yeah, they will come.
Scott: I'm gonna wait until it's like a standard.
Scott: It's set in stone not while it's still some flaky thing.
Scott: Ati had their a demo of the whatever they call it where you can get a shit ton of monitors on one video card.
Scott: They had four HDMI outs coming out of one card.
Scott: It was.
Scott: it was pretty ridiculous.
Rym: now doing it in like the wall mode like six monitors was kind of annoying because you have the bars But when they play the racing games, there's just.
Scott: I think I think it was eight and they had an SLI.
Scott: Well, I don't know if ati calls it SLI But they had a two card setup with eight display port cables going to eight ultra sharps in a two by four Right.
Scott: That was pretty impressive.
Scott: But the racing who and who is really gonna get right?
Scott: I mean buying one video card that is for display port outs.
Scott: That's pretty good because you can get two ultra sharps and hook them up frickin sweet.
Scott: Yeah, right getting with three video cards with eight Nobody has eight ultra sharps.
Scott: It is not gonna happen.
Rym: However, you know who's gonna use that?
Rym: a lot of companies who get demo their games are gonna do that people like in exhibit halls Maybe conventions.
Rym: I think that's not.
Scott: it's not useful for normal people unless you're crazy.
Scott: However, the thing didn't have a demo though of a three screen setup, you know, you could do like a racing game Like you're really into racing games or when FPS is support that better.
Rym: I'd have to see like how like older FPS is would handle that.
Rym: because if I had you know The three for the peripheral vision, you know I was always big back in the quake days of playing with like the 120 fov and the like the fisheye Just so I could see around my back.
Scott: That's pretty much the expo.
Rym: Oh, there's the warioware DIY, which they didn't play for it.
Rym: People seem to really like it.
Scott: Yeah, Nintendo had a tiny booth with warioware and Pokemon gold and silver which were ubiquitous at the con anyway, so whatever we didn't even bother to wait.
Scott: We just said oh look warioware.
Scott: Okay We'll see it one day.
Rym: So, you know, what do you do with these kinds of mail all the badges?
Scott: I mean you just go get the badge if you don't have it already like, you know Cuz they don't mail out the panelist badges.
Scott: They only mail out the attendee.
Rym: Yep, so we had to go pick up our badges as a result.
Rym: We didn't get a Charlie card.
Rym: I just spent like money to get a Charlie ticket that cost more than a Charlie card, whatever.
Scott: But anyway, we did manage to get you know, the lanyards which are in the bags of goodies Which are just they're just sitting there and these big bins in the queue room and you just take them.
Scott: You can take more than one.
Scott: They don't give a shit.
Rym: now You might not think about it, especially, you know, a lot of PAX people don't go to like anime cons.
Rym: But fan cons especially anime cons It used to be like the goodie bag would have crazy goodies in it like DVDs of stuff.
Scott: the PAX West Goodie bag actually crazy stuff.
Scott: I mean it didn't.
Scott: it's sort of crazy.
Scott: You know that.
Scott: first of all, they were there's the little DS game with the pins.
Scott: They didn't have that.
Scott: that was just yeah.
Rym: That was actually sorely lacking via distributed tournament system.
Scott: Yeah the DTS they didn't have.
Scott: Like I remember at PAX West you would get they had a full case of.
Scott: it was Lord of the Rings online the game.
Scott: It was a full game.
Scott: But of course it was a game of the subscription.
Scott: No one was giving you a full game.
Scott: that really for free.
Rym: Maybe we should find out.
Rym: we should put something awesome in those bags like pay to do it.
Scott: Yeah, why not?
Scott: So here's what comes in the bag, right?
Scott: So you get the program with the awesome art on it, of course, right?
Scott: The program is you know, it's alright.
Scott: it has all the information you need about tournaments and schedules and a map.
Rym: It's got the same aesthetic as the PAX West.
Rym: one is basically the PAX West.
Scott: It's got a description of every event, you know, and all these things got a lot of notes pages.
Scott: The only thing with this is that they don't give you this is the only place you're gonna have the schedule that you can carry Around.
Scott: they don't give you a separate pocket schedule.
Scott: So you have to carry this whole thing around to you and keep you know Referring to it.
Scott: if you had a pocket schedule, you could just leave this in your room.
Rym: This is one of the few things where we think, you know, usually we say oh the anime cons could all learn from packs.
Rym: This is one situation where packs could learn from the anime cons.
Rym: a one-page pocket schedule Would just be great and it wouldn't cost that much to stick it in the bag All right, maybe put an ad on it.
Scott: So other than that you get a bunch of flyers.
Scott: Here's one for let's see Magic is a gathering.
Scott: Here's goozex.com, which is a website.
Scott: Oh, this is that sort of scam ish website where you you send you trade games and get points.
Scott: you with the points you earn You can get games and they get a cut somehow.
Rym: We're basically giving free advertising to everyone who paid.
Scott: I guess.
Scott: Yeah, anyway play on whatever Flame on Dolby axon.
Scott: Okay, it's probably some audio gaming thing.
Scott: Cge classic gaming expo 2010.
Scott: Oh, where is this?
Rym: Yeah, maybe we should go Vegas.
Rym: Alright new egg was in the room.
Rym: Yeah new egg was in the house.
Scott: We actually talked to an Intel guy about some chips and stuff.
Rym: Yeah, we were asked him why the smallest ones like the ones you want on your like my home media PC don't have HDMI out.
Rym: He was like, yeah, I know it kind of sucks.
Rym: I think it technologists not there yet.
Scott: Yeah These people are selling some computers.
Scott: He explosion man that games.
Scott: Alright, and Here's the only interesting things that were in the bag.
Scott: Alright, so first of all, right you Got this Magic magic money the wasting magic the gathering and the thing is most of the time they give you like some boosters.
Scott: You know, maybe they give you a booster.
Rym: what you throw away or give to a kid He's waiting to do with a booster.
Rym: This is an entire day.
Scott: This is enough cards to play magic the gathering and not only that.
Scott: it comes with the rules how to play.
Rym: Oh, I gotta read those.
Rym: cuz the last time I read him was revised.
Scott: Yeah, and look at this Here is a full 40 card deck, right?
Scott: It's all green.
Rym: They give you a 15 forests, you know, and then they give you any artifacts or just green.
Scott: No, it's just green.
Scott: Right, they give you 15 and they give you a whole bunch of creatures and then like a handful of instances it's like if you play that Magic game that's on the Xbox is the same kind of deck that you're gonna find in that game.
Scott: You know a real simple straightforward deck.
Rym: What was amazing is, you know walking around the con like before it opened just out.
Rym: Everyone's playing magic like people had magic out and they were playing these decks and a lot of these weren't people who brought magic cards With them.
Scott: there's are people who just busted these decks out and played this magic that they got.
Rym: Multiple groups that I ran into were like two guys like us who had played magic in the past Teaching someone who had never played it how it worked with these decks.
Scott: And the thing is I got the green one, right which is random.
Scott: I want if I would have could have chosen I would have chosen green but the I just picked it in video bag, you know, and this is the one that was in there and I could have gone through back to the bag bin and looted and gotten one of every different color.
Scott: I think there were five different decks that were available.
Scott: I think you got a different color.
Rym: I didn't even look.
Scott: you didn't look I don't know.
Rym: I think Emily took my bag home.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: Oh, whatever, but yeah full playable deck of magic cards.
Scott: That was a good call by them.
Scott: Not that I support the playing of magic.
Scott: The final thing that was in the bag was this this very important card, which I have kept that the omega-thon card The omega-thon card big change at PAX East from PAX West.
Scott: I can see why they changed.
Scott: it Is that they used to.
Scott: when you pre-reg for PAX West There'd be a box that you would check and say yes I want to be an omega.
Scott: not the problem with this was that You know, they would call people up and say you wanna be omega.
Scott: not, you know.
Scott: You check the box and they would say oh no, you know, they couldn't get people to confirm.
Scott: It was a lot of work calling people on the phone such and such and such.
Rym: I still can't understand that.
Rym: I mean if Mike and Jerry called me like hey, you're an omega not I would just been like People, you know?
Scott: not people had to prepare to be an omega.
Scott: not they would train right and they.
Scott: it was very inaccessible very difficult And people might not show up to the convention unreliable.
Scott: It's a big pain in the ass.
Scott: So this way anyone who is applying to be an omega not does so at the con, you know, they're there.
Rym: But even then so they passed him out, you know You you toss these in as you walked into.
Scott: that was a problem.
Scott: Is that you toss them in the bag as you go to the keynote?
Scott: So the the entrance to the keynote was slowed down by people tossing cards in the back.
Rym: It was great.
Rym: We get there, you know, basically, you know We got in early.
Rym: as we wander around and then we hear this noise And we were standing like in the front of where the main events are gonna be and we see the line Being led in by all these enforcers walking backwards like holding them barely at bay.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And then we see this one enforcer with this little basket to catch the omega-thon cards and he looks around like oh shit Robert coo actually came over with a big bin.
Rym: He's like, alright, I got this.
Scott: Yeah But you know The point was is that this is a better system in all ways except for the fact that they had to slow down that.
Rym: and no But here's the amazing part.
Rym: So people took these filled them out and put them in as they walked in.
Scott: and Then what about people who didn't go to the King, you know, well, you gotta want it.
Rym: I mean, it's the omega-thon You gotta want it.
Rym: They can't just make it really easy.
Rym: You've got to want it in some way.
Scott: I mean if you the pigeons not get just jumping into your I think it would have been better to do it the same way.
Scott: That like baseball stadiums have the all-star voting that she just had bins about that were omega-thon.
Rym: I know cuz look even There's the point I was gonna do even with you.
Rym: turn them in as you walk into the event where they will announce them.
Rym: They had like six people who were called up not be there.
Rym: Remember they recalled they called up the alts.
Rym: Yep I don't know what was up with that.
Scott: I don't know what's up with that either.
Scott: It doesn't matter They got the people they needed.
Scott: the omega-thon happened.
Rym: I like the fact that it was all co-op all the way through.
Rym: I think that was a really.
Rym: it gave the omega-thon at PAX East a totally different style.
Scott: Yeah, the thing was I felt it was.
Scott: while it was a different style and the co-op was awesome It was less epic.
Rym: It was dated.
Scott: They did one omega-thon round on its own as an event.
Scott: omega-thon round two was before the concerts on Friday.
Scott: Round three was before the concerts on Saturday and the final round was the closing ceremony I want.
Rym: it was good that there was one.
Scott: there was one less round.
Rym: Yeah usually five round but it was good that they put them before these big events like you.
Rym: go to the concert and You see the omega-thon.
Rym: They didn't take up panel room space.
Rym: They weren't like out and about.
Scott: it was also less epic.
Scott: It wasn't like this thing that was going on that you would follow.
Rym: They didn't have the big board with all the people's faces and they would cross them out, you know I think my guess I didn't actually ask you because notice how they didn't say anything about the omega-thon for a long time and then Suddenly they busted out.
Rym: My guess is they were planning on not doing an omega-thon the first year and just you know Making sure the con happened and then when they realized that it was gonna easily be bigger than PAX OS Like it is going to be as I go said the real packs.
Rym: Yeah, they were like, ah shit.
Rym: We gotta have an omega-thon.
Scott: Yep so they did it.
Rym: either that or not.
Rym: once we now that we know what the final round was because while the other three rounds were Kind of met the final round was I would say the most epic final round they've ever had.
Rym: like that was crazy I don't know.
Scott: I think that the versus excite bike was the most epic round.
Scott: I'm sure plus there were rounds We haven't seen.
Rym: well final round.
Rym: I mean the ones before.
Rym: that I don't know.
Rym: The excite bike one definitely was awesome and I see a lot of people talking about it.
Rym: I guess only time will tell.
Rym: maybe they were equally epic in different ways.
Rym: Maybe alright, so So the keynote, you know, we all file in it's standing room only Originally, they weren't letting people go out to pee and I gotta tell you I really had to pee.
Scott: I actually walked out in the middle of Will's keynote And I soon and you wouldn't be able to get back in.
Rym: Yes, but then as I walked out there's an enforcer.
Rym: I was like, dude, I'm a special guest.
Rym: I got a pee and he's like, I'll let you back in Mmm, and he totally let me back in and I got back.
Rym: But we'll eat and you know, well, we'll.
Rym: wheaten to pronounce it correctly gave the keynote.
Rym: He's given a packs keynote before.
Rym: I'm curious Specifically like on the inside why they picked.
Rym: well because it at least from the way he told it they kind of threw this at him.
Rym: He was like, I don't know if I want to do it.
Rym: Okay, I'll do it.
Rym: so I wonder if it was because Maybe they couldn't get anyone in time.
Rym: Maybe like I don't know what the planning process was actually for paxies, but He gave a good keynote in the end though.
Scott: It was okay.
Scott: It wasn't epic though.
Scott: It wasn't like.
Scott: oh man, that was the greatest, you know, it was just.
Scott: it was no cakey, you know.
Scott: It was.
Rym: I'll admit it was kind of a letdown from the last two packs keynotes We saw because those were just one there.
Rym: They had like slides.
Rym: They were much more kind of professionally delivered.
Rym: There was much less woo game going on.
Rym: Well, I love you All right But you played the woo game the game that we've done everything in our power to crush Since we started doing panels.
Rym: your that whole part of your speech was basically Final Fantasy and the crowd goes.
Rym: You were just tricking the crowd into saying woo.
Rym: You were taking social currency and throwing it at them and then getting that to reflect back on you.
Rym: And I used to do that at panels.
Rym: I don't anymore.
Rym: I know better.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Do not play the woo game.
Scott: It was very disappointing to see the woo game played at the keynote of all places.
Scott: Yeah, I got understand like a small lowbrow panel playing the woo game.
Rym: I guess it's just the last two keynotes that PAX West.
Rym: I was like deeply inspired by them because they were all kind of the same story of like a narrative of Why gaming is important like not just why it's important to us as gamers.
Rym: That's a big part of it.
Rym: But really like gaming is important in ways beyond everything in this room and they were really inspired.
Rym: I remember being moved almost to tears tears in a row just like feeling like this is it?
Rym: and that feeling After I remembered oh, yeah I'm here to play some games but But definitely like you felt that like that catch in the heart of like gaming matters and we're on the cusp of gaming becoming You know the great the next great media after writing.
Scott: Yeah, and well we tried to say gaming man He did.
Rym: he said that he said it really well But then he got it kept going with the woo game for a while and then he did that whole.
Rym: you know spoil some games for people bid and I feel like His keynote should have been shorter and just done the inspiring part or he should have had more inspiring things to say.
Rym: Yeah, it was a good keynote.
Rym: Don't get us wrong.
Rym: It was good.
Rym: It was solid.
Rym: people really liked it.
Rym: It's just I'm comparing it to the two keynotes prior that I think were better.
Scott: Yeah, anyway Let's see.
Scott: What else was going to?
Scott: Oh immediately following the keynote, right?
Scott: I attempted my vision.
Rym: So we had a vision right and the vision was you know gave in taiko.
Rym: they come out every year and they play that song Every day, I'm hustling every day.
Rym: I'm hustling right so they Play.
Scott: vision was to have the entire keynote and main events singing the song Before the song played and then singing with the song and then they would come out and it'd be epic.
Scott: and
Rym: we learned how to Do this like we've tried this sort of thing a long time ago when we were young and stupid at Otakon and it failed Miserably, but then no years of experience and a college humor video of a lone dancing nut job causes a movement of how to make a movement in a crowd.
Rym: so we just took that exact method and we planned it and we had people around who were waiting for the queue and Scott was gonna start.
Scott: I was worried right.
Scott: I was worried because I was you know during the time in between the end of the keynote in the beginning of the Q&A They might have Right played some music or something and I would have to overpower this music with the vision
Rym: or it might have been a long Wait, like what if they attend kill difficulties like Pax is known for and you know you started and then there's a half hour.
Scott: It's not gonna be able to keep me going for a half hour or it'll become the most epic thing ever like Bohemian Rhapsody.
Rym: But that will talk about that.
Scott: The thing is the worst case scenario happened immediately as the keynote applause ended.
Scott: They started playing the song.
Scott: So what was I supposed to do?
Scott: but vision was a failure?
Rym: I'm sad, but I'm also glad.
Rym: I'm sad because the vision failed.
Rym: It's always sad when a vision dies But I'm glad because there was zero technical failure.
Rym: It was the perfect most professional transition from keynote Q&A.
Rym: Yep, now the Q&A at PAX is special and we're trying to know a bunch of our friends weren't gonna go.
Rym: They're like, I don't want to see some Q&A people.
Scott: always there's no reason they go to the second Q&A But you gotta go to the first one.
Rym: I don't know if I missed the first one.
Rym: I would go to the second one That's right.
Scott: Yeah, that'd be true if they scheduled a panel during the first one.
Rym: Plus, you know funny things happen at the second one.
Rym: Like it's a good deal It's more, you know, what do you care about at the con?
Rym: We had to you know, remind everyone that the Q&A at PAX is not just fanboys asking stupid questions.
Rym: It's people usually asking good questions.
Rym: Like I'd say there's a 60 to 70 percent hit rate of good questions versus fanboy.
Scott: It's not just questions.
Scott: either people get up and do stuff or will announce things You know like at the last PAX Prime those guys brought a cardboard cutout.
Rym: other friend who couldn't come and they're like Can we do it again?
Scott: dude in front of me in line called his friend who couldn't make it on the phone and everyone Yells.
Scott: so it was someone's birthday and we all said happy birthday.
Scott: asshole.
Rym: at the second Q&A like someone or it was one of the Other events someone was like, will you play Thunderstone with me?
Rym: This game is up you guys's alley and then they you know from the Q&A They organized.
Rym: so the people on stage and this guy and someone else in the audience at another microphone about to ask a question All scheduled a game of Thunderstone.
Rym: then they all met and they played it.
Rym: Yeah, it's kind of a. it's like this Give-and-take like the knuckle crack happens.
Scott: Yeah, the knuckle crack very important Tradition.
Rym: no one Rick rolled the audience.
Rym: No, no one Rick roll surprised.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: No, but I Pulled off some epic.
Scott: It wasn't that epic.
Rym: It was epic.
Scott: Look at how epic was it?
Rym: It was epic in the sense that you know, we got it up online and the first planned it Well in advance, it wasn't like some improvisational genius.
Rym: The thing is we planned it so far ahead, but you know this sort of thing There's such a fine line between.
Rym: that is awesome.
Rym: And you're a douchebag.
Scott: Yeah, like the line is so narrow So basically we're doing this action castle panel and I said, you know what right?
Scott: I told Jared the creator of action castle Look, you should go to the Q&A you mean?
Rym: action Castle.
Scott: I told them look you can go to the Q&A go up and as your question just stand up and say welcome to action castle And start playing it and then after a few minutes or whatever after your time is up You know.
Scott: basically don't stand there forever Just say you know.
Scott: This concludes the trial version of action castle.
Scott: to play the full version come to the Wyvern theater on Sunday 30.
Rym: Scott tried to convince him like four times to do this and at PAX the last moment He's like, will you do it?
Rym: and Jared's like.
Rym: basically Jared said Scott.
Rym: I'm in fact a wuss.
Rym: I'm not going to do this I'm going to be a total wuss and fam.
Scott: So I said do you want me to do it?
Scott: and he was like, it would be awesome if you did it.
Scott: So I did it.
Rym: so, you know, we're sitting there and Scott lines up and he goes.
Rym: you can see the YouTube video But the crowd went fucking nuts.
Scott: people seem to really like it far more than I expect.
Rym: well taiko It's funny cuz.
Rym: taiko got it.
Scott: I knew he would get it.
Scott: I knew that Mike wouldn't get it at all.
Rym: He's Mike.
Rym: I think he got it at least enough.
Rym: He was more playing to the crowd.
Rym: I mean his whole.
Rym: what the fuck do you want from me?
Rym: That was good for the vibe of the whole thing I guess but it went on the perfect amount of time like the crowd was losing it when he's like.
Rym: what the fuck do you Want from me?
Rym: like I don't know how to what the fuck?
Rym: the crowd just like the microphone on my camera was like busted By how loud everybody was and just at the moment when it was about to go on too long It was gonna move from awesome to douchebag.
Rym: He did.
Rym: Mike is like what can you say to end this?
Scott: and then he's like say whatever will make him stop.
Scott: He's like quit.
Rym: and then you did.
Rym: it was so epic.
Rym: I was so happy about that and it was on joystick.
Rym: So yeah, very action castle and you know people lined up.
Scott: Yep So I guess that about wraps up that morning, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Let's leave it recording.
Rym: Let's do another thing.
Scott: Let's do the tabletop area.
Scott: Yeah, go through all the games you were playing.
Scott: All right.
Rym: So as we were want to do at PAX is we spend a lot of time in tabletop because it's quiet For we can play some games that we like to play with sit down.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: It's all.
Scott: it's a hot place to be.
Rym: Yeah, it's one of my favorite parts of packs other than the concerts the Q&A and the keynote.
Scott: So we played a bunch of games.
Scott: so we go over there and I checked out this game Bacchus banquet.
Scott: But I didn't get to play it because I ended up teaching some awesome The listener rising through the ranks chase Gordon and his friends how to play.
Rym: he's Gordon.
Scott: You're like one of my favorite fans at this point Yeah, so I taught him and his friends how to play and then I got roped into actually playing.
Scott: It's a Rym played Bacchus banquet.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Tell us about Bacchus back.
Rym: So Bacchus bankruptcy way back.
Scott: We picked it up based on the theme alone.
Rym: We bought another game that the cover is basically bohemian bot not bohemian bot.
Rym: That's the movie that Emily's freedomism by is a bot And the theme of that game is you're all Roman nobles trying to get all your shit together.
Rym: Get the fuck out of Rome before the Visigoth comes and kills you and you got to get to Carthage.
Scott: You're it safe.
Rym: The cover is this this guy all fat with wine and women going great And in the background Rome is burning.
Rym: Yep, like over the ocean.
Rym: It's so beautiful.
Rym: So that game was not actually that good.
Rym: This game is much better.
Rym: Bacchus banquet the glory and gluttony of Rome.
Rym: So everybody plays as up like a character from the Caligula era.
Rym: Awesome, and everyone has a secret role, but one person plays openly as Caligula.
Scott: Can I be Caligula's horse?
Rym: So let me tell you what.
Rym: Caligula.
Rym: the the graphic on the card, you know your identity card like Octavius or whatever Caligula's card is one of the funniest goddamn things I've ever seen.
Rym: like you look at this thing and you cannot help but laugh all right, so Caligula plays openly everyone else plays secretly and It's kind of a every round, you know?
Rym: You put seven cards up and some of them are like a dish and some of them are wine and some of them are poison and stuff like this.
Rym: and You're you have a score that is your belt buckle Yeah, and if it great you keep having to widen it the more you eat and drink.
Rym: if it goes above ten you die.
Rym: So poison just fills your belt buckle like nine points.
Scott: Oh, so you gotta have zero to and you can handle the poison.
Rym: Yeah, and some things can make it go down like having sex Or taking a nap.
Rym: And it's this.
Rym: dinner parties.
Rym: every round one player whoever's the active player picks three cards openly from the table.
Rym: So maybe a poison a day and the dishes to like the.
Rym: you have goals like one player will win if he eats just eight Dishes.
Rym: that's all he wants.
Rym: one player want one card wants like three points of wine and four dishes.
Rym: Caligula has these different.
Rym: everyone wants different stuff.
Rym: But some of the dishes are like a lobster belt one and it counts as one dish.
Rym: One of the dishes is an entire deer and it's just a plate with this deer like laying on it and it's five points.
Scott: So widens your belt buckle by half the way, but it only counts as one dish, but half kills you.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, so so that's a bad one to get depending.
Rym: so you pick the three and then you shuffle them up.
Rym: You put one face down on your sheet.
Rym: You're saying I will eat this one On my turn.
Rym: then you take one.
Rym: you say I'm discarding this one.
Rym: you take one and offer it to another player as a gift.
Rym: They can choose to either eat it right then flip it over.
Scott: So they have a one in three chance of knowing what it is basically.
Scott: they know it's one of those three.
Rym: Yes so they can either flip it over and apply it to themselves immediately or gift it to someone else who hasn't had it yet.
Rym: if Everyone regifts whoever was the active player has to eat it.
Scott: But so you want to To become.
Rym: there's only one way to become the active player and that is to accept a gift and not die.
Rym: and the only other part of the game really is that Everyone has a special ability like a card you draw randomly.
Rym: You can use it once in the entire game.
Rym: you just flip it over and use it.
Rym: and there are things like take the card that the active player was gonna keep and use it on yourself or Take a card that was gifted to you and force whoever gifted it to you to eat it right there.
Rym: If you die, you just you throw away your card.
Rym: you died.
Rym: you draw another player card and keep going.
Rym: Oh whoever makes their goal You can still win.
Scott: like if you get close to your goal people are gonna attack you you're gonna die.
Scott: You're gonna get sent back to zero, but everyone might get sent back to zero.
Scott: So being close to winning isn't necessarily close to winning.
Rym: Yeah, you can get killed and everyone is secret except Caligula plays openly.
Rym: so you can try to you know.
Rym: Con people into.
Scott: so what if Caligula dies, so if Caligula soap, here's the deal.
Rym: There are two women to those roles and all they want is a bunch of gifts.
Rym: There's like three old men and two other women and they just want to eat and drink in different quantities of food and wine.
Rym: Caligula wants to eat some and drink a whole bunch or if any three people die he wins.
Rym: Then there are the three conspirators if Caligula dies or if there are three daggers Which is one of the gifts in play at the same time.
Rym: They all win Mmm, so they're trying to get the daggers in play or feed man.
Scott: That would have helped Rome a lot.
Rym: No, Caligula, okay, but it's basically Citadels.
Rym: it is not a good game from game theory, you know our beyond candyland panel.
Rym: It is just.
Scott: but would you.
Scott: would you play instead of all my girls or would you pick citadel?
Rym: They're both important because they're a party game.
Rym: They're really fun.
Rym: They're the who poison the cup game and you can if you get into it in roleplay and It's citadels without the building part of the game.
Rym: It's just the poison in the cup, you know second-guessing.
Scott: So would you play?
Scott: would you picks?
Scott: if you're sitting there and citadels and Bacchus Bank Which one did you pick?
Rym: I would play Bacchus bank you it with because the building part is not super fun in citadels.
Rym: All right, however, citadels, you know can have six or seven people.
Rym: Bacchus banquet goes up.
Rym: I think it's three to five.
Scott: So I played ticket to ride.
Scott: like I said and I remembered that game pretty much comes down to what routes you draw.
Scott: Yeah, and the rest is pretty obvious what to do.
Scott: and it just comes and if there's if two people have pretty equal routes It comes down to like luck of drawing more routes Which is sort of mitigated by the fact that you draw three and you only have to keep one at most yeah, and at least but you can keep all three and You know the colors of the cars, you know, you might get lucky like oh you need a yellow route.
Scott: so bad It could just be yelling.
Scott: Yell.
Scott: Oh, maybe it happens.
Rym: Yeah, it's still fun though.
Scott: Yeah, it's still a fun game, but it's not a great quality, you know skilled game.
Rym: We saw some other listeners right next to us during all this playing learning how to play and then playing Agricola.
Rym: That's good I'm so I gotta play some more Agricola.
Rym: I really like that game.
Scott: Yeah, definitely.
Scott: We want to get the expansion.
Rym: So we played Stone Age vs.
Rym: Future Tech.
Scott: Yeah, okay.
Scott: Well, it's called time streams, right?
Scott: This is a versus non collectible card game that was supposed to play like a collectible card game From the look of it.
Rym: Anyway, Scott pulls this out.
Scott: He's written the rules I'm flipping through the cards and I've got the future to get tech and he has the caveman tech and I'm like, alright Well, how the hell do we play this game?
Scott: The rules are written so poorly and independently.
Rym: the game itself is actually a cool concept.
Rym: You build kind of this board of like days like you build it out and there's actions and then you go through the whole thing Again, kind of playing out the actions.
Scott: Yeah, so imagine if you have a bunch of cards, you know It's normally a magic card right as a for a Dominion card is text on it.
Scott: Yeah, right Imagine if the cards had two texts or some of them had one text and some of them had the other texts.
Scott: So there's the play action which happens when you add the card to the game and there's the score action Which happens after you're done with the whole playing of every card and you just go through scoring everything.
Scott: They all do something different.
Rym: So you build a machine and then the machine runs.
Scott: Yeah, and while you're building the machine you do funky stuff.
Rym: Also now that mechanic is awesome I think we should make a game like that some sort of like.
Rym: I want to be good.
Scott: Good fundamental idea.
Scott: the game itself terrible that the words on the cards poorly written the rules poorly written the game of repeat cards Too like it was just.
Scott: yeah, the game didn't really have a lot of strategy or anything.
Scott: The art was good though.
Scott: The art was nice, but the game very bad.
Rym: mainly the theme had nothing to do with the game.
Rym: The theme was just.
Rym: it was tacked on to the degree that it was not even there.
Scott: Yep Stops also in the tabletop area right a guy we know from New York.
Scott: right good friends sort of I guess where you know.
Scott: He's in the nerd the nerd NYC sort of group, right?
Scott: He has a game called super gachapon fighter and I told him I would bring some gachapon's which I forgot to do.
Scott: Yeah, but basically this ring my house name Iku if you're a hero clicks kind of fan, you know You're right.
Scott: forget that just get super gachapon fighter with this.
Scott: lets you do is you get?
Scott: you know, your little PVC toy figures Right your little transformer guys, whatever it is, maybe whatever it is little street fighters little GI Joes.
Scott: Maybe you know some anime characters whatever you got, you know You bring it to the table at a Red Bull is now my leading guy.
Scott: can a Red Bull sure go for it?
Scott: Right you both.
Scott: you can roll up a character for whatever thing it is, you know, it's a point.
Scott: systems.
Scott: You don't actually roll you just make the character to match whatever the PVC is or the right and you play and it plays Sort of like hero clicks and it's actually a pretty good game.
Rym: Like the fixes a lot of the crap that hero clicks has kind of wrong with it the the math of the.
Scott: I mean It's still a miniatures combat game It's still dice and randomness and all that stuff that the dice actually works similarly to burning wheel with the successes and the failures and that.
Scott: but the the the metaphor of the dice actually matches a fighting game like you do flurries and Combos and you do.
Rym: you have special moves and yeah, like getting in close or being far away.
Rym: You got projectiles Hadouken, he's got a mechanic with movement and projectiles where you like lay out these strips and that shows the distance.
Scott: So it's like the old war games where it doesn't have to be super precise either, you know.
Scott: So it's.
Scott: it's a pretty high quality game.
Scott: It's super fun.
Scott: I'm gonna buy it and you know get the whole thing going on in, you know.
Scott: Now there's no reason to throw away all your old toys and it works.
Scott: He played with like a big old Unicron.
Scott: He played with tiny stuff big stuff.
Scott: It's all good.
Scott: It all works.
Rym: So Live-streaming thing we tried to do where we played some jungle speed and if any of you watch that you might recall that we thought We were so smart.
Rym: We're like this game is broken.
Rym: Scott took his turn, you know, it's the game where you flip up cars.
Rym: So with your same as I flip a card like this.
Rym: Scott flips a card like flip flip flip flip.
Rym: And if the cards match in certain ways Then whoever grabs the jungle speed totem first like wins that round and the other player gets punished has to pick up all the cards.
Rym: They're not out of cards you win.
Rym: So I'm like, alright, this game's just broken.
Rym: Scott take your turn I just put my fingers around the totem.
Rym: I'm like go for it.
Rym: Yeah Scott, you know flip his card I go up Or I go.
Rym: All right Let's go continue.
Scott: Yeah, so we go to this guy.
Scott: He's demoing jungle speed.
Scott: So I'm like, all right, we gotta ask this guy if this game is broken or not right away.
Rym: He's like European clearly.
Rym: He's smart.
Scott: I you know I was.
Scott: you know whenever I do this I expect that I'm gonna prove to this person that their game is broken.
Scott: But I hope that they will prove to me that I'm wrong and the game is awesome.
Scott: This is a case of them proving to me that the game is actually awesome.
Rym: Yeah, the guy doesn't even Scott's like.
Rym: so here's what the guy's like.
Rym: All right, just show me what you do.
Rym: Show me what you do.
Scott: So I'm like, okay, I flip a card and when it's your turn.
Scott: I'm gonna put my hand around the totem like this and the guy just says just like that.
Rym: Yeah I guess you knocked it over.
Scott: And if you the rule is if you knock if you're the last person to touch the totem and it gets knocked over Then you have to pick up all the cards in the table.
Rym: I realized the rules don't say don't hit the other player.
Rym: All it says is the totem.
Rym: whoever knocks the totem over loses.
Scott: So the guy just whacked my hand and the totem went flying.
Scott: and he's like take all the cards.
Scott: and I'm like, oh, thank you so much You have fixed jungle speed.
Rym: They were like, what are we grabbed at the same time?
Rym: He's like most fingers.
Rym: What is the same number of fingers closest to the bottom?
Rym: What if you know, we're on top of each other inside wins like.
Rym: it's all these obvious.
Rym: He should make a little radish II.
Scott: they should.
Scott: I'm gonna write new rules for jungle speed that fix the game.
Rym: So we're gonna play that game again.
Rym: They're gonna play some jungle speed cuz I can still do the strategy of the blocking.
Scott: apparently the way they play is they'll usually Hold the deck in one hand You know their deck in one hand and play with the other hand to guarantee that they're only using one hand.
Scott: Yep, and any edge of the table put their hand when it's not your turn.
Scott: They'll put their hands on the edge of the table and then go ha for the totem like that man.
Rym: They're so faking out this kind of game like spoons back there.
Rym: I would be like, huh and not grab it.
Rym: Yeah, I'd be like, I feel like I should make the Colossus noise every time.
Scott: Yeah, so the guy fixed jungle speed for us, yeah, I was so happy about that.
Scott: Yeah, I think that pretty much covers what we did in tabletop.
Scott: I wish I wish we would.
Scott: yeah, Luke crane ran his burning wheel demos.
Scott: A lot of people played there were pretty much.
Rym: it was so crowded.
Rym: one point He was trying to get hold of our friend Alex who does burning wheel demos wherever he can because he loves doing that.
Rym: To get him because so many people wanted burning wheel demos, especially after our panel when basically he was like Yeah, all the books sold out like right away after our panel.
Scott: Yeah It was weird.
Scott: the complete strategist came.
Scott: it seems like they didn't stay on Sunday Which is really weird.
Rym: I sold out of everything that was selling.
Scott: Yeah, it was really I don't know but you know, they it seemed like they were in what they brought, you know They brought this giant stack of tickets to ride and zero dominions.
Scott: It's like if maybe they didn't have dominions understandable or maybe that was excess stock.
Rym: They said to get rid of.
Scott: yeah It's like dude, if you wanted to make mad bank, you should have brought a giant stack of Dominion as tall as your ticket to ride.
Rym: No Thunderstone is not the greatest game.
Scott: It would have sold.
Rym: not enough people have played it yet if you would add thunderstone out with a demo and you're like This is Dominion plus dungeon crawling.
Rym: They were sold every freaking cop.
Scott: Yeah, but they sold like they sold out of action castle.
Scott: They sold out of burning wheel.
Scott: They had you know, and they didn't bring that many.
Scott: They only brought like with 30 copies or so.
Scott: So yeah, I saw the whole stack.
Rym: I feel like I have a terrible power because so many people came up to me later in the con.
Rym: They're like I tried to buy like any other every game we talked about.
Rym: they're like and I couldn't find it for sale or it sold out.
Rym: Sorry, even the games like dogs in the vineyard that we didn't even talk about.
Rym: It's just it's in the panel description.
Scott: I was actually, you know sort of impressed.
Scott: a lot of people come up to us during the con.
Scott: They're like we want you to play X. We want you to come do this with us, you know.
Scott: And I'm like, you know I have a hard time saying no and usually it doesn't happen just because it's hard to meet up with people.
Rym: Yeah, and too many of you were it didn't happen.
Scott: Like I really wanted to play.
Scott: right.
Rym: so the vineyard with you.
Scott: The thing is at PAX East everyone who wanted to do something with us except for the one dude who wanted to play dogs In the vineyard and the other people who wanted us to play their game.
Rym: Oh, we didn't go back to the.
Rym: that education will make your game game either Where you make the game and then you play the game.
Scott: All right forget.
Rym: So that's nothing we fucked up.
Scott: Yeah Other than that, right we did everything that we said we would do.
Scott: so it was.
Scott: actually we got a lot done.
Rym: Yeah, but I really wanted to play dogs in the vineyard.
Rym: that guy he was the kind of guy to run it.
Rym: He was the kind of guy like had his deal.
Rym: Yes, like when uncle yo runs the inspectors like he knows exactly what he's doing.
Scott: Let's talk about.
Scott: the education will make the game game.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Yeah, so the concept here who was that?
Scott: You did it.
Scott: It was some guy that we met like once in the past.
Scott: I forget his name.
Rym: Sorry, dude Yeah, but we'll do a show on this like GeekNights.
Rym: So don't worry.
Rym: Well, we're gonna talk about this a lot But the concept is that you make a game aimed at younger kids where it's a flash game.
Rym: The game is your plate.
Rym: you have a game that is broken like and every game is different.
Rym: Like what's the platformer?
Rym: What's the tile game?
Rym: Whatever.
Rym: and you fix the game?
Scott: The game is yeah, basically you're playing a game and while you're playing the game you have play mode and edit modes.
Scott: You like a level will be broken.
Scott: You'll have to go to edit mode and fix the broken level then go to play mode and get to the end of the low One.
Rym: that's a concept that you could take in a lot of directions, but they're taking it in this like educational kid direction.
Scott: Yeah, it was.
Scott: it was pretty awesome.
Scott: So I highly recommend it.
Scott: if I can remember the name of it I would tell it.
Rym: we'll do a whole show about it.
Scott: We'll put a link up and all that.
Rym: So we did three panels at PAX East the exact same three we did at PAX West.
Scott: they you know.
Scott: It was surprising.
Scott: we did beyond D&D first and I actually felt like it wasn't our best beyond.
Rym: I was just like I was really wrecked and we forgot some stuff.
Rym: We backpedaled.
Rym: We didn't do our usual disclaimer about how much we actually loved D&D.
Rym: Yeah halfway through.
Scott: Yeah It wasn't.
Scott: I wasn't like what.
Scott: while I was up there I was like, this is not our best beyond D&D, but you know what people loved it Crane told me afterwards.
Scott: I was like hilarious.
Scott: I was like, what are you talking?
Scott: the whole?
Rym: Entire convention.
Rym: people kept coming up to me like so beyond Dungeons & Dragons.
Rym: They like.
Rym: question that a comment.
Rym: Everyone said it was great.
Rym: I don't want to chew my own horn, but I Feel you liked even a crappy rendition of.
Scott: you know, it's like we.
Scott: it's like if you have a song it's a good song.
Scott: It's a song people like.
Scott: that's a hit but you did a poor singing job.
Scott: You got some notes wrong and I guess people still thought it's very hard of it.
Rym: Is that one?
Rym: even if we do a bad job?
Rym: Even if we did a terrible job the content matters.
Rym: There's a reason.
Rym: we've been doing this panel what this is our third packs.
Rym: We've done it at yeah, like we did.
Scott: we gotta retire this shit.
Rym: We did it at Otakon.
Rym: We might do it at magfest.
Scott: Yeah, we'll see a magfest.
Scott: I would do it again someday.
Rym: I want to record like a definitive version and be done with it right after that.
Scott: We did losing should be fun, which I think we didn't.
Scott: even worse job.
Rym: I think you did a better job.
Rym: I think it was really.
Scott: think so cuz I was falling.
Scott: It's literally falling asleep.
Rym: But I was like, uh, see beyond D&D is like a to a both of us panel Like we both wrote it straight up.
Rym: We both perform it with equal parts.
Rym: losing should be fun Like I wrote and I Drive and Scott provides commentary and insight.
Rym: and beyond Candyland Scott Drive Scott wrote I just provide insight and commentary.
Rym: So I driving.
Rym: I think losing should be fun cuz I had some coffee So I had a second wind for that one.
Rym: So I think I pulled it all the way off and yeah, you were kind of falling asleep toward the end.
Scott: I was literally like yeah Like I'm like.
Scott: that's so bad if you're on doing a panel and you're just like meh.
Rym: But at the same time again the contents of what matters because Everyone's had those experience like beyond D&D.
Rym: I mean look no one in that room except for that core of like fanboys who come to all our panels and already know us Even though it's the same panel.
Rym: every time everyone else didn't know we were gonna say and they're all D&D people.
Rym: and the moment I live for and beyond D&D is when We say like D&D combat takes for fucking ever and you see people whenever I see people nodding Yeah, that's what I know.
Scott: It's going well.
Rym: and like the moment I said what if you just abstracted currency and you didn't count?
Rym: because it doesn't matter you want to skip to the fun part and there's one guy up in the front who went And he went to his friend.
Rym: he's like what another.
Rym: and I think it resonates because there are a lot of people who want these better role-playing Experiences and D&D is good for what it is, but it isn't good at that.
Rym: So I think that's why the panel is so good because even if we keep doing if you do it at every packs forever.
Rym: Most of the people in the room have not seen it and don't know.
Rym: That's why we got to make a video and get the word out there.
Rym: I don't want to take up tax time anymore Yeah, I just want everyone to know this stuff.
Scott: Yeah losing should be fun.
Scott: We talked about dwarf fortress Yeah, and such.
Scott: it was about losing.
Scott: It was a panel.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: All right I think the plan with that panel is we'll probably run it at some other packs or something at some point.
Rym: But I think I'm gonna break it up because we basically touched on like single-player losing Multiplayer losing and narrative branching losing.
Rym: those could each be a panel.
Rym: that losing should be fun.
Rym: It's kind of the overarching like think about the idea that losing should be fun that your game should always be fun.
Rym: If there's any point your games not fun games fucking broken.
Scott: Yep beyond candy line I think we actually did really well.
Scott: It was the room was not a hundred percent full.
Scott: It was like 90 percent full, you know, we did.
Scott: we ran the panel really?
Scott: Well, the only thing was that we were sort of pressed for time, you know.
Scott: So I sort of rushed the end a little bit But the rest of the panel was.
Scott: it was a you know, it's usual awesome panel.
Rym: We'll try to get these up online in whatever forms we can.
Rym: as much.
Scott: beyond candy land was filmed.
Scott: We're doing we.
Scott: there's a someone up in New Hampshire who's doing a board game documentary someone awesome, by the way.
Scott: Yeah, we went and interviewed with them on after packs was over on Tuesday on our way to fun spot.
Scott: But they recorded and filmed the beyond candy land panel.
Scott: So that's gonna be on the the Internet's.
Scott: hopefully ish soon and also maybe even in a documentary or who knows what?
Rym: I'm gonna try to get her other stuff online even the bad running of beyond D&D because a bad one is better than nothing.
Scott: Yep, people want to see it.
Scott: Yep and action castle.
Scott: Of course, we did action castle and also jungle adventure And it was the typical awesome.
Rym: They died Jared like he had a sore throat Like he was kind of sick trying to run this but he did it.
Scott: Anyway, they had a rough time dealing with the with the ogre Troll the troll.
Scott: they couldn't get past the troll.
Scott: they kept dying.
Scott: It was not a good sight to see.
Rym: it was funny because you know We did the action castle like thing in the main events.
Rym: So, of course action castle sold out and everyone kept hearing us talk about it.
Rym: people already knew about it.
Rym: So I think a lot of people like memorized it or came into this like knowing what to expect.
Rym: So they won pretty hand.
Scott: There were a lot of people cheating.
Scott: They had pieces of paper and they were writing.
Rym: But yeah, I think that's awesome.
Rym: But jungle adventure happened.
Rym: you I know people like came into this thinking they'd be awesome and like know what to do.
Rym: Like someone came in they're like save game because they knew.
Rym: but then jungle adventure suddenly Oh shit, like.
Scott: I never played jungle adventure before so I had no clue what to do.
Scott: Luke crane actually told me some secrets of jungle adventure.
Rym: Yeah, I like jungle.
Rym: I like the fire ants thing a lot.
Scott: Yeah, the fire thing was good.
Scott: You get the fire ants on you.
Scott: You're gonna die in three turns, but it was weird.
Rym: You know We always thought that PAX is like where it's hard to be a celebrity like it's.
Rym: it's harder to break into It's real deal like the panels of serious business.
Rym: Everything's real and anime cons You know like we do these million panels.
Rym: But PAX is where like everyone kept coming up to us throughout the con like.
Rym: oh, man, that panel was great.
Rym: Oh, man, I have a quick.
Scott: yet anime cons Not a lot of people come, you know, some people come up to like that awesome I forget your name.
Scott: fans come up to us But it's not constant.
Scott: at PAX it East at least never really at the West.
Scott: it felt like when I was walking around the hallways Like every minute or two someone would come up to me or if I'd be in a line somewhere someone would say hey panels are Awesome, sweet
Rym: or like just constant college humor guys, you know We went to your panel and cuz we're interested in darkly like we do enough
Scott: college humor things of the day.
Scott: We went to the college humor panel.
Rym: I mean come on and it's funny.
Rym: because well one, you know, I was walking in and Jeff have to be walking by.
Rym: You know, he's one of the college humor guys, you know The guy with the glasses and the kind of scraggly but anyway, he's walking up and I'm walking next to him.
Rym: I'm like, hey, you look like you're on your way to the college humor panel.
Rym: He's like, I may be and I'm like, I'm on my way too.
Rym: And he's like.
Rym: I hear those guys are handsome But actually Emily thought he was just some listeners, okay, I blew him off.
Rym: So we go in and after their panel, I go up to talk to him.
Rym: cuz I want to talk about darkly.
Rym: I want to I think darkly.
Scott: Yeah, if you don't know they're making a new site called darkly and basically, you know college humor.
Scott: There's a lot of nerdy videos like Tetris guy There's those Mortal Kombat parodies Street Fighter later years.
Scott: They do a lot of gaming stuff.
Scott: But the thing is they avoid stuff that's too obscure for normal people to inside baseball.
Scott: But right, so they're making a new site darkly where they can do the stuff that would be too inside baseball for college humor.
Rym: What's cool though their point like and it kind of echoed actually will weed in this keynote.
Rym: They were like look we think that if we just had video game references They're ubiquitous enough for people will get him.
Rym: But we can't get away with that as much with just the college humor stuff with the demographic.
Rym: Let's go all out and see what happens.
Rym: I look forward to that with.
Scott: I look forward to that site.
Scott: It'll be a frequent visitor.
Scott: I hope it produces many fine things of the day.
Rym: But I went up to talk to him because you know, I didn't know about darkly.
Rym: So I was like, yeah, we got to talk about this.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: And while I was up there talking to them these people who came up to talk to them after their panel We're like, I think the guy who asked that question was Scott.
Rym: Oh that Scott.
Rym: Yeah, the guy from GeekNights did the action castle thing.
Rym: and then they then some other guy comes up to me.
Rym: He's like, oh my god Rym.
Rym: I was at your beyond D&D panel and then those guys like oh my god Is that Rym?
Rym: and like this weird clusterfuck and at all these people asking me questions in front of them Waiting for you last them questions.
Scott: I was outside while that was going on.
Rym: Yeah So back to the present on Tuesday with us in New York and not in Boston too.
Scott: Well, I think you know, there's a yeah.
Scott: Anyway, my many Tuesdays do not be confused.
Scott: as of right now of this talking.
Scott: It is Tuesday, April 6.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Pax is long gone anime Boston long gone.
Scott: But you know, what any of us is not long gone.
Scott: It's shortly gone.
Scott: Feels like forever ago, but PAX West is less than six months.
Rym: I know and PAX East is less than a year away.
Scott: I can't wait.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: We don't have packs.
Scott: East dates You never know.
Scott: so
Rym: I think what we want to do the thing we didn't get to when we're recording this stuff in Boston is kind of The crazy moments of packs like all the kind of things that didn't really fit anywhere else Just the stuff that really stood out up to us and I don't know kind of in reverse order.
Rym: I want to start with the elbow bump.
Scott: The elbow bump very important with this carried over to anime Boston for us as well and it were.
Rym: and it got to the point To where people who approached us came elbow ready because they remembered and every time someone like gave us the handshake I'd be like no elbow.
Rym: and once they realize what was up there like oh crap.
Rym: Yeah disease.
Rym: Damn it.
Scott: Yeah I mean packs penny arcade.
Scott: put up the comic telling you to use the iron guard position right instead of using You know the elbow.
Rym: I wonder how many people realize that the iron guard position is basically the I am invisible and larping position sort.
Scott: of.
Scott: the problem I have with the iron guard position right is that there is a. there is a psychological thing about like You know touching somebody right like they did a whole bunch of studies where it's like, okay They'll have someone go into a phone booth and leave a wallet behind, you know.
Scott: and on their way out of the phone booth They'll touch the person who's waiting to get into the phone booth.
Scott: And if they do that then the person will more often, you know call them and be like, hey your wallet.
Scott: But if you don't touch the person on your way out of the phone booth It is less likely that they will say hey your wallet, right?
Rym: So what happens if you pick up the phone booth, right so that you die?
Scott: But the point?
Scott: so the point of a handshake is you know, you you touch this person and there is something about that.
Scott: The iron guard position, you know eliminates all touching whatsoever.
Scott: And the thing is you don't really need to eliminate all the touching.
Scott: you can do the elbow bump Which gives you the touching that has the same psychological impact as you know.
Scott: a handshake, you know Maybe not quite as much but you but you don't have to get me your your hands on their hands Do not contact and the hands are you know?
Rym: The the disease transfer positions and I think the way forward because you know This elbow bump.
Rym: iron guard thing kind of came out of the fact that there was an unrelated Norovirus outbreak at like colleges and everyone got swine flu at Pax West Yep.
Rym: So I think what we need to do is every time there's a con The con should just lie and say there's an outbreak of something like that and remind everyone to elbow bump And then the kids won't get sick.
Scott: You don't even need to do an elbow bump.
Scott: You should just be like yeah cons are you know, dens of horrible disease.
Scott: Do not shake hands with anyone.
Rym: It amazes me that everyone just bump elbows.
Rym: New York fucking city does not make me sick.
Rym: touching like grimy subways and then sticking my finger in my eye.
Scott: Cuz you wash your fucking hands even though I don't that often and you know You could.
Scott: you know, it's actually really easy to get in New York City.
Scott: pink I feel like if you're on the subway and you rub your eyes.
Scott: pink eye Ho.
Rym: I think I is one of the things I fear almost more than death.
Rym: I hate pink eyes so much.
Scott: What's to fear?
Scott: your eye just goes in for a little while?
Rym: I hate that.
Rym: anything where that makes my eyes itch just drives me crazy.
Scott: I can't deal with it's not so bad I mean if you get a lot worse things than pink eye like I don't know Norovirus where you're basically puking and diarrhea and like crazy, but at least that ends quickly A couple days.
Scott: Yeah, I'll tell you what I'll take ten pink guys over one norovirus.
Rym: I don't know where they consecutive or concurrent Both ten times.
Scott: It'll be ten squared guys in both eyes at the same time.
Rym: number nine.
Rym: There's no actual list.
Rym: I'm just kind of going up from things.
Rym: I jotted a notepad.
Rym: Yeah, and in case we didn't talk about it the omegathon whatever.
Rym: the omegathon finale was The most epic or at least I think equal to the excite bike epicness It was.
Scott: it was a good omegathon finale right.
Scott: there was a. it was good.
Scott: There was no way I could have predicted it right, but once I saw it It was obvious.
Scott: the thing is right for the second omegathon in a row.
Rym: there are technological difficulties Yeah But at the same time the fact that there were so few I expected disaster.
Rym: When I saw what they were trying to do all I thought was there's no way this is gonna.
Scott: You know they did do test runs of it.
Scott: You know I mean, I don't think we could have done any better.
Scott: I think the thing is that they mess up right and that they insist on using the actual technology.
Rym: They should lie.
Rym: they should just have the NES there.
Rym: make everything look like it's in an NES.
Rym: But behind that NES is a NES controller to USB converter and a frickin emulator.
Scott: It's just yeah, they should use.
Scott: they have all those Dell PC's right.
Scott: you can grab like ten of them and use them.
Rym: You know I'm sure there are concerns about legality, and they're big and they don't want to worry.
Rym: Just fake it Just totally fake it.
Rym: no one would know.
Scott: look just if you worry about the legality right I don't think anyone is gonna challenge you right on You know if you emulate an NES game and right there you have an NES and the game and the controller is just sitting there You know and may have.
Scott: you know.
Scott: if you need to you have to.
Scott: if you need ten you have ten and just use the Emulator right in front of it, but like I said nobody is gonna complain if you fake it.
Rym: you're double protected That's true.
Scott: But anyway You know and you can use the actual controllers the USB connection and it doesn't need to be authentic if it Roo if it ruins.
Scott: The suspense then you know and the awesomeness of the omega-thon with a technological difficulty.
Scott: don't use the old busted technology.
Rym: But luckily at least with this omega-thon like he got all the way through and then there was kind of the choke near the end But before kind of the ultimate round of it.
Rym: so we basically got to experience the omega-thon twice.
Scott: Yeah, I thought you know I on the one hand I thought that you know on the second go-through after all had been revealed the suspense would lessen.
Scott: But after they started playing the suspense It came right back in.
Rym: so I have two points about the omega-thon finale.
Rym: one team left got robbed.
Rym: Team left did indeed get robbed because team right did not know how to play Mario.
Scott: one right I did not know how to play for crap.
Scott: team right the right team on the right sucked ass Right, but then because they got to do a second go around because of the technological difficulties They knew where the coins were right.
Scott: the team on the right was able to come back.
Rym: The thing is the key team on the left despite you know in the second round they screwed up.
Rym: They had a couple of chokes and Tetris and such, but when they got to the contra round.
Rym: They were catching up so fast they almost won in any way.
Scott: Yeah, that's you know.
Scott: the team on the left was clear the superior team.
Scott: the thing is you know it says clearly in the omega-thon Rules they they decide who wins.
Scott: there is no appeals process, which is fine.
Rym: the only problem I had like I feel bad for him But one of the guys on that team looked kind of genuinely pissed as opposed to good-naturedly pissed Mmm.
Rym: I felt kind of bad for him, but at the same time.
Rym: What are you gonna?
Rym: Do it's entertainment?
Rym: I mean yeah.
Rym: the other point is that neither one of those teams could play any of those games for shit.
Rym: And I don't know.
Scott: the team on the left was okay at Contra.
Rym: They were good.
Scott: they were pretty good at Contra But they couldn't play Mario 1 or Tetris and rad racer is such an easy game.
Scott: everyone played it just fine.
Rym: Yep I don't know that Tetris part really got to me.
Scott: just and the whole audience - that was another thing I you know they want to talk about like you know.
Scott: oh it has to be the real system Otherwise it doesn't count.
Scott: right we have to use the real control in Tetris right But they gave the two teams different Tetris's.
Scott: they didn't work both playing the same version of Tetris.
Scott: So if you're worried about a fair competition using actual NES's or whatever Then how could you also not be concerned with using two different Tetris versions?
Rym: That's yes the problem they ran into.
Scott: that's hypocritical right there.
Scott: So you know no excuse not to use the emulators that will work perfectly every time.
Rym: with the the whole Konami code thing.
Rym: you know The problem they had with Contra.
Rym: they made him have to start over Props to coup for being there to put it in on the spot.
Rym: Imagine if he had screwed that up, and they had to do it a third time.
Rym: Yeah, he had it He did it.
Rym: But I think it would have been better if they didn't enter the code And they just gave you Contra.
Rym: and if you didn't know the code and you got game.
Scott: Oh, if you could enter the code or if you got game over you could you know just keep restarting.
Scott: Yeah, so you got it.
Rym: I mean imagine that.
Rym: imagine if you know one team just like goes for it and starts to die and the other team just Konami codes it and then the audience realizes the Konami code But then the other team wins anyway because they're just that good a cop.
Scott: I think the only read.
Scott: the argument against that though is that you know in trials right because they tried it out and The the time between the winner and the loser was one second, so they were like oh, this is perfect It's gonna be so down to the wire and awesome Yeah.
Scott: But if you if one team knew the Konami code the other didn't it would be a no contest.
Rym: He'd be like ah but at the same time see this is the trouble because you are correct for the entertainment of the crowd That was the best option, but does someone who doesn't know the Konami code deserve to win the omega-thon?
Scott: Well does someone who doesn't?
Scott: it was trying to go down every single pipe and Mario one deserved to win the omega-thon.
Scott: No But they did so.
Rym: if he'd been small we might not have noticed But the fact that there's that big-ass Mario just ducking on all the clearly non duckable pipes.
Rym: Yeah, I was just sad that guy He'd be.
Scott: you know We I think we need to recreate this this challenge minus the contra part You know because that part was uninteresting and You know just see what how we can do.
Scott: I think I think I could beat you in a Mario 150 coin.
Rym: Doubt that?
Rym: Okay, we'll set it up.
Rym: We have to have some sort of live Rimmens got dual uh-huh anyway.
Rym: We'll see.
Rym: so briefly.
Rym: I don't want to dwell on these but our panels went freaking awesome and everyone in the crowd was badass.
Rym: I got to say one thing this this actually surprised me.
Rym: We had a little bit of extra time just because the way the staggering was in the panels And we took some questions something we never really do it packs.
Rym: The questions people asked were great like they were good questions.
Scott: Yeah, I mean some of them were awesome.
Scott: some of them were okay You know but there were no questions.
Scott: where I was like shut up fanboy.
Scott: every question was a quality question.
Scott: You know I mean we got the.
Scott: of course you always get the occasional.
Scott: What about this game?
Scott: Have you played this specific thing?
Scott: and it's like no I haven't played that specific thing But you know those are.
Scott: those are not so bad.
Scott: That's like the average.
Scott: that's a three star out of five star question.
Scott: Have you played this specific thing?
Rym: yep?
Rym: Though I will now take the opportunity to announce that at least as far as packs is concerned We are retiring beyond Dungeons & Dragons.
Rym: We've done it at three packs is we're not doing it there again.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, I think as good as it is seriously.
Rym: We're gonna film it at some point.
Rym: We'll stick it up.
Rym: We'll probably end up doing it like magfest and things but no more packs.
Rym: We got to bring fresh stuff.
Rym: We might retire beyond Candyland and losing should be fun too.
Scott: I don't want to retire beyond Candyland.
Scott: I think that has like another year left.
Rym: We'll see the.
Rym: the working title.
Scott: People still need to play more German games.
Scott: We can update it with some different games.
Rym: To tantalize two working titles I have for panels I'm slowly working on for future packs is our egregiously unrealized potential?
Rym: yeah, which is basically the Nintendo panel right and Games make the player hmm Some sort of mechanism design, but we have to not tread on Luke.
Scott: Luke cranes game is mind control panel.
Rym: I think they can both exist in the same ecosystem.
Rym: I'm not going to steal his hobbit example again Yeah, but we'll be using our DDR example.
Scott: Which is almost the same thing I think.
Rym: one more thing that is worth mentioning It was pretty damn awesome was Scott having the balls to do the action castle thing in the first Q&A Balls.
Rym: it was easy.
Rym: I point out jerry did not have the testicular fortitude to do it himself.
Scott: He just didn't want to you know.
Scott: I asked him I'm like you sure you don't want to do it you sure and he just didn't want to be all Self-promotional and whatever at the same time.
Rym: He was fine with you doing it.
Scott: He was fine with me doing it.
Scott: apparently a lot of other people thought it was okay.
Scott: I you know I didn't think it was that great when I was doing it or what you know.
Scott: I thought it was oh, you know pretty clever, but it people were like oh, man I think part of it is that no one expected it.
Rym: and every year like there are a few people who do something clever at The QA and no one you think about it.
Rym: in all these packs is no one thought to try to play a game with them.
Rym: Right there a short one mmm.
Rym: And also you know I think the fact that you didn't milk it that you stopped it at the appropriate time.
Scott: Well, I was planning to you know I knew that I had to keep it short right.
Scott: so I wanted to I wanted to you Know to cut it off at the appropriate time because if I stood there too long it'd be very bad.
Scott: It's a question-answer thing.
Rym: the genius of taiko that at the perfect moment.
Rym: He was like quit.
Scott: Well, I don't think it was his genius right.
Scott: I think it was.
Scott: you know I I knew that Mike would not do Well right in advance, but I didn't know he would do that poorly and I sort of messed up right in that.
Scott: You know it wasn't his turn, but he kept thinking it was his turn And it's like oh what am I supposed to do?
Rym: you should have just either.
Rym: you could have kept saying I don't understand.
Rym: What the fuck do you want to me?
Rym: I don't come into your house and do this shit to you.
Scott: He didn't say that until after I told him it's not his turn.
Scott: You know Jared?
Scott: I think you know it could have been a little bit better because afterwards I asked Jared what I should have done And he said you should have said something along the lines of you know player one.
Scott: It is not your turn.
Scott: You know as opposed to saying you know it's not your turn You can't say anything if it's not your turn.
Scott: and like.
Scott: the other thing is that Jerry just was not helping me out like he Thought it wasn't his turn.
Scott: He was just being all quiet.
Rym: because yeah I think he was I think he thought to say quit and he was just waiting for them.
Scott: No, no because if you if you actually look back at it You know Mike's like you know say whatever will make him stop, and then he says quit You know.
Scott: so that that's what see.
Rym: the thing is with the showmanship.
Rym: I wonder how much of that was like the Unstated nod between the two of them that that interchange would have been a good joke and then they pulled it off.
Rym: I have no there's no way to know what those guys I got to admit those guys are getting pretty damn good at entertaining a crowd.
Scott: it is it is in.
Scott: it is difficult if nay Impossible to know.
Scott: so it doesn't really matter either.
Scott: It's just a silly action castle question whatever, but people liked it.
Scott: It made people excited for action castle.
Scott: action castle sold out.
Scott: it totally worked, so now.
Scott: I just have to think of Ways to promote whatever else I'm trying to sell at a Q&A without being blatantly self-promotional like you know.
Scott: Hey, everybody come over to my booth and buy my shit.
Rym: Well, I think the thing is PAX is special for now at least in that no Like attention-getting thing will ever work more than once.
Rym: I mean if someone does that which thing next year And no one's gonna stand for that, but doing every single thing once is awesome at PAX Except the knuckle crack.
Rym: that's gonna happen every goddamn year and luckily it did.
Scott: I was worried It wasn't gonna happen.
Rym: I was gonna make it happen if it didn't.
Scott: someone came in and they saved the day.
Rym: that noise is just Surprisingly sickening.
Scott: That's the greatest.
Rym: So we learned.
Rym: you know we had the vision like we talked about earlier And we failed to achieve the vision because we did not account for the immediate competence of the people Said it like doing the tag between.
Scott: I was you know I was worried that okay keynote ends There's gonna be applause.
Scott: you can't start until the applause and ends and people are sort of getting ready for the Q&A right.
Scott: But and I was like oh no there might be some sort of you know Rock and roll musics for a minute or two before they begin the Q&A.
Scott: I'll have to overpower it.
Scott: so that was a challenge But that they would just start it right away immediately.
Scott: You know at the moment that I should have you know needed to start.
Rym: it was there was nothing.
Rym: It was no it was a foregone conclusion.
Scott: unless I suddenly gained the mutant powers of Banshee the x-man It was not gonna happen, but think about this.
Rym: This is like in the you know the Mario Party vision.
Rym: if you had the vision and you start the mat And there's already small mushrooms lined up all the way down.
Scott: That's pretty much it yeah, but we will reattempt.
Rym: We had another opportunity to test our theory and we now know that it is in fact solid gold.
Rym: it worked.
Rym: We were in line for the closing ceremonies the omega-thon finale And we were like right in the friggin front of the line like right where the people are who do the in-line entertainment.
Rym: I think it's step in line game something like that.
Rym: we talked to him.
Rym: They're pretty cool people But they decided to have a dancing contest and they're like we need a guy and a girl and me and Scott look at each Other and we look at our friend Katsu.
Rym: and Scott starts yelling katsu.
Rym: katsu.
Rym: I was looking around.
Scott: I'm like oh, it's gotta be an FRC person.
Scott: I'm like who who who?
Scott: Katsu.
Rym: and Katsu looks up with this what?
Rym: and then you know the same thing.
Rym: I start yelling katsu.
Rym: Scott embraces my katsu.
Rym: Everyone else starts joining in.
Rym: the whole freaking line joins in.
Rym: people didn't even know his name - yeah - yeah - so you've got like thousands of people yelling katsu's name.
Rym: There's a circle formed around him, and he's screaming.
Rym: I swear to God.
Rym: I will kill you all Mm-hmm.
Rym: so of course he has to go up and do it and of course he wins.
Scott: of course That's why I wasn't gonna pick someone who was gonna fail.
Scott: I mean if I would have picked Rym.
Scott: It would have been like okay Not a winner fail.
Rym: I don't know if I could have won it But I katsu.
Rym: if anyone could have won it it was katsu, and he did.
Scott: he won it by a zillion.
Scott: I Realized now that after having watched that college, and he got a free Cardboard to samurai figure which is a very expensive toy, but I saw it on eBay if I was him We have a terrible power.
Rym: if anyone wants to use this terrible power just watch that college humor We link to it works almost anywhere.
Rym: Yep So getting near the end I think we have to end on this because this was like the moment.
Rym: so in the line You know there's the line up room, which is something that anime cons could probably learn from.
Rym: of course I don't know if they could manage it the way packs does but regardless in the lineup room.
Rym: It's so happened that as we're all going into you know the biggest biggest event They started playing Bohemian Rhapsody just before the line went in.
Scott: yeah It's like the line is okay guys.
Scott: now You can start walking and then they play Bohemian Rhapsody.
Rym: so Bohemian Rhapsody is playing and you know people were singing along stuff already anyway.
Rym: So everyone in line starts singing Bohemian Rhapsody But the line goes past the monitors out the door down a long haul way off upstairs and everything.
Rym: So as a result we're rapidly as a line leaving the already playing Bohemian Rhapsody.
Scott: So we don't hear it being played anymore at all.
Scott: It's it's in another room far behind us.
Rym: But the crowd kept singing it and kept singing it and kept singing it to a point That was scary.
Rym: like we're walking the music's long gone in the distance.
Rym: Everyone is still singing all the way through people who were kind of in the area like enforcers who saw the line coming.
Rym: They're looking up like are they singing Bohemian Rhapsody, and then I thought all right It's gonna die at the instrumental part.
Rym: It did not die.
Rym: people did the instrumental part and We made it all the way through and this is for the Saturday night concerts.
Rym: I believe yes I believe so.
Scott: and then right going into the closing ceremonies final omega-thon round.
Scott: it was repeated They did it again.
Rym: I think that is the PAX East thing.
Rym: now.
Rym: the Bohemian Rhapsody Continued meme.
Scott: yep it is now a tradition.
Rym: I mean there's a.
Scott: let it be set in the stone.
Rym: There is a point where it's fizzled out almost like everyone's kind of going you know But everyone's got it going in their head, and then someone comes out with the right timing.
Rym: It was so beautiful.
Rym: I could have cried.
Rym: that was that was a moment that deserved a man tear yeah, and then to cap off the whole week we had in Boston we get in the cab to go back to the airport and What plays on the radio, but Bohemian Rhapsody?
Scott: Yeah, that was kind of weird So I don't know.
Rym: in conclusion PAX East was 90 to 95 percent of the awesome that is PAX West.
Rym: it was.
Scott: the one thing at PAX East that really Got me compared to pretty much every other convention ever was that basically people were constantly coming up to me Yeah, being like hey.
Scott: Hey, it was like non-stop.
Scott: You know it was actually weird like I mean when I'm at conventions even PAX West Right you know some people come up, and they're like hey like hey, but it's not Right it's not like you know.
Scott: I mean this wasn't like this wasn't Celebrity
Scott: level
Scott: where you can't even move because there's people all around you like ah fuck, but it was like hey, man Hey, man, like every minute or two walking around people would be like hey, and it you know they was like wow okay?
Scott: How many more people are gonna come up and say?
Rym: And everyone had like interesting questions or things to say.
Rym: or oh, would you try this game?
Rym: or yeah?
Rym: I bought burning wheel is freaking awesome, or hey, so how do you win jungle adventure?
Scott: Oh the other thing is that you know of course you know the.
Scott: Usually when people come up to you at a con are like hey We should do X you know we should.
Scott: I want to run a game for you.
Scott: I want to do this.
Scott: I want to do that.
Scott: usually it's like I really want to But it's just not gonna happen.
Scott: You know even a ConnectiCon there were like two people wanted to play burning wheel And I was like all right We'll make it happen show up here and whatever and then of course it just doesn't happen.
Scott: they disappear or something And you just can't.
Scott: they're strangers.
Scott: you don't meet up with them at the right time in the right place And it doesn't happen.
Scott: Yeah, well think about no matter how much you try it doesn't happen.
Rym: how much trouble we had meeting up with our friend at joystick Ever.
Scott: two packs is yeah, but you know even with all that we managed to meet up with everyone We had to meet up with except like two people, and I think we're still in contact with them.
Scott: I got their cards, so we're gonna dude.
Scott: We totally will make it right.
Rym: dogs in the vineyard with you like straight up.
Rym: I really want.
Scott: and those other people I forget who you are who had your game that you you made And you wanted to run it for us.
Scott: I also wanted to play.
Rym: yes seriously shoutouts to everyone who said hi to us everyone at our panels and Pack.
Rym: I think as taiko said this is the real packs.
Scott: I don't know if he was being for serious.
Rym: It depends.
Rym: What's he gonna say at PAX West?
Scott: No.
Scott: This is the real packs.
Scott: I was kidding about West forever.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Rym: cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.