Rym: Hey, it's Monday January 25th.
Scott: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We talk a little bit about tablets ahead of the Apple tablet.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Well, I actually bought my new computer.
Rym: It's sitting completely built and really unnecessary new computing completely built and working and prosthetic long sitting next to me right now.
Rym: But I'm still doing GeekNights on the old computer because the whole point of this was that I can set everything up on the new Without interrupting GeekNights any further than we've already interrupted it for the past.
Scott: all the holidays and moving You're always like the slowest to set up computers.
Scott: if I get a new computer.
Scott: It's working like the next day 100%.
Rym: Well, no problem I didn't get all the parts until you know not that long ago and the day the video card came yesterday or earlier The day the video card came it was booted and then I went out of town for the whole weekend.
Rym: So I just got back.
Scott: I don't go out of town when computers are coming in the man.
Rym: Yeah I was.
Rym: I was debating skipping my out-of-town obligation, but I'm glad I didn't because it was actually really fun and relatively productive Mm-hmm.
Rym: All right, but I don't really want to talk about that what I was doing cuz that's like anime stuff that Monday people don't Care about.
Scott: I said there's not a topic of conversation for this moment in time.
Scott: No, it is for a later time.
Rym: But the computer, you know a couple of notes.
Rym: for a hundred and fifty bucks I got a 32 gigabyte solid-state drive and I installed windows on that.
Rym: This wouldn't have worked if I'd gotten the bigger windows with that stupid XP compatibility mode.
Rym: But the only thing I needed that XP compatibility mode for was cool edit and I decided I'm not gonna bother with cool edit anymore.
Scott: Oh, that's why okay.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah the windows.
Scott: I don't understand why anyone would buy the professional version.
Rym: It's really there's one reason to.
Rym: if you're a company you need it to do all the domain stuff.
Rym: What do you need it to do if you want to like connect to the domains in certain ways like you really need that version There's.
Scott: I'm trying to find the stupid chart.
Scott: Oh, here's the chart.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah the domain joining.
Scott: You need to do that.
Scott: But the thing is right.
Scott: if you are a company and you're buying like that Then you're.
Scott: you have like a site license.
Scott: so that shit don't.
Scott: it doesn't matter nearly as much Yeah as if you're buying an individual copy, which is why you know, it's like I think they could actually help themselves out a lot.
Scott: It's like okay for home people.
Scott: They should only have Home premium and that's it, right?
Scott: Because if the home premium were sort of halfway between the price of the home basic and the home premium I take issue with them even calling it home premium because there's no non premium version.
Scott: Well, no this home basic there is.
Scott: yes It's basically useless Wow.
Scott: It's big.
Scott: It does nothing that you need.
Scott: I didn't even it doesn't have Windows Media Center.
Scott: It doesn't.
Rym: Right media center is not that on useful.
Scott: Okay, so here I got the chart, right?
Scott: So yeah, you want you don't want home basic.
Scott: I know is it called?
Scott: it's called starter edition.
Scott: Wow, right.
Rym: What I don't get is the home like the ultimate version doesn't offer anything to make it worth the money at all All right.
Scott: So yeah.
Scott: So the professional one gives you XP mode which is pointless because why do you need XP mode?
Scott: I can just get virtual box for free again.
Rym: corporations need it because it is better than It is.
Scott: virtual is all it is is like Microsoft Virtual PC.
Rym: No, I mean the reason.
Rym: as far as I can tell it makes the Windows install much bigger.
Rym: That's the main reason I didn't get it because if I got the XP compatibility mode Windows would not have fit on the 32 gigabyte solid-state drive.
Rym: I would have had to buy the 64 gigabyte solid-state drive which would have made my computer stupidly more expensive.
Rym: That is pretty much the reason I did not get any version But home basic because I didn't want to get a bigger solid-state drive for the OS.
Scott: Mm-hmm No, but I mean like.
Scott: they sell home premium professional and ultimate right?
Scott: These are the three versions they sell, you know.
Scott: Why do they even sell the professional and the ultimate like individually?
Scott: You know who you know, I mean in stores, you know.
Scott: I mean I could understand that they should have them in like a secret place on the website for the few people that actually need That yeah,
Rym: and then like a link like I'm a business person who needs one more license Like you click here and they've got that
Scott: right there aren't that there are very very small number of actual people who need Professional and ultimate on an individual, you know retail
Rym: I would argue Microsoft is very smart with the ultimate.
Rym: ultimate doesn't offer any tangible benefit Really?
Rym: Well by selling it in the store if you have home basic premium and ultimate with the black People that don't know better will say yeah, I want the biggest one I want it.
Scott: I want the one that goes to like sell a few copies of the biggest one.
Scott: But I think that they would do a lot better by you know, reducing consumer.
Scott: Remember that guy.
Scott: he talked about how when people are given a whole bunch of choices on their 401k of what to pick A lot of them just end up not picking because the choice is too difficult with Windows.
Rym: That's not an option for most people.
Rym: They're not gonna use Linux.
Scott: No but I'm saying is that a lot of people might choose Mac instead whereas they should just say go to the store and it's just Windows 7 and there's only one of them and it's all premium and it's you know.
Rym: I point out the vast majority of people will never buy a Windows operating system.
Rym: They will buy a computer that just has a Windows on it and they don't know or care about that.
Scott: beyond the point Might sell more retail II and make more money.
Scott: if they did what I said, I think they would.
Rym: I don't think they will.
Rym: I think those people just buy a new computer.
Scott: Yeah I think that is a problem is that there are a whole lot of people out there like there can basically break their computer and a software way and they get rid of the hardware and We need to do something about.
Rym: of course We have the opposite problem of Scott and I had acquired enough hardware to build like four or five working computers But it was so much of a pain in the ass to get all that old Athlon All working with itself.
Scott: the problem is that we were trying to dispose of it responsibly.
Scott: We could have just thrown it in the trash.
Scott: like 90% of people.
Rym: There's a lot of people like we could have taken all that and made a whole bunch of working computers.
Rym: But we have more computers than we need working already
Scott: and there's plenty of places you always see on the news Like we take old computer parts and make working computers and then we give them to poor people and I'm like, dude I'll totally bring my computer parts to one of those places.
Scott: They're so hard to do those places Like there weren't any nearby.
Scott: I searched on Google.
Scott: It's like all those like only maybe two of those and they're in California or something.
Scott: It's.
Scott: there was no one in the area who would take our stuff.
Rym: there was one in like the Bronx that we had to go to during the day between like 8 a.m.
Rym: And 5 p.m.
Rym: and Physically give the stuff to them and pay them for the privilege.
Scott: Yeah, it's like no, that's just not gonna happen.
Rym: And sadly you wonder why you find so many, you know dangerous toxic computer components.
Rym: just throw it out in the woods.
Rym: It's why?
Rym: it's because if you're a responsible person you'll do it But if you're if you don't care, it's a lot cheaper to just chuck it.
Rym: Yeah, and there's no way to catch these people.
Scott: No, there's no way to.
Scott: and the thing is even though there are Responsible ways to get rid of things there aren't.
Scott: they're not everywhere and they're not all convenient.
Scott: If you're not convenient and you're not everywhere you might as well not exist.
Scott: It's like ego because the amount of coverage you're getting is basically not enough to make a difference.
Scott: You need to you know if you want to Be a computer recycling place You need to accept things From anywhere and you need to not charge people money to take their stuff and you need to be open at all hours.
Scott: people need To be able to walk up at like, you know 9 p.m.
Scott: After work and drop off their shit.
Rym: But uh, you know other interesting notes.
Rym: I got that and tech 900 that everyone's getting because it's pretty much the best non crazy expensive PC like mid-tower ATX case there is except it's kind of ugly but It's super ugly but functionality wise it is pretty much great.
Rym: In fact, the inside of it is a lot better than the much more expensive much more quote unquote Nicely designed case that I had for my old computer.
Scott: That looks a lot better.
Rym: Yeah, the old computer looks a lot better.
Scott: That's the intake p180, right?
Rym: Yeah, it's got that nice door on the front.
Rym: It's got like the really cool cable chain.
Scott: I have the intake solo, which is just perfectly fine and normal except that the front door is kind of blue.
Rym: Oh this front door people were like the front door is gonna break off immediately.
Rym: and I broke the front door off immediately.
Scott: Yeah, they're really bad with doors.
Rym: thing is the door.
Rym: I don't know I never opened it anymore because I don't need my DVD drive.
Rym: Yeah But I realized more and more that all the cut all the things that the more expensive cases have to offer are things that I Don't need anymore.
Rym: I mean I used to need like the ability to pull out my hard drive cage because I'd like swap out hard drives install new Hard drives, I never opened this p180.
Rym: I built it.
Scott: She's got an acrylic cowboy.
Rym: I Like the acrylic cowboy.
Rym: There's a lot of cool cases like that.
Rym: now There's all.
Rym: there's a whole bunch of competition in the like acrylic cowboy market.
Rym: in the exposed motherboard case I guess strata Mmm, some of them look pretty cool, but I worry about dust.
Scott: Well, it's not supposed to be something that you use.
Rym: some of these are definitely use all the time cases.
Rym: I question the logic there.
Scott: the acrylic cowboy is not a use all the time case.
Rym: All right, but I did go with the GTX 260 as opposed to the 250 for the Nvidia card.
Scott: Oh, you didn't listen to those ATI fanboys.
Rym: Alright kids and I will say this.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: The ATI cards are more powerful per dollar at the price point I was looking at.
Rym: however, I need it to work in Linux.
Rym: That's it.
Rym: And I do not trust ATI for shit in Linux.
Rym: I've had too many bad experiences and no one.
Rym: there is no evidence that the ATI drivers are as good as the Nvidia drivers in Linux or at all.
Rym: I'm not gonna.
Rym: I will not speak on that part because I don't know enough about it and I'm not going to fall on my old man prejudices.
Scott: Old man, I mean, it's just like, you know, and people talk about these things.
Scott: They just you know, all they look at is like these benchmarks and the prices and they'll for example, right?
Scott: We had to do is something that I know 100% sure, right?
Scott: We were talking in the forum also about monitors, right?
Scott: And of course people didn't know what the hell they were talking about except for me because I know what
Rym: I think is when I was researching monitors way back I agonized over the decision and I looked at like the specs of the ultra sharp versus the non ultra sharp versus like some other non Dell and I was like, ah, and finally I was like, you know what?
Rym: I'm just gonna do what Scott did.
Rym: I'm just gonna buy the ultra sharp.
Rym: I'll just buy the nice one because everyone says it's better.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: It's perfect.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is people like Scott Johnson, right?
Scott: It was a big new egg sale during like Black Friday, whatever He bought like two big ol LCDs that were wicked cheap like a hundred something bucks.
Scott: And he was like, oh, yeah I'm so awesome.
Scott: I got these giant cheapo LCDs and I'm like these LCDs are not so great.
Scott: First of all, they have a glossy screen which gets lots of glare in the Sun, but that's just a personal preference.
Scott: You know, maybe you don't have any Sun and then it looks kind of nice, you know, I mean I mean is I'm 50/50 on glossy But I don't like the glossy at all.
Rym: It depends like some laptops get away with it, but that's that's a preference, right?
Scott: The point is that people look at all these stats.
Scott: They look at maximum resolution.
Scott: They look at refresh rate.
Scott: They look at contrast ratio, which is usually completely false.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: It's like thread count, right?
Scott: You can't look at contrast ratio.
Rym: The most important things kids that everyone forgets to look at is one how well does it swivel and tilt?
Rym: Yes, that is more important than half the other stuff on it.
Rym: Yeah, two it's better.
Rym: It better have at least one if not two DV eyes.
Rym: Otherwise, what's the point?
Scott: Yeah, what inputs does it have?
Rym: and three?
Rym: Check out the horizontal and the vertical viewing angle because those cheap LCDs usually have a shit.
Scott: vertical viewing angle That's true team.
Rym: They can't swivel that well, so you're fucked.
Scott: But the most important thing to look at is just simply what kind of screen is it, right?
Scott: I mean the thing is these days they pretty much people know, you know, at least tech people know.
Scott: They know LCD and they know plasma right?
Scott: They know the difference.
Scott: They might even know the difference between like an LCD that uses cathode Lighting for its backlights and an LCD that uses LEDs for the backlight.
Scott: yeah, they might even know the difference when the LEDs that are backlighting it are just on the edge of the monitor or when They're directly behind the screen which is even better because then you get a nice even lighting and you don't have sort of this Messed up kind of contrast.
Rym: go even the old LCDs remember they even have one passive matrix versus active matrix.
Scott: Yep They even have ones Nowadays where the LEDs are sort of in an array behind the screen and if one area of the screen is dark It'll turn the LEDs off to get a better contrast ratio.
Scott: The only problem with that is on the edges of like, you know sharp things you might have sort of, you know artifacting going on, but anyway, what people don't look at is the most important thing is that most TFTs, which is an LCD screen these days that you buy in a computer monitor or even a television are twisted pneumatic, right?
Scott: That's how they work.
Scott: and a twisted pneumatic TFT is only capable of displaying six bits per color.
Scott: That is six twelve eighteen bit color.
Scott: two to the 18th.
Scott: power is like two hundred something thousand so the monitor is only capable of displaying physically two hundred thousand something colors.
Scott: an IPS screen is the only LCD monitor that is capable of actually displaying 16.7 million colors, which is what your computer is rendering.
Rym: That's why you bought that expensive ATI video card that renders 32-bit color except I will point out back in the days of CRT's where you didn't have to worry About that CRT.
Scott: I mean, yeah CRT could always display 16.
Rym: There was that long period.
Rym: but when LCDs just could I remember you bought one of the first LCDs with a low enough refresh rate To actually work for gaming.
Scott: Yeah, the 12 millisecond.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Yes Samsung's.
Scott: Yeah, of course now my tea like one of them's right over there.
Scott: I see it.
Rym: I think mine has a six millisecond my TV claims to have.
Scott: I think a IPS monitors do have you know lower refresh rates than a twisted pneumatic, but they still get 60 Hertz, which is enough.
Scott: That's perfectly fine.
Scott: That was more than they way used to be a long time ago.
Rym: Yeah, I'm happy to get 60 FPS in every game.
Scott: I felt like you guys have these.
Scott: like you'll see a guy you'll have like You know three video cards lined up rendering these beautiful 32-bit color scenes and he'll only be seeing 200,000 you know Like a mere fraction of the color of the different colors, you know They'll be like like a leaf and leaf love like a thousand different greens and he's only seeing like three different greens Because he's monitor his poop and he doesn't even realize it because people can't actually tell what their eyeballs think
Rym: about.
Rym: like I was trying To buy a TV, right?
Rym: I end up getting that one a pretty nice Samsung but the what I noticed was that there were like four different price classes in the 52 inch range and If you didn't know what all these specs mean there's like you.
Rym: look at them all like.
Rym: these TVs are all identical Except that one of them cost three thousand dollars more than the other one Mm-hmm, and it had to do with like what kind of backlight what kind of refresh rate and all that stuff?
Rym: Well, I don't want to say all that stuff because half of the matters and half of its bullshit.
Scott: Yeah, like even some of it does matter like contrast ratio does matter.
Scott: The thing is the number they tell you is wrong.
Scott: Yep, it's like if you go to the store to buy some like I was just saying You know the thread counts on sheets.
Scott: They don't.
Scott: most of those are lying to you.
Scott: Like you see go to the store.
Scott: It'll say like 1000 thread count.
Scott: It might be like 500.
Rym: they could just lie on that shit or they they use some other Definition that doesn't quite jive with what's really there.
Scott: on average It's actually if you go on the internet you can go and it'll tell you which brands of different bedsheets and it'll say Reported thread count actual thread count and some of the brands have you know slight differences like, you know reported 500 actual 475.
Scott: Some are like reported a thousand actual 100. so You can usually tell though by the price of the sheets and also by opening up and feeling that
Rym: yeah Well think about it you get what you pay for and while it's easy to overpay for something that doesn't live up or doesn't do What it says it does a
Scott: monster came.
Scott: It's
Rym: equally easy to buy something that is cheaper and not Understand why it's cheaper and the fact that the more expensive one is actually superior And a lot of times the more expensive option is a better value per dollar
Scott: Mm-hmm, which
Rym: honestly it sucks if you don't have enough money to buy the best value per dollar part like processors, right?
Rym: I got the core i7 920.
Rym: Okay, it's it was like $288.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Now if you look at the curve It's the best dollar per performance in the Intel core i7 because the next one up is like $480.
Rym: Oh, yeah, and the next one after that is like seven and they're only marginally faster and the next one under it They're basically the same thing only crook slightly.
Rym: So but the next one under it is like $250.
Rym: So there's obviously like the price per dollar gets to this maximum value point.
Rym: if you buy something more than that You're basically saying I'm willing to spend a ton of money for like a 1% performance increase.
Rym: But if you buy below that you're basically saying I didn't have enough money to buy the maximum value and it totally sucks for me.
Scott: Yep That's just said.
Rym: yeah Of course.
Rym: Really if you're gonna buy under the maximum prep like the optimal price point on the highest end Intel like the i7 You should go buy a dual core instead because you'll probably be better to do.
Scott: I was still holy shit awesome.
Scott: I mean I have one.
Scott: it's already wicked old, but it's still one of the fastest and best chips out there.
Rym: Yeah, I mean the core tube solo back in the door.
Rym: the core solo was pretty good.
Scott: It's okay.
Scott: I mean, I have one of my laptop and it's a little a for its time.
Scott: Yeah, it has a little trouble with high def YouTube.
Rym: I want to point out for anyone who doesn't realize when I bought the new but that's also partially because it has the Integrated Intel graphics.
Rym: I ended up having to buy six gigabytes of RAM and I didn't want six I only wanted four.
Rym: I wanted exactly.
Scott: there's no reason to have six.
Rym: However Triple channel I needed three dims.
Rym: So basically my choices were three gigs of RAM not enough obviously or six gigs of RAM too much.
Rym: So I had to buy the stupid six gigs.
Scott: Luckily, I would have done the same thing if I had also the triple channel.
Rym: They have this pack of three two gigabyte dims.
Rym: that is cheaper than a lot of four gigabyte.
Scott: If only you could have gotten three one and a half gigabyte dim.
Rym: I know I considered getting six one gigabyte dims just to fully load out all my dim slots, but now that's stupid.
Scott: Yeah, because in the future you might buy be able to get like three, you know, maybe something crazy will happen.
Scott: There'll be some crazy app that just uses shit ton of RAM.
Scott: You'll be able to buy like three four gigabit days ago.
Rym: tick tick tick.
Rym: My philosophy was right with RAM is that that's one of the biggest things you can revitalize a computer with when the RAM it uses Is dirt cheap.
Scott: Oh you want to hear funny story?
Scott: So my aunt right she had a computer and the computer was really slow.
Scott: and Blair Right and it was obviously because she filled it with full of crap with some e-machine, right?
Scott: It was like the company that made.
Scott: it was a machine, but it was just a PC.
Scott: So I check it out and I'm like, alright.
Scott: Alright, there's nothing really wrong with it.
Scott: It's just full of Blair and she really didn't have anything on it.
Scott: All she did was like go to Facebook and stuff.
Scott: So I'm like, oh, I'll just wipe it.
Scott: So it had a Vista disk.
Scott: it came with.
Scott: so I reinstalled the Vista and it worked and it was significantly better.
Scott: But it was still slow and I realized it basically only had 512 megs of RAM yet.
Scott: It shipped with.
Rym: My video card has more than that.
Scott: So 512 megs of RAM is not enough to run the Vista that this thing came with.
Scott: so obviously it was one of those You know bargain-basement piece of craps Monitors.
Scott: so, you know, I she gave.
Scott: I was at her house.
Scott: So we took her credit card who went to Newegg and I ordered the maximum two gigs of RAM for that computer.
Rym: It's probably dirt cheap by that point.
Scott: It was like 40 bucks.
Scott: I was like this as soon as you put this in the computer, it's gonna be amazing, right?
Scott: So they ordered it and it showed up and I explained to my cousin like how to install it.
Scott: I'm like, you know, well you put it in these slots here, right?
Scott: I Hear I heard the other day for my parents that they tried to put it in while the computer was on and they fried it.
Scott: Turn it off.
Rym: It's like I thought you were going to say and the computer was a thousand times faster.
Scott: It would have been if they would have turned the computer off before putting it in there.
Rym: man You know, what's really?
Scott: I told them but they didn't listen.
Scott: It's like I did.
Scott: turn the computer off unplug it put the things in the servers I work with we can.
Scott: hot-swap RAM CPU motherboards Yeah, so I'm just like so maybe they didn't throw it out.
Scott: Maybe there's a chance actually get this.
Scott: There's a slight chance that it works and if I go there I can check it out and see what the situation.
Rym: one thing I Didn't do cuz I'm gonna buy a NAS instead.
Rym: I just have one physical hard drive I bought like the best value like cheapest 650 gigabyte hard drive there was.
Rym: that was fast just to put like all my games and stuff on and all my like working files With a HCI which now is supported well and fully in both Linux and Windows 7.
Rym: Mm-hmm I tried it.
Rym: I can mount and dismount and connect and disconnect Sata drives without powering off the computer.
Rym: Mm-hmm, so I could have used one of those back planes and had a raid 5 in the computer.
Rym: That's hot-swappable Right.
Rym: I didn't because I'm gonna make an I'm gonna get a NAS or something.
Rym: But it's really cool that that is kind of come to fruition to where I can do that with just commodity hardware.
Scott: Yeah, why not?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: All right, you want to see some news?
Rym: Yeah, we should get away from my computer But my computer is a tiny god.
Rym: I'm very very happy with it.
Scott: so You know when you're backing stuff up right, you know.
Scott: And you need to back it up permanent Like most people nowadays are using something like Amazon s3 to back up on the Internet's because you need the remote backup.
Scott: Or maybe they're backing up onto actual hard drives because a one terabyte hard drive is fucking cheap as all hell, right?
Scott: You just be like BAM hundred bucks back up a whole terabyte of stuff.
Rym: Maybe you have some regulatory Requirement.
Rym: it has to back things up onto an immutable media like some sort of optical things.
Rym: So you can't change it later.
Scott: Well, yes says many people do have these government requirements or perhaps, you know physical requirements You know the.
Scott: for their own security desires They want something to be on a physical thing that they own not on anyone else's computer not on some hard drive that might crash but on a tape or a disk that is permanent that they can then copy and ship one to one place and keep one in another place perfectly safe.
Scott: and they own it and it's in a safe and no one can get to it.
Scott: and Mostly companies need to do this.
Scott: not normal people but companies.
Scott: and the thing is many companies do this You know with maybe a blu-ray or something, right?
Scott: But how much does a blu-ray hold like?
Scott: I don't know not that much really like 30 gigs something like that, right?
Rym: It's amazing how fast a physical media like that becomes obsolete in the modern day.
Rym: That's why I don't care about blu-ray because it's gonna be completely supplanted by digital.
Scott: Yeah, blu-ray blue blu-ray can have 50 gigs for a dual layer disk.
Scott: Oh 200 gig 200 gig disks are available Right.
Rym: All right, that's that's that's.
Scott: It's like I'd rather buy the one terabyte hard drive.
Scott: Yeah for like said problem is they're not immutable.
Scott: But anyway, so You know many places though are very old.
Scott: They still use magnetic tape.
Rym: I'll just note at least that magnetic tape has a lot of advantages.
Rym: depending on what you're trying to do Magnetic tapes can hold a fucking shit ton of data.
Scott: So, um, you know a while ago, right?
Scott: There were they released eight terabyte magnetic tapes, but IBM and Fujifilm They just invented a new magnetic tape that they advertised in a in an awesome old-school Advertisement, right?
Scott: That's all like, you know UNIVAC magnetic tape.
Scott: It's black and white.
Scott: It's pretty good, right?
Scott: Guess how much this met.
Scott: run real of this.
Rym: new magnetic tape can hold you wouldn't to quote Futurama You wouldn't ask unless it was either a really really big number or a really really small.
Scott: So they now they just invented and are selling 35 terabyte magnetic tapes.
Rym: now think about that.
Scott: It is rare that there that's 35 hard drives, right?
Scott: So think 35 hard drives, you know, you know what a hard drive looks like.
Scott: just imagine 35 of them.
Scott: Now one roll of tape it can hold all that.
Scott: that is how good this magnetic tape is.
Rym: order of magnitude.
Rym: It is very rare that things jump by an order of magnitude from one from one technological step from 8 to 35.
Scott: So 8 16 so more than five more than four times as much per tape as before.
Rym: One thing I love in general There's you could
Scott: back up like even if you have a shit ton of data like, you know A place like where Rym works might have you could get a few days on one Or maybe even a few weeks on one of those tapes.
Scott: It might be worth getting the system that uses them.
Rym: It's just frightening and amazing and awe-inspiring that just in the last five years or so The technology related to computers has been increasing at it.
Rym: Like there are discoveries on this magnitude on a fairly regular basis right now And I think computing as we know it within 10 years is going to be almost Unintelligible and indistinguishable from what we have now.
Rym: Like if you think computers from 10 years ago look crappy We're gonna get to the point to where a computer that's six months old looks like cuneiform on a clay tablet.
Scott: Oh, they actually they put them in uh in cartridges nowadays.
Scott: You don't actually need the roll of tape They just have a tape thing and you slide it in and you're all done.
Rym: Uh, it's been that way for a long time.
Rym: No, in fact at ibm, we had these gigantic awesome robots.
Scott: I'm watching.
Scott: i'm watching videos of uh, You know tape reel cartridges at ibm right now you should find videos of like our ibm archive robots in the warehouses.
Rym: They they basically the warehouses move the tapes around on their own, right?
Rym: Yep We also have new physical things around.
Rym: They're cute because they'll if I get in their way when they're like puttering around with something They'll be like, please get out of my way.
Rym: Please get out of my way.
Rym: I need help.
Scott: Will they really say I need help?
Scott: I need help and you'll have to pick one up and shove it to get it in.
Rym: No, these things were bigger than me.
Rym: they would kill a man.
Rym: Oh, they there were.
Scott: why are they saying please get out of my way.
Rym: They should be like get out the way Get the fuck out the way Some of the warehouse.
Rym: So, you know speaking of advancement like that this article is just crap.
Rym: but The article raises a point.
Rym: i'm coughing out here because we're you know, we've already talked a lot about my computer.
Rym: So i'd feel guilty bringing up the news.
Rym: But the fart conversation is kind of interesting.
Rym: remember that woman Amy who was.
Rym: he did.
Rym: she did a ted talk about prosthetics because she's missing two of her legs And she has prosthetic legs that are better than real legs for running.
Rym: Yep, and more there are more and more articles like this kind of pop sci or commentary or op-ed articles talking about the fact that You know What are we going to do when people get to the point of?
Rym: Like electing to have surgery to have a prosthetic that's better than their real body.
Rym: I mean are people going to start our pictures going to cut off their arms get a prosthetic.
Rym: Is that legal?
Rym: Is that like?
Rym: what's that going to do to sports?
Rym: What's that going to do to society?
Rym: Should we allow it?
Rym: And I just want to nip all this in the bud by saying yes is definitely going to happen.
Rym: There's nothing we can do about it.
Rym: And the future of our society is cybernetics and ghost in the shell.
Scott: yeah, I mean everyone's always.
Scott: you know, I took how many classes at rit that were all about like Technology and ethics and the scary cyborg future.
Scott: and yeah, I took like 10 classes on that.
Scott: It should have been like a you know, a special minor or something.
Scott: But were you in the same boat?
Rym: I was where every class.
Rym: the conclusion in the end was It's going to advance.
Rym: It's all going to happen.
Rym: It can't be stopped.
Scott: Actually the conclusion of most of my classes was just like yeah.
Scott: Well, you know technology itself isn't evil.
Scott: You know, there's.
Scott: you know, an atomic bomb just sitting there isn't bad.
Scott: Just people picking one up and dropping one on someone is bad.
Scott: Yeah, but you know, it's like, you know We should always try to invent new sciences that use it responsibly and not for evil.
Rym: and you know I think it's more than a lot of people They make.
Rym: they beg questions whenever these arguments come up, you know, someone will the question.
Rym: the articles always say things like.
Rym: But you know, it'll be a bad thing or they imply that it'll be bad that people augment themselves.
Rym: or are they even human?
Rym: That's the biggest question.
Rym: If someone starts modifying their body to that extent for no good reason are they even human anymore?
Scott: Well, if some?
Scott: well, that begs the question is the lady who just lost her two legs human?
Scott: Yes So if I put on a super leg to be a kicker in the nfl or something Then I am also still human as human as that lady.
Rym: that is the uh ship of thesius conundrum.
Rym: You know if we have thesius's ship it was the ship that he went out.
Scott: Oh your favorite ship of thesius.
Rym: I remember Yeah, he kicks everybody's asses with this ship.
Rym: so the people say all right We're gonna save this ship forever and they put it in a dry dock and they're like look that was thesius's motherfucking ship.
Rym: So, you know a hundred years go by and one of the planks of wood rots because it's an old ship.
Rym: So to repair it they replace that one plank of wood.
Rym: Is it still thesius's ship fast forward a thousand years?
Rym: They've replaced every single plank one by one over a thousand years.
Rym: Is it still thesius's ship?
Rym: Take the same concept and apply to your human brain.
Rym: if you replace one brain cell with a chip That does the same thing that brain cell did.
Rym: are they still human one?
Scott: It's 100 identical in every single way to that brain cell.
Scott: In fact, no forget to forget doing a chip, right?
Scott: They make an absolutely 100 perfectly identical Brain cell in a thing and then they surgically replace the other one in the exact same position.
Scott: So not even a question about like electronics in here it's a brain cell.
Scott: it's just one they made outside.
Scott: It's exactly the same as the one that's inside.
Rym: still humanship of thesius all that.
Rym: so To get back to the big question the big question, you know people ask are they even human anymore?
Rym: The real question is does the word human even mean anything?
Rym: Yeah, it's not a matter of humor.
Rym: now We're all just consciousnesses that may or may not have free will.
Scott: yeah I mean, it's it's pretty much.
Scott: the problem is that people attach, you know, these semantic, you know words Uh to emotional ideas that really have no Real connection to the realities of our universe.
Scott: So when we learned any, you know, when the the we discover New disturbing, you know realities of our universe.
Scott: they disturb because they conflict with the existing realities Upon which you know all our current assumptions of language and everything else are based on.
Scott: so when the foundation is shaken Everything else would be shaken on top which is you just have to sort of Shift over and get an earthquake proof building and then you'll be all right.
Rym: well which is interesting because I just picked up uh our scout backers neuropath and As far as I can tell the whole kind of thread of the book Is basically the idea that it takes a whole bunch of characters And confronts them with the reality that everything they do is a product of everything that came before them and cause and effect and that they probably don't have any free will.
Rym: and That's one thing.
Rym: I mean philosophers have debated that point for as long as there have been people.
Rym: the point this book brings up is What if you have a world now where science has basically proven all of that to be true?
Rym: What if you prove that you don't have your own free will?
Scott: well, it doesn't matter because things Things were going to turn out that way anyway, and things will turn out the way they were going to turn out.
Scott: So it doesn't change.
Scott: Yes knowing it doesn't change it But at the same time only knowing for sure that it's not there can change it.
Rym: Yep, but it raises an interesting question of how Does that does it affect a society?
Scott: It's like how inventing time travel can't change anything because if you do invent time travel you would have invented time travel And any time travel to the past that could have affected the past before you currently has already happened.
Rym: Well, unless unless you have time lords that stop you and there's some sort of intergalactic police But everything that they have done will have already happened.
Rym: Maybe or maybe time is non-linear and there's just this one long contiguous time frame That follows the protagonist's point of view and that's the only actual timeline.
Scott: But then that that one is completely not going to.
Scott: you're never going to you know.
Scott: If someone changes something in the past, you're not going to know it now.
Scott: You're not going to go.
Scott: Someone just changed the past.
Scott: fuckers It's you wouldn't?
Scott: you wouldn't even know.
Rym: you might if you're the protagonist and the entire frame of reference of the universe is around you.
Scott: If if you are the time traveler, then you would know that you change the time but your actual time personally Would just be what it is.
Rym: it would be like going on vacation to the past Unless it was bill and ted where you know, you say things like man.
Rym: It was so great after we solved all this stuff where we went back and put the blah in the blah And then the blah and the blah is there as long as they remember to do it later.
Rym: Yeah Yep, god, I gotta watch that movie again.
Rym: That movie was fucking awesome but anyway, I just I I don't know.
Rym: I wanted to bring this up because it It's becoming more and more likely that in our lifetimes We're all going to have to confront the reality of the fact that we are likely going to take human consciousness Break it down and put it for real in a machine.
Rym: Yeah, like.
Rym: I have no doubt that in my lifetime.
Rym: We will see a ghost in the shell style person I stand.
Rym: I believe that a hundred percent.
Scott: Yeah, but I don't believe ray curves while he's a nut.
Rym: Actually, no, I I think that shiro has a better handle on what's actually going to happen.
Rym: Yeah, I mean well the thing shiro has the right balance of People are fucked up and will do weird stuff and have gigantic butts but at the same time the science will be there.
Scott: Mm-hmm Kurzweil thinks that like if he eats vitamins like a thousand vitamins a day is gonna live forever.
Rym: So now the way to live to forever is to put your brain in a robot body and then eventually put your brain's brain In a cybernetic thing.
Scott: i'm going for a jamison body.
Scott: I know about you.
Rym: Oh, man I'm hoping at least if they get to jamison technology before I die Then I can go to jamison and hold out until I can be the major.
Rym: Yeah, I realized talking to emily, you know, we're watching ghost in the shell standalone complex again.
Rym: You know I'm watching that.
Rym: reading neuropath and reading this article all at the same time made me think about this a lot And emily said man I hope I live long enough to just be able to have the major's body.
Rym: And I realized that my only response to that is so do I?
Rym: Mostly because I also want the major's body.
Scott: Here's something I realized right just now two seconds ago.
Scott: It's kind of good that i'm practicing playing some street fighter because you know what?
Scott: In the See where you're going in the ghost in the shell world, right?
Scott: You know, no one can really have the major's body because it's so incredibly difficult to control that kind of body.
Scott: It's just really really fucking hard And that's why people have jamison bodies.
Scott: Like if you put jamison's brain in the major's body He'd probably just stumble around like a doofus if he could even stand or walk The major.
Scott: is that fucking hard?
Rym: the major is only the way she is because she was kind of Fucked as a kid and put into these like she lived.
Scott: Yeah, she was in that body since she was like zero.
Scott: so she's an expert at controlling cyborg bodies.
Scott: She basically had played street fighter constantly because it's so complex.
Scott: just walk You know let alone do the thing She does like jump off a building or kick someone's ass and do martial arts.
Rym: She gets the point of playing street fighter on like 10 simultaneous games and kicking ass in all of them.
Scott: Yeah, so, you know by practicing street fighter and get keeping my brain able to do you know complex physical coordinated things like that I am increasing my abilities to perhaps control a more complicated and advanced cyborg body in the future.
Scott: So maybe I won't have to be in a jamison.
Scott: Maybe I could be more like, you know, you want to be in chun li?
Scott: No, not really.
Scott: But you know the thing is in all reality.
Scott: I would probably be more like togas.
Scott: I'd be like the guy who's just you know doing nothing and i'd be cool because I was the mostly human guy.
Scott: Nah, except you'll be old But togas is the best guy.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I think it's weird.
Rym: I've realized that by and large it's girls Who like the major is their favorite character and by and large guys like togasa bato and aramaki equally.
Scott: Uh, aramaki is totally awesome.
Scott: Togusa is the best dude.
Rym: I think togasa has the uh, awesome badass, but understated.
Rym: He's the hachiroku exactly, but bato has the Dude, I should just put my brain in hachiroku and aramaki is just astro boy.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So Anyway things of the day.
Rym: as I go back to college humor because this is too cool to pass up you suck.
Rym: This too shall pass.
Rym: It's a marching band video that is totally awesome and not on a football field.
Rym: I don't want to say anything else about it other than it is totally fucking awesome Especially when they use the camouflage and I like things that start really small especially musical acts Like you start with just freddie mercury singing and then one by one you keep adding backup dancers and backup singers Until there are 10 000 people on stage in a spectacle.
Rym: That's pretty much all I want out of life and this video does that to a small degree Except without freddie mercury because no one could ever get anywhere close to that.
Scott: All right So Rym likes to complain a lot about this thing.
Scott: that is true About the devorahi keyboard and how you know.
Scott: people don't realize.
Scott: maybe some people don't realize this but there is a you know.
Scott: You look at your keyboard.
Scott: It's a qwerty keyboard.
Scott: Why?
Scott: because you look at the top left and it says q-w-e-r-t-y.
Scott: All right, the qwerty refers to the arrangement of the letters, you know, why aren't they in alphabetical order?
Scott: Why aren't they in some other order?
Scott: Right?
Scott: So devorak was this guy not john c devorak?
Scott: a different devor?
Rym: I believe you mean john devorak.org slash block.
Scott: No anyway, and he decided he came up with a different layout for the keyboard, right?
Scott: And what you know?
Scott: his logic, you know, if you just think about it common sense wise Make sense.
Scott: The devorak keyboard has the most frequently used letters near the index finger and on the home row.
Scott: So like the home row is like a o-u-r-s-t or something like that.
Scott: I forget exactly what it is But it's like a-o-u-r-s-t-l.
Scott: So like, you know, you're basically you have the least you theoretically you have the least finger movement while typing If you get used to that layout as opposed to the qwerty layout.
Scott: and there's all sorts of fud, you know out there Talking about how.
Scott: uh, you know, the devorak keyboard is better you can type faster and it's better ergonomically speaking and it's just better.
Scott: and people just don't use it because there's some sort of Evil monopoly something something we're not going to get into it.
Rym: Don't even it's wrong It's not better.
Rym: And in fact, it's worse for the single reason that even if it is marginally better from a efficiency standpoint The whole world uses qwerty and you're at a disadvantage if you're required to use this one special weird one to type, right?
Scott: Well, it says here in this article at reason.com They typing errors the standard typewriter keyboard is exhibit a and the hottest new case against markets.
Scott: But the evidence has been cooked and basically what happens is in all kinds of economic debates people always talk about you know How.
Scott: oh, well, whoever's first to market or achieve mark or achieves market dominance early wins even if they're not superior Because you know that.
Scott: and then the qwerty is like the example of that, you know.
Scott: And sometimes they try to use like vhs is the example of that like oh beta max is better But vhs won because it was first or something like that conflated though.
Rym: I mean beta max was and basically Right.
Scott: So basically here's a gigantic article that talks about not only presenting all this evidence that no dvorak isn't actually better But b this whole market theory of first to market or first to market dominance is complete bullshit and better things do win quite often You know, I mean look the xbox 360 was first in this console generation And you know, it's beating the ps3 But the ps3 is still alive and the we is out selling them both.
Scott: So first to market didn't mean dick squat, right?
Scott: so Check out this article and learn some stuff and do not use the dvorak keyboard and anyone who uses dvorak keyboard is not your friend.
Rym: So We got to talk about the stupid apple tablet because everyone else I want to talk about just about the apple tablet.
Rym: I want to talk about tablets in general because they're this weird Market space that's always been really niche and there's been booms and busts of tablets more than once.
Scott: Well, I think the problem with the tablet right is that the tablet was sort of an obvious idea.
Scott: It wasn't like some you know, it was one of those things like everyone was imagining it even before we could make it, you know.
Scott: So, you know, it was.
Scott: it was very quick for someone to make one as soon as they could because it was just so Obvious.
Scott: everyone was always thinking about it.
Scott: Oh, of course a computer.
Scott: That's just a screen that you hold like a book duh.
Scott: So, you know, they finally made some.
Scott: Well, actually they've made them for a very long time for as long as they'd have touch screens and they've had You know different varieties of resistive touch screens for quite a while.
Scott: They they were just sort of expensive and difficult to get you know, but they were around In like the 90s.
Scott: you can get a touchscreen they existed.
Scott: But it wasn't until like the early 2000s when microsoft actually came out with like microsoft windows tablet pc edition And like viewsonic and all these other companies they made tablet pcs that you know were just The screen and and with a stylus because it resistant resistive and they had a thing where they had an on-screen keyboard And you would you know, you could write actually handwriting and they had a pretty good handwriting recognition thing Sort of like the newton did you know, which is also sort of a tablet pc.
Scott: It was just smaller.
Scott: and the thing is these things kind of sucked because Well, you know the battery life was poop because you know laptops were also poop in those days.
Rym: The touch screens were nothing like modern touch screens.
Scott: No, they were terrible touch screens.
Rym: Handwriting recognition was not great.
Rym: Like it was good great relative, but it wasn't good.
Scott: and two Writing is a lot slower than typing And they didn't have any sort of custom user interface.
Scott: like you had a palm pilot which had you know A little area you could draw on.
Scott: that was touch sensitive, right?
Scott: And those are all right because the whole thing was made assuming that you were going to do that.
Scott: But a tablet pc was just a copy of windows your web browser that was on there Or you know was not designed to be used with you know, the tabletness.
Scott: So basically you would touch the location bar And then you would have to use the handwriting recognition to put in a url or the on-screen keyboard And then you get a web page and it's like you couldn't pinch and zoom in or scroll it easily.
Scott: You had to like use the stylus on the scroll bar to go up and down.
Scott: You couldn't just sort of scroll up and down with your fingers or whatever.
Scott: So they're pretty much Absolutely terrible and useless and they never sold and they couldn't even think.
Scott: you know They made these things and they said well, you know who the hell wants one.
Scott: What force they tried to think like Oh, well You know doctors are going to want one because they stand up and use the computer like they are imagining like a doctor standing next to a patient's bed with this tablet pc instead of a you know, a clipboard full of stuff or like Maybe someone who's out in the field like a construction site will use it because they have you know Pretty much.
Scott: they imagined any job they could think of where they could imagine a person holding a clipboard And they thought that that was the person who needed the tablet pc.
Scott: now I will admit they're forgetting that all of those people on their clipboards had like these very custom and specialized forms that they were Filling out that they would need to write custom applications for to go on the tablet pc and those applications were never written.
Rym: Yep plus the fact that a lot of the data entry stuff in like hospitals or Construction sites or anything that they did have on their old like unique like terminals connecting to a mainframe.
Rym: They weren't going to hire anyone to write any custom software.
Scott: and also if you think about it right a doctor takes out a clipboard And he's got a lot of stuff to write on there.
Scott: Maybe it's going to take him a lot longer to write it with even if you're good handwriting nation in virtual keyboard versus, you know Dr.
Scott: Scrawl on the on the piece of paper, right?
Scott: So the tablet pcs were just completely terrible for everyone.
Rym: Well, I think straight up.
Rym: the way to analyze this is look at the modern market.
Rym: There are two primary in my opinion.
Rym: Well, I guess now there are three markets for a tablet pc.
Scott: I'm talking like a large tablet like and all of the people making them are completely ignoring these markets And they're going for markets that do not exist.
Rym: And the weird thing is these three markets are almost all completely mutually exclusive in terms of what the people want in their tablet.
Rym: Exactly market the first because they're the easiest ones the people who want something new and shiny.
Rym: They want a crazy apple tablet that looks all fancy.
Scott: They'll buy whatever you make so it doesn't matter.
Rym: Yep, make it really expensive and shiny.
Rym: It's just a gigantic iphone.
Rym: They'll be happy.
Scott: Yeah, it doesn't matter what it is.
Scott: It could be poop on a stick.
Scott: They'll buy it now market.
Rym: The second is artists, but the vast majority of tablet pcs are terrible for drawing compared to like a waycom or a cintiq.
Scott: Yeah, well, here's the problem right?
Scott: is that?
Scott: okay?
Scott: the waycom tablet even the you know, the cheapo waycom tablet Which doesn't which isn't a screen?
Scott: It's just a touch pad right is good for artists.
Scott: It has the pressure sensitive pen thing and right, you know, and it's.
Scott: it's still pretty good.
Scott: and you know, even the cheap one It's just smaller and it's not as good as the more expensive one.
Scott: Of course It's more expensive one is greatly superior, but it's still good.
Scott: The thing is the touchscreens on you know tablets and uh You know iphones, right?
Scott: They have the resistive touchscreens like the ds We have to use a stylus and they have capacitive touchscreens like the iphone where you have to use fingers and a stylus doesn't work.
Scott: And the thing is capacitive touchscreens are very precise, but they can't really do pressure sensitivity.
Scott: All they can do is sort of, you know, multi-tracking of you know, multi-fingerness multi-touch And do it fast.
Scott: Yeah, and they can do it precisely.
Scott: and they can tell taps apart from drags But they can't tell like hard and soft presses.
Scott: They have no idea really, you know.
Scott: So those don't really work for drawing.
Scott: and the resistive ones, you know.
Scott: or the you know Those don't really work for drawing either because they're so imprecise.
Scott: only the waycom style Sort of electro ones where the pen has some magic in it.
Scott: those ones Actually work for drawing but they never put those in the screen of any laptops ever part of it.
Rym: I mean look at a waycom.
Rym: there's no screen under.
Rym: they don't have to worry about like the durability of the screen anything like that Scratching it.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: It's just an input device.
Scott: Well, I was about to say they have the cintiq and the cintiq is exactly what you are saying.
Scott: It is the waycom screen on top of a monitor.
Scott: The problem is It's not a laptop or a tablet it's a monitor.
Scott: you have to plug it into the wall and connect it to a computer with like a dvi cable and usb cable and It takes a lot of electricity and it's gigantic.
Scott: You can't like bring this thing, you know around with you and walk around drawing trees or whatever you're gonna do, right?
Scott: You have to put it on your desk, you know, and it's it's your monitor.
Scott: It's gigantic.
Scott: It's heavy It's expensive and I really don't understand why there really isn't a technological reason.
Scott: they couldn't put.
Scott: you know waycom Screens, you know on a laptop it can totally be done Uh, and they just don't.
Rym: well the one argument at least is that things like photoshop a lot of the software you would use If you're drawing is, you know, pretty heavy footprint relatively, especially, you know, manipulating large image files that sort of thing.
Scott: You so so you can make a lat.
Scott: they have laptops core 2 duo 2 gigs of ram I mean solid-state drive you would put.
Rym: you can put a photoshop on there as light as my ultra portable.
Scott: It'd be like a normal 15-inch laptop.
Scott: Yeah, plus you'd want it to be a normal 15-inch laptop So you get more room to draw.
Scott: it'd be harder to draw I imagine on like a tiny weird laptop, you know Like a netbook, you know have a lot of room on there now.
Rym: Well, you could go one step further and have the cintiqi style screen That can be detached and used as a cintiq style screen at home or you stick it to your laptop.
Scott: The thing is if you could do that you could sell that for a lot of money because it's sort of like.
Scott: hey this Not only is it a laptop, but you can plug this into your desktop computer And you won't need to buy a cintiq also so you can use this to draw On itself or on any other computer with a usb cable.
Scott: You could probably charge fifteen hundred to two thousand dollars for that just because it's doing the work of two devices.
Rym: Yep, I guess that's the second market segment that really is not being addressed at all.
Scott: No, and there's a lot of money to be made there even though it's you know, it's it's a it's you know Definitely a vertical market of just artist people.
Scott: There's enough of them out there.
Scott: I think that if you made a product that just blew everyone away You'd pretty much sell one to every single one of those people no matter what.
Rym: And and plus it'd be kind of one of those obligatory purchases for people in certain markets.
Rym: Yeah You might even have like situations where it's like like every film every like animation school Every like art school is gonna have to have these for their students.
Scott: Yeah, like kids who are going to art school, you know, they would all you know It's like.
Scott: well which computer should I buy going to art school?
Scott: Well, duh the only one that's actually an art computer.
Scott: Now the third obviously the one to get market segment.
Rym: probably the easiest one to make a profit on Are the doctors the construction people the business people who basically need portable rapid.
Rym: I am walking around data entry.
Rym: These need to not run windows.
Rym: They need to run a proprietary Operating system or something built on linux that has a very customizable plug-in style interface for data entry.
Scott: Well, I think the way to make money got to be cheap.
Rym: They got to be durable They got to be extensible and you got to get a bunch of third-party vendors on board to make stuff for them.
Scott: Well, I think the way to do this actually is not to make a tablet platform or maybe at least not Publicize the fact that it's a platform but instead to make custom devices sell, you know, dr pad and you just it's.
Scott: it's called the dr pad and that's it has Hospital software on it already and you sell it as part of a system because you're providing it to hospitals And you don't actually sell it, you know on newegg or whatever, you know It's companies.
Scott: go around and make sales calls and try to sell this whole system to companies.
Rym: There are a million things like this part of the yeah, but they're terrible They're.
Rym: they use these custom non-tablet just horrible to use devices And it was easier for me when I worked at that hospital back in the day When I was trying to do an inventory I walked around holding a laptop that was open typing.
Scott: I actually think you know apple basically only makes products for you know consumer stuff.
Scott: if there was another company that came out I think there's even more you can make.
Scott: apple actually I think would make more money If they stopped making consumer devices all together just like well poop forget that right?
Scott: maybe you know.
Scott: Keep the ipod division open and what they would do is they would just go to different vertical markets And basically make a well-designed product because there are no well-designed vertical products And they would just dominate every vertical market one at a time by introducing a well-designed Market dominating thing into each and every one.
Scott: and the best part is they basically and the money you make there is enterprise money.
Scott: That's not like, you know, hundred dollar ipod money.
Scott: This is like ten thousand dollars a piece of money You can make.
Rym: they could do the same thing that mobling and nintendo do Once you capture like two or three of these vertical markets.
Rym: There is so much overlap in what each market requires that you basically did most of your work already And you could have a fairly small development team, you know, you've already made doctor.
Rym: basically what dentist pad so you can make.
Rym: uh I kept thinking of fake doctor things like chiropractic and homeopathy.
Scott: Yeah, basically what you would do is apple would spawn off a new company for each mark in each market.
Scott: So they would make apple.
Scott: they would make apple med and that would only make apple's Awesome design devices for medical verticals and they would be like apple, you know, uh Something else like one example charting.
Scott: once you apple restaurant and it would just be like, you know Apple point of sale machines for restaurants with the whole, you know Once you make the like charting is the hugest thing in hospitals.
Rym: That's hard for people to do reliably especially with technology.
Rym: If you just made if you made the charting technology work There are like 10 separate vertical markets.
Rym: you could take over with that alone.
Scott: Yep And you know people just don't go for that.
Scott: That's why everything you ever that's why everything people use at work is horrible And poorly designed and terrible because the companies that know how to design things don't go into those markets And it's just these terrible old nasty companies.
Scott: If someone hired some designers and went in to the verticals, they would rake in the dough.
Scott: There was
Rym: an article a long time ago about why you see certain kinds of businesses in certain places like in airports On military bases stuff like that and it had to do with the fact that The companies that get these large enterprise style contracts are not the companies that make the best product or have the best pitch or have The best price.
Rym: they're the companies that have the best skill at negotiating the bureaucracy.
Rym: So their primary skill is getting into these big contracts not necessarily executing them Yep.
Scott: So if you could put together some people who could make a better quality product and also the people who are better at getting into These projects, you know contracts and navigating bureaucracies You could just pretty much blow every single competitor out of the water.
Scott: They have no chance.
Scott: This is why you know things like oracle and cisco have way more money than anyone else, you know Compared to say apple because you know or uh anyone cool because cool people can't do that kind of stuff.
Rym: Only the boring people can get in even though there's more money in the borrowing if you're willing to do the boring.
Scott: But that's because no one that's.
Scott: but no one does the boring.
Scott: Well, if that's I think the the biggest, you know You could take over the world be even bigger than google bigger than anyone else if you manage to be the first company To do the boring.
Rym: Well, this is what high school guidance counselors need to remind people.
Rym: They got to go to these kids and be like look You could be a professional juggler and live your life that way.
Rym: Or you can make a ton of money by doing the boring shit.
Rym: No one else wants to do Yep, and then retire at 30 and live with your millions and go juggle for fun.
Scott: Or you can work in a gas station because you guys you did terribly in school and you're obviously a moron.
Scott: That's all you're gonna be in life, I just hate to break it to you.
Scott: I know i'm supposed to worry about the self-esteem bullshit.
Scott: But listen, you gotta face reality here.
Scott: kid The gas station.
Scott: maybe you could be the gas station manager and you know what.
Scott: if maybe you work at it learn some mechanics Maybe you can be the gas station owner.
Scott: That's about it for you.
Rym: You know, there's another tack to take with those kids.
Rym: It's not a federal crime if you don't rob a federally protected institution.
Rym: Here's a mask.
Rym: This is your best shot.
Scott: Yes, rob this non-federal credit union.
Scott: Rob this, you know illegal bookie or you know what kid.
Scott: he's breaking the law, too.
Scott: He's not gonna call.
Scott: you know what kid?
Rym: you got about a 20 chance of making it through college and coming out.
Rym: Okay, take all this college money you saved up Red or black.
Rym: you got better odds All right, all right, but so what's going on with apple?
Rym: because they've you know, they're gonna announce all their shit.
Rym: I'm not even gonna bother i'm gonna predict right now.
Rym: They're catering to the first market.
Rym: We talked about shiny useless bullshit.
Rym: their tablet is going to be a gigantic ipod touch.
Rym: Probably now it's going to be between the ipod touch and the iphone touch.
Rym: Here's the thing They're gonna have like one pseudo killer app.
Rym: Like it's also a universal remote that synchronizes with all your apple stuff.
Rym: Yeah, probably and maybe it'll even sync over the air, but that's it.
Scott: Well, the thing is right even though they will probably just cater to that first market.
Scott: there is actually A reason that I would want a tablet and this is something, you know I know exactly what you're gonna say and it overlaps with the shiny thing market.
Scott: No, it doesn't.
Rym: I think it does a little bit.
Scott: What do you think i'm gonna say?
Rym: You're gonna say you want something you can lay down in bed and surf the web.
Rym: That's right.
Scott: That's right, because right look at this I wake up in the morning, you know And if you're in your bed or on your couch You people have laptops and netbooks and things but they're uncomfortable.
Rym: That's why you see people with like the snuggie and the weird little like pillow that holds the laptop on a tray But even then it sucks your wrist start hurting.
Scott: It's just not comfortable, right?
Scott: And pre also like on a on a on a plane on a train.
Scott: It's not comfortable to use a laptop and i'm not doing.
Scott: if i'm doing coding or if i'm doing writing something I need the keyboard.
Scott: I need to swing it out.
Scott: But if i'm not I don't need the keyboard.
Scott: It's just making things uncomfortable.
Scott: and basically a big ipod touch would be pretty good for those situations You know because I basically lay in bed with the iphone but it's small and it sucks and it's uncomfortable.
Scott: so the thing is Is you know a lot of times, you know, my ipod is too small.
Scott: i'm in my house.
Scott: So what do I do?
Scott: If I want to like browse the web with the computer attached to the tv.
Scott: now i've got to use like You know a keyboard and a mouse all the way over to the tv.
Scott: that sucks Right.
Scott: or I can go sit at my computer, but i'm sitting at a desk.
Scott: It's not as comfortable as lying on a couch.
Scott: Well, I only want to sit at the desk to do work.
Scott: or you know something like, you know Playing fps where I need a mouse.
Rym: Here's what I have to say about this.
Rym: All this is is very simply a convergence between iphone and kindle And when those two things combine it's basically either what apple is making or what all that technology is going to converge upon.
Scott: So the world does need I think You know some sort of computer that you can use from the couch or the bed or wherever Right.
Scott: that doesn't have this stupid keyboard always in the way.
Scott: the thing is.
Scott: I think the product apple will make.
Scott: You know regardless of any other rumors if they even come out with a tablet who knows maybe they'll come out with like.
Scott: You know the apple poop on a stick.
Rym: Right, I poop I poop every day every day.
Scott: Um, right Regardless of what they come out with it could be You know, it might be too limited as apple products always are.
Rym: they're going to announce it.
Rym: It's going to be really shiny.
Rym: It'll look great.
Rym: They'll announce one, you know, pseudo killer app.
Rym: That's just killer enough to where the people who are waiting for it are gonna buy no matter what.
Rym: Yeah, and then they'll have one half like half.
Scott: It could be like the apple tv where it just doesn't have enough functionality.
Scott: It's you know, it can't do everything.
Rym: I'll bet they're pseudo like their secondary thing not their main killer app.
Rym: I'm, not sure what the main quote unquote killer app is going to be.
Rym: I think the secondary thing is they're going to have some sort of like e-reader Like.
Rym: it'll do what a kindle does but you know you can do it.
Scott: Yeah, they'll be like well it reads books and magazines in full color and has a great You know touch screen user interface for doing so and all those books and magazines.
Rym: It'll cost money.
Scott: and our drm It'll probably and has a web browser, but the web browser doesn't have flash.
Rym: It'll probably run itunes natively and It'll like do all the media stuff natively but also sync up with all your apple stuff in your house.
Scott: Yeah, it's just gonna be like well it can do all this cool stuff but only if you have other apple stuff and only if you buy movies on whatever and it's You know.
Scott: if it's too limited it's probably gonna have this great interface and it'll probably Theoretically have all that awesome functionality that I want to be there.
Scott: But that all that awesome functionality Will probably be missing a few things that annoyed the hell out of everyone like no copy paste and you know What they're gonna do and it's only gonna really work 100 perfectly.
Scott: if everything in your house is apple They're gonna buy all your media from apple.
Rym: They're just gonna wait until a competitor appears.
Rym: that does those other things, right?
Rym: And then suddenly all those features will appear like they always do.
Scott: Yeah, see i'm hoping right.
Scott: i'm beginning to gain more Hope that the there are other companies that can actually come out and design something You know as well as apple has designed it while also providing all the necessary functionality.
Scott: If you looked at how boxy totally shredded the apple tv times a billion, right?
Scott: The thing is boxy's actually probably selling more mac minis than apple is.
Scott: um You know, but their boxy box should actually do a lot to stop that right.
Scott: and the roku not a bad user interface either.
Scott: Yeah, they split out the xbox 360 windows media center.
Scott: pretty good, right?
Rym: I'm glad I got the original roku.
Rym: now They have like the the non hd version the hd version the 802 like all these different versions.
Rym: Mine because I got it originally is cheaper than the biggest version has everything that one has except 802 11n.
Scott: Ah, yeah, I think you know, so We'll see what happens here.
Scott: but I definitely you know I am sort of looking for a computer that I can just use on the from the couch or the bed.
Scott: because You know, I I see I have no interest.
Scott: people always think about this tablet like bringing it places.
Scott: I really I would only probably bring it if I was going on a trip, you know to read stuff on a plane or something.
Scott: I would probably never bring it You know to.
Rym: You know, I wouldn't bring it on the train.
Scott: Yeah, I wouldn't bring it to work or around town.
Rym: The only reason I don't buy a netbook and carry that everywhere with me is because I own an ultra portable.
Rym: That's not that much bigger than a netbook.
Scott: Yeah Um, but yeah I definitely am looking for a way to like read some websites From my couch as opposed to having to go sit at my desk all the time It is going to be I I predict about a year.
Scott: read some web comics from my couch read comics from my couch Which yeah, which I can do already but non-paper comics.
Rym: It's going to be about a year and a half before what you want exists.
Scott: That's my prediction, but I am looking for it.
Scott: And you know what?
Scott: There is a Very very very very very tiny chance that maybe apple will just be like, yeah, we made this totally awesome open tablet platform with My.
Rym: I mean it's gonna fall short in in the in the exact same distance from glory that nintendo and apple always do.
Rym: They come just high enough to where you want it But not high enough to where it's good enough to do what we really wanted to do.
Scott: Also, it seems that a lot of rumors are pointing heavily towards some sort of you know Cellular connection right so that you'll you know, it'll connect to at and t or verizon or something And then
Rym: they'll suck they'll solve the wrong problem
Scott: They'll subsidize the cost of the tablet and you just pay like 30 bucks a month so that you can write.
Scott: it's like, uh, no Sorry, I really have no interest in having this connect to the cell phone network because it's never leaving my house ever Right, and
Rym: clearly
Scott: I have no interest in you know Getting cellular data to it because anything I want to put on it i'll put on it with a usb stick.
Rym: Like i'm saying apple and nintendo will very often solve the wrong problem and everyone forgets what their original problem was.
Scott: Yeah Uh, they just they bombed the wrong place.
Rym: So my prediction is I will be disappointed and sales are going to be really high for this thing.
Rym: It's probably going to sell out whatever it is.
Scott: I don't know about that.
Scott: My prediction is it'll be about Equal to macbook air right?
Scott: It's going to be sort of like, you know Whoa, it's incredibly thin and there's a few things that are really cool about it and interesting and whoa, look at that You know, there's a feature there and a piece of software there that I really wish I had.
Scott: those few things are awesome But the whole package too much money and or Has things I don't want and is not really something i'm gonna buy.
Scott: when you summon all interesting this This doesn't matter to apple and it's going to be too closed too close.
Rym: This doesn't matter to me in regards to apple.
Rym: what this is causing me to do is not go out and buy it or whatever.
Rym: The fact that this is coming out is causing me to not buy a kindle or a nook Because I realized after they announced this that all these technologies are converging And i'm not going to buy any product in any of those like lines until they converge on some sort of.
Rym: Hey, you know the the thing that is a kindle and is a tablet and is all these things and never leaves my house And i'll put two of them in the library.
Rym: and that's the end of it.
Scott: Yeah, I have no plans to buy any of these.
Rym: that is the product I will buy and it will come out in about 1.5 Years.
Scott: if you had not noticed I have not been bought or planned to buy any of those things either, you know Because I need openness I need you know, I can't.
Scott: the technology's not.
Scott: it's like look at this right with The ipod right.
Scott: the ipod is the thing that apple needs to learn from right because they made it so they should know That the only reason the ipod succeeded right at all is because it could just play fucking mp3s.
Scott: Right if the ipod cannot play mp3s and could only and was limited only to the drm Music files in the itunes store.
Scott: The ipod would have been a bust.
Scott: It would have not gone anywhere.
Scott: Nobody would have bought one ever.
Scott: It would have been a flop, right?
Scott: But now when they make something like, you know the iphone.
Scott: Oh, well, you can only make apps that we approve, you know.
Scott: It's like uh, you realize if you made the iphone so that it could just run any app Android and palm and blackberry would basically all be at zero.
Scott: now as opposed to Slightly competing with you and ganging up on you and such it, you know, it's like oh, we're doing just fine.
Scott: We sold a bajillion abs, you know, it's like you would have sold, you know, and they think oh Well, if we would have made it open we wouldn't have sold that.
Scott: No, if you would have made it open you would have had 100 market dominance, you know.
Rym: I can sum this up really simply unless you have money to burn Never buy a technological gadget style product when it is clearly on a convergence course course with some other products in the same line because whenever there are two products converging The point at which they converge is where you want to be because that is where suddenly Like all this functionality opens up like web 2.0 When suddenly like the social stuff merged with the static pages merged with the hosted cloud stuff Suddenly all the crazy ideas were just like common sense and just all happened at once.
Scott: See, this is why the apple tv failed.
Scott: the apple tv right was limited in functionality It can only do.
Scott: it can only interact with the things you bought on itunes and such and such.
Scott: Well, because media centers whereas the boxy could do everything and that's why the boxy is the win.
Scott: it can play Youtubes you can visit hulu.com in it even though the hulu app is sort of gone, but you can you know?
Rym: Because dvrs and media centers and all those things were all converging toward one point.
Rym: and we're just about to be at the point Of perfect convergence, yep at which everyone will buy the perfect product at that time or maybe they'll be two competitors.
Scott: So apple needs to learn that lesson and they need to make the tablet be able to just read, you know Free ebooks from whatever they don't.
Rym: they don't need to do it at all because what they need to do now Is make their product.
Rym: that is on the convergence path, but not there.
Rym: yet.
Rym: All the people who don't realize this are going to buy it now and then they're going to add functionality Just as the convergence is happening to maintain their market share and people like us wait until the convergence.
Scott: Yeah, but you see this is where it's like.
Scott: yes that will work.
Scott: Yes, that will make them a lot of money.
Scott: But the thing is They could make a billion times more money If they just went.
Scott: if you just it's like oh, we don't need to score a goal now Let's just go to like center ice and hang out, you know, you know, all right, let's move it Let's go across the blue line and hang out.
Scott: It's like just score the goal now.
Scott: What are you waiting for?
Rym: It's more of a risk.
Rym: It's not as guaranteed because the convergence line, you know, it's an empty net.
Scott: It's not like the goal.
Scott: He's there.
Rym: You got to understand.
Rym: with a business all these lines are converging.
Rym: on a point If you take one of those lines and you think you know where they're all going to converge and you jump all the way out There early you might just have made another newton.
Rym: No and remember also apples changed a lot and the the apple of today is not the old wasniac kind of apple of.
Rym: Let's just go for it and make a newton They're not going to go for it and make the convergence point which has a risk and a high possible payoff When they can do the follow the convergence line and wait until other people force us to change And make guaranteed money all along that line.
Scott: They can make more guaranteed money.
Rym: if they listen to me guaranteed money now is worth more than slightly risky money Later to the vast majority of investors.
Rym: I disagree But that's why I invest in the companies I invest in.
Scott: Uh, if I was in charge, uh, you know, and I had some resources I would i'll admit I would not invest in apple.
Rym: if you were in charge in apple I would invest in competitors to apple.
Scott: Why?
Rym: so I don't know.
Rym: I I don't think the market would be kind to that sort of risk.
Rym: And right now I think it's too soon to jump to the convergence point because I think well, well, here's an example, right?
Scott: All right.
Scott: So right now, uh apple computer, right?
Scott: What's what's the actual market share of max?
Scott: It's like less than 10 percent.
Scott: It's you know, I mean you see a lot of them out there.
Rym: I'm talking about just the tablet thing.
Rym: What's the point of convergence?
Rym: It might be between tablet pc and Uh kindle nook kind of thing, but it might be a three-way convergence also with cell phone.
Rym: It might be a four-way convergence also with augmented reality and that's the wild card.
Rym: If augmented reality comes up faster than anyone expects then the conversion point gets pushed a lot further out and is a lot more important to society.
Rym: Hmm I mean if deno coil happens But not too long after the conversion point that apple would jump to if you were in charge Apple's fucked at that point because they've made a future newton and it's totally made obsolete 10 minutes later by deno coil.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean it's like if someone else is working on that already.
Scott: It doesn't matter what you make now because the the tablet they release now whether it's a whether it's good or double plus good If deno coil comes out tomorrow It's fail either way.
Scott: that has nothing to you know, that makes no difference.
Rym: I like how you say something like double plus good, especially thinking back to old apple advertising.
Scott: Yeah What do you think i'm doing here?
Scott: stuff?
Rym: Yeah, I got you.
Rym: I don't.
Rym: I don't know how many people would have caught that out there.
Scott: Don't don't give it away.
Scott: It just ruins it.
Rym: But the the real trick where you want to be is you've got to be the dark horse that forces the convergence line way out Which used to happen a lot more often from companies like apple and I don't know where it's going to come from right now.
Rym: It might be google It might be someone out of nowhere But i'm waiting for the dark horse to suddenly announce some crazy like altered virtual reality kind of technology That just throws everybody off their game.
Scott: I think the big problem is that just there aren't enough Product, you know quality product designers in the world.
Rym: There's a lot of people out there who can sort of get the right idea about something into a situation where there's not enough Talent in a lot of industries and it's surprising how hard it is to get skilled people Above a certain line in all levels of technology.
Scott: Yeah, there's just you know, so it's like apple has these designers and And nobody else, you know, even if they can you know, look at look at make the computer kde or gnome.
Rym: They are not uh, the best interfaces in the world.
Scott: Yeah, people just can't.
Scott: they just aren't people available to do this.
Scott: no matter how much money you're willing to spend.
Scott: It's like all these people already have jobs working at places like, you know, palm and apple and wherever And you just can't get a designer.
Scott: They just they don't do not exist.
Scott: There aren't enough of them, you know, and They're.
Scott: even if you have bajillion dollars They're not going to switch jobs or you know It will take so many bazillion dollars to hire them that you can't get anyone else.
Scott: And therefore even if you have all the right ideas, aha.
Scott: This is the exact specifications for a product that is going to win.
Scott: It just can't happen because you can't get the people that can make it exist.
Rym: well, what would be interesting.
Rym: imagine if this is getting way out there we should.
Scott: or also you can't even get the uh, The economy of scale at the factories.
Rym: imagine if what we did is at a much broader level forced through political reform To make education in america better to the point that it found anyone with the capability to succeed In you know, very specific and crazy areas and gave them everything they needed to succeed.
Rym: and you you greatly raised the bar.
Rym: Like right now we've got this like, you know less than one percent of you know, ultra geniuses in any given field.
Rym: Then you've got like the one percent of the really skilled people and then there's this sharp drop off after that.
Rym: What if 25 of it people were at my level and then instead of there being like 0.1 above what I do There was 0.0001?
Rym: because there's so much more pool talent at the like high-end pool That you've raised the bar on the low level.
Scott: all those talented people would be paid and appreciated a lot lot less Yes, but at the same time the total output would increase a lot.
Rym: You've raised the bar of society heavily Yes.
Scott: So the result of that the gdp would greatly increase due to the increased output and the people at the top would make a whole lot more money.
Scott: But because you know, no individual worker to be more skilled than the other workers They wouldn't be paid significant.
Rym: That is the problem of the more you increase the average skill the more you decrease the value of the work In the current basic economic system we have.
Rym: obviously you could try different systems, but uh everything we try fails.
Rym: Yeah, but if we could solve that well, you know if we could solve that the allocation of scarce resources We saw yes, it's turtles all the way down.
Rym: We know I think we're done.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat lee for web design and brand ok for the logos Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech mondays gaming tuesdays anime comic wednesdays and indiscriminate thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.