Rym: Hey, it's Tuesday, June 1st.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: We had a little trouble doing the opener just now, but tonight we're gonna talk about Zularetto.
Rym: It's like Russian roulette, but it's a board game with animals.
Scott: So many words in the opener.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So, playing my Street Fighter.
Rym: Getting slowly, but surely better, but not that great.
Rym: I haven't beaten the game on medium yet.
Scott: Yeah, oh really?
Rym: Yeah, I haven't tried too hard.
Rym: I've tried like four times.
Scott: I beat the game on hard disk.
Scott: Right yesterday, and you know what I learned from Daryl Surratt today?
Rym: What'd you learn from Daryl Surratt today?
Scott: My suspicion is correct, and that basically the computer cheats.
Scott: So, playing against the computer is not good if you want to get good against people.
Rym: Dude, I read some interview where one of the guys who developed or something said something along the lines of, "Yeah, we made that guy as annoying and cheap as
Rym: possible.".
Scott: Basically, right, the computer, the way it cheats is it looks at your inputs, right?
Scott: So, you know, think about a human being, right, probably isn't looking at your hands.
Scott: They gotta look at the screen.
Scott: Are you kidding?
Rym: If I'm looking at the screen and I hear on your stick next to you, "Kuh-kuh-kuh-kuh-kuh-kuh-kuh-kuh-kuh-kuh" or, "Hadokan, I know you're doing a
Rym: Hadokan!".
Scott: But think about it.
Scott: The amount of time it takes for the sound to get to your ears or whatever, versus the human reaction time is no good.
Scott: Now, think about the computer though.
Scott: I input a move, right?
Scott: And as soon as I input the move, move, right?
Scott: Me putting in the Hadouken can trigger on, right?
Scott: Cause it can do something as fast as I put it in.
Scott: So my, me doing a Hadouken can immediately trigger a counter to the Hadouken at the same exact moment.
Scott: The computer can do that, that a human cannot do.
Scott: And basically when you play the game on hardest difficulty, the game is Bay is pretty much really easy right through the whole game.
Scott: I just beat everybody beat win, win, win, win, win, win.
Rym: They're beating everybody.
Scott: But as soon as you get to Seth, basically they spent all their time programming him to be ultra cheap.
Scott: So basically what happens is it watches all of your moves and counters them immediately, right?
Scott: With whatever is available and it's next to impossible to actually win.
Scott: And basically I use no continues and I got the set and I use like a whole flood of continues.
Rym: And then eventually I want to be interesting if we could make a little app, right?
Rym: That would, it was USB.
Rym: So it controls like it's controlling our controller and a webcam pointed at the other guy playing and seeing if you could write some sort of AI or some sort of algorithm to do the same thing.
Scott: The thing is you couldn't react as immediately, right?
Rym: No, no, no.
Rym: You write a program that does the reaction.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, but I mean, you know, the same thing.
Scott: It's like if a guy does Hadouken, even if I have a camera and I see split screen, his joystick and his hands, right.
Scott: And somehow my brain can process and see what he's doing.
Scott: I can't input something at the same exact nanosecond that he is inputted it.
Scott: There is some delay between him doing it and me doing it.
Scott: Whereas the computer, there is no delay because the second you push the punch button on the Hadouken, it doesn't need time to input moves.
Scott: It doesn't need to think it just, Oh, it's as if you're actually focused.
Rym: dash forward right away.
Scott: It's as equally, if you think about it, you're actually controlling the other guy.
Scott: You just don't know how you're controlling him, right?
Scott: So it's like, Oh, if I do this input, it makes the other guy do this.
Scott: And if I do this input, it makes the other guy do that.
Scott: And you just don't know what the mappings are exactly.
Scott: You know?
Scott: Yeah, it's cheating.
Rym: What I wait for is no one has made a, like an aim bot for FPS is yet that just watches the game is only aim bots for FPS.
Scott: You know what you mean aim bot for fighting game.
Rym: I think we've invented a biological aim bot.
Rym: It's a 14 year old South Korean kid.
Scott: That's for RTS is.
Scott: I've seen some street fighter kids that I'm pretty sure from Korea probably, but you know, the point is, is that, you know, just the breadth of skills.
Rym: I mean, I'll play a guy who cannot deal with my simplified jury flow chart, which is foot Hadouken repeated until the other guy dies.
Rym: And then the next guy I fight, I will never touch him and I'll only use like jabs and kicks.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Makes me feel really, really the only thing wrong with the game.
Scott: It's a great game in that it has this huge, you know, skill cap is basically stupid high.
Scott: Even the people who kick your ass and you don't even hit them once.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The greatest guy in the world is Diego guy.
Scott: They can't even touch him.
Scott: He's got like three times as many Xbox points as anyone else.
Scott: And he's not even using his own account.
Scott: He's using like his friend's account because he doesn't have an expert.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, you know, the skill cap is huge.
Scott: The problem is, is that the curve is not high quality, right?
Scott: You know, like I just said, fighting against the computer, the curve is flat and then you get to the end, it spikes straight up.
Scott: It should be a linear curve.
Scott: It's each guy should get progressively more difficult.
Scott: And then I would actually be bothered by the fact that the computer cheats less.
Scott: if the skill was, you know, the difficulty of each guy was slightly harder than the previous one.
Rym: And no one's playing this game for the single player.
Rym: That's just there is kind of like a cool challenge.
Scott: But the thing is, even with the multiplayer, right, the skill curve is not so is really problematic because they don't, you know, they have these trials to sort of help you, but that's not really helping you.
Scott: And the instruction book does give some more information than it used to.
Scott: Like it tells you that a cancel exists, but they don't give you a real tutorial.
Scott: Right.
Scott: What explains, for example.
Scott: OK, so I jump in the air and I do like, you know, the like the double fist that Bison has.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And some other guy jumps in the air and he does a light kick.
Rym: You want to know which one wins, which one wins.
Rym: So, you know, there is a manual that tells you.
Rym: this is called Game Facts.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But does it matter who does it first?
Scott: Does it matter who's higher in the air?
Scott: Does it matter?
Scott: Right.
Scott: There's all these.
Scott: There's no X, you know, so how do if I'm jumping in the air, which button do I push is the best.
Scott: I'm pretty sure Game Facts knows it's such a, you know, and then there's so many possible combinations, though.
Scott: It's like, OK, so maybe my, you know, strong kick in the air beats that guy's whatever.
Scott: But everyone has six different pods.
Scott: And then some people have an air throw.
Scott: You know, it's like you need to tell me each and every possible move and how to make it to make it and how to defend each and every possible move.
Scott: Like there's some moves like, oh, I figured out how to defend that move.
Scott: You do this, but then some guy will do a move and it's like, I can't figure out any way.
Scott: You can't block it low.
Scott: You can't block it high.
Scott: You can't jab the guy while he's doing it.
Scott: You can't shield it with a focus attack game.
Scott: How do you beat that move?
Scott: Game facts, you know, I don't know.
Rym: Game facts.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But the point is, is it should be in the instruction manual.
Scott: Imagine if you bought a copy of some board game and the board game, I just did something and I got 100 points and you're like, what the hell am I supposed to do to stop you from doing that?
Scott: It'd be like, oh, I'm not telling you.
Scott: I just kept doing it.
Scott: And then you look at the instruction book and the second book doesn't even say the move exists.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then you go to game facts and maybe it says something about a game facts.
Rym: You're like, ha doe can.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You go to game facts and you read something.
Scott: You're like, hmm.
Scott: All right, let me try that.
Scott: You try to do in the game and I go like, nope, that's wrong.
Scott: It doesn't work like that.
Scott: You didn't clearly didn't understand what you read there cause it wasn't in plain English.
Scott: You go to some forum and some guy tries to explain it to you and then you watch a youtube video of some guy playing the board game, doing the thing and then another guy stopping doing the thing and you look at it real close and slow motion and then you come back to the board game and I do the thing and then you do the same exact thing you saw in the video.
Scott: I'm like, well, nope, no, I still get a zillion victory points.
Rym: It's see at least you got it wrong.
Rym: It is good that we are both bad at fighting games and RTS is not only even the guy.
Scott: All right, so think about this though, right?
Scott: Oh, we're bad at fighting games and RTS is right.
Scott: That Diego guy who has three times more xbox points than anybody.
Scott: You think he's going to beat us at like Puerto Rico?
Scott: No, it ain't gonna, it ain't gonna happen.
Rym: But I'm saying it's good that we play these games, we play these games and we're bad at them and we try to be good and we still fail.
Rym: That is the last vestige of gaming humility.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: What will we do if we're good at those games?
Rym: It'll never happen.
Rym: I mean, Conrad was watching me play and just sighing over the weekend.
Rym: I'm getting there though, but I have a little tiny quick news.
Rym: A lot of you probably know, but in case you don't, Dennis Hopper, very important, very famous actor and he is dead now, but the reason you might care is that you young kids might have not seen movie, a very important movie, movie called Mario brothers, super Mario brothers.
Scott: I saw it when I had the first, he is in the theater.
Scott: I got a story, right?
Scott: So it was my friend's birthday party.
Scott: And for the birthday party we were all going down to see this movie in the movie theater, but the projector broke saving saving us.
Scott: And we went to like, you know, the town baseball field and played baseball for like an hour.
Scott: But you know, I later saw the movie of course, but it was this weird fate that had, you know, I should have listened to the omen and not see, you know what?
Rym: You know, we're going to see Dungeons and dragons.
Rym: I was like, fuck you guys.
Scott: No, it's weird because in my memory, right?
Scott: It's like, I always remember like there was no way that I ever expected that to be good, right?
Scott: Never.
Scott: But I'm trying to think like, why did I actually go to see it to this day?
Scott: Like everyone was going to see it and I went with everyone to go see you all infected by some sort of ghost.
Rym: I don't know why, because at no point did I have an expectation of the quality being high because I remember you guys are all on aim and you're like, come on, we're going.
Rym: I'm like, no, seriously, no, I'm not coming.
Rym: No.
Rym: Why are you going?
Rym: And Pete came back and he was like, that was the worst movie I've ever seen.
Scott: I was like, what did you expect?
Scott: I didn't expect, I'd never expected it to be good.
Rym: I don't know why I went.
Scott: I definitely wouldn't go if it came out today.
Rym: Dennis Hopper played King Koopa and as bad as that movie was, it had two things that it got right.
Rym: One, it treated the Bob-omb with the proper amount of respect.
Scott: That was like the only thing in the movie that was Mario accurate.
Rym: And King Koopa played by an Ennis Hopper, pretty hilarious.
Scott: What in the movie was not hilarious?
Rym: Well, hilarious and good.
Rym: I think he was good.
Rym: He played the part as best it could have been played.
Scott: We asked you that yesterday before he was dead.
Rym: I still would have said, you know what?
Rym: King Koopa played that part really well.
Scott: I don't even know who this guy is.
Scott: What is he?
Scott: Is he famous or anything else?
Scott: I'm sure he's not just famous for being King Koopa because then he wouldn't be famous.
Rym: Easy Rider?
Scott: I don't know what that is.
Rym: You've never seen Easy Rider?
Scott: I'm moving the camera around by accident.
Scott: Good game.
Scott: It's attached to a chair.
Rym: Oh no, some Ustream got into the audio show.
Scott: Oh shit.
Rym: Good game.
Scott: Why do you help to the long right there?
Rym: So you got any actual news for me or anything?
Scott: It's sort of news, but I don't know how much news it is, but basically there's this thing called Super Mario Brothers X.
Rym: There's this thing called Super Mario Brothers.
Scott: Super Mario Brothers X, right?
Scott: And it's a game.
Scott: It's free.
Scott: You can go to this website, download it.
Scott: It's an exe.
Scott: It just runs, right?
Scott: And basically what it is is the ultimate Mario engine.
Scott: It contains, basically it's everything that's in Super Mario All-Stars.
Scott: So everything from Super Mario one, two, three, and world, basically the real Mario games, right?
Scott: It has every single power up, hammer suits, Nuki suit, kuribu shoe, everything, a whole bunch of you, Yoshi's new Yoshi's they invented.
Scott: It's crazy, right?
Scott: I bet, I bet this hammer Yoshi, I don't even know.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And you can play co-op mode with Mario and Luigi at the same time.
Rym: What does it do if you get too far apart?
Scott: It's split screens it, and then it will unsplit screen when you're close together.
Scott: Oh man.
Scott: And it's got like, you know, an editor, so you can basically make levels and a real time editor.
Scott: So you can edit while you're playing and you can create episodes in a Mario theme 3 or Mario world styled map, but you can also create a Mario 64 style map where there's a hub world that lets you collect stars from other worlds.
Scott: And basically you can just, you know, this is the thing to make.
Scott: the ultimate Mario game on.
Scott: And I think it comes with this three different worlds that you can get already is that there's the princess cliche, the great castle adventure and the invasion.
Scott: Great castle adventure.
Scott: Sounds like my kind of time.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Cause I'm a fan of the castles the most, the castles or the mansion, but I'm going to get this going on my windows run in HTVC, get a couple of X-Box controllers.
Scott: and who needs new Super Mario Brothers.
Scott: This is going to be way better than that.
Rym: Oh man.
Rym: I'm actually kind of excited about playing that.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean this is totally not legitimate in any way, shape or form is probably infringing on all sorts of copyrights and they put up a nice big message like we love Nintendo.
Scott: Don't Sue us, blah, blah, blah.
Scott: But I downloaded it already.
Scott: So what you going to do?
Rym: Yeah, it's free.
Scott: Take their website down.
Rym: Go ahead.
Rym: I got it on BitTorrent forever.
Scott: I got me a copy.
Scott: So that's the end of that.
Scott: I suggest you also grab one soon is going to be fun.
Scott: It's funny.
Scott: It's a Mario night because it turns out now for all of us, you know, we've done a lot of Mario stuff on the show cause I was working on the, I'll talk about that later.
Scott: There's a lot of Mario stuff, but there hasn't been a lot of Mario lately.
Scott: No, not lately.
Rym: We haven't been playing Mario games.
Rym: I've been playing Nintendo games.
Rym: I mean I'm playing street fighter on my X-Box and star crafts.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You actually played some star craft.
Rym: God, I, you know, I remember that I sucked at star craft.
Rym: Like I just wasn't good at it and I'd be slow and then all this shit just comes and kills me and I can never do anything.
Rym: So I'm playing in the, in the beta and I underestimated how fucking bad I am at that game.
Rym: Jesus Christ.
Scott: You just start, you just lose immediately.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I'm like, all right, I go, all right, I got to build a thing.
Rym: I got to harvest the two kinds of shit.
Rym: This I'm dead.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Ah, great.
Rym: So pretty much how it rolls, but for anyone who's old school, you know the answer to this already, but the video one is very well done, very short and two, it hearkens back to an earlier time.
Rym: Someone did a myth busters style kind of treatment of the old myth.
Rym: You know, when you're a kid, it's like 1988 and your friend down the street is like, Hey, stop moving the camera.
Rym: Scott.
Scott: I'm trying to figure out where it should be.
Rym: He's like, it's right where it should be.
Rym: It was fine until you moved it, bringing it into the show.
Rym: The kid down the street is like, Hey, I jumped over the flagpole and you're like, bullshit, bull fucking shit.
Rym: There's no way.
Rym: you jumped over that flagpole and maybe you fight with each other.
Rym: Maybe like one kid has a game genie.
Rym: He's like, here, let's use the game genie to jump over the flagpole.
Rym: And of course with the game genie, you can jump over the flagpole.
Rym: Not that hard, but there was always the legend.
Rym: Could you do it without the game genie?
Rym: And before there was a game genie, could you do it?
Rym: And what's back there?
Rym: You know, this was back in the day when NES games were mystical.
Rym: They were like magical places.
Rym: There was shit back there.
Scott: It wasn't even just NES games.
Scott: Pretty much every game was mystical, right?
Scott: They'd be like, Oh man, immortal combat too.
Scott: They've got all these alities that you don't even know.
Scott: You can see boobs.
Scott: You can see everything.
Scott: You just got to do it right.
Rym: You know, there are, I want to bring general Leo back to life.
Rym: Spoilers by the way, walk back and forth in front of his grave.
Rym: 99,999 times.
Rym: And did you do it?
Rym: I didn't, but, uh, I don't know.
Rym: I know people who did at least try.
Scott: It doesn't work, does it?
Rym: But the worst thing is some of those myths were totally legit.
Rym: Like the way to get the pink puff tail and then get the extra item from the adamant guy in a Silvertown.
Rym: in final fantasy four or Mac or Mac or Mac scared the ever living shit out of me.
Scott: The only reason I suspected at all that he really existed was because Nintendo power told me, yeah, you get, that's the thing is if there wasn't like a Nintendo power to told you everything, then how could you know?
Scott: And the thing was you always suspected.
Scott: aha, but what if they don't know everything?
Scott: Right?
Scott: Cause like in those days, the game developers weren't just giving their codes to some strategy guide, right?
Scott: Or, you know, they were, they were actually secret stuff.
Rym: And the tech to dump a ROM was not in the hands of the majority of people, let alone analyze around.
Rym: But imagine if you're playing right and you know, you're near the end of the game, you hit war mech and he just kills you and you tell your friends and none of them and all the experimenting they can do ever see a war Mac again and you never see a war Mac again.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And you didn't take a picture, but
Rym: uh, you know, those days are long gone, but this video really brought back a lot of nostalgia for me because they, they took one of those things and they did something that I would have loved for people who are done
Scott: your thing of the day.
Rym: It's my news.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: I just thought it was cool.
Scott: I was like, at what point are we at in the show here?
Scott: It seems like thing of the day material.
Rym: Cool Mario thing.
Rym: And you know, think about it.
Rym: This is an era of gaming that can never come back.
Rym: At least not any time in the near future where there'll be mysteries that aren't just solved by game facts or walkthroughs.
Scott: How was this news though?
Rym: Cause it was a new thing and it was cool.
Rym: What other gaming news is there?
Rym: Nothing.
Rym: Starcraft two is coming.
Rym: We already talked about the stuff we don't care about.
Scott: Yeah, it just doesn't seem like at least mine is, is pretends to be news cause like, Hey, this thing came out.
Scott: That's the news.
Rym: Mine is new.
Scott: Alright, whatever.
Rym: So anyway, things of the day, I guess I did two things of the day since my news wasn't news enough, but uh, you may not know who this is.
Rym: You don't pay attention to pop culture, but Keisha or Keisha or however you want to say it made a song.
Rym: You might recognize it.
Rym: And I inexplicably like the song.
Rym: I actually found out about it from the stupid Simpsons opener that was done to it.
Rym: And then I saw the music video for it and I liked the chorus, but the lyrics are like eighties bratty and I kind of hate that part.
Rym: But all that aside, for some reason, this song, well, no, for many reasons generated a lot of internet and musical hate.
Rym: So someone made a remix, a pretty awesome remix mashup, if you will, of the Tik TOK song mashed up with black eyed peas.
Rym: Shut up.
Rym: And it's pretty fucking fantastic.
Scott: All right.
Scott: I don't, I, you played a part of it.
Scott: I don't, I don't get it.
Rym: It's music.
Rym: It's good dancing music.
Rym: What's wrong with you?
Scott: It doesn't sound so great to me.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Well, what do you like?
Rym: What music you listening to right now?
Scott: Right now?
Rym: Like what?
Rym: Like old, how old, like Baroque, like late 18 hundreds.
Rym: That's what you're listening to right now.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Name a song like Dvorak and shit.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Can you name any song he wrote the new world symphony?
Rym: Can you name another one?
Scott: Anyway, Pandora just sort of takes care of it for me.
Scott: I don't really look.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So anyway, what do you got for me?
Scott: So my thing of the day, as far as appear to your thing of the day, I don't know.
Rym: This is pretty awesome.
Scott: Now you're thinking these shit.
Rym: Shut up, shut up, shut up.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: You want to shut up, but you can't handle this Russian hobbit illustration.
Rym: That's a hobbit.
Rym: That's the sob dent.
Scott: Check out how fucking bad ass the illustrated Russian hobbit is.
Scott: Look at that shit.
Rym: Oh my God.
Rym: Who illustrated it?
Scott: Some Russian dude.
Scott: Look at Bilbo's hairy fucking legs.
Scott: And Gandalf's like rye smile.
Scott: Like, Oh yeah.
Scott: Pimping Gand off the wizard.
Rym: You know what I want?
Rym: I'm telling you right now.
Rym: I want to make a poster of one of those pages.
Scott: arguing, arguing ogres, right?
Scott: Frigging, frigging, nasty dwarves, all greedy and shit.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Right.
Rym: I'm saying it straight up.
Rym: If I can, I'm going to blow those up, make a series of like a column hanging out in the series of frame posters based on that and put it on my wall.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Wait, wait, wait.
Scott: You got to check out the awesome spiders.
Rym: It's very reminiscent of the illustrations in the movie.
Scott: Look at those spiders.
Rym: You ever read like the Moomin Valley books?
Scott: No, not really.
Rym: You'd like him similar illustrations.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But you know what?
Scott: They got.
Scott: think y'all check out the sleeping smog.
Scott: Oh shit.
Scott: Watch out invisible hobbit.
Scott: Come and take your goal.
Rym: Oh no.
Scott: Smog got arrow.
Rym: Oh my God.
Rym: Look at his face.
Scott: He's like, Oh no.
Scott: Let's say you want to do some, you want to do some hobbit trivia.
Scott: Who is the name of the guy who arrowed small?
Rym: I read that book when you know what?
Rym: I haven't read the hobbit since my age was single digits.
Rym: Really?
Rym: His name, but he was the human from the town.
Rym: He had the black sheathed arrow.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: And he only had one, but it couldn't miss.
Rym: So only needed one.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I forgot his name.
Scott: I also forgot his name.
Scott: That's why it was a typical trivia question.
Scott: I'm looking at it.
Rym: I should have been like, yeah, that's a Joe bow.
Scott: The archery dude at the bar shot his black arrow into smogs left breast.
Rym: I got to read the hobbit again.
Scott: Armor's weak spot killing him.
Scott: Anyway, this actually is sort of a double thing of the day because this appears on a blog called English, Russia.com.
Scott: And you know what?
Rym: Wait a minute.
Rym: Is that just like the English.com of Russia?
Scott: No, it's basically just awesome shit from Russia.
Rym: I like stuff from Russia in a big way.
Rym: Like Russia has always been my go-to place for cool stuff.
Scott: The subtitle of the site is only in Russia.
Scott: It has everything from like graduating girls, uh, hanging out in the water to like stuff in the supermarket that has swastikas on it to the saltiest lake, to crazy Ukrainians at a soccer game to, uh, a truck full of alcohol that crashed.
Rym: Oh, wow.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Here's some college girls hanging out in the fountain.
Rym: I am a big fan of that.
Rym: Zobnit from Faulkner.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So there you go.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Meta moment, the meta moment.
Scott: So the book club is cosmos, which I'm reading right now.
Rym: We're going to finish it.
Scott: We're going to do it Thursday unless something weird comes up now, which, you know, if you're listening, maybe is already past that day.
Scott: Who knows?
Scott: Um, also I did a whole bunch of updating to the website from recruit.com.
Scott: Most of it, you will not notice yet because it was all stuff that is behind the scene.
Rym: It's basically setting up for awesome.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's going to be more awesome.
Scott: I'm going to keep working on it and doing a bunch of stuff.
Scott: Most of the stuff I'm going to do in the Fred first, it's both basically to make our jobs easier, you know, to make posting the show a lot less work.
Scott: But, uh, in the longer run, we're going to start changing other things.
Scott: If you notice errors on the site, if there's any broken links, if there's anything you would like to see changed, if there's anything we could do, that would actually make you want to visit the site.
Scott: Cause I know that almost nobody visits it.
Scott: Everyone just goes to the forum or just goes to iTunes and never comes to front recruit.com.
Scott: Uh, let me know.
Scott: I'm going to try to get figured out how to do some like collaborative show notes and all sorts of stuff to try to make you visit it.
Scott: So, uh, visit it.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: We're coming up in.
Rym: a lot of you've been joining the forums lately.
Scott: Going to try to add a video section eventually, you know, that kind of stuff.
Scott: It's, it's good times.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And of course, you know, conventions, Connecticut is coming up in about a month in Connecticut, Hartford, Connecticut, June or July, ninth, 10th and 11th.
Rym: So keep that up.
Rym: I'm not going to go into our list of panels or everything, but we're the heads of panels.
Rym: So all the panels kind of have our seal of approval.
Rym: Gee, well, as best as we could.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, we still, we need, you know, we needed a lot of panels to fill the schedule, which, you know, we had to accept.
Scott: panel, you know, pretty much all the panels.
Scott: Right.
Rym: And, uh, PAX West, New York anime festival, comic con combined MAGFest, all that stuff is coming up off on the horizon.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: And, uh, the only other thing we got to watch out Libsyn is being kind of a cock lately.
Rym: So, right.
Rym: So if you ever hear an advertisement on GeekNights, let us know immediately, even if it's just something at the beginning of the show, that's like, Hey, Libsyn, this is hosted on Libsyn because we're, we're, they're already on notice.
Rym: So if an ad so much as comes your way in any capacity, it wasn't fucking us and there, the shit will fly.
Scott: And if anyone advertise, if anyone knows like a legitimate alternative to Libsyn, right.
Scott: Let us know right away.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Basically what we need is we need something that is reliable, like guaranteed to host our stuff, you know, for reals and has basically infinity bandwidth and won't cost a fortune.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Because if it costs a fortune, Amazon S3 is not that much money.
Rym: We'll go to that instead.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: That would cost us like $200 a month.
Scott: Whereas Libsyn's like 30 something.
Scott: So we need, basically it has to be reasonable amount of money.
Scott: It's like we would pay $50 a month, but we would not pay 200.
Rym: You know, remember this kids we're trucking for you.
Rym: We'll, we'll, we'll move from 30 bucks a month to 200 a month just to not have ads in our show.
Scott: I'm not moving to 200.
Scott: You want to, you pay, well, we'll split it in the show for a hundred.
Scott: I mean, a hundred dollars a month is too much.
Rym: You're going to let ads be in the show.
Rym: Then what are you going to do?
Scott: I'm going to find some, what do you do?
Scott: What do you do?
Scott: I'll do.
Scott: So I'll find something.
Scott: She had the hostage, I guess, but I will, I will do everything I can to find some, I'm curious.
Rym: Cause I know Daryl Surratt would get that.
Rym: Do you get it?
Rym: Anytime I reference, what do you do?
Rym: What do you do?
Rym: Because the answer to that is shoot the hostage.
Rym: Do you, do you, do you have any idea what movie that's from?
Scott: Uh, I remember that there was a movie where you shoot the hostage, but I forget which movie it was.
Rym: I'm just curious.
Rym: I feel hard.
Scott: I've seen, I've seen, you've seen like part of it.
Rym: It's a Charlie Sheen movie.
Scott: It was some movie.
Scott: I remember they're like guys in an elevator when he's going to shoot the hostage or something like that.
Scott: And then they were in a parking lot.
Rym: Anyway, speaking of shooting, there's a board game that is basically a prettied up simulation of Russian roulette and we really like it.
Scott: It's not Russian roulette.
Rym: It's Zularetto.
Rym: It's basically like Russian zoulette.
Scott: No, it's not.
Scott: There's nothing.
Scott: It is.
Rym: So here's the game.
Rym: You've got like, you've got five people sitting around a table.
Rym: You've got five pistols with three chambers each and you put bullets or animals in them.
Scott: There's no bullets, nothing.
Scott: There's nothing bad that you can put in there.
Rym: I'll point out that if I've got, you know, monkeys and giraffes and like I've got my setup, I got no more free spots for animals and I don't need giraffes.
Rym: And you put three giraffes in that gun.
Rym: That is three bullets in that train.
Scott: I'm pretty sure you only lose points for type of animal in your barn, right?
Rym: So if I don't need a giraffe, it's per each type in your zoo or in the barn, I think.
Scott: So it's type in the barn, right?
Scott: It's not number of total in the barn.
Scott: So if you have three different guys in your barn, that sucks worse than having three giraffes in the barn.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Still a bullet.
Rym: I don't want to take it.
Scott: No, but the thing is, it might not be a bullet for anyone else.
Scott: So, you know, it's, it's far more selective bullets.
Scott: It's far more advanced.
Rym: Like in a lesson is learned, but the damage is irreversible with the love gun.
Scott: It's far more advanced than Russian roulette.
Scott: It's not even close.
Rym: Scott actually played this game before me.
Scott: You know, I've played it two times now.
Scott: I think you've only played it one time.
Scott: First time I played, I won.
Scott: I did really well.
Scott: The second time I played, I just saw so bad.
Scott: That was awful.
Rym: It was just awful.
Scott: Oh, it was absolutely awful.
Rym: But the thing is, you know, if you're looking for a board game to play, it won this field as you are.
Rym: So it's worth buying.
Rym: I mean, if not, if you, if you're looking for recommendations to buy board games, you can listen to us or just go to board game geek and play the top 20.
Scott: That's pretty much it.
Rym: It's like 18 of those games are great.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But basically the way Zulu better works is you got the zoo and you got to get animals in the zoo, right?
Scott: And there's three, there's three different patches.
Scott: They're all three different exhibits in your zoo.
Scott: And you can unlock the fourth exhibit, which you pretty much have to do to win.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Uh, and you want to fill each exhibit with one kind of animal.
Scott: You can't mix the animals.
Scott: You can't have the elephants and the drafts together.
Scott: That doesn't work.
Scott: You got to have, you know, so you want to get four kinds of animals and you don't want any other kinds, right?
Scott: Every other kind.
Scott: you get all your extra animals.
Scott: You have to tie them up in the barn and that's cost you money, but no one can visit the animals in the barn.
Scott: So you don't get any points for that.
Scott: You lose points for paying for animals to stay in the barn.
Scott: So you want to get rid of those guys.
Scott: So basically there's these trucks that deliver animals and every turn, everyone takes turns.
Scott: Every round, everyone takes turns, filling up the trucks with animals from the Savannah, I guess, or wherever, wherever the poachers collect them from next door, right?
Scott: Wherever the animals come from.
Scott: So they get piled on the trucks and the animals mixed freely on the truck.
Rym: Now this is the fun part because you got these, you know, five players, there's five trucks.
Rym: It's kind of like musical chairs of the animals.
Rym: At this point, every round you draw one of these tiles and you think, all right, what truck do I put it on?
Rym: So say there's a truck that has two monkeys and I know Scott wants monkeys.
Rym: I put a fucking bear on that truck and I don't want bears.
Scott: So basically Rym is saying, aha, Scott, if you want, you know, to take these two monkeys, you're going to have to also take this bear.
Scott: And it's like, ah, and basically what you do is you look at what everyone else wants and you look at what you got and you try to make trucks that are going to be good if you take them and bad if other people take them.
Scott: And, but the thing is on your turn, you can either put an animal on a truck or take a truck.
Scott: You can't do both.
Scott: So if you draw something that's really good for you, you have to put it on a truck and you have to wait for everyone else to take their turn before you have a chance of taking that truck.
Scott: And you know what?
Scott: Someone else might take that truck from you.
Scott: So if you make these really good trucks, someone else is just going to take them and leave you with a crappy truck.
Rym: And there are some things that can go into the trucks like a coin or a vending stand that are always good.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Just, oh, great.
Rym: They're just points.
Scott: So they're still not as good as animals that are, you're, you're kind of animal, nothing.
Scott: And then right on top of that, there's some animals, most animals are too young and genderless, but there are a few animals that have gone through puberty and can make a baby.
Scott: Now that that's where some of the, if you can get like a male giraffe and a female giraffe, you get a free giraffe when you get them together in the, in your zoo.
Rym: Now, this is, that is the aspect of the game.
Rym: I mean, you know, this is one of those board games that really brings out the German board gamer style, playing with the theme, making lewd jokes about smashing sheep into wood.
Rym: And it really, it really comes out strong in Yep.
Scott: Uh, lots of babby making jokes there.
Scott: The thing is, let's say you don't have room for the babby.
Scott: No, no, you get him.
Scott: He just goes in the bar.
Rym: And even if you've got a pen full of monkeys, you got one more monkey in the bar now.
Rym: Well, that's, that's points.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Negative points.
Scott: And then there's the money, right?
Scott: Which you can get from coins and from other things.
Scott: Like if you fill up an area of your zoo, you get coins and basically you can use the coins as a corrective measure, right?
Scott: So it's like, oh shit, I need to unlock the next area of my zoo.
Scott: So I'll pay coins or I need to move these animals.
Scott: I put them in the wrong section of the zoo.
Scott: Well, you can use coins.
Scott: Basically you can use coins to correct for mistakes that you have made or for things that you didn't really make a mistake, but you know, the odds and the way things turned out, it didn't go your way.
Scott: If you get enough coins, you can sort of fix it a little bit.
Scott: You know, you can use coins to get an animal out of someone else's barn, which helps them out, but it also helps you out because you get the animal you want and you know, it gives them a coin also.
Scott: So then they can correct for something that they messed up a little bit.
Scott: And the game ends when I think there's no more animals, right?
Rym: I think so.
Rym: I forget.
Scott: There's a stack of tiles on the table.
Scott: And when the bag of animals runs out, you start using the stack.
Scott: But then as soon as you start using the stack at the end of that round game over now, I really like that mechanic.
Rym: And you know, I wonder if we could make a slight variation to Tigris and Euphrates to use a mechanic like that.
Scott: Where we just take some tiles out, put them in a stack.
Scott: And then when the bags empty, start using the stack.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And then we have some sort of like end run condition.
Rym: Like everyone gets a turn.
Rym: Something we, I think we could come up with an interesting variation.
Scott: The game doesn't need fixing.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: It's a little worried about fixing other games that need fixing.
Rym: I mean, the only little bit of stagnant stuff.
Rym: I think we could mitigate just by making a slightly different board.
Scott: I definitely think the board.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: It's just interesting.
Rym: Cause you know, you wonder when a game that was 99% perfect was made.
Rym: And then years later, someone has another game that has a similar mechanic and they do one thing slightly differently and slightly better.
Rym: Like you wonder what effect that would have on the older game that maybe they just didn't think of it.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: There's not that much else to say about Zoolorado.
Rym: It's a fun light game.
Rym: It's not solved by us yet.
Rym: We only played it twice.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And you know, it's a whole lot of, uh, like you got the, cause a little bit of that chicken going on, like, you know, like that game where you pass the cards around with the tokens on them.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's exact.
Scott: You know, it's like a game of chicken.
Scott: It's like, all right, you, I'm going to stay in this.
Scott: I'm not going to take a truck.
Rym: I'm going to put another animal out there, which is also a lot like raw with the Egyptian slot machine.
Rym: You're like, I'm going to keep going.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, I'm going to keep going.
Scott: The difference is that in raw, there's one shared slot machine.
Scott: Whereas in this it's this separate ones, you know, there's one for each player.
Scott: So everyone's going to get one every turn.
Scott: It's just a matter of which one you get and which what's on it.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Now the cool thing is it was made by Michael.
Rym: And he also made another game called colorado, which is basically the same.
Scott: It's like the same game, but it's just a card game, right?
Scott: It's like a small portable version and I'm mistaken.
Rym: And I think there's an expansion aqua red.
Rym: Oh, I've never seen this in person, but dude, I've never seen or heard of that.
Rym: I don't know if it's out yet, but a couple of people have mentioned it when I was poking around.
Scott: Let's see, wait, this colorado and this colorado Amazonas.
Rym: Oh man.
Rym: There's also expansions for Zula red, like a petting zoo and some other stuff.
Scott: Really?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, I mean, I'll just feel this yard winning game.
Rym: So of course it's going to have expanded and all that.
Scott: There's three coworker tiles for aqua red.
Scott: Oh, there's all sorts of, so aqua red has a dolphin on the cover.
Scott: The Amazonas colorado has a, the toucan, the regular colorado colorado has a chameleon.
Rym: The main good thing about this game is that you can whip it out in like 20 minutes.
Scott: It's one of those ones.
Scott: It's really quick to learn.
Scott: It's easy to play.
Scott: Kids can play it.
Scott: Old people can play it.
Rym: It's a great game.
Scott: Like if you want to definitely, I think it's actually, you know, it, to be perfectly honest, right?
Scott: You always say, Oh, if you're introducing someone to German board game settlers, you know what?
Scott: I think Zula red is better than that.
Scott: You know, if you're, if someone has only played non good board games, first good board game.
Rym: Well, you know what?
Rym: It depends.
Scott: It's even more, it's, it's got the same sort of fun accessibility park zone, but it, I think it depends just as good who the person is.
Rym: I mean, someone like me before I'd seen the German board game settlers would be a better choice for a Rym type.
Rym: You know, someone who, you know, will get it.
Rym: If you just show them that the game is not random bullshit like monopoly, then settlers is fine.
Rym: Hell Puerto Rico is probably fine for someone like that.
Rym: But for someone who, you know, you're not sure Zula red Oh is probably going to get them.
Rym: Cause it's super fun, super short.
Rym: And if you want to play a German board game with a bunch of other German board gamers, but none of you have a game in common, a situation we run into a lot of nerd NYC where I just want to play a game.
Rym: I already know.
Rym: I just want to have fun, play a game, but no matter what game I pick, at least one person at the table has never played it.
Rym: So I'm going to have to teach for like an hour.
Rym: This game takes 20 minutes to teach 20 minutes to play.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: It's really quick to play Zula.
Scott: Red Oh is really easy to learn.
Scott: It's pretty just great all around.
Rym: Now one thing.
Rym: it's going to be on the way, as far as I can tell.
Scott: And it's already on the iPad.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: We'll see when I'll bet.
Rym: They're going to make an iPad version at some point soon.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's understandable.
Scott: I mean, it's, you know, how this kind of game could become really popular all around.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: I think that's about it.
Rym: Short show, but there's not that much to say.
Rym: It's a great game.
Scott: I would definitely, I'm thinking about getting one of the card versions.
Scott: Cause that's something you can carry around with you everywhere and play at any moment.
Scott: Right?
Scott: It's like dominion.
Scott: You could play at any moment, be to carry a big box of cards.
Scott: I'm just going to buy Zula.
Scott: I definitely need like.
Scott: a couple games are like the small individual, right?
Scott: The games I have that are just a pack of cards, you know, like safe or like a monitor.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Something like that.
Scott: They're more complicated, whatever.
Scott: You know, I really need a game like, you know, the Zula, Red Oh Colorado kind of game where it's just a small thing of cards, ultra portable, but you can whip it out and play it with anybody at any time.
Scott: Just strangers, fricking anybody.
Rym: Children, parking lot, old people.
Rym: And I think I'll buy Zilla, red Oh and acro letter.
Rym: though, because I need to own more games that I can bring to like an event that is gamey, but isn't like super Germany to just start introducing more people.
Scott: But it's still a party.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Cause I really, especially now I'm in the city.
Rym: I have a vested interest in just finding people and be like, look, these games are awesome.
Rym: Play them because it'll spread rapidly through social circles that I think can come right back to me and make more players for myself.
Rym: I'm going to try this out.
Rym: I want to see if I can personally expand the sphere of German gaming in like Manhattan in the next few years.
Scott: Go for it.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: It's worth a shot.
Rym: And I can bring it home and play it with like my mom.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: All right.
Rym: We'll just stop right there.
Rym: I think that's a good shot.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion, news, and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, gaming Tuesdays, anime comic Wednesdays, and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: It's Tuesday, June 1st.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: Are you yawning?
Rym: Let's try this again.
Rym: Hey, it's Tuesday, June 1st.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I was yawning again.
Scott: No, I just said I was yawning about the previous day.
Rym: Hey, it's Tuesday, June 1st.
Rym: I'm Rym.