Scott: It's Monday September 6th.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: And this is GeekNights.
Scott: Tonight we interview Mark O'Sullivan of Vanilla Forums.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Man, we're finally back from PAX.
Scott: No we're not.
Scott: Yeah we are.
Scott: We need to go to PAX.
Scott: Alright name for me one awesome thing that happened at PAX 2010.
Rym: The Friday night PAX Late Show was totally awesome.
Rym: What happened?
Rym: We had John St.
Rym: John as the guest.
Scott: Alright name one thing he said.
Rym: He said it's time to kick ass and chew bubblegum and I'm all out of gum.
Scott: Name one thing.
Scott: he said that you could not possibly predict that he would say.
Rym: You realize this is flawed because whatever I say I could go back in time and have him say it.
Scott: You mean go forward in time and have him say it.
Rym: So PAX was awesome.
Rym: We did our two panels and we did the Late Show.
Rym: and if any of you are new listeners.
Scott: You know you're chasing it because you know we're gonna fail to do them somehow.
Rym: And then these people are gonna be coming you know today after PAX to hear about it because they found out about us from the Late Show.
Scott: Yeah I know it's.
Scott: it's.
Scott: it's still August 30th.
Rym: No it's Monday September 6th anyway.
Rym: Labor Day.
Scott: The listeners know.
Rym: No they don't.
Scott: I don't need to continue to fight for them to know the truth.
Rym: The truth that you for some reason decided like in the fourth take of this to continue to insist that it's still before PAX.
Scott: It's not even necessary.
Scott: everybody knows it.
Rym: You know it'll be really funny if like that hurricane prevents us from flying to PAX.
Scott: I don't think it's gonna.
Rym: I don't think it will.
Rym: So it is Monday before we got to get into this interview.
Rym: pretty quick cuz I think it's gonna be pretty fun.
Rym: so what you got?
Scott: Oh we want to do some news.
Rym: Yeah it is Monday.
Rym: So the least done GeekNights' night in a while.
Scott: Yeah so you know AMD bought ATI a while ago.
Scott: That they did.
Scott: and now the news is out that not only did they buy ATI which they was done a long time ago but now they're actually gonna destroy the ATI brand.
Rym: That was expected.
Scott: So now you're gonna buy it.
Scott: it's still gonna.
Scott: they're still gonna keep around like Radeon and shit.
Scott: they're just gonna not call it ATI.
Scott: so it's gonna be an AMD Radeon video card.
Rym: I have nothing.
Rym: I mean I think it's a great plan from their perspective.
Rym: it'll just solidify the AMD brand.
Rym: why bother also marketing this ATI that no one's gonna remember.
Scott: I think it'll.
Scott: I think it'll really cut down on people buying AMD CPUs with Nvidia GPUs because it's like they really try to emphasize that fusion thing they have going on.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You know and then so you're gonna buy the AMD set as opposed like Intel and Nvidia which still kind of hate each other but they really should team up with each other for their own benefit.
Rym: It is also definitely kind of a sign that they're going to probably move more and more toward crazy integrations.
Rym: I mean I could really foresee them eventually selling like GPUs, CPU, motherboard, combo all in one.
Scott: That is one thing I never understood.
Scott: right is like okay you're putting these integrated GPUs into the CPU right why don't you just remove the PCI x16 slot from the motherboard in that same space just put the GPU right on the motherboard.
Scott: So here's the real one.
Rym: Here's because video card technology moves a lot faster than the rest and now you can upgrade.
Scott: It's true.
Scott: well you could upgrade if they also put the slot.
Scott: then you could deactivate the one on the motherboard and put a new one in the slot.
Rym: That's like we do now.
Scott: The thing is the vast majority of people don't want to upgrade.
Rym: It depends though the people who buy an AMD who know to buy a particular motherboard.
Scott: That's true that's true.
Rym: I mean normal people don't know.
Rym: they don't care.
Rym: they go buy a Dell.
Scott: Yeah but you know right does Dell?
Scott: even people like I have an AMD option nowadays.
Rym: Even people like us buy a Dell half the time now.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I mean I built my computer from scratch because I had some requirements and I could have gotten pretty much the same thing from like Dell or someone for pretty much the same money.
Scott: The problem is people always when they go to Dell or whoever they always look at the consumer models or they look at the gaming model.
Rym: Oh I wish I could buy the ones I've got at work at home.
Scott: Yeah you're supposed to look at the business models.
Scott: Any company that pre-builds computers the only good ones are the business models like Lenovo.
Scott: all the business class Thinkpads are awesome and everything else sucks.
Scott: Dell the Optiplex is the business ones.
Scott: those are pretty good.
Rym: I wouldn't say every other Lenovo sucks though they're actually pretty good.
Scott: We get the idea pad the cheap plastic piece of crap.
Rym: It's not that bad.
Scott: It's pretty bad.
Rym: Verge price point not that bad.
Scott: I would not buy one.
Rym: Name another laptop that competes with it at that price point.
Scott: What do you mean at the same price?
Rym: Yeah like at the same price can you get a better laptop elsewhere?
Scott: You can't get a good laptop for that price is the point.
Rym: So why not get the best one at that price?
Scott: Don't get any.
Rym: What if you don't have enough money but you need a laptop?
Rym: It's not that bad.
Scott: Don't get it.
Scott: It's gonna break and you're actually gonna end up spending more money in the long run than if you would have bought a good one in the first place.
Scott: They're not that unreliable.
Scott: Everyone I ever known who has bought the lower-end laptops has always had them cracking and breaking and all kinds of troubles and the only people I know who have laptops that are reliable are Apple people who spend too much money and people who buy the high quality.
Rym: I've actually found the people I know who have apples tend to have problems that require them to get it replaced by Apple fairly frequently.
Scott: Well those are people who are just you know they're gonna break whatever computer give them because they drop it or kick it or do stupid crap to it.
Rym: I remember I knew one person no no names.
Rym: who would leave an Apple MacBook kind of cracked open with the speakers on to play music in the shower.
Scott: Yeah that is a bad idea.
Rym: That one I don't think actually broke from that though.
Scott: Did it break?
Rym: Eventually.
Rym: I think it was an unrelated physical defect.
Scott: Okay good job.
Scott: Unless I hope that's a real cold shower because the humidity is gonna.
Guest: No no no no no.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: So I mean I guess we'll have to wait and see how this pans out.
Rym: There's no other news than yeah they're destroying the ATI brand and I didn't even see a lot of fanboy like craziness about it.
Scott: Well because I don't think fanboys really care about the name so much.
Rym: Now had they changed it from Radeon to something else.
Scott: They care about the benchmarks.
Rym: I think those fanboys might have got a little mad but I wouldn't be surprised if in the long run they dropped the Radeon brand and have some brand new brand.
Scott: Well you know they look they they already have.
Scott: they're just using the existing ones right.
Scott: The thing that is interesting is that are keeping the red color.
Scott: they're not changing it to green right which am because then it'll be green vs green AMD vs Nvidia.
Scott: No it'll be Christmas.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: So I've got an article here and it's interesting because say that I think people who are old in IT and computer science are discriminated against in the job force.
Rym: There's a million articles pointed out that.
Rym: yes in fact if you're over 40 you're not gonna get hired for IT or CS.
Rym: but if I decide the exact opposite that young people are being discriminated against there's the same number of articles saying that no one hires the inexperienced out of college people.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: I'm pretty sure that no one hires anyone at this point.
Scott: No Pete there is one kind of person that's hired.
Rym: 24 single no prospects of a relationship family or future willing to work 60 hours.
Scott: Well that that helps.
Scott: but I mean it's pretty much it's.
Scott: they don't vary.
Scott: only certain places you know and not enough of them will hire the completely inexperienced college person.
Scott: right but as soon as the person goes to one of those places if they manage to get there then they can get a real job at a place and then they can have real jobs for a certain period of time until they're old and their skills are washed out and then it's hard for them to get jobs if they lose it again.
Scott: but what you have to do in that time is like you know go out on your own or become a fancy consultant or become so awesome in some way that you're gonna be alright.
Scott: If you don't elevate.
Rym: If you're 40, 50 it's gonna be tough.
Rym: Even if you're awesome I'll be honest.
Rym: I don't think people hire older people because they know they can get more out of a younger person.
Scott: You have to elevate during the short time that you have to do something bigger like being a manager or something you know maybe a something it's got to be something besides the low-end guy.
Scott: you can't be the low-end guy after you're that old.
Scott: you got to be working out.
Rym: Well actually here's the thing.
Rym: it just at least in my experience and having worked you know for three big iron companies and never worked anywhere small ever.
Rym: this article I bring it up for the news partly because it talks about this kind of ageism problem where young and old people in technology I think are discriminated against often unfairly.
Rym: I mean very young people have tons of awesome knowledge like they know whatever is hip and current now usually at least if they went to a good school or they're really motivated but companies won't really hire them because they want.
Rym: you know they always say like I want five years of experience with this thing.
Rym: that's only existed for three years.
Rym: but that's the real problem.
Rym: there is that non tech people write the job listings.
Rym: so the real advice is ignore experience requirements and apply anyway.
Scott: yeah I don't you know.
Rym: I think that in fact don't lie but count college years as experience.
Scott: I think the thing is is that just.
Scott: yeah a lot of people are scared away.
Scott: they're like afraid to apply.
Scott: if you're looking for a job in technology or anything else right just look at if it sounds like a job that you want.
Scott: don't look at the requirements don't look at any of that bullshit.
Scott: right just if it sounds like a job and that's the job you want apply.
Scott: it doesn't cost anything to apply.
Scott: if it does don't apply no matter what.
Rym: oh I would argue if you have if you live in some barbaric place like Australia where you have to pay for your bandwidth in a metered way it costs to send that email a very negligible.
Scott: the point is it doesn't cost anything to apply.
Scott: so even if you don't meet the requirements at all like you're not even close apply anyway.
Scott: what's the worst?
Scott: they can do not email you back.
Scott: oh no they didn't email me back at the end of the world.
Scott: listen just email it doesn't hurt do it.
Scott: and then something you know.
Scott: maybe they're probably I imagine if they have stupid requirements they're not getting that many emails.
Scott: so the competition will be light.
Scott: if nil and they might call you back they might why not you know and they're pretty much it pretty.
Scott: it comes down to whether are you desperate for a job any job then freaking shotgun you know boom blast your resume all over the place so you get a job.
Rym: spam it though.
Scott: no no no just you know.
Rym: you know those people who actually spam.
Rym: you gotta do that.
Scott: it's a shotgun you can't just go.
Scott: doom doom doom doom doom.
Scott: you got to get one shot and hit the clay pigeon.
Rym: yeah but don't email like the operations number of a company and say I have an h1b and I know Java.
Rym: please hire me to do your Java project.
Rym: how many emails those I get every single day?
Rym: they're almost always the same email just with a different name.
Scott: but if you are you know.
Scott: if you can if you got money and you you don't need a job right away and you're good job and you're willing to stay at home and do nothing until you find the good job then you can get your sniper rifle out right and just go
Rym: metaphorical sniper rifle.
Rym: don't go shoot anyone no.
Rym: but here's why I want to link to this article and I think it's worth.
Rym: I think a show on ageism might be worth doing later but this article.
Rym: every time you see an article that talks about like how to fight ageism and how to like how to get a job in tech if you're over 40 or nowadays over 30 they always say you know be really current in your skills and be able to demonstrate it and that's BS.
Rym: this article says what I would say if you want to still be relevant when you're getting into your 40s and 50s and you're an IT or a CS guy I'm just gonna quote the quote from slashdot.
Rym: one move up the ladder into management architecture or design.
Rym: do not stay at just coding or IT because there's basically no future in those.
Rym: no matter how old you are - if you're going to stay in programming realize that the is stacked against you and deal with that.
Rym: three actually keep your skills current actually current.
Rym: know what people are actually doing.
Rym: I mean if you're if you want to get a job now in like web or something and you can't do pretty much any common framework.
Rym: just off the drop of a hat you're already screwed.
Scott: yeah unless you want to get one of those like enterprise Tomcat Java I mean yeah it also depends on what you want to like.
Scott: if I want to work in finance I had to go learn a bunch of crap I don't know like Java's or dot nets or something you know.
Scott: it's like you got to aim for the industry where your skill set is gonna work out.
Rym: yep but I think the most important advice is really you've got to move up and to the side into management architecture or into sales into product management into consulting into project management.
Scott: you said project management two times.
Scott: yes you can also.
Scott: another good idea is if you learn an additional skill like you keep all your technology skills way current and awesome.
Scott: but you also have some other skill.
Rym: that's like finance or medicine or biology because holy crap you realize like bioinformatics or anything like.
Scott: that is the hot shit right now or even like even something stupid like sports or fucking.
Scott: you know liquor store managing or you know anything.
Scott: you can combine the technology skills with your skills and the thing is most people have the other skill set.
Scott: don't know anything about technology so you can make a product or you know find an existing business and really help it out or who knows what you can do.
Rym: but most people who know tech only know tech professionally.
Rym: or if they know something else they don't think that
Scott: or they're in tech but they don't really know - yeah
Rym: but one of the most important like things on a resume is if you know like someone who knows IT and something else you will basically have perfect job insurance forever.
Rym: law laws a good one yeah plus imagine a world where the lawyers were also able to do their own IT.
Rym: that and the doctor understood why Firefox was better than IE.
Scott: that's yeah that's okay but I think the real thing we need is we need the judges and that's gonna be much more different.
Rym: so moving right along to get into everything it's time for the things of the day.
Scott: oh no thing of the day.
Rym: I got sick of saying things of the day.
Rym: I wanted to mix it up all right whatever.
Scott: so you know the one of the most famous supercomputers to ever exist was the cray.
Scott: and you know people back in the day used to be like oh my god cray cray dad cray fish.
Scott: no just cray the cray supercomputer cray.
Scott: why are you being stupid anyway?
Scott: so the thing with the cray is that it was sort of I don't know it was real famous and it was real impressive looking like it's if you've ever if you've never seen one.
Scott: it's like a big cylinder right with a hole in the middle and then it actually has like a bench around it.
Scott: you know it's like.
Scott: you know the idea was that you would have it there and they could the programmers and sort of sit next to it thinking and then they would go over to the terminal and coat.
Scott: you know and this is like an ancient relic of computing but it was very important you know to the world and specifically to the u.s.
Scott: where you know the government bought a whole bunch of them back in the day.
Scott: your computer now though is way faster than a crazy for computer at least the first cray.
Scott: but anyway the thing is some guy.
Scott: he made a model of cray one the very first cray supercomputer and it's not a full size model it's much smaller than the original but it is very very accurate to the original.
Scott: so it's like a little tiny cray.
Scott: could you know sit in a room?
Scott: but he went one step beyond that.
Scott: you know what step beyond that.
Scott: he went to what he do.
Scott: he took an FPGA and he made it binary compatible with the cray one.
Scott: so if anyone doesn't know an FPGA is right basically what it is it's it's a it's a chip right and you it's a chip that you can reprogram.
Scott: so you can.
Scott: let's say I have it's it's a. I think it's like a something programmable gate array right fully programmable gate array something like that.
Scott: but the way it works is let's say I have like a penny of one right.
Scott: well I can do is I can just I can make if I have a penny of one it's a penny of one.
Scott: that's all it is.
Scott: you can never change field programmable gate array field programmable gate array got to him.
Scott: I was so close anyway.
Scott: but if you have an FPGA right you can change it into different chips like.
Scott: I could turn the FPGA.
Scott: it's like an and gate a big ol.
Scott: and Kate I could turn it into a penny in one if it's big enough.
Scott: you know I could turn it into a penny in two if it's big enough.
Scott: I could turn it into a honey in three if it's big and I can turn it into like a power PC.
Scott: or or I could turn.
Scott: I could turn it into the same chip that your cell phone has in it.
Scott: you know I could turn it into any chip I needed to turn into.
Scott: I just have to program it to to be that.
Scott: now why don't we use FPGAs and computers?
Rym: well they're not as efficient.
Scott: yeah they're not as it's not as fast as you know the the chip you have in your computer.
Scott: so having an actual Pentium 2 is a lot better than having a FPGA program to be a Pentium 2. also you know it's hard to get an FPGA has to have enough stuff in it and or you know if it's not big enough or it doesn't have enough.
Scott: you know things in it.
Scott: if there might not be possible for it to you know turn into certain chip plus.
Rym: imagine the malware you could write if you were able to hack someone's computer that ran on these things.
Scott: oh god yeah you could just switch someone's chip into doing something else.
Scott: good god yeah you don't want to you.
Scott: mostly these are used for developing and stuff like that.
Scott: you know so.
Scott: but this guy he took one and how is he gonna get a crate the hardware for a Cray one right there was no way he could do it.
Scott: that'd be so difficult.
Scott: so but we could do is he could get the documentation for a Cray one to see how it works and then you could take an FPGA and program it to be exactly the same as the Cray one you know and you could do this for any sort of chip.
Scott: that's like missing in the world like you could make an NES out of one or you know whatever you need.
Scott: so that's what he did and he put it inside the model of a Cray one.
Scott: and it's all and there's a whole bunch of pictures and everything and it's way awesome.
Rym: so you all know at PAX this past weekend we did the late show I mean PAX this next weekend and we had you know theoretically some sort of set but it was a very ghetto set compared to the kind of sets you see I'm like why we get.
Scott: we get there and it's an all fancy set.
Scott: what are you gonna be so wrong?
Rym: because I know I was there last weekend.
Scott: so this is a video a short video.
Rym: I'm sorry it's on Hulu but this is the best place to get a video like that where it won't get knocked off the internet by copyright.
Rym: this shows just what it's like for them to change the set on the commercial break on a live show.
Rym: it's pretty hectic.
Rym: and now as Scott pointed out when we watch it together we I understand why.
Rym: every time SNL starts up again the crowd is cheering
Scott: yeah cuz like the
Rym: guy's standing he's like come on 30 seconds just get the desk just get the desk and there's
Scott: like three two and then
Rym: they're good to go like
Scott: they got the desk and there's like ten seconds.
Scott: so the guy like tosses a chair under this day yep.
Rym: and then the guy the actors like fiddlers wig wig wig wig and then he starts the skit like right away.
Scott: yep damn the thing.
Scott: I don't understand though.
Scott: why don't they just have the rotating Les Miserables stage?
Scott: it would be so much.
Scott: that's really expensive but I mean they've been doing the show for how many years?
Scott: how much money do they make?
Scott: I mean come on they could have the rotating stage where that has like three sets and they can set up the set.
Rym: and I went to a thing where I got to like walk on one of those sets and like talk to the actors and everything when I was in high school.
Rym: it is hard as fuck to walk straight on that Les Mis set.
Scott: yeah but this that's because in Les Mis they're what that they don't?
Scott: you're walking on the thing while it rotates.
Scott: for this it would be just three positions that were static and you wouldn't be on it while it was rotating.
Rym: you know Les Mis they have those scenes.
Rym: they're like everyone's walking next to each other while the prisoners and the chain gang look down.
Scott: yeah so for the first time in a long time we are actually doing something we said we would do but did not do and that is have interviews and more guests on the show.
Scott: so today we have with us someone that you probably don't know but it's very important to at least listeners of this show.
Scott: you definitely know his work.
Scott: you know his work that we have with us Mark O'Sullivan the creator of the vanilla forum which is the forum that we use the show.
Guest: thank you.
Scott: so maybe we should start out.
Scott: you know just some basic questions about.
Scott: you know vanilla.
Scott: so to get people on the ball here.
Scott: so vanilla is obviously an internet discussion.
Scott: you know web forum software.
Scott: right but obviously obviously why did you you know what was the original impetus to to make it sure?
Guest: well so at the time that I that I started vanilla I was doing.
Guest: I had I had my own discussion forum that I was running for graphic designers and programmers.
Guest: it was called oh wait as in the number or the letter O and the number eight it came out of another form called dreamless org.
Guest: sorry it's like a whole history of forms thing that happened in many many years ago and so my form oh it was.
Guest: it was a sort of a catch-all discussion forum for people to get together and talk about whatever the hell they wanted and it typically was graphic designers and programmers and we found in all the software that was out there didn't really suit our purposes.
Guest: we wanted to do a you know have special features for the forums and they were all kind of one-size-fits-all and so we started to custom program things here and there and eventually we got the idea to make a whole plug-in framework around it and and we were able to take something that was really complex and make it very vanilla and and then you know introduce cool functionality through plugins and theming and and run run that community for a really long time and then eventually all these designers and programmers really wanted to use the software.
Guest: so they asked if I could open source this this custom form that I'd written and that's when I released vanilla in 2005.
Rym: so it was definitely the functionality driven as opposed to aesthetics driven.
Guest: it was a little of both.
Guest: like I said there were designers in the forum and we took a sort of a very simple approach again another vanilla approach to the layout.
Guest: we removed all that bloody stuff that you see in many other discussion forums and and and kept it very simple and and because of that it made adding new design kind of easy.
Guest: so I mean you can look at it a ton of vanilla one installations and they might look exactly like the default install but they might look like something you've never seen before.
Guest: so we you know we've seen it go from being a simple forum to being a project management tool to being a blog to being an issue tracker.
Guest: at one point it was the reviewing tool for add-ons for Firefox.
Scott: oh wow really I didn't know so.
Guest: so yeah it's.
Guest: I mean we like to say that you may not have heard of us but you probably use our software.
Scott: hmm so so now vanilla 2 is has come out.
Scott: so what is the you know big difference between vanilla 2 and vanilla 1?
Guest: so we realized that there was still a lot of ground to be broken in in the forum space.
Guest: and what community discussion space.
Guest: and looking around at all these amazing social networks that were popping up everywhere we thought you know everybody should be able to build one of these and and so with vanilla 2 we sort of went at it that way.
Guest: we also realized though that okay first of all there were a lot of improvements that could be made to the plugin framework and theming engine.
Guest: so we sort of basically rewrote the whole thing from the ground up and and you can do a lot more with that now.
Guest: but more importantly we realized that a lot of forum solutions try to be you know the full solution for your site.
Guest: so instead of adding a forum to your site they want you to the form to be your site and and we thought it was much more interesting to look at all the platforms that people are using out there like Drupal and WordPress and you know name your CMS.
Guest: and wouldn't it be really cool if it was just very very simple to add vanilla to that?
Guest: and so once your users sign into your existing site they're automatically signed into vanilla.
Guest: all the look and feel sort of transfers across and so that's sort of where we've gone with it and beyond that we're looking at making activity cultivation our number one goal.
Guest: so we want to make sure that if you're running your forum on our software your users will be more engaged and you will get more organic search traffic.
Rym: so did you put any thought when you were designing it into the sort of you know not to throw on game theory terms but the mechanism design like you know like BB and all these different kinds of software they show like post counts and things and they tend to engender a certain kind of behavior.
Rym: did you wonder about how your design would cause certain behaviors in the users or is that just completely off the table?
Guest: no that's absolutely one of the things we played with.
Guest: even with vanilla one.
Guest: we wanted to get rid of all the stuff that people were used to and and try to make them think that you know when they look at vanilla do they even know it's a forum because they have this archetypal idea of what it is and and what it means to see those things on the screen?
Guest: like we looked at most other forms we were like half that information you don't need and it doesn't add value in any way and so let's just get rid of it.
Guest: and and then and then beyond that you know let's let's look at each community on a on a one-off basis and and let's see what works for that particular community.
Guest: you know like post counts and signatures might make sense on one might totally not make sense on another.
Scott: I can tell you that's pretty much the.
Scott: the reason that I picked vanilla from the beginning was that it didn't have you know each.
Scott: the posts were not gigantic with avatars that you know the size of.
Scott: I need my 600 pixel animated avatar.
Scott: everyone didn't have a huge animated banner ad signature that showed up over and over again every time they posted a comment.
Guest: yeah absolutely and actually you know we we we do like.
Guest: no no with vanilla - we also have vanilla forums.
Guest: that we're sorry vanilla forms dot org is where we have the download product.
Guest: we also.
Guest: we also know vanilla forums calm which is it's sort of a wordpress model where you know you can go to calm and set up a forum online and then you can chart where we charge you for extra features.
Guest: and so we have a lot of forums on running on there and we're working very closely with a lot of the bigger ones at you know getting that activity cultivation happening and we found that for some of them those giant signatures and and all those little things that you used to do make sense but you know they can still be improved upon.
Guest: so for example one of the plugins that we've made recently is a signatures plug-in but it has a bunch of different settings so you looking at the forum can decide do you want to see any of signatures of your friends or no?
Guest: and if you do do you want to allow HTML in them or not?
Guest: and so you you know simple signatures could be broken down to something that's as simple as the plain text to something that has a giant animated manga character - no signatures at all it's up to you.
Scott: so you know as far as like a user of the forum is concerned right because I mean most people out there using vanilla are just you know they're commenting they're not running their own right.
Scott: so it's right for the people who are who are using our forum what what in vanilla 2 is there to to excite them you know in terms of new features.
Guest: so again we've looked at a lot of what's going on in community and social network space and we've grabbed a lot of these features that we think are just awesome for example at mentioning somebody.
Guest: if you at mention somebody in a comment in vanilla that person will get notified not only in the activity stream but by email.
Guest: if it's in their preferences.
Guest: you can hashtag searches so you can hash a word and then that becomes a tag for for a discussion and those can be clicked on to run a search and see everything like we.
Guest: just we want to streamline the process of it.
Guest: what users are getting used to seeing on other sites is very much there in vanilla.
Guest: so and that that's not even touching on all the things that you can do with with all the plugins that we have available.
Guest: I mean vanilla 2 has only been out for four weeks and even at the time of launch there were already 40 plugins written for it.
Guest: so the community is really getting ramped up and and for me the most exciting thing is just seeing a the plugins that get made for the software because half the time people come up with stuff that we had no idea about and and it's really fascinating.
Guest: but the second was seeing how the users end up using it.
Guest: I'm excited to see what everybody thinks about it and and actually on our own forum vanilla forms dot org our open source community forum.
Guest: we're always throwing out plugins that people have made whether it's us or people in the community and testing them out and and seeing how people react to them and and and seeing how how that drives usage.
Guest: and specifically related to that we even got a plug-in that we've been working on in-house that we've got on some forms on our hosted vanilla forums com site.
Guest: that is specifically about tracking those statistics and finding out you know who are the most active users and are they actually adding value or are they just putting a lot of content out there?
Guest: and and and you know what are the most popular discussions during particular time ranges?
Guest: and I don't know.
Guest: it's a lot of fun and really interesting to look at your community in that way.
Scott: no all right.
Scott: so I know you sent out a little press release today that mentioned something about like a vanilla forums partner reseller program.
Scott: can you tell me?
Scott: yes
Guest: yeah so like I said we've got the dot com hosting service right now and and you know we're one of the things that we've realized is that first of all growing starting a community is very very difficult and second of all if even if you have an existing community getting it over and moved across and gaining traction is still very difficult.
Guest: but when we removed the boundaries that our users had of you know getting the software downloading it getting it on a server understanding how all those things work you know if you're technical enough to make it through that then you can think about starting your forum.
Guest: and with dot com we wanted to get rid of that whole process.
Guest: so you just go and you fill out a you know a little form.
Guest: you can create a form really quickly and then what we realize is that what happens is a lot of people come they'll sign up to create a form to look around and they'll be.
Guest: you know they won't have invested any time so they'll be much more ready ready to abandon it.
Guest: and so we started talking to our existing users who are using the software and we found that a lot of them were you know graphic designers programmers contractors or even straight-up design firms and they you know they have customers that need this stuff and and and they were they want to resell it you know we they want to even be able to white label our software and and then go to their clients that yes we now offer this forum service.
Guest: so this is the first step towards that and you know enabling those people that are already engaged and want to start building on this on the platform to you know have an incentive to do so but also you know make it an easy process for them.
Guest: so basically it's a simple referral program and and if you get if you say no somebody who's running a discussion forum and you bring them onto our platform you get 20% of the revenue that we get for the entire time that that customer is with us.
Scott: no that's pretty cool.
Scott: so you.
Scott: so if I give I get someone and they stick with vanilla for like forever.
Scott: you know cuz then we've been using it for how many years?
Rym: Oh God it's almost the beginning like four or five right?
Scott: so if they just keep paying I just keep getting money.
Scott: you know that 20 absolutely absolutely yeah.
Guest: I mean we're also the mindset that you know if you're whether you're it's you guys just doing something for fun or if it's you're actually a design firm and and you need a forum solution you know why shouldn't you make money off of that?
Guest: yeah and you you're using the software you're building with it.
Guest: you should be making money.
Scott: so so on some you know slightly less related things.
Scott: so vanilla I notice it's made with PHP right yep yep so the you know I'm a programmer.
Scott: I work with Python for a living.
Scott: I used to do PHP stuff.
Scott: I'm not one of those you know sort of zealot people who will say oh this is good and this is bad and you shouldn't lose you know.
Scott: but obviously there are many people who are PHP haters out there.
Scott: you know yeah and it's it's pretty much you know the the whipping boy of web development at least if you read.
Scott: you know the various tech enthusiasts sites.
Scott: so you know given that what made you you know decide to stick with PHP or pick it in the first place?
Guest: so the dirty little secret of vanilla is that the first version of vanilla was written in dotnet.
Guest: oh so C sharp okay and that was the first version that I tried to open source.
Guest: and this was basically what was going on.
Guest: is the first version that was written not for release was all done with VB script.
Guest: and believe it or not the very first version of it which is probably written around 2001 had a Microsoft Access database.
Guest: so like this is going back a really really long time and for people who know what ASP is.
Guest: but I got hired by Microsoft to do dotnet support when they released dotnet to the world and so I had sort of a little edge on what was going on with dotnet before it even was released and I was using it to do some test development for the support tasks that I was going to be doing at Microsoft and I decided that I was.
Guest: I loved it.
Guest: I loved C sharp.
Guest: it was you know very similar to Java.
Guest: it was a lot of fun to write with and let's face it if you ever use Visual Studio it's the best ID in the planet.
Guest: I don't care what anybody says.
Guest: yeah they're their IntelliSense.
Rym: as an IT guy I don't write a lot of software but I'd write a soap service.
Rym: recently and after banging my head against all the broken Python modules dotnet I basically said right click make soap service done.
Scott: yeah yeah Visual Studios.
Scott: you know I'm a vim UNIX kind of guy but you know I've used Visual Studio to do XNA stuff and I definitely you know I'm not down on it.
Guest: yeah it's it's amazing.
Guest: so so I just really wanted an excuse to keep on working with Visual Studio and so I did the first version in C sharp and of course when it came time to release it nobody wanted it because at the time not only was there not a lot of dotnet servers out there nobody knew how to use it nobody knew what it was.
Guest: and I you know I I don't even know if I tried to release now what to get the pickup that it needs.
Guest: because let's face it you know you think open source you don't think dotnet.
Scott: I mean even if the even if you give out something like that open source let's say WordPress you know was written for dotnet and was open source you know to be able to run it you guess you could use mono and it's it's.
Scott: that's a huge pain right you would have to.
Scott: you have to use what like Microsoft SQL Server and IIS but those aren't really free you know.
Scott: so yeah even though this one part is free the rest of it isn't free.
Scott: but if you do any of the other you know an open source language Python Ruby you know Perl PHP whatever you know the whole lamp stack is.
Scott: the whole thing is free.
Guest: yeah absolutely and I mean so when it when I realized that that wasn't gonna fly and I had to sort of abandon it it wasn't the saddest part of my life.
Guest: I I've never really.
Guest: I didn't set out to make vanilla and open source project.
Guest: that made me money back.
Guest: when I did it in 2005 I was just doing it because I was I'm a big freaking geek and I like to program and I wanted to program in any language and use any database and try any technology I could get my hands on.
Guest: and so you know when I found out that that wasn't gonna work and people didn't like it they wanted the functionality they didn't want the language.
Guest: so I I just looked around at what was available and I realized that lamp works like PHP and MySQL can run on anything and so that was the deciding factor.
Guest: so vanilla one was the first thing I ever wrote in PHP.
Guest: oh well actually if you look at if you look at the code that it kind of makes sense that you know there's a lot of classes which at the time with PHP for didn't didn't really make sense because it didn't scale.
Guest: and that was one of the problems with vanilla one is that as soon as it hit a large capacity of users it really didn't scale.
Scott: well yeah I had that.
Scott: I had that problem also.
Scott: it was like our forum got slow and slow.
Scott: but then eventually what I did is I just went into MySQL and I like indexed a whole bunch of you know the the columns and then you know as soon as I did that it was.
Scott: it was alright yeah.
Guest: and even then like we've had some very very big forums use use vanilla one and and you know we did a lot of hacks to make it work well.
Guest: and when we decided we were gonna do vanilla two and we were gonna rewrite it all from the ground up and we were gonna go PHP 5 we knew that.
Guest: you know this time it'll be fast and just by the fact that it's PHP 5 only it's faster.
Guest: but we've also done tons of optimizations from the lessons that we learned with vanilla one.
Scott: so what are?
Scott: so?
Scott: what are some of the like the biggest vanilla forums out there?
Guest: well the biggest one obviously that we've ever seen out there in the wilds was the the Firefox add-on site.
Guest: I mean that's millions and millions and millions of people using that forum and the sad part about it is that they customized it so much that you couldn't even tell it was vanilla.
Guest: so we really didn't get any credit at all which is fine.
Guest: you know that's open source too but we've also been talking to some bigger companies with millions of users that want to want to use it now and and we're working on modules for vanilla two that you know some memcache modules and other kinds of caching mechanism pretty useful.
Guest: I could use that yeah and and for our own purposes with our hosting services you know we've had to do a bunch of changes to the code you know to allow things like multi server database selects and all this kind of stuff.
Guest: so so scaling is a big thing for us for sure.
Guest: I'd love to mention one of the ones we're working with right now but it's not locked in deal so I can't do it right.
Scott: so when you when you move to PHP and gave up Visual Studio what are you like using Eclipse?
Scott: or what do you?
Scott: what did you move to?
Guest: yeah that was a long long arduous road of what the hell ID should I use in the beginning?
Guest: yeah I did a lot of notepad.
Guest: I'm not not really a vim guy one actually my favorite.
Guest: if you're going con like straight up command-line stuff whenever I SSH to a server the first thing I load up is midnight commander.
Guest: oh yes if you guys know what midnight commander is a sort of Unix and that has a really nice editor in it.
Guest: if I'm doing live edits on the server that's what I'm using.
Guest: but if I'm doing straight-up development typically I'm running Komodo and but it's weird.
Scott: like in my office everybody runs something different nobody runs the same ID it's the same in my office like one guy uses Xcode one guy uses textmate I got vim.
Scott: it's it's a. no one wants to do the same thing as anyone else.
Guest: yeah we got one guy using net beans another guy using what's the company that does transmit Toda?
Guest: oh yeah which blows me away because there's no auto completion or anything.
Guest: I don't know.
Guest: well I think there is for classes but there's not for PHP in classes anyway I couldn't do it myself all right.
Scott: so let's let's get away from from vanilla here.
Rym: the more fun stuff.
Rym: yeah yeah because you said pretty much straight up you're a big geek.
Guest: so yes just about vanilla it's well no things I think it would be unfair for me to lie.
Guest: but um like so video games for example the geek that's a loaded statement.
Rym: video games like what's the game you're playing right now?
Guest: this is for online play is like heroin to me.
Guest: I can't get enough.
Guest: I can't stop playing as soon and I never ever put the headphones in.
Guest: all I do is go online and and make friends with somebody and then I'll drop a grenade into their car.
Guest: I love I love the fact that you can go on there and every once in a while I'll actually put the headphones in I'll hear what they're saying and it's just a bunch of kids screaming or else they're gonna threaten that they're gonna come get me and that's my favorite thing is just to antagonize everybody in the game.
Guest: preferably you know as many players as possible until they're all after me.
Scott: oh well it's.
Scott: it's so fitting that someone who's like a big video game griefer would make an internet discussion for him which is the tool of trolls everywhere.
Guest: that's another thing actually.
Guest: so trolls.
Guest: I don't actually don't know if I want to give this away but we've got a bunch of troll plugins for vanilla - that we were working on.
Rym: we've wanted that forever.
Rym: I wanted little funny things to do like if someone gets flagged as a troll they think they're posting they see their own posts but no one sees their posts.
Guest: yeah we've got that.
Scott: I've.
Scott: actually we've thought of some other things like once a long time ago years ago on slash that there was like a tech demo of like a stupidity detector and it was basically you would type any text into it and if it thought that your post was like a stupid post like if you just said you know first it would detect it as stupid.
Scott: but if you actually wrote a cohesion you know coherent coherent sentence it would say okay this post is not stupid and I'm like oh I wish the forum would just automatically you know tell someone your post is stupid.
Scott: we're not allowing it rewrite it stupid like tech typing detected.
Guest: actually that's a really good.
Guest: we haven't.
Guest: we hadn't done that one because that's not so much trolling as it is just you know idiocy right.
Rym: that's something we do like the biggest thing in our forum that we use and we just kind of hack it.
Rym: we have moderators who can do it.
Rym: is we correct in line grammar and spelling really in anyone's post?
Guest: yeah it's funny.
Guest: like I was talking to a guy recently who runs a really really really big forum millions of users millions of people every day on it and they moderate every single comment in their forum.
Scott: well they must have like an army of moderate.
Guest: yeah there's a big and all the moderators do it for free of course but yeah like I can't imagine going to trust all those moderators too because any one of them could be.
Guest: you know yeah and when when he told us this I you know it blew me away.
Guest: but at the same time I was like there's such a huge opportunity right there like we just writing even the most rudimentary parser to figure out if something is bad or good or even just looking for you know words that flag something is bad and you know have a black and white list.
Guest: they don't even have that.
Guest: I mean imagine how much it could be reduced.
Scott: so I mean that would.
Scott: also.
Scott: there's a lot of sites out there that you know have a requirement that they need to moderate everything like newspapers.
Scott: for example whenever you try to comment on an actual newspaper especially a local one it's like they always moderate every single post that goes in.
Guest: you know actually actually it's funny.
Guest: you mentioned that a friend of mine recently tweeted that apparently the very first newspapers in the States had pages for comments at the end like blank pages.
Guest: oh wow I don't understand how that possibly worked.
Scott: I guess you would write a comment and then you would leave the newspaper on the trolley and yeah and also pick it up.
Rym: so back in the day that people just draw cockboats they're like.
Rym: what did they do?
Scott: they drew a big animated flip book.
Scott: that was their signature and you would flip through.
Rym: so how about games like?
Rym: well how did you get indie game like?
Rym: what was the first game you played that you recognized as a game like?
Rym: your sentient mind was like I'm playing a game oh god like.
Guest: as in video game because I mean obviously tag I mean you're a kid you're playing tag.
Guest: but the first video game I ever wrote or sorry played it was one that I wrote in basic.
Guest: my dad had one of those like original computers that had like a tiny little screen.
Guest: you flip up and the keyboards underneath it and you remember which model it was.
Guest: I don't remember.
Guest: and he threw it away.
Guest: I think so but it had.
Guest: so it didn't have a hard drive it just had a floppy and it was.
Guest: and and so I turn it on it would boot up and I'd have to program my game and I'd spend you know 45 minutes programming this stupid game and then I'd play it and I'd be so exhausted and tired of it.
Guest: by then I'd play for like two minutes and then I turned the computer up knowing that everything's getting all 45 minutes of code is just gone.
Scott: that's every good.
Scott: every good programmer started working on some old machine that only did basic yeah 85 used in school.
Guest: basically this was just.
Guest: it was that stupid game where you know the block in the center is your car and then the roads coming down.
Guest: you know like there's two bars along the side they're going side to side.
Guest: you go to steer your car down the road.
Scott: no it's a good game.
Scott: yeah did you have turns and obstacles there?
Guest: I I was not that that's dedicated.
Guest: there were turns.
Guest: it was zigzagging.
Guest: right but that's all Zach's on.
Guest: I think was the first one I got really excited by three-dimensional.
Rym: Wow so any non video like it you ever play like D&D or like German board games anything like that?
Guest: no maybe when I was younger.
Guest: actually I did get into Magic the Gathering when I was in college.
Scott: what?
Scott: so what sets were out?
Scott: when at that time do you remember?
Guest: um it was.
Guest: it was like they didn't have a lot of sets.
Guest: this is like right in the very beginning.
Guest: and so what was my best?
Guest: I had a bunch of Sarah like.
Guest: I had an like an angel that had a bunch of Sarah angels and oh yeah I was.
Guest: I had a like a white deck and a blue deck that was sort of munch together and I had one of those oysters that catch people and hold them at the bottom of the ocean.
Guest: it's been a long time.
Scott: it's always interesting you know because we still.
Scott: we go to conventions and we still see kids playing magic today and we look at the cards they're playing with.
Scott: we don't recognize any of them but occasionally there's one card they got on the table that I I'm like.
Scott: oh I know that card and every single person around you will if will either still be playing or will have played and they can tell you like I stopped playing at Fallen Empires I stopped playing at the you know the Arabian Nights and I you know
Guest: for me it was one of those things like I think as soon as they started coming out with decks with other cards period and they were like they stopped making the old ones they started making these new ones and they didn't make any sense to me and they weren't very as powerful as the old ones.
Guest: and I was like this is BS.
Guest: yeah I don't know.
Guest: and in the end what it came down to is that I was in college and I needed beer money and so I sold all my.
Rym: I wish I'd sold mine back when they were worth money.
Scott: yeah right well they're still kind of worth money just not you know it's not the $400 black Lotus days?
Scott: yeah yeah.
Guest: so if you and if you want to talk geek.
Guest: so another thing that I sold for money was comics.
Guest: I'm a huge comic nerd so what.
Scott: so what do you still read comics like now?
Guest: no but I still have most of my good ones like.
Guest: I have a ton of.
Guest: I guess it would be around issue 240 250 something like that I was reading.
Scott: I had like the 300.
Guest: oh yeah I know I've been.
Guest: I had them like very old and I also have.
Guest: I have like the entire McFarland collection of amazing spider-man.
Guest: so from whenever he started I that was the early 90s I think yeah I have all those I had.
Guest: I had us like all my the all of spawn and I ended up selling spawn number one to this comic shop for beer.
Guest: and then I this sounds bad that I sold everything for beer but it was college.
Scott: come on I guess it depends what kind of college in Canada right that's right?
Scott: are we getting?
Scott: was it labott blue?
Scott: you were drinking those pilsner.
Guest: is the prairies okay like Molson pilsner I don't know.
Scott: and Rochester all the Canadian hockey player because we had a huge hockey team in Rochester.
Scott: so all the it was full of Canadian players from.
Scott: you know the from.
Rym: they were all like hotel management majors yeah and they would all.
Scott: all they drank was the Bob blue.
Scott: you would see bottles of it like in big pyramids everywhere you know.
Guest: and in the prairies it's it's a lot of Molson.
Guest: what else they got?
Guest: about 50 a lot of the bats and Molson I guess I don't know they're all.
Guest: it's weird like from one part of Canada's the other.
Guest: the beer is totally different.
Guest: I mean coming to Quebec it's like a whole different country.
Scott: no yeah so you don't read comics anymore there.
Scott: and so then?
Guest: no but I still have them there and they're all individually wrapped and cardboard backed and everything.
Guest: I was a huge comic.
Rym: so why'd you stop reading beer?
Guest: money money?
Guest: yeah it was purely money and it wasn't.
Guest: it was college and I couldn't afford to buy them anymore.
Rym: but now after vanilla I mean you're clearly a millionaire.
Scott: so if I if I if I could make a comic suggestion right there is a Jeff Lemire wrote a series of comics called the the Essex County trilogy which will probably appeal to you because it's about it's it's set in Canada Canadian that's all you know.
Scott: it's also really awesome no but I you know if you if you you know you'll have a you know a shared you know childhood experience with him possibly because he was all you know.
Scott: he's like also a comic reader same kind of person.
Guest: right cool check it out.
Rym: I guess that or I mean ever in a Batman Dark Knight Returns is pretty much like.
Rym: that's a different road of comics.
Scott: I know knows about that.
Guest: yeah heard of that one.
Scott: yeah it's like.
Scott: hey have you heard of movies?
Scott: you know you should see this.
Scott: so I mean you know you're you're up in you're up in Montreal.
Scott: it's not really like the big tech scene right I mean usually it's it's San Francisco and stuff.
Scott: I mean we're in New York and we even get like flak for not being very technological.
Scott: so do you does that like cause any problems for you or anything like that?
Guest: well I mean the way I look at it is first of all Montreal actually has a really good startup scene right now.
Guest: so it's sort of on the turnaround here and there's actually a lot of money coming into the province right now specifically into Montreal for for people who want to do startups in tech.
Guest: I recently went to Vancouver just a week or so ago to this conference called grow and it was basically an opportunity for US investors and Canadian entrepreneurs to get together and talk about funding their companies and for me the most the best part about it was and no offense to the investors but meeting all the other companies from Canada because you know Canada is so big and it's so spread out that half the time we don't even know about each other even though we're all up here and it's actually across the entire country.
Guest: you know a relatively small group of techies and and there's actually some really really cool stuff going on and some of it is as close as like.
Guest: I met a ton of people from Ottawa and apparently there's a great startup scene in Ottawa and really cool stuff going on there.
Guest: for example I don't know if you heard of Shopify but that's that's a big one I thought about.
Scott: I've thought about using it.
Guest: yeah they're great and I met one of the founders of Shopify.
Guest: he has another one that he's doing now called SWIX which is the social web index which helps you to do all kinds of tracking of your campaigns across the social web like crazy stuff.
Guest: yeah Montreal is actually really good and and the like.
Guest: I say that the tech scene here is really starting to blow up.
Guest: there's events all the freaking time.
Guest: I can't even keep up with them anymore.
Guest: yeah yeah it's a lot of fun.
Guest: and hey if you do come up let me know and you can come to the vanilla office.
Guest: we'll hang out awesome.
Scott: yeah I guess we've got some place to go on vacation there.
Rym: so we do have to ask because you do live north of the Messier line.
Rym: you're a hockey fan.
Guest: yeah you know that's.
Guest: I'm almost embarrassed to be Canadian because I totally am NOT.
Guest: I'm not a sportsman at all.
Guest: don't watch any sports of any kind only into total geekery.
Guest: my co-founder is a huge sports fan but it just didn't.
Guest: I don't even understand what the hell he's talking about.
Guest: I'm like failing and being Canadian by saying that that's all right.
Scott: I you know I mean not everyone in the u.s.
Scott: is you know whatever stereotype of us you want to name?
Rym: so you said you were a geek and you said specifically geeks.
Rym: I'm just curious because it seems like different parts of the world they use the words differently.
Rym: do you think there's any difference between a geek and a nerd or do you just use them interchangeably?
Guest: yeah I don't know a nerd.
Guest: I can't help but think of revenge of the nerds and and that's their they're just not cool.
Guest: you know a geek a geek can be really smart and really cool half the time.
Guest: even if a geek is a pretentious jerk you still want to know them because they're really smart and they think about stuff a lot and they can say amazing things that blow your mind.
Guest: or as a nerd is just an idiot like.
Guest: I knew lots of nerds in college who who?
Guest: you know they were into comics and stuff like that too.
Guest: but then they come out of an exam like hey how'd you know?
Guest: exam like oh you know high 80s high 90s and then they failed you know.
Guest: oh really well that to me is a nerd.
Scott: that's us is a is a is a I think a dork dork maybe the same thing as a nerd.
Scott: I guess a nerd for us is someone who is you know at least for us it's.
Scott: it's like the guy.
Scott: the guy Steve Urkel is a nerd.
Scott: right he has no social skills.
Scott: you don't really want to be near him.
Scott: he's annoying.
Scott: but yeah could make a rocket and it would work because he actually knows.
Rym: you know right a geek can make 90% of the rocket and he's totally cool.
Rym: yeah.
Guest: so like screech would be a nerd.
Rym: then yeah probably go more broad we always.
Rym: the definition we use on the show at least because it's GeekNights is then our whole like focus is that a nerd has depth of focus in one area or maybe a couple areas and like they're like if there's a spider graph of their life there's like these gigantic spikes going way way out.
Rym: yeah but a geek is like they have depth of interest in many fields like they have this depth and breadth kind of combined.
Guest: yeah yeah you know it's weird.
Guest: like since since I took the the plunge and tried to turn vanilla into a business started about I guess two years ago I decided that I wanted to stop working for other people and just do open source stuff.
Guest: and at that time I realized as time got went by that I had to cut out a lot of other things that I was passionate about in life to make room for all that stuff that I had to learn.
Guest: I mean going from being a straight-up developer to being somebody that you know.
Guest: I'm a CEO.
Guest: now I have board meetings.
Guest: I got a. I don't know about financials.
Guest: I got to know about marketing.
Guest: you know business development.
Guest: these are all things that that you know.
Guest: they're very very nerdy and geeky but in a totally different way and I had to sort of push room out out of my brain to move into other things.
Guest: like at the time that I decided to do this move I just started to learn how to play guitar and it was another one of those things I was picking up I was getting better at and I had to drop it in.
Guest: life is a guitar dude.
Guest: if you're a true geek you'll learn.
Scott: yeah I mean it's weird like I played it when I was in trouble with the harmonica which was kind of a test I played.
Scott: I played the guitar in fifth grade and then I stopped because I went to middle school.
Scott: in middle school I joined the band and played the clarinet and I couldn't play to it once right so.
Scott: and then after middle school I stopped playing the clarinet also so then it was nothing.
Scott: and then later on I was like.
Scott: you know I made a big mistake.
Scott: I should have stuck with the guitar the whole time because if I had stuck with it all the way through college I would have been like a rock star already.
Scott: right right that many years.
Scott: but then I was like okay as soon as I had money I was like alright I should buy a guitar but wait what if I don't actually practice?
Scott: I'll just waste money and I'll see the guitar sitting there you know making me feel guilty every day.
Rym: eventually you'll see it on eBay.
Rym: yeah.
Scott: so I was like I know I'll buy a cheap instrument and if I have the discipline to practice it that means that I will also have the discipline to practice the guitar.
Rym: of course part of the trouble was you said harmonic and I'm like yeah I'll do it too.
Rym: but I played music all my life.
Rym: I almost became a professional trumpet players.
Rym: I was like I was rocking it.
Scott: yes I bought harmonica and then I did not have the discipline to practice it.
Scott: so I said well I guess a guitar will just sit there making me feel guilty.
Scott: so I will not buy one that harmonica make you feel guilty?
Scott: no because it was only five bucks.
Guest: well no offense to harmonica players.
Guest: but how can you feel cool playing a harmonica feel cool playing a guitar you know.
Guest: if you don't know what you're doing like walking by and they see you strumming on the guitar they're like that guy is cool.
Scott: no not in New York City where half the people with guitars just sort of you know got a bucket.
Scott: they were looking for spare change and they don't know how to play anything.
Guest: and yeah anyway anyway I digress it's it's a same for.
Guest: so for that reason I mean I don't have enough time to dedicate to video games.
Guest: I bought all these games because I get excited about them and like Left 4 Dead I really wanted to play it.
Guest: I played it a little bit.
Guest: I had already left for dead - yeah I know I'm but I'm the I didn't.
Guest: even I haven't had time for Left 4 Dead 2 I've only done Left 4 Dead 1 and again I honestly I actually had to stop playing that one because it gave me nightmares.
Guest: for some reason zombies terrify me I don't know why and actually I just read World War Z by Max Brooks.
Scott: I've heard about that.
Guest: if you should read that book it is amazing and it's again.
Guest: there's another reason that I'm geeky.
Guest: I read a ton of geeky books like that.
Rym: you got any any book recommendations besides book club we get people to read like Ray Bradbury Princeton nothing all these crazy books.
Guest: well actually this is gonna sound weird but my wife made me read the time travelers wife and I know like.
Guest: I was like really you're gonna make me read this just sounds so lame.
Guest: and then they made the movie.
Guest: this is she made me read it before the movie but I was like.
Guest: that's actually like a kick-ass book that you know written by a woman and and it's it comes across like some kind of sci-fi thing by a guy.
Guest: I don't know it.
Guest: it was really cool and not what you expect.
Guest: it was kind of hardcore huh.
Guest: and the movie just like softened it up and it was total cheese ball.
Guest: so don't watch the movie.
Guest: duly noted as can often happen my books right in front of me.
Guest: so well Irvin Welsh I'll just I'll just throw that out there read anything by Irvin Welsh.
Guest: Wikipedia is the guy that wrote Trainspot Trainspot oh yeah and and so like his books.
Guest: if you can if you can make it through one of his books then you can make it through all of his books.
Guest: and here he has a very strange way of writing and half the time he uses that Scottish slang so you it takes a while to understand what the hell they're talking about.
Scott: that could be really fun though because when you watch the movie with the slang you don't really get all of it.
Scott: but if I could read it I feel like I could go slowly and learn it and actually maybe you reuse it and learn pikey maybe.
Guest: and if you if you like Trainspotting he's made a sequel to it called porno which is way way better than Trainspotting was and apparently Ewan McGregor has been saying that he's never gonna do this.
Guest: he hates porno he thinks it was a horrible sequel and blah blah blah blah.
Guest: but and they say they're not gonna make the sequel unless he agrees to do it.
Guest: so it's kind of dead in the water but it's it's amazing it's so funny and if you like Francis Begbie you know Begbie if I don't know can we swear on this show?
Scott: yes you can say whatever you want okay.
Guest: so in in Trainspotting he's the one he's playing pool and he throws this his mug or his pint of beer over the balcony goes and smashes some girl in the head and then there's like mayhem.
Guest: downstairs is everybody trying to figure out what's going on and he comes down the stairs and goes some cunt glass lassie and no cunt leaves till we find out what cunt done it in porno he goes absolutely wild.
Guest: is is an amazing book.
Scott: I had to have to put that on a list here.
Rym: so how about notice how we started?
Rym: very specific we draw out now.
Rym: so movies.
Rym: now the the lame question anyone ever asked like what your favorite movie?
Rym: because it's just a crap question to try to answer.
Rym: so I don't know what are like three movies that you like.
Guest: well you know what.
Guest: when we were just talking about sequels there it reminded me of I I'm a huge Mad Max nerd and and now they're making Mad Max Fury Road.
Guest: I don't know if you know what that yet.
Rym: oh actually I just learned there's a Mad Max convention in Southern California where if you're not dressed up like a mod Mad Max character they don't let you in.
Rym: that's hilarious out in the desert it's well.
Scott: there's also the guy in Australia who like made a Mad Max whole like his whole.
Scott: his whole property is mad.
Rym: basically lives Mad Max.
Guest: yeah that's crazy.
Guest: the guy yeah you know Inception the movie Inception yeah so the there was the the guy in that who was also a movie called Bronson British guy more a little more like beefier Tom Hardy.
Guest: anyway he's gonna be the new Mad Max in Mad Max Fury Road.
Scott: oh so it's not Melvin gibstein.
Guest: no I mean I think he's a little out of shape.
Scott: yeah some other troubles do.
Guest: yeah exactly I don't know.
Guest: probably a favorite.
Guest: hang on my wife's sitting right here and she's a better memory than me.
Guest: Sarah what's my favorite movie?
Guest: yeah no she she says Wizard of Oz.
Guest: that's her favorite movie.
Scott: come on not the sequel.
Guest: no definitely not a dumb and dumber.
Guest: that's probably it.
Guest: I've watched dumb and dumber probably a million times.
Guest: I can't help it.
Guest: it's just it never gets old.
Scott: that's fine.
Scott: well there's stupid movies.
Scott: I watch over and over again.
Guest: thing stupid movies are the best like airplane classic.
Scott: I keep the plane top secret lately.
Rym: oh my god top secret.
Rym: I should watch that again.
Scott: yes I've never seen it.
Scott: what really really really really not everyone's seen everything.
Rym: everyone's seen everything.
Guest: no I just aged myself.
Rym: no I've seen.
Guest: everyone seen it except Scott apparently okay yeah I don't know big nerd so I'm into lots of TV shows too.
Guest: we actually a couple years ago I as soon as I discovered what you could do with Torrance I'm not gonna say what that is that you can do.
Guest: it's fine.
Guest: I will say that the result of this that discovery is that I disconnected my cable television.
Scott: we also have not had cable television since 2001.
Guest: yeah about the same here yeah and and so as a result of that I it's changed the way I I take in media of all forms.
Guest: now it's all that.
Guest: I'm not gonna say I download it but uh it's just.
Guest: there's no more commercials.
Guest: let's put it that way.
Guest: and you know instead of sitting down and waiting every week to watch a TV show you you decide oh so there's been seven seasons of bones.
Guest: all right I'm gonna watch all of that this weekend.
Scott: mm-hmm you said you like Mad Max.
Scott: have you ever watched a show called fists in the North Star?
Guest: yes of course I've seen lots and lots of
Scott: anime and
Guest: actually if you want to get into really geeky stuff when I was in college we used to go to these like when Chan Jackie Chan was first coming with like super cop and and all those ones operation Condor.
Guest: remember that those are in the Bronx.
Guest: yes you're in the Bronx and there's a ton of ones like.
Guest: there was one like sergeant kabuki man or something like that.
Guest: there's all these weird Japanese movies they came out of there that are just amazing like of course drunken master.
Guest: you you you have to have seen drunken master.
Rym: I assume you've seen that iron monkey.
Scott: yes how about attack the gas station?
Rym: I have not seen no one's ever seen attack the gas station.
Rym: I have.
Scott: so up your I have a feeling attack the gas station will be one of your favorite movies right on.
Scott: it's a.
Guest: have you guys seen have you seen that?
Guest: it was like a short sitcom thing that was made for the internet I'm pretty sure they say as a pilot but I don't think it actually was.
Guest: with Jack Black and Owen Wilson.
Scott: I'm gonna talk about Tokyo breakfast.
Guest: this is like for some reason when we're just talking about these these weird like funny special effects and wacky premises.
Guest: it reminded me of this.
Guest: this show which is about Jack Black was a cop or like an FBI agent or something.
Guest: anyway he got too close to the space space man.
Guest: he got too close to the Sun and it changed his brain and it made him super smart at in a daylight and and really dumb at nighttime or something like that.
Scott: and that's okay.
Scott: as long as you sleep all night you'll be.
Scott: you'll be just fine.
Guest: his sidekick is a motorcycle played by Owen Wilson.
Guest: if you have you don't I?
Guest: I'm gonna have to find out what this is and give it to you because it is the funniest friggin ridiculous sitcom you'll ever see.
Guest: that sounds right up that alley though of crazy premise and dumb special effects.
Scott: yeah attack the gas station is a is a Korean movie and basically the story is you have some delinquent kids.
Scott: they're not really kids they're a little bit older you know and they didn't go anywhere in life and they're sitting eating some noodles and they say hey what do you want to do?
Scott: we're bored.
Scott: they say hey let's attack the gas station.
Scott: so they go rob the gas station and then it's just a pretty mundane.
Scott: you know robbery?
Scott: you know yeah.
Scott: and then the movie cuts and they're in the noodle shop again and they're bored again and he says hey what do you want to do?
Scott: let's attack the gas station again and then opening credits and then yet the second time they attack the gas station is far more eventful than the first time right you know?
Guest: 90 minutes eventful okay okay I see yeah nice yeah pretty good I'm interested.
Guest: I'm gonna have to get that.
Rym: I've never met a person who didn't love that movie at least the first showing.
Scott: is there anything else that you you know?
Scott: you want to say that we did not give you an opportunity to say sure yeah so my name is Marco Sullivan.
Guest: I'm the founder of vanilla forums which is open source forum soccer that powers discussion on hundreds of thousands of sites around the web.
Guest: you can download vanilla at vanilla forums org and you can set up a. so check us out start your community.
Scott: actually I just thought of one more or two more questions.
Scott: right used to be called Lucy mo.
Scott: right what happened to Lucy?
Guest: my question it's a it's it's an embarrassing question okay?
Guest: so so basically I bought you know back in the day when people just bought domain names for the hell of it.
Guest: I guess they still do but they were a lot easier to get.
Guest: back then I had a ton of domain names and that was one of the ones that I bought and I ended up using it for a sight I made for my wife not my girlfriend at the time but wife now for Valentine's Day and it was bless you mo.
Guest: that's how I pronounced it.
Guest: less you mo was our ugly googly talk to each other and it means love you more as in less you mo.
Rym: no I less you mo.
Guest: oh god it's embarrassing.
Guest: but so when I made vanilla I was trying to sort of go for this.
Guest: I don't know weird like here's the brand that owns multiple products because vanilla was gonna be the first one and there was a file browser and file browser.
Scott: is the file browser still?
Guest: oh really yeah I guess it's weird.
Guest: some people still have it out there.
Guest: but I kind of felt like once once things like Flickr became you know more commonplace.
Scott: and yeah the thing is the reason I use it still is because well actually that you know what actually I used to.
Scott: I was using Flickr.
Scott: but Flickr is really only good for your photos that you want to share with people.
Scott: right but sometimes you want to post an image usually to then post it in a forum and I need to host it somewhere.
Scott: but I want to host it on Flickr.
Scott: so I just upload it to my server and then I had the file browser there.
Scott: so I could find old ones if I needed to read you know just to get a link to them.
Scott: yeah I think imgur is actually had made that sort of obsolete.
Guest: yeah there's there's imgur and then there's also like we're actually doing some stuff for our dot com hosted forums where you can upload files now and the first stage was just getting the files uploaded.
Guest: and now we're gonna have little media repository.
Guest: so anybody who uploads files you know they have a little page they can go to to grab the links and all that kind of stuff.
Guest: but so yeah that's where the name came from.
Guest: I needed to use something to umbrella over these products and I had that one laying around.
Guest: so I used it and then over the years it just became more and more difficult to explain to people first of all what it means but even more importantly how the hell do you pronounce it mm-hmm?
Scott: and so I didn't think about the pronunciation until just now when I got it wrong.
Guest: yeah.
Guest: and then what you know and the other turn take it the other way and say oh my domain name is lassi mo comm and everybody like okay and then everybody spells it wrong.
Rym: what you can do is make a legend of Krauser and every time you get interviewed give a different story and then no one will ever know exactly.
Guest: well anyway it's it's sort of gone by the wayside.
Guest: we just realized that vanilla was the name that stuck and it was a name that everybody recognized and you know we had some good domain names for it and it just didn't make sense to hold on to the other one.
Guest: so we just dropped it all right.
Scott: yeah okay I think that's that's pretty much it.
Scott: thanks a lot for coming on the show.
Scott: it was a good time cool.
Guest: yeah thank you so much for having me.
Guest: this is fun.
Scott: yeah we'll definitely talk again in the future perhaps.
Scott: yeah let me let me know when this goes online and where I can find it and probably we normally would have gone online today but we're going to to PAX this week so it'll probably be Monday next week I guess.
Rym: yeah we got like two panels.
Rym: I gotta finish.
Scott: maybe Monday maybe Monday next week you know.
Scott: maybe after we don't know.
Guest: are you guys going to blog world in Vegas?
Scott: I didn't even know there was a such thing as blog.
Rym: we're going to the penny arcade expo.
Guest: okay I'm just like if if there's any opportunity to hook up we should.
Scott: oh yeah absolutely if you want to go to PAX east it's in Boston net account.
Rym: we're trying to get a big tech presence at.
Scott: yeah we could you.
Scott: we're in charge of the the the programming at well not all the programming but the panels programming ConnectiCon.
Scott: so maybe we could get them so you could be like a guest or something.
Guest: yeah yeah that'd be cool.
Guest: well when when is it?
Rym: uh like next year?
Scott: it's in the middle of the summer in Hartford Connecticut.
Guest: cool well I guess keep me keep me up to date.
Rym: yeah we only get like seven thousand people.
Rym: it's not like the biggest convention but seven thousand is big.
Rym: no not really Otakon it's like the anime account we go to out here is thirty thousand.
Scott: oh wow yeah okay well that's something else you have to uh something else you have to realize.
Scott: like you.
Scott: look at san diego comic-con.
Scott: right it's big and famous and they'll tell you an attendance number like a hundred thousand.
Scott: they're actually lying because what they do is they're actually giving you a turnstile count.
Scott: so if someone goes if someone goes to all three days and preview night so it's wednesday night thursday friday saturday sunday they count that person five times.
Scott: so the you know san diego comic-con is the biggest but the true attendance number is probably between 40 and 50 000.
Rym: yeah i mean our little con by if we count it the way like all the vegas cons count is like 20 000 people.
Scott: yeah right right but we're yeah when we count we're actually counting the number of unique individuals.
Scott: so a weekend pass counts as one and a saturday pass counts as one.
Scott: the only time we would mess up counting is if somebody bought a saturday pass and a sunday pass we might count them twice and mess up yeah yeah but it's much closer to and plus.
Scott: sometimes they count the vendors and don't even get me started.
Scott: yeah all right all right now we're actually done.
Scott: i gotta go eat dinner.
Scott: okay cool have a good one.
Guest: thanks guys.
Scott: thank you.
Rym: all right this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to dj pretzel for the opening music cat lee for web design and brand.
Scott: ok for the logos be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech mondays gaming tuesdays anime comic wednesdays and indiscriminate thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.