Scott: It's Wednesday April 14th.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Scott: I'm red and this is GeekNights tonight the Museum of comic and cartoon art festival 2010.
Rym: every time we do a mocha opener you always kind of say it slow like that.
Scott: It's hard to say.
Rym: Let's do this For the last like week.
Rym: I've been rollerblading home from work in the city.
Scott: It's gonna rain tomorrow though.
Rym: Yeah, so I'm probably not going to do it tomorrow Which is fine because I'm finally going to the DMV to give up the Otari license plate.
Rym: Oh It's the end of an era.
Scott: I always still have to go to the DMV.
Scott: Also, I'm gonna.
Scott: I gotta find a way that I need one in Harlem is open until six.
Scott: That's not late enough.
Scott: I got like maybe eight.
Scott: It's I have to go to the doctor the dentist and the DMV and I know the 3ds.
Rym: That's pretty dangerous.
Scott: Yeah, so I got it.
Scott: I got to like schedule it to take the minimum time off work.
Rym: Just take a day off and then use the day to dick around.
Scott: That's the four DS Dr.
Scott: Dennis.
Scott: DMV dick around.
Rym: Well, the doctor might also involve some dicking Hopefully not the DMV.
Rym: Definitely.
Scott: I mean I need some doctoring but not in the dick.
Rym: But I have some observations about rollerblading in New York City, you know, just almost no one does it.
Scott: actually today I think as long as I've lived here, I've seen three people today.
Rym: Today I ran into not literally three Individual rollerbladers other than myself and when I stopped and waited Did you ask them like where they were getting their like rollerblade stuff from now?
Rym: They were just going past me.
Rym: I didn't want to stop.
Rym: cuz you know rollerblades it takes a while to get up to speed.
Rym: You did not want to slow down.
Rym: That's the main reason why I'm on the sidewalk anyway, so Observation number one the most important one.
Rym: number of times Rym has almost been hit by a car running a red light?
Rym: zero Number of times Rym has almost been hit by a jackass bicyclist running a red light.
Rym: You're counting eleven times have I had a green light and I go to rollerblades.
Rym: some jackass biker almost hits me.
Rym: Yeah, the cars are fine It's the bikers Even though I noticed biking.
Scott: cuz when you know when your bike like when I got the Mazda 3 suddenly you notice every other Mazda 3 on the road.
Scott: Yeah, as soon as I'm biking I notice all the other bikes on the road.
Rym: So the thing here's the thing, you know why you're noticing all these assholes on the road anyway.
Scott: now the So.
Scott: so the thing is right, you know, sometimes there are cars that are sort of you know, annoying like I'll be like Hey, dude, give me some room or like they'll double park and it's like great now I can't get around you and this car is going by.
Scott: and if unless I can't go past any further unless I go on the Sidewalk and sometimes that's annoying dude
Rym: You haven't driven in the Bronx and
Scott: but you know and sometimes a car will I get behind me and be like beep beep And be like, hey, yeah, you know and it's like, okay, whatever, you know, I can you know sort of understand even it's a little bleh But the bikes are just like whatever.
Scott: Whoo.
Scott: I see even like old man.
Scott: Just run in the red line You know, the bikes are way worse than the cars.
Rym: and I'm on the bike saying this, you know, yeah So, I don't know I mean I want a bike but I almost don't want to be associated with all those other bikers.
Scott: then be like me stop with The fucking red lights, you know Don't freakin, you know ring your little horn and everybody We'll see.
Rym: the thing is I don't know how much like it.
Rym: I don't know if it'll be that much faster to bike just because it's so short as it is and the primary thing slowing me Down even rollerblading is red lights.
Scott: No, the thing is it's way fast.
Scott: The bike like you go over that bridge and it's just like like I'm like even when I'm pedaling up the hill on the bridge going Yeah, right and I like.
Scott: I look at the little fence that prevents you from falling off the bridge and I watch how fast the fence is going by.
Scott: it's like fence post fence post fence post fence post fence.
Scott: and it's like Wow, if I was walking you'd be like fence post.
Scott: Yeah Fence posts, you know.
Scott: So it's like wow even just pedaling really go and struggling in a low gear up a hill on this bridge is Significantly faster than pretty much, you know anything.
Rym: but what amazes me is how many?
Rym: Bikes who end up.
Rym: they walk their bikes up that little tiny hill.
Scott: I see some people walking it up I see some people using the wrong gear, but the thing is it's like it's always like, you know, there is no like stereotype of Bicycling.
Scott: like.
Scott: you'll see people who like you like if you saw them just walking around the street normal clothes You might think oh that person, you know, they don't know.
Scott: now they're like going way faster than me some old lady.
Rym: Well with bicycles in particular I think everyone knows how to ride a bike and New York is just a place where that skill is actually useful Mmm-hmm.
Rym: I think that a lot of people ride bikes just because it's useful and everyone learns not to ride a bike when they're a kid except Greg.
Rym: So on Sunday is the non sequitur And Sunday, you can't make something a sequitur by simply declaring that it was a non sequitur.
Rym: Yes, you can.
Scott: So on Sunday, I made some manueva cochina.
Scott: It was so tasty.
Rym: I like it, too.
Scott: So then you know Monday just sat in the fridge and yet last night I ate it again.
Scott: But you didn't want to come and help me eat it even though I had so much like.
Rym: I did want to come and help You eat it, but I had other important things to do.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Rym: I was editing YouTube videos.
Rym: You know the GeekNights YouTube stream is gonna come online at some point.
Scott: You sure you weren't dicking around.
Rym: I was also playing DDR.
Rym: cuz I got a setup again.
Scott: It does the 50 Initial D that 60s.
Scott: You know what?
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I got to save this for Tuesday.
Rym: I'm not gonna talk about DDR.
Rym: I'll say one thing I fucking miss playing that shit.
Scott: DDR is the best.
Rym: Oh my god Wildwood doesn't do it for me cuz I'm not.
Rym: the memory in Wildwood is so dancing.
Rym: It's so like you can't hear the music and everyone sucks.
Rym: and I kind of forgot how great it is to just have the loud Music using step mania.
Rym: Yeah, of course.
Rym: Okay, and you know what?
Rym: I downloaded some torrent of every step mania song.
Rym: ever me too.
Rym: It has DDR first mix second mix third mix fifth mix six.
Scott: We got the same torrent.
Emily: Where the hell is?
Scott: it had a fourth mix folder that was empty, right?
Rym: It actually was full but there were no arrows in there just mp3.
Scott: Oh really the one I got was all arrows and no mp3s.
Scott: Ah, but I did get this Konami official folder.
Rym: I downloaded that.
Rym: I didn't look in it.
Scott: yet the Konami official folder that came in the same torrent as the everything else Had a bunch of fourth mix in it.
Scott: cuz it was like night in motion and shit weird problem.
Rym: Where are you?
Rym: so get this.
Rym: I started to play and I was sucking like bad and I'm thinking I'm hurt.
Rym: I'm hurt real bad.
Rym: What's going on?
Rym: Do I suck at DDR?
Scott: Are you a monkey?
Rym: Is it the Actually downloaded that announcer me too.
Scott: I also got that.
Rym: that's the best one.
Scott: But I need to get Alice character pack and also Baldo character pack.
Rym: I was doing so bad and then I thought wait a minute and I turned on the auto sync for one song Which let it little look at how you're dancing and then it'll use the statistical deviation of your steps based on whether like when you hit Close but you're off by a couple milliseconds to figure out how offset the arrows are from the music.
Rym: Mmm, and it offs.
Rym: it changed everything by point one one nine seconds.
Rym: Mm-hmm, and then everything was great.
Rym: But then I thought wait a minute.
Rym: Maybe I just calibrated this now differently from every DDR machine.
Rym: I'm gonna screw myself in the long run.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So I started calibrating.
Rym: like every song.
Rym: I went through 15 songs.
Rym: I was within point.
Rym: Oh three milliseconds Deviation on all of them.
Rym: So there's a delay in the Mac going to the HDTV.
Rym: Oh Where the delay is.
Rym: Okay, I was like what but I felt very precise in my dancing that I was that I am within point zero zero three milliseconds not millisecond seconds of Perfect timing.
Scott: but anyway getting back to my point is I last night I ate some leftover Nuevo cochina and there's even more left over.
Rym: Oh my god, you can eat it again tonight.
Scott: No, no, maybe tomorrow, but the like keep that long.
Scott: Yeah, why not?
Scott: No microwaving it.
Scott: So if there's anything nasty thing in there, it's getting hosed unless it already made its poison That's true.
Scott: But um, I So I ate two burritos last night.
Scott: Hey, my stomach was so gurgly.
Scott: It's even gurgling now.
Scott: It's that's great is the ultimate gurgle.
Rym: So anime comics all that stuff.
Rym: Hi everybody Heard about us from anime Boston saw our panels saw the link to the slideshow that you all asked about.
Rym: it's online.
Rym: All I want to say is we're not talking about anime Boston tonight.
Rym: We're gonna talk about the mocha first.
Rym: So, I don't know anime Boston.
Rym: there's not a lot to say.
Rym: we recorded a show already, but we're not gonna upload it just yet.
Scott: No, it was a convention of anime.
Scott: Yeah, we did some panels We seem to go over.
Scott: Well, we went to some panels.
Scott: We walked around the dealers room.
Scott: once we walked around the artists alley a couple times.
Rym: Darryl Surratt was as always incredibly impressive with his mad array of mad panels And we saw we hung out with people and I'm sorry guys anime Boston was fun and all.
Rym: but The we be.
Rym: it being the weekend after packs just it's really hard.
Rym: It's like riding the biggest roller coaster in the world and then riding the kiddie coaster like five times in a row It doesn't matter how many times you ride it.
Rym: It just can't compare.
Scott: Yeah, so it's like you ride the big roller coaster Whoo, and then you ride the kiddie coaster and you're basically taking a nap on it.
Rym: You know if I'd gone to anime Boston the weekend before packs, it would have been great.
Scott: That's what they should have done.
Rym: Well, they there's.
Rym: I don't think there was anyone who had a chance to change that situation.
Scott: The anime Boston could have just scheduled two weeks earlier.
Rym: But when did packs actually schedule?
Rym: and when do I remember when they announced where paxies was going to be?
Scott: It doesn't matter.
Rym: It was too late to get the Sheraton.
Scott: So hopefully they just there won't be the same weekend cuz that'll be the end of ahead of my boss.
Rym: Yeah, at least for us.
Rym: Yeah, oh Well, so I got any anime manga comic media news.
Scott: I do indeed, you know at the mocha I was noticing that you know the you know fan of graphics started doing the oshihiro tatsumi stuff.
Scott: But the gecky guy action see, you know in the the you know, the indie underground comics of Japan They're starting to bubble up even more in the indie comics.
Scott: publishers of the u.s.
Scott: Are picking them up You know and it not just fan of graphics brothers like top shelf and such, you know, it's pretty interesting.
Scott: It must have been a success for you know fan of graphics if other people are following suit anyway.
Scott: A top shelf is gonna publish a 400 page compilation of stories from a you know underground Anthology of manga from Japan called ax.
Scott: The guy who's in charge of ax named Akino kando is gonna come to New York City on April 21st Next weekend.
Scott: Is it really next weekend?
Scott: I think so.
Scott: Oh shit.
Rym: Yeah next week.
Scott: No, it's next Wednesday.
Scott: It's a week from today.
Scott: Oh crap.
Rym: Oh, yeah Wednesday.
Scott: Yeah And the thing is he's doing it at this exhibit that's going on and the exhibit is a showcase of all 120 issues of Garo which is like the original real deal gecky guy magazine that you know tatsumi and others worked on.
Scott: So not only do I get to go hear this like, you know modern Underground manga dude talk, but I also get to see every issue of Garo ever in this museum exhibit So it's gonna be totally sweet.
Rym: Well, it's even worse.
Rym: There's an opening reception that we could go to but it's Already happened from 6 to 8 p.m.
Rym: Today.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: No, I didn't.
Scott: I knew about that a while ago But I didn't want what's.
Scott: I didn't want to go to it.
Rym: You know, it looks like it's interesting looking at the picture of them.
Rym: It's never.
Scott: it's never a good idea Like, you know, I mean people like to go to like openings.
Scott: gallery openings or exhibit openings are great.
Rym: Here's why one free wine Two free cheese and crackers, right?
Scott: The thing is if you act, you know, that's fine.
Scott: if you want wine cheese and crackers, which I do But if you just how I survived RIT if you actually want to see the exhibit going to the opening is actually pretty bad Because that's the time.
Scott: It is the most crowded.
Scott: There's the most people in your way.
Rym: It's tough though, because it's always
Scott: I like to go at a time like when no one else is there so you can just totally take your time
Rym: underestimating the factor of the fact that most of the people who go to the openings of these things are going primarily to Hobnob with the other people there.
Scott: Yeah, that's saying is I'm saying, you know as opposed to look at the art.
Rym: So the few times I've gone to a gallery opening like that was a big deal.
Rym: Most of the people there were kind of standing in the middle talking Drinking the wine eating the cheese and I just went looked at all the art with no one in my way Possible depending on the size and shape of the the gallery.
Rym: But well, yes, I mean if it's shit I don't know what shape would be bad.
Rym: Maybe a hexagon.
Rym: So That it.
Scott: yeah, that's it.
Scott: so I got.
Rym: yeah, I don't have too much.
Rym: I'm watching a vote Tom.
Rym: slowly I get some DVDs from Scott.
Rym: I started watching Yamato, but I think I'm gonna hold actually watching the.
Rym: I'm gonna hold off on the Yamato because I gotta watch all the vote Toms first so we can actually review it.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: I think it's actually worth.
Scott: Yeah I've watched both.
Scott: so you can pick whichever one and we can review how much vote Tom's first.
Rym: I gotta.
Rym: it takes a lot longer to watch both times Yeah, but I'll power through it and I'm almost caught up on Dora which is fucking awesome.
Scott: You know the last episode of Dora, I think I don't know if there's a new one on crunchyroll yet But the last one I watched right?
Scott: I think it was episode 12 or 13.
Scott: It seemed like the end of the show.
Scott: It's like oh the show's over and then I went and apparently I talked to you know Some friends of ours who also watched all the episodes that were up there and they're like, no, this is like 24 episodes total.
Scott: That's like the halfway climax.
Scott: I was like wow Good, you'll get to an episode and you'd be like, oh, that's the ending right there and it's not the ending.
Scott: It's like oh shit, but my prediction in Dora that I predicted way early was absolutely correct.
Scott: So the show is not so good at being like, you know Keeping its mysteries mysterious, but it is still pretty good at being entertaining and awesome.
Rym: So yeah So things of the day.
Rym: I made a critical fatal error recently and now is the time to correct it.
Rym: I Go to College Humor.
Rym: that's where I steal most of my thing of the day videos as many of you smart people may have been Able to figure out.
Scott: let's not let's link to like the YouTube version of this video.
Scott: Well, I'd make the pose so guess what.
Rym: but regardless now normally I pride myself in my internet filter.
Rym: I mean, you know, well Scott now will be sitting there.
Rym: We'll have friends over we'll be going through the College Humor or some other site looking at funny videos and Scott my usually we look through and we pinpoint like that one will be funny That one's not worth watching.
Rym: that will be funny.
Rym: That was not worth watching.
Rym: We got a filter.
Rym: we're always on the same page and all the kind of inexperienced people will sit there and be like, ah What about that one cute dog blah blah?
Rym: that looks good, but they're never good.
Rym: Yep Well, uh my filter for the first time in my life has failed me.
Scott: Well, I to your credit right and you know to the credit of our filters, right?
Scott: It wasn't a situation of a false positive reset.
Scott: Oh, this will be good and it sucked.
Scott: It's a situation of you said, oh that sucked and it was good.
Rym: So I filter filters out pretty much all the plankton.
Scott: Yeah, as long as you get as long as you don't watch any bad things if you miss some good things It's okay cuz good things come around again, especially from the vault or whatever.
Scott: Whereas if you you know, you just want to avoid wasting time on bad things and you're all set.
Rym: So Gary oak, I'm Gary oak with my cribby crab is this is just fucking hilarious Miss tea, there's nothing else to say about it.
Rym: pedophile.
Scott: That's right Let's see, okay, so my thing of the day here is totally awesome.
Scott: it is a is for As a four as takes in atomic armor attacking anomalous amphibians.
Scott: So what this is here, it's I guess unreality magazine Which I've never heard of before.
Scott: but they've got a post here and the post is the most badass Alphabet ever.
Scott: and it looks like they got a different artist to do each letter of the alphabet in some nerdy fashion with alliteration and You know.
Scott: and so there's an illustration and an alliteration in nerd fashion for every single letter of the alphabet by a different artist.
Rym: So I saw one of these before.
Rym: I didn't realize it was the thing.
Rym: I just saw W like links over.
Scott: so for P it's like Peter Parker playing ping-pong with Pikachu and there's a hilarious picture.
Scott: and For K there K is for kiss King Kong and it's King Kong throwing up the horns with some kiss makeup.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I think my personal favorite is still Q is for Q and Q reading Q just because it has a Recursion.
Rym: recursion does add a lot to that one, you know, it's the classic picture of your cubicle.
Rym: But in the picture is the picture of the cubicle.
Scott: I like the art the best on the Tintin one because it actually looks like Tintin art.
Scott: It's Tintin and a Time Lord taking tea in Tibet.
Rym: But if I had to pick a favorite one, I don't know that evolving emu is pretty funny just for the way It's kind of laughing.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty good.
Rym: a little bit of Psyduck with a little bit of Howard the Duck.
Scott: Yeah Picking a favorite like none of them like they're all pretty awesome.
Scott: But I don't I can't find one that's like the awesomest like way up above the other ones.
Scott: I guess this Optimus Prime obliterating Oompa Loompas is pretty good.
Scott: Yeah, whatever.
Scott: This is a totally awesome nerdy alphabet.
Scott: And if you want to see Galactus geeking out with his glove puppets of Gundam and Godzilla, you should go to this website.
Rym: But all that aside we kind of talked about a lot of non mocha.
Rym: So I suppose we should just talk about the mocha or at least the art festival Not the museum that we've never really talked about saying art festivals redundant because the last a and mocha is art.
Scott: so it's like if you say mocha art festival, you're actually saying Museum of comic and cartoon art.
Rym: If I say just mocha festival it might be about coffee.
Scott: No, the mocha festival is definitely the correct way to say it, but doesn't that not also refer to coffee?
Rym: or perhaps?
Scott: no There isn't a mocha festival with an H in it, it doesn't exist.
Rym: maybe we should pronounce one of the C's different like No or draw anyway, ha ha so you might have noticed much like before when we had guest host Conrad Crayley Why do you keep insisting on this guest host business?
Rym: talk about cell phones?
Rym: We have it yet again.
Rym: We're gonna try to make this a trend at least for a while.
Emily: We have the right honorable Emily Compton because it's so rare that I'm in this room with you guys.
Rym: She's usually the studio audience.
Rym: She's been a guest in the past a guest host in the past.
Scott: Well, see, uh, let's see even you your fail.
Scott: It's not a guest host unless they are hosting.
Scott: just give up on it Just like you give up on your stupid guess.
Scott: that's pride and all that other stupid shit you keep doing.
Rym: my hilarious sticks.
Scott: Yeah, you're non hilarious repetitive annoying sticks.
Scott: It's not me it's.
Scott: nobody likes these takes.
Rym: I will point out that for everyone other than you that's pride.
Rym: It's not a stick.
Rym: That's a one-off joke.
Rym: That's hilarious.
Emily: No, I see it every time and I'm like, it's coming.
Emily: You guys know it's coming.
Rym: When I was anime Boston guys sitting to my left He did not see it coming.
Rym: when I said, I guess that's pride you left You know what.
Scott: for now on every time we do that.
Scott: I'm gonna be like, oh, I guess you're Greg Hartman And you know what?
Rym: No one else is gonna know what that means.
Scott: It doesn't matter.
Scott: You'll know what it means.
Scott: It should make you you'll feel bad and you should feel bad.
Emily: There was this chart about dweebs and geeks and nerds and stuff like that And one of the things for being a dweeb was that you go around repeating the same joke over and over to different people.
Rym: So you are point out is that not also what someone like George Carlin does?
Rym: he tells the same?
Emily: About it and you can see it and it's like record.
Scott: He wrote the joke.
Emily: Yeah, he's not pretending he's being like Original every time.
Emily: it's.
Rym: it's like yeah, this is like it's a performance Like old Jews telling jokes, it's not any telling of a joke or performance.
Rym: So what if you happen to tell the same joke multiple times in the course of your life?
Emily: Well, I guess you're part of it is you're pretending.
Emily: when you tell the joke It's like a one-off performance.
Emily: Like I am performing just for you.
Emily: And this is an original joke I thought up because I am so witty but It's just.
Scott: I think it's simpler than that.
Scott: your joke isn't funny.
Scott: George Carlin is funny every time.
Scott: I think the pride.
Scott: you are funny zero times.
Scott: It wasn't funny the first time or any time thereafter.
Scott: The point is is that we are not Guest hosts unless we are not here is just guest.
Rym: All right, I might get some backup arguments later.
Scott: I don't think anyone will agree with you that someone is a guest host unless We are not here and they are taking up the duties of hosting.
Scott: if they're just on the show with us They're only a guest and not a guest host.
Rym: But if what?
Rym: if they're hosting with us?
Scott: if someone sits next to Letterman those that's not a guest host as a guest We'll see.
Scott: if Letterman is letterman is sick at home.
Emily: Okay, so GeekNights is like an apartment that you guys share.
Emily: It's like having a guest host would be like putting somebody's name on the lease or having them sublet.
Emily: So anyway the mocha the mocha art festival it was Festival and not boiling hot like it was last year, which was very very nice.
Scott: Yeah, I have to give credit to the to the people running it right?
Scott: It's like okay.
Scott: They were in the puck building not so good because it's cramped with the multiple rooms.
Emily: Crazy old elevator.
Emily: you go up in the creaky.
Scott: I mean, it really wasn't it wasn't ideal Yeah, so they moved to the armory which was you know cheap.
Scott: right because they don't have a lot of monies.
Scott: You know, it's mostly.
Scott: this is where the mocha museum gets all its fundraising from.
Scott: is, you know, the armory selling ammo Right.
Scott: So, you know they had it in the armory Which is this big empty room that they do like drills and usually when it's not being used for festivals.
Emily: There were actually some On-duty soldiers walking around on the second floor.
Scott: It's an armory.
Scott: It's real.
Scott: It's in use.
Scott: There's arms there.
Rym: Yeah, it's the real deal, but it was funny how many people at the mocha just had no idea.
Rym: That's what was going on.
Emily: Like that's what the building was Because it's got all these signs and it's like US Army and they've got a list of people who passed away in wars Says like operation, you know Iraqi freedom and stuff on some of this it is really old.
Rym: That sort of thing they don't look at like a building like that and just think about modern military.
Rym: They think of it as like a relic something old.
Rym: They don't.
Rym: no one really considers their daily life that all those things are kind of real and that we do saw that stuff Just kind of next door in the building.
Emily: But the thing is I mean the Chrysler buildings damn old but like modern day businesses are still in that.
Emily: how is a military Building any different?
Rym: Well, just because people don't think about military stuff like that in their daily lives.
Rym: Anyway, this is this is completely tangential.
Scott: The point is is that you know, they had it.
Scott: they moved it to this armory But they didn't change the time of year and the result was that the armory had really no air conditioning.
Scott: It was like an a zillion degrees last year.
Emily: Is this big?
Emily: You know metal dome and it had the worst fanboy funk, but the thing is there were no fanboys there.
Emily: It was just that hot.
Scott: Yep So all credit to them because I would have tried to find another place, you know And I wouldn't have found one because there aren't any and all credit to the people at the the mocha for coming up with the idea Of hey Let's just move it to a different time of year in the same building when it's not a million.
Rym: They got really lucky because I note that the entire week up until the mocha.
Rym: It was like 80 degrees Couple days.
Scott: I think it's pretty.
Scott: it was a pretty safe Safe-go plus it, you know, it wasn't as warm as it was for the last year not even close It was.
Emily: it was like incredibly pleasant weather that day.
Emily: It was nice and brisk.
Scott: It's very good.
Emily: Anyway, so in terms of my policy like every time I go to mocha It's kind of like I'm overwhelmed by the amount of things that I want to buy.
Emily: So I figured I'm gonna take out a certain amount of money.
Emily: It took out $100 and I wasn't gonna spend more than that which is a sizable sum, but I also figured you know They have a lot of publishers there.
Emily: They're indie publishers, but they're pretty big like like top shelf or vertical and stuff like that.
Emily: And so I said to myself if there's something I can get online.
Emily: I'm not gonna buy it at the festival I might buy it later online.
Emily: But it's like this this money is just set aside for any comics and special things.
Emily: I can only get here.
Scott: Well, the you know, I totally agree with that like, you know, it's obvious sort of logic that I would normally follow.
Scott: You know, it's like.
Scott: why should I buy this book from top shelf?
Scott: It's on Amazon You know like buying a funny mini comic about lumberjacks, you ain't getting that anywhere else, right?
Scott: But you know a book from a real publisher.
Scott: you can get that anytime.
Scott: The thing is the people are there if the person's there right and it's not like, you know autographs.
Scott: I don't really care so much about autographs, you know.
Scott: But it's like need to talk to.
Scott: it's like the person's there and it's like what I'm gonna go up and talk to the person.
Scott: Wrote the.
Scott: we made the book that I like and then I'm not gonna buy it, you know.
Scott: So it's like.
Scott: well, you know I can go do it's like.
Scott: I could go and buy.
Scott: I had if I could go and buy The newest dr.
Scott: McNinja volume, you know from you know, the Internet's or I could go buy it from the dr McNinja guy who's there right now and it's you know, it's to pay to co either way.
Scott: So what's the difference?
Emily: I'm gonna buy.
Rym: definitely All you have to do is you know, you talk to him and be like hey So, you know I already bought your book on to pay to go.
Emily: but that's a lie Rym, if we hadn't already bought the book, it would be terrible.
Rym: You haven't already bought it.
Rym: But if you pre-order everything or you get it on to pay to co that's true Like if you got a pre-order in.
Scott: but the point if it's like the same price, it's like what you know, who cares?
Emily: Well, it's like Hope Larson's book.
Emily: She it's sold on Amazon and everything.
Emily: But it was cool to buy it directly from her and talk to her Briefly.
Rym: the person reason I bought it from her in person was that a lot of people were saying that it's gonna sell out.
Rym: There's gonna be another print run.
Scott: That's that's also a quite frequent possibility.
Scott: Another thing is that the person who makes it.
Scott: usually when you buy it from them at the they get a lot more monies.
Scott: Then you know if you buy it on Amazon, it's like oh, yeah Amazon takes a cut
Emily: the publisher
Scott: takes a cut and the person who wrote made it got a royalty if you buy it from them At the convention, it's like they get a lot greater percentage of money.
Rym: I didn't realize that This funny feeling that several of them do not in fact pay the duly owed sales taxes.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Most likely.
Rym: Yes I have that impression.
Emily: Yeah, probably some of the mini comics.
Emily: But actually I was happy to see that the Scandinavian comics had actually expanded this year.
Scott: I think they were more like three or four years in a row.
Emily: Yeah, but I Know they had more than one table.
Emily: It started with two it started with two like two years ago and then it's gradually expanded.
Emily: and I think this year there were More comics than ever before.
Emily: and I actually a shout out to our friend Timo Because he sent us a box of comics which I've read most of them and you guys haven't so nag nag, but He sent this one.
Emily: I don't even remember the name of it But it's about these two girls who live in a cabin and it's kind of funny.
Rym: I had no idea either.
Emily: I still thought it was it was cute and there was like goofy stuff going on like somebody fart in a bottle.
Emily: But I was like, you know, I saw this is it?
Scott: well, I guess they call it a Dutch oven Right when you fart under the blanket, so is that like a Dutch bottle?
Emily: I guess so.
Emily: The point being I recognize this comic book character on one of the The Finnish comics tables postcards and I was like, oh I know this comic.
Emily: my friend sent it to me And it's really cool and I was talking to the lady and they were like really really surprised I knew it.
Emily: So I was.
Emily: I was very proud of myself.
Scott: Yay but That you coincidentally saw something.
Emily: Yeah Well, you know that I that I actually had something to talk about common knowledge with Finnish comics.
Emily: That was that was part of it.
Emily: I was like, yay.
Emily: I knew something about Finnish comics.
Scott: It's like if you're a comics person any random person who's walking around.
Scott: it's like, oh, yeah, we all know these same things.
Emily: Yeah, it was.
Emily: it was cool and I talked to like one of the guys from Sweden for a really long time.
Emily: But I felt really bad for him because most of his books got lost by UPS in international shipping.
Emily: So he he drew like this picture of him and his friend and they were all sad because we have no books.
Emily: and but he was also showing me this Quarterly publication that has all sorts of international comics in it that that the Scandinavian consulates seem to be involved in.
Rym: Because there was another situation.
Rym: apparently some of the people coming from Canada they were on a bus and the bus got stopped for customs and customs almost took all their books because they wanted to get him on some import tax that they didn't know.
Scott: shit.
Rym: and the sad story I was told was that apparently customs like made a big deal about it and delayed the bus for like an hour and Was mad.
Rym: and this huge problem.
Rym: and then they finally like they flipped through one of the books and they look disappointed like oh these Aren't professional.
Rym: and then they gave him back Sad story I'd ever heard.
Emily: that is not the ending I was expecting for that.
Emily: Oh, that's so sad.
Rym: That was incredibly heartbreaking.
Emily: I thought it was gonna end with.
Emily: oh it had porn in it or something.
Emily: because actually there's a surprising amount of like Strangely erotic comics.
Emily: not like.
Emily: they're not sexy sexy.
Rym: They're just like penis head guy In an r-crumb kind of exactly.
Emily: that's a.
Rym: that's a wonderful way to put it.
Rym: It's very like.
Scott: I don't even know if a lot of them are erotic.
Scott: They just happen that they have nakedness the way like, you know old art has no Very very weird like there's a palace coming out of this.
Scott: Is that erotic for you?
Emily: But it's it's like.
Emily: I suppose it sends it like draws a lot of depictions of genitalia.
Emily: it's it's Erotic art in the very least.
Rym: there are many many more penis related items than there were.
Scott: vagina I don't know personally.
Scott: I don't count, you know, just because something has a depiction of a of a phallus or something else You know in my book that doesn't make it erotic.
Scott: I mean is my is this day, you know, is the statue of David?
Scott: is that erotic?
Scott: It's got a penis.
Rym: So what if the David was using his penis to bop people over the head?
Scott: That would just be funny.
Rym: My mission to anyone out there is to have that.
Scott: at the mocha someone someone draw a picture of.
Scott: you know 24 hour come.
Scott: okay 24 hour comics at the mocha Like a new hot thing to do.
Scott: it's like people go to like comic stores when they're having big sales or what, you know Whatever.
Scott: There's a like a local comic event.
Scott: Yeah, they'll get some artists to show up and do a 24-hour comic at the event and then you know That's like the stick lately, but it's like I.
Emily: I picked up a handful and a lot of them were written on it.
Scott: It said, you know, this was done as a 24-hour And I think the 24-hour comic day also like the day you're supposed to do it And then all the artists who do it they keep the 24-hour comic and then they sell it.
Emily: You know over and over again like yuko does it and a handful of my art friends do it.
Emily: So yeah, it's it's like a yearly thing, but it it also.
Emily: you can do it whenever it's like the.
Scott: you know The the NaNoWriMo, it's like it's the same kind of stick but less Intensive than the NaNoWriMo.
Scott: Yeah So so the mocha I guess this year compared to last year, you know two years previous It was I think they were actually it was smaller in terms of number of tables.
Scott: The turnout in terms of you know, visitors seemed to be about the same, you know.
Scott: But the you know The number of tables was less.
Scott: in the back right corner There was actually an area with all these like tall circular tables kind of a hangout zone.
Rym: Yeah Various business cards like that.
Emily: It's like then somebody who couldn't afford a table would just put their put their business card.
Scott: I think people who had tables also put their business cards on there, you know, yeah But you know, it was just.
Scott: you know They had as they always have an area where you can put flyers at the mocha.
Scott: But you know having it back there it's like well we didn't sell enough tables to fill this space So let's fill it with this instead.
Scott: and that was you know It made a nice area.
Scott: you could just stand in and go.
Rym: ah But while the side like there were definitely I think fewer tables and everything The density of awesome was such that usually I budget like a few hours and I can walk through the whole thing see everything be Good to go.
Scott: Yeah, it was weird ever man.
Scott: I didn't like I didn't eat breakfast.
Scott: Well, I ate a little bit of breakfast.
Emily: barely I had a chunk of rims corn muffin and that's all I ate.
Scott: right because I was expecting to like go to the mocha See a whole bunch of stuff eat lunch Maybe go back for an hour and then be like, all right, whatever and be out of there like, you know mid-afternoon.
Rym: So usually usually through barely an aisle and a half
Scott: Yeah Usually you go to the mocha you see everything and then you've seen it all and then you walk around again like sort of cursor Lee and You know, it's like okay
Rym: my two hours of walking and I know I was not even halfway through like all the like all the I also wanted to see a bump through enough and I'm like, hey, how does it go?
Rym: And he's like man It's like molasses.
Scott: Yeah, so this year the quality was definitely way way way up.
Emily: yeah, actually it was funny.
Emily: I convinced one of my co-workers to go and He he was.
Emily: I'm not sure if he's so much an indie comic person He doesn't know much about comic books But he went to check it out and he was like there are a lot of illustrators there that were kind of cool and everything.
Emily: So I was happy.
Emily: I was like, maybe he'll get into it But I don't see.
Scott: you know, if you're a human being who enjoys any amount of arts there is something for you.
Scott: You know, there's no reason not to go.
Scott: It's so cheap.
Scott: It's like what 10 bucks to get in 14 bucks?
Rym: Well, no, no, it's about $400 to get in because you're gonna have to buy all that stuff.
Scott: No, but you know the point way to avoid that.
Scott: the point is is it just it's cheap to get a badge?
Scott: You know you just go in it's.
Scott: you know It takes only a few hours and it's just like it's such a good time if you're anywhere within distance There's no reason not to go unless you got something better going on.
Emily: There's just a really really wide range of both the skill levels like everything from the guy who just photocopies his own stuff all the way up to like the glossy bound Hardcover books from the big publishers, but it's like what did we see we saw?
Emily: $125 enormous full-color book And stuff like that.
Emily: a bunch a bunch of artists.
Rym: there were a lot of hardcover books from very small press.
Rym: I think there's suddenly a cheap way to make hardcover.
Emily: Well must be cuz.
Emily: uh Kalman I ran into the guy who used to run.
Emily: He's like a nerdy guy who ran D&D for us freshman year of college and he's he's very loud and kind of bossy.
Emily: but he's been doing a comic with this artist from Argentina or something like that and he had a bunch of hardcover books for sale.
Emily: and I know if Kalman's still pretty indie.
Emily: So if he could afford hardcover books, I guess it's not so much of a money drain.
Rym: So things that really stood out to me in no particular at all one diary of Diaries.
Rym: the trilogy has ended three years and I'm sad to say it has come to an end.
Rym: But the quote from the.
Rym: I'm gonna read the quote from the last page because it sums up the whole epic story arc.
Rym: So in closing let me leave you with this when a hard winds a-blowing take heed and realize the storm she's a-coming.
Scott: So, let's see, what else is it?
Scott: Oh the like the SVA and the Center for cartoon studies.
Scott: So many tables of people who are from one of those two schools Might have even been approaching like 25 or even maybe maximum like 35 percent of the table.
Emily: Of course, there are people from those places who reasons I think that this is is one SBA is really close.
Scott: So it's like you have a Center for cartoon studies in Vermont and they had a whole row of tables in the back.
Emily: Very true, but like SVA has always been there.
Emily: Like I remember the first Yeah, the first time I went to the mocha they had just the one table.
Emily: like SVA take her free compilation of student work and this is really cool, but it's like You know people who weren't necessarily affiliated with the SVA table, but were SVA students.
Emily: there were a ton of folks like that mmm and Late lately.
Emily: I've just been like Oh SVA.
Emily: Why are you so good?
Scott: There must I wonder like.
Scott: maybe if like even someone who has no arts whatsoever goes to that school Like they just turn you into awesome arts How much does it cost to go there?
Emily: Lots of money.
Emily: It's a private school.
Emily: Not as much as NYU But not as well, I mean RIT is a private school.
Scott: Is it the same as RIT?
Emily: I actually don't know what tuition for SVA costs, but they do have really good programs and I don't know.
Emily: It's it's fairly difficult to get in.
Emily: I think you have to have a decent portfolio If you're trying to get into art school In in place of an application essay and often in addition to the application I say you have to submit a portfolio and that's
Scott: that's not like already college graduate and I'm old I don't know the high school anymore.
Scott: I still have to do that.
Emily: You can look on the SVA website and see if you'd get accepted to one of their Anymore going back to college like FAFSA.
Rym: I gotta find one of those things.
Emily: It would be like that song from Avenue Q.
Rym: So I bought this for our friend Scott Johnson, you know He's.
Rym: he's a politician like for real and he's really into politics independent of that.
Rym: and he said I can't come to the mocha.
Rym: I have something important that I can't skip.
Rym: Rym buy me Anything that you know, I would like.
Rym: and I found a guy who was selling.
Rym: He has series one which I bought for Scott Johnson of black conservative trading cards Got some Clarence Thomas some Michael Steele Alan Keyes Condoleezza Rice.
Rym: He's silkscreen these things.
Rym: They're pretty high quality.
Scott: Yeah, I know silkscreening is really popular.
Scott: I bought this really awesome silkscreen motorcycle poster thing.
Scott: They were only like 60 something of them, but the guy silkscreen all of them by hand.
Rym: This is four color silkscreening - which is not easy to do.
Rym: I suppose you have a fancy machine.
Emily: was that from the table with the cute girl whom whose brother made pixel art?
Scott: Yeah in the back left.
Emily: Yeah, she was nice.
Rym: Although the black no that wasn't from there.
Emily: No, no, the one I got the silkscreen of the motorcycle.
Emily: I was all like art deco.
Emily: That was really cool.
Rym: A couple of people went to buy that thing because you had you showed it to him or said hey I got this thing and they were sold out.
Scott: They were like, ooh Yeah, the I don't want to spend like too much time just going over like the list of things that we got.
Rym: We'll do a separate because I got to say this really stood out.
Rym: someone wrote a play and just had it bound for sale.
Rym: That's not a comic.
Scott: he said there's a lot of stuff there.
Rym: You're the first person to even look at this.
Rym: It is called parens and when I showed it to our friend Conrad He said so what it's a play about lisp Nerds left.
Rym: Yes, no one else did.
Rym: no But I'll play it.
Rym: actually I'm excited about this.
Rym: and the other non-comic.
Rym: that was kind of strange.
Rym: Scott Bateman took a public domain Horrible movie took just the audio from it and just Animated a movie using that as the audio track and I bought the DVD.
Rym: It's an hour and ten minutes long and it says on the box 2009 71 minutes color mono Aspect ratio 133 bad acting.
Scott: Yeah, that's one of the warnings You know, what's really interesting is that last year right Randall Monroe had like the big-ass line, you know, but this year He wasn't there, you know who had the biggest line.
Scott: He'd beaten had this gigantic line.
Scott: It was known as the beaten path Joke stealer.
Scott: you stole it from someone else.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: In fact, you stole it from the guy who runs the mocha, right?
Rym: I think he was either the head of the mocha mocha or the head of logistics.
Scott: It was like the festival He had.
Scott: I had a fancy festival director Yeah, but it was funny.
Rym: cuz we're standing in line to see Kate beaten and I hear the guy behind me.
Rym: You know Scott and Emily and the rest of the crew.
Rym: They're all talking.
Rym: I'm kind of half listening and he says well, I guess we're on the beaten path and his friends all left.
Rym: So I just turned to Scott Emily and I said, well, I guess we're on the beaten path We hadn't heard.
Emily: so we are like.
Rym: I was like, I just totally stole your joke and he made all that laugh.
Rym: and then they laughed.
Rym: Yes, it was a good joke For you.
Rym: Yeah, I should have told it to keep beating.
Scott: Yeah, it was still.
Scott: it was really interesting to see that she had this gigantic line.
Scott: I mean she was there last year, but we didn't see her like.
Scott: we showed up But we noticed oh, this is her table and she wasn't there at the time and we never tried to see her again.
Scott: But it was just like wow that you know, it's like I knew that you know She's pretty popular and her stuff is high-quality, but I didn't realize she was that popular.
Scott: I know that that were that many, you know, like.
Scott: more so like dr.
Scott: Meningin dude is sitting there.
Scott: He's got like a person coming up to him every, you know, a few seconds or whatever, but he doesn't have a line.
Scott: You know Wonder Marks in between Kate beaten and dr.
Scott: Meningin guy.
Scott: What's it?
Scott: What's that guy's name?
Scott: Chris Hastings, I think And you know, so Dave Malki's the Wonder Mark guy.
Scott: he's got people coming up once in a while just chillin doing his thing.
Scott: He's there every year, right?
Scott: We discovered him because of the mocha in fact You know and he's got someone coming up every once in a while and then Kate beaten is there with his mob.
Emily: Yeah, it's like really which is kind of awesome because you figure only a couple years ago She started out on live journal and it was one of those instances where there was no real self-promotion or anything.
Emily: It's just kind of got mimetic Lee traded around and everybody.
Emily: Oh my god You gotta check these comics out.
Emily: They're hilarious.
Scott: I think it's the same phenomenon as xkcd, right?
Scott: It's like, you know your art which kind of art style you don't have, you know have or don't have It doesn't really matter.
Scott: as long as it's you know, it's good and your writing is really.
Scott: what is the winner?
Emily: Different?
Scott: not that you know, her arts is amazing.
Scott: That's you know, but that's besides the point.
Scott: It's like the style of the art really complements the kinds of job But it's like look, you know like the penny arcade art style can do just as well as the key beaten art style It does.
Scott: you can do any style as long as your style You know the stick figure art style of xkcd.
Scott: any style is good on the internets as long as you know You do it.
Scott: Well and your writing has to be there, you know Itself from the pack.
Scott: There are plenty of webcomics out there though that have like amazing like holy shit arts Like.
Scott: they look like art books, but no one reads them and they don't have big lines at the conventions because the writing is not You know world-changing, you know as it is with the three comics.
Scott: I've just mentioned and others.
Emily: so One of the tables I spent the most money at was Lucy measly's table.
Emily: I think that's how you say your name, but Actually way back at the first mocha I went to I bought this funny little comic where a girl was talking to an apple and a snowman and a refrigerator.
Emily: It was really quirky and cute and I really liked the style.
Emily: and then the next year I saw her again.
Emily: I was like, oh, yeah I bought your comic and I bought.
Emily: she had a CD of ukulele songs and they were.
Emily: they were really cute and happy and sometimes I would listen to them while I was doing chores and stuff.
Emily: And so it was weird because pre-mocha Rym and Scott and I had gone to see the RIT hockey game at a sports bar.
Emily: It was like an RIT alumni event and the car.
Emily: I know it was so sad But the comic store was right next door.
Emily: And so I was like, come on guys before we go to the subway Let's go comics.
Emily: and they were all like no, but they were doing some sort of event there.
Emily: It was like a woman in comics event And she was there.
Emily: I was like, oh I remember you from the mocha Are you gonna be there?
Emily: and then I ran into her again at drink and draw like a lady and then again at the mocha.
Emily: So I was like, oh, I've totally got to buy your books.
Emily: So I got two.
Emily: I got one that was a collection of all her old like Journal comics and stuff called radiator days and that one was really good.
Emily: There was like a very wide range of subject matter and styles in it And it was.
Emily: it was kind of a bummer though Because it was something I would totally give to my mom except that there were like three pages of porn Right smack dab in the middle of the book.
Emily: So it's like Situation really.
Emily: it was like they were all individual stories.
Emily: It's just one or two of the stories happened to be rated X, you know, and so it was like Give this to all sorts of people, but there's a little bit of porn it.
Scott: How about that?
Emily: So you have to be okay with that sci-fi yaoi.
Emily: Oh, I haven't read it yet You know, I picked up a card from it, but I was like sci-fi plus yaoi.
Emily: Maybe this will be a good webcomic, but the art looked.
Emily: the art looked very good.
Emily: So I was like if if I am gonna read a yaoi That looked like the kind of yaoi that would be interesting to me because it looked like a sci-fi story with plot and good art.
Scott: So I was like, hey You know if it was just sci-fi, I would read it.
Emily: Why?
Emily: why does yaoi stop you from reading it Scott?
Scott: Why would I want to read?
Scott: Yeah, but what if it's a really good story?
Emily: What if it's okay?
Emily: What if it's not?
Scott: yaoi is like definition?
Emily: I know I was going Going and explaining but say it's not yaoi.
Emily: say it's it's a homoerotic Sci-fi story.
Emily: would would you not read it?
Scott: Isn't that sanctuary?
Scott: Sanctuary is incredibly homoerotic.
Scott: It's definitely a work of fiction because politics is never that awesome.
Emily: Anyway, but I might give that a look and see.
Emily: see how good it is.
Scott: So, you know what was interesting is I just realized, you know It was missing something that we've been checking out at the mocha for like two or three years in a row that dude who did the story about like the Chinese dude and Oh, yeah Poser that one.
Scott: and then the year at same guy last year He did the the one with the animals, you know that escaped from like the circus or whatever.
Rym: Yeah, I didn't see him.
Scott: yeah, he wasn't there.
Scott: and Also vegetables guy the cute vegetables guy wasn't there either.
Scott: his comic was great.
Rym: Yeah, I love that cuz it was actual cooking stuff.
Scott: yeah, but the What was interesting though?
Scott: Is that Lamar Abrams right?
Scott: the remake guy who did it was pretty much Astro Boy the Jerk?
Rym: So I was like the sleeper hit like so yeah everyone cool loves it no one else knows about.
Scott: yeah So he wasn't like.
Scott: I didn't see his.
Scott: he didn't have a table or if he did I didn't see it.
Scott: But then when we finally got to the front of the beaten path He'd be you know, he comes up and K beans like oh you check out this guy's work.
Scott: I'm like, oh you mean the bar Abrams working?
Scott: Yeah, it's like, you know.
Scott: and Rym has a little remake pin like on his little, you know, I showed him.
Rym: he's like.
Scott: That's my pin.
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Scott: yeah, it's like.
Scott: we know who this guy is.
Scott: You don't tell us what's what's going on.
Rym: Yeah, we gotta talk.
Emily: shit up keep beaten.
Scott: Do you think we are?
Scott: you don't know us you don't know us.
Emily: There was also pirate that's right.
Emily: there were also a number of tables with really really cheap comics like There was one and he was just like buy a comic and we're like, uh, we're looking.
Emily: we're looking.
Emily: he's like it's 50 cents.
Emily: Put it in mr.
Emily: T's head.
Scott: Yeah, they had any kind of bank.
Scott: They had a big plastic.
Scott: Ma, you know bust of mr T his head and you would put quarters in his top of his head and you could take any comic For these 50 cents and the.
Emily: I could you say no, even if the comic is bad I know and it was just 50 cents.
Emily: You get a pretty decent mini comic.
Emily: I got one called crazy lady.
Scott: That was a good one.
Scott: I read that it was really good Jews not nearly as good really I didn't I?
Emily: the title made you choose it though.
Emily: Yeah, you had to get that one.
Rym: But crazy lady was actually pretty damn good.
Emily: Yeah, it's just basically the story about.
Emily: you know The the strange people that populate a neighborhood and this guy observing this lady who owes weights at the bus stop.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Emily: So there was also baba luba.
Emily: That was a good one too little tiny mini comic like tiny in size about This.
Emily: it's based on this lady's Russian grandma and she's very foul-mouthed.
Emily: It's like she reprimands pussies and tulips.
Rym: No bad catch About a couple of those little things like a bored angel.
Rym: It's just a bored angel for a few pages.
Emily: Yeah, they're just tiny tiny comics with no real plot.
Rym: It's just you know funny little picture lumberjacks which came with a felt beard in it.
Scott: It's always funny how like the prices can like vary between Tables like there's no like standard price for a mini comic and it's almost like.
Scott: you know You'll see something like way awesome Like.
Scott: I bought this one way awesome thing called hobby and it's just the art style of it is like totally sweet.
Scott: But it's it, you know, it's a it's a relatively mini comic.
Scott: It's not the ultra mini It's just sort of like, you know, the digest dish size and it's only like ten or so pages But it's full color and it's really hard paper.
Scott: and the guy was like seven bucks and I was like, ah, really?
Scott: But I bought it anyway, but you know, it's like the other dude is like 50 cents for this, you know more You know for crazy lady, it's like come on.
Rym: but those are the things I really look for.
Rym: because the stuff that like someone hand-bound themselves and stapled together and that they clearly Printed it at a Kinko's equivalent.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, because that's the stuff you're never gonna find anywhere else except at the mocha.
Emily: That's so is exciting.
Emily: and I I have to mention here's another one which the art wasn't all that great But for the price it got us like a great amount of laughs which was like poor poor angsty Hungarian and the poor poor angsty Hungarian.
Emily: was this story about this prince who gets Chased out of the castle?
Emily: it there's.
Emily: basically it was just random and it was weird and it would be like and that's Weathers whales in Lake, Ontario and and it's like aren't?
Emily: I know?
Emily: That's the whole point.
Emily: It was just random.
Emily: shit would happen.
Emily: and there was like the Hungarian prince and the Moldovan prince and they go around and have these inference.
Emily: Are you yeah.
Emily: Oh, no, then you should be vegetarian.
Emily: You needed to have soy and and stuff.
Emily: Anyway, it was just weird and just completely batshit random.
Emily: and so Nury and I were reading this.
Emily: You know, I bought this.
Emily: you have to read it Nury and she starts reading it and flip it and then she starts laughing and Laughing.
Emily: and so I think for the price paid that was that was well worth the money.
Scott: It's definitely, you know, you go around you look at these indie comics You're like, you know These are not like the professional high-quality amazing entertainment package that you would get, you know from pretty much anything.
Scott: That's actually in a comic book store, right?
Scott: But in terms of like the price per entertainment like the value, you know of what you're getting is like So much higher, you know for like 50 cents.
Scott: You can get something like crazy lady, you know.
Scott: Or for a couple dollars you can get like, you know, friggin lumberjacks or actually that one little funky beer That one 24-hour comic.
Emily: I bought Catan the spider, which was actually what I think I kind of agree with you because it was it was very different and the art was very sketchy But actually what it portrayed was very imaginative and I liked little dragons, too.
Emily: I suppose I was swayed by that.
Emily: little dentists little dentists little.
Scott: so are we gonna?
Scott: are we pretty much gonna wrap this up?
Rym: We'll cut from here to a Various cavalcade of interviews and audio from the mocha floor and at some point in the near ish future We'll try to get up a video of the kind of unboxing and reviewing.
Scott: Yeah We'll do some sort of Scott's box ish kind of like mocha edition where we display the the hall Haul of what all the stuff that we got the hall from the hall mocha hall.
Scott: Yay I'm Steven vratos.
Rym: I work for fanfare
Scott: opponent Mon publishing
Emily: much like Japan,
Rym: which is
Scott: one of our better-selling books
Rym: Which
Emily: is a short story collection 17
Rym: creators talking about their views in Japan.
Emily: Korea will be coming out.
Emily: we'll probably have advanced copy of San Diego comic-con and it's 12 different creators on their perception of Korea and It's a really wonderful book.
Emily: We're pretty happy.
Rym: fanfare fanfare has seven seven nominations for Eisner's this season.
Emily: so yeah, you know and Part of like.
Rym: why can't this?
Scott: the comic I buy look like that, you know part of being the artist you it's like you gotta You learn each time you get your thing printed.
Scott: But you got to learn what works and what doesn't.
Scott: what reproduces.
Rym: well on what doesn't you know as an artist?
Scott: I get really into like some of the dry brush But some of the more subtle dry brushing doesn't show up very well.
Emily: so you still
Scott: have to have your your pretty bold areas
Rym: of dark and light and You learn.
Rym: you learn what works and what doesn't.
Rym: yeah That's part of this is part of being a comic artist because you're not.
Rym: you're not doing it to display the originals You're doing it to be reproduced.
Rym: Part of the deal.
Rym: comics look like that.
Rym: Well, maybe for web comics you can do I guess you could.
Rym: But even then it's like people's screens.
Scott: like, you know, some people's screens can't display all the colors So they don't have a lot of.
Scott: it's just basic design, too.
Emily: Okay, basically a lot of the words A lot of it is just basic design to you because even even if you have the highest resolution image you could possibly do It doesn't really matter.
Emily: your eye can only take so much.
Emily: your eye wants to have areas to rest and wants areas for it to be led.
Scott: so If everything's is pretty detailed, but it's all the same tone.
Rym: It's just not going to work.
Scott: You need these areas of simplification even if it's an incredibly high resolution and high detail piece.
Scott: So you always have to keep that in mind, especially in comic pages because so much is going on In individual panels, you still have to think of it as a whole thing.
Rym: So larger, you know, it does well to officially just sell the like.
Scott: here's the ultra edition at the hellboy stuff and those be.
Scott: Yeah, I. but the thing is though, like I love the small format.
Scott: I really do like.
Scott: I really do like small Like Comic guys, you know You know traditional comic fans miss that bigger or even the really bigger formats.
Scott: You know like Alex Ross did those really big?
Rym: Those big superhero comics and I was like, uh, they look good.
Emily: They look good obviously for painting like that But they're so in money.
Scott: Yeah, I just would rather have a little book, you know read on the subway or whatever.
Scott: That's you?
Rym: Definitely You gotta tell me about this.
Rym: So tell us a little bit about this movie.
Rym: The movie is called Adam age vampire.
Scott: I took the sound from a really old science fiction movie also called Adam age vampire.
Rym: It's very bad.
Scott: took the sound and animated a new movie to it.
Scott: Hopefully there will be no more poop.
Emily: Yes, that's that's the hopes and the dreams of my.
Scott: no I wanted to do with three.
Scott: I wanted to be a trilogy from the beginning.
Scott: Yeah, I'm a regular George Lucas.
Rym: My name is Allison Braun and my comic is psychoanalytic and it's a photo collage comic.
Rym: and it's not your typical photo collage because I did a lot of printmaking and all the backgrounds and
Scott: Basically what it is is I had a journal for like the last Ten years and I decided
Rym: to make it
Emily: into a comic and the journal is basically just me ranting which basically, the girl is Trying.
Emily: the girl in the comic is trying to just find her path and figure out her place in the world And that's that's pretty much what it's about.
Emily: My name is Ross wood Stoodler.
Rym: my new comic book is the Raven and the crayfish and It was inspired by Native American legends about Crater Lake national about Crater Lake National Park the area and a Monstrous crayfish that who is guardian of the lake.
Emily: and it's an original tale featuring what happens when the mischievous Raven Tries to claim the lake and has to reckon with the crayfish.
Scott: and you can find more of my work at Ross wood Stoodler blogspot.com.
Scott: Stoodler is spelled s t u d l a r. Yeah.
Scott: My name is Matthew Lux and I am the artist and writer for the only press series of all ages books saltwater taffy.
Scott: Which three volumes are available right now?
Emily: It's generally a story
Scott: about two brothers that are on a summer-long vacation in a mysterious
Rym: Seaside
Emily: town in Maine called Chowder Bay and it's about all the adventures
Rym: they get into involving This is really interesting folklore including sea monsters
Scott: Treasure
Rym: hunts and
Emily: ghost stories
Scott: and a lot of just
Rym: a quirky
Scott: characters that they
Rym: run into
Scott: in these Mysteries and adventures and it's a really fun series to read and it's a fun series
Rym: to work on.
Rym: So who should read saltwater taffy?
Scott: I think everyone should read it because When I say they're all ages it really I really did write it so that really anyone can enjoy the adventure.
Rym: I would say it probably starts at like age 8 and go and up.
Rym: But but I think that anyone can get something out of it.
Rym: Definitely Did you watch everything that the blockbuster had including the bad stuff like Armageddon and Doom Megalopolis?
Emily: No, no, I saw Doom Megalopolis on TV once though I had like a weird antenna channel and it just came in and I saw I think there's a scene where the guy was like Fish or something like that.
Emily: I was like 13 years old and I was like So it was.
Emily: it was kind of shocking but and then I that's actually how I got started reading comics too.
Rym: It's because I love beautiful dreamer so much.
Rym: I went to the comic book store.
Rym: I was like find this for me and they happen to have.
Rym: They were calling it like return of the bomb or something.
Rym: That's when they were coming out on monthly issues and I went in every month and I would just pick it up.
Rym: I was like, I don't know who half these people are.
Rym: They're not in the movie.
Rym: I was like, why is she calling?
Rym: That's weird But it was just all downhill from there.
Emily: And so when I saw that tour to Uniqlo, I was like, yes That's right here.
Emily: Like lung was my screen name on AOL back in like 95 or something like that.
Emily: So Sure sure, I do a comic called winters in Lavelle.
Scott: It's a fantasy adventure book for Young adults actually do it as a webcomic twice a week online.
Emily: It's it's about like a brother and a sister who gets stuck in another world.
Rym: It's like kind of like Narnia, but with teenagers.
Rym: so you get like a lot of like teenage fighting and stuff like that, too.
Rym: so But it's it's I'm trying to do the kind of stuff that I liked when I was a teenager Like I loved like magic pack rare and stuff like that.
Rym: So that's that's what I'm going for.
Rym: It's like I want to do that again.
Rym: Did you watch the dub or the sub with the subtitles all the way?
Scott: Openers in English with Sandy Fox.
Emily: Yeah, I remember that.
Emily: no, I'd actually been watching it at my anime club at that point.
Emily: so I was like school And that was how I got into it.
Scott: I was like the only person there who was in the target demographic for rare.
Scott: that was like 13 or 14 and I was like oh my god, and Everybody else there was like.
Scott: it's like older dudes who like sci-fi stuff, but like thinking back on it.
Scott: I think they just showed it for me.
Scott: They were like, all right, she sits through Gundam.
Emily: Let's throw her away.
Scott: So and then it just like it just kind of made me want to do my own comics from that.
Scott: So it was like things like that really are kind of what got me started.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: My name is Casey van Hise.
Emily: My webcomic is winters in the Lavelle.
Rym: It's winters in Lavelle.
Rym: calm.
Rym: Patrick McQuade the artist of shapes the new brethren.
Scott: Steve Solis the namer of shapes the new brethren.
Rym: So what's going on here?
Rym: What does this you guys do?
Rym: well, what started in high school chemistry class back in the fall of 1994 has Evolved to the new brethren.
Rym: we did about 400 shapes in high school.
Rym: What happens is Steve You know in the back of ditto paper or whatever Withdraw a bunch of abstract shapes and then he would pass them off to me and I would create a character You know inside or inspired by that shape.
Rym: then I would pass it back to Steve and he would give that character a name.
Rym: So again, we did about 400 in high school and it kind of stopped.
Rym: and then in 2005 We reconnected via email and and via the posted postal service and you know, we did a whole new a new new batch and then And then the new brethren.
Rym: in the last six months we've done 34 new characters and Yeah, they are the new brethren and We have characters like Ramburger the Chancellor Stag, Willy and the Fronion man.
Rym: And the book is kind of like a whole shows all history and evolution of the process and documents the whole The whole.
Rym: you know the whole deal.
Scott: So yeah I Discovered my passion for cartooning right after 9/11.
Rym: as a turban and a bearded man.
Rym: a Lot of people know didn't know who six are.
Scott: so I was really a target of a lot of hate crimes.
Scott: but one thing that inspired me is a couple of cartoonists who actually Sketched six into their cartoons showing them as victims of hate crimes and I said, hey, that's interesting Maybe you know, there should be more cartoons about six.
Rym: So that's how it got started and that was almost eight years ago, and I came up with the idea of sick tunes Cartoon sick tunes and I basically take news items from around the world relating to six and Create a single usually single panel cartoons.
Scott: so a lot of the stuff you see here is from the last eight years this piece the I Call this the American turban chronicles collection and it's kind of like my experience and a lot of other people who wear turbans with a lot of it comes from ignorance.
Scott: people don't know who.
Scott: People presume that everybody who wears a turban is Arab or Muslim, which is not true.
Rym: So this is my way of Also looking within our own community and making people think about our shortcomings and those kind of things.
Rym: So this is it looks like your first time at the mocha.
Rym: Yeah, are you having a good time?
Rym: Do you think the response is good?
Rym: I mean the response is great.
Rym: People are coming in and you know, they they haven't seen Turbans and beards in cartoons.
Emily: So they're really.
Rym: they're kind of you know, they're really coming in and they're like wow I mean, so yeah, it's been a great response.
Rym: Plus I'm getting to see a lot of other people's work and it's quite amazing.
Rym: Vishwajit Singh Sick tunes calm.
Rym: My name is Morgan P L e and my website is Morgan writes a book calm and I do a quarterly Sci-fi anthology called indestructible universe quarterly which can be found on.
Rym: Morgan writes a book calm to buy and I also have a webcomic called driftwood, which is a horror comic and That's it.
Emily: Morgan writes a book calm over the rare bits comics collective and there's three of us.
Emily: I'm Jen Vaughn There's Sam car ba and Jason week.
Rym: We're all friends and cartoonists who have attended or are attending the Center for cartoon studies in the White River Junction, Vermont.
Emily: Yeah, just about this whole row is all CCS kids and we all decided that we wanted to Control our own destinies with the webcomic and have a you know Instantaneous access to readers in a way that print comics sometimes takes longer to do.
Emily: So that's sort of the reason we all did this.
Rym: Yeah, I mean you get back right away you start you can get it out to people and get responses for it.
Rym: So it's really gratifying Like I've got a couple people who actually follow the comic and email me and I just care about it.
Emily: So it keeps you moving forward because it feels like people are enjoying your work, which I mean Kind of what I like about it.
Emily: It seems to be the way that print media could be going.
Emily: is that you uh You have a webcomic.
Emily: you can actually prove to editors and publishers how many readers you have using Google Analytics And then they'll be like, I guess we could print you.
Emily: I mean, we love you.
Emily: We love your stuff, too And we also like to hang out and drink together.
Rym: So it was a good way to also be productive.
Rym: So it all works out.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So when we have a group website to where we do Just random posts and whatnot for fun Let's just do illustrations that just kind of close steam off And you don't have to worry about it being in continuity or the character models matching.
Rym: or you know I want to draw the Autobot symbol crying tears.
Emily: So Sam does.
Emily: here comes everyone.
Emily: It's at Sam Carball comm its intellectual political humor.
Emily: That takes place usually at a coffee shop.
Emily: and then I I make mermaid hostel.
Emily: at mermaid hostel calm.
Emily: It's exactly what it sounds like a bunch of mermaids in a hostile situation with the many mysteries and ill-fated troubles that come across.
Emily: Yes I do Billy the dunce.
Rym: It's basically just child geniuses running amok doing whatever I want to so I can tell the science fiction or Fantasy story or whatever that we it's available at Billy the dunce calm or dunce press.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.