Scott: It's Thursday, July 1st.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Scott: I'm Rynn.
Scott: And this is GeekNights.
Scott: Tonight, non-Legos.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So Scott, you want to start with the fireworks or the bed wedding?
Scott: Why did you?
Rym: If you weren't going to say it, I was going to say it.
Rym: I mean, our listeners, they don't get the five seconds before I hit record.
Scott: They're not supposed to.
Scott: That's why it's before.
Scott: We have to come before.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: That's what your mom said.
Scott: So I'm laying in this bed doing the show or getting ready to do the show.
Rym: And now I got to take the futon out.
Scott: Now the bed's wet because I had a water bottle with water and some of it dripped out onto the bed.
Rym: I call mine the young master water bottle.
Rym: That's not water.
Scott: Well, it's not a euphemism.
Scott: It's literally.
Scott: I had the water bottle with actual water in it.
Scott: And it, you know, when I was done drinking, I fell over it.
Rym: So apparently there were fireworks last night.
Scott: Well, yeah.
Scott: So I'm sitting in my bedroom working on something, which is actually getting scarily close to reality.
Scott: It's actually the first thing I've done that might make money.
Scott: It'll make at least a dollar and has a potential of infinity dollars, as does everything.
Rym: I'm not sure which thing you're talking about.
Scott: Yeah, because it doesn't involve you at all.
Rym: At all?
Scott: Really?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So it's not a Dorf or anything?
Rym: No.
Scott: It's basically the only thing delaying the return of Dorf.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: That's fine.
Rym: We got to make that video.
Scott: So I'm working and I'm actually on a roll.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And suddenly I hear this noise outside and it sounds like some jerk is like revving his fucking engine.
Scott: I don't have an alley.
Scott: You know, it's actually a road, but it's not.
Scott: It's a less main road, which is why it's a road and not a street.
Scott: Right.
Scott: If it's a street, that's like a street.
Rym: Well, that depends on where.
Rym: I mean, right here we got streets, avenues, roads, lanes, and they all have the same numbers.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, yeah.
Rym: It literally goes 44th road, 44th street, 44th avenue.
Scott: Well, the streets in Queens, at least in our area of Queens, the streets go up and down and they're real important.
Scott: The avenues go east and west over here, which is the opposite of Manhattan.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And they're still pretty important.
Scott: And the roads also go east and west, but they're in between the avenues and they're less, they're less important than the, uh, than the avenues are.
Scott: So the road behind my, you know.
Rym: Yeah, but what about, cause Verde or Northern Boulevard is like the biggest road right here.
Scott: That's a little out though.
Rym: That's a Boulevard.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Boulevard, boulevards are serious.
Scott: Anything that's different is serious business.
Scott: Like Union Turnpike, serious business.
Scott: Cause it's not, you know, it's a Turnpike.
Scott: It's like, Oh, fuck me.
Scott: Right.
Rym: I remember as a kid, I was confused as to what Turnpike meant when I was really young.
Rym: Cause like the only time I'd ever heard the word was in the context of a ride at Cedar Point called the Turnpike, which it was made in the fifties.
Rym: and you drove fifties looking gasoline cars around a track.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: So I hear this noise out there.
Scott: It sounds like a dude revving his engine and it's slightly disturbing, but it goes away.
Scott: and no, it doesn't go away.
Scott: It sticks around and it keeps bothering me.
Scott: And I'm like, what the fuck, dude, your car is working.
Scott: What the fuck?
Scott: And it doesn't even sound like a ricer.
Scott: It sounds like some old shitty broken car with no muffler.
Scott: And I'm like, Oh, fuck you.
Scott: So then I go out onto the balcony and I'm going to just yell, shut the fuck up or something like that.
Rym: Right.
Rym: That's what you do.
Scott: And when I'm out in the balcony, suddenly it doesn't sound the same anymore.
Scott: It sounds like thunder or perhaps thunder or perhaps cannons.
Scott: And it does lights like flashing.
Scott: I can't see around the corner of my balcony.
Scott: So there's some flashing going on.
Rym: So, so my question is at this exact moment, did you suspect fireworks first or were you still confused?
Scott: Well, I was, I knew it was equally one of three things.
Scott: Either lightning was around the corner where I, uh, there was bombs around the corner, I guess possible or fireworks around the corner.
Scott: And so I go to the roof, which is on fire.
Scott: No, it wasn't.
Scott: Sadly.
Scott: Anyway, I go to the roof and there's like four or five neighbors already chilling up there and there's some firework action.
Scott: And I'm like, Oh, come on.
Scott: Seriously.
Scott: It's like, you can't hold it in until Sunday.
Scott: Are you like testing it or something?
Scott: Testing the launch tubes?
Scott: or are you fucking like getting rid of some extras?
Scott: or what the hell are you doing guys?
Rym: Might've been a different festival.
Rym: Where were they?
Rym: Over the river.
Scott: It was out on the river.
Scott: So they must've been testing, right?
Scott: Or getting rid of some excess or something.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: But yeah, those fuckers.
Rym: I'll tell you about the karaoke guy that I had to dispatch.
Rym: So, you know, we have in the fancy like big building and we're in the bedroom and it's really late.
Rym: It's like two in the fucking morning.
Rym: All right.
Rym: And there's this guy and it doesn't bother me during the day because I don't hear it during the day.
Rym: And even if I'm home, like I wouldn't be in the bedroom, but because the bathrooms like are connected to this positive air pressure thing.
Scott: Yeah, you could, I can, I have that same problem.
Scott: If you're in like my kitchen, this event or in my bathroom, this event, and I can hear like adjacent people through the vents.
Scott: But if I, you know, close the bathroom door or, and I'm, you know, not right in the kitchen, I can't hear it.
Rym: See, we can't hear adjacent.
Rym: We can only hear up down and only in the- Yeah, it's up down adjacent.
Scott: It's not left right adjacent.
Rym: But only in some of the bathrooms because not all the apartments have two bathrooms.
Rym: Ah.
Rym: So the second bathroom, which is connected to the bedroom, there's a dude who lives above us who sings karaoke in Korean terribly.
Scott: Like, how can he even, is he playing, maybe he's playing Korean rock band or something.
Rym: He might be, but it's only him.
Rym: I never hear anyone else.
Rym: And he sings the same fucking songs.
Scott: You sure he's not singing in the shower?
Rym: No, he's definitely not because he's got a stereo going.
Rym: He sings the same fucking songs over and over and over again forever, which is fine because I usually don't run into it.
Rym: Like I'll go to pee and I hear it and I'm like, wow, that guy really sucks.
Scott: Dude, you should record him and put him on the internet.
Rym: One time I just started singing back at him.
Rym: I was like, I didn't, and he stopped singing and then the singing went away for a while.
Rym: I think at that moment he realized people could hear him.
Scott: Maybe.
Rym: But you seem to have forgotten that because we're like two in the morning and he's singing.
Scott: Two in the morning?
Scott: Louder and louder and louder.
Scott: He must have been drunk.
Rym: And louder.
Scott: That's why.
Rym: So finally I just get up and I go into the bathroom.
Rym: I stand on the toilet.
Scott: You could hear him in your bed all the way from the bathroom?
Rym: Yes, with the bathroom door shut.
Scott: Whoa.
Rym: So I go in there and I listen for a bit.
Rym: I'm like, dude, it's fucking two in the morning.
Rym: Shut up.
Rym: And he stops and the music keeps playing like the music, but he's not singing.
Rym: And it's quiet for like a few minutes and then the song stops and then another song starts and then he starts to sing again.
Rym: So I was like, what did I just say?
Rym: And then I hear like a scrambling, scramble, scramble and the music stops, dead silence the rest of the night.
Scott: You should find out who it is and go to the doorman.
Rym: I know who it is.
Rym: It's the apartment directly above me.
Scott: Oh, well then you can go knock on his door.
Rym: Yeah, if it happens again, I feel like I should just record it for a while and then just leave like a USB stick with MP3s of him singing like under his door.
Scott: No, you should do is you should go up there, right?
Rym: Well clearly, Scott, the USB stick is also a virus.
Scott: No, what you do, you ready for this?
Scott: This is the guaranteed win.
Scott: You ready?
Scott: I'm a genius.
Rym: I've got a couple ideas.
Scott: Now there will be demonstration of my genius.
Scott: Are you ready?
Scott: You go and you knock on his door.
Scott: He opens the door.
Scott: Vuvuzela in the face.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: Done.
Rym: Why not just play the vuvuzela through the vent?
Scott: Because it'd be so much louder if it's just right in his face.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I kind of like the singing back at him as loud as I can.
Scott: Vuvuzela is made of wind.
Scott: Vuvuzela.
Scott: Anyway, all right, let's check some news out.
Rym: You have some news?
Rym: It's Thursday.
Scott: Yeah, there's basically, there is nothing happening in the world.
Rym: There's tons happening, just nothing.
Rym: I have a lot to say.
Rym: All right, there's news about homeopathy.
Rym: I'm going to say the same thing.
Scott: It's not a big deal news.
Rym: There's news about like a kid getting arrested because he made a bomb out of dry ice.
Scott: Not a big news.
Rym: Well, no, it's more that all the news, all of you out there know exactly what I'm going to say about it.
Rym: The BP oil spill, you know what I'm going to say.
Rym: Politics, you know what I'm going to say.
Rym: So, I don't know, what do you have?
Scott: So there's a big steam sale going on.
Rym: What are you going to say about that?
Scott: It's basically got, no, I haven't bought any, I bought one game for $2.50.
Rym: Wait, wait, wait.
Rym: So, you have nothing to say about anything.
Rym: So instead, you say that you have nothing to say about the steam sale.
Scott: No, what I have to say about it is that it's kind of weak sauce compared to their usual sales where it's like, "Oh man, I got to buy some of
Scott: everything.".
Scott: This is sort of like, "Hey, where's the
Scott: beef?".
Scott: You know, they got wicked low prices.
Rym: Where's the beef?
Rym: That's your reference?
Rym: I don't think any of our listeners, or at least 99% of them have no idea what that is actually from.
Scott: Well, then let them go to YouTube and find out.
Rym: That was barely our generation.
Rym: That was like the beginning of our generation was the end of that.
Scott: Well, that's dumb shit for them.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: I mean, it's like they got all these games, but it's like none of them are games that are like, I sort of learned my lesson with these steam sales, that like the first time I bought all these games and I barely played them, where you buy like some huge pack
Rym: for $20.
Rym: The id Software pack was the first one I ever bought.
Scott: Yeah, you play like five of the games for a little bit, and then you hardly ever play them.
Rym: Let's see, I'm looking at the deck pack right now.
Rym: Let's see.
Rym: I never even installed Doom 3 or the sequel to Doom 3 that I got.
Scott: I definitely didn't beat Doom 3.
Rym: I never even played it.
Rym: I played like a little bit.
Rym: I didn't install Indiana Jones or Hexen or Hexen or Hexen or Heretic.
Scott: I played those back in the day.
Rym: Loom, Master Levels, Quake, Quake 2, Quake 2, Quake 2, Quake 3, Quake 3, Quake, Quake Castle Wolfenstein.
Scott: Yeah, but basically you got, you know, you get all these games, and even though it's only $2.50, right, it's like, "Hey, $2.50?
Scott: That's a fucking breakfast sandwich,
Scott: dude.".
Scott: And if I'm not actually going to play these games, I just basically took a breakfast sandwich and threw it in the trash.
Scott: So even if a game is a crazy low price, if you've played it already or if it's not something you're actually going to invest a lot of time in, it's not worth it, even when the price is wicked low.
Scott: So like look at this, they got...
Rym: Well, think about what this means.
Rym: It's the same thing, you know, I don't really want to talk about it on Thursday, but that whole ASCAP thing that's happening right now.
Scott: All right.
Rym: It's the situation that, you know, everyone thinks us nerds are always mad about piracy and we're trying to fight for the right to pirate, but even way back, all we care about is the fact that so much stuff is free and we have so many options of entertainment that piracy is nothing compared to the fact that we're just apathetic about the majority of media.
Scott: Yeah, the only reason that, you know, I think, you know, for piracy, right, is you have made something so difficult to obtain and I happen to want it now-ish, so piracy is an option.
Scott: Now bear in mind, if you had made it, you know, available for a dollar like Steam does and I could have just gone and got it, I wouldn't have pirated because that's a pain in the ass.
Rym: But at the same time...
Scott: You made it a pain in the ass.
Rym: At the same time, even when the game is a dollar, I'll sit there and I'll look at Steam and I'll be like, "Huh, that game's only a dollar.
Rym: People said the game's pretty
Rym: good.".
Rym: And I'll look at it and I'll be like, "Do I really want to pay a
Rym: dollar?".
Rym: And it's not like.
Rym: I'm going to say, "Fuck them, I'm pirating
Rym: it.".
Rym: I just don't play it.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: It's not even worth free to me, let alone a dollar.
Scott: I know, it's like, should I install that thing and take up space on my hard drive?
Scott: I mean, I have to click and wait and get some bandwidth going.
Rym: It's going to take up like 20 megs.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, if I'm not actually going to play it, why would I do that?
Rym: Wow, I guess I have Team Fortress Classic.
Scott: Well, so does everyone.
Rym: The dig!
Rym: Right, right.
Rym: Commander Keen.
Rym: God, that's not even a stall.
Scott: Why do you have the dig?
Scott: I don't have the dig.
Rym: It came with some pack I bought, I guess.
Scott: What pack did you buy?
Rym: I don't even know.
Scott: Do you have other LucasArts adventure games?
Rym: I think I have every LucasArts adventure game.
Rym: You have Monkey Island and Loom.
Rym: Yeah, I think I have all of them.
Rym: Really?
Scott: I never bought that pack.
Rym: Well, I guess I did.
Scott: I played some of those on ScummVM, though, back a year back, though.
Scott: I played Full Throttle all the way through.
Rym: I got to say, of all those games, we don't want to turn this into a Tuesday show.
Rym: Quest for Glory 2 is like...
Scott: That's not a LucasArts game.
Rym: I know, but that style of game, you know, click on stuff, type stuff, walk around, solve puzzles, that's the only one that I could actually play again, I think.
Scott: I like the later King's Quest, because you got the right click to change your cursor and then you click on things.
Rym: All the Quest for Glory's are like that, except two.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Rym: Except the Quest for Glory's are actually decent games, but the ScummVM games, this may be heresy for some of you gamers, they're not even really games.
Scott: No, they're basically...
Rym: Like, at least Quest for Glory, the puzzles were like actual puzzles, and the games were mildly open-ended.
Scott: It wasn't just crazy fucked up logic, so you get a fact, and then you basically, now that you got a fact, it's basically a movie, but because you've got a fact, you're not seeing all the alternate pathways to failure, you're only seeing the success.
Rym: Oh, we did a whole panel on that.
Scott: So a lot of the humor is out, and then, but the thing is, the failure really isn't fun, at this point in my life, because it takes a lot of time, and when I was younger, it'd still be great, and it's also no longer funny, most of it.
Rym: Yeah, well, I think part of it was, you know that game you were just playing on the iPhone where you mix things together to make other things?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: ScummVM games are the same thing, they're just a novelty generator machine, and eventually you expose all the novelty and that's it.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: They're barely games.
Scott: You can just better off watching them on YouTube than playing them.
Rym: Yeah, unless you're under the age of six, or you got nothing better to do, I guess.
Rym: Those are good games for like laptop, 12 hour plane ride, can't sleep.
Scott: Very good.
Rym: That's pretty much where I play a lot of games.
Rym: Oh, God.
Rym: So, you know, I'm going through these games, listing them right now, and you know what I see?
Rym: Civ IV, Beyond the Sword, Warlords, Civ V, because I own it, and I can't play it yet.
Scott: I didn't preorder it yet, because you know why?
Scott: It doesn't matter if I preorder it now or at the last minute, so why rush?
Scott: Maybe it'll be a dollar, maybe it'll be cheaper, you know, later.
Rym: I got something for preordering it.
Scott: Well, then again, it could be more expensive later.
Rym: Yeah, I think I got something, but I'm not sure.
Scott: Maybe I'll preorder it just because I know I'm gonna play it immediately, right?
Scott: So, why not?
Rym: I don't even remember preordering it.
Rym: It's just here.
Scott: All right, what do you got over there?
Rym: I don't really have much, actually.
Scott: All right.
Scott: I don't know, it's summer.
Scott: Heatwave's coming, maybe, that's gonna be cool.
Rym: Yeah, I'm looking forward to it.
Rym: I'm just chilling.
Scott: There's a holiday this weekend, so who knows what, oh, let's save that.
Rym: Yeah, we're having some sort of party.
Rym: What could we possibly have for the meta moment for that?
Scott: There might be a disturbance in the show next week.
Rym: All right, yeah, I guess we'll talk about that.
Scott: Because of Independence Day.
Rym: Now, I mostly got the fact that my whole hopper's been basically pushed back by preparations for Otakon and ConnectiCon and PAX and other big things that we're planning.
Scott: Yeah, they really sort of infiltrated my hopper quite a bit.
Rym: Yeah, my hopper got pushed back severely, but we've got a couple of videos coming.
Rym: I guess we're getting into meta again.
Rym: I don't know, it's Thursday, I got nothing.
Rym: I really just want to play Counter-Strike right now.
Rym: Of all the things I could do right now.
Scott: You know what I really want to do right now?
Scott: Eat dinner.
Rym: Eh, I had a big ice cream.
Scott: Oh, you know what, I'll mention one more thing, right?
Scott: So, near my office, there was this place I used to always get a breakfast sandwich from.
Scott: That's bad, don't do that.
Rym: I'm thinking about learning the song from Okadono Ken.
Scott: So, the breakfast sandwich place went out of business a while ago, and I haven't been able to find a place to get a decent breakfast sandwich near my work.
Scott: The only place is Tim Hortons, which is like, ugh.
Scott: It's like a combination Tim Hortons, KFC, Dunkin' Donuts, and Pizza Hut.
Scott: All in one, all in one.
Rym: So, I do not know if Tim Hortons and Dunkin' Donuts have changed their recipes over time.
Scott: I guess it's not a Dunkin' Donuts anymore, it used to be.
Rym: Or if it's just that I have not eaten that sort of crap food in so long that I no longer am bamboozled by it.
Rym: But I ate a Tim Hortons breakfast sandwich the other day, and it tasted like sugar.
Rym: But it wasn't a donut, it was like a sausage, egg, and cheese on an English muffin, but it tasted like sugar.
Rym: It was so sweet, I couldn't stand it.
Rym: I threw the fucking thing away.
Scott: So, across the street, there's a place called The Majestic, and you can get one there.
Scott: But it's like $7, because it's all touristy and shit.
Rym: Dude, for $7, I'm expecting some lox and like a Bialy.
Scott: I know, right?
Scott: But not even.
Scott: You get lox and a bagel with cream cheese or $5.
Scott: With the coffee, right?
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: So, there's this other place I discovered, because they had a chalkboard out on the sidewalk.
Rym: Wow, this is suddenly New York.
Scott: Yeah, the chalkboard on the sidewalk was like custom omelet, whatever.
Scott: And I noticed that during lunch one day, because basically, there's this strip where there's an everything place, then there's a Qdoba, and then there's a Pret, and then there's another everything place.
Scott: Oh, Pret sucks.
Rym: I know, I don't know, all these people in my office like the fucking Pret.
Rym: It's just like Cozy.
Rym: Like, why do people eat at these places?
Scott: I don't know why anyone eaten the sandwiches that come in a cardboard box, please.
Rym: Well, Cozy doesn't even cook their food.
Rym: You order like a hot pizza that it's not even cooked?
Scott: At least Metro Cafe is like, you know.
Rym: Thing is, I got a bunch of tweets, and people emailed me when I tweeted out like, "Yeah, fuck you Cozy.
Rym: You've crossed me for like the fifth
Rym: time.".
Rym: And they were all like, "What are you talking about?
Rym: Cozy's awesome.
Rym: Your Cozy must just
Rym: suck.".
Scott: I'd rather go to fucking...
Rym: So, listen kids, in full disclosure, it is three separate Cozy's in three separate geographic locations.
Rym: If you think Cozy's good...
Scott: You don't know what's good.
Scott: What's the place that puts the sandwiches through the toaster?
Rym: A lot of places do that.
Scott: No, the place that was in, you know, the chain.
Scott: Yeah, Quiznos is better than fucking Cozy.
Rym: Yeah, definitely.
Scott: I mean, Subway's better than fucking Cozy.
Rym: In fact, I wouldn't mind a Quiznos nearby because when I'm... You know, sometimes you get in that mood where you look at a Subway and you're like, "You know what?
Rym: Maybe I'll eat
Rym: Subway.".
Scott: There's actually this place near my work called Fresh End Co.
Rym: Oh, those places are pretty cool.
Scott: It's actually like the sandwiches they have there.
Rym: I was gonna say cool, and then I said good.
Scott: You can get a sandwich there.
Scott: that's Quiznos style, but it's like 10,000 times better.
Scott: Anyway, and it's so cheap, it's like $6.
Scott: So there's two everything places, right?
Scott: But one of the everything places is only lunch, right?
Scott: It doesn't do breakfast or dinner.
Scott: And it's better than the first everything place.
Scott: So we've never actually been to the first everything place because the second everything place is just so much better.
Scott: But the first everything place I discovered today has breakfast.
Scott: So I went to get a bacon, egg, and cheese on an English muffin.
Scott: Dude used so much egg, right?
Scott: He had egg, then he put the bacon and the cheese in the egg and folded the egg over the top.
Rym: Oh, man.
Rym: That was like an omelet sandwich.
Scott: And then he put the egg into the English muffin.
Scott: The English muffin was basically so tiny compared to the egg.
Scott: It was like I had to eat the egg around the edge.
Rym: It was basically a Gothic Lolita English muffin.
Scott: I had to eat the egg around the edge before I could actually sort of hold on to the muffin.
Scott: But it was only $3.
Scott: You know, everything places usually charge like a big markup, but it was only $3.
Scott: So I was like, hells yeah.
Rym: Not bad.
Rym: I'm still sampling.
Rym: I walk by six different breakfast sandwich places on my way to work.
Scott: You haven't tried them all yet?
Scott: No.
Scott: You've been to work more than six days.
Rym: Yeah, there's two of these places I walk past every day and I look at them, I'm like, eh.
Scott: Well, just go to one of them on Tuesday and one of them on Wednesday.
Rym: Yeah, the thing is, usually I'm either running late or like they just they don't grab me.
Rym: And I walk past them and go to a place I've already been to.
Rym: because while they're not the greatest, I know they're at least acceptable.
Scott: Well, you can, you know, just try it out.
Scott: It's not going to poison you.
Rym: Yeah, but so imagine you're in this situation.
Rym: You're really hungry and you have a choice of a place that you know is acceptable, not good, but acceptable.
Rym: Or an unknown quantity that looks a little shady.
Scott: Well, if it looks shady, I'm not going to go there no matter what.
Rym: Because if I get the equivalent of a Tim Horton sandwich, what am I going to do?
Rym: Throw it away and go to another place in the same morning?
Scott: I would just eat it and deal with it.
Rym: I'm done with that.
Rym: I've started, if something's really bad, I just throw it away.
Scott: But what if you're missing out on an awesome sandwich?
Scott: Yeah, I'm not.
Scott: That just happens to be in a shady place.
Rym: Yeah, that could be.
Scott: Because it means I went to the place I went to, the everything place that I went to and got this breakfast sandwich, is the shadiest looking everything place we have.
Rym: The place that I keep walking past has had two competitors spring up like adjacent to it.
Rym: So I have a feeling there's something going on.
Rym: So anyway, things of the day.
Scott: My computer went to sleep.
Rym: That's fine.
Rym: I'll talk about my thing of the day.
Rym: I'm a reader of Fark and I just want to point out as an aside, Drew Curtis had an interesting talk where he basically said, "You know what?
Rym: The wisdom of the crowds is bullshit.
Rym: 99% of what anyone says on the internet is terrible.
Rym: I should know.
Rym: I run
Rym: Fark.".
Scott: That's right.
Rym: So there's an article on Fark and this is why I read Fark.
Rym: This is one of those things that is just so weird and amazing that I'm not really sure how to take it.
Rym: It is an article that begs questions.
Scott: All right.
Rym: So there's an American Airlines flight, right?
Rym: It's going to take off.
Rym: People are on this flight.
Rym: They're ready to go.
Scott: They get stranded on the thing.
Rym: No, no.
Rym: They don't get stranded.
Rym: So apparently maggots started falling out of the ceiling somewhere onto this woman.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: So obviously there was some sort of meat in the overhead compartment that was left there by a previous passenger and they failed to clean it out as per the requirements that they clean the airplane after each flight.
Rym: So what they found, so obviously they take the flight back.
Rym: There's a minor emergency.
Rym: They're going to figure out what's going on with this maggot infestation.
Scott: You don't really need to go back for that.
Scott: You can just land at the nearest airport.
Rym: No, they didn't take off yet.
Rym: They taxied back to the terminal.
Rym: They sit there and people look around.
Rym: They're wondering if maybe it's something in the ceiling.
Rym: Maybe there's a problem with the airplane.
Scott: Maybe somebody actually brought maggots onto the plane in their carry-on.
Rym: So apparently there was a suitcase brought on by one of the passengers just a carry-on full of meat that was full of maggots.
Rym: And it was leaking maggots all over the place.
Rym: Now, how could this carry-on suitcase have been so sealed that maggots weren't falling out during that security check and everything?
Rym: And then suddenly maggots, when it's on the plane.
Scott: And how could the maggots weren't killed by x-rays?
Rym: I don't think they would kill the maggots.
Scott: Maybe it would multiply.
Scott: That's why they started spilling out.
Scott: They were strengthened by the x-rays.
Scott: Because they were now radioactive super-strong maggots and they busted out of the luggage with their superpowers.
Scott: Like the Hulk or Spider-Man.
Rym: The article doesn't tell you anything more than that.
Rym: It's like, "Oh, they found the suitcase.
Rym: There were maggots in it because of spoiled meat in the
Rym: baggage."
Rym: And it doesn't say anything else.
Rym: What kind of journalism is this?
Rym: Obviously, we want to know who brought it on, why they brought it on.
Rym: I want a police interview with the person like, "See, you brought a bag full of spoiled meat.
Rym: Were there maggots in it when you put it in the
Rym: bag?".
Scott: Were there maggots who took it out of the bag?
Scott: Why didn't you put it in a refrigerated container and send it by next day FedEx?
Rym: See, that doesn't bother me that much.
Rym: Because I'm assuming that this is a person who willfully put meat, possibly spoiled meat, in a carry-on bag.
Rym: Probably not even in plastic.
Scott: Are you sure it was actually meat?
Scott: It could have been like, you know, bad bathtub cheese or something.
Rym: It says meat in the article.
Scott: Was it like just a dead animal?
Scott: or was it actually a proper cut of meat?
Rym: They don't say.
Rym: There's a little video of the maggots.
Scott: Because it could have just been like someone's pet died, you know?
Scott: In the carry-on, in the overhead container.
Scott: Well, no, he died and then he was bringing it somewhere to a pet cemetery far away, so he just put it in a carry-on.
Rym: But then, so cut back to our wonderful Homeland Security people.
Rym: You'd think they would have noticed the skeleton in the x-ray.
Scott: No, no, no, no.
Scott: Don't talk to me.
Rym: Just, this newspaper people.
Scott: He de-boned it.
Rym: The people who say, oh, newspapers.
Scott: Was it fish?
Scott: It could have been fish.
Rym: When newspapers go away, that we're going to lose journalism, there already isn't journalism.
Rym: This article told me nothing that I needed to know.
Scott: Well, I mean, there already isn't journalism at 99% of newspapers, right?
Scott: It's pretty much, because all the local newspapers, they get all their news from the big newspapers.
Scott: And basically, there's only actually like two or three sources of actual journalism.
Scott: And at those sources of actual journalism, such as New York Times and such, the majority of the journalists there aren't actually real journalists.
Scott: So it's like you have a small, the smallest percentage of journalism places have a small percentage of actual journalists, and that's it.
Scott: So, yeah.
Rym: It's going to bother me, because I'll never be able to find out what the deal was.
Scott: You know, you would have been better off not knowing it even happened.
Rym: I know.
Rym: Thanks, Fark.
Scott: That's why I don't read Fark.
Rym: But it's one of those things I would love for there to be a website that was like a collaborative thing that was designed solely, you know, integrated with phone apps and everything, to geotag, you know, like give location coordinates and things.
Rym: And basically, it's a what the fuck website, where you just say, "What the fuck was up with
Rym: this?"
Rym: And you give as much information as you have, and then maybe other people will tell you what the fuck it was up with, whatever it was.
Rym: you're wondering what the fuck it was up about.
Rym: Like, you know, you're walking by, and like a boot just falls from the sky, like lands in front of you.
Rym: And it's full of, like, gerbils, and they're fine, and they run off.
Rym: You're like, "What the
Rym: fuck?".
Rym: So you post, and the guy's like, "Yeah, I dropped my gerbil
Rym: boot.".
Scott: It was Currybo's shoe.
Scott: So, here's my thing of the day.
Scott: What is man?
Scott: No.
Scott: What is the best Gundam of all Gundams?
Scott: Freedom.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Freedom Gundam is the best Gundam.
Scott: So, here's a video, and in this video, this guy builds Freedom Gundam.
Scott: In fact, he builds the same exact Freedom Gundam model that I have, which is the first Gundam model I ever built, the 1/100th Freedom Gundam.
Rym: Alright.
Scott: And he does it fast-forward, right, in the video, so it takes a few seconds for it to do that.
Scott: Then he builds another Freedom Gundam model that happens to be four feet tall, but that is not the important part, the fact that it was large.
Scott: That is not that impressive.
Scott: The impressive part is that he makes it out of paper.
Scott: He basically prints out 178 sheets out of his desk jet, and he gets an exacto knife and some glue and some folding in his hands, and he builds a four-foot-tall Freedom Gundam exactly like the plastic one.
Rym: Whoa!
Scott: And he basically does this, you know, also in fast motion.
Scott: So, it took him two weeks of sitting on the couch with a piece of cardboard on his lap, and, you know, scissors and whatever, but it takes you about four minutes to watch.
Scott: So, you watch four minutes of fast-forwarding, and you can see what the funniest thing about this, right, is you basically get four weeks of this dude sitting on the -- two weeks of this guy sitting on the couch, you know, building this model, and you see people occasionally come to sit with him on the couch and just sort of chat him up, and you notice, like, these people who sit with them on the couch, like, they're just, like, flipping around with their cell phones and whatever the whole time or just not doing anything, and this guy, he's building something.
Scott: So, don't be the guy with the cell phone.
Scott: Be the guy making a model out of paper.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Don't be the other guy.
Scott: And also, four-foot-tall Freedom Gundam.
Scott: Oh, fuck.
Rym: Not bad.
Scott: Shit, yeah.
Rym: All right, Fark did a little bit of digging.
Rym: It was a woman who brought the suitcase on, and she was on the flight, and that's all they know.
Scott: No one asked her?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: This is just Fark being like, "Hey, here's the best we could come up
Rym: with.".
Scott: Call her on the phone.
Scott: Be like, "Why did you have
Scott: meat?".
Rym: But, bonus points, there's a screenshot someone took, and they posted it on Fark, off the article, right?
Rym: And there's contextual advertising on the news site that reported it.
Scott: For selling maggots?
Rym: Selling meat.
Rym: And the first post, "Carry in
Rym: luggage."
Rym: That's a good joke.
Rym: The rest of the posts are garbage.
Scott: Yeah, it does.
Scott: "Carry in
Scott: luggage.".
Rym: So, the meta moment.
Rym: ConnectiCon is next weekend.
Scott: Oh, fuck me.
Rym: Yes, Jesus Christ.
Rym: Fuck me in the eye.
Rym: We run panels there.
Rym: It's going to be awesome.
Rym: July 9th, 10th, and 11th.
Rym: We'll be there.
Scott: Yeah, we're not just doing panels.
Scott: We are in charge of the panels.
Scott: Like, who is the boss of panels?
Scott: Us.
Scott: Us is the boss.
Rym: And there have been some problems along the way.
Rym: I can tell you that much.
Scott: We're doing the best we can, considering our late induction.
Scott: But, next year, they'll be much better.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Also, the New York Anime Festival Comic Con, off in the future, will be there doing stuff.
Scott: Oh, my God.
Scott: October 8th, 9th, 10th is going to be the weekend of doom.
Rym: The biggest fucking weekend ever.
Rym: There's the NerdNYC Board Gaming Night Friday.
Scott: October 8th, that night, 7 o'clock at Think Coffee downtown, NerdNYC Board Game Night.
Rym: Also, that is the beginning of 10-10-10, the Burning Wheel Extravaganza in Queens.
Scott: Yes, the Burning Wheel was originally released on 5-5-5, so it's 10-10-10, Burning Wheel Con on the 8th, 9th, and 10th.
Scott: Now, watch out.
Rym: If you can't do modulus math, you won't be able to figure out when the next one is going to be.
Scott: I know.
Scott: And, even worse, right, the New York Comic Con, New York Anime Festival double mega convention in the New York, in the Jacob Javits Center on the west side is also the 8th, 9th, and 10th.
Rym: So, it's anime.
Scott: Of October.
Rym: And comics, and gaming, and we'll be there doing big shit.
Scott: But, before then, about a month before then, on Labor Day weekend, PEX West.
Rym: Oh, my God.
Rym: And, by the way, PEX West will be there.
Rym: We're doing numerous events.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: The Book Club book is Still the Lies of Locke Lamora.
Rym: It's not the best written book, but it's really fun.
Rym: Really fun.
Rym: You'll probably enjoy it.
Scott: I chose it because it was a fun and easy book that would, hopefully, people would read it for fun.
Rym: It's like Lupin in a fantasy world, basically.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But, you see what I'm talking about.
Scott: It has that, we set up a fantasy world, but the story isn't about the fantasy world.
Scott: It's just in the fantasy world.
Scott: So, like, the deal with, like, why are there these towers of crystal and shit?
Scott: Well, we're not going to really explain, or that has nothing to do with the story.
Scott: They're just part of the setting.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Let's go.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I don't know what other meta we have.
Rym: Next week, basically, for the next two weeks, gig nights will be on and off again.
Scott: You may not live in the United States.
Scott: You may not know that it is the 4th of July this weekend, which means we don't have to work on Monday.
Rym: It's the day where we kicked your albionic asses.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, that means that who knows- You like my alliteration?
Scott: Who knows what kind of shows we're going to be doing next week, considering, like, Friday, you know, Thursday night or maybe Friday morning, we're running off to ConnectiCon and Monday we don't have work.
Scott: So, it's pretty much a Tuesday, Wednesday, Thursday next week, and who knows if we're.
Rym: I don't think we're going to do any shows next week.
Scott: We're going to do some show.
Rym: We might do one show.
Scott: What show should we do?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I got an idea.
Scott: Maybe we'll do something.
Scott: Anyway, next week, who knows about the status of our podcast.
Scott: Of course, but maybe not the Phantom.
Rym: So, we did a show on Lego.
Scott: A long time ago.
Rym: So, we realized, you know, we needed a show to do.
Scott: And I came up with an idea, a genius idea.
Rym: Clearly, we would do a show on UnLEGO.
Scott: Yeah, because there's a lot of UnLEGO, so that we can definitely cover enough, you know, material to make an entire episode of GeekNights.
Scott: We're talking about all the various UnLEGOs.
Scott: So, I- Pick an UnLEGO, or you shall begin with it.
Rym: See, it's tricky because what we each pick as our first one will say a lot about our personalities, I think.
Scott: I think it's, no, it's actually just gonna say about what I have the most to talk about.
Rym: Eh, no, because the one that I think stands out the most in my head is Tinker Toys, because nothing else was like Tinker Toys.
Scott: That's the one with the little wooden balls with the holes and the sticks.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: I actually, like I, you know, I knew Tinker Toys, but I never really had them.
Rym: I think my- Tinker Toys date back to World Fucking War 1.
Rym: I know.
Scott: My grandma, I think, had one bucket of them.
Scott: And I know of some friends who had them.
Rym: There were also, Kelvin played with them in Kelvin and Hobbes.
Scott: Yeah, but I never really had them or used them that much or really explored any of their possibilities.
Rym: In my mind, they were much more kind of, there was a lot more you could do with them.
Rym: They were just more versatile and more weird.
Rym: You could make big, weird contraptions, the likes of which you really couldn't make with other things.
Scott: Yeah, but they didn't really move.
Rym: You know, you could- Nothing back then moved.
Scott: Oh, yeah, it did.
Rym: What?
Rym: Construction or constructo?
Scott: No.
Scott: The erector set.
Scott: I had the erector set.
Rym: Yeah, honestly, I didn't like the erector set.
Scott: Oh, you see?
Scott: This is the thing, right?
Scott: So, I had, right?
Scott: I had my freaking mom's brother's erector set.
Rym: Yeah, I had the same deal.
Rym: Basically, the whole family was super full of nostalgia for erector sets.
Rym: So, they got me an original real deal erector set.
Rym: And I already had a bunch of other kinds of things that were more updated.
Rym: So, the erector set was kind of difficult.
Rym: I couldn't make anything interesting with it.
Scott: Oh, see, I had this old erector set, right?
Scott: And it had all this crazy- It even had like a motor and some crazy shit.
Scott: I couldn't even make it work because it was just so old and crazy.
Scott: But the thing that was awesome about the erector set, right, was that you could- You had actual screws and nuts.
Scott: It was like you're actually doing for real hardware.
Scott: It wasn't like some, you know, like snap together child-friendly thing.
Scott: It was like, "Here, here's a bunch of pieces of fucking metal with holes in them and screws and nuts that are the right size for the holes.
Scott: Go
Scott: nuts.".
Scott: And you could actually, you know, you can make like there's some wheels.
Scott: I made some cars, some other stuff with that.
Rym: See, I guess much more fun than erector sets.
Scott: But then, actually, later on, they like the re- You know, erector set disappeared for a while or at least lied low.
Scott: But then it made a slight resurgence.
Scott: And I had like one more modern erector set thing that was like a helicopter of some kind.
Scott: And it actually was relatively compatible with the original erector set.
Scott: It was just more modern, you know, less cut yourself, more safe for the modern times kind of situation.
Rym: See, I had this set of toys.
Rym: I have no idea what they were called.
Rym: Maybe someone can help me out.
Rym: They look kind of like erector sets, but they were- Because this is mostly of flat green pieces of plastic with large holes kind of interspersed, like along their lengths, and the holes had kind of ridges around them.
Rym: So you could use these plastic bolts and screws and nuts and things to connect them together.
Rym: And they were kind of like a big plastic erector set.
Scott: It might have just been wussy erector set.
Rym: No, because they actually- you could do things like make large swords and actually hit people with them.
Scott: You could make a fucking sword with an erector set.
Scott: Watch the fuck out.
Rym: But they were also bendy, so you could make really interesting shapes with them.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Rym: And actually, I would use them to make these very elaborate vehicles to put my mask men in, and then see if they would survive.
Scott: See, erector set is like more of an engineering thing, right?
Scott: You can't just make like a long stick, right?
Scott: You got to think about it like a bridge.
Scott: You got to tress it and stuff like that.
Rym: Well, if you're talking about wussifying things, there's always connects.
Scott: Yeah, my brother had connects.
Scott: I didn't really do too much of it.
Rym: They kind of, like by the time we got connects, was right about when I was getting to the end of that era in my life.
Scott: And the problem with connects is that it was really only strong- the links were strong in only one direction.
Scott: So if you wanted to make anything that was actually durable and stiff and could actually be for serious- You had to basically fully truss it.
Scott: You had to work in both dimensions.
Scott: You could make a sword, but if you made a flat sword, which is pretty easy, it would be all floppy.
Scott: You had to make a sword in the shape of a plus to actually get it to be kind of strong.
Rym: Which was good in a way that it was more for building structures rather than building a sword that I hit my brother with.
Scott: Yeah, it was very similar to erector set, but it only worked at certain angles, and you snapped instead of screwing.
Scott: So you lost the screwing aspect of it.
Rym: But notice how they would pop in and out the sides, which really limited your structural integrity.
Scott: That's what I was just saying.
Scott: Any link was only strong in one direction, which means you needed to go in multiple directions to get any sort of strength.
Scott: Plus, honestly, you couldn't do that much interesting with them, and most of the interesting things were- Yeah, other than following the directions, it was actually pretty hard to come up with something original that wasn't just like, "I made a gun.
Scott: It's an
Scott: L."
Scott: "I made a box with a stairway inside," or something.
Rym: I gotta say, though, I don't know if I should save it for last or just jump in the middle, but of all those sorts of things, the best, far and away, bar none for me, were waffle blocks.
Scott: You mean just fucking the fluffy foam things?
Scott: What?
Rym: No, these were big pieces of very sturdy plastic.
Rym: For a little kid, they were huge, flat pieces of plastic with interlocking notches along the edges.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: But they were hard plastic.
Scott: They made those still, but they're foam.
Scott: They're like jigsaw puzzle pieces, but they're all identical.
Rym: Yeah, but these, well, they weren't all identical.
Rym: Some had holes in them.
Rym: You could mount them on the sides, not just in the middle.
Rym: Oh, right, right.
Rym: But you could make large structures that could hold your own weight.
Rym: I would make entire forts, walls to block off parts of the house.
Scott: Yeah, that is something to be said, right?
Scott: It's like none of the other things.
Scott: When you're working with, say, Lego, you're making things that are miniature size.
Scott: It's like you're making toys.
Scott: Unless you're rich, you're not making Legos that are the size that can interact with the real world.
Scott: But some of these other ones, like erector set, you're also usually making something small.
Scott: Unless you have so much erector set, you could make a real go-kart.
Scott: you could sit in.
Scott: But that's a lot of fucking erector set.
Rym: One time I remember we would always make, my brother and I, we'd make a boat in the living room.
Rym: Like a gigantic with a floor.
Scott: You'd put it in the pool?
Rym: No, it wouldn't float.
Rym: But we'd make it on the floor, right?
Rym: With a hull and walls and a deck.
Rym: And then we'd basically fight off the pirates from the outside with Nerf guns.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Oh, and also there were Wii waffle blocks, which were like two or three inches by two or three inches.
Rym: They were much smaller.
Scott: Was that for adding detail to the big waffle blocks?
Rym: No, they were incompatible.
Rym: They were just like a smaller scale.
Scott: They were basically- So I hate that when the shit's incompatible.
Scott: Like why isn't Duplo compatible with Lego?
Rym: They kind of were.
Rym: No.
Rym: I used them.
Rym: You know why I used them?
Rym: The Duplos were the old cyclopean ruins of ancient giant civilizations.
Scott: They're not compatible.
Scott: They really got to work on that.
Scott: I think that what they should do for Duplo, right, is because you get a Duplo and like you got a big Duplo.
Scott: And it's got like eight big circles on it, right?
Scott: What they should do is they should just make Duplo just have Lego sized dots on top, right?
Scott: So it's just, it is a Lego.
Scott: It's just fucking big, right?
Scott: Then it would be way more awesome and Lego would be compatible with it.
Scott: It would just be, you know, Lego pieces that were gigantic.
Scott: And it would actually help you out with your Lego later on when you grow, you graduate.
Scott: Because then you want to build a big castle, like big.
Scott: You just do blow it up.
Scott: You get to forget, you know, instead of having a million small Legos to build a big flat wall, it is just a lot of pieces that make a mess.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Of course, if you're going to make a big thing, I mean, like the waffle blocks are like this big.
Rym: I'm gesturing.
Rym: No one else can see, but they're like, they're gigantic.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Did you have any other non-Legos?
Scott: Because I had- I had quite a few.
Rym: Actually, my favorite thing with waffle blocks though, which was always dangerous, was I'd make the tallest stairway I could make and then climb it until I broke it.
Rym: Or turn it into bridges over gaps.
Scott: If you made it too tall, wouldn't you hurt yourself?
Rym: Yes, I hurt myself often.
Scott: I guess that makes them the most dangerous non-Lego, right?
Scott: Because the other ones are not dangerous at all.
Rym: I would argue that actually the Tinker Toys were the most dangerous.
Scott: What?
Scott: How so?
Rym: Because they consisted of hard, brittle, easily snapped into basically stake pieces of wood.
Scott: They're little tiny sticks.
Scott: They're no more dangerous than pick-ups.
Scott: They're like pick-up sticks.
Scott: They're not dangerous.
Rym: Pick-up sticks are reasonably dangerous.
Scott: Or what's that game where you pull the sticks out and the marbles fall down?
Scott: Same sticks.
Rym: No, they were wood.
Scott: They actually, if you broke one in half- Not like- My pick-up sticks are wooden.
Rym: If you broke these in half, you could stab a kid right through the chest with it.
Scott: Well, you had a serious Tinker Toy then.
Scott: I think that's just the way they were.
Scott: I never saw a Tinker Toy that was that serious.
Rym: You ever snap one in half?
Rym: They snap into basically a stiletto.
Scott: Alrighty.
Scott: I see that you are much practiced with stabbing.
Scott: You have a third sibling that was murdered.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: The other ones I had to- If I think back, the ones I actually used quite often were Lincoln Logs.
Scott: Really, you couldn't do anything with Lincoln Logs except make log cabins.
Rym: Why was it so satisfying, though?
Scott: The only pieces you had were long, short.
Scott: You had the one that was half, so it was flat on the bottom.
Rym: Oh, I had more.
Rym: You had the green slats.
Scott: I had the green slats and the plastic things that held together the green slats.
Rym: See, I didn't use those.
Scott: Oh, really?
Rym: Those were wussy, but the sizes were- How did you hold your roof together?
Rym: You know the sizes, there were the three long ones with the notch in the middle and the two ends.
Scott: Well, there were three long ones.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Rym: Yeah, there's the two long ones, like the short ones, and there's the one long ones.
Scott: Yeah, the one longs, right?
Scott: I forgot about those, so you mentioned them, but yeah, I do remember them.
Rym: So, I would use those to make columns.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Rym: And basically, I'd use those to make structures that had awnings and arches coming out of them, or I'd have a deck three stories up with a column coming all the way down.
Scott: See, my problem is I just didn't have enough Lincoln Logs.
Scott: I pretty much had one log cabin, and that was it.
Rym: I also had four long ones.
Scott: Oh, shit.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I didn't have any, so I obviously, I just had a set that was like a single log cabin set, so I couldn't really expand a lot with my Lincoln Logs, but now I wish I had more.
Rym: See, so what I would do with them is I usually make- Do they still make that shit?
Rym: I'd assume so.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I'd make big structures, but instead of using the slat holding plastic, I would put the slats flat across the top and build another structure on top of that one.
Scott: Oh.
Rym: I fucking love my Lincoln Logs.
Rym: And then I'd put a firecracker at the base.
Scott: Yeah, I think Lincoln Logs, they don't get enough respect or attention, but the fact that we both had them and both liked them and used them a lot, pretty much second to Lego, I was using Lincoln Logs.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You know?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I had- And all I was doing was building the same log cabin over and over again.
Rym: See, what I really do is I don't remember the names of really any of these products, but I would combine my Legos, but I can't talk about any of the Lego, obviously, so I'll skip that.
Rym: I'd make Lego cities, but I had micro machines.
Scott: Micro machines don't count.
Rym: No, no, no, but here's what I'd do.
Rym: So I'd use the micro machine like villages, right?
Rym: And I'd connect them to this road building system that I had.
Rym: that was just like this third party completely independent toy where you'd connect like these roads together.
Rym: It had intersections and lanes and everything.
Rym: Well, I guess, I mean, I had this particular micro- Ah, but here, I'll link it to the stuff.
Rym: So I'd use those and I'd interface them finally with the wee waffle blocks and the wee waffle blocks would be used to make the suburbs.
Rym: And I'd basically make this gigantic heterogeneous city between hot wheels and road systems and micro machines and waffle blocks and Legos.
Scott: I actually had this one particular micro machine set, right, where you bought them individually for like five bucks, which is like the easiest toy to get.
Scott: Yeah, but you could connect them all together.
Scott: Because every time you go to the store, you're like, "Hey, mom, buy me one of those for 10 bucks.
Scott: Hey, buy me one of
Scott: those.".
Scott: And then you eventually get so many of them, you can connect them all together.
Scott: Did you ever get the two city centerpiece units?
Scott: No, my brother had the big van that opened up.
Rym: Oh, yeah, we had the van and there was another one.
Rym: And we combined those with the little ones and everything else to make an entire city.
Scott: But I had these little gray plastic rectangles and they folded in half.
Scott: And they had all these accessories that you'd put inside when you fold it in half and they would seal it.
Scott: And you'd open it up, like in a gas station, for example, and you would open it up and you'd put these decals on there and the gas station pieces would come out.
Scott: You'd put them on top.
Scott: And then you had these little cars.
Scott: So every set came with a highway intersection and some set pieces and some cars.
Scott: And you just kept getting enough of these.
Scott: It was like the greatest deal.
Rym: I remember the guy would talk really fast in all the commercials and that was how I would sell them.
Rym: Remember that guy?
Scott: All right, so let's go to things that are actually, you know.
Rym: The point was that I'd take the wee waffle blocks, but they were like one aspect of a basement-filling city that I would build over the course of an entire weekend.
Scott: Well, I think that's, you know, it's like no one had enough of a single toy to go all out.
Scott: You had to combine your toys, you know, and your different constructing things in some way to go large, right?
Scott: You know, unless you're rich, you didn't have so much Lego.
Scott: you could just cover the whole fucking basement, you know.
Scott: You only had enough Lego to build like a few castles.
Scott: So if you wanted to add something in there, you had to add something in there with some non-Lego.
Scott: Because, you know, you had this Lincoln Log sitting there.
Scott: It's like, well, I can't just ignore that shit, right?
Scott: Just let it sit in the closet, you know.
Scott: I don't have enough Lego to do what I want.
Scott: I got to bust something else out.
Scott: Now, let's see.
Scott: The only other two, I barely had any of it, but the Play Mobile.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: Because Play Mobile really, you don't build so much with it, but it's like it competes with the Lego men, right?
Scott: And the thing with Play Mobile is that it has pretty much anything you can imagine, they got it, right?
Scott: Pirates, they got it.
Scott: Ninja, they got it.
Rym: But because it was like 60% compatible with Lego...
Scott: Zombie, they got it.
Scott: It was kind of...
Rym: I would take the weapons and like file them down a little bit to get them to work.
Scott: Play Mobile's really more about the guys than it is about the building, you know.
Scott: But, yeah, I mean, they just have so many freaking sets.
Scott: Like, you can't imagine like a single thing that they do not have.
Scott: You know, if it's like fucking helicopter, fucking army, fucking just like wizards.
Scott: And it's like they must sit there and think of every possible setting for any possible story you could possibly imagine.
Scott: And any possible character you would need in that setting and any possible building you would need in that setting, there's a Play Mobile set for it.
Scott: You know, whereas Lego tends to stick to a setting and just sort of make, you know, the full like a whole run on it.
Scott: You know, Play Mobile will just make like one or two things per setting.
Scott: Like maybe a big, a medium, and a small.
Scott: And then they'll do as many settings as they can.
Scott: Whereas Lego does just a few settings.
Scott: And then they concentrate on them real hard.
Scott: Like, let's make a hundred castle sets.
Scott: Whereas Play Mobile's got like... We got three castles.
Scott: We're good.
Rym: One thing that I had, I don't remember what it was called, but it was a whole series that eventually died out.
Rym: It was basically eye beams and towers and all this kind of stuff that would construct together.
Rym: Like you could make all sorts of different structures with them.
Rym: And you could combine the sets.
Rym: They were all compatible with each other.
Rym: But you'd make like a huge structure, like a radio broadcasting tower or a skyscraper.
Rym: And then they gave you like these four different, basically, bombs that would destroy them.
Rym: What?
Rym: They were designed...
Scott: This isn't what I was going to talk about.
Rym: No, but you could build them like Lincoln Logs or K'Nex or anything.
Rym: Because, you know kids, you'd eventually build like a gigantic tower out of something.
Rym: And then you'd destroy it.
Rym: And you're interested in like the way it destroyed.
Rym: Imagine a system, like a toy, that was designed to be destroyed.
Rym: And in fact was designed to where when you tried to destroy it, it fell apart in an awesome way.
Scott: I never heard of such a toy.
Rym: I had every set of it and all my friends did too.
Rym: They were huge among like my play group in like second grade.
Rym: I have no idea what they were called.
Rym: The first set was the simplest.
Rym: It was just like eye beams and connectors for them.
Rym: They were like brown.
Rym: And then they got more and more complex.
Rym: One was like this white and orange radio tower.
Rym: One was like an oil rig kind of thing.
Scott: Uh huh.
Rym: It was pretty fucking badass.
Rym: I need someone out there to tell me what it was.
Scott: Yeah, the only other thing I had a lot of was constructs, right?
Scott: I don't know how many people out there know constructs.
Scott: But basically the way it works, you have these plastic pieces, right?
Scott: That are just sort of long and of various different lengths and colors.
Scott: And then they have at the ends of each piece is a place to snap.
Scott: And they give you these little tiny square pieces.
Scott: And you basically can, you know, a square piece has a connector on all eight sides.
Scott: All six sides, not eight sides.
Scott: Right?
Scott: So you can connect, you know, these long pieces, the beams.
Scott: And you basically put a connector at every joint.
Scott: And you can just go nuts.
Scott: And sometimes they'll like give you a piece of plastic that you can like snap to fill in one of the sides.
Scott: And then like I had the best set.
Scott: I had like this one where there's a spaceman and he had a spaceship.
Scott: And there's an alien and he had a spaceship.
Scott: And they're like totally like the coolest looking alien dudes.
Scott: They were totally evil.
Scott: And they gave you like this cool, like before Lego did the outer space.
Scott: Like this set the tone of the outer space style for that kind of stuff.
Scott: And, you know, the best thing was because you had the plastic pieces to fill in.
Scott: You can actually make like these big surfaces with them.
Scott: So you could do is you could like make sort of like a, you know, a flat surface.
Scott: And then a more elevated flat surface and then something else.
Scott: And then you could, you know, use that as a platform.
Scott: And you put your big flat Lego bases on top of that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: To keep them off the floor.
Scott: And actually you could put like a castle up high or a tree and then a castle down low.
Scott: And then a boat.
Scott: You know, you get you can make it as like the foundation for the Lego.
Scott: It was a very, very good combination there.
Scott: It was also had a motorized thing for it, but I never really, you know, I never really had great success with anything that was motorized.
Scott: You know, I never really.
Rym: Because they're always got a chintzy.
Rym: They never work.
Scott: The Lego Technic worked, but I didn't have motorized ones.
Scott: I had cranked gear ones, you know, but none of my motorized things work.
Scott: And I think it's because I never got the more expensive motorized sets.
Scott: I always got the cheapest possible ones that sucked ass.
Scott: I didn't get like the Mindstorm that actually works.
Scott: You know, I got like if I can put 2D batteries in here and push a button and it spins around.
Scott: Gee, thanks.
Scott: That helps.
Scott: I think that's all the ones I had.
Rym: Yeah, we couldn't come up with much else to talk about.
Scott: You didn't have any others?
Rym: Not that I can recall offhand anymore.
Scott: Yeah, but yeah, constructs were...
Rym: No, I suddenly was reminded of a toy that I think almost everyone's forgotten about.
Rym: Remember the Nerf fencing system?
Scott: No.
Rym: It was gigantic, awesomely constructed Nerf swords.
Rym: And the like the hilt had basically four targets sticking out of it.
Rym: And you had to push in the four targets on your opponent's sword.
Scott: It's like the vaguest of vague recollections.
Scott: It's like so vague, I don't even know if it's...
Rym: Basically, I remember having this and it's suddenly like all these memories of like playing with it.
Rym: And getting frustrated with trying to hit the targets, just hitting my brother over the head.
Scott: We had to look it up on YouTube.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Cause you know there's gonna be a video of it.
Scott: Or a commercial.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: (Singing in Japanese).