Rym: It's Monday, February 15th.
Scott: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: Google buzz reminds us about privacy on the internet.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: So Rym, you know that the four laws of physics Before I believe there are more than four.
Scott: No, I mean, you know the The.
Scott: No, there's only four.
Scott: I just there were three and I added a new one.
Scott: don't don't worry about those other ones.
Scott: Okay, I'm not otherwise I can't make my joke.
Scott: if you consider the laws of physics that aren't other than Newton's three laws I'm not.
Rym: I'm not quite sure where you're coming with this.
Rym: So you meant Newton's laws.
Scott: Well, there was.
Scott: you know, there are many laws in the universe, right?
Scott: But there is one that people have referred to as a law.
Scott: that wasn't actually a law But I have just proved that it actually is a law.
Rym: and which law would this be?
Scott: Murphy's law?
Rym: I wouldn't even say that's a law so much as as a divine revelation.
Scott: Regardless, you know be anything that can go wrong will go wrong is Absolutely.
Scott: It is like it is.
Scott: It is as it set in stone as every action has the equal but opposite reaction.
Scott: Those are equally 100% true.
Rym: that does not make sense because if that were true right now Every atom in all the recording equipment that we were using right now would have spontaneously Exploded while simultaneously Krauser appeared in real life and raped us today.
Scott: It did.
Scott: that was just in another universe that we're not in man.
Rym: I'm glad I'm not in that universe.
Scott: I know right.
Scott: so What can and did go wrong?
Scott: So I have this car and I bought this car and I paid for the whole car.
Scott: I own the whole thing and I was like, oh man's I have this car.
Scott: It's an awesome car.
Scott: I bought a brand new is totally awesome.
Scott: And I used it and I used it.
Scott: He's gonna used it.
Scott: No, I was so great.
Scott: That's like the Rym and Scott convention mobile right now and my plan With the car was that I would keep it forever and ever and ever until it died and it was like a hundred years old.
Scott: No, I
Rym: remember you're talking about how yeah, this Mazda 3 one day is gonna be a fancy and
Scott: it's gonna be yeah It's gonna be like an antique, you know, they'll be like the year 2040 and I'll have a car that from 2006 and It'll be like a classic.
Scott: and I'll be like, yeah check this shit out.
Scott: when they don't even have gas cars anymore.
Scott: I'll have a gas car and I'm like, you know, like special gas tank, you know to drive at the antique car show And it'd be totally sweet.
Rym: You have some interface where where the gas tank would be There's just a battery that somehow acts like gas.
Scott: now Actual gas that's stored up, you know.
Scott: for you know I have to pay like $100 a gallon for it from the antique car gas selling.
Scott: guys, you know someday We're gonna run the same guy who sells leaded gas to work in like a Model T or whatever.
Rym: We're gonna run out of dead dinosaur juice and then what?
Scott: no, I don't know.
Scott: Well anyway So I moved to New York and my strategy was okay.
Scott: I have this car.
Scott: I don't really need it that often But I do still want to keep it until it's a classic.
Scott: So what do I do as I say?
Scott: I know I'll work really hard on stuff and try to make more money And if I can make more money Then I can get enough money to buy.
Scott: a parking space is a parking space where we are.
Scott: It's a hike a hundred and thirty Bucks a month.
Rym: Oh, it's only 125 in my building buzz away.
Scott: It was 125 actually.
Scott: I think someone took the last parking space.
Rym: There's one opening right now in my building.
Rym: I was I was for a little while, you know, it was bonus time.
Rym: I was like, maybe I'll buy a car.
Scott: the thing is I could get one that's like maybe out Long Islander.
Scott: You know, I don't have to get the one at my building.
Rym: It's not about it.
Rym: I was like, maybe I'll buy a car.
Rym: and While they're like, it would be really useful for a couple of really specific things like going to get groceries.
Scott: Yeah, like there's a Costco really close to me.
Scott: The thing is this Costco is sort of a little bit out of walking distance, you know Maybe it would be like even if it was walking distance.
Rym: It's Costco.
Rym: What are you gonna carry back?
Scott: Yeah, that was insane to get.
Scott: even if I got one of those grandma, you know grocery push carts that everyone has Right, even if I got one I couldn't even put like one Costco apple juice in there.
Scott: You know, I would have to get like a giant one.
Rym: what you do Scott?
Rym: buy a real shopping cart.
Rym: Where am I gonna store this real shopping chain it up on the street like a bike?
Scott: And a homeless person will take it and it'll become their shopping cart only if they've got a hacksaw.
Scott: You know you ever seen a homeless person?
Scott: They've already got one shopping cart and it's definitely got a hacksaw in it.
Scott: It's probably guys.
Scott: It's like a holding.
Scott: It's got everything in there.
Rym: Why is the hobo?
Rym: They're not really hobos anyway.
Rym: I like saying hobo even though none of the people I refer to as hobos are actually hobos.
Rym: Uh-huh, but why are they gonna steal your shopping cart when they can just go to the grocery store and pick one?
Rym: That's unlocked and just sitting there waiting?
Scott: because if what they see one that's not at the grocery store They'll have to feel better about taking that one because obviously it doesn't belong to anyone's been lost.
Scott: I have ones at the grocery store.
Scott: They might feel bad about stealing it a little bit.
Rym: I'll bet it's more of a hey crackhead situation.
Scott: That's true too.
Scott: But yeah, you've seen almost you've got multiple shopping carts.
Rym: All right, they're like tied together in a little train.
Scott: Yeah, so I had this car and other than like if I wanted to do certain things it would not really be useful.
Scott: You know, it's like how when am I gonna use it?
Scott: Well, I was gonna use it this weekend.
Scott: I'd use it maybe to go to my parents house, but I can take the train.
Scott: I don't need to use it for that.
Scott: I could use it to go to a convention, but I don't need to use it for that.
Scott: so there are certain things, you know, basically the times I would use it are extremely extremely limited and the Even those times that I would use it.
Scott: there are viable alternatives that are not really worse.
Rym: Well even like for me, you know, I gotta go skiing.
Rym: Renting a car is not that much money for the.
Rym: you know The four or five times I go skiing in a winter.
Scott: so it did not take very long.
Scott: Right for me to switch from being like, oh, I'm gonna keep this car forever to fuck this car.
Scott: It's a hassle.
Scott: It's a pain in my ass.
Scott: get it the hell out of here.
Scott: Like it took about like a week before I'm just like fuck this car.
Rym: Part of that catalyst was the fact that you were doing the alternate side of the street parking.
Scott: Yeah, but even if I didn't have to move it is basically just like just having it there.
Scott: It's a burden.
Scott: I'm paying insurance money and I'm not using it.
Scott: If I took all my insurance money from the whole year I could buy multiple plane tickets and have money left over.
Rym: as Jared said you buck the trend.
Rym: most people move to the city Like just hold on to their car.
Rym: like they linger they keep it.
Rym: They're like, I'm gonna keep this car for like a year or two before they realize it's pointless and get rid of it.
Scott: Mm-hmm So it's only been a couple of months and I'm getting rid of it.
Scott: So I'm smarter than those people who keep on to it for a year.
Scott: Yeah, so I tried to find someone to buy it and nobody's buying cars But our friend wanted to buy it.
Scott: So I sold it to them and then of course I just mailed them the papers and then the next day car didn't start huh?
Rym: It's funny because I remember a while back same thing happened.
Rym: You tried to blame it on me for turning on a light that I didn't turn on.
Scott: I think you did turn on the light and I think that didn't cause the problem.
Scott: Haha.
Scott: I can still blame you.
Rym: Sounds like your alternators shot.
Scott: Yeah, I went down.
Scott: I had a guy.
Scott: he came first of all, you know.
Scott: He tried to boost it.
Scott: It boosted it started.
Scott: He he unclipped and the car turned off Which I did not think it happened cuz it's like okay the battery gets the engine started.
Rym: now battery does a bunch of other stuff.
Scott: I know.
Scott: the battery makes the lights turn on and all that kind of stuff.
Scott: right and the thing is the lights are working.
Scott: It's like the battery has juice.
Scott: It was like the engine started but then as soon as he unplugged the jumper cables the engine turned off.
Scott: It's like whoa, how did you know?
Rym: so I was that's how cars work?
Rym: Yeah, it's your my best bet He's gonna replace your battery or alternator.
Rym: You'll be fine.
Scott: Yeah, he's checking.
Scott: so, you know.
Scott: Then I'm like, how are you gonna tow this out of this parallel parking spot?
Scott: and he had a clever machine.
Scott: Maybe I'll try to find a YouTube that shows how this clever tow truck works.
Scott: that can pull you out of a parallel spot And then he's gonna fix it up and then this weekend I will sell it.
Scott: cuz good God I had to get rid of this thing You know, but I can't sell it if it's not fixed up.
Scott: So I got to fix it up and then sell it.
Rym: Yeah, you're gonna leave that dent in it.
Rym: Is that sold as is I'm gonna?
Scott: I'm gonna attempt to repair the dent But really the dent is entirely on the bodywork, you know It is not.
Scott: there is no under damage.
Scott: The dent is entirely in one piece of the bodywork right and I'm pretty sure you could just pop it out.
Scott: I just haven't popped it out because it's cold.
Scott: if it was the summer I would had no problem laying on the ground getting underneath the car and hitting it a few times to see what happened.
Scott: You know, I'm gonna try the hair dryer, you know and followed by cold method that I saw videos of working on YouTube.
Rym: So I know ice method is worked for me many times in the past.
Scott: So I'm gonna attempt the.
Scott: well I'm gonna not actually use dry ice cuz someone said that why bother with dry ice?
Scott: buy one of those cans of compressed air at Staples turn it upside down and use the liquid dry ice coolant.
Rym: Well, that's the conundrum of dry ice.
Rym: dry ice is a lot cheaper than using one of those kids of air.
Scott: It's real easy to buy a can of air.
Scott: It's kind of.
Scott: where am I gonna get a piece of dry ice?
Scott: Google?
Rym: I'm sure there's a bunch of place.
Scott: Yeah, but it's like I gotta find a place.
Scott: You got to get it in the styrofoam container.
Scott: You got to get a towel around you gonna grab with the tongs and the rubber gloves and the.
Rym: the styrofoam container is Just a beer cooler.
Scott: Yeah, but you got it.
Scott: You know, it's a whole to do with the dry ice with the can of air that it's a lot less work plus.
Rym: However, they're wait.
Rym: There are a lot of distributors of dry ice all set to go.
Rym: I mean, that's something you can do like in that when there's a heat wave They'll give dry ice to the old people to put in their house to cool it down.
Scott: Mm-hmm Still it's.
Scott: you know, it's work.
Rym: I wanted to do that at RIT and I found out afterward We could have gotten dry ice for free where at RIT.
Rym: But we didn't and we always complain.
Rym: But we could have just cooled the house with dry ice.
Scott: my grandpa would always talk about how you know How.
Scott: today like if there's a butcher they drive the meat around in a refrigerated truck.
Scott: He's like, why do they have a refrigerated truck?
Scott: take a piece of dry ice put a fan in front of it Close the truck.
Scott: done that cut that truck would be colder than fucking anything, you know way better than a refrigerator And you won't have to power the refrigerator with gas or whatever.
Scott: Yeah, of course you have to use energy to get the dry ice.
Scott: So it's you have to do the math on that to figure out what's more efficient.
Scott: But the dry ice is definitely colder than the.
Rym: you know, you don't want it to be too cold.
Rym: You don't want to freeze the meat.
Scott: Well, no, but that's you do want it.
Scott: You know, if you're shipping meat long-distance, you do want to freeze.
Scott: it depend.
Scott: basically have a big freezer truck It depends.
Rym: so, you know, sometimes you want to just cool the meat.
Scott: Yes, if you did just want a cool but not frozen thing Then you might have to you know Regulate the dry ice somehow put it in a box a little vent or something like, you know, but you it's manageable.
Rym: I look forward to the day when we make Peltier or something like it a lot more efficient and we can just do everything I don't like.
Scott: I don't think that's happening.
Scott: Notice how quickly they abandoned.
Scott: Peltier is a computer cooling method due to its crappiness.
Scott: Yeah Lack of ability to improve.
Rym: I think it can improve.
Rym: I heat pumps and heat engines.
Rym: We just have to figure out the molecular stuff better.
Scott: Yeah, anyway car is getting fixed now and then I'm getting rid of it.
Scott: Good God get out of here car And watch you it.
Scott: and then my new strategy right is because obviously The strategy of wait till I get money for a parking space did not work.
Scott: So the new strategy is aha wait until I have so much money that I can buy a new car and a parking space.
Scott: And until I have that much money do nothing.
Scott: That's the new strategy.
Rym: Yeah, I mean honestly the the nail in the coffin for me buying a car well again was just the fact that fresh direct delivered groceries last night and I realized that Nothing is more awesome in the world than having every grocer you would ever want just brought into your apartment by people Who would be perfectly willing to put it in your fridge for you?
Scott: Yeah, it's not even just you know.
Scott: I mean you think grocery delivery.
Scott: that's pretty amazing.
Scott: you can get delivery of fucking anything like if you go to Bed Bath and Beyond and you buy like some bed sheets and a Pan a frying pan That's what you're buying and a toaster oven, right?
Scott: You can go to the checkout and then you can go over to the other counter and be like Yeah, send this to my house and they just bring it to your house.
Scott: I Think they might charge you a delivery fee, but not that much though.
Scott: No, it's not that much.
Rym: I just I've realized everything.
Scott: in New York City They have like almost every place has delivery.
Rym: what it basically comes down to is everywhere else.
Rym: I just had Amazon so I bought 90% of the stuff I bought online and it got delivered.
Rym: now I buy 99% of the stuff I buy and it just gets delivered and the other 1% is basically like street meat.
Scott: Yeah, I actually go to the grocery store though, cuz it's right I get off the subway when I get home from work and there it is and then I buy a food and then I go Home and I immediately eat it.
Scott: So it's like, you know, it's a little better than waiting for a grocery delivery.
Rym: Yeah, well, I buy cheese and fresh bread at Grand Central.
Scott: Mmm.
Scott: Yeah, watch me.
Scott: I should.
Scott: I have troubles with breads.
Scott: I got to find some some bread eggs.
Rym: My policy is pretty good.
Rym: now I only ever buy brand new fresh bread from like a bakery or something.
Scott: The thing is I got some bakeries But they're the kind of bakeries that have like cakes and cannolis and shit and I can't.
Scott: I'm looking and some of them have breads But some of them like long breads, you know or big breads.
Rym: That's the best kind of bread.
Scott: It's a good kind of bread, but that's not the kind of bread that one person needs I need like?
Scott: no I need like a bag of rolls or you know a small loaf I don't need like a big long bread.
Rym: Well, you can buy the big long bread use what you're gonna use and crouton the rest.
Scott: You know how many croutons I'm gonna have you eat.
Rym: a lot of croutons will all work out.
Scott: Don't eat that many croutons.
Scott: I mean I bag of croutons last me like a couple weeks.
Scott: That's like you who eats the croutons like a snack because they are a snack.
Rym: No, they're not.
Scott: Snacks is snacks.
Scott: croutons is croutons.
Scott: So are you gonna put Doritos on your salad?
Rym: Blackberry might be in trouble again.
Rym: I mean the iPhone was never really competition for the blackberry.
Rym: They were like two distinct products with two distinct kind of people who would use it.
Scott: I mean iPhone made a token effort to try to appeal to corporate people by putting in exchange support in the Cisco VPN.
Rym: At work, I went to my corporate support people.
Rym: I was like, hey, can we support the iPhone?
Scott: because I was thinking maybe I'll buy an iPhone and they just laughed Yeah, it's like it's not enough because they don't realize that the blackberry also gives all this other stuff You know, which basically is stuff that Steve Jobs hates.
Rym: So and whether I do it has basically I think relegated itself to the very solid kind of All the cheap default.
Rym: like person goes to the store and says I want a smartphone.
Rym: Eventually, I think they're all just gonna be web OS.
Scott: Hmm I don't know about that.
Rym: like low-end smartphones is where I feel if web OS survives at all.
Rym: The low-end smartphone is where they do.
Scott: like though that we actually have like real competition.
Scott: We've got five real competitors, right?
Scott: I know where you got web OS Android iPhone Blackberry and Microsoft five at.
Scott: look at this.
Scott: what happens in this actual competition?
Scott: The thing is that so depressing is that we have actual competition and people are stepping up the game but nobody's really stepping up the game, you know, and I think the reason for that is because Even though there's a real competition in the smartphone OS arena There is no competition in the carrier arena and it's tied up.
Scott: if the carriers were loosened or also had to compete Then we would see craziness happen.
Rym: Absolute crazy, it's tough because there is competition.
Rym: if you live in cities Like if you live in New York Verizon Sprint and AT&T are all equal except for the fact that AT&T sucks.
Rym: But like Sprint is super fast and they're a lot cheaper than Verizon you get pretty much the same coverage.
Rym: But if you live in a lot of places, you can really only go with one carrier Maybe two.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I mean t-mobile is not gonna mean.
Scott: it's not just about coverage It's about you know pricing and it's also about you know Data networks and their data network policies and whether they allow the tethering or the charge, you know that kind of stuff
Rym: Yep, but even with it with the competition in the you know, web OS and BlackBerry and everything I think what it's really coming down to it I didn't realize this until recently is that patent encumbrance is probably the biggest.
Rym: like that It's the biggest thing that's holding back having a smartphone that does everything right.
Rym: that is also very true because everyone has patents on all these Obvious good idea UI things that other people can't use.
Scott: it's not even UI things, right?
Scott: There's a lot of other things that the people have patents on.
Scott: that aren't UI things Like for example for all the Verizon and Sprint phones, right?
Scott: they use the ev dues and all that stuff.
Scott: all those people don't realize right?
Scott: all that ev dues CDMA stuff is Owned by Qualcomm, right?
Scott: There are Qualcomm chips and all Verizon and Sprint devices and all the GSM GPRS stuff.
Scott: That stuff is all open standards, you know.
Scott: You could just make your own GPS G not GPS GSM network just in your house if you get the right radio equipment.
Scott: You know people nerds have done it.
Scott: You can go read about it.
Scott: And there's even like some guy he makes I think he called like the magic stick or something like that and You it's just a USB thing and you put it in your computer and it creates a GSM network in your house and then all of all your cell phones will use that instead of the local antenna because they're getting a stronger signal from it and You'll be able to make calls on your cell phone.
Scott: No problem over your internets with this little stick but little things to like web OS.
Rym: the only thing it really has over the other I guess OS is is That they have this great internet like all your contacts and chats and everything or just seamlessly integrated with each other.
Scott: That's the one thing that I really wish other people would get right.
Scott: that only web OS gets right.
Scott: It's like wow Come right on, you know iPhone doesn't even have I chat right?
Scott: That's completely retarded.
Scott: Android I guess has some chatting but it like, you know It's not like.
Scott: it's all super integrated with your SMS and every single chat network and there's a bug.
Rym: A lot of people are having this weird problem where their phone will just get duplicates of every SMS from some of their contacts.
Rym: Yeah, and I still haven't heard any good risk.
Scott: and then like if you have you know The Android has the best Gmail but the Gmail separate from all the other mail.
Scott: So it's like give all this other mail and then Gmail in two separate places.
Rym: Yep at the pre actually I will say integrates with Gmail better than Google integrates with its own Gmail.
Scott: Well, I mean the actual Gmail app on the Android.
Scott: I haven't used it but every single person says that it is like the best better than any other phone dealing with Gmail.
Scott: But the problem is is that it's all on its own.
Scott: So if you also have like an IMAP, it's separate whereas on the pre It's together.
Rym: Yep Everything's just together and it's all.
Rym: just push because it pulls and figure all your emails in one place.
Scott: all your IMS and SMS Is in one place.
Scott: they're all you know, all your contacts are.
Scott: you know span across the whole thing?
Scott: So you only have one of everything and that's what I like the most, you know on the iPhone It's like everything is separated into apps.
Scott: so your Facebook is over here and your Skype is over there and your emails over here and you don't even have I am unless You pay for one of those stupid apps that I'm not paying for.
Scott: and maybe even if you have I am it's separate apps one For aim and one for something else, you know, I want all I am is together just like on the computer pigeon.
Scott: does all I am?
Rym: Yeah, of course.
Rym: I used to run everything separately.
Rym: I used to have like multiple I am clients open at the same time back in the day.
Scott: Yeah, it's like we've gone back in time and then yeah, I got no multitasking.
Scott: So if you don't put them all together in one place, I can't even do more than one at a time.
Rym: Well, here's the real problem.
Rym: It's that computers like evolved to a certain point and we solved all these problems on the computer because it's a multi-purpose device and it's open Like completely open unless it's an Apple and even then it's relatively open.
Rym: It's a computer.
Rym: if someone makes program You can just install it.
Rym: So like we evolved to a certain point we we as nerds who use our computers to the fullest have these expectations.
Rym: But now because we're mobile we're nerds who walk around a lot.
Rym: so now that we've got smartphones we carry the smartphone everywhere and There are tasks that our computers are perfect at that.
Rym: We only did on the computer because we didn't have a computer that was in our pocket.
Rym: Now we have a computer in our pocket.
Rym: So we want to do all this stuff primarily on the phone.
Rym: But the phone can't do it as well as the computer can and the first.
Scott: it's only frustrating because there's nothing wrong with the hardware.
Scott: It's simply that someone did not write the software or will not allow the software to be written.
Scott: There is no technological reason.
Scott: It could not be done.
Scott: Luckily should not be.
Rym: it will be done in the long run.
Rym: This is all just a conversion smart.
Rym: I've had everything wrong.
Scott: the reason we're talking about this is because of Windows Mobile 7.
Rym: Yes, Windows Mobile 7 is basically another pillar in this gigantic vehicle Eddie.
Scott: Yes So here is my prediction for Windows Mobile 7, right?
Rym: Let's see if we have the same prediction.
Scott: So you look at it and you say, okay, it's like zoom phone basically, right?
Scott: You know the UI is you know what you might like it.
Scott: You might not like it.
Scott: You know the Facebook integration is really heavy.
Scott: The thing is here's here's what it's got ready number one.
Scott: It's Microsoft.
Scott: So it's got all the exchange corporate stuff that anyone could possibly need therefore Blackberry.
Scott: Well, why do you need the blackberry anymore?
Scott: Well, the one thing the blackberry still has is got the keyboard.
Scott: So the need for the corporate people who basically write crazy long emails on their phones.
Scott: You got to make a Windows Mobile 7 phone with the keyboard Which I'm sure they will make because it's not gonna be like the iPhone where there's only one phone.
Scott: This is an OS that's gonna go on many phone.
Rym: I was watching a bunch of videos about it and the Microsoft guy I skipped through this part But I remember him saying something about like what is required and what isn't required in the hardware.
Rym: They're gonna use keyboard optional like he was like, yeah, it doesn't matter.
Scott: Yeah, so yeah people there is an on-screen keyboard obviously because you have a capacitive touchscreen Absolutely necessary, but you know, there's gonna be one that has a keyboard that will please the corporate people and there'll be ones without You know, the thing is right.
Scott: in addition to that.
Scott: It also is soon.
Scott: So it's got your music and your video and all that stuff that you know, nothing but the iPhone does.
Scott: That's the thing with the iPhone that people still no one talks about except me.
Scott: I feel like is that okay?
Scott: the iPhones closed.
Scott: Okay, whatever whatever whatever Android your mom but the iPhone.
Scott: if I had an Android phone I would probably still need to have an iPod nano because the Android is not good, you know I mean it does it but it's not good if audio and video and music and podcasts, you know This is Google listen and stuff but it's not as good as having an iPod and the iPhone is an iPod
Rym: and the the pre is even worse at that because it had the like the good hack together integration with iTunes Which gave me about 60% of what I needed from it and it was good enough.
Rym: and then Apple decided to break all that.
Scott: Android is like 80% but it's not a hundred percent.
Scott: You know, it's all about the if I can carry one less thing in my pocket.
Scott: That is so much a bigger difference in my daily life.
Rym: See sadly, I've gotten to the point to where I feel like at least for the next many years I'm gonna just have to have a smartphone and completely separate from that an iPhone some sort of like Apple media playing device.
Scott: Yeah, the I mean the new iPod nano - is so crazy awesome.
Scott: That's a fucking video camera.
Scott: I mean good God Yep, and it's right.
Scott: It's really there is nothing to complain about with the iPod nano, right?
Scott: What can you possibly complain about with it?
Scott: Nothing?
Rym: So, you know what I can complain about.
Rym: It doesn't just download podcasts over the air.
Scott: That's what nothing does though.
Scott: I know right so it's not.
Scott: you can't Complain about them not doing something.
Scott: Oh, it's doing it.
Rym: What's going to that stupid integration with Ford cars?
Rym: That is like.
Rym: our only hope God is that that Microsoft.
Scott: Microsoft is doing that.
Rym: Yeah so my only hope is that that thing will finally be the point at which I can just have Podcasts that I just listen to on my phone.
Scott: the Android does it with Google listen, but Google listen doesn't like sink and down I don't know.
Scott: You know, it's not exactly the same kind of thing Because it's got it that no one does both.
Rym: They either let you sink from a computer and then listen or they let you listen while you have an internet connection But as soon as you go like into a tunnel you lose it.
Scott: Well, the Google listen like caches heavily so it'll download.
Rym: it'll try to download the whole podcast But you can't like switch it up while you're in the tunnel.
Rym: It doesn't like keep you try.
Scott: Yeah, if you try to start a new podcast in the tunnel I don't think that Google listen will be able to play it.
Rym: So listen kids.
Rym: obvious app that for like Android that would make everyone happy.
Rym: Just have a podcast II or internet media listening watching device.
Rym: There's video and audio and all it has to do is you say what things you want to listen to and how much space?
Rym: Or how many whatevers you want to alligate to it and it'll always keep the most recent and episodes cached on the phone And it'll let you listen to anything streaming as long as you have a connection
Scott: and then you know If you do want to stream something, it'll download it And if you're done listening to something you can delete it and free up space for something else.
Rym: Yeah Just have a little option of I'm done with this or not not deleting or undeleting.
Rym: just I've already listened to this and it still Won't get rid of it until you know, it has to roll over because it ran out of space in its cache.
Rym: Yeah, no one's even tried to do anything close to that.
Scott: Nope, not even remotely.
Scott: So the thing is right.
Scott: this Windows mobile it's got it's got a zoom So it's like.
Scott: well if I've got one of those that now has sort of jumped ahead in that Well, look there is now it's not just the iPhone anymore.
Scott: There is another phone that also is as good at music and video as the iPhone is and it has you know The they support like the fancy OLED screens like the Zune HD.
Scott: So it might actually be better than the iPhone at audio and video.
Rym: two more than X, right?
Scott: So that's a big shocker.
Scott: Now.
Scott: Here's the thing.
Scott: I don't think it's actually going to Compete with the iPhone in a direct way.
Scott: I don't see people who are iPhone people going for the windows phone.
Rym: You know, it competes with the with the iPhone in the same way that PCs or Dells just compete with Macs.
Rym: I mean some people were like not really in the sense that eventually every now and then you'll snipe or someone who like would be Buying the next Apple product like some nerd points out.
Rym: Hey that Dell is twice as fast and half as expensive Mmm, but otherwise, you know, it's not direct competition.
Rym: They're competing with blackberry.
Scott: Yes I think what's gonna happen here is unless blackberry can step up their game that in the long run not in the short run Right, but in the long run as corporate IT places slowly switch to Windows 7 and slowly They're blackberries die and they need to buy new phones.
Scott: They're gonna get these Microsoft Windows Mobile 7 phones instead of the blackberry or in the very least They're gonna stop paying for blackberry enterprise server.
Scott: Right and you people don't realize you think oh iPhone is the number one smartphone Not really black.
Scott: in terms of smartphone market share blackberry is way way way ahead of everybody else Simply because most people don't buy smartphones.
Scott: Here's what we'll do if I normal phones.
Scott: So most smartphones are the ones people get from work for free which are blackberries straight up a hundred percent.
Rym: What would do?
Rym: it is if the blackberry enterprise server equivalent for the Windows 7 phone?
Rym: Which is was was just exchange, but it is just exchange Yes, but if like exchange just had like the phone tab and you could do everything I do with like it does.
Scott: it's had that for a long time.
Rym: With these phones integrated with everything that blackberry can do Remote wiping phones remotes, you know all the things you need to be able to do for corporate compliance.
Scott: Jay I'm pretty sure exchange already does that for the windows mobile six and a half phones.
Scott: So why wouldn't it do it for the windows mobile seven phone?
Rym: Are you sure though?
Scott: I'm pretty sure cuz how come?
Rym: no one uses them in a corporate setting.
Scott: people do use them in a corporate not enough for it To matter.
Scott: I think it's just cuz you know, the blackberry name and marketing and all those sorts of things and you know Whatever, I don't know because at least every big company I've worked with always they want to use something other than blackberry.
Rym: They always explore the options and they always come back saying yeah, it doesn't offer this thing that by law.
Rym: We're required to have.
Scott: I'm not Informed in these matters so but you know I cannot imagine that my you know that Microsoft would not include the necessary things in exchange for their own phone.
Rym: Well, I think the fact that they're launching this the way they are and especially looking at the UI like the way it's used They're definitely.
Rym: this is marketed differently from other windows mobile devices.
Rym: This is joy.
Rym: This is the convergence between the business phone and the home phone Mmm, so people like me who have like a work blackberry and a home pre Well are probably best served in the long run sadly not by a droid but by some sort of Windows device That'll do the work stuff and do the home.
Scott: It's also kind of crazy that his Microsoft Office in it like all of Microsoft Office.
Scott: Yeah, not like part at all.
Scott: It's.
Scott: it's got.
Scott: you know PowerPoint and exchange and word and the whole thing.
Rym: My pre's got something halfway there.
Rym: I've got this Microsoft doc view that came with it that I can read any Microsoft like document.
Rym: Yeah, and I can edit some of them.
Scott: Yeah, I mean like, you know iPad was talking about how to have I work.
Scott: Yeah, well, it's like.
Scott: well Windows Mobile 7 has Microsoft Office.
Scott: It's like game over right there.
Scott: Yeah, so I I foresee Windows Mobile 7 being a lot like Windows in the long run.
Scott: Where is it just dominates market share because it'll slowly eat away all of blackberries market.
Rym: There are two markets that it'll probably never penetrate into and those markets will become blackberries like long-term like permanent business plan Government and military because those people never fucking change anything.
Scott: No, they'll never change.
Scott: Did you ever see that video of them asking Hillary Clinton to install Firefox at the State Department?
Scott: Maybe I'll make that my thing of the day.
Scott: Oh Next time.
Rym: Well that went on a while.
Rym: So things of the day.
Scott: Oh shit.
Scott: So I was gonna do a different thing of the day, but then I was reminded of this video.
Scott: So why not?
Scott: I'll just make it the thing of the day.
Rym: I had not seen this video until just now.
Scott: this is from July of 2009. if you're you know, it's not new antique antique.
Scott: it's Basically, it's a video of the US State Department.
Scott: It's basically like I guess it's like the employee meeting.
Rym: That's the same kind of thing.
Rym: Like when I worked at IBM or all those big companies.
Rym: The government's no different.
Rym: They'll have like big Q&A with big wig in the company and everyone asked these pre scripted trip to kind of like lame Questions like why can't we do this?
Rym: Why don't we get more Vegas?
Scott: Someone's like why don't we use fucking Firefox?
Scott: Why are we using piece of shit ie right?
Scott: Sure, I get the impression the thing is right.
Scott: you think oh man people are so stupid right, but like the whole audience is like.
Scott: So it's like well smart people work in the State Department.
Rym: the best part is that Hillary Clinton Clearly is taken aback and has no idea what this is.
Scott: She's like.
Scott: she's like oh the whole room knows something and thinks something is awesome And I have no fucking clue because I don't use a computer.
Scott: I just have someone who does that for me.
Rym: Hey Answer the question and the other guy gave like the stop stock corporate answer of it cost money.
Scott: Yeah, it's not actually freaks.
Scott: You have to pay money to install it and stuff Which is technically true, but that you had the money you would save from people not having viruses and ie.
Scott: You know if you limited you guys what you could do is you could limit their ie's so that the ie's could only visit Intranet sites which are the ones that you might have that might be ie only and then you could require all out Internet browsing to go in Firefox
Rym: yep And thus
Scott: you would not.
Scott: you would eliminate viruses and spywares and malware.
Rym: so much really to do.
Scott: just use Windows group Any money that it cost to get Firefox on there and to update it and such and to make sure you know Prevent people from doing weird extensions or whatever you would save.
Scott: well I mean like in my company we actually don't even need to do a study to figure this out.
Rym: I'll just tell you we actually push Firefox and ie updates simultaneously as part of all our other updates.
Rym: So we force everyone to have Firefox and we keep it up-to-date for them, so it's just always there always works.
Rym: Yeah Of course I also have Chrome installed because it actually works better for a lot of our internal stuff.
Rym: Then ie that it was designed for because we use a lot of Ajax and the one thing that Chrome is great at is Anything with Ajax?
Scott: Any JavaScript anything.
Scott: Chrome is the fastest any client-side stuff.
Rym: Chrome just seems to handle a lot better.
Rym: Only Chrome could properly block ads.
Scott: yeah, well, I mean there is an ad block extension But it's a little it.
Rym: basically the ads go and then disappear.
Rym: Yeah great I don't want the ad to download at all yeah, and then you know there's other things that chromed.
Scott: You know it just doesn't have the features that Firefox has when fully extended.
Scott: you know I mean you know they do have that little developer thing not as good as firebug.
Scott: You know they got.
Scott: it's just you know Stuff.
Scott: yep, what's your thing of the day?
Rym: so in Arizona?
Rym: Oh of course you remember?
Rym: You know riding the bus as a kid there were kids.
Rym: Riding the bus was always annoying because kids are loud and punching each other and you know the bully.
Rym: kids are bullying the nerd kids.
Scott: And you missed us.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: randomly Something.
Rym: someone missed their bus on the way to work during the snowstorm and my boss's boss starts singing crisscross.
Rym: I miss the bus.
Rym: no you're shitting me and everyone in the room is like What are you singing?
Rym: and I'm your boss's boss?
Scott: This is a hive.
Rym: yes, and I'm like.
Rym: I just look at him.
Rym: I'm like I saw them in concert And no one no one had a clue what the hell that was all about.
Rym: so we reminisced about crisscross wearing the pants backwards Missing the bus missing the bus and jump jump jump.
Scott: Yep, one word songs.
Scott: and the thing is they had more lyrics than gwk though I mean jump and miss.
Scott: I miss the bus is four words.
Scott: You know it's like They had all that six words, so it's like parties is one word.
Rym: You know they had other words than I miss the bus in.
Rym: I miss the bus.
Rym: I haven't heard that song since there's a lyrical narrative of the touching story of a young man who misses the bus.
Scott: I gotta go find that on YouTube.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: I gotta see if I can find videos of their concerts.
Scott: Oh shit.
Rym: Yeah, that was one of the earlier concerts.
Rym: I went to in my entire life.
Rym: It was awesome.
Rym: I remember thinking I was so cool.
Scott: Anyway, crisscross miss the bus here.
Rym: It is great, so Buses generally suck ass especially for nerdy and smart kids.
Rym: you just want to like read their book with the dragon on the cover Or like talk about the D&D game, but you know the other stupid kids are throwing stuff at each other.
Rym: And there's fights on the bus and all that.
Rym: yes and in Arizona and in a lot of places There are serious problems on buses like serious fights.
Rym: You know they put cameras on the buses.
Rym: You know deal with okay?
Scott: We had fights and cameras on our buses.
Scott: I'll see how it's any different unless unless they're stabbing we just had fist fight.
Rym: Yeah, the fights are getting more and more serious like serious injuries.
Scott: big trouble, so we never had serious injuries.
Rym: We just had fights on the bus in Vail, Arizona Where there are serious behavioral problems on the public buses because the bus rides can be up to 45 minutes long for a lot of These kids.
Rym: uh-oh attention span short bus ride long for a couple hundred bucks.
Rym: They put a wireless router that just gets internet from the cell network on the bus on all the buses and They give the kids free internet while they're on the bus.
Scott: who the kids?
Scott: off laptops?
Rym: Yeah, netbooks.
Rym: every freaking kid has a netbook outside of like a fourth grade.
Rym: Well, these are like middle school.
Rym: Okay Elementary kids don't have the stabbing problems as much as the middle school and high school kids.
Rym: But what they discovered is that if they give the kids free internet all the behavioral problems stop straight away.
Rym: There is no trouble on the buses at all.
Rym: The kids are all completely quiet just on Facebook the whole time.
Scott: Yeah Listen, any babysitter could have told you like a hundred years ago.
Scott: You slap on a Disney movie.
Scott: kid sits down shuts up.
Scott: That's it.
Rym: I don't think a Disney movies gonna stop the sixth grade punk from stabbing the other sixth grade pump punk.
Scott: Listen, you know you could do right if I was a bus driver and see I could save a lot of money because I just Get a TV with a DVD player a lot cheaper than an internet, right?
Scott: Put the same DVD on every day right, but it would be an awesome DVD like it wouldn't be.
Rym: What's it gonna be that you're not gonna get sick like diehard or something?
Scott: Right, it's something that they would.
Scott: the kids would think was totally awesome and special like holy shit or like the predator, right?
Scott: And then like the kids would build up all these rituals around it.
Scott: You know like like every time during a certain scene they would do stuff and it would be like a total thing And they'd remember that for the rest of their lives.
Scott: every time the predator kills that guy They Yeah, and then I could get the kids like act it out or they'd remember all the lines and we could do fun stuff.
Scott: It would be a cool time Not.
Scott: instead of internetting it would bring all the kids together around some sort of arts.
Rym: I was thinking about why this work if you consider the predator be arts, which I do.
Scott: Oh, so I would just show all of hokuto no Ken new episode each day.
Scott: There's 180 days of school.
Scott: We would finish the show before the year was over.
Scott: Watch hokuto no Ken in the morning.
Scott: I mean you could watch Rosa for sign the way home.
Rym: then you get the next year.
Rym: You know the seventh graders are like.
Rym: they've seen it all already and the sixth graders Watch Pokemon will watch whatever one episode a day.
Rym: So the sixth graders like oh, no, what's gonna happen to catch your own?
Rym: the seventh graders have the law.
Rym: Oh, well, you haven't even seen row.
Scott: you watch a bus ride right every day.
Scott: Imagine like a bus got like 40 kids.
Scott: They all go what?
Scott: all at the same time.
Rym: But I realized why this internet thing is working so well and it's not just the babysitter syndrome.
Scott: They would fight each other but they would use hokuto.
Scott: no Ken, so it would be permissible.
Scott: Not because of the southern cross.
Scott: It would solve the fighting problem in the reverse direction.
Scott: It would make the fights, you know finishable.
Rym: But and there are a lot of like anecdotes and like kids talking about it.
Rym: And I think what's going on here Is that all the nerdy kids who would get picked on or who don't have anyone to talk to are just talking to all the other nerdy kids elsewhere in the world with internet.
Rym: because some nerdy kid in like Arizona has more in common with the nerdy kid in Germany and the Nerdy kid in like Australia than he does with all the other kids on his bus,
Scott: dude I would just fucking bring my DS and play games If I had it, you know I don't even need fucking internet on the bus.
Scott: if I was a kid today on the bus Everyone would have a DS and everyone be playing.
Scott: no player.
Rym: This is the thing.
Rym: The kids do have these things but there's still behavioral problems.
Scott: The behavioral problems only stop even behavioral problems with everyone playing DS Scott.
Rym: Yeah The whole point of this article is that the behavioral problems only stopped suddenly like a hundred percent when they gave them internet.
Rym: But nothing distracted them nothing they could bring.
Rym: because thing, you know the nerdy kid with the DS is playing his game and the other nerdy kid with his dragon book is reading his dragon book and The.
Rym: the problem kid, you know takes the kids DS and breaks it.
Scott: Why doesn't he have his own DS?
Scott: Why isn't he playing against the nerdy kid?
Scott: because it's the social stuff.
Rym: This is what matters the fact that the kids want social interaction many of them But there's no one near them that they want to socially interact with.
Rym: So what happens when you give them internet is the kids who are all internet are gonna talk to all their internet friends elsewhere.
Rym: I mean look at how many kids today.
Rym: They basically can't wait to get the hell out of high school because they have real friends on the internet and they know that when They get to college they'll just be real friends with the same kinds of people.
Rym: and the kids who don't have that are the ones who are gonna talk to each other and do the stuff on the bus.
Rym: and The fact that giving kids the internet causes the problems to go away But DS is and books and TV and all these other things don't really points that social interaction is the root cause.
Scott: I think fist of the North Star would keep them under control.
Rym: possibly It's hard to say that might also lead to serious bodily injury But that would be okay.
Scott: bodily injury Like I already said it would not be like, you know when kids tried to do fake wrestling moves.
Scott: It would be like, you know, one kid would hit the other kid his head would explode and I'll be that.
Rym: So a long time ago Google decided to make something that the world had not really seen.
Rym: they made a social network.
Scott: Well, I mean they didn't make or cut like oh they sort of did like a guy who worked for them made it But he sort of know didn't he make it?
Scott: but then Google bought him.
Rym: so it was something weird I forget exactly what happened but or cut appeared and all of us jumped on it like oh, wow This is awesome.
Rym: And then about six months later the nation of Brazil discovered this thing and that was the end of it.
Rym: Mmm, I believe it's still used in Brazil and nowhere else.
Scott: It says it's one of the Wikipedia says it's one of the most visited websites in India and Brazil.
Rym: Oh India, huh?
Scott: 51% of orcas users from Brazil filed by India with 20% and us with 17.
Rym: What those 70% must be?
Rym: people who came from Brazil?
Scott: Maybe there or India you could be.
Rym: it's otherwise it's impossible to use.
Scott: It's 60th in the world and has more than a hundred million active users.
Rym: But it's funny how you know.
Rym: people always come to me and say things like why are you not on Facebook?
Rym: You're so internet II and you're so like I had to the curve and all this internet stuff.
Rym: and yet you don't use these social Networks and all I have to do is point back and say I used the first social network and I realized everything that's wrong With them.
Rym: Mm-hmm but the thing was orchid failed.
Rym: and Now that I look at Facebook and basically I didn't realize this fundamental truth about social networks until oh shit Google's trying again with Google buzz.
Rym: Google buzz is kind of doing things the opposite way that everyone else did.
Rym: then look at Facebook and or cut and all these things.
Rym: They're walled gardens.
Rym: everyone looks at them as though they're walled gardens.
Rym: They they're like.
Rym: I will put my information in this thing and I'll interact with people entirely within the context of this thing.
Rym: and recently Facebook has like their Interactions to the outside like it can be.
Scott: Facebook has had that for a long time.
Scott: They had Facebook connect and they you can make a Facebook app and Facebook can talk to any other website.
Scott: You just got to go through their API and Twitter is the same way.
Scott: Twitter as an API and Google has had open social For quite a while as well.
Rym: Yeah But people didn't use that stuff a lot until people started using Twitter.
Rym: Like a lot of people unless someone else like set up an integration for them.
Rym: They just lived in Facebook land and then they had the rest of their internet life separate from Facebook land.
Rym: Mm-hmm But I think the whole walled garden thing is the cause of a lot of the problems we have with social networks especially when it comes to privacy and Google with buzz seems to be taking kind of the opposite approach of that.
Rym: It's not really a walled garden it's just an interface.
Rym: like your point from Google just goes out in every direction with every possible means from by default from the start and I think that's why all the people who use Facebook Seem to hate Google buzz and all the people who have not been using social networks up till now seem to love Google buzz.
Rym: Because it's weird, you know you look online and there's a lot of a lot of what people say about Google buzz.
Rym: It's really really negative.
Rym: people really hate it and people like well I'm not using Gmail anymore and all these concerns about privacy and like it's all the news about it is bad Except among the really tech people who don't use Facebook.
Scott: even the really tech people, you know If you look on like all the nerdy soup like the super nerdy sites like the hacker news They're all saying the same shit.
Scott: They're saying all Google buzz privacy fail, but they use Facebook.
Scott: No, they don't use Facebook either.
Rym: I think a lot of them.
Scott: They'll just use Twitter.
Scott: Some of them probably use Facebook, but you know, I think a lot of them use Facebook.
Rym: It's hard to not use Facebook.
Rym: Yeah I mean, I've only gotten away with it because I have my own private forum and that kind of does all the things.
Scott: They don't have Facebook, but I don't use it.
Scott: You know, I point Twitter forwards to it, but that's it.
Rym: Yeah, I very pointedly avoid it because I don't want to have to maintain it.
Rym: I don't want because it'll diverge like that face of Rym on the internet would rapidly diverge from my face Mmm, you know in possibly a bad way.
Rym: Also people might message me in it and expect me to respond.
Scott: Yeah, people message me in it and I just ignore it.
Scott: Well, you know if people like try to send me like say join this club I just click the ignore button if they give me an invitation to event.
Rym: I just say no Yeah, I don't even want to have to click.
Scott: I don't know I could just ignore it, but I'd set it up.
Scott: So it sends me an email, you know just in case cuz you never know Someone might eat send me a message on Facebook that says hey want a million dollars.
Rym: So I don't want that risk.
Rym: I don't want the risk of there ever being communication.
Rym: that matters over a chance.
Scott: It goes through email, that's why I said so.
Rym: it's not an unintended communication from Facebook.
Rym: Just by the mechanism design of Facebook could slip through and I don't want that either.
Scott: Whatever Is that anyway?
Scott: Yeah, I think the people going nuts over this privacy thing.
Scott: I think that the big problem is People have like too much Emotional investment in like what it says on the screen.
Scott: It's weird because at the one hand they don't read what's on the screen But on the other hand certain things they read on the screen Like they care about them too much.
Scott: Well think of this.
Rym: they hate.
Rym: they'd hate reading what's on the screen, but they love inputting data About themselves on the screen, but they only want certain people to see that data.
Scott: Yeah, and it's like, you know, you have.
Scott: I think there's actually room for a third place here, right?
Scott: So you got the one place which is Twitter, right and Twitter you post something and then the whole world can see it.
Scott: And if you do the stupid private thing, what the hell is the point?
Scott: Yeah, I never understood Why they offer that feature, right?
Scott: So Twitter is you just broadcast to the world and that's that.
Scott: and who cares if someone follows you or you follow someone?
Scott: It's not it doesn't really well.
Rym: it gets around the spam problem Just with a very simple network of trust that you only follow people who care about.
Scott: you can't get spammed unless you follow people who suck Yep, so and then you got Facebook, which is you know was originally more like or cut but then moved To being more like Twitter where it's you know with the status update model, right?
Rym: Yeah, of course or cut had the weird problem of it had all that status stuff and that's actually what brought it down in The end because people could respond to friends and friends of friends and it was made.
Rym: there was zero spam protection.
Rym: Mmm Facebook has a lot of things to protect you from I guess obvious like Viagra.
Rym: spam Yeah, but it doesn't protect you from your friends being dumbass.
Scott: Facebook or cut also had the groups like you join a group and then You would get all sorts of shit for that.
Rym: Yeah, well because a million people speaking Portuguese would join your group and talk about things unrelated to the group.
Scott: Yeah, I never understood what was going on.
Scott: That's not reading again.
Scott: Yeah, but the thing with Facebook right is that you're only with your friends, but people seem to strangely really care, right?
Scott: They don't care if you're following or not following on Twitter At least I don't think they are.
Scott: but they really care if your friends on Facebook.
Scott: So it's like if you don't friend someone who knows you.
Scott: it's like they'll feel bad and you feel obligated.
Scott: You know, I don't feel that way at all.
Rym: It's like it comes out of the whole walled garden mentality.
Rym: They look at Facebook as this thing separate from other things.
Rym: So and all the drama about Facebook comes of that idea.
Rym: I mean look at you know Say like a lot of people have the problem of their boss sees that they're on Facebook and ask them for a friend invite Mm-hmm.
Rym: And now they don't want to actually say yes because they don't want their boss to see all the stuff that they shared with just their Friends, but they don't want to say no to their boss because then their boss gets mad at them And it's a no-win situation because they have these weird Expectations that Facebook does not account for and inside of the walled garden.
Rym: There's no context for dealing with them.
Scott: Yeah, and I think also that Something on I don't know go nowhere with that I was thinking about.
Scott: I've had something and then I thought about the car that I had to go pick up when it's fixed.
Rym: Well again, look at the walled garden.
Rym: Another problem is that people expect that they can control What level people see of them like when they use Facebook.
Rym: they expect that?
Rym: All right, I will put this picture of me naked and drunk and like punching some like puppy in the face.
Rym: You know, this is just what happened at a party.
Rym: They want to share it with all their friends.
Rym: they put it in Facebook and they say only my friends can see this and They somehow expect that that will protect them and that that picture is never going to appear anywhere else on the internet ever.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, that's something you got to realize, you know, you might post something on Facebook.
Scott: Let's say I only have one Facebook friend in the world.
Scott: It's Rym and I post a picture of me I don't know dancing stupidly.
Scott: that is already on flicker like Rym can just take the picture and put it on the Internet's right?
Scott: So any privacy that you think you have is totally an illusion right?
Scott: people are all upset.
Scott: Oh privacy this privacy that?
Scott: no really you don't have any.
Scott: if it's on the internet It's all.
Scott: you might as well be on the front page of the newspaper Anywhere on the internet no matter how private you think it is.
Scott: you make a flicker account you turn off all public photo posting.
Scott: You turn off everything.
Scott: you put it on flicker.
Scott: Maybe some guy at flicker is searching through and he sees your picture and he's like, oh, that's the best picture.
Scott: It sneaks out somewhere.
Scott: No one knows who did it.
Scott: So he doesn't get in trouble.
Scott: And then what are you doing?
Rym: Well, the trouble isn't some.
Rym: I mean you can't do things privately if you either use your own servers or software.
Rym: That's true you could but the trade-off there is that you can either do stuff in your own Completely private walled garden or you have to let other people in which basically gives you no privacy.
Scott: unless you as soon as you let One person in you're letting everybody in.
Rym: but every day people want to share information about themselves.
Rym: They want to have like their photo stream and their updates and everything.
Rym: But they have this weird hang up where they only want them to go to certain people which is also fine.
Rym: But they don't trust the people the other people enough or they rely on trusting the other people too much and if you go too much in either direction, you're screwed and They run into these weird social situations where they have their real friends.
Rym: But then there's people who think that they're their friends but they're not really and they're Confronted in these walled gardens with the fact that they have to either Friend the person and give them access to the secret side of their lives or not friend them and reveal the fact that they Don't actually like this person.
Scott: Yeah, it's like because people are you know, not high-quality people.
Scott: They have drama in their lives.
Scott: then the drama the the internet forces the exposure of this drama due to the framework.
Scott: you know the way the social network dictates for relationships, yep, and Google Buzz.
Rym: I think the reason it's getting so much flack from so many people is that they have all these walled garden expectations.
Rym: But Google is taking the exact opposite model and making it not at all a walled garden.
Rym: It's just kind of a self-publishing thing.
Rym: There's just you and you just publish out to the world.
Rym: and if you don't want to publish out to the world don't.
Rym: and that's it.
Rym: There's kind of no middle ground.
Scott: There's a private button and a public button.
Scott: I don't see what the problem was that people had, you know It's like.
Scott: well if I have a post a funny picture I can put I can click specifically who I wanted to go to and then push a button.
Rym: Well their problem What were the biggest problem?
Rym: I've seen people complaining about is that kind of?
Rym: by default if you're using it It'll add to the top of your friends list the people you email most often.
Scott: Yeah, and obviously there are people you email a lot that are not your friends.
Scott: You don't any friends with that.
Scott: There was a big popular post that was like, you know abusive ex-boyfriend Automatically followed.
Scott: it's like so just unfollow the dude, you know, it's like.
Scott: what's the big deal?
Rym: Well, I think what is gonna come down to is that people who I kind of get like when a walled garden is useful and And people who understand what is possible with internet privacy and what isn't are probably all going to migrate toward Google buzz or toward nothing and Everyone else is going to stay on Facebook.
Rym: I don't think Google buzz actually competes with Facebook except that People who wanted something more like buzz who use Facebook just because it's the default that exists are going to move if they can.
Scott: I don't see a lot of people going to Google buzz because every post I see is how do I turn it off?
Scott: It's gonna be like Windows Vista where people have a false perception, you know And thus they all just turn it off and hate it.
Rym: and whatever the gods get in my gmail Google buzz is brilliant because in the long run I think the way it's gonna go is that the things you publish out of it It doesn't even need to be buzz.
Rym: It could be anything.
Scott: Yeah, my hope is that it will be like Google talk where first no one really used it But eventually everyone used it just because it was in their Gmail on their face all the time.
Rym: I think it's gonna be more like Effectively giving everyone the means to run their own Social network, but it's not a walled garden It's just.
Rym: I put my updates out and they appear in whatever format everyone else would see them in.
Rym: You know, it puts.
Rym: it pushes them to Twitter.
Rym: It pushes them to Facebook.
Rym: It pushes them to websites.
Rym: But for me buzz is like the command console where I am sending out all the updates to everywhere.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: That's my hope for it.
Rym: That's what I will use it for.
Scott: Yeah, because you're not you know, you have nothing to hide.
Scott: don't give a shit about suit privacy.
Rym: I do have things to hide and you know where those are you hiding?
Rym: we know what those are in our form.
Rym: You know We have the the GeekNights farm and everyone uses it and we have the private part of it.
Rym: just for our actual friends We made our own wall guard.
Scott: Yeah, but I'm not trying to keep that private because there's stuff in there I don't want anyone to see.
Scott: I keep it private.
Scott: private because then people you know It's not relevant to those guys.
Scott: So they would be they just be like what the fuck is this shit?
Rym: I don't know why you're trying to argue with me.
Rym: I'm saying the exact same thing.
Rym: I keep it private because it's basically walled gardens have a place for example in the private form is where I'll say hey having a Party at my apartment.
Rym: Here's the address and the time.
Scott: who cares of people?
Rym: I don't care if anyone knows the address in the time, you know I don't want to tell everyone in the world when I'm having a private get-together because then people will show up.
Scott: Did you tell you know you got this visibly say hey you and you and you are invited and you're not.
Rym: and That's how I use the forum.
Rym: I know that in my walled garden only X people are there.
Scott: Yeah, but the point is is that I think people are just too concerned with like, you know privacy in general And they're also, you know get upset when they see things that they don't want to see.
Scott: You know like that person who just saw that their abusive ex-boyfriend's email address is listed in like the following thing Automatically got upset.
Scott: It's like it's just a name on a screen.
Scott: You can get rid of it.
Scott: Why are you upset just over the appearance of it?
Scott: I get I get requests from people very very frequently on the forum.
Scott: They want the ability to like block posts and I'm like just ignore it.
Scott: If there's a thread that doesn't interest you just scroll past it.
Scott: if there's a comment that is someone is you know You don't like that person.
Scott: just don't read their comment.
Scott: Just you know use your scroll wheel.
Scott: doo doo doo and people have a really hard time with this.
Scott: like they're like.
Scott: no I need to block it I need to make it go away.
Scott: and what I think what buzz does that makes a lot of people upset?
Scott: is that because Google is spidering the internet and gets all this information.
Scott: It's grabbing all this stuff and putting it in your face and you need to do stuff to make it go away.
Scott: You know and me I don't need.
Scott: I don't have this compulsion to click and make it go away.
Scott: I'll just scroll past it.
Scott: but other people they had to keep clicking to make it go away.
Scott: And what is it when you're clicking to make things go away?
Scott: It's like deleting spam from your email.
Scott: That's what it's like.
Scott: So they feel like Google buzz is spam.
Rym: Whereas something like Twitter or Facebook is most of the complaints I've seen actually weren't along those lines.
Rym: They were along the lines of information about them got out that they didn't want out.
Rym: And the biggest one is still the contact thing Like.
Rym: basically it would show other people The people you're emailing the most often and a lot of people were not comfortable with the fact that that information became public Automatically.
Scott: Oh, no, you know who I'm emailing because I'm you know, I have secret emails to to like.
Scott: You know this this porn site and now you know that I'm emailing this porn site.
Rym: That was a big problem with Firefox when they when they like change the way it would do a lot of like bookmarks and suggestions and stuff and it would like.
Rym: people would always have like, you know, ten layers of bookmarks and then under like the kittens and the puppies and Like the taxes way at the bottom was a folder called like documents and then there was all the porn links.
Scott: Why do you even bookmark a porn site?
Scott: You can't remember the name of it.
Scott: You can't just search for it on Google again.
Rym: But this was a problem because you know Like it's just be a 45 year old husband who hides his porn links from his wife.
Rym: Suddenly the porn links are like on the front of Firefox like here are the pages you visit most often.
Scott: Yeah, and here's the other problem, right?
Scott: I think this is actually this is.
Scott: I think this is kind of why I don't have a problem with it.
Scott: Other people do right is like.
Scott: I look at that person and I'm saying why is you know?
Scott: The technology is sort of exposing you and making you confront a problem in your real life.
Scott: Why are you hiding your porn links from your wife who is supposed to be the most important person in the world in your life?
Scott: If you you know married them, right if I had a wife and I had porn it would be like hey honey Let's watch some porn That.
Scott: so the people have privacy issues with this privacy stuff Right?
Scott: are people who have personal issues that they need to resolve and then they wouldn't have such a problem with it.
Scott: like if I'm emailing someone else way often and You're bothered by that then either that's you have an issue or I have an issue.
Scott: I'm keeping something secret from you.
Scott: Like if my girlfriend sees that I'm emailing this other girl constantly Obviously, I'm just a shithead who's cheating.
Scott: or you know She is Jealous and doesn't realize that that person's just a friend and is all bitchy.
Scott: in which case why is she my girlfriend?
Rym: See it's tricky because you don't want to go all the way down the slope of.
Rym: if you got nothing to hide Then you don't care about people snooping on you.
Rym: I think it's more that people need to understand what is possible and what isn't with privacy.
Rym: on a fundamental level and independently people need to be able to confront the ugly truths about themselves and their friends and That's I think we're all.
Rym: 90% of the drama about privacy and social networks Facebook internet everything comes down to the fact that a lot of people have friends But they keep different of their friends at like different levels of information and they don't want Information to leak beyond all these kind of arbitrary boundaries they've set up in their own lives.
Rym: But at the same time they want to publish information To all their friends and they're not technical enough to do it on their own.
Rym: They're not good enough to do it in person Mm-hmm.
Scott: So I watched.
Scott: this is sort of relevant, right?
Scott: I watched The the TED talk of moot the fortune guy.
Scott: I still gotta watch that and he was talking about how you know the internet.
Scott: You know, he wants more things to be crazy.
Scott: anonymous like fortune is right.
Scott: So I was like, huh?
Scott: Maybe I will make something that is crazy anonymous like fortune but not fortune.
Rym: an anonymous social network.
Scott: That's completely and I wouldn't work as the social network is defined by identity.
Scott: It's just.
Scott: no couldn't do that.
Rym: You could do it.
Rym: you could do it if it was an anonymous social network where you create your persona and you use some Sort of a verifiable means of proving your identity when you're posting to it and you're doing stuff with it.
Scott: But then it's not anonymous.
Rym: It's anonymous in that you can prove that the person who made those posts before is the same person now.
Scott: But that's the point.
Scott: Is it anonymous means?
Scott: No, it's not every single post.
Rym: No, another way to have anonymous is that you have a verifiable identity that cannot be linked to your real identity.
Rym: You can have a separate completely like self-consistent identity that unless you fuck up is not linked to your real identity.
Scott: Yeah, but that's not that's not that's not the anonymous that we're talking about.
Rym: anonymous like fortune is, you know It's supposed you're saying anonymous capital a because anonymity means there are a lot of great fortune is I mean and not.
Scott: Fortune also has the feature where you can you know make an identity with a code so that you know people can verify you.
Scott: But you can also post completely anonymously.
Scott: No one even knows if that's a brand new person or and that's you know, you can't have that at all on a social network.
Scott: So, you know it just it's counter to the idea of a social network.
Rym: Well, but Scott you that's cuz.
Rym: you're using this very specific definition of anonymity.
Scott: That's what that's the kind of anonymous I was talking about.
Scott: So anyway, I think that we I'm trying to think of something I should make that is completely anonymous But on the other hand, I should also make something that is like the opposite of anonymous.
Scott: What it could be is make some sort of Facebook like thing, right?
Scott: Maybe even simpler than Facebook but make it like Real friends only because I've read a lot of these studies that show that even when people have like a Facebook They actually only communicate heavily with like four or five six people.
Scott: people have a very Small circle of people they actually communicate with extremely often like, you know wife girlfriend brother mom dad You know friend it's you know, that's pretty much it.
Scott: for like the vast majority of people statistically Like 90% of their communication is with like six people.
Rym: but what they do is they have like hundreds of Facebook friends and they watch all the update like they did passively consume the Updates from these other people but they don't actually interact except that those other people passively consume their updates.
Scott: so I'm gonna make some sort of social network right and the way it could work is You only are ever actually going to friend those six people.
Scott: That's the idea.
Scott: You're never gonna friend all these other people.
Rym: You're only gonna friend the real friends and it bears all 100% no matter what.
Scott: no Well, you know, I mean to those people, you know, yeah, that's the point.
Rym: Oh that you're right.
Scott: But the thing is how do you make it to where?
Scott: how do you friend someone?
Scott: Right?
Scott: How is that gonna work?
Scott: And the way it would work is you just sort of type in people that are your real friends and it doesn't send Requests to them right?
Scott: it just sort of.
Scott: you just type in a list of your real friends and then other people Type in a list of their real friends and where there is a match it will actually friend.
Rym: you Make an account for someone who I know doesn't have an account on it.
Rym: I pretend to be them and then I put in a list of everyone they know and wait for that and then I basically Man in the middle.
Scott: Okay that we have to solve these.
Scott: But you get the idea and that there would be some sort of system Compromise.
Scott: Yes, there would be some sort of system by which you would only actually friend the real friends.
Scott: You know if somebody was on it and they said hey, why don't you friend me on the thing?
Scott: You would say I'm not on the thing, you know You could just lie and they couldn't.
Scott: they wouldn't know if you were on there or not.
Scott: there would be no way for them to know whether you were there or not, so you could totally lie and You would only you know friend your mom dad brother girlfriend kids course.
Rym: at the same time I feel like with Facebook they should have grades of friends like.
Scott: well, that's what I actually do.
Scott: have that on Facebook I have to have a limb.
Scott: What I do is I friend everyone on Facebook who requests unless they're obviously like spam like, you know It's one of those fake Non-existent people and if it's someone I don't know I just check limited profile and if it's someone I do know then I just say yes,
Rym: but see I think it'd be interesting if you had a proper gradation of like say five levels and you just could have like.
Scott: You can say they have that.
Rym: you can set that up, but they don't give you control over everything.
Rym: No Facebook There are a lot of things where you can't control a hundred percent between different groups.
Rym: Like how much they see.
Scott: I'm pretty sure that you can say like, you know Anyone on this list allow them to do this and this and this but not this and this and this but a lot of those Lists a lot of those this and this and this is our all or nothing.
Scott: Well, they're like, you know post on my wall see my wall You know show their posts in my feed don't show their posts in my feed allowed them to see my address.
Scott: I love them to see my phone number.
Rym: one thing that orchid I remember.
Rym: I remember doing something along the lines of you kind of noted how much of a friend they were and You can.
Rym: I like that idea because you can have like your layers of friends very openly Like these are my best friends.
Rym: I'm friends with you.
Scott: Then you still then you still have that same problem where it's like, you know Request to be a friend with you and they put five and you put one.
Rym: But the thing is that is that has always been a problem in humanity.
Rym: That is just the fact that a lot of people have really fucked up social interactions with their neighbors and friends.
Scott: I hope my hope is that in people being forced to confront their social problems will fix them.
Scott: But I know that the reality that is probably not the case.
Scott: Yeah, but I it'll probably just make more drama.
Rym: I just think all the drama comes out of the fact that people have drama in their real lives and it just spills over into the privacy quote-unquote debate of social networks because Information kind of automatically exposes truth over time.
Scott: Yeah, this is see.
Scott: people have lately been talking about like, you know The old quote information wants to be free and people are like information doesn't want to be free information can't want anything.
Scott: And I'm like, wow way to not get a you know metaphor.
Rym: analogy more than information Reveals all that is hidden and in the end.
Rym: There's no way around.
Scott: Yes, the thing is what information wants to be free means right.
Scott: is that once a piece of information has been revealed Right, you cannot.
Scott: it is incredibly difficult to bottle it up.
Rym: He has been seen cannot to be as see.
Scott: keeping a secret requires lots of effort and energy and difficulty, right?
Scott: It's the momentum of information is to spread, you know the same way that it's hard to hold a boulder at the top of a hill But it's real easy to let the boulder roll down the hill.
Rym: Think about it where the drama comes from.
Rym: people they leak information out a little bit and then they don't want it to get any Further than it already got and if it does they try to like put it back in.
Scott: Yeah, you can't do that I mean or it's incredibly difficult to do so.
Scott: You know information wants to be free and that it is like a boulder at the top of a hill Once it is set loose once it is out of your mind and comes out of your mouth and someone hears it.
Scott: now It can be replicated trivially and spread around the whole world with no effort whatsoever.
Scott: Just like it requires no effort whatsoever To let the boulder row down the hill and crush the houses and the cars at the bottom.
Scott: But it requires a great deal of effort to like, you know, you just told someone oh shit Don't tell anyone that.
Scott: then you have to watch that person.
Scott: make sure they don't tell anyone that or just they do Right.
Scott: It's incredibly difficult to keep a secret any information, you know any information that has been let out.
Scott: it is Super impossible to not let it get out even farther and farther.
Rym: Information wants to be free means I want to pull the debate all the way back.
Scott: Once you have typed something into Facebook regardless of your Facebook settings You have effectively pushed the boulder over the top of the hill and it can just roll down.
Rym: So allow me to pull the argument all the way out now because this is where it's all going with.
Rym: so, you know Regardless of how much people want to have their walled gardens of you know, they want to publish their data, but they want walled gardens.
Rym: They only want to publish it to certain people and that works for things like I'm inviting you my real friends to an event.
Rym: You know, I'm doing this.
Rym: Let's do it.
Rym: You're when you're making plans with friends.
Rym: That's no different than calling all your friends.
Rym: It's just a more efficient way of doing it.
Rym: But when they put out information like pictures of me naked dancing on top of a flagpole It's gonna be on College Humor tomorrow.
Scott: Yes,
Rym: but when they want to hide these sorts of things They're forgetting the fact that in the long run Data aggregation of stuff that is out there can figure stuff out about you whether or not you have ever published it outside of a walled Yard,
Scott: well think about this.
Scott: if you were dancing naked on a flagpole Odds are whether you go to Facebook or not.
Scott: Someone else took a picture of you on top of the flagpole and it's on the Internet.
Rym: Well, you say you did it in your house.
Rym: So no one was there.
Rym: by calling your house Yeah, and you took a picture of it.
Rym: Well, if you put that picture on the internet you effectively did the flagpole thing outside in the first place.
Rym: now Yeah, actively basically but like people want privacy like your anonymous stuff.
Rym: anonymous breaks down in one very fundamental way Algorithmically.
Rym: you can figure out who someone is based on their style of typing pretty accurately.
Scott: Yep, mister.
Rym: or even if you can't figure out who someone is you can statistically correlate and do things like this person.
Rym: We have a ninety nine point nine percent like a likelihood that they're responsible for All of these thousand posts over the last three years and all these different social networks.
Rym: and oh look He was posting an anonymous and he was posting on anonymously in all these different places.
Rym: But he also has a LinkedIn profile and we're pretty sure it's the same guy now.
Rym: You're fucked now.
Rym: It's all linked.
Scott: Yep, and Eventually, there's like if you go and you make some let's say you have a blog right and you have two blogs.
Scott: You have one blog for all the stuff You don't want people to know about and another blog for the stuff you do want people to know about right?
Scott: You're clean stuff.
Scott: People all right, they find the bad blog.
Scott: Let's say both blogs get popular Right, or even let's say only the bad blog is popular, right?
Scott: But nobody knows.
Scott: it's you and only the people that you you know want to keep the bad blog a secret from.
Scott: They look at the good blog.
Scott: They don't know about the bad one or they maybe they know about the bad one.
Scott: They don't know.
Scott: it's you.
Scott: that's two samples of data that they can use and compare and then figure out.
Scott: it's you with science.
Scott: So the only way to keep something private like that bad blog would be to make the bad blog and then never make any other Posts on the internet other than that.
Rym: so I feel like really there are three levels of privacy that will exist in the long run and We won't have problems anymore once people understand this, but I don't know when people will understand.
Rym: I mean people still don't understand that it's a bad idea to take a picture of yourself Holding your illegal gun and then putting it on YouTube and be like check out my illegal gun.
Rym: Of course there was an article a while ago I think was an Oregon where some cop was basically saying that they arrest so many gang members with illegal guns and drugs Because they just posted on like YouTube and Facebook.
Rym: He was like, I hope they never figure it out.
Rym: nice He's like, I think I don't think they realize how easy this is right fine.
Scott: Maybe this is why crime is way down.
Scott: huh, maybe Prime is way down Your big time.
Rym: I think there are people who are about.
Scott: usually you would think that even you know Even though crime has been going way down since the 90s You would think that with the recession it would have gone up but it went down.
Rym: Well, it's the thing is it's weird.
Rym: It did go up in some places But it went down in the places people traditionally expected it to go up like the cities.
Rym: I mean New York City is having like no crime like it's kind of scary how little crime there is here now.
Rym: Yeah, despite the fact that the economy kind of you know, fuck up still.
Rym: But privacy, I mean think there's.
Rym: there's actual private like.
Rym: I have the naked picture of myself that I don't share with anyone in a Way where they could also share it with someone else, you know That's the on my own private server Encrypted on my USB key.
Rym: or how about?
Scott: you took a picture with a Polaroid and the Polaroid is in your house.
Rym: All the real security like.
Rym: you don't share these things or you share them within a walled garden that you maintain
Scott: The thing is their whole websites of like, you know, like, you know ex-boyfriend, you know When we were when we were going he took a video of me, but now he posts on the internet.
Rym: Well, that's why you know, I said there are three levels.
Rym: That's level one The.
Rym: you are the only one who has actual mathematical control over that data And you might show it to someone something that you thought and have not said.
Rym: or you show it to someone but you don't give It to them so they can say yeah Rima has all these naked pictures of Pikachu But you don't have any evidence of this other than you said you saw it.
Rym: So now it's a matter of do they trust you or me?
Rym: There's no evidence.
Rym: Mmm, I have a lot of naked pictures of Pikachu by the way.
Rym: Actually, I do have one that I didn't keep it But I saw it.
Rym: remember when we went to Bay image to see what was going on there.
Rym: It was nothing but Pokemon porn and pedophilia.
Rym: Oh, it's being still around I don't even know but last time we checked it was basically 90% Pokemon porn 9% digimon porn.
Scott: Okay, it looks like it's still around.
Rym: how much Pokemon porn is there?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Ranma is the biggest tag.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: I'll bet it's porn.
Scott: No, it's actually.
Scott: I think it's all of Ranma the manga.
Rym: Oh Okay, huh, I feel like torrents are a better place to do that.
Rym: yeah But level one is I control it.
Rym: level two is Trust and this is the in the far future.
Rym: The only thing that matters in all the technology is trust networks because you're a being an identity.
Rym: You are your knowledge and you choose which other knowledge identities you will trust with information and with links to your information and Trust networks are 100% secure Unless someone in your trust network is a fucktard and then you're done and your whole trust network is compromised.
Rym: So you really have to decide who you trust in the world?
Rym: And if you trust them, you're pretty much gonna have to trust them all the way You know.
Rym: level two is I trust this person and that's the walled garden of.
Rym: you know What people try to do with Facebook?
Rym: That's the.
Rym: I'm having a party at this place and I only tell people in the walled garden As long as you trust everyone in your walled garden and you trust the walled garden.
Rym: You're 100% safe.
Rym: But if you want to publish information Anywhere outside of those two levels, you've basically got to publish it to the world.
Rym: and just no holds barred.
Rym: No holding back No going back Mmm, and I think those are the only three levels of privacy that will ever exist in the future
Scott: Possibly
Rym: and I think the second one breaks down for the majority of people because people have this weird meta problem Where there are people who?
Rym: Expect to be in their trust network that they don't actually trust and they will either make the mistake of trusting that person in which Gave days compromised their entire trust network.
Rym: That's equally bad to the nerd who PGP signs a key that they don't trust.
Rym: They're fucked if they do that or they say I'm not going to trust you but now they've admitted I don't trust you yeah, and Then it'll make drama for them because they're fail.
Rym: But in the long run you basically have to cut off the people.
Rym: if someone's gonna cause drama because you've refused to trust them You have got to cut them off because you will never have good interactions with that person.
Scott: So I think in summary Technical, you know privacy problems on the internet really boiled down to two things.
Scott: It's not whether Google or Facebook gives you the features necessary or anything like.
Scott: no You can't blame anything on them.
Scott: the two things to blame are a people's technological incompetence not understanding what they're doing Which is always clearly documented.
Scott: In fact privacy is so well documented that every frickin site in the universe has a privacy policy that tells you everything and they're usually in plain non lawyer text or at least have a plain non lawyer text component.
Scott: and to In addition to the technological and competency people just have actual social privacy trust problems that they need to resolve and that's their real privacy problem.
Rym: that really I think accounts for the majority of all the Facebook drama is just Real-live drama that suddenly came to a head because technology forces and confront the harsh reality of the fact They're able to pass the blame on to Facebook.
Scott: somehow like Facebook's supposed to know that you just broke up with that guy or Google's supposed To know that that you know.
Scott: the person you emailed a thousand times You know and said all these good things to was actually an evil ex-boyfriend.
Rym: Google eventually or something like Google will know because that stuff's all statistical.
Rym: remember way back at RIT There was that cool app that would take a sample of writing of more than like 50 words and tell with pretty much like a hundred Percent accuracy whether or not it was a man or woman who wrote it.
Scott: Yep That's the kind of stuff.
Rym: So I mean we're gonna have algorithms eventually that can look at all your email and tell you not only who you've dated Who you're currently dating who you're cheating with who you should be dating.
Scott: Well, I mean, it's the same with anything.
Scott: we're eventually gonna be able to just look into your house and see everything with a satellite and You know, we're gonna be able to you know, wait and see what you're thinking.
Rym: Here's the thing.
Rym: I feel like this is where the three levels of privacy come in.
Rym: You are responsible ultimately for your own for your own privacy And if there is something that for whatever reason either for shady reasons or legitimate reasons you want it to be private The onus is 100% on you to maintain that privacy.
Scott: Yeah people keep thinking that there is some sort of right to privacy and I think there's a right to the.
Rym: your right is the Right to protect your own privacy within your own legal me.
Scott: I mean that's exactly if you look at the Constitution.
Scott: It doesn't say you have the right to the privacy that shall not be infringed upon.
Scott: It says right.
Scott: the government shall not make unwarranted searches and seizures Which pretty much means if you want something to be secret you can keep it a secret.
Scott: And as long as the guy's a secret to everybody right as long as and the government cannot come and take the secret by force without a warrant, right and Well, we got problems with that.
Scott: So that's the.
Scott: that's really.
Scott: the only time I'm going to be angry about privacy is if the government makes an unwarranted Search and seizure which they do and that's something to be very very concerned about right?
Scott: But as long as they're not, you know, as long as that's not happening, right?
Scott: It is possible for you to keep something a secret if you want to.
Rym: well Here's the.
Rym: here's the other thing.
Scott: the other because anyone else who isn't the government tries to take it by force They're breaking the law.
Rym: I captain interrupty.
Rym: Yeah I'm gonna interrupt you because the other big component you're completely ignoring in the body of law is all the precedent regarding a reasonable Expectation of privacy and I think that is a good body of law and it's a good standard and reasonable expectation of privacy.
Scott: It is good to hear their problem.
Rym: I know where you're going with this.
Rym: The two problems are that one Different people due to their misunderstanding of technology of different expectations of what is reasonable when it comes to privacy.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: and two We've got this problem where the there is technology that basically makes it to where you base.
Rym: You can't effectively have a reasonable expectation of privacy anywhere unless we make better laws to handle that.
Rym: Mmm, I think we definitely
Scott: think the other problem is that the people who exist now have a reasonable expectation based on You know a world in which certain things are not true and because of the advances of science technology Those basic assumptions upon which their reasonable expectation were based are no longer true And thus their reasonable expectation is no longer reasonable and the problem is still living with their old reasonable Expectation.
Rym: the reason this comes about is pretty simple.
Rym: to explain even a non-technical people.
Rym: It's the fact that the laws and the and all the rules we followed before are perfectly valid But they break down any time.
Rym: you can have machines iterate and automate so, you know It's your.
Rym: you have no expectation of privacy in the street if someone's just walking down the street and they're just video videoing you That's awesome.
Rym: There's nothing you can really do about that if you're both on public property, so That was fine in the old days because not everyone had cameras.
Rym: not everyone's gonna be filming everything all the time.
Rym: With computers and technology I can just put a camera on every street corner and film every street 24/7 and just make that public.
Scott: The only reason you can't do it in New York City is because you need a permit to set up a tripod.
Rym: Yep, but you can use a monopod.
Scott: Maybe.
Rym: I've seen people using monopods to get around that.
Rym: I don't know if that works or not But it's basically just a stick with a camera on top.
Scott: you could get someone maybe for littering or vandalizing or dumping.
Rym: Oh, no, what if the government did it?
Rym: I still stand by.
Rym: I think the best thing we could do for like New York City right now is to have public cameras that record Everything that's going on.
Scott: What do we need them for though?
Scott: I mean like.
Scott: I agree that there's nothing wrong.
Rym: What do we need them for one?
Rym: It'd be really cool because I could go watch myself walking down the street and figure out if I have a funny gate.
Scott: They have some cameras you can.
Scott: on my television There's a channel I can watch that shows like three different cameras of what's going on in the city in different places.
Rym: Yeah, but I want more of that and I want To.
Rym: I would use it to whenever I am wronged.
Rym: I usually I'm of the mind at least that almost every time I've had an altercation in society I was in the right and were there of everyone always thinks they were in the right.
Rym: Yeah, but I'm pretty sure I'm in the right most of the time.
Rym: So imagine if we had the camera and I could just go back and be like, okay So fat and ignorant woman you're claiming that I bumped into you.
Rym: Well, let's roll the tape and you see the fat and ignorant woman like backing up without a beeper and then slamming into me.
Rym: You know Or like?
Rym: recently there was a big news story in New York, you know during the blizzard One whole street in Manhattan I think it was a Manhattan like every car on it got totally smashed in the side like it looks like a plow just went down the street just
Scott: Probably what happened
Rym: and the city is like.
Rym: well There's nothing we can do about it because you can't prove it was a city plow and there's a million private plows that drive by And it might have just been some drunk guy.
Rym: Oh, it's true and there's no camera.
Rym: So all these people were wronged and there's no way in the world to figure out what happened.
Scott: They have insurance.
Rym: Yeah, but that sucks.
Scott: It does suck.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.