Rym: It's Wednesday, February 24th, I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights tonight for anime Phantom Thief Reina Durara, Chuuuubraa, and Cobra.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So Emily and I are trying to get some food at the desire like we do often But we happen to get it together like during the day.
Rym: like normal day We end up getting lunch.
Scott: No snap.
Rym: And normally, you know, nothing weird is gonna happen except Took stranger from a candy.
Rym: Stranger from a candy.
Scott: You took a stranger from a candy?
Rym: I took candy from a stranger.
Scott: Man, I wish there were free strangers.
Scott: Man, I would just fill my closet with them.
Scott: So useful.
Rym: See, Scott, the problem is there are plenty of free strangers, but if you fill your closet with them, the police usually come knocking.
Scott: Well, they do the same thing if you get the free candy, so it's a lose-lose.
Rym: We're sitting there and this guy comes up and he's very friendly and smiley and clean.
Rym: doesn't like nothing.
Rym: I'm not really getting any alarm bells from him.
Rym: I ignore most people, but he says like Many thanks.
Rym: Wonderful day.
Rym: Have a present from Saudi Arabia and he hands us this little packaged thing of like date candies.
Rym: Alright, and it looked really good because I really like dates.
Scott: I like dates also, especially if they are wrapped into bacon.
Rym: So we were kind of taking it back.
Rym: So we just took it like, alright, thanks We didn't really think about what we were gonna do with it.
Rym: And then he went around and tried to give him to like everyone else in the restaurant.
Rym: He went over to like the chef and everything and then he put the box from down with the rest of the food like Out front.
Rym: I don't know if he got permission to do that or what.
Rym: and we're sitting there and we're like, alright We probably shouldn't eat this being Candy from a stranger.
Rym: That's like the first thing you learn not to eat.
Rym: Like don't go in the van with no windows.
Rym: Don't take candy from guys.
Rym: You don't know.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, you know Seinfeld talks about the Danish.
Scott: you're walking through a hotel.
Scott: You see a tray sitting on the floor outside a room.
Scott: Someone got room service.
Scott: is a Danish sitting there?
Scott: Maybe it's half-eaten.
Scott: Right?
Scott: Well half-eaten.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I don't want a hepatitis That's true.
Scott: But I mean you could eat the half that you know The part that they didn't bite into right.
Rym: but if it's on eaten if like say there's just a Danish untouched on a plate There's nothing wrong with that?
Rym: What are the odds that someone went around and point it poisoned a Danish that was just laying there or took a Danish that I'm gonna Poison this and leave it out.
Scott: Yeah, they wanted to poison a random person as opposed to a specific person.
Scott: I mean if it was the only chance The best chance of it being poisoned was if there is like a high-profile person that you know In the room that someone was actively trying to poison and that high-profile person did not eat the day.
Rym: No you realize Scott we have increased the odds that we will die by poison Danish.
Rym: because if someone really wanted to get us and we're Really famous someday, right?
Rym: I'll figure out.
Rym: you know, we're at Otakon or Pat.
Scott: If someone would have done that to Seinfeld already who was already famous.
Rym: Yeah, but he's so famous that he probably doesn't encounter.
Rym: Danish is in the wild too, right?
Scott: He's so famous.
Scott: He travels and goes to so many hotels.
Scott: He definitely encounters.
Scott: It depends.
Rym: Does he have an entourage?
Rym: I don't think he has a big entourage because as much as you know, I'm the kind of person if I find a Danish I'll just eat it.
Rym: But if I if I was big enough to have an entourage, I wouldn't even think Oh a Danish I'll eat that.
Rym: I think Oh a Danish entourage get me a Danish not that one entourage.
Scott: taste that Danish for me.
Scott: I See you have not dead.
Scott: Thank you.
Scott: Give me the rest of the Danish.
Rym: But you know, I'm on.
Scott: I'm on the same page as you know, that's my strategy if there's ever some fugu.
Scott: Actually, I read an article recently.
Scott: They said that they say some fishery in Japan Bread some fugu with no poison in them.
Rym: But from what I've read you want a tiny bit of the poison because your tongue is supposed to go numb.
Scott: Well, you know the point is is that it's not gonna kill you.
Scott: But the point the thing is is that You know people were like, oh, it's not the real deal.
Scott: then I'm like, what are you talking about?
Scott: I would totally eat that one as opposed to the poison one.
Scott: But on the other hand whether it was poison or not poison I would not eat a fugu unless I saw someone else in the restaurant eating it before me.
Rym: But what do you know?
Rym: What if they cut two different fugu and the first guy got the skilled hands of the skilled chef?
Rym: And for the second guy the skilled hands were busy?
Scott: Then that's just the luck of you at the food dress tries.
Scott: then you're already eating mr.
Rym: Scott.
Rym: You may have been Poisoned.
Scott: well, that's that's a risk you take with this sort of thing.
Scott: But at least the risk will be much lower.
Scott: if you know I'm eating a non poisoned fugu and I saw someone else eat it first.
Rym: or you know, the random Danish.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, I'm still I'm on the same page as Jerry.
Rym: if someone went through all the trouble to poison that random Danish You know what?
Rym: They got me.
Rym: Yeah so the guy then kind of sits down next to us and is watching us like waiting for us to eat it and We just kind of sit there and he's like, it's good and we're like.
Rym: and then you know Emily's like.
Rym: hey, yeah You know, I'm kind of full.
Rym: so maybe you should give this to someone else, you know in case I don't get a chance to eat he's like no, no, it's very good take eat.
Rym: and we kind of waited awkwardly until eventually he wandered away and We threw the thing away.
Rym: Yeah, and I'm not a paranoid person I mean I'm assuming that this guy was just trying to be really friendly and he just had.
Scott: but why in that?
Scott: Particular restaurant at that particular time with that particular food and why?
Scott: why present it in that particular way?
Scott: what you know?
Scott: The fact that he didn't explain himself like he could have explained it is a gift from Saudi Arabia.
Scott: No, he could have explained like, you know, look like for example, let's say I made some cookies, right and I All right.
Rym: I see where you're going But if someone made cookies or brownies or something and was giving them out for free I would probably take them because I would assume the worst thing anyone does is something like that is put pot in him.
Rym: In fact, I think the I mean, you know random cookie having pot in it are high.
Scott: Just the circumstances were so strange that you didn't know what to think He could have explained in detail like look I made these cookies Right or it's a holiday something something.
Scott: explain the tradition of the holidays explain a bit.
Rym: It is a gift from Saudi.
Scott: That's not an explanation.
Scott: an explanation involves many details.
Scott: Why did you make the cookies?
Scott: Why are you giving them out in this particular restaurant at this particular time?
Scott: Why these particular cookies?
Scott: What you know, who are you?
Scott: why you know, they provided all these reasons and they were reasonable.
Scott: I would have been like, oh it makes sense.
Scott: All right, you know, for example, it's a special holiday.
Scott: You're so everyone's supposed to bake these cookies and give them out to people and it's a special Treat to eat this cookie on this special day, you know, so I'm going to every restaurant and the whole street I work in the next building over giving out the cookies.
Scott: It's like oh now it makes perfect sense.
Scott: And now it is reasonable and you're no longer a crazy person.
Rym: So I figured there are three ways to react to the situation.
Rym: on the one extreme is eat it because you don't fear nothing.
Scott: It probably wasn't poison probably not the.
Rym: the opposite side of that is call the police Right then and there and punch.
Scott: the guy didn't do anything illegal.
Rym: Yeah, I know But in case.
Rym: so I took the pragmatic rational approach, I did not eat the stranger candy But while he was walking out, I just took a picture of him with my phone surreptitiously.
Rym: So on the tiny chance that in the news the next day I saw mass poisoning in New York City Date candies in this eye.
Rym: I can be like got you guy.
Rym: That's all I got.
Rym: that was the weirdest thing that happened to me in the last 24 hours.
Scott: Alright.
Scott: so I guess we're doing some geek.
Rym: It's been what forever since Wednesday episodes just got the shaft for like the last couple months.
Rym: Yeah, I mean we keep.
Rym: we had this weird schedule, you know We're doing whatever shows we can fit in as we're getting the studio back up and everything and then stuff.
Rym: She kept coming up on Wednesdays Like we go out to some event.
Rym: it didn't happen and for it until real.
Rym: recently We weren't watching that much anime either.
Scott: Well, I was watching animes.
Scott: But you know, I've actually watched a lot of animes, but you haven't been watching them.
Rym: Also, I've been watching a ton of anime recently just now But we started watching anime right as we stopped doing Wednesday shows for completely unrelated reasons.
Rym: But before that when we were doing Wednesday shows we were watching anime except you were watching fist of the North Star And I was watching boat arms.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So I'm watching boat arms All right and fist of the North Star Okay.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, how about that?
Rym: Is there any anime you particularly want to talk about?
Scott: Well, you know, I did watch all of the original space battles of Yamato all the episodes.
Scott: I have to say that You know when it comes to the space battles of Yamato you can tell that it is an early work of.
Rym: You forgot his name.
Rym: You're stalling for time.
Rym: that whole time You were gonna say his name right away.
Scott: Actually, no, I was IMing someone on Meebo on my iPhone.
Scott: So I was that my brain was having to work double.
Rym: Were you perhaps IMing Daryl Surratt to ask him?
Rym: No It's name.
Rym: I know it's Leiji Matsumori But anyway, the I've only ever experienced Space battleship Yamato through Katsu singing the opening theme at karaoke.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, that's that's the opening theme.
Rym: Yeah Does it?
Rym: does it live up to the opening theme?
Scott: I mean the thing with the show is it's like.
Scott: it's not like the best show in the world, but it's all It's doing so well here because it's hard to explain.
Scott: it's like the show.
Scott: it doesn't have strong characters.
Scott: the characters are very flat and Like stereotypical.
Scott: it's like, you know, the road.
Scott: the doctor drunken doctor is the drunken doctor from beginning to end.
Scott: You know the captain is the captain from beginning to end.
Scott: You know, the main character is the the guy who wants to Shoot it up, you know all the time.
Scott: He's shootin up again.
Scott: Yep, so and people don't really change from the beginning of the show to the end.
Rym: so is it a show more of Kind of like the way a lot of people who like comic books like American superhero comic books like them you care about the series Of events and what actually happens?
Rym: Mmm, like the procedural well the ship went here and this is the war and this is the politics.
Rym: and this is the war and Politics.
Rym: and here's the plot.
Scott: now It's basically every episode though The overarching plot is actually a really high quality very sort of revolutionary for its time story.
Scott: Right of you know, oh my god, the earth is gonna die.
Scott: It's getting destroyed by aliens.
Scott: The only hope the earth has of not of not being destroyed.
Scott: Is it this one the only spaceship they have left Going all the way across the galaxy out to another galaxy Getting this space cleaner technology from some other aliens and coming back to earth within a year?
Scott: That's the only hope of earth.
Scott: So it really builds the suspense for every time the ship isn't gonna make it.
Scott: It's not just oh the ship isn't gonna make it like you're watching Gundam seed if the ship's gonna get blown up or the Gundam Is getting it blown up.
Scott: It's like, okay, it'll get blown up But in this it's like if the ship gets blown up as the does effectively the same as earth being destroyed.
Rym: You know, it's kind of the same deal with Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles the whole like, yeah If you don't come back a whole bunch of people get screwed.
Scott: Yeah, so you basically every episode is like, oh my god The Yamato is gonna get destroyed because of eggs.
Rym: Oh great.
Rym: So it's Ava syndrome.
Rym: Oh, they're not gonna make it.
Rym: Oh, they made it.
Rym: No, they're not gonna they made it.
Scott: Yeah The thing is they get they get hurt pretty bad quite often and this is one episode that you know.
Scott: You watch it and it's like so many things happen in the episode.
Scott: It's like ridiculous.
Scott: and then it like the fan subs I watch are really good and they had all these notes and the credits that told you stuff and like just the amount of production That it wasn't even the last episode.
Scott: It was the episode with the gigantic space battle where they fought like the four or five different colored space fleets all at once.
Scott: And it was just like you.
Scott: I thought you may I read the note at the end about how much Production went into that one episode and I thought back of all the stuff that happened in it I was like, wow, that was some fucking feat for the time.
Scott: It was made.
Scott: Holy shit.
Rym: I gotta watch it.
Rym: I mean, I just started a while ago on Legend of the Galactic Heroes.
Scott: Great.
Rym: Yeah, because you know captain Tyler is such a great show and it's clear the homage in Tyler to other shows like this.
Rym: So I feel like I really need to watch all of all the shows that Tyler was.
Rym: Oh margin.
Rym: Mmm, maybe but anyway If you are being a being what we are anime, you know panels and things.
Rym: we have to have seen this show.
Rym: So I figure I'll watch it.
Scott: Yeah I'm gonna.
Scott: I'm gonna probably watch eventually, you know The other Yamato's that were made at later points in time and are probably much more advanced, you know.
Scott: I mean because most of the flaws in Yamato are not fundamental flaws They're just sort of craftsmanship flaws because it was so early in the career of Matsumoto.
Scott: He didn't yet build up his full powers.
Scott: It's like reading in one of those really old Tezuka mangas, you know, not everything Tezuka did is gold.
Scott: I love it is ambassador magma exact, you know, if you read some like really early Tezuka manga it kind of sucks.
Scott: You know, he wasn't that good from the beginning.
Scott: I'm not saying I don't want people to think that I'm saying that the space battles of Yamato sucks Which is not what I'm saying, but it's got animation mistakes, you know, I'll put it this character is a very flat You know, it's these sort of.
Scott: but the overall it's you know, it's better than the vast majority.
Scott: I feel like we're obligated is very historically significant.
Rym: We're obligated to treat any anime regardless if it's new or old Or not on the scale that we've been using personally forever the.
Rym: is it an anime of be anime?
Rym: what so independent of the historical importance of this show and the importance to the culture of this show and the importance to his career of This show?
Rym: is it an anime be anime?
Scott: I guess it depends on the mood you're in, you know, like, you know certain episodes of the show would be like.
Scott: You know B or B plus and other episodes are like it could get towards a. you know, you know overall It's in the B plus a minus area.
Scott: I would say.
Scott: All right.
Rym: I feel like I should watch it then.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, it's only 20 episodes and then you know It opens up to you the ability to watch all the rest of the series which you know, very in quality I guess.
Scott: I assume You know, they can't.
Rym: you know see the trouble I have more and more and I really really have to fight These urges.
Rym: is that?
Rym: well that sounded kind of bad.
Rym: Anyway, whenever I start to watch a show that I haven't seen before especially if it's not one that I already know a lot about Like I know it's a good show or it's come to me with very specific recommendations or anything like that.
Rym: I Keep getting distracted by shows.
Rym: I've already seen that other people I know have not seen that I feel obligated to watch again with them like the first episode like Oh, you should watch this and we watch the first episode together and then I remember oh, yeah This show was like one of the best shows I've ever seen in my life and end up watching the whole show again.
Rym: Yep, like ghost in the shell standalone complex Emily and I this is God my third watching through of it at this point.
Rym: And we're right at the point at the end where oh shit everything happens.
Rym: And all I can think is I want nothing more than more ghost in the shell.
Rym: No other anime could do it for me right now than more ghost in the shell.
Scott: I Could take more things more bebop except that really wouldn't work.
Scott: That doesn't work.
Rym: more Ava there is more.
Scott: Ava There is.
Scott: I haven't seen all those weird extra things.
Rym: I could use another escaflowne, but there are some shows like goon saga that I think could fill that niche.
Scott: Yeah, I got a watch.
Scott: I only why I watched.
Scott: I started watching through the goon saga and then I stopped.
Scott: it's like I should Have kept watching that.
Scott: what is wrong with me?
Rym: Yeah, LuPone.
Rym: I feel like I could always watch more LuPone.
Rym: for some reason We just don't.
Scott: I can just watch more Satoshi khan anything.
Rym: Yeah, but there isn't any yet that we do.
Rym: I'm on Miyazaki anything.
Rym: Oh my god.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, but some more Gundams that are actually Gundam seed quality.
Rym: Yeah, or or old Gundam OAV quality.
Scott: That's true, it's more war in the pocket some more quality Gundams as opposed to you know, Gundam see destiny Gundams.
Rym: I feel like I should.
Rym: There was no Gundam see destiny.
Rym: What are you talking about?
Rym: That was like some sequel made by someone else.
Rym: It wasn't actually Gundam.
Rym: It was gun.
Rym: Damn.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: then like how there was only one matrix movie.
Rym: Yeah, sure But I am watching Botoms.
Rym: It starts out as a Gundam II kind of clone, but I know it goes somewhere different.
Rym: It I don't know what's doing it for me so far just feels like a B anime nothing special.
Rym: Mm-hmm Really all I'm watching right now until I finish ghost in the shell again And then I feel like I'm just gonna watch second gig and I'm just gonna keep watching ghost in the shell till I've seen it All again, I'm
Scott: still watching hokuto nuken on and off, you know, I watch it.
Scott: I watch a segment, you know until it gets you know, a plot point is dissolved.
Scott: I watch something else.
Scott: I come back to it, you know that sort of thing.
Rym: We kind of stopped watching Rosa Versailles feel like we should start that up again.
Scott: Yeah, but things are watching it.
Scott: The only reason I didn't watch more is because you know, we watched it together.
Rym: So yeah, so we got to start watching it together again.
Rym: We can't really double feature with hokuto nuken though, because I'm way behind.
Rym: I'm like 60 episodes behind you Mm-hmm.
Scott: Yeah, I'm on episode 90 something I think but the thing is it's like I'm episode 90.
Scott: I'm like, uh But it's like there's a hundred and forty fifty episodes.
Scott: So you gotta I got a ways to go still.
Rym: that's less than Sailor Moon That's true.
Rym: Yeah, I watched all of that in like two weekends.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: That's not gonna get repeated.
Rym: So things of the day.
Rym: Emily found this movie for me and she said it was right up my alley.
Rym: and after watching the trailer It is totally right up my alley and probably yours too.
Rym: The Secret of Kells is an Irish animated movie.
Rym: it just watch the trailer.
Rym: It looks crazy awesome and it'll be in theaters pretty soon.
Rym: If you live in a real city, is that it?
Rym: That's all I got.
Rym: I mean the style.
Rym: at least in the trail You'll see the style is kind of unique and kind of flat and colorful.
Rym: I I really like everything about it.
Rym: I'm really looking forward to actually seeing this.
Scott: Alright, so this would be better on a science day, but whatever it's still awesome.
Rym: You're a cross-pollinating.
Scott: That's fun.
Scott: there's a guy here.
Scott: his name's Derek Lowe and he has a PhD in organic chemistry and Postdoc stuff and where he's a scientist.
Scott: He's real smart.
Scott: He's got this blog here and one of the categories on his blog is things I won't work with and every blog post talks about a chemical that he refuses to work with.
Rym: Oh like dimethylmercury.
Rym: Dimethylmercury, I know really that's not on there.
Scott: Well with that it's actually does it.
Scott: there is a A post about straight dimethyl zinc and in that in that post he says dimethylmercury.
Scott: I will not get within yards of However, the most recent post.
Scott: I'm gonna link to the whole blog.
Scott: you can just read through all the posts, but specifically the most recent post which talks about dioxygen difluoride and he actually talks about how.
Scott: you know, okay at some point, you know, some guy made this stuff and 1962 and he did a basically did a bunch of tests, you know to see how it reacted with a bunch of different things and This guy was basically, you know Risking his life every single day.
Scott: And here is here is an excerpt, right?
Scott: Let's see the Where.
Scott: some liquid what's it called di Di oxygen difluoride, so he has some liquid dioxygen difluoride.
Scott: He mixed it with some liquid ch4.
Scott: a violent explosion occurred.
Scott: now Let me read to you all of the of the words.
Scott: when point two milliliters of liquid You know di oxygen difluoride was added to point five milliliters of liquid ch4 at 90 degrees Kelvin a violent explosion occurred.
Scott: So basically this shit right causes crazy explosions and crazy fires Even at basically almost zero temperatures there being a high-energy oxidizer Dioxygen difluoride reacted vigorously with organic compounds even at temperatures close to his melting point.
Scott: it reacted Instantaneously with solid ethyl alcohol producing blue flame and an explosion And an explosion.
Scott: when a drop was added to liquid methane cooled at 90 degrees Kelvin a white flame was produced instantaneously Which turned green upon further burning?
Scott: So this is basically dangerous, holy shit gonna explode stuff.
Rym: Well, here's the question.
Scott: guy will not work with it.
Rym: Is it used for anything useful?
Rym: I mean, I forget what chemical I was reading about on Wikipedia the art of them, but okay the final paragraph.
Scott: So does anyone use dioxygen difluoride for anything?
Scott: not as far as I can see most of the recent work with the stuff has come from groups at Los Alamos where it's been used to prepare national security substances such as plutonium and Neptunium hexafluoride.
Scott: But I do know that if you run the structure through sci-finder it comes out with a most Unexpected icon that indicates a commercial supplier.
Scott: That would be the hung so sage chemical company.
Scott: They offer it in hundred gram 500 gram and one kilo amounts.
Scott: Whoa, which is interesting because I don't think a kilo of dioxygen difluoride has ever existed.
Scott: Someone should call them on this.
Scott: as for free shipping If they object tell them Amazon offers it on this item.
Scott: serve some right more But this whole blog is full of this sort of awesomeness about crazy crazy Chemicals that this guy refuses to work with.
Rym: that was one career path that I gave up on very early when I realized I hated Doing chemistry and I hated naphthalene.
Scott: Hmm.
Rym: I was cool with chemistry.
Rym: It was all like oh math I can figure out what's going on with math.
Rym: and then when Argo happened I had to sit in that stupid lab with the fume hood and every single reaction was take naphthalene And turn it into something that smelled horrible and stained your hands.
Rym: Mmm.
Rym: and after like a month of that I gave up.
Rym: I was done.
Scott: He also won't work with as it As a dough tetrazzolate salts or your mom.
Scott: that's true.
Scott: my mom doesn't know chemistry.
Rym: so So we actually holy shit watched a whole bunch of anime we hadn't watched before to kind of preview it.
Rym: Yeah, we're going.
Scott: we're going back to old-school GeekNights.
Scott: We watched like a handful of episodes of a handful of animes.
Scott: We didn't finish watching any of the shows and we're just gonna talk about what we watch.
Rym: So two of the shows involve bras, so should we start with or end with the two bra shows?
Scott: Let's let's do the bras first.
Rym: All right.
Scott: Oh, I think all the shows have a raw right if I'm correct.
Rym: What one is a yeah.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: They all ended.
Scott: Ah, so chew bra.
Rym: I don't know if any of you have actually looked into this show
Scott: in this infamous
Rym: horror, all I want to say is that it's the kind of show to where if you describe to someone what it's about and They're an anime fan their first thought will be you're just making fun of people who like moe shows that show doesn't really exist.
Rym: this show exists Exactly in the way that you think it is so real and so exactly what we expected that it was kind of horrifying.
Rym: It was like a train wreck.
Rym: We couldn't look away.
Scott: Well, I mean, you know, let's see.
Scott: Let's there has to be something good to say about the show.
Scott: It's not a straight-up hentai, but in many ways a straight-up hentai would be better says.
Rym: secondly Well, it would be better because if you were watching a straight-up hentai you at least have to have admitted to yourself that yes I am watching porn.
Rym: I'm watching this to arouse my guess.
Scott: I guess this is 12 episodes, right?
Scott: So somebody spent 12 Episodes worth of money on this that they could have spent on like one episode of Ghost in the Shell, which is fucked up.
Scott: Ah, right.
Scott: I guess you know, it's it's animated Averagely for a modern show.
Scott: It's not like bad animation, you know, they put some work into it And there are a couple Humorous moments, you know, it's like ha ha ha Involve the bras.
Rym: No, they involve the duck and the turtle exactly as far as I can tell have no reason to be.
Scott: It's just like love Hina right where there's a turtle in the show and the turtles just sort of funny and cute.
Scott: But the turtle really doesn't mean anything in the show.
Scott: It doesn't really do anything.
Scott: It's just there It's.
Scott: there's ever the one episode where the turtle matters.
Scott: So in this show, there's like a turtle and a duck and this other animal and the animal are just.
Rym: they're just funny animals Weird cutaway where the ducks just like in the pool being super pissed off and it just cuts to that and then cuts away With no explanation.
Scott: Yeah, and that's pretty much they should have just made.
Scott: They should have spent all their money on making the turtle duck and cat show and ignored the other stuff.
Scott: Basically Chubra is a show If you don't know this already right where it's about a girl in middle school and She wears non middle school underwear.
Scott: She's like.
Scott: she wears grown-up underwear because she's an underwear tester and she is an underwear fan.
Scott: Like she knows all the details about underwear the way initial D knows all about cars, right?
Scott: So and the other girls at school?
Scott: their underwear is no good.
Scott: Their underwear is too small or it's not, you know comfortable or whatever.
Scott: and she starts an underwear club and helps everyone out with their Underwear, but meanwhile everybody thinks that she's like, you know, I got a sugar daddy or you know.
Scott: They don't.
Scott: they don't think it's legit.
Scott: They think that you know, she's obviously, you know a slut or something.
Scott: So they spread all these rumors about her and whatever when really she has this perfectly legitimate underwear fan ism.
Rym: however, however It's hard to what we'll start with the opener because the opener and the closer are this weird mix between panty shots and breast shots and Like Imagery of flowers blooming and plants.
Rym: It's all just really creepy.
Scott: Basically, it's just another one of those moe shows where they show you all sorts of T&A But they put in you know a run-of-the-mill.
Scott: You know cookie cutter plot of school drama, right, you know making friends at school Starting a club and being interested in something and teaching you about it.
Scott: You're like a car.
Scott: no go teaches you about.
Scott: go.
Scott: this show teaches about underwear same thing.
Rym: So it does but it's so forced.
Rym: it's really weird to watch it.
Scott: Well, yeah And all that all the cookie cutter stuff is there so that the pervert watching it can use that as an excuse to say No, I'm you know the same way playboy.
Scott: Oh, I'm reading the playboy for the articles.
Rym: I'm watching this to learn about girls underwear or because I think it's cute like the people who watch bingo town.
Scott: Yes, but really it's just perverted.
Rym: It's literally butt shot butt shot butt shot penny shot and then oh a quick random aside.
Rym: This kind of underwear is called this.
Scott: And here's some more T&A of middle school girls.
Scott: you pedo.
Rym: The first episode is called the girl who wore adult panties.
Rym: the second episode this swelling chest.
Rym: Yeah, a windy day between an adult and a kid radical puberty.
Scott: So if you are a Pedophile perv I've got the show for you.
Scott: Yeah well and you could.
Scott: the great thing about this is you wear pedo.
Scott: you can just make an excuse about watching the show cuz it's Totally legitimate school drama.
Rym: one thing I can say about the show though while you're watching it And I've seen this with other similar like crap moe shows.
Rym: they'll.
Rym: whatever is going on on the screen the music that is playing in the background is Really really really inappropriate.
Rym: like there's this dumb goonie scene.
Rym: We're like one girl's trying to take a picture of the other girls panties to prove that she's wearing adult underwear But then she falls.
Rym: so another girl tries to save her But then the girl is in underwear tries to save both of them and it's like goonie and they're all gonna fall.
Rym: It's all weird But the whole time in the background is playing kind of the same music that you hear in the background of two girls one Cup.
Scott: there is only one good thing that can come out of the show.
Scott: I don't know if it will actually ever occur But it is the only good thing possible that can occur from this show And that would be if some girls who are over the age of 18 would cosplay as to bra and have revealing sexy underwears.
Scott: That would be nice.
Scott: Anything else has to do with the show not good?
Rym: I love.
Rym: the opener song to its credit was similar to the opener to PETA 10 Which is kind of.
Scott: it's just one of those high-energy data data data data data song.
Rym: I kind of forgot that I actually do like music like that.
Rym: When I'm in the right mood you got to be in the right mood.
Scott: It's just a catchy tune.
Scott: It's not you know, it's not something I like or actively listen to.
Scott: it's just sort of catchy.
Rym: Yeah, I just catchy.
Rym: I mean no one remembers PETA 10 but it was for some reason pretty popular like when we were at the anime club at RIT and It's a very short amount of time.
Rym: It's weird that both of us kind of independently were like, yeah That's kind of like the PETA 10 opener.
Rym: I never even watched PETA 10.
Rym: I watched one episode of PETA 10 on the first game on the first day of middle school.
Rym: You have middle school.
Rym: you perverts.
Rym: Naya Hamia accidentally shows her black lace panties during the opening ceremony.
Scott: I think we've talked too much about true bra.
Scott: Let's talk about cobra.
Rym: Cobra is about an adult man who wears brought up.
Scott: Yeah, so so basically the story with Cobra right is that there was this old anime space adventure.
Rym: We're talking if this anime was on TV in Japan when I was zero.
Scott: Yeah, so two years ago They made an OAV which was a remake of the original space adventure Cobra.
Scott: and then one year ago They made an OAV that was a sequel to the remake and this year They made a TV show that was a sequel to the sequel to the remake.
Rym: so if you want to know what kind of show this is the opening scene of the first episode is basically guys in a truck that looks like a shark being chased by people in a helicopter that looks like a pterodactyl and
Scott: then they go into a tunnel and are chased by sort of flying cubes and
Rym: My favorite part is that.
Rym: so like the the good guys with some sort of you know MacGuffin are in this land shark trying to get away and they're driving in the tunnel and the pterodactyl goes up and then there's this giant gun battle and the main character gets introduced and all this craziness and The people with all these like attack robots and guns and power suits and the pterodactyl robot book.
Scott: Immediately when the local cops show up It's like you know, they're chasing down like the galaxy patrol and then the highway patrol shows up Which is just a bunch of like, you know, like, you know middle-of-nowhere desert cops.
Scott: and you know, like paddy wagons Shit the highway patrol and they run away highway patrol comes out.
Rym: They're like, oh it looks like there was an accident There.
Scott: It's like, you know, great good great.
Rym: So Cobra is kind of like a cross between Lupin and riding bean and Wolverine.
Scott: Yeah, he's got the powers of Wolverine You know, he can regenerate.
Scott: he's near invincible.
Rym: That's instead of.
Scott: instead of claws instead of six claws He has one gun.
Scott: one of his arms is a gun.
Scott: He basically takes his hand off which is otherwise a normal hand and under there is a gun and it's not just any gun It's the psycho gun and he shoots in it.
Scott: Basically.
Scott: It's ultra powerful gun that seems to have infinite ammo.
Rym: Yep, so he's Wolverine and he's kind of a badass and he's kind of a jerk, but he also talks.
Scott: He's like, you know, he's super dangerous But he talks a lot like spider-man as opposed to gogo 13 who says that that that And There's all sorts of ladies with giant boobs and he has to deal with them and survive and also Get ladies.
Rym: I think the most important part of the show is that he always has a cigar in his mouth.
Scott: Yeah, it's just always there as an accessory.
Scott: Like it's not late.
Scott: He's not smoking it It's just in his mouth all the time.
Scott: Just you know, whether when he's talking it just sort of wiggles around all over the place.
Rym: Everything about this show is dumb like it's it's kind of like watching an old bubblegum crisis or something where if you watch it in the in certain mindsets you think This is just dumb.
Rym: everything about this is dumb But the action is pretty good and it kind of it.
Rym: it scratched an itch that I didn't realize I had.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't think about.
Scott: you know, I'm not like going out to watch more of it But like if it was on I'd be like, all right, you know, it's it's fine.
Scott: You know, it's not like abhorrent It's just.
Scott: it's not like so exciting.
Scott: I need to go watch it, but it is Sort of silly, you know, it's silly.
Scott: It's got action.
Scott: The animation is decent enough You know, I think the one problem the show lacked is that there really wasn't a really good hook.
Scott: You know, it's like the character.
Scott: he's cool but he's not like so awesome that it's like.
Scott: I'll you know that I got to watch it no matter what he does and The plot was basically like.
Scott: you have this golden key.
Scott: You needed to stop this at comment from crashing into the Sun and destroying earth.
Scott: and it's like well There's really no mystery here.
Scott: Is there I don't really care.
Scott: You know, he's obviously gonna save the earth so Whatever.
Rym: Yeah, but it's just like it's dumb goonie comedic action.
Rym: It's kind of.
Rym: it's got a lot of the Lupin kind of stuff.
Rym: He makes Lupin II kind of noises like go on he ducks under things But he's a little more You know rough than Lupin.
Rym: Lupin is more, you know, he's like red Lupin But times two he kind of reminds me as the main guy in Kazanoyo Jimbo, which was a pretty mediocre show.
Rym: But that guy was the kind of consummate like he was a badass, but he acted like an idiot most of the time.
Rym: Master Keaton had that a little bit too, except this guy's nothing like master Keaton.
Scott: master Keaton was a nice guy.
Scott: This guy's jerk.
Rym: Well master Keaton was a master.
Rym: This guy's clearly a professional.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: He's a professional either.
Rym: He's a pirate but he hates the pirate guild, but he also hates the space patrol But he hates the pirate guild more than the space patrol.
Rym: It's funny how the show about middle schoolers had breasts and bras But the breasts were relatively small But not as they should be but cobra the animation which has as far as I can tell almost no bras Has some of the most accepted name.
Rym: Brock enormous jubilees.
Rym: you will see an anime to date I mean the one bad guy main girl character is pushing naga the serpent levels.
Scott: You can't hang these.
Scott: all of them were like double naga the serpent.
Scott: What are you talking about?
Rym: Not quite double because double is It doesn't matter there are way.
Scott: Every female like gigantic gigantic knockers, you know, I know and the guy is totally, you know a womanizer.
Scott: of course like he was he was on a stretcher gonna go to the hospital before they knew he had healing powers and He's like, I don't wanna go to the hospital cuz you know, he knew he didn't need to go there But they thought he did and they're like, you know, that's hot nurses there.
Scott: He's like, oh, I'm totally going to the hospital.
Rym: It's kind of I just call it another dumb actiony romp But the action is pretty good and I could see myself watching it every now and then when I was bored.
Scott: Yeah, nice nice be be show.
Rym: Yeah, it's hard to say if it's a high B or a low B. It really depends on whether or not it is.
Rym: I don't know if it takes itself seriously toward the end or not because if it pulls the kind of slayers II.
Rym: it doesn't take Itself seriously and everything just goes crazy.
Rym: It's a lot more awesome More serious.
Rym: it takes itself is gonna be really really dumb.
Rym: unless it takes itself so seriously that it comes good It becomes a meta non serious show that takes itself seriously.
Rym: Mmm, I'm trying to think of an example of a show like that because I know I've seen things that take themselves.
Rym: You know what giant robo takes itself so dead seriously, but is so stupid that it kind of balances out.
Rym: Maybe I don't know if the show can balance it out, but pterodactyl robot basically raping that land shark.
Rym: I think it's got some potential.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: All right, the other show we watched Oh What's it called?
Rym: Phantom thief Raina, this is another one of those like tiny five-minute episodes.
Scott: Yeah, you know We like.
Scott: we like those shows that are really short.
Scott: We're actually doing a panel on short animes Like fur Akapa and
Rym: Ryoku sagi
Scott: all these, you know We like the animes where the episodes are like a minute or two long and this is another one of those And it's phantom thief Raina and the animation is sort of like Wario where you know If you ever played a Wario where game and the jokes
Rym: are the same jokes, basically - yeah
Scott: and basically the story is there's a girl she works in a convenience store, but she's also a phantom thief and there's like a detective who's out to get her and Like the detectives assistant likes is in love with the convenience store girl.
Scott: And they don't know.
Scott: the convenience store girl is the phantom thief obviously and every night She goes out to steal things that are awesome.
Scott: Usually gold things.
Scott: It's like she steals like the with the gold potato.
Rym: I think the more operative part here is that she's kind of a bitch Kind of yeah, and mostly she's a bitch to her sidekick.
Scott: cute animal the rat basically the whole episode, right?
Scott: You'll the episode will be all about.
Scott: you know, I'm gonna go steal this thing.
Scott: Oh, I'm in the convenience store I'm gonna steal this thing.
Scott: How am I gonna steal this thing?
Scott: No, no, no, no.
Scott: But meanwhile the whole time every time the rat will show up and say something like, you know Oh, you're lazy and then she'll like smack the rat and then it escalates.
Scott: She basically murders Yeah, and then the rat will come back from being smacked and he'll be like, you know Are you gonna steal that way?
Scott: you stealing that for you should get a real job and then she'll like put a bottle rocket in his butt and you know It's like just basically it's show.
Scott: hurt the rat show.
Rym: Hurt the rat shows over is it's on the page and then you're at the right exactly page.
Scott: So it's basically half the show is just torturing this rat and half the show is you know, Phantom thief Raina.
Scott: She works at the convenience store and she steals things and there's detectives.
Rym: I get the impression.
Rym: I feel like every like segment of it like every distinct portion of the show is Doing some sort of a mod or parody to some older show because they like they keep cutting to these weird like asides or things Within their.
Rym: you know, I I don't even want to say there's a plot because there basically isn't a plot.
Scott: Yeah, we watch two episodes and if there's a plot it moves way slow.
Scott: it's mostly like the reveal one plot aspect per episode.
Rym: It's pretty much just a bunch of puns and weird kind of jokes and I don't know It's.
Rym: it's if you want to kill like a minute.
Scott: It's basically like a knock-knock joke, you know of phantom thieving.
Rym: Yeah sadly I don't have any use for the show other than to use it as an example of short anime.
Rym: to show one episode.
Scott: It's not as good as like, you know, I can.
Scott: I feel like manga BRE.
Rym: I feel like I'm gonna show this like at near the beginning of the bite-sized anime panel.
Rym: cuz you got to show the kind of meh shows like.
Rym: you got a Hit with one really good short show Like gag manga and then do a bunch of like, okay ones and some bad ones and then hit again at the end.
Rym: It was like three awesome ones in a row.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: Oh my god, like chew bra is like the nut is like, you know The show that is like currently like the head, you know the header on crunchyroll on the front page.
Rym: Oh my god Look, this is crunchyroll.com.
Scott: chew bra is like the top show here.
Scott: Ah That's that's fucked up right there.
Rym: See I I really want to know cuz who's watching this in America?
Rym: I understand that the the perverted money depend.
Rym: Yeah, we did.
Rym: we did watch it.
Scott: Here's my theory on this.
Scott: now You ready for this theory?
Scott: I'm ready.
Scott: Okay, so here's my theory.
Scott: You could make a show like say one piece or Pokemon right where you're gonna.
Scott: it's gonna be so ludicrously popular that everyone in the universe is gonna watch it right and You know everyone it's gonna sell so big.
Scott: you're gonna have Pokemon toothbrushes and Pokemon.
Scott: this and Pokemon and Pokemon everything right and Therefore right and all those merchandise and all the DVDs and everything is.
Scott: and you get so much Advertising dollars and you're gonna have such, you know, you're gonna have reasonable margins on all these products, right?
Scott: You're gonna make a ton of money if you want to make an anime that is not going.
Scott: you know already It's not going to be Pokemon.
Scott: It's not gonna be Dragon Ball.
Scott: It's not gonna be super popular across a zillion kids everywhere, right?
Scott: If you make say ghost in the shell, right?
Scott: You're not really gonna sell that much merchandise.
Scott: You're not gonna sell that many advertisements.
Scott: You're not gonna get big sales numbers.
Rym: That's why I think standalone complex was pay-per-view in Japan.
Scott: Yeah, you're not gonna get the big numbers on it.
Scott: So right without the big numbers.
Scott: if you want to make money you have to have big margins Right.
Scott: and for big margins, that means the show can't be a kids show.
Scott: It has to be a show for people with money.
Scott: and the thing is when it comes to merchandise Even if some guy in Japan is like a you know, it's like a 30 year old business guy.
Scott: You might like ghost in the shell.
Scott: You might watch it.
Scott: He's never gonna buy ghost in the shell action figure Or a t-shirt.
Scott: or you know, maybe he'll buy a manga but that's you know, he's not gonna buy any of that other stuff.
Scott: He's not gonna buy the DVDs.
Rym: So so clearly what's going on here?
Rym: Is that chew bra is going to sell bras to perverted 30 year old men?
Scott: when you make something like chew bra you can get it might even be a smaller audience than ghost in the shell.
Scott: and But all of the merchandise and such these otakus who watch it Actually shell out money for action figures and posters and Such in models and and and and uh, and you can mark those things up with high margins.
Scott: You can sell them a plastic tchotchke for 50 bucks.
Scott: So if you want to make money on an anime your two options are either become so popular that you can have reasonable margins on your products and make a big bank or You have to actually target your.
Scott: if you're not gonna be popular You at least have to be popular among a segment of people that will shell out dough for stuff at high margins So you can make your bank.
Scott: and I think this actually is parallels in the US comic book industry where it's like, okay You know, we've sort of given up.
Scott: There's no way we're gonna get it zillion people to actually buy spider-man comic books, right?
Scott: So if we the only reason to make spider-man comic books is first we jack up the margin on them right to four dollars an issue or whatever they charge these days.
Scott: and Then you know we have to make bank by selling like a spider-man statue for 50 bucks and a spider-man t-shirt for 20 bucks and only you know For the nerds will buy it all up and we'll be able to make money on them, you know.
Scott: But I think the thing is with something like spider-man They've actually achieved the double the double-deuce in which they have spider-man movie or spider-man cartoon And you know, which is wicked popular and sells a zillion across the board and then they also Have the low quantity high margin at the same time.
Rym: That's probably the Holy Grail but you brah not getting there.
Scott: No So juke, you know.
Scott: That's why I think the moe shows have been making the bank because the otaku in Japan will buy high-margin products But the shows that would appeal to a smaller mark to us equal size Maybe even larger size audience, you know a ghost in the shell type of show, right?
Scott: That audience is not an audience that will buy high-margin Merchandise extra crap at all.
Scott: All they will do is watch the show and you can't make money off of them.
Rym: Therefore you only you can with things like, you know in Japan unlike in America It's on TV ads.
Scott: all you know, all these shows are only on at 3 a.m So there's the ads.
Scott: don't make anything.
Scott: so you can really if you want to make money with anime your options are Miyazaki movie type of situation.
Scott: right one piece kind of situation or The chubra situation.
Rym: Scott, how do you think that all these shows like Dora on everything right now?
Rym: How are they gonna make their money?
Rym: They're not gonna sell the merch.
Scott: I don't think they make that much money, but they make money.
Scott: I don't know if they make money or not.
Scott: I think they're sort of my.
Scott: so you think they're on the edge.
Rym: you think that pretty much every show that comes out is Unprofitable.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I don't know but it can't be.
Scott: it's not.
Scott: it's not excessively profitable.
Scott: They're not.
Scott: you won't convince me.
Scott: You're saying the Dora is making mad bank.
Scott: Is that what you're saying?
Rym: I'm saying that.
Scott: are you gonna say that Dora makes more bank than chubra?
Rym: I'm saying I don't know.
Rym: I just think your picture of the way the only ways to make revenue is a little bit.
Scott: I'm saying the only way.
Scott: I'm saying the only ways to make Bank, you know I mean you might you can't.
Rym: you basically can't make bank with anything.
Scott: I think you brought nothing makes bank.
Rym: you bro is not gonna make bank.
Scott: I think you brought makes a scare and it's not making one piece back, but I think it's making scary Bank.
Rym: I highly doubt that.
Rym: actually I don't think it's gonna make that much money.
Rym: I don't think nearly as much as you expect.
Scott: I think it's gonna make more.
Rym: in Durara Cuz perverted 30 year old guy can only buy so many pairs of underwear.
Scott: You can buy a lot more than three-year-old kid.
Scott: Anyway, so why don't we talk about that Durara?
Rym: So Dora is our second Narita show.
Rym: we got baka no first, which is freaking awesome Even though I didn't watch the last two episodes yet.
Scott: I didn't why I've watched about maybe ten episodes.
Scott: eight I'm not sure.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I'm gonna start over about solid b-plus a-minus anime.
Rym: It's just awesome.
Scott: Yeah, but Durara the reason is called Durara is because that's an onomatopoeia for a motorcycle noise like dude Right.
Scott: and The show is basically about this kid who moves to Tokyo You know from the boonies sort of like Detroit Metal City except.
Scott: He's not secretly metal He's just regular old kid, and he totally doesn't get you know, but what's going on, but he's got a friend.
Scott: He's totally city guy and his best friend.
Scott: So you see you know showing on the ropes how things go and as long as the interesting characters and happenings in the city.
Scott: But mostly there's this you know sort of urban legend of this motorcycle girl who's wicked dangerous, and who knows what she's up to.
Scott: and What I think is so cool about it is that you know usually when you have an urban legend show It's always that cliche plot of.
Scott: there's an urban legend spreading around and no one it doesn't.
Scott: you know There's no evidence of it being real, but then there's something that might be it.
Scott: No.
Scott: It's not it.
Scott: It might be it It's not it.
Scott: I saw it.
Scott: No one else saw it.
Scott: This is like everyone is standing on the side of the street and the motorcycle goes down the street and everyone sees it well It's like a real urban legend and everyone's like oh shit It does something that I like and a few other shows have done this before.
Rym: I'm not saying which ones because it kind of Depending on how this show goes and how you watch it it can actually spoil those shows.
Rym: But it's a show that presents a normal world except weird anime kind of stuff happens.
Rym: But I get the impression that the weird the reason that this weird anime kind of stuff can happen is the plot of the show.
Rym: You think that is there's some sort of deal with this world.
Rym: I mean you know it's some punk kid who's you know he's never really lived anywhere except his parents house.
Rym: He goes to he goes to the big city, and there's just weird like effectively superheroes fighting like way in the distance And he sees like the explosions all the weird stuff happening far away and Everyone else in the city is like yeah, that's that's what happens here.
Rym: Well.
Rym: You don't know that's just.
Rym: that's just how it is.
Scott: Yeah, the show also it has some pretty good characters in it.
Scott: You know the main character He.
Scott: you know he's kind of funny in his country bumpkin ways.
Scott: He's got something to him.
Scott: You know his best friend is kind of is really silly and has bad jokes.
Scott: the motorcycle girl Urban legend girls really intriguing.
Rym: I like the Russian.
Scott: the Russian sushi guy is the best.
Rym: Oh my god the black Russian.
Rym: you see him, and you know it's a. it's a Naruto show.
Rym: So there's a million million characters and all of them are really fleshed out or at least Iconic enough to where you know that they're all gonna have their moment with something crazy.
Scott: Yeah, it's like sad.
Scott: you know it's like snatch or one of those movies All these.
Scott: it was just cast of awesome characters, and you know they actually do stuff.
Rym: Yeah, that's kind of take snatch or bacchanal or Dora.
Rym: You just take a bunch of awesome characters put them in a bin go shake shake shake and throw them out and see what happens.
Rym: Yep I love that.
Rym: so the action is good too like this the comedic timing of the of the I guess fight Which by the way the show gets points or someone using a motorcycle as a melee weapon and yeah, right?
Scott: Yeah, the other thing is that The show is interspersed with like showing you these instant message chat room like this IRC chat Weird cuz.
Rym: it almost sounds like the same person is reading all the chats, but with a different like accent.
Scott: Yeah As opposed to the different people really reminds me of that second bayside shakedown movie where they had the IRC chats.
Rym: Oh, yeah the Let's save the Rainbow Bridge.
Scott: Yeah exactly There are some other things like it's in ghost in the shell has a little bit kind of you know well What's cool.
Rym: one thing about this show that I get and the problem is this is the same kind of thing I said for paranoid Agent way back, but then when I asked Satoshi khan he was like that's really cool and interesting But that's not at all what I was thinking.
Rym: Look at the beginning.
Rym: the country bumpkin comes and all the scenes show like every character in the background who isn't him is In black and white except for the people he knows like everyone's kind of just a shadow.
Rym: But the people that he interacts with are real.
Rym: it's kind of like the real world like living in the city.
Rym: There's all these weird and strange and cool things going on that you don't get if you're living somewhere rural.
Rym: And yet then look at the plot.
Rym: there's all these crazy things these superheroes these urban legends like the fights going on in the distance and the Explosions the motorcycle girl and all these things are just normal to all the people in the city But they're completely crazy to him who came from outside the city.
Rym: so I wonder if it that like they're taking that kind of metaphor of going from the old Farmville to the big city and like instantiating that metaphor Into the world on multiple levels.
Scott: I think also what's kind of cool about it Is that it simultaneously gives you that city environment where there's a lot of things happening a lot of energy a lot of people a lot Of excitement, but it also gives you that neighborhood feeling where it's like.
Scott: he knows everyone in the neighborhood He knows all the places.
Scott: he says hi to all sorts of people on the street.
Scott: You know and it's it's kind of rare that you would have both of those things.
Scott: You know it's hard to it's hard to really like you know find You know walk down the street and like know everybody.
Scott: you know or at least you know know someone in every block.
Scott: You know personally you know in such a crowded crowded place.
Scott: You know and So that's that's pretty cool And it's almost just like fun to be in that city environment.
Scott: And it's like.
Scott: I hope that as you watch more episodes They just really flush it out, and it's sort of like whoo.
Scott: I'm in a fun place.
Rym: So I noticed something now really weird and you're gonna have to bear with me on this.
Rym: I don't know if this just says a lot about me and the way I think so.
Rym: Baccano the first Narita show we got and Durara the second Narita show we got and the titles are in English here Right like I've got him like romanized in English mm-hmm Baccano.
Rym: Durara has one more character in it than Baccano and Baccano has one exclamation point, but Durara has two exclamation points.
Rym: So I feel like the third Narita show whatever it may be is going to have nine characters in the title and three exclamation points.
Rym: All the data I have indicates that this is exactly what is going to happen.
Scott: Okay, whatever.
Scott: Why don't you check the Japanese?
Rym: Titles well Baccano was just called Baccano, but there are two exclamation points here very specifically It is you know.
Scott: the thing is you know Baccano.
Scott: I think they said what does it mean?
Scott: it means like static or noise?
Scott: Yeah, and Durara is a noise.
Scott: So it's like he's definitely doing going for the noisy titles.
Scott: Yeah, the next show is probably like boom or Boom headshot.
Scott: Zoom bang or something along those lines.
Rym: It'll just be three exclamation points.
Scott: Or it might be like you know farting noise something like a movie about cows Bay Bay Bay.
Scott: It's good to have a formula for coming up with titles though.
Scott: It makes a lot easier.
Scott: Otherwise you sit there going.
Scott: what should the title be for like 10 days?
Rym: God remember trying to do the panels at ConnectiCon sitting there like what are we going to call these 30 pens?
Scott: All right, do we got anything else to say?
Rym: Really, I mean I'd really like Durara the same like at the exact same level that I like Baccano.
Rym: But if you thought Baccano was too violent because it is really crazy violence like it really Especially because the violence is pretty realistic and creepy and also if Baccano was kind of too out there Just because it jumps around like in the chronology constantly And it never really lets you settle and it keeps showing you the same scenes like over and over again for different perspectives.
Rym: Everything's all over the place.
Rym: Durara at least seems to follow a Strict chronology of this happens.
Rym: then this happens then this happens and the violence is much more comedic and much more interesting and much less Horribly depressingly realistically violent.
Scott: Yeah, that's true.
Scott: We forgot to do the meta moment.
Scott: Do you want to do it now?
Rym: Right at the end?
Rym: All right We're going to be at Anime Boston doing a crazy ton of panels.
Rym: We're going to be at Otakon doing a bunch of panels.
Scott: Otakon's way later.
Rym: We're gonna be at PAX East doing a bunch of panels.
Rym: We're running panels at ConnectiCon, so if you have an anime panel or any panel you want to do at ConnectiCon We're the ones you submit them to.
Rym: Do we have anything else?
Rym: The book club is Carl Sagan's cosmos.
Rym: You anime kids should read it.
Rym: You might learn a thing.
Rym: Might learn you something.
Scott: Or ten.
Scott: Or a hundred.
Rym: You can cop out and just watch the TV show.
Scott: It's mostly the same.
Scott: No, why are you telling them this?
Rym: Because I just want I don't care.
Scott: The point is to get them to read a book.
Scott: Read a book?
Rym: Read a- if they if they Watch the show.
Rym: I feel like they got a third of the way there.
Scott: That's better than zero.
Scott: Well, if you if you watch the show and you don't read the book, you should still feel bad.
Rym: Yeah, you should feel bad.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I don't really have anything else.
Scott: No.
Scott: All right, so that's it.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special Thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.