Rym: Hey, it's Tuesday, April 20th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight on the DS heroes of Might and Magic Tonight on the DS Might and Magic clash of heroes.
Rym: Let's do this.
Scott: So you remember that show we did where we talked about how people literally do not see the text on the computer screen.
Scott: They literally do not see.
Scott: I have found another example of literally do not see.
Rym: all right.
Rym: What do you see?
Scott: pedestrians literally do not see anyone on a bicycle?
Scott: Basically, you know, they're there's they're getting ready to cross the street and the red and white lights That doesn't mean shit to them, right, you know, just like you and me red and white light doesn't mean shit, right?
Scott: So as soon as the last car is gone, and they don't see any cars coming that it's time to go They do not see bicycles.
Scott: there could be a hundred bicycles behind that last car and they'll just go, right See what I've discovered is that I at least myself see the bicycles.
Rym: But is that just possibly because of the zebra storyteller?
Rym: because I am in fact a bicyclist?
Scott: So, you know what the solution?
Scott: that there is solution though Yeah, you have to use your gay ass Bell which is required and all Noise-making device is required on all bicycles and yet to use it.
Rym: So I actually I had a trouble with that when I was a kid because I did not have a bell on my bicycle Or horn is required by law at least in the city.
Rym: I was one stopped by a police officer When I was young and he said, you know you ran a red light and all these other things.
Rym: then he's like and you don't have any sort of noise-making device.
Rym: and I got into a long argument.
Rym: and finally he let me go on the grounds that I can clap loud enough to Constitute a noise-making device of the proper decibel level, but you can't do it while your hands are on the handlebar.
Rym: Yeah, but I can ride without my hands on the handlebars if you can't do that.
Rym: You shouldn't be biking.
Scott: I'm just saying is that the point is that it you know, that's like saying oh well It's okay to have.
Scott: you know, your car has this safety device, but it requires two hands.
Scott: You have to take your hands off the wheel.
Scott: Yeah, but I can drive with my knees.
Rym: Okay, you can yell out enough to and the thing is but I really don't feel like yelling proper way around.
Rym: This is one really you should just yell get the fuck out the way as you're going.
Rym: But if that if you don't feel like it Why don't we just make a bell that is actually a little mp3 player and a loudspeaker that plays your voice or maybe some?
Rym: Better stronger voice yelling get the fuck out the way.
Scott: well They'd have to.
Scott: so happens that there is a crude and lewd a rap song that I remember from the olden days because I think my brother used to To quote it quite often in the ruder and or luder than get the fucking out the way.
Scott: The chorus of the song I believe is pretty much move bitch get out the way and that's pretty much it.
Scott: It's just like move bitch get out the way.
Rym: So maybe that's the solution.
Scott: The way bitch get out.
Rym: The thing is my problem isn't so much that the bicyclists just they keep running the fucking red light and hitting me.
Rym: It's not the fact that I just go and I don't see him.
Rym: I see him that I go anyway because they got a red light.
Scott: Yeah It's interesting like which bicycle people will stop for red lights and which won't and when they'll stop at a red light and when they Won't.
Scott: and you know, I've sort of found a happy medium.
Scott: Of course, you know when I started out, I just stopped at everything for the full duration.
Scott: But now it's like okay if I'm on the left side of the street right next to the sidewalk And I'm making a left turn and I'm gonna stay next to the sidewalk.
Scott: I can just go whenever it's okay to go.
Rym: I thought really, you know, I follow California rules.
Rym: I don't know what parts of California do this But apparently there are places where the law is that for bicyclists stop signs count as yield signs as opposed to stop signs.
Scott: you know if it's like if it's like a one-way if I'm crossing over a one-way and I see that there's no car on the Right and they have a stop sign there and there's no one stopped at the stop sign Then you can just go right across, you know
Rym: the rationale.
Rym: think of this is that it the the disruption caused to traffic by bicyclists stopping and starting again because of the time it Takes to get up to speed.
Rym: It's safer for them to just basically run stop signs as long as they would have had the right of way Otherwise by treating it a yield regardless.
Scott: They still stop far more often than everyone else.
Scott: The other weird thing I'll see people do right is like this is bicyclists to just like hate Stopping and what they'll do is they'll get to a light or something Around right waiting to go.
Rym: So I I've discovered those people almost Universally just don't actually know how to ride their bike and they have their seat way too high.
Rym: So when they stop the bike falls to the side and they can't easily kind of jump to get it up again.
Rym: Every person I've ever seen doing that has their bike configured incorrectly.
Scott: I see the thing is I?
Scott: some of the people I see doodling.
Scott: It's like they just don't want to lose, you know momentums That's what I see a lot, but it takes more work to maintain that doodly-doodly-doodly.
Scott: I don't know as me.
Scott: I'm not the doodler.
Rym: I might just stop it.
Rym: I just continue rolling because rollerblades are the best of both worlds.
Scott: I guess if I can jump on the sidewalk and in and out of people and just go But only if it's really empty Yeah, and only if I really have to like, you know There'll be three cars stacked right and I can't get in between.
Rym: What amazes me is it was it's so annoying on the sidewalk because there's slow people just kind of waddling around People people walking I've realized and the faster you're going the more you notice it are Incredibly erratic in their movements.
Rym: They kind of just drift to the left drift to the right arm flying out with a cigarette on the end of it all over The place.
Rym: Yep but I ended up walking the route that I normally rollerblade because I wanted to sit down somewhere else everyone to restore and put on my blades.
Rym: and Normally when I rollerblade on the sidewalk I'm slowed down by the slow people in my way and I get kind of irritated.
Rym: So I walked and it was equally irritating.
Rym: I went just as fast I had.
Rym: I've been rollerblading.
Rym: people are just slow.
Rym: The people are also anyway, yeah, but I've been playing a lot of DDR.
Rym: Uh-huh, and I'm very happy in the kit.
Scott: So you realize yeah, I would be playing DDR cuz I got it all set up.
Scott: I got the step mania I got these songs.
Scott: I got my pad.
Scott: I got the home theater PC.
Scott: Yeah, but you know, what?
Scott: Reason I'm not playing DDR is because instead I am doing things that are the opposite of shit.
Scott: talking meanwhile you Shit talking still about what?
Rym: e-commerce anything other than that everything such as any all shit, I Would like one piece of shit.
Scott: every poop you have talked it.
Rym: That's That's the private Twitter Can't lift ten poops, but you realize there's a new version of step mania.
Scott: That's like alpha alpha alpha Really and it uses I'm not sure which one I have It's got.
Rym: you would know it looks completely different from the one you know in love okay, but I tried it because there was this crazy delay like so profound that I could not dance.
Rym: and Basically, what I discovered was that there is a point one one two Millisecond delay between me stepping on an arrow that arrow being transferred to the ps1 controller to the ps1 to USB converter to the Mac.
Rym: That is the problem.
Rym: the fucking Mac and the way it handles the USB device that I plug my ps1 controller into Introduces this point one millisecond delay.
Scott: This is why you know OS X is really just not you can't be.
Scott: you know Even though like steam is coming out for it.
Scott: The gaming is just gonna be terrible.
Scott: It does absolutely no support for input devices or any of these things.
Scott: that it was amazing.
Rym: I tried it.
Rym: I used the keyboard and I used a gamepad.
Rym: that like other things that I plugged in and there was no delay.
Rym: It was only and there's no delay in Windows.
Rym: if I use that device It's just that device in OS 10 causes a point.
Rym: one one two millisecond delay.
Scott: exactly Games right people don't realize PC games computer games and even console games.
Scott: They basically just need like raw Hardware access like full-on.
Scott: right but OS X with all its niceties and user interface What all these Steve Jobs things when you when you build an application on top of that?
Scott: That's fine.
Scott: if you're making like a web browser or something, you know, something like that.
Scott: But if you're making a game you need that shit to get out the way.
Scott: Right, you just need the hardware in your game and you need everything else to move aside.
Scott: interesting You know, that's why like Microsoft DirectX is called, you know That's why it was called direct from the beginning.
Scott: right is because it basically let you bypass like all this, you know It was a new API to go direct between your program Direct X then the drivers and you basically went around all those windows.
Scott: bullshit Grabbed your full-screen display device and through your 3ds up there, you know, that's what DirectX and directory.
Rym: What's interesting though?
Rym: Is that all that precision for gaming is actually pretty shitty if you use it in the rest of the computer like OS 10 is a Wonderful experience.
Rym: until you want to play a game on no, it's.
Scott: it's a pretty.
Scott: I think it's a terrible experience.
Rym: all around though My I've got that SteelSeries laser mouse, which I still.
Rym: I recommend that to anyone who cares about their input.
Rym: This mouse is maybe I should get like I cannot Express to you.
Rym: I can't even begin to overstate how wonderful this mouse is.
Scott: I mean the thing is so I plugged it.
Scott: We need to be so.
Scott: he needs to gut like a regular old logitech mouse.
Scott: put it in the same exact case as that one And then do the double-blind test to see.
Rym: you know, yeah, the thing is I've done customizations with this mouse.
Rym: You know within the individual like the response rate that you can't do in software with a logitech.
Scott: Yeah, but has it helped you or not?
Scott: We don't know.
Rym: I think so.
Scott: It could be psychosomatic Plus.
Rym: it just feels nice.
Rym: It doesn't work so well in OSM though, but all that aside speaking of raw Input and playing games.
Rym: There's been a lot of buzz about the.
Rym: so You know people always talk about when the next-gen shooter comes out Even though the next-gen shooter has always been like five gens back if you count old PC shooters.
Rym: Yep, but Body count apparently everyone's talking about it.
Rym: Like it's the new first-person shooter.
Scott: I've never heard of it.
Rym: I'd never heard of it is it?
Rym: but there's a bunch of buzz about it And I what I want to skip to is they make a huge.
Rym: just tell me if you've heard this before.
Scott: The dike.
Scott: it's a dike atana.
Scott: Let me guess.
Rym: It's not a dike atana.
Rym: It's not.
Rym: we have revolutionary AI.
Rym: It's another claim that has been made in the past.
Scott: All right Quote.
Rym: it is not just about effects.
Rym: It's about access.
Rym: in body count You can blow chunks out of interior walls your fortune.
Scott: Yeah faction.
Rym: It is the blow shit up Game they make.
Rym: they keep talking about how you want to hide behind a crate and check out the business shoot a hole in the crate and then peek through the hole.
Rym: and That's all anyone has to say about this game.
Rym: other than you can crouch and then and here's where everyone They lost me.
Rym: and then you can use the left stick to peek Do a little peek and peek around the corner like this is some new revolutionary thing that no one's thought to do.
Scott: Yeah, okay.
Scott: So soldier of fortune had peeking right mech warrior 2 for MS das Tie fighter and any various other descent any number of 3d games or you know games that were at least in quote.
Rym: It's natural.
Rym: It's allowed to control units adaptive and it will surely consign the whole locking on mechanic to the graveyard of cover system history The first way.
Scott: it's a console game.
Rym: the first I said left stick.
Rym: Oh, right the first post on slash dots Mm-hmm.
Rym: I'm going to read it in its entirety.
Rym: Will this also be available on a system with an input controller suitable for shooters like say a mouse?
Rym: It amazes me that for all I pay attention to gaming I'd never heard of this game and a lot of people are talking about how they think it's gonna be this next-gen game.
Rym: But it looks like it's just rehashing a bunch of tricks from games five and ten years ago.
Scott: And then basically we had Halo which was like Goldeneye Unreal tournament level of game and now they're stepping up to like the soldier of fortune level of game on the console.
Scott: So how many years will it be before you've got like?
Scott: and I'll never Never will there be NS level or tribes to level of game on the console.
Rym: It will never happen Considering I had difficulty mapping enough buttons in weapons factory on my keyboard, which is plenty of buttons.
Rym: So What do you got for me captain news?
Scott: So I said before on the show a long time ago I think around the time that you know bionic commando and Megaman 9 bionic commander re-armed and 3d 3d by yeah, no died.
Scott: I had a commander reunder.
Scott: Megaman 9 came out that Capcom was the company that knew the business right.
Scott: and in terms of all game Developers, you know at the time The only ones who are really know what was up was Capcom.
Scott: and well Capcom had their event in Hawaii And they had a nice Hawaiian theme.
Scott: they had captivate 2010.
Scott: Capcom captivate pretty good, huh?
Scott: Yeah, and it was cool to have it in Hawaii, which is sort of like the Japan us halfway point, you know.
Scott: But anyway, they came out with a whole bunch of announcements.
Scott: First of all, I didn't realize it was next week, but Super Street Fighter 4 is coming next week.
Scott: But on June 15th, it's gonna have a DLC tournament mode and basically the online multiplayer features of Super Street Fighter 4 are going to be Insane.
Scott: you can have group battles where it's like us four versus you four, you know, so it's like oh you better fight this guy.
Scott: Oh you bet, you know that kind of stuff going on.
Scott: right team teamwork.
Scott: They got.
Scott: tournaments were like the tournament guy can like manage the bracket and like you can start up a tournament But not everyone actually has to be connected at the beginning.
Rym: Oh Goro design tournaments you could.
Scott: yeah You know you could.
Scott: so it's like I can set up a tournament for eight people and if only two people are there they play their bracket and then we wait for everyone else to show up and then they you know We could do it like that.
Scott: You could do basically all sorts of wicked awesome stuff.
Rym: This is not good is gonna be like it's not good at all because I gave up fighting games.
Rym: I've not played fighting games in a long time.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: I don't really want to go down that road again.
Scott: Oh you gave up fighting games.
Scott: Well, you might be interested to note the the trailer for Marvel vs.
Scott: Capcom 3 Including now that there's two really interesting things.
Scott: number one, right?
Scott: I know it's probably not gonna happen, but They really just need to come out with thousands of characters in one game.
Scott: why not?
Scott: I mean, you know Marvel's Capcom 2 had an insane number of characters But why can't they just have it where they have every character at least every character that anyone cares about.
Scott: or in the very least Is it really gonna take them that long to make every character if they had a nice enough sprinkling of?
Scott: The the weird ass care at least at least 50, you know or a hundred.
Scott: then I would be like, okay That is enough character.
Rym: I'd be okay with reskins like in smash.
Scott: Yeah, you don't want reskins.
Scott: But what you can do is you can do sort of like.
Scott: you can like patch together things, right?
Scott: For example, like, you know Iron Man shoots a blast of fire from his fist or whatever, right?
Scott: And then Silver Surfer can have the same, you know blast.
Scott: but then Silver Surfer also has like a flying move and you can give him the same flying it like attack with a Surfboard that spider-man has when he swings on a rope, you know.
Scott: So you can mix it up like that.
Scott: where there's just this there's a set of moves and each character sort of has different Combinations of the pre-existing moves as opposed to say Mortal Kombat where it's the exact same character in a different color But anyway Right.
Scott: So the other interesting things about this number one right Resident Evil dude is in the game.
Scott: So they're really.
Scott: they're getting creative like.
Rym: the greatest thing is the picture here and it shows like all the characters standing there ready for their Melee, he's just holding his gun.
Rym: Like hey guys.
Rym: Yeah, they I fear for the martial arts term.
Scott: I'm hoping to get really creative with which characters they bring in especially on you know, I guess on both sides, right?
Scott: It's like on the Marvel side.
Scott: They should start bringing in like some cosmic outer space dudes, which didn't make a really big presence in the.
Scott: you know They had Thanos.
Scott: I guess, you know maybe bring in like Ego the living planet something like that, right?
Scott: That'd be freaking awesome.
Rym: This is where you lose me right Galactus.
Scott: That'd be cool.
Scott: But maybe if in Capcom side why not bring in like Phoenix Wright why not bring in?
Scott: I don't know Frickin, I can't even think anything.
Scott: but you know, there's plenty of Wood man wood man, you know some of the man's cuz they had Megaman but they didn't have proto man, right?
Scott: Or don't?
Scott: no one can be proto man.
Scott: Just dr.
Scott: Wily straight up He comes out flying in a giant machine and you do damage to him.
Scott: the machine blows up and then he's just standing there.
Rym: Maybe all of his attacks are just bringing other robot masters to do their man.
Scott: Oh, that'd be freaking awesome.
Scott: I'd be great like wood man move.
Scott: Oh, what's the move for quick man?
Scott: I forget.
Scott: Oh shit.
Scott: So anyway, but the other the engine.
Scott: other interesting thing is that the rent they got this MT framework, which is like Capcom's internal Engine they're using for this game Apparently the like the in-game models.
Scott: They look like just like art straight from a Marvel comic book like it like you're playing the game and just your guy on screen.
Scott: It looks like some dude drew it and it's a you know Any still image looks like it was drawn on a Marvel comic book page every single one.
Scott: It's like unbelievable that they and these aren't even like final images.
Scott: They're still doing work on this.
Scott: but they ever they put up these screenshots or of like, you know Rendered models and it looks like just you know, like some dude drew it and I'm like they just copied that have a comic book.
Rym: That is weird.
Rym: Oh, they look a lot more like a straight up still then something that would actually be fluid.
Scott: It looks like someone drew it inked it and printed it and that you know, but it's a 3d model somewhere.
Scott: So that's kind of crazy.
Rym: Then they also announced that they're releasing the sequel to Okami.
Scott: finally Oh that no, it's not a sequel.
Scott: Apparently.
Scott: It's a I don't know what they called it The DS sequel to Okami.
Rym: Oh, come again.
Scott: No, I read that it was the DS spiritual successor not sequel spiritual success.
Scott: Yeah So you'll be able to take your DS or whatever and paint every single tree in the whole world with your stylus Which would be you know, maybe gonna be a lot better than doing it with you know, the Wiimote.
Rym: There's a chance they didn't follow the same Mechanic of do a million boring things for 40 hours that are coming.
Rym: I'm gonna take a wait-and-see approach on that but what I'm most excited about is still bionic commander.
Rym: We are because what did we say way back?
Rym: We said the remake is the awesome game and that 3d one is gonna fail.
Rym: and what happened?
Scott: It was right.
Rym: The 3d one was a disaster.
Rym: I don't think anyone even remembers it.
Rym: And yet bionic commander rearmed was crazy popular.
Scott: The thing is I'm worried because bionic commander rearmed too.
Scott: It looks like they have it right, but I didn't hear any music.
Rym: So, I don't know if the music is as good because the music honestly I'll say straight up was half the game solid half of what made that game awesome.
Scott: and number two You can jump.
Scott: so it's like well, what the fuck?
Scott: This isn't even bionic commando anymore.
Scott: What the hell is this jumping?
Rym: My only hope is that jumping is not always available.
Scott: No, it looks like jumping is always a bit.
Scott: Oh, maybe there could be an item that allows the jumping but it looked like it's just a tiny hop.
Scott: So it's like they'll have something just out of the reach of your hook and you jump a little bit and now you can hook It.
Rym: it'll only be worth it if he actually goes doesn't?
Scott: it doesn't look to me like he can jump, you know Marioing anything that's.
Scott: no it looks like it's a very tiny jump, but it's a jump nonetheless.
Rym: I am NOT dubious only because that they you know.
Scott: The thing is there might be situations you have to like use the jump to go over a bullet or something.
Scott: It's like a dodging bullets with jumping is annoying.
Rym: The thing is I trust them because rearmed was one of the most satisfying gaming experiences I had since portal.
Scott: Yeah, at least it graphically looks pretty much right in line.
Scott: Yeah, Mega Man 10 is already out.
Rym: So I didn't even be.
Scott: nine Capcom is still what I said, you know how maybe a year ago.
Scott: if not, right?
Scott: Capcom is still the number one game company right now.
Scott: if game companies want to make money do a Capcom's doing.
Scott: They got it, right.
Scott: You got it wrong.
Rym: So things of the day.
Rym: Oh shit This is just too funny and I have to push off another thing of the day just to get this out here.
Rym: You might have seen it but Kotaku has a short little story about a concerned parent who Discovered that his son had been banned from Xbox Live until the year 99 99 Mm-hmm.
Scott: So why did?
Scott: why did it ban you until 1999?
Scott: Why don't they just say permanent ban?
Scott: Why do they have to set a date on it?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I kind of like the idea though of that ban because theoretically, you know in the year 99 99 that kid can show his dick again.
Scott: Theoretically, I guess.
Rym: so the father, you know didn't.
Scott: he could also just get another account.
Scott: It's not like.
Scott: that's the only thing I understand about this.
Rym: God is Xbox Live.
Rym: You're paying for gold.
Rym: You have to give up all your shit to make a new account.
Rym: Yes Oh big deal that most people care about that.
Rym: All right, someone cared enough to get.
Scott: all you want to do is play games online.
Scott: You can just play.
Scott: get another guy.
Rym: Yes, but if someone cared enough to get their reputation get their points and get all these things They're not gonna give them up just to get a new account.
Rym: Mmm, but Regardless, I mean, I think you just put too much on the stock and the fact that other people care about these things.
Rym: Okay, the father posted in the public Xbox forum, you know, hey, that's a pretty cool dad.
Scott: He's smart enough to go do that.
Rym: I would like to know why my son's account was banned until 31 12 99 99 without any notification and The response from the Xbox Microsoft enforcer guy was and I quote Your son was exposing himself on camera in Uno.
Scott: Yep, that's pretty typical of Uno.
Scott: I mean basically the chat roulette of Xbox, right?
Rym: I Mean, it's not like.
Rym: Uno is a game That's for sure.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: that's it okay.
Scott: So I've always said and I'm pretty sure it's true right that the read that you know We look at all this bad typing on the internet.
Scott: You're like people saying I love you and they spell love Lu V and these little you and letter R.
Rym: It's just people who don't know how to type.
Scott: Yeah, I think you know a lot of.
Scott: I think older people attribute it to kids with like having no grammar or no writing skills.
Scott: But I really think it's just no typing skills and that that you know.
Scott: They still they can't type.
Scott: so they're hunting and pecking and trying to use as little few letters as possible and also Texting, you know on a cell phone with digits one through nine because most kids don't have smartphones that have full keyboards or whatever.
Scott: So, you know doing that, you know that typing leads them to you know Right in this way and then that writing in that way carries back to writing by hand and so forth.
Scott: So I Think that this person here on this website I'm linking to which is called hyperbole and a half dot blog spot comm made a bunch of funny comics.
Scott: How every time they see some bad writing on the internet they imagine that it's a person with just two fingers and one of them is mangled.
Scott: and how they imagine, you know, whatever someone writes a lot as one word and not two words that they imagine this monster called the a lot and they draw the a lot and there's a picture of an a lot.
Scott: and then you know, there's a picture of Someone caring about this a lot and a picture of a lot of fire and a lot of mist
Rym: I think you got to actually see these things and
Scott: a lot of straw and a lot of beer cans And it's it is a pretty funny comic that you should
Rym: Feel like we could use this in the forum because you know for a long time we had the moderators.
Rym: We currently have basically no moderators, but us and one or two people again, but we Would correct the grammar and spelling of the kids in the forum.
Rym: Maybe a better way is to have an a lot style comic for every common mistake and just stick it into the post of anyone who fails.
Scott: Mmm, the thing is it would be ideal to have the the comic appear as some sort of metadata and not actually in the post Itself true, but that would require you to write some sort of plug-in maybe when vanilla 2 comes out, right?
Rym: Yeah No We're not investing time in writing something for the current.
Scott: when vanilla 2 comes out and we switch to it and whatever.
Scott: whenever I can Make like a plug-in where a moderator can click and they'll be like a they could there'll be a list of grammatical mistakes And they can click the checkboxes right and basically you'll get the badges will appear on the post.
Rym: Right, that'd be perfect.
Scott: And basically they'll be Negative.
Scott: see the thing is.
Scott: well negative badges work, you know, it's all this whole psychology thing.
Rym: Right, maybe someone will collect the bad bad As the problem right is like.
Scott: if you want to use the badges negatively.
Rym: Well, I wanted one.
Rym: one way around it is to have punishments for we're in the meta Moment, by the way, cuz we're talking meta shit about the show It's right.
Rym: I'm feeling I want a cat-like typing filter When you are actually typing a post, I don't know I'm gonna.
Scott: I'm gonna beta test putting this stupidity filter on there, you know that one.
Rym: Yeah, that one worked pretty well.
Scott: Yeah, it's surprisingly well.
Rym: So also meta stuff the book club book right now is still Carl Sagan's cosmos.
Scott: Yeah, what do we do?
Scott: that episode?
Rym: Well, have you read it yet?
Scott: Maybe I'll add it to this Amazon order.
Scott: cuz you don't want to lend me here cop.
Rym: cuz I'm reading mine and I'm enjoying.
Rym: Book is cuz I haven't been reading it that much.
Scott: No I'm gonna air.
Scott: I'm getting it on Amazon.
Scott: Let me find a cheap coffee.
Rym: I've been reading more and more Java lately because I'm learning to write better Java because I'm basically transitioning and being a freaking developer.
Scott: Lucky you.
Rym: I'm not happy but I convinced everyone we're switching to get.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: Oh shit How about that?
Scott: I think it'll learn how to use it.
Scott: Do you know how to use it?
Rym: I'm working on it.
Rym: I'm setting up the server and setting up all the procedures and stuff.
Scott: Well, how are you setting up the server?
Rym: Well doses.
Rym: It's a Tuesday not Monday.
Rym: We'll talk about this on a Monday.
Rym: I think all right.
Rym: I Think that's it.
Rym: Pax is a long way away, but we'll be there doing panels and if you want to go to Pax West PAX Prime You should buy our badges now.
Rym: They're gonna sell out.
Rym: get hotels to Mm-hmm and kinetic.
Rym: on.
Rym: if you want to do an awesome gaming panel, we are still accepting submissions.
Rym: very soon We're gonna search.
Scott: there's not to be a gaming panel.
Scott: could be any panel, but it is Tuesday.
Rym: So I would assume if you're listening now you want to do a gaming panel.
Rym: We've got a lot of good gaming panels already.
Rym: You would not feel left out or alone if you were doing a gaming panel.
Rym: plenty gaming panel friends.
Rym: I don't think we have much else.
Scott: That's about it every.
Scott: all the used cosmos copies on frickin Amazon are all hardcover.
Scott: What the hell?
Rym: Actually the the soft cover I have right now because I don't know where my original copy went.
Rym: I bought at Wildwood for like a dollar.
Scott: You know one new from six bucks fun.
Scott: Okay, anyway, whatever.
Rym: Okay, so Might and magic.
Rym: we're not going to talk about the might and magic franchise or all the associated cruft.
Scott: It's a good series Man, it's all I'm always.
Scott: I do want to say though that might magic is one of those gaming franchises.
Scott: That's old.
Scott: There's a lot of games in it, right?
Rym: It appeals to a surprising demographic.
Rym: Yeah, what you would expect?
Scott: Oh, it's out there.
Scott: people has name recognition.
Scott: The thing is it's like, okay.
Scott: It's obviously not crazy popular.
Scott: It's not like Mario, you know, it's not like I don't know Friggin any Sonic the Hedgehog any.
Scott: it's not, you know Street Fighter, right?
Scott: It's like there are these.
Scott: it's weird how there's these sort of mid to low-end gaming franchises Manage to stick around.
Scott: it's like.
Scott: it's a franchise.
Scott: a lot of games say might magic on them.
Rym: They're not.
Scott: it's not crazy popular, but it's around and somehow it sticks around Despite not being one.
Rym: they were pretty crazy popular during the PC.
Scott: Yeah for a very short time.
Scott: But think about the number of people who played them in those olden days.
Scott: not a large number at all.
Rym: But I think what it is more is that I believe the demographic of a lot of the might and magic games skews a lot more to road toward girls surprisingly and at least in my experience, but also toward people who are Either almost off the radar on gaming like they're not online and vocal about their gaming but they play might magic and they like these games and the other types of people who play it a lot are the people who even if they're on the radar are not the people who Go to gaming websites and participate in like the online gaming culture.
Scott: Do you think there's a whole bunch of might and magic?
Rym: Players out there who just aren't talking because they just sort of sit home play So or in the very least they talk to each other And they go to those like might magic fan sites, which they're surprising.
Rym: I'm sure there's probably plenty of this but we're talking about one recent might and magic game clash of heroes on the DS.
Scott: Yeah, it's not heroes of might and magic.
Scott: It's might and magic clash of heroes And it is not heroes of might and magic because that would be silly.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: Here's a mighty magic clash of heroes.
Rym: Yeah, you know, I kind of wish it was named that now.
Scott: It's yet this.
Rym: it's basically.
Rym: There is technically an RPG in here, but no not really.
Rym: it is tacked on.
Scott: It has an RPG like Advance Wars has an RPG?
Scott: No,
Rym: no, no, Advance Wars was an engaging thorough story compared to might and magic clash of heroes
Scott: Like the part where you walk around the map at least in Advance Wars is just a map and you click on the next dot and then you fight and clash of heroes.
Scott: at least you do A little bit of stuff on the map.
Scott: but
Rym: there's a guy with a purple bandana who says I sure like my purple bandana and right next to him is a guy who Says I will pay you a whole bunch of money if you find a guy with a purple bandana and kill his ass Yeah, and then you go back to the guy with the purple bandana.
Scott: That's a lot more than Advance Wars, which says click on the next city to fight.
Rym: But Advance Wars you had the romance between the characters least in the old games romance in this.
Scott: Yeah Yeah between night guy and woodsy girl.
Rym: Oh fuck that You know where the best romances.
Rym: so far you haven't gotten it to this part But in the demon level you meet this succubus who won is totally hot.
Rym: Oh shit hot like actually totally hot both literally and figuratively And she basically joins her party.
Rym: she's kind of a bitch but whatever but there's definitely sexual tension there.
Rym: But it is so tacked on it is so flimsy, but it's just an excuse to play a puzzle game with a theme.
Scott: Yeah, I was kind of really surprised.
Scott: every might and magic game I've ever played right including Kings bounty, right?
Scott: Which is also people don't realize this, you know is a is my magic game right?
Scott: sort of secretly is The way they work generally is you walk around a map and you're sort of doing this town castle management kind of thing.
Scott: But you're also sort of managing this army and then you're also when you get into a fight there's a little there's like a tiny hex map and you move your units around and Fight and that's what it might imagine game is all about.
Scott: But this game has basically nothing to do with those at all whatsoever.
Scott: I can't even find any connection at all period except for the fact that as you walk around You can purchase units at certain stops and that's it.
Scott: And in no other way does it even resemble might magic any any other might imagine game I've ever seen.
Rym: now The thing is despite the theme Basically having nothing to do with the game whatsoever Yeah, I mean it makes so little sense and it even breaks down internally when you try to figure out like what's actually going on with the plot.
Rym: and How come you fight everyone you talk to with an army?
Scott: You don't fight everyone you talk almost everyone.
Rym: Okay Just the logistics of this do not make any sense, but had it just been the puzzle game It wouldn't have been as fun.
Rym: They did the theme for somehow it adds something to the game surprisingly and it basically just tricks you into Playing a series of puzzles that are kind of match up the colors with a little mechanic of making a little wall Different factions to do different things.
Scott: I think the puzzle game on its own would have been just as fun.
Scott: The thing is you the part of the you need to keep the theme on the puzzles, right?
Scott: Because the puzzles it's like you look at say magical drop, but it's a very similar puzzle game to this right and You know, it's got the same sort of action pull off the bottom and push back up right up match up three colors in a row To act to.
Scott: you know score but the this the combat and this has a theme like you choose different units.
Scott: they got swordsmen and spearmen you got big Knights and angels and Demons and all sorts of skeletons and all that sort of stuff and they actually attack and do damage and you build walls and You have different items and different powers.
Scott: So it's like they.
Scott: it's sort of like puzzle quest, right?
Scott: Puzzle quest was sort of like the first in this.
Scott: Okay, we have a puzzle game But we've also got sort of an RPG combat thing attached to what's basically Tetris or bejeweled or whatnot, right?
Scott: So this sort of takes it a step further.
Scott: It makes a better puzzle game and instead, you know puzzle quest the RPG part was sort of external, right?
Scott: You'd play bejeweled to get mana to play magical gathering in puzzle quest.
Scott: But in this you are.
Scott: the puzzle is the RPG Combat II part at the same time.
Scott: It's merged.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: it's not like they tacked on this combat to a puzzle to magical drop.
Scott: It's magical drop of fantasy.
Scott: It is the magical drop is the fantasy combat together.
Rym: now I think for people like us it wouldn't matter that much.
Rym: I mean look it's a game that we still love to this day is Battle balls where the theme is just pictures in the background and you're fighting with balls or cod crap to Sakura Tetris One of the best Tetris is except for I guess DS Tetris is better.
Rym: Yeah, probably Yeah, but we like that stuff.
Rym: people like us will play The versus puzzle game in any context if the versus puzzle game is good Especially if it's direct versus like doing damage to someone.
Rym: Yep But the theme of this game kind of adds a much more universal appeal.
Rym: But I think it really just serves the same purpose as the character you pick in the background of battle balls.
Rym: That has no effect on the game whatsoever.
Rym: It just adds this kind of element and also because of the different factions are different You know the skeletons or the elves or whatever and they're really different too.
Rym: It adds a huge kind of paper rock scissors or in the very least.
Scott: It's not a paper rock scissors I think it's just.
Scott: you have to play differently Not necessarily.
Rym: I'm pretty sure that certain factions can just kick the shit out of certain other factions.
Rym: you think so.
Scott: cuz I Get the feeling that every faction is sort of equal, you know I mean your units might not be leveled up or you might choose the wrong units.
Rym: You know versus everything's leveled up all the way.
Scott: That's the only part.
Scott: that's.
Rym: it's definitely what makes this game.
Rym: Is that the RPG?
Rym: whatever?
Rym: it's kind of fun leveling your guys up and whatever cuz you don't really have to grind.
Rym: But when you play versus it just gives you everyone all maxed out.
Rym: Everyone's maxed up level up all the way and then you both pick an artifact Yeah, and everyone has access to every artifact.
Rym: The only unlocking in the game at all is you have to beat the that part of the game of a given character.
Scott: maybe didn't beat the necromancy level.
Scott: then you can't use necromancy stuff like skeletons and wraiths and whatever in the.
Scott: You know the verses which is fine.
Scott: You know, that's I've seen a lot worse unlocking than that.
Rym: The only thing that really bothers me is that I kind of wish there were more things to do in the versus mode Like it's one situation where they made the versus mode great.
Rym: It's just a direct straight-up competition.
Rym: They didn't do anything stupid like Pokemon games tend to do.
Rym: it was exactly what I wanted But as a result, I just want more.
Rym: I want like 2v2 maybe some team fights.
Rym: I want different battle modes.
Scott: I think it would be cool if there was like some sort of mode, you know.
Scott: If you could like just give me allow me to modify the rules a little bit.
Scott: You know like tweak the number of guys that get sent in or yeah Cuz maybe I want to play a versus with two really low-level guys.
Rym: Yeah, you can't do that.
Scott: Yeah stuff like that.
Scott: I don't know or like, you know versus no big guys, you know Just like be like no big guy mode.
Scott: That'd be cool.
Rym: Now.
Rym: I still haven't actually played this game much with humans.
Scott: I played it once.
Scott: Versus against.
Scott: Alex are waiting for our food in a fancy restaurant and you know what that.
Scott: for the one time we played it It was crazy epic.
Scott: Like.
Scott: I come out like I played this a lot more than Alex has cuz.
Scott: I played it for you know weeks and he only Played it like, you know since he bought it which is after I told him about it because you didn't buy it, right?
Scott: Maybe I should.
Scott: I'm gonna buy it for the Xbox instead of the anyway.
Scott: So I come out with this huge devastating combo and bring his health halfway down.
Scott: He's like, oh shit and then we keep playing and he starts whittling me and whittling and whittling and I can't really mounting strong defense.
Scott: And he's got a big guy charging up and I don't have an.
Scott: I use my big guy right away I don't have another one coming in and it's not looking too good.
Scott: And we're basically at the point where he's got stuff charged up.
Scott: as soon as it lets loose I'm dead right and I've basically just I was like, oh I lost it's over.
Scott: But I charged up the only guy I had on the screen and yeah, I just went out.
Scott: whatever I can't win.
Scott: Then my one guy Frickin.
Scott: he activated on the turn right before and I didn't think he was gonna do enough damage to win.
Scott: So I had wrote him off.
Scott: He busted through a tiny broken wall and a couple units and he had exactly enough life left to do the eight damage Necessary for me to win.
Scott: exactly enough You know damage and he was down to zero and I won and I would have lost in the next turn.
Scott: So that is a friggin balanced awesome multiplayer right there.
Rym: I want to play a lot more of this game online with people.
Rym: I just want to fight actual humans.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Does it the DS play online?
Rym: I don't even look at them.
Scott: I know the Xbox will play online in the very least.
Rym: I'll play with people at the next packs.
Rym: Oh for sure These people better have this game to play because the single car you can play it seems to only let you play nights Mmm and nights.
Rym: I don't like.
Rym: I personally like the nights.
Rym: I like being the elves or the undead.
Scott: So I kind of like the big guys on the nights like the angel and the giant armored dude.
Rym: Yeah, but that's skeleton night in the.
Scott: he's pretty dangerous.
Scott: The thing is I like with the spider cloak.
Rym: He'll do like 190 damage.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is in terms of walls, right?
Scott: I like either the skeletons or the elves because the skeletons they have the walls that sort of build up when the skeletons get crushed.
Scott: But the elves actually I think of the slightly better walls because they just rebuild themselves.
Scott: So you can build like a tiny wall and you don't have to keep stacking it.
Scott: It'll just sort of grow on its own.
Rym: But at the same time the stacking is usually because the you can do some pretty amazing combos in this game despite the limitations Though I do wish there was a way to play with a slightly deeper and wider field.
Scott: Yeah, I think the thing is is like when they've designed the game they built it like exactly Definitely because it's like okay if you build any walls at all We're not going to give you have only five spaces, which means you can't build, you know, the six tall You know double fusion behind it, right?
Scott: You can only do that on an empty row and they you know We only gonna give you this many wide so that you can't just you know It's not a multiple of threes.
Scott: that way you can't just build a wall straight across perfectly You know, you're gonna have some funkiness going on there and that forces you to you know Manipulate your units cleverly and such and such.
Scott: so they balance it to the perfect height and width for the rule set they had.
Scott: But if they allowed you to go bigger and wider it could get pretty interesting.
Scott: But I think it also might not scale well because it would just be like it would just be more.
Scott: It's like oh, well great.
Scott: Now.
Scott: I basically it's like playing.
Rym: you might as well just play three games at once that are separate A little bit but it'd be interesting to play a similar game on a slightly larger scale.
Scott: I mean like would Tetris be any better if you made it taller and wider unless you also made it different.
Rym: That's exactly what I'm saying a slightly different game just with the slightly larger more zoomed out scale to it But otherwise similar in the way that you go about it.
Rym: Hmm, it's definitely it shows the triumph of a game that has a very small number of rules But yet has emergent strategy.
Rym: just by the interaction of those rules I mean get three guys in a row vertically and they start charging their laser.
Rym: Yet another three guys Vertically that will finish charging at the same time and are the same color as someone else already charging and they link up and they both Do more damage together.
Rym: Mm-hmm If you make a guy of the same color and type behind a guy who's already charging his laser double laser
Scott: Yep, you can even get like triple laser quadruple laser and
Rym: every big guy and most of the little guys have some weird special power But they're still very they're deterministic.
Rym: They're things like this guy does X more damage under y situation or this guy doesn't take damage when defending.
Scott: Yep, this is also, you know get three guys wide and they make a wall.
Scott: but what if you get?
Scott: you know You got three guys wide and you delete a unit and now you got three guys wide and three guys tall at the same time.
Scott: You basically get a wall and a charged laser.
Scott: you like get extra stuff for doing that.
Scott: Yep, you also get like extra turns because they only give you three actions per turn.
Scott: But if you delete guys and your deletion makes things happen, then you get extra moves.
Scott: So like you delete a guy that makes a wall it charges two lasers, but with that one deletion.
Scott: Well, guess what?
Scott: now you've got like three extra actions.
Scott: with those extra actions You could bring in extra units and build two more lasers and you know You can get.
Scott: you really get the machine rolling that way Pretty good.
Rym: It's just.
Rym: it's a solid game and I'd recommend, you know, anyone who's in this DS drought right now This game is pretty much up anyone's alley, you know, I think the DS I don't know if it's in like the biggest drought.
Scott: It is a slight drought compared to where the DS was before.
Scott: But you know the DS really is.
Scott: it's like the sleeping giant, you know, it's always there.
Scott: people don't talk about it too much But it's freaking.
Scott: everyone's got one.
Scott: It's got piles of awesome game like babies fashion like babies fashion You know and I think because people don't pay attention to it pretty much.
Scott: if someone does make a really great DS game That isn't like, you know Nintendo pretty much anyone but Nintendo makes an awesome DS game.
Scott: No one will know about it.
Scott: It'll be completely mystery.
Scott: What like this game was.
Scott: But then as soon as people discover it, it's like holy shit.
Scott: There's an awesome DS game We didn't know about discovered, you know, hidden grail and that's exactly what clash of heroes is.
Rym: I have to take a moment though.
Rym: The the tacked out RPG is Dangerously cheesy like there's some fucking dialogue.
Scott: It's just a generic RPG.
Scott: You know how many DS games have like just generic fantasy RPG attached to them?
Rym: but the the reason it feels so tacked on primarily is that you move around by moving between These dotted nodes and they'll be like a guys.
Rym: It looks a lot like that fight that bastardized Final Fantasy mystic quest Uh-huh.
Rym: It looks a lot like that.
Scott: There's you know, I've played a lot of DS games that are sort of you know Generic fantasy RPG and this is pretty much the same as all the others.
Scott: at least this one is a little bit better.
Rym: arts and Yeah, the arts good.
Rym: No, I think about the music.
Rym: The music sounds really good, but it sounds almost exactly like the music in Wesnoth.
Scott: Yeah, it's like when I started playing the game, you know You know, I was like, huh?
Scott: Where is the?
Scott: you know this music?
Scott: I've heard it before somewhere and I was like, you know at first I'm like.
Scott: this seems to sound exactly Like a lot of other music from you know, DS fantasy games, you know.
Scott: It just sort of felt like that even though I couldn't figure out exactly which game.
Scott: But then as soon as someone said Wesnoth, I'm like, huh?
Scott: Yeah, this you know.
Scott: I don't know if it's DS games in general or Wesnoth in this game or what but it is a style of music That just seems to be the music used in these fantasy games And I don't know what's up with it.
Scott: But it's sort of weird because it's not great like I wouldn't put on my iPod But it's catchy and you sort of remember it in this weird way and it's also sort of fitting.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: But yeah, it's it's fantasy musics.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.