Rym: Hey, it's Thursday, September 20th, I'm Rym and this is GeekNights tonight with the roll of the dice men in space Or something like that.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So I recall some years ago We didn't do a show one night because a building collapsed on the train that me and Scott and Emily all need to get out Of the city.
Scott: Well knee dead.
Scott: Yep
Rym: So I remember then I was the only one in my company that I knew of affected by this and everyone kind of laughed Like good luck getting home as I walked out the door and we had all of our you know That's shenanigans journey of getting dinner and taking Amtrak and then that scary-ass cab ride.
Rym: Yep so this year the The bridge the only bridge connecting these train lines to the rest of the world just fucking caught on fire.
Scott: Well, there was a fire near the bridge which me it might not have been the bridge itself.
Scott: It might have just been some, you know train equipment such as signals near the bridge.
Rym: Well what I read?
Rym: I saw pictures of a video online but what I saw the wooden pylons holding the bridge up were on fire.
Rym: Whoa, like way on fire.
Rym: But they started using two of the tracks again, and it wasn't that bad.
Rym: But it was funny how this time I see this notice because I forgot to unsubscribe from the oh shit.
Rym: alerts from into MTA.
Rym: So I get this text.
Rym: I'm like, oh Metro North is on fire and there's no trains.
Rym: and two of my co-workers who had been kind of snickering when that To me last time now live on Metro North lines And the tide was turned and I didn't give a shit and it was hilarious.
Rym: I was giving them advice like oh good luck getting home.
Scott: Actually, what they did is they had the trains just run to the Yankee Stadium station And yeah You take the subway to get there to go.
Scott: basically take the subway which is not on fire past the on fire bridge Using the non on fire subway bridge.
Scott: Remember that trains are on the other side.
Rym: They had the new station on the other side and they were set up to use it.
Rym: So they basically apparent out my guess is after the problem last time they came up with a plan for if there's trouble in Manhattan Can they make the rest of the train line work?
Rym: Cuz last time none of the trains ran anywhere because I didn't have a place to like turn them around switch tracks or anything.
Scott: Yep, also today.
Scott: Apparently there's a bunch of UN action because you know I was biking at work this morning and I get over to Manhattan and then it's like hey This road's closed and I bike past a little sign.
Scott: It's like you agree to security checks.
Scott: if you go past here and I'm like, oh, this is fantastic.
Rym: Yeah, 42nd Street had like a middle lane that they so did 57th Street at the middle lane.
Rym: I watched a motorcade go by.
Rym: I don't know what country or what limo or whatever it was But in the middle of the motorcade on either side of the limo where I guess The guy was were two vans with no doors on either side and there were guys with mounted machine guns.
Scott: I don't understand right?
Scott: why?
Scott: If You're in a motorcade, right?
Scott: Yeah, it's like cop car Like SUV SUV SUV the limo maybe another limo right vans, right?
Scott: If I was the important person, I would not be in the little.
Rym: I was the important person.
Rym: I'd be dressed as a cop on one of the motorcycles all secret like.
Rym: well The thing is you got body double in the limo.
Scott: The thing is that's a little risky because you might just fall off the motorcycle.
Scott: Yeah, right, but I would just be like in the cop car, you know in like the back.
Rym: So Scott you ever see a clear and present danger.
Rym: No, that doesn't help you.
Scott: Oh They took out the whole motorcade now.
Rym: Yeah, they took out the whole motorcade except for Harrison.
Scott: if I was a bad guy I would use RPGs to take out every car in the motorcade just in case it was smart.
Rym: It was a little like I'm used to.
Rym: you know, we live in New York.
Rym: I'm used to people with machine guns hanging around and I'm used to that.
Rym: Well submachine guns assault rifle This is the first time I saw Actual machine guns as in mounted on on some sort of swively bit much as it not an m4 but a para.
Rym: Yeah, not a not a carbine.
Rym: Not a car It's carbine.
Scott: It's fine.
Rym: I'll be fine.
Scott: No beans are what you trade for in bonanza.
Rym: Say I got the ultra rare carbine and Only CT's can have you RT.
Scott: I dropped for you.
Rym: But the reason it was eerie was I realized that I thought about this What if I had set up the motorcade?
Rym: why would I have that gun?
Rym: there's only one answer Why you would have those guns on either side of the main car to spray the crowd with suppressive fire while you escape?
Rym: Yeah Yeah, and I was in that crowd.
Scott: That's alright No, so I had to like bike all the way around and on the way home I just like I fuck Whatever.
Scott: I went north before I went because the thing is I biked past all these fancy hotels Where apparently they were all staying and that was why it was all locked down.
Rym: Mm-hmm, so Tech day.
Rym: We haven't done tech show.
Rym: We had this dearth of tech shows for all.
Rym: we did a really good tech show last time for a long time and then we started coming back in force, but we had a delay.
Rym: so we got a. I know we got to keep the game very high on the tech episodes.
Scott: I will see if we can do that.
Rym: So we'll get to what our topic is in a little bit.
Scott: And the meantime, let's do some news.
Rym: there is actually very important news, but we didn't get to talk about it when it happened for various reasons, but You all know HDCP at least I hope you know what HDCP is.
Rym: it's the thing that damn crap pola Theoretically prevents you from connecting non authorized digital output devices to Devices that are protected with HDCP for video and audio is a movie and you have a fancy TV and the T. if the TV supports HDCP and the device does you get the ultra high resolution?
Rym: But if your device doesn't support it they give you crappy resolution.
Scott: Well, no, it's it's that the TV has not about the device about the TV, right?
Scott: So what?
Scott: basically it's a macro vision for the 21st century?
Scott: So you have a blu-ray player and there's an HDMI cable coming out of the blu-ray player and on that HDMI cable there's some HD video and audio and Surround sound audio and they don't want you taking that video and audio off of that HDMI cable putting it Into.
Scott: some say, you know a recording device like a you know HDMI capture card in your computer and Recording that blu-ray disc basically copying it.
Rym: now Never mind the fact that I can still get an SD rip which is Almost as good and then I can just copy that.
Scott: Well, this thing is still be macro vision also, so it'll be going bright dark.
Rym: Now I don't think macro vision.
Scott: It's still in there though.
Scott: It's still there.
Scott: This is basically it prevents you.
Scott: it only stops you if you're doing it the stupid way like you plug a VCR and your blu-ray player that it'll stop you from doing that.
Scott: but Basically what it does is it checks to make sure that your TV is like a legit real TV.
Scott: If you try to make your own TV is not gonna work, right?
Scott: It's even if it's an HD TV.
Scott: If it doesn't have this fancy secret code in it Then the it'll just get SD.
Scott: the blu-ray player will refuse to put HD out the cable.
Rym: now There was that study a while ago that pointed out that the majority of American households who think they have a high-definition Television don't even know they don't have it set up and they couldn't tell if it was set up correctly or not.
Scott: Yeah, that's true.
Rym: But all that aside obviously, this is bullshit.
Scott: I shouldn't need you know special don't because you can just put your blu-ray disc in your computer and use handbrake and the HDCP doesn't even come into it.
Rym: I'll get to that later.
Rym: But I shouldn't need to digitally sign my TV to watch something that I legally bought Because the real problem here isn't that the pirates can get around it.
Rym: The Pirates can always get around it.
Rym: Nothing you do will stop the Pirates.
Rym: In fact, all you can do is hurt the people who paid by implementing stuff like this.
Rym: Yeah, my moral argument is that if I buy a piece of technology.
Rym: I should have the legal right to do whatever the fuck I want with it and with whatever the fuck I want with the outputs Of it now.
Rym: I'm I might break some other law and get prosecuted for that.
Rym: Like if I kill Scott with my TV Yeah, it's like.
Scott: should it be okay to make a gun that doesn't shoot if you point it at a person right or it's like The gun will only go off if you're doing something legal with it You know, like if you try to shoot a target, but if you aim at anything else, it won't work.
Scott: now Some people might think that's a good idea.
Rym: I actually think that'd be a cool idea.
Rym: Yeah, but I mean it's basically the same principle but at the same time it should be okay to circumvent those things for your own use.
Rym: hmm Regardless HDCP didn't stop anyone but people who legitimately bought stuff and wanted to watch it legally and it has no effect on the pirates.
Rym: and It got broken as we expected.
Scott: because like all DRM It didn't get broken by hacking got broken by someone leaking the key I heard.
Rym: the thing is no one has confirmed that the key was leaked.
Rym: Very likely the key was reverse engineered because Mathematically DRM can't work because the devices that do the decoding are in the hands of the consumers.
Scott: Yeah So it's like I give you a DVD and the DVD has a lock on it and you need to be able to watch The DVD.
Scott: so I give you the key, right?
Scott: So you unlock the lock and you watch the DVD.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So there you go.
Scott: The key is in your TV, you know, so you really the thing is it's you know.
Scott: So you're only unlocking the blu-ray disc when you watch it on your TV.
Scott: But if you can just get the key out of the TV somehow then you can unlock the blu-ray disc whenever you want.
Rym: Think about this.
Rym: We already know a truism of computer security.
Rym: Is that if someone has physical access to the device you're fucked?
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Now you can encrypt data and someone can get physical access and not be able to get to that data.
Rym: But that requires that the key to unlock that data is not on the device.
Rym: So All it takes to break any DRM you will ever see is some manner of reverse engineering and in this case Apparently it took about 40 or 50 non sequential public keys and then you could derive the private key with the right computing equipment And the guess is someone did that.
Rym: Yeah, so awesome and Intel's already like yeah I will DMCA the shit out of any who tries to use this too late.
Scott: I like how.
Rym: it's a nice short number.
Rym: I'm sure people already are getting this number like tattooed on their backs Just like they did with CSS.
Rym: Yeah, we should make some songs.
Rym: I think we sang the first bits of CSS on the show a long time ago.
Scott: I don't remember that.
Scott: Anyway, that's good.
Scott: Uh, here's an interesting story that I'm not sure if I like this or not But I want to.
Scott: I want to talk about it because it's an interesting.
Scott: someone had a clever idea.
Scott: That doesn't seem.
Scott: it seems shady, but whatever so easily.
Scott: Captchas right.
Scott: Hmm.
Scott: We all have captchas and all our websites because they're useful and it's really the only way we have of Keeping like just spam robots from doing things that are evil, right?
Scott: You know, if I have a form for like a poll or Registration on my forum or even e-commerce, right?
Scott: if I don't put some sort of capture then somebody can trivially write a tiny script that will hammer my website and Just do whatever the submit the form over and over and over again And maybe post a zillion posts on my blog or do something really annoying and spam the fuck out of me, right?
Rym: I'm curious what you're gonna talk about because there's the the Turing test question.
Rym: There's the disabled access question.
Scott: I know there's.
Scott: there's some company called solve media and what they've done is That the problem with captchas right?
Scott: is that you know?
Scott: is that they're annoying for regular people to do?
Scott: You know because they look at it and sometimes they don't even get it right.
Scott: or the you know Normal people don't like captchas that they're bothered by them.
Scott: And in fact if you had like a capture solving tool you could probably just sell it to normal people not even to spammers just Regular old actual legitimate humans because they hate having to fill out captures.
Scott: So what this company has done is they made a new kind of capture where instead of looking at some weird letters that are all Jumbly, it's an advertisement and you have to type in the quote, you know, what's in the advertisement?
Rym: Wow, that is Brilliantly evil.
Scott: Yeah, so look here's an example, right?
Rym: Brilliant.
Scott: and this is an example.
Scott: and the example says Windows Internet Explorer 8 and as an IE has an inner Explorer logo Clearly they're selling Internet 8.
Rym: so that's what I will type and then it says no.
Scott: and then it says browse safer.
Scott: And then it says please enter the quoted text.
Scott: You would type in browse safer and if somebody was using some sort of you know Digital imaging like something that would read the text in the image It would read Internet Explorer 8 or browse, you know And it might not that it might not know.
Rym: that it's only supposed to type in the quoted text just escalates the arms race in a way because they they could.
Rym: I mean if they know the Basic namespace or the basic question space they could do things like alright It asks for quoted something OCR for quotes and then do the stuff in between.
Scott: but no The thing is it'd be like a different questions for each ad.
Rym: Oh, yeah, but you could probably come up.
Rym: I mean basically one way to solve captures if they don't have a wide enough space is to have a human who works.
Scott: Porn companies do it right?
Scott: is you sign up for the porn site and in order to sign up for the porn site You have to do like 10 captions.
Scott: But those captions are actually captures for another site and the guy who with the porn site Uses the captions that you solve to go and send spam to someone else.
Rym: I'm curious how you discovered this fact that porn sites do.
Scott: this is news about it everywhere.
Scott: Uh-huh a lot of it's not.
Rym: just have you solved zero?
Scott: Well, you mean you know.
Scott: not, you know, I haven't solved any catches that weren't for me.
Rym: But The I always thought a better way.
Rym: I mean the ad thing that's brilliant is you're gonna make brilliant from the making money person exactly what I'm saying.
Scott: It's a guaranteed impression.
Rym: The person guaranteed has read the ad thought about it and typed something they had to interact with your ad.
Rym: It's brilliant and fuck them.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: but at the same time I think a non-evil way to go about it would be to have a picture of say a cat and they have to.
Rym: you have to type in English what it is and Fuzzy guessing and if they don't get it, well, they didn't pass the Turing test.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: That's that's a good way to do it.
Rym: Yeah, well, there is the trouble.
Scott: What is this cat with captures?
Rym: that some people are just not smart enough to pass a capture?
Rym: But I feel like that's a good idea because it filters out people.
Rym: I mean if someone it's a good idea.
Scott: if you have if you're looking if you're filtering out blog comments or something like that.
Scott: It's a bad idea if you're say E-commerce saying it's like well the stupid person isn't gonna give me their money now.
Rym: But at the same time do you want to do business with the stupid person when your credit card gets charged back because the shirt Didn't arrive because they gave you the wrong address.
Scott: I'll say I'm not gonna deny money.
Scott: It's like hey in football, right?
Scott: you never take points off the board.
Scott: if you kick a field goal and it was three points and it's good and you have a Chance to like do over the play or you could deny because there was a penalty Do not redo the play Ever.
Scott: do not take points off the board.
Scott: if you're a company and you have money sent over the wire Do not undo the money.
Scott: It's money.
Scott: It's good score money.
Rym: Yes So we had trouble actually coming up with what show to do tonight because we've been so focused on.
Rym: you know gaming after you.
Scott: Don't do things today first.
Rym: We're still in the opening bit here.
Rym: All right, I think we can do this now.
Rym: We did not decide what to do the show on and I was going through this whole list of shows that Emily compiled from forum Suggestions and the two we came up with that are the best I guess topics for us to talk out of our asses about our Nuclear weapons.
Scott: I know I thought it was space exploration.
Rym: Oh, yeah space exploration that works, too Uh-huh.
Rym: I guess you don't want to talk about the nuclear vessels.
Scott: Not really.
Rym: No, you don't you don't admit that we'll talk about that later.
Rym: then.
Rym: or Presentation software.
Rym: So I got this d6 here on a one two or three.
Rym: We're talking about space exploration on a four or five or six.
Rym: We're talking about presentation software.
Scott: Alrighty It's a - it's - Which one was that?
Rym: So things of the day this is definitely been making the rounds But I want to bring it up because I have an extra bit of hilarity from this.
Rym: This is a video of two dudes in Brooklyn or three dudes in Brooklyn I can't quite tell how many dudes and they're in their apartment.
Rym: and a Couple of weekends ago.
Rym: There was a thunderstorm in New York, which is kind of a rare occurrence.
Rym: It's very rare that a thunderstorm a real thunderstorm actually enters the borders of New York One.
Scott: that's really.
Scott: I mean, there's some where it's like rumble rumble lightning light.
Rym: Yeah, but it's rare that it's like Basically cut storms apart and sends them around the city and these dudes Lose their shit about this tornado because that tornado went through Brooklyn and another tornado went through Staten Island.
Rym: That's crazy.
Rym: That never happens.
Rym: But it's funny watching this for me because I grew up in the Midwest around Detroit Where storms far worse than that and tornadoes much like that.
Scott: Yeah, it was pretty loud through like every other weekend and it was pretty powerful But it was small and it moved so fast.
Scott: Like I got home.
Scott: I Did some stuff in the house the storm passed over and then it was quiet and then I went back outside Like as a kid.
Rym: that quick as a kid storms like that were the kind of storms We'd open the garage door and hang out in lawn chairs watching.
Scott: We'd only go inside if it looked like debris was gonna get thrown at us And then maybe you could even like close the garage door and look out the windows.
Rym: Yeah, are they?
Rym: if it was the worst it would ever get is we go down to the basement and watch out of the reinforced Glass.
Rym: Yeah, but that was if like the tornado was probably gonna hit the house.
Rym: Yeah, that was.
Rym: These guys really lose their shit.
Scott: Yeah, I think they were probably on some substances.
Rym: I don't think they were.
Rym: No, I don't think they were.
Rym: I mean to be fair to tell these days.
Rym: It was not a double tornado.
Scott: That guy wasn't on substances I know.
Scott: so it's the always the opposite of what you expect.
Scott: I Just want to pause to say that this is crazy blinking light out the window.
Scott: Look over there towards the end of the bridge on the side of one of the buildings.
Rym: Wow, I feel like that should be a thing of the day.
Rym: That is a really really bright light and it is like many many miles away from us.
Rym: It's on the other side of the river and it's blinking and it's like it looks like it's almost at the alt like a halfway down Manhattan like it's one of those buildings.
Scott: It's like one of those lights that you'll see blinking to like keep airplanes away from the top of a building.
Scott: But it's on during the day and it's not on the top of a high building.
Scott: It's on like the mid the side of a shorter building.
Rym: I cannot express to you how fucking bright this thing is.
Scott: It's really far It's like someone's.
Scott: it looks like, you know When you look at a stadium and someone flashes their camera and it goes like right.
Scott: it looks like that, but it's ridiculous.
Scott: It's like miles away, but that's what it looks like and it's repeating it pretty frequent intervals like flash.
Rym: My best guess is some sort of art welding Flash, but why is he flashing?
Scott: Why is he arc welding at regular intervals?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: fiddle fiddle fiddle fiddle fiddle fiddle fiddle.
Scott: It's like every.
Scott: it's like exactly every second.
Rym: That's really weird.
Rym: Hopefully we aren't going to die and then we'll tell you what that was a really reflective surface spinning and reflecting the sunlight But there's not that much sunlight left and how it's pretty sunny so slow and why?
Rym: as such a point source.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: That is really bright anyway, she got a thing in the day other than that thing.
Scott: Here's my thing today.
Scott: All right, so I don't know.
Scott: people listening to Monday shows know about hell.
Scott: But anyway, here's the hell of the anime variety, you know anyhow.
Scott: and this Goku Yes, this these videos.
Scott: there are two of them.
Scott: They are quite hellish.
Scott: it's apparently from a movie called kuno ichi ninpocho, which is a Movie like a bad old movie about female ninjas and they all have a vagina bubble power.
Scott: That's all that tells you everything you need to know now about these stupid clips.
Scott: These are two clips from the movie.
Rym: the thing about the vagina bubble power is that you might be thinking maybe that's euphemism.
Rym: You might be thinking well, they're making some joke.
Rym: And when I see it, I'll get it now.
Scott: It's just like naked cars.
Rym: It is literally a vagina bubble just like utenna movie and naked fucking cars.
Rym: Yep, it's anime.
Rym: Hell is something I almost feel like any like.
Rym: I feel like we should do an internet equivalent like we should make our own like we sit on the couch and like a darkened room with like spotlights on our faces and we do anime hell as an hour-long show and Put it on the internet.
Rym: because non anime con going.
Rym: people do not know what anime hell is.
Rym: It has nothing to do with anime.
Scott: There's some animes in it.
Rym: sometimes there's anime in it but it Imagine taking a bunch of nerds and put them in a room at like midnight like 11 o'clock after they're exhausted from a day of conventioning and Showing them strange things with no context and no explanation.
Scott: lots of the kind of clips that you would see on late night.
Rym: Yeah, like remember that story from North America that thing a day from a while ago.
Rym: That was that was something we saw that was hellish at an anime hell.
Rym: That was like a seven out of ten on the jikoku scale.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: All right, so the meta moment about your thing today.
Rym: I already did a thing of the day captain.
Rym: All right, you know your face in that light.
Rym: Are you sure it's not a mind eraser?
Scott: I think it's a orbital mind control.
Rym: So metamoman You okay metamoman we're good doing the night.
Scott: So the New York comic-con slash anime festival is October 8th 9th and 10th.
Scott: We have a panel Friday night Which is 8 Friday night.
Rym: It is 730.
Scott: Yep So I guess we're not going to board game night.
Rym: I guess we're not going to board game night Which is the same exact time.
Rym: This will be the first board game night I've missed in a while, but that's fine.
Scott: That's fine.
Rym: Also that weekend 10 10 10 is all weekend.
Rym: That's the burning wheel calm.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know I don't know how much if I'm gonna go to the big con on Saturday and Sunday if we're only doing one panel there now.
Rym: Yeah, I'm going to the burning con something fierce.
Scott: Yeah The burning con actually I found out is full up now like they've reached the fire marshal number of the space that they have gotten.
Rym: Well, then kids stuff you didn't pre-register don't go.
Scott: Yeah Well, I mean he is a thread on the burning wheel forum.
Scott: That's like if you want to go and you haven't registered yet post here.
Scott: So we'll see how that goes.
Scott: What else is meta?
Scott: There's not that much.
Scott: Oh one thing the nerd NYC who does the board game night also is doing this Gotham Gaming Guild thing, right and Basically the way it works is in the month of October.
Scott: There are three RPG sessions in New York City and If you do this, you have to do all three sessions.
Scott: You can't be like, I'm just going to one.
Scott: No, you have to do all three.
Scott: if you can't do all three don't sign up.
Rym: I'll sign up under an assumed name and if they suck I just won't show up.
Scott: it costs actual money though That's fine.
Rym: So money not as valuable as time.
Scott: and basically there's five games with five GM's and you sign up and you have.
Scott: you give like Your first second and third choices of which game you want to do and then they put you in a game and you have even If you didn't get your first choice, you still have to go.
Scott: Yes dangerous It's like you committed, you know You're in and then you basically pay money which they use to rent the space with the tables And you go to the three sessions and you play an RPG for three sessions and I am doing a free market game.
Scott: So if you want to play free markets, it's October 1st October 15th and October 29th at 7 p.m.
Scott: And Go to nerd NYC forum and this threads about it and you can sign up and all that jazz.
Scott: So there you go.
Rym: All right, so space exploration is actually recently a very hot topic among nerds Mm-hmm.
Rym: I wonder why?
Rym: maybe because we don't have a lot of money anymore and Nerds really want us explore space because we want to live in space someday.
Scott: Well, I think the thing is right.
Scott: It's like we look at all this other technology that we have and the power of this technology is advanced So much in such a short time.
Scott: right like especially computers, you know I mean the first the Apollo guys.
Scott: they had like a Commodore 64 to go to the moon with and now we've got like Pentium azillions, so shouldn't we be able to go to ten moons?
Scott: You know instead of just one moon, but no we can't.
Scott: and I think the real problem is simply the laws of physics.
Scott: It's really really difficult to get the hell out of here because gravity sucks.
Scott: You need a lot of energy and no matter how fancy your technology is You need a lot of energy which is expensive and difficult and you need fucking rocket fuel and it sucks.
Rym: I think more to the point.
Rym: I'm an advocate of unmanned and Scientific space exploration but there's a certain impatience among a lot of people who want us to explore space in that Even if we invent even if we put like half of our national resources toward space exploration We're not good.
Rym: It'll be generations to get the technology.
Rym: We want.
Scott: probably it'll be generations and generations Before we figure out crazy chase the laws of physics don't even get in our way and we don't run out of fuel.
Rym: Yeah, I mean it could be the old Devine hypothesis come to bite us in the ass.
Scott: Yeah, maybe you should explain that for the people who don't know it.
Rym: It was an idea and there are a number of other similar theories, but we don't know if it's true.
Rym: It's a hypothesis You can lump and it actually was kind of discredited because it made very specific predictions.
Rym: but you can boil all these different kinds of hypotheses together into one idea that it is possible that a planet like Earth has a Finite number of chances to escape its own Orbit and achieve permanent settlement outside before the planet isn't gonna leave the orbit.
Scott: there's something on the planet.
Rym: The civil is the planet.
Rym: as in things from the planet have one shot To make it out and make a colony that turns into like one of those Michio Kaku level 1 level 2 level 3 civilizations Before they use up all the easily accessible latent energy on the planet.
Rym: now Some people have gone one step further and argued that you only get one chance to industrialize And if you don't get to a kind of post energy scarcity society before you use up all the limited resources You're done and it's caveman times forever.
Scott: Yeah, cuz think about it, right?
Scott: You got this big planet.
Scott: It's a big rock, right?
Scott: It's only has so much fuel and energy in it and you're getting more from the Sun.
Rym: But it's now we could get energy from the Sun.
Rym: but it's gonna take a lot of resources that aren't from the Sun to theoretically to build up the technology to Usefully utilize the Sun enough to achieve high levels of usefulness.
Scott: exactly So you you have this fuel and you use it and you have to use the fuel to build up a society And to build rockets and to build whatever.
Scott: But you have to build you have to get your whole society to the point where you can get people living on another planet Right with only the fuel you have.
Scott: and you can't get more fuel very easily You can just get it trickling in from the Sun very slowly.
Scott: So it is really it's like you have one chance Maybe to get out and if you miss that chance You're just stuck on your earth or wherever planet you're on forever Unless aliens come to save you or something like that.
Rym: Now the original Olduvai theory really said that an industrial civilization has like a hundred years to exist.
Rym: And we've made it about a hundred years without trouble.
Scott: and it looks like, you know Even with the doomsayers out there, right?
Scott: Even if we just didn't even bother in giving a shit at all We you know, it just went out.
Scott: whatever.
Scott: we still have enough oil for at least a hundred years now.
Rym: only an energy theory.
Rym: We're not talking about pollution and all the other bad stuff.
Rym: Say whatever about that, but when it comes to energy utilization, we're probably doing okay.
Rym: But that's I don't think that is a valid argument to say we shouldn't.
Scott: no no No I'm just saying that we if we just didn't give a shit We could still all our cars and all our factories and everything we have.
Scott: we'd still have electricity and the power plants would still be Churning in a hundred years with just the resources that we have available now.
Rym: But space exploration is very much among nerds like us.
Rym: I mean you can't help but watch cosmos or read cosmos at a still more glorious dawn.
Rym: a way to just think yeah Yeah, we'll go out to the stars.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: It's not so easy.
Rym: I think the analogy is to why I'm actually against any further funding for manned space exploration for the next like 30 or 40 years If not, the next several generations.
Rym: is pretty simple.
Rym: and I sit now.
Rym: I know how.
Rym: I brought out my fairly controversial opinion.
Rym: just BAM kind of stuck it in there.
Scott: All right, you didn't just BAM sneak it in there by saying BAM.
Scott: I snuck it in there In order to sneak it.
Scott: you have to not say anything it's unsnuck.
Scott: that's like sneaking it.
Scott: That's like being completely stealthy sneaking into a museum getting right next to the diamond Taking the diamond off its stand replacing with the fake diamond and going security guards.
Scott: Did you totally see that?
Scott: Oh, I don't you see that shit leaders.
Rym: I got the real diamond in.
Scott: a fake diamond is in the butt.
Scott: Oh, man, I am the boss.
Rym: We have that is called stentorias stealthy.
Scott: Oh, it's called upon the third.
Rym: Anyway, I feel this because quite frankly I'll use an analogy from a video game.
Rym: let's look at the civilization games right now say I can research pottery and mining and I don't know gunpowder.
Scott: Gunpowder is the winner.
Scott: No, because you can just use your gunpowder to take the pottery and mining from the other guy.
Rym: All right, so gunpowder is gonna take me a hundred years to research Because you know my current level of science is not that high.
Rym: Pottery is gonna take me a year to research And the benefits of pottery might speed up the bet the the time to get gunpowder Such that if I research all these other things first gunpowder will take less time Even if I add all those other things together then gunpowder with my current technology.
Scott: And that's obviously a simple analogy, but a very good lesson from civilization which civilization 5 comes out tomorrow.
Scott: Oh shit, that's perhaps today because most people will probably listen to this today.
Rym: That is the end of GeekNights you realize.
Scott: September 21st 2010.
Scott: War was beginning
Rym: But I feel like right now I mean the space race in the Soviet Ute era and Accommodating in us getting on the Russian
Scott: space minute
Rym: when we landed on the moon in fucking 1969 Which was a long fucking time ago, and we haven't really done anything cool to the masses Except
Scott: landing on the moon a bunch more times.
Rym: Yeah, but no one cared anymore.
Scott: Fucking space stations, holy shit.
Rym: actual space stage I know and no one cares.
Scott: and that amazing fucking shit robots that fucking work on Mars for real.
Rym: Yes, we have pictures of Mars.
Rym: I saw he's almost live stream of the Martian atmosphere from the surface and that itself was a while ago.
Scott: Oh shit fucking like basically what our metal box robots with not so many moving parts going so far out into space like oh my god Like they're out by Saturn and shit or even farther away Perhaps even out of the solar system.
Rym: Imagine what it really felt like is we didn't even live through that we.
Rym: it was so long before we were born.
Rym: Imagine the feeling of watching live a dude walking around on the goddamn moon god day next to the goddamn Batman And the fact that most people are not excited about that and don't Marvel at that anytime.
Rym: it's brought up kind of sad because it's what have you done for me lately?
Rym: Yeah, and even then what have you done for me though?
Rym: You don't see.
Scott: you don't see any like, you know Chicago Cubs fans They're not partying because this the World Series they want years ago sent the Chicago Cubs to the moon.
Scott: They won the World Series a hundred years ago.
Scott: You don't see them partying, right?
Scott: That's what have you done for me lately, you know, if it doesn't happen right now, I don't give a shit.
Rym: I think my issue is that the cost to society to continue manned exploration right now is Way more than the benefits were likely to get.
Rym: I mean even if we wanted to establish a permanent colony on the moon or on Mars, I don't think manned exploration is the way to go about that quickly.
Rym: I think very detailed non-man like 40 years at a rocket scientist.
Scott: What do you know?
Rym: Well, the rocket scientists all seem to agree, too.
Rym: I don't see a lot of people advocating seriously who are in a position to advocate Legitimately that we should be really spending a ton of our resources on manned spaceflight right now.
Scott: Well, I think the thing is is right.
Scott: The problem with a lot of spaceflight stuff, especially in the US right is that people care way too much about safety in particular Especially with manned spaceflight, you know and they care about losing money, right if they invest a whole ton of money into something They don't want it to fuck up like has happened many times and they especially don't want people dying Which has also happened more than once.
Scott: so Basically, they need to avoid those things at all costs.
Scott: and since our space stuff is all Commercial and even if is all government owned and even if when it is commercial, it's still heavily regulated, right?
Scott: They're very worried about these things and there's all sorts of limitations and the result is that they need to make these things any Rockets or whatever.
Scott: they make them like ninety nine point nine nine nine percent safe And the fact is is a diminishing return in terms of money spent versus safety, right?
Scott: I can make a rocket that's ninety percent safe So one out of ten times it'll blow up or whatever But it'll get the job done nine out of ten times and but it'll be like ten percent of the price of that Rocket is ninety nine.
Rym: I mean physics really.
Rym: I'm just making numbers up But the point is you know that the famous rocket fuel equation?
Rym: Yes, the equation that tells you how much fuel to put in a rocket depends upon how much fuel you put in the rocket.
Scott: Yep, that sucks.
Scott: It sucks big-time.
Scott: But the thing all right, but it's like okay to make the rocket.
Scott: if let's say the rocket starts out zero percent safe It's gonna kill everybody.
Rym: Okay, so it's just a gun.
Scott: It's just a bomb.
Scott: It's a bomb a rocket.
Scott: it's a rocket fuel bomb.
Rym: you just shoot someone to say did it push him into space?
Scott: All right, so I want to make this rocket 10% safe.
Scott: It cost me X dollars.
Scott: I want to make it 20% safe.
Scott: It cost me like 2x dollars.
Rym: I'm curious.
Rym: What do you imagine the 20% safe rocket looking like one out of five times?
Scott: It works and the other four times it blows up.
Scott: That simple it's got four.
Scott: it's like it's got a Russian roulette.
Scott: How about over?
Rym: How about the 1% rocket?
Rym: What kind of fucking rocket actually has a 1% chance?
Scott: So it's like a little toy rocket, you know made a cardboard and whatever and the engine which is sort of gimp from the factory.
Scott: So it looks kind of funny.
Scott: You don't know if it's gonna go but you push the button and maybe one in a hundred days take a whole bunch of Engines and strap them to some cardboard and put a guy in a chair.
Scott: Yeah, it just it might happen You know, maybe balloons see but at the same.
Rym: that's one aspect.
Rym: But I think as a society we could easily sidestep that particular issue.
Rym: because if you look at I mean if you imagine right now if the the president of the United States came to the American people gave a press conference and said We're looking for volunteers for a mission a manned mission to Mars That will likely not see any of the people on it returning home or even making it to Mars.
Scott: No No, I'm not see.
Scott: the thing is I'm not even talking about just the man stuff.
Scott: obviously that right but if you have a non-manned Thing they still make it crazily safe because a they don't want the rocket hurting anyone who's sitting on the ground.
Rym: I don't think that's as much of a.
Scott: it's not that much of a concern because they're really good at making rockets.
Scott: But be they're worried about losing the really expensive equipment inside right.
Scott: if it blows up with a billion dollars You get in big trouble.
Rym: So here's the the.
Rym: I think what you're not looking at.
Rym: I was only talking about the crazy insane cost of safe manned space flight, which is far more costly.
Rym: But with unmanned stuff.
Rym: I'm sure they've already calculated what costs more.
Rym: losing five rockets to get one up or sending one up is guaranteed to go up.
Rym: They wouldn't because their lives aren't at stake.
Rym: They wouldn't be doing the more expensive way?
Rym: I don't think.
Scott: but that's the thing.
Scott: right is this is actually was that SpaceX, right?
Scott: I watched they.
Scott: they had was a commercial rocket and they launched it and I watched the launch and it totally worked.
Scott: It's cheaper than the shit NASA's using.
Rym: Where do you think we launch rockets from are like not not our man stuff, you know the space shuttles.
Rym: What about all those satellites?
Rym: We put out pretty fucking cheaply and a lot of them blow up.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, we've already got that down because there's practical applications of that.
Rym: I just feel like the thing.
Scott: the point is that this is commercial company that made a satellite launching rocket that is cheaper than The ones that NASA is doing.
Scott: Yeah They're.
Scott: obviously they're not optimal down.
Scott: They got.
Rym: a lot of our satellite launches are done from outside the US.
Scott: Anyway, that's also true.
Rym: I think more really man exploration is the thing because I feel like we gain a lot more benefit from Surveying the space and sending unmanned probes on 20 40 80 year missions then we do by sending a human out there to die Mmm, or not die and just walk around on the moon going I'm on the fucking moon.
Scott: I like the space tourism though, right?
Scott: It's like people want to go to space just so they can go to space.
Rym: I think that's fine.
Rym: I don't think there's any problem with a commercial endeavor that's willing to risk money and lives.
Scott: go for it Right, but the thing is is right is now what if there is that limit on?
Scott: we only have one shot to get out there?
Scott: And now you're wasting the precious rocket fuel on people.
Scott: I would look around.
Rym: Alright, if we're gonna make that argument, I would argue that 90% of what I do in my daily life is similarly wasteful.
Rym: I Mean, you know hot the stupid firewire thing is how much electricity that thing's burning?
Rym: or those lights when we tried to record that video?
Rym: Again, what's that adding to society?
Scott: something something.
Rym: Yeah, I just I think the sieve analogy really says my opinion best.
Rym: I feel like we should really focus on unmanned and practical space exploration and we should really hold off until technology Reduces the barrier to entry like if say right now it's like 80% of our resources to get to Mars with humans.
Rym: But who's to say that in 40 years?
Rym: It won't take 40% of our resources to do the same thing.
Rym: I mean think about how hard it was to send a megabyte of data a hundred miles 20 years ago.
Scott: Well the other right.
Scott: the other issue is that sometimes politics just gets in the way right.
Scott: for example There was that They were gonna try to develop that thing where it would go into space and then it would have a whole bunch of fucking nukes to go out into space really fast.
Scott: and They basically didn't want to do that because people don't like the idea of nukes even though it's in space and it wouldn't bother them at all.
Rym: Or the fact that sometimes presidents of many nations will say things like we're going to put a man on X Because this is a politically expedient thing to do
Scott: and
Rym: While it was a probably one of the greatest achievements in human history to actually put people on the moon in 1969 Think what did that get us other than a unifying moment like aside from the social and the kind of visceral feelings What did it really get us that unmanned exploration could not have gotten us at a fraction of the cost?
Rym: Mmm and imagine how much cheaper it would have been to try to do that starting today.
Rym: if today We were like all right now.
Rym: We're gonna try to go to the goddamn Batman.
Scott: Yeah, you wouldn't have had a 10 failed attempts.
Rym: It wasn't necessarily 10 failed attempts.
Rym: the Apollo mission was not 10 failures, and then we made it.
Rym: It was in a series of steps along the way of course, but the plus Scott Are you forgetting the Gemini program or the Mercury program?
Scott: I don't know all the.
Rym: you know anything about the space program?
Scott: I do.
Scott: I just don't remember every single fucking goddamn mission because it's like a zillion of them.
Scott: There aren't that many.
Scott: there's a lot.
Rym: You know how many Apollo missions happened in total.
Rym: Yeah You know there were at least 13 because there's that movie.
Scott: I know I think there was like 16 or 17.
Rym: Oh a Gemini.
Rym: Do you know anything about Gemini?
Scott: It's a constellation what?
Rym: Did Gemini have men in it or not?
Rym: It Did.
Scott: okay it had men.
Scott: that people man's man.
Scott: how many men's more than one?
Scott: That's why I was called Jim, and I went to space camp as a kid, so that's why you know.
Scott: well technically It's not like they teach you the shit in school.
Scott: Maybe they should.
Scott: oh they did then teach me in school.
Rym: They taught me that in school.
Rym: in fact I remember when I didn't actually go to space camp.
Rym: space camp was for kids younger than me Academy so fancy.
Rym: if you look anytime you see like videos or TV or movies or anything involving space camp like say the movie space camp.
Rym: Everything they show is actually from space Academy.
Rym: space camp is like lame.
Rym: It's like young kids.
Rym: science II can't?
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: space Academy is what you think is face care, but anyway I remember when I got there and most of the kids already knew most of the stuff like we already knew like all the Gemini missions and Mercury program and the probes and everything and The kids who didn't know were kind of like the kids who got to RIT in the CS program.
Rym: It didn't already know how to code.
Rym: Yeah, it was basically like that Usually no good for the record.
Rym: I was the mission commander of our simulated mission in like the full space shuttle simulator, and we lost three men.
Rym: Uh-huh we my team barely made it back down alive those ideas.
Scott: the thing is usually with space missions You're losing everyone or no one right?
Scott: How did you lose three guys?
Rym: You know how we lost three guys because they were jackass scientists.
Rym: So they're they're on the space station and they came back to the space shuttle And we detached and then they had to do some last like mission on the spacewalk crane, right?
Rym: And then come in and I was gonna have him come back down.
Rym: They had already missed their landing window because they were dicking around up there.
Rym: So we're already off script and I had to basically order them to just give up on the scientific mission.
Rym: come in We're going to do the emergency landing in White Sands because that was the last window they had and then they're gonna.
Rym: You know, they were basically gonna die.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So they refuse to come back in and their science officer refuses to force them back in.
Scott: he was just role-playing or what?
Rym: Uh, yeah, I don't.
Rym: I honestly the kid was kind of dumb and I don't know why he was the space camp But he refused my order and I couldn't even talk to them directly.
Rym: I did you know like in Gundam shows where like the captain says blah blah blah and then like Another person listens to the captain and then tells each department what to do.
Rym: I could not talk to them directly.
Rym: I just talked him through the calm.
Rym: Mm-hmm And eventually I gave the order to close the doors on them and prepare for landing there and they died.
Rym: They died in space.
Rym: We cut them off and we landed and I saved my team.
Scott: Yeah Okay, I guess the only other way like an individual really heated.
Rym: It was actually kind of fucking awesome.
Rym: I guess I had my clipboard and my headphones.
Rym: I was yelling.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: That was a that was a fun fucking moment.
Scott: I guess the only other way like individuals could die in space is they as well.
Scott: if you're on a mission alone, right?
Scott: Heart attack.
Scott: Yeah, if you get a heart attack much pooping disease Or like you've got a spacewalk and you fuck up right then Yeah You could hurt yourself.
Scott: or if you just you just go open the airlock go out into space on purpose.
Rym: someone died Independently in the space station, but they died of an accident on the space station.
Scott: I guess like if you're in a space station module and that module blows up but or like he has a hole in it But everyone else is in a different module and it's totally safe.
Scott: That can happen in the space station.
Rym: a meteorite broke one of the windows.
Rym: Yeah, that's exactly that and it depressurize stuff and the crew survived that an escape plan that they they made.
Rym: But then when they went back in to fix it One of them did not properly do the airlock and died and then the other one tried to save him and he didn't die But he couldn't save the guy.
Scott: Yeah, I guess Really fucking fun.
Rym: So if you're gonna have to do it, you should do it.
Scott: There's plenty I guess there's plenty of opportunities to not kill everyone in space and only to kill a few people.
Scott: I guess all.
Scott: there's another chance like if the aliens come But then they only get one of you right?
Scott: Oh, yeah, cuz Sigourney Weaver totally makes it.
Rym: Yeah, but I Swear to God if my people had attempted a landing there.
Rym: So, I mean I guess do you agree or disagree?
Rym: should we just hold off on manned space exploration until the Diminishing returns is a reverse curve?
Scott: because think about it We're playing sieve right now right as a world and right now space station is we get you know The screen has come up and it's like what would you like to research next?
Scott: and it says going into space or Sanitation.
Scott: All right and going into space will take a hundred turns or Sanitation two turns.
Scott: which one are you gonna pick?
Scott: Because you know if you keep picking the one that takes two turns over and over again Eventually the one that takes a hundred turns will only take two turns.
Rym: and that's the situation you get into where.
Rym: yes I've got gunpowder and no one else has gunpowder.
Rym: My two musket men cannot stand up to the 400 barbarian horsemen.
Scott: Mm-hmm You know also it's like we're we're we're also really close, right?
Scott: It's like we're developing all kinds of technologies that will help us out in space like, you know Ways to get oxygen and all that kind of stuff and not have to keep shipping oxygen containers out there or anything like that.
Scott: You know, we can actually make little colonies and whatnot.
Scott: And if we I can actually do that then maybe then is the time to go, you know It's like going out there now, you know and testing our really early prototypes.
Scott: that sort of thing aren't gonna You know help us as much now.
Rym: A lot of people make the argument that so much great technology came out of the space race.
Rym: That is practical for everyday use but I feel like a lot of those things Could have happened anyway with similar investment into more practical.
Scott: Well, the other thing is, you know, we still have a space station already Right, so we can still do plenty of zero gravity experimentation.
Rym: I have a much better argument against that kind of thinking.
Rym: Mm-hmm s slash.
Rym: space exploration slash war slash S/g.
Rym: Yeah, I guess I put an extra s in there, but you get my point.
Rym: Yeah war gives us so much practical technology.
Rym: Should we spend more money on war or should we spend money on developing technology?
Scott: Yeah, I mean cuz think about the kind of technologies that war makes right.
Scott: think about what those are and there are many of them.
Scott: Not all of them are bad.
Rym: a lot of them are practical or everyday.
Scott: But think about the kind of technologies that we've made recently that have nothing to do with war like, you know Had something to do with war yeah, but not mobile phones really as much you know, or you know Facebook Podcasts,
Rym: so I wonder how much of a contrary opinion we're taking.
Rym: I want what do you guys think?
Rym: Maybe I'll make a little poll in the thread about this episode Mm-hmm, and then we can have further discussion based on that.
Scott: Sounds good.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and a comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.