Rym: It's Wednesday October 6th.
Rym: I'm ready.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: all the new anime from October 2010 give or take some.
Scott: Let's do this Alright, so yesterday.
Scott: I'm bored at work, and I'm watching the tweets right and Alex Levitt from MIT He tweets out something about G is trending on Twitter with a link wow who watches the trending on Twitter?
Rym: like?
Scott: I can't think of Anything more useless, and there's actually a site that it will explain to you.
Scott: I think it's called.
Scott: What's the trend?
Scott: and it explained.
Scott: if you don't know what why or what something is that is trending?
Scott: It will tell you what it is.
Rym: I just I've never Run into anything worthwhile because it trended on Twitter, but nothing I like friends on.
Scott: so I was curious.
Scott: I was like okay the word GEE is trending on Twitter right and a fellow anime Japanese culture person is tweeting it as if it's something nerdy Right as opposed to say something sports, or you know mainstream related or Duke Nukem forever.
Scott: exactly right, so I'm like huh?
Scott: All right, let me click and see what this is and what I saw was one of those.
Scott: You know those girl groups because you know in the u.s.. They tend to have like one girl like Britney Spears.
Scott: But in Japan Korea, you know they have these groups like AKB 48 Right it's like a team of girls that they train them all to be little robot Idols and they make a big team and they do pop shit and whatever right.
Scott: so this one the name of this group I think is like SDSN is like the.
Scott: is the the short way the abbreviation for it?
Scott: right?
Scott: because in Korean it's like four words that begin the first.
Scott: you know SDS whatever and it's also known as girl generation, so they did this song called G and It's you know it's a trashy lame pop song like oh fashion and boyfriend But it's one of those things that gets stuck in your goddamn head Right?
Rym: see luckily the only thing that's been stuck in my head That's kind of insipid lately is remember that mashup that I forget.
Rym: who did it of every like the top 25 pop songs from 2009.
Scott: well they do that like every few months don't they?
Scott: or at least every year that mashup itself has been stuck in my head But not any of the individual songs, uh-huh anyway, so I'm like oh, that was pretty catchy, and it got stuck right, but then I investigated further.
Scott: so get this deal ready.
Scott: Why did this thing trend because apparently?
Scott: G was an actually a year or two old right and this group has been around since like oh seven no eight ish Apparently remember Boa.
Rym: Oh, yeah, we saw her in concert.
Rym: Yeah, she was a New York Tokyo anime or music festival in what?
Rym: 2001.
Scott: It's not really a long time ago, and So she was a Korean pop singer, and she knew you know Korean Japanese and English.
Scott: She was multilingual right.
Scott: so apparently girls generation or SDSN is a team of Boas.
Scott: they all Know they all can sing dance and know three languages.
Rym: Oh, that's that's dangerous.
Scott: They basically train them, and they're so popular that according to Wikipedia They put up posters of them around.
Scott: you know like Seoul and South Korea Got stolen.
Scott: the posters were them in Like jeans t-shirts and roller skates.
Scott: right the posters were stolen and their phones are ringing off the hook Asking you people if to buy the posters.
Scott: So this is like insane apparently.
Scott: But what happened was is the G song was a huge hit in Korea And the reason it was trending globally on Twitter is because they redid the song in Japanese And it was just released.
Scott: and there's a music video and everything and it's kind of out of control.
Rym: yeah G Okay, it amazes me how disconnected got I am from both Global like pop culture on the internet like trending Twitter and from local pop culture.
Scott: the thing that really bothers me Right is like you know I don't I don't think of myself as like a weeaboo right But the thing is you look at the world and you look at the internets And I'm I want to at least sort of get an idea of like what cultures are around the entire world.
Rym: Scott Who's Snooki?
Scott: I don't know anyway.
Rym: Can you name any movie that Leonardo DiCaprio was in?
Scott: Like Inception, okay, I saw that DiCaprio is a famous guy.
Scott: ah actor is using a movie is an actor You know.
Scott: But I kind of want to know if there's something that's ridiculously popular You know in some place in the world it might.
Scott: there could be things that are like in Eastern Europe that like a like a billion People are interested in.
Scott: that I wouldn't even know it existed.
Rym: And you see I just take Eurovision, and I assume that is what everyone in Europe likes, but those are for.
Scott: those are Specifically things that are not professionals, which is exactly what I want.
Scott: Yeah, but the point is is like if something happens in Europe like this We might know about it if something happens in Japan.
Scott: We're dead.
Scott: or you know Korea even or China.
Scott: We might know about it, but like the rest of the world is sort of like this mystery land like you know India.
Scott: We can get some Bollywood stuff and once in a while We can get a dollar mendi, but it's kind of hard.
Scott: You know this.
Scott: their stuff doesn't really go around the internet as much one.
Rym: Japan very pointedly and much purpose.
Rym: Korea is like this too.
Rym: They try to export culture very much like by design.
Rym: Yeah, here is culture.
Rym: We were sending it out.
Rym: Yep, and other countries.
Rym: Don't try.
Rym: or if they do try.
Rym: They don't do it very effectively I think.
Rym: so couple this with the fact that we live in America where the internet is pretty much Like.
Rym: this is where the internet lives.
Rym: Yeah And I mean look at the Japanese internet.
Rym: even other than the phone SMS stuff people are using.
Rym: Their internet looks like geocities from the 90s.
Rym: I just don't know how to use the internet.
Rym: I'm
Scott: just saying I wish that all the countries of the world would export their culture on the internet actively like Japan and such do to create these sort of you know to contribute to the world culture because otherwise Their cultures are getting washed away as the internet culture dominates And they're not gonna have their.
Scott: you know the internet culture will not be as influenced by them.
Scott: I think it is by others who are actively export.
Rym: It's a lack of culture Exportation.
Rym: like they don't have the like the infrastructure built to do that sort of thing.
Rym: they don't design Songs from the ground up to be all right.
Rym: this song is going to be popular among this demographic.
Rym: We're going to get it out there with this means and we're gonna make people go crazy about it like they've got it down To a science in America and Southeast Asia, and the rest of the world.
Rym: I don't think they work to that cynical level of like kind of Manufacturing of media and manufacturing of culture.
Scott: that's true, but you know that the sad thing is like if you're Italian right?
Scott: I'm sure there's plenty of awesome music scenes in Italy that aren't big anywhere else, and you would like if you're creating this world culture That's a mishmash of everything on the internet.
Scott: You know that's gonna be the internet culture.
Scott: You would think that Italians should have their proportionate contribution to this world culture that will Regardless of whether they like it or not dominate all culture.
Scott: the other thing There's a. but if they don't if they don't actively put their you know their ingredients in the pot Then they'll be washed.
Rym: There are a lot of very strong ties between Southeast Asia and the Western world especially the United States And we don't have these ties in other places.
Rym: I mean Japan Europe.
Rym: Yeah, all right, so we've got Britain, but what do we get from Britain other than the Beatles?
Rym: Spice Girls and maybe Monty Python?
Rym: What do people know?
Rym: name any Singer from the history of the world from France Belgium or Germany.
Scott: Alizé all right name a second one Belgium or Germany or hell.
Rym: all of Europe.
Scott: Oh all of Europe.
Rym: go for it.
Rym: all of Europe.
Scott: any singer any singer that girl that was at RIT from Croatia Fana Fana.
Rym: all right, so we got to obscure Britney Spears from Croatia.
Scott: I Got a non obscure Britney Spears from France, but look at internet culture.
Rym: look at nerd culture.
Rym: Here's where I'm trying to make this correlation.
Rym: nerds have a big crossover with internet.
Scott: all of Europe, dude There's so many fucking metal bands mocking eyes.
Scott: the premises from Europe alright alright.
Rym: You got some hands.
Scott: Yeah But you want to know an actual just just a singer.
Rym: a band doesn't count or name anyone from marking a supremacy.
Scott: Oh one guy's name is Johan.
Rym: That was a pretty good bet.
Scott: no I know it is because I wasn't looking at their website today.
Rym: That's the old trick of go to a wedding.
Rym: You'd be like hey John.
Scott: Hey Just wave around the whole room.
Scott: someone in that area has got to be named John.
Rym: But look there's a big overlap by and large among geeks and nerds We're into tech stuff and our internet savvy and who are also into anime manga or comics to some degree.
Rym: And there's also an overlap there with you know weird East Asian cinema and kung fu movies and stuff too Mmm, and gojira because those things all overlap with the internet.
Rym: I think that culture from those places places is as a result overrepresented in our internet culture.
Rym: as a result I don't think those things are even on the radar of non internet people in the u.s.. Of course not so non-internet people in the u.s.
Rym: Are completely distinct from internet people culturally and we as internet people are in this weird culture.
Rym: That is also only the internet and internet savvy Manipulation machines from the rest of the world.
Scott: you know what I gotta say to that.
Rym: yeah Okay, I didn't listen to the song enough to get it stuck in my head.
Rym: Now God no fuck you.
Rym: I still have the goddamn Tetris song stuck in my head.
Rym: Who ranges the?
Scott: So this weekend the 8th 9th and 10th of October Is the New York Comic Con and New York anime festival?
Scott: We are going to be there.
Scott: I'm gonna be there on Friday.
Rym: I will be there Friday from like 430 until some point.
Scott: I'll see if I can be there all day Friday even including the early You know pre-show hours, but if not I guess I get in at 1 o'clock with the normal people right.
Rym: yeah I'm not.
Scott: I'm not leaving work to go to the pre-show not this time Yeah, but anyway, I think 1 o'clock to our panels at what?
Scott: well I guess this is a okay.
Scott: before our panel.
Scott: our panel is at 730.
Rym: our panel is called anime.
Rym: You'd never thought you'd like.
Rym: it's Friday.
Rym: 715 to 815 in room 1e 14.
Scott: it's right before our panel in the exact same room.
Scott: I will also be there watching a panel with the creators of.
Scott: Hatsune.
Scott: Miku will be there.
Scott: It'll be awesome, and then before that from 1 o'clock until that panel I'll just be walking around the show floor trying to see all of it.
Rym: and Because I'm not gonna be there Saturday and Sunday This is the big double mega con that we've been waiting for forever.
Scott: I might be there Sunday.
Rym: Maybe we'll see what happens.
Scott: It's gonna be crazy.
Scott: go nuts you ready.
Scott: I heard some things.
Scott: you ready for some things.
Rym: I heard some things too.
Rym: M Night Shyamalan is gonna be there.
Scott: It's not the guy everyone hates.
Scott: they hate him now like I know something.
Rym: Why why do they hate him Scott?
Scott: because he makes bad movies.
Rym: No he made one bad movie.
Rym: well Well he was.
Rym: he was hated by some some people for later movies He made, but then he made a really really bad movie and people suddenly were like oh wow what the fuck.
Rym: He also made.
Rym: really good.
Rym: He made signs.
Scott: Remember that like them.
Scott: I was the one to where the water killed the alien.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't like that movie didn't like that movie.
Scott: well mostly cuz it was you know sort of the bullshit part of it.
Rym: Well that it's all downhill from there, okay?
Rym: He made that elevator movie the one who saw the trailer for yeah with a devil.
Scott: Everyone booed at because it was him.
Rym: yeah well everyone's watching the trailer like what the fuck is this movie?
Rym: And then it was like M Night Shyamalan, and then suddenly everyone's like oh, okay.
Rym: I get it anyway.
Scott: What's the M stand for?
Rym: Magic night.
Scott: So there's gonna be a zillion famous people there.
Scott: I'm not even gonna bother to list them because you just go to the website and look but it is up.
Rym: if you're in I Have GeekNights will be there.
Rym: Oh Carl Custer uncle yo will be there.
Rym: yep, yeah Daryl Surratt might be around.
Scott: oh my god watch out.
Scott: It's dangerous.
Scott: Yeah, there's gonna be the artists alley.
Scott: supposedly you're ready for this.
Scott: How many tables?
Rym: 450 tables I hear so significantly smaller than Otakon's artist.
Scott: I don't know how many tables the Otakon's artists alley have.
Scott: I think it's pretty close.
Scott: ah yeah 450 I mean that's.
Rym: but to be fair the tables Traditionally at comic cons are smaller than the ones at say an artist alley.
Scott: But it's not the size of the tables right it's the quality of the person sitting behind the table.
Scott: They could put everyone with a chair and a tiny little podium, and if there's 450 of them You know ranging from guys selling anime bookmarks to you know top-line comic creator Yes,
Rym: well at the same time It's tricky because comic-con artist alley tables are usually crazy expensive and they give them to famous people and it's there's a very different skew from say the Anime-con where
Scott: it's gonna be really interesting with this big mix of people at the tables you know from webcomic artists to Marvel guys to Anime people's you know.
Scott: there's also get.
Scott: every booth is sold out so every regular booth.
Scott: So it's gonna be crazy full.
Scott: I even hear that this is gonna be like Intel supposedly has the biggest booth.
Scott: That's gonna be kind of weird.
Rym: well think about this.
Rym: This is the comic-con.
Rym: the comic cons are becoming the Hollywood cons where the industry just jumps all over it.
Scott: Yeah, but Intel.
Scott: I mean that's a that's a pecs kind of booth.
Scott: You know with technologies and gaming and stuff and apparently Intel booth is gonna have loads of just open gaming video gaming at it.
Rym: yeah, they was weird because they were the con because it's a comic-con - was really gonna push gaming.
Rym: and Then they kind of backed off of that at least when I was talking to him originally because there's a lot less gaming than was Originally at least in my perception going to be there.
Rym: Wizards the coast is doing a bunch of crap.
Rym: They're same old.
Rym: you want to play D&D.
Rym: come play D&D thing.
Scott: come play magic.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Here's magic Running there that gamma world D&D which I can't.
Rym: it amazes me that we explain that to me.
Rym: really You'd never.
Rym: you don't know anything about gamma.
Scott: Why don't I think my gamma world so gamma is it a world of?
Scott: The Incredible Hulk is you know what I have cuz gamma rays and credit.
Rym: I have an issue of dragon magazine.
Rym: I'm a bomb that I'll have to dig out of my pile of old dragon magazines where an editorial was about gamma world.
Rym: It was the guy who had never role-played before and he went to a con and played gamma world.
Rym: Okay, and it's a world where character creation is kind of random and you play a mutant like I'm an ant-man with six arms And six lightsabers.
Scott: that could be fun.
Rym: Yeah, and I conceptually I feel like all the magic of a game Like that is going to be raped out of its corpse by using Wizards the coast D&D.
Scott: I'm a guy with six arms.
Scott: All right, this could be fun.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Now walk around the dungeon and kill them on other monsters with six arms highest average damage per minute.
Rym: Don't forget to use your healing surge.
Scott: Yeah The thing is like I think a burning gamma could be pretty good.
Rym: Oh my god burning gamma would.
Scott: Anyway, it's not Tuesday No, what other awesome?
Rym: Originally planning to really cut down on the anime stuff do a whole bunch of gaming stuff at this con.
Rym: And then in the very end they were like, yeah, just do the anime stuff.
Scott: Never mind Yeah, and then they're like, okay do even less of the anime stuff that you were asking to do.
Scott: Anyway There's also gonna be a whole bunch of concerts all over the place.
Scott: a lot of them won't be at the con itself.
Scott: They'll be nearby for example vamps at the Roseland Ballroom.
Scott: Yeah extra pans gonna be somewhere puffy.
Scott: It's.
Scott: uh, it's crazy off the hook with all sorts of concerts.
Rym: There's that shami-san band with the two guys.
Scott: Oh nice.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, I forget their names.
Rym: Oh, I gotta look it up.
Scott: It's not the Yoshida brothers.
Rym: No, it's not Other guys, I remember Otakon was working on stuff with them.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, yeah, there's gonna be all sorts of musical events.
Scott: There's gonna be oh you ready for this.
Scott: There's gonna be an event called rock comic-con.
Scott: I actually have the information for it right here.
Scott: Where'd it go?
Scott: I just had this fucking email.
Scott: All right Here it is.
Scott: so rock comic-con you ready for this ahem will feature the following bands Kirby crackle H2 awesome fortress of attitude Bedlam rock the girl who did the fuck me Ray Bradbury song and also Adam warrock.
Scott: You heard that song from Adam.
Scott: I know about Adam war right hosted by some guy from TV.
Scott: It's gonna be on October 9th at something something.
Scott: It's like this crazy awesome concert and it's in the city somewhere and I will maybe post a link to it So you can find out about it, but that is like the craziest awesome.
Scott: That's like if I had a Packs right and the packs had.
Scott: it was a packs of comics instead of a packs of gaming and I had a concert.
Scott: That's who would be doing the Saturday night concert, right?
Scott: So you can think of it sort of as the real Saturday night concert of newer comic-con Even though it's separate from the con in a you know a city location.
Scott: But yeah, that's that's gonna be wicked crazy.
Scott: Awesome right there.
Rym: the biggest part about this con I mean the pet a lot of the panels.
Rym: There's so many panels and a lot of them are done by professionals which is good or bad.
Rym: I mean look at pass packs is mostly industry professionals doing panels and they're very hit or miss as a result But they're at least hit or miss in a professional manner.
Scott: Yeah, I actually heard that while I'm pretty sure the show floor and all that stuff is mixed You know.
Scott: But the anime and the gaming is all mixed.
Scott: right.
Scott: is the way they've done it?
Scott: is they sort of Categorized the show floor, right?
Scott: so even though it's one big show floor like one area will just be dealers and in fact like Guys selling old comic books will stand next to this, you know be next to the other guys, you know Selling old comic books, you know.
Scott: and the people selling like kid robot style toys and all that sort of stuff They have like a cult area that's got all that stuff.
Rym: So it's like the back by the right that area I'm really looking forward to check out.
Scott: So they've got like all the.
Scott: you know There's one big show floor, but they've segregated the show floor to put all these similar booths next to similar booths Right.
Scott: in addition to that The Panel areas are.
Scott: all the comic-con panels are in one space and all the anime festival panels are in a different there.
Scott: They're in separate locations.
Scott: They're like two different panel hallways.
Scott: So that way, you know all the anime kids can hang out near the anime panel.
Rym: No, that's not gonna happen.
Rym: This is this is my interest in this con.
Scott: Oh so interest.
Rym: I mean I've Speculated to a degree that is unhealthy as to like what the panels would be like like the layout how it's actually gonna flow.
Rym: but the only thing that I really find interesting and I have no idea how this is gonna play out is to see all these Comic nerds all these Hollywood nerds and all these anime nerds in the same place at the same time because there are the people we Know that we see them at every read event in the Javits that go to the comic-con and the anime festival.
Rym: I don't think they're the majority and I can't wait to see what happens.
Rym: I just want to see like how these groups react to each other.
Scott: I think that's gonna be see.
Scott: the thing is there are cons out there that are such as Fan Expo in Canada or mega con in Florida, which are literally they don't even try to hide it everything cons.
Rym: they have gaming and anime and right and they But everything cons tend to draw the same kinds of people who will go to both New York comic-con and New York anime festival.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I think that when you have it everything con if there's enough comic dealers comic nerd guy shows up in enough numbers.
Scott: But the thing is this is a little different because you have an existing Big blob of comic people and an existing big blob of anime people and you're gonna smash them together at once.
Scott: now They did say I heard that there was like a seventy five percent crossover people who go to both something like that Which I think is a little bit high, you know I don't know if that maybe that number is wrong But I heard that there was actually a very large crossover.
Scott: because they look at the names of people who bought one badge the names of people about the other in previous years and they Say aha, but I also heard that they're like a hundred and something percent Ahead of like estimated sales of pre-order badges.
Scott: So it is gonna be crazy crowded like oh my god This might be even though you know, they are going to report a false Attendance figure as they often do.
Rym: this is probably going to be if not this year then definitely next year The biggest nerd thing there is in America really rapidly Yeah, it's gonna be the second biggest con probably after the city.
Scott: Of course.
Rym: This is the East Coast effect.
Rym: I mean, you know people on the West Coast they have the Anime Expo and whatever but on the East Coast We got Otakon which is already too big to fit into the biggest convention center we got and like PAX East is already surpassing PAX Prime just because there's so many more people in the area.
Rym: and part of the reason cons don't happen that often in New York City is Because even if you put on a little con like I'm doing my little anime con you'll sell out immediately and then you'll have tens Of thousands of people at the door the day of the con trying to get in.
Scott: Yeah, it's it's gonna be crazy good not so, you know I don't know how much more there is to say about this this con.
Rym: I mean really just have to wait until after it happens and then tell you that's why I didn't want to dedicate a whole episode.
Scott: I just wanted to get dedicated news portion to to this.
Scott: But yeah, New York and there's gonna be so and that you know There's still little news because everyone is holding their news and they're gonna announce all their news at the con.
Scott: So I'm sure the next Wednesday episode we do There's gonna be a whole pile of news and all.
Scott: we're gonna just probably spend the whole episode talking about You know the one or two days you spent at this con.
Scott: So there you go.
Rym: So things of the day.
Rym: What do you got for me?
Scott: All right, so this is video Called mouseland right and apparently the deal about Mickey Mouse.
Scott: No Set what it is about your mouse.
Scott: There was this guy and he was the socialist ID mouse.
Scott: All right, that's enough.
Scott: There's this guy named Tommy Douglas, and he was a famous Canadian politician.
Scott: He was the socialist premier of Saskatchewan Right and he is the creator of the Canadian health care system And he's also happens to be the grandfather of some actor named Kiefer Sutherland.
Rym: Kiefer Sutherland He played the guy in Armitage the third or Armitage 3 polymatrix really?
Rym: Yeah Okay So the Armitage the third that was a matrix guy to to make it clear that Includes the second worst voice acted line in the history of anime.
Rym: I mean, it's really bad where Armitage gets shot and goes flying off of something.
Rym: and keep yourself there.
Scott: Lynn says no So his grandpa was this famous socialist guy and he gave a speech in the Parliament of Canada.
Scott: So it's e I Kiefer.
Scott: it's then it should be kee not.
Scott: If you see that and you don't know how it's supposed to be you would.
Scott: you would say Kiefer like right.
Scott: Anyway, I mean you the other way to pronounce it be like heifer But then it would be keffer and that doesn't sound like someone's name.
Scott: Hey keffer Kiefer.
Scott: It sounds like someone's name.
Rym: I guess it's another one of those pop culture.
Rym: Thanks.
Scott: So The here's a video of someone animating.
Scott: this guy gave a speech in the Parliament about mouseland Right, and it was awesome, even though it's socialist, but whatever.
Scott: It's awesome.
Scott: And so the guy animated it and Kiefer Introduces the video at the beginning, you know because it's about his grandpa.
Scott: So it's just really awesome video.
Scott: and even though you know it is socialist at least the fundamental point that it is making it is humorous and You know quality and it lacks any specific policies, you know.
Scott: So you it's.
Scott: it's hard for a a mouse to disagree with it.
Scott: cats might get really mad watching it though.
Rym: So not to fall back on an old standby of college humor, but there's.
Scott: it's been a few times there without you know.
Rym: There's nothing more amusing to me in all the world then watching squirrels try to figure stuff out.
Scott: How about other animals trying to figure stuff squirrels trying to figure stuff out?
Rym: I like more cuz what squirrels are very long-lived.
Rym: an old squirrel has accumulated and not a lot of squirrely knowledge over the years Not as much as an owl.
Rym: Ah Depends, I don't see turtle.
Rym: I always don't have as many problems to solve as squirrels do.
Scott: that's cuz.
Scott: they're just so good.
Scott: They know right they know from the beginning how to not get into problem, but we live in a world.
Rym: and exactly it's boring.
Rym: You want someone who is just.
Scott: it's boring when someone's so badass They never fuck up exactly.
Rym: squirrels are great because they are just smart enough to realize there is a problem But just dumb enough to not realize.
Scott: Didn't get my joke.
Rym: I sidestep.
Rym: you're real really right away I was talking about elves and then I said, oh really I was gonna hit you later with a yeah, really Okay.
Rym: Anyway, or yarly as it were.
Scott: so you got a funny squirrel video.
Rym: So this is a funny squirrel video, but it's a perfect storm of squirrel video because you see Squirrels will try to figure shit out.
Rym: if there's food at the end of whatever there is to figure out Almost any animal will do that.
Rym: now a lot of animals either will never figure it out or won't realize there's something to figure out.
Rym: a lot of dogs if you Give them a certain kind of puzzle will not actively try to figure out.
Rym: they will literally run in every possible direction Until they just brute force their way through.
Rym: they don't think they don't stop squirrels.
Rym: Stop and go.
Rym: All right, I Think I can handle this.
Rym: they pause and look at something for a while and then they suddenly go for it and fail.
Scott: It should be.
Scott: you should use an octopus or a crow instead.
Rym: much smarter independent of squirrels and their nature.
Rym: nerds with cameras will set up squirrel traps just to see what happens and this genius took a Slinky and just hung it over the pole of his bird feeder and his squirrel can now figure this the fuck out.
Scott: Alrighty So metamoment the meta.
Scott: We already talked about that big convention.
Scott: So we're gonna not talk about that.
Rym: We are gonna talk about the other big convention.
Scott: Yes, you see you can't really go to it.
Scott: I'm pretty sure it's full.
Scott: there might be one spot open because I think he said he opened two spots this morning Three and then two went right away.
Rym: and I don't even know.
Scott: I don't know anymore But we are.
Scott: the reason I'm not gonna be at the Comic Con and such much on Saturday And maybe I'll be there Sunday But probably not is because we're going to 10 10 10 the burning wheel convention, which also occurs on 10 9 10.
Scott: Yeah, well 10 is same exact.
Scott: is this weekend the same weekend as the double mega con, right?
Scott: So Because the burning wheel was originally released on 5 5 0 5. he's having a convention on 10 10 10.
Scott: So the next one is gonna be what 15 15 which is also which is also binary day.
Scott: Yeah, maybe 20 20 20.
Rym: I think you should be 15 15 15 which would be?
Rym: I guess we have to use modulus on the months.
Rym: It would be like March.
Scott: No, what you would do is 15.
Rym: it would be March 15 2015.
Rym: No, it'd be March 2016.
Rym: Why?
Rym: Because if it's the 15th month of the year No, I say just mod you just do modulus on each individual component to make it be a real date Uh-huh.
Rym: Anyway, that's how I continue to celebrate International Day of Slayer Because until 2066 we will not get another true and proper International Day of Slayer.
Scott: It's on the calendar.
Scott: Let me go if I could find out what it is if you need to.
Rym: yeah, but we had one that was the most I mean, I guess 1966, but we didn't have Slayer yet.
Scott: If we get if we become immortal will eventually be alive on 66 66 66.
Rym: Ah, and if only Slayer would still be alive.
Scott: Well, if we become immortal, maybe they will too, you know somewhere out there in the cosmos, of course, we'll use different methods We'll use science and they'll use the powers of Satan.
Rym: All right, I'm not even gonna make my homeopathic Slayer joke.
Rym: So yes, the burning con is this weekend.
Rym: if you're not already going and do not already have a registration You probably cannot go and that sucks.
Scott: the first also this Friday is Nerd NYC board game night.
Rym: Oh, yeah, we won't be there.
Scott: It won't be there.
Rym: It's the first one I've missed in a long time.
Scott: There's also about a bajillion other nerdy things in New York City.
Scott: You can look them up on the Internet's.
Scott: There will be no shortage of them.
Scott: I think there's a website called nerd York City that has like a Google calendar with every nerdy event of it in New York City As opposed to nerd NYC, which is just the board game.
Scott: So you like check their Google Calendar.
Scott: you can see nerdy events in the whole country.
Scott: Well, there's also some gaming thing going on upstate at some college this weekend.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, the thing is you put your little gaming thing at the same time as two other gaming related events.
Scott: Not smart dudes Yeah.
Scott: So the only other metamoment thing to discuss right now is the book club, which is World War Z I don't want to read this by Max Brooks and Z stands for.
Rym: zmabi Ordered it but I didn't hit submit yet.
Rym: because if I hit submit Then it's also gonna pre-order the next Prince of Nothing book and I won't get that zombie book until like March of next year.
Scott: Split that shit up.
Rym: But if I split it up, it splits the whole thing up and that's bullshit.
Scott: It is.
Rym: but I want an option that is Ship my pre-orders when they become available but bunch everything else up.
Scott: if you can you just order one and then you make another order.
Rym: I know but that's annoying.
Scott: Just lightly All right, so we watched a whole bunch of anime.
Scott: yeah, it's a new anime season.
Scott: I didn't watch.
Scott: I only watched three shows because they didn't have that much time because we only decided to do this a couple days ago.
Scott: I only watched four.
Scott: you watch.
Scott: Oh you watch more shows than me, but you didn't watch.
Scott: we only how many show?
Scott: What shows did you watch?
Scott: just how many titles I started watching?
Rym: Well here watch because I skipped through shin ray tent a Yakima that Detective with the glowing eye.
Scott: Okay, just do the titles.
Rym: and I watched bakuman All right, and I watched mm.
Scott: mm exclamation point.
Rym: Yeah, all right, and I watched arakara under the bridgie bridgie bridge ex bridge bridge bridge.
Scott: It's like hunter ex hunter in the show.
Rym: They say bridgey bridgey.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Well, then it's bridgey bridgey.
Rym: Actually.
Rym: I also watched.
Rym: I'm I can't believe I watched this Yosuga.
Rym: no, sorry.
Scott: Did you watch the whole episode?
Rym: I Started to watch it and then I decided that this was going in a bad direction.
Rym: So I skipped through it to see if it did go in that direction And it not only went up to the line that I was worried about but it went way past it.
Rym: But we'll get to that.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: All right, so I watched a bakuman also.
Scott: Yeah, I watched that penny stocking and garter belt.
Rym: See, that's the only one.
Rym: I didn't watch that.
Rym: I wanted to watch.
Scott: is that what we're talking about by guy next?
Scott: I was really really good.
Scott: I watched star driver.
Scott: I Start driver first here.
Scott: All right, so star driver This is the show that anime news network will not review yet because it is going to be like Premiering at the anime festival this weekend, right?
Scott: Oh, wow.
Scott: So but I just watched it on the Internet.
Rym: It is funny how they won't review things because obviously then they would have gotten them illegally.
Rym: Yeah, yet IMDb has reviews of stuff like months before it comes out and no one cares.
Scott: Yeah It's just.
Scott: it's basically an industry thing.
Scott: Right the company that licensed it asked you not to and so that they will still cooperate with you in the future.
Rym: you obey Yep, an anime news network can't?
Rym: they're like the AP wire of anime.
Rym: They can't.
Scott: So anyway, I watched this show and the first half of the show, right?
Scott: First of all, it didn't really have any characters that I gave a shit about right?
Scott: You didn't have any personalities.
Scott: I didn't care about.
Rym: you know, that's been a problem with a lot of anime I watched lately other than a few really big shows.
Rym: I liked like der I don't know a lot of anime I start watching like even bakuman was like, alright I don't really care about these characters so but However, the show did have that sort of anime.
Scott: cliche of is a bunch of mysterious stuff going on.
Scott: Whoo, don't you wonder what it is?
Scott: right, so the beginning of the show is basically these people are this girl and this guy are hanging on a beach and This dude gets washed up on the beach and they save his life and they don't call 911 or anything.
Scott: We bring them to their house where he wakes up and then they're just chatting like normal and like hey, she saved your life.
Scott: Oh, does that count as a kiss?
Scott: Whatever?
Scott: and then they go to school and the school is a little bit weird and then they sort of reveal to you that yes They're on an island and there's weird stuff on the island.
Scott: the guy who washed up on the island is looking for his dad and one of his dad's paintings is hanging in the school and The girl is some sort of magical maiden and his four maidens of the island.
Scott: And she asked like she's doing some ritual on the island with a magical seal on her chest.
Scott: is some rune or some shit?
Rym: Wait, wait, is this the show with the?
Rym: because I found a Wikipedia article about star driver kagiyaki no takuto.
Scott: This is just our bones.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: it's hated by bones.
Scott: I didn't look.
Scott: it's just star driver.
Scott: Anyway, so it's just they set up.
Rym: Yeah, this is the same show.
Rym: So there's that includes the galactic pretty boy the ginga.
Rym: That's the show.
Scott: That's the show.
Rym: Yeah, so it gives you reeks of DNA angel.
Rym: So first no DNA squared not DNA.
Scott: So first is mysterious.
Scott: You don't know what's going on.
Scott: Then they set up all these supernatural mysteries, right and then basically They got the the the guy who washed up on the beach.
Scott: He's in the dorms and he goes to this meet that the dorm meeting where the.
Scott: you know The the RA is basically explaining the rules of the dorms Like don't go on the girls floor and that kind of shit.
Rym: and how to join the fight club.
Scott: Yeah And then one while the guy actually the guy in the boxing club is trying to convince them to join the boxing club.
Scott: Yeah, and then right they freaking it's like alright and don't go to the abandoned gold mine.
Scott: It's dangerous.
Scott: Next scene he's going to be banning gold mine.
Scott: He goes in the gold mine.
Scott: There's giant robots and ridiculous shit down there and you know what?
Scott: Every character pretty much knows everything.
Scott: the maiden girl knows everything that's going on.
Scott: You know the red-haired guy the guy who washed up on the beach.
Scott: He knows how to pilot a robot.
Scott: He's all up in his business, right and they basically eliminate all these mysteries, right?
Scott: It's like all these people know the business and they're fighting right off.
Scott: right and there's a robot fight Down in the gold mine, this is all in episode one episode one, right?
Scott: I could take this What do you mean?
Scott: They just leave all these men.
Scott: the end that red-haired guy is the galactic pretty boy and he's told and is he?
Scott: that is the Kind of persona you don't have for the main guy.
Scott: It's a persona for a side guy, you know.
Rym: now at the same time and this is part of the only mystery I don't like Bakuman that much but we'll get to that because I hate it lately when you have the main character Who's really generic or doesn't have like a really strong thing about them?
Rym: Because then I just don't care about them at all.
Rym: star driver Was like the extreme.
Scott: the only thing star driver had going for it was the fact that it had the cliche of mysteries stuff and then they sort of threw all the mysteries away.
Scott: except for where's this guy's dad?
Scott: and Basically all the characters?
Scott: none of that.
Scott: usually you need that one character who is also doesn't know anything that's going on that you can identify with and you discover what's Going on along with that character.
Scott: But this show all the characters know everything and only one guy was acting like.
Scott: he didn't know but he knows and you're now you're The viewer and you're the only one who doesn't really know everything But all the characters know everything or at least they know a whole lot more than you do and you're just like what the fuck?
Rym: Did you at least care about the answers to all these mysteries only because they were mysteries and I'm just naturally curious?
Scott: They didn't give me any reason to care.
Rym: So it's a situation where you watch a couple episodes give up
Scott: Some guys who are up to evil magic and they're doing something that hurts the maidens or whatever and the other guy they're trying to Unlock some evil power on the island or some typical anime bullshit and the other the other people I guess are trying to prevent them From doing evil with the magical powers of the island and his dad is somewhere secret and involved and that's it.
Scott: Wow, and his robots in there somewhere.
Rym: so Yosuga no, sorry.
Rym: Ah, okay it opened to the.
Rym: you know There have been shows like kuji BK unbalanced where they're a joke show.
Scott: you get like the joke Unbalanced is part of another show, right?
Rym: I know but exactly you get off but when you're watching that it reeks of being a joke show like it's so cliche Or there's something so just messed up about it that you know, like alright, this is the joke show part of the real show.
Rym: The beginning of the show looked like that.
Rym: It was like a girl in this really elaborate dress with silver hair and this kid who with also with silver hair and they're sitting On like a bus or a train going somewhere
Scott: Okay,
Rym: and it seemed like such a cliche that it almost couldn't have been a real show.
Rym: But then that really was the show and it had creepy incest vibes.
Rym: Okay, really creepy incest vibes.
Scott: Well, what did you find out?
Scott: where these two silver-haired people siblings?
Scott: Yep, real nugger.
Scott: now It's not the typical anime trick of their their steps up there.
Rym: They're twins twins.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Wow So I'm thinking alright, this is edging into creepy line.
Scott: Was it like kiss excess where they're like, you know groping his boner or whatever?
Rym: No, because that was almost stupid and humorous enough to not be immediately repulsive.
Scott: Well, I think the reason it was repulsive was because they actually made it sort of graphic, right?
Rym: It was at the same time.
Scott: They were to let more the animation.
Rym: they could have made it more humorous, but at the same time it didn't give off this like in Incredibly creepy vibe that this show gave off it.
Scott: basically, you know Yeah, kiss exists is basically love Hina but even more perverted kind of vibe.
Scott: So
Rym: going through this They one by one introduce a just panoply of female characters with giant breasts and there's like every stereotype in the world
Scott: It's a quiet girl the strong girl They really excited energetic girl
Rym: the one girl with like the shrine outfit who also has a ho gay.
Rym: Yeah, and they say and they're all like fondling each other and it nothing's really perverted.
Rym: yet It's just except for big boobs and fondling each other not directly fondling fondling like oh, let me smell your perfume Blah-blah-blah, you know the same kind of anime bullshit that happens all the time, okay.
Rym: So I start skipping through to see all right, the show's giving me a creepy vibe.
Rym: let's see if it's just porn or what's going on.
Rym: and Yet it crossed the incest line less than halfway through the episode.
Scott: Like did.
Scott: was it just implying the incest or was there actual?
Rym: there's brother-sister kissing and then I skipped and the cliffhanger Like the way siblings kiss or no, they were kissing the way siblings kiss in utana, okay So it's okay for incest to be in utana.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: Yeah, because the moral of incest in utana was yeah not working out so well for you.
Rym: Is it?
Scott: So is this show like pro incest this show I Didn't.
Rym: I've run into all these shows doing zero research whatsoever.
Scott: Are you sure they're not cousins or they're not gonna reveal that they're not actually?
Scott: or did no one like breaks up there?
Rym: I'm pretty sure they are siblings having sex or are about to have sex.
Rym: I Yes, it was based on a porn game and but they actually left the porn in.
Rym: they left all the party.
Scott: It's not like that your heart.
Rym: anime was cute because it took all the porn out and was basically just kind of a dumb Comedy about dating.
Scott: Yeah, or what's that other with a fantasy one that was based on a porn game where they took the porn out?
Scott: Oh, well, there was the ass the guy wearing the mask.
Rym: Oh to water a room.
Rym: Oh, no.
Rym: Yeah that one Yeah, but that had the problem of the generic main male character.
Scott: Yeah What is up with this?
Scott: porn games?
Scott: having plots good enough that they can take out the porn and make a show Except this one.
Rym: the plot as far as I can tell is hey, dude You want to have sex with your sister, you know, there is totally okay.
Scott: There are a lot of animes out there based on the porn games, right?
Scott: So Let me ask something are there.
Scott: has there ever been an anime based on a porn game?
Scott: That was actually like not just good but really good like wow, that was a really really worthwhile.
Scott: Has that ever happened?
Rym: Has there ever been a porn game?
Rym: That was really really worthwhile.
Scott: I Was gonna say said five, oh no way I got one customers revenge.
Rym: Not beat him and eat him.
Scott: I Could come up with a few more if I have to anyway.
Scott: No, wait, that was a customer.
Scott: revenge doesn't count because there's never an anime.
Rym: What amazed me was how lush the animation was because I remember running into this problem.
Scott: You know hentai's always have the best animators.
Scott: Yes, that's what they make all the money.
Rym: What's the one that Daryl Surratt was talking about?
Scott: where that the crazy guy and Gerald I think was talking about it Where the one guy drew every frame completely over many years by hand.
Rym: Yeah ridiculous like that Yeah, but I remember before like when I was a freshman at RIT a friend of mine and I we uh, we found these Screenshots from an anime.
Rym: We didn't know what it was.
Rym: We're like.
Rym: it looked like this awesome fantasy thing.
Scott: it looked like it looked really really beautiful and I was trying to remember what the name of it.
Scott: words were.
Scott: Yeah words are hurt.
Rym: Yeah Then we're like, alright, let's see if we can find the anime and yeah, it was actually a porn game.
Scott: Oh, look at that.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Scott: Pretty horrifying for him, but there's such good pictures of it with that.
Rym: We're not in porn parts Yeah, but then there was like the skeleton dude.
Scott: Yeah skeletons.
Scott: Awesome.
Scott: Yeah, I have a lot of bones.
Rym: I think the skeleton dude was involved in the porn.
Scott: who's involved in the bones?
Rym: It bothers me that if I don't do research If I don't do research before watching like whatever's on TV in America I'm gonna get it worse.
Rym: some like crappy pop show.
Rym: if I don't do my research before I watch whatever anime is out Well granted it's gonna be at 3 a.m.
Scott: Right?
Scott: You're not watching TV at this hour Yeah, but only nerds TiVo and shit true, but at the same time it is Russian roulette kids at 3 a.m.
Scott: Sure, it's ramen.
Scott: It's rams Russian roulette in the u.s.
Rym: To Who even watches TV at 3 a.m They have like their people with no lives or insomnia.
Rym: now cuz they've got YouTube There there's.
Rym: there's so many porn and or kitten-in-a-cup videos on the internet that there's no reason to watch TV at 3 a.m.
Scott: Anyway, anyway, so I watched that panty stocking show, right?
Scott: And the first thing I noticed about the panty stocking show was that basically one of the characters is this pet dog, right?
Scott: It's a green thing.
Scott: and I was like they just stole that from invader-zim.
Scott: Alright, it's it's straight up.
Scott: I mean look at that.
Scott: They just straight-up stole Scott.
Rym: Did you ever watch invader-zim?
Scott: I watched a couple episodes.
Rym: What's the green dogs name girl?
Rym: Okay.
Scott: It's got the zipper on the front.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, cuz he's actually a robot, right?
Scott: So anyway, so I'm like, wow, they just ripped that off.
Scott: and you know stylistically the whole show was actually a little bit Invader-zim ish and I was like what the fuck.
Scott: so I went to anime news network and I saw this Posting where they actually asked jonan vasquez about panty and stocking and he and I will quote I will read the quote from the anime news network article exactly and fully Dot dot dot took ger out of the whorehouse.
Scott: He was working in and gave him a new job.
Scott: It's nice seeing him get some work But I got to say it's a bit on the simple side for my taste What with the fart and shit jokes?
Scott: But the ending is pretty ridiculous and guy next produces some of the only Japanese animation I can stand without wishing I was the drinking type.
Scott: So I'm looking forward to more.
Scott: He also says Seems a little underused in the new show, but What's he?
Scott: he surmises that it's all the creators can expect from what's left of his mind after all the heroin.
Scott: So he's facing easy makes a joke about how ger is all washed up and he's glad he's got a job.
Scott: But you know, he's took.
Scott: he was on heroin.
Scott: so much that is he's not so good.
Rym: So Scott all I had to go on with panty stocking with garter belt.
Rym: is this one like poster from a Japanese Okay.
Scott: So here's what the show's about.
Scott: You're ready.
Scott: There's these two girls panty and stocking.
Scott: right.
Scott: panty Loves to fuck and stocking loves to eat things that are sugary.
Rym: This is kind of like dirty pair.
Scott: panty is all like hot and you know blonde and like Oh baby and stocking is all gothy and like oh, you know.
Scott: and Garter belt is this priest and he's a big black.
Scott: He's like shaft, right?
Scott: He's got a big fro and he's he's in charge.
Scott: Alright so fun to have the pet.
Scott: the ger is playing the part of Chuck the dog and Basically, what happens is they need to collect like these heavenly coins to do something.
Scott: I think they're angels or some shit made magic powers.
Scott: I don't fucking know.
Scott: And the way they collect these heavenly coins is by defeating ghosts and the ghosts are sort of a gatekeepers kind of thing Right.
Scott: So in the first episode the ghost that they have to fight is the poop monster and basically they learn that toilets are eating People all around the city and then eventually they go to investigate and panty gets eaten by the toilet.
Scott: And then the poop monster comes out and they fight the poop monster.
Scott: Wow And the way they fight the poop monster is panty takes off her panties and her panties turn into a gun.
Scott: And I've just a name for the gun, but I forget the name of it.
Rym: Oh, wow looking at that picture That was my sole understanding of this anime.
Rym: Yeah panty gun, right?
Scott: so then stocking takes off her stocking and becomes a katana.
Scott: and And Then they fight the ghost in some ridiculous action scene.
Scott: and they do this twice per episode because each episode is actually two parts.
Scott: It's a lot like a Cartoon Network cartoon, you know Like a Dexter's lab kind of thing right where they do So the first in the first half of the first episode they fight the poop monster and the second half of the first episode The ghost is actually this thing that inhabits vehicles So it starts off in a car and then it switches to a Mack truck and eventually switches to a train.
Scott: Right, and they're fighting it the whole way.
Scott: and it's basically just this ridiculous action scene with all sorts of sex jokes and poop jokes and pee jokes and All sorts of just lewd crude.
Scott: and it's not like disgusting lewd crude.
Scott: It's just sort of shallow ridiculous over-the-top stuff.
Scott: Now.
Scott: This is not a show.
Scott: I think that I would watch Intentionally, like.
Scott: I'm not gonna download the episodes and watch it or go out of my way.
Scott: But if I was at an anime club This show would be so ace That people would be rolling in the aisles losing all their poop when they see the poop monster.
Rym: This definitely sounds like one of those shows that were we still running in the RIT anime club We would show this shit, right?
Scott: It's an excel saga sort of category, right?
Scott: So It's not the highest brow.
Scott: It's not an anime for the ages.
Scott: It's not even I'd say it's like in terms of staying power.
Scott: It's like a Full Metal Alchemist kind of thing or an Excel saga kind of thing.
Scott: But if you're looking for just a crazy, you know Slapping the kind of time, you know, and you got some excited people in a group panty stocking if you're willing to deal with you know, a Little bit of perverted, you know, it's not even perverted with the sex jokes.
Scott: The sex jokes are actually kind of funny.
Scott: It's just like panty likes to get with all these guys and then they make all sorts of you know innuendo.
Scott: It's you know, it's actually not that bad.
Scott: This is a show that you can reach for, you know, and you know, that's for it's pretty much it it's.
Scott: it's interesting.
Scott: It's not something that you would expect from Gainax.
Scott: It like totally doesn't match, you know There are other.
Scott: it's got a little bit of FL CL in it I think.
Rym: so speaking of weird shows to show an anime club I think Arakawa under the bridgie bridgie is equally out there.
Scott: So you like you like this bridgie bridge.
Scott: I like this bridgie bridgie, but remember I like saying bridgie bridge.
Scott: We were at.
Rym: I don't know where we were but we found that really Weird looking manga the one that had like the priest with a gun and the guy with the starhead And the giant rabbit and like all the crazy one.
Scott: That's just really I'm talking about.
Scott: Yeah, that's this Really?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Oh, she's watching.
Rym: I'm like, this is really familiar This is really familiar.
Rym: and then the starhead guy came out and I'm like no way.
Rym: and then the priest came out of the others.
Rym: The nun that was actually a dude with the scar comes out and everyone's like sister blah blah blah and he's like Oh shit, it's that thing.
Scott: So why is it bridgey bridgey?
Rym: It's the second.
Rym: there was a first season 13 episodes of Arakawa under the bridge.
Scott: Wait, so the show of the crazy manga has been out and we haven't watched it.
Rym: Yes And now this is the second season of it and it looks like it's just following the manga because it went through like five Quote-unquote episode numbers through this first episode and each one was like kind of a different story and just kind of went through.
Rym: and the Numbers like 105 106 107 108. so the story now that I actually see what's going on here It's about an alien girl that comes down and just lives under a bridge with a bunch of weirdos.
Scott: Oh, so she lives.
Scott: her name's Arakawa and she lives under the bridge.
Rym: Her name's not Arakawa, but she doesn't live under the bridge the bridge bridge the bridge bridge.
Scott: Why is it the bridge?
Rym: because the title of the show is Arakawa under the bridge X bridge Or bridge - and in the show the characters themselves call it the bridgey bridge.
Scott: Are they friend?
Scott: Oh even so even in the first season they say bridgey bridge.
Rym: I don't think they did in the first season.
Rym: I think there's making it.
Rym: you'll see the show is very meta.
Scott: Are they friendly with hunter x hunter?
Rym: I don't think so But I don't know.
Rym: This is just.
Rym: it's really really weird Like there's the mayor and he's a kappa but he's clearly just wearing a kappa costume Like a zipper showing okay, and they're all just kind of weird dicks to each other and it's just.
Rym: I Don't know how I can describe this, but I really like it and maybe I'll have to check out the episode.
Rym: I'll say I think you should.
Rym: I kind of want to go back and watch the first season.
Scott: maybe.
Scott: oh, yeah Maybe I should start with the first season.
Scott: See what's he was going on or going on with the bridgey bridge.
Rym: Yeah, cuz he kind of jumps right into the business here.
Scott: So if they're if they're referring to the bridgey bridge a lot, they must be hanging out near it a lot in the show.
Rym: Well, they trade you'll see.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Is that I get to say about it?
Rym: Yeah, it's all I got to say about it.
Rym: We got to move quick.
Scott: Okay, so bakuman right?
Scott: Let me let me talk about this.
Scott: So bakuman is a manga.
Scott: that's that's coming out now from the death note creators same artist same writer.
Scott: So that's already a win.
Scott: and the thing that I read the first volume It's already out in English.
Scott: and I gotta say I really like this manga because what it is?
Scott: a manga about manga, right?
Scott: It's it's got sort of a a cavalier and clay vibe to it.
Scott: You know with the with the sort of the way that it's two young kids like we're gonna make comics.
Scott: Yeah, let's do it.
Scott: And at the same time though, it teaches you a lot about the actual industry.
Scott: They talk about how much money you can.
Rym: he's not a manga guy.
Rym: It's just a gambler.
Scott: Yeah, and how hard it is to become, you know an actual manga creator.
Scott: and they even talk about like.
Scott: You know the tools that you need like the G pens and all this, you know It gets into details of manga about manga or if it gives a lot of information Even though it's a shounen jump thing, you know, it's it's it's pretty interesting and on top of that They sort of a generic school story that sort of reminds me of like, you know Every other anime story of you know, I can't actually you know, just go out with you We're gonna be all shy and blushy and crap and you know that kind of stuff.
Scott: And that's that's pretty much what it's about.
Scott: so this anime of bakuman right the first episode came out And I read that I watched the first episode and it pretty much covers half of the first tanka bond of manga Pretty much directly literally and I think that shows that these two guys They also made death note Which also pretty much directly translated to anime without modification are really good at making manga.
Scott: that directly translates to anime without.
Rym: But you know at the same time, I don't know how well they really translate.
Rym: I mean, maybe if I had just started watching the death note anime had never seen the manga It might have grown on me.
Rym: But watching the anime Having already read the manga was kind of just boring and I just got sick of it and stops really cuz.
Scott: I watch the whole episode and while I knew everything that was gonna happen because I had read the manga already and I think I'm gonna stick with the manga over the Anime.
Scott: and I'm gonna but for a different reason than you'll think right?
Scott: I thought that the anime actually sort of gave a little bit more Energy because you know with the voice acting and the people actually moving around right, you know They would get a little bit more, you know, it felt like they were more excited, you know.
Scott: Or you know their emotions came out a little more than it did in the manga.
Rym: See what's weird is I actually got the opposite vibe at least for the main character.
Rym: I very I don't know the voice acting and the way they kind of animated him and that whenever he was kind of Moving around and talking and his body posture didn't seem to fit the character that I'd seen
Scott: I actually kind of like the main character because the way he like, you know He come when he especially in that scenery comes back to the school to get his notebook and he's just like, alright, dude Seriously?
Scott: Yeah, I'll just leave you with the notebook.
Scott: You know, he was a lot more.
Scott: You don't see a lot of anime characters doing that sort of having that kind of.
Rym: Oh, yeah I like that in the manga.
Rym: But in the anime there were a couple of times where his character seemed just like suddenly revert to generic Protagonist for a while and then come back to the character.
Scott: I also liked how they open the show with the opener to the to the uncles anime series.
Scott: You gotta do that right with the superhero.
Scott: and then they brought this, you know They actually had that guy Animated and you could actually get a feel for what that manga was like a lot better than you could in the manga version.
Scott: now The reason I think I'm gonna stick with the manga over the anime actually is because I know that this isn't its meta knowledge Right.
Scott: This is an anime series the bakuman manga.
Scott: I don't believe is done.
Scott: I'll have to research that.
Scott: Therefore is this anime going to continue to faithfully adapt the manga to the end or will it stop or will it change and divert?
Scott: I don't know and the manga was already so good.
Scott: I'll just stick with that.
Scott: So I know that I get the full real deal with no historically I mean look at what happened to Fullmetal Alchemist Exactly.
Scott: So I'm you know, while they the thing is when they animated Death Note They did it after many volumes of Death Note were out.
Scott: I'm not sure how many bakuman volumes are out and if I'm gonna look it up and if every volume of bakuman is out or It's nearly done then I know that the anime is probably safe to watch and I'll.
Scott: maybe I'll go that way.
Scott: But I've already got volume one of the manga.
Scott: So if there's any doubt, I'll just stick with the safe manga bet because it's basically identical.
Rym: See, I'm going with the manga more because I feel like it was made as a manga and it works as a manga.
Rym: Being an anime.
Rym: at least this particular show did not add much for me.
Scott: Well, the thing is I'm sort of two minds about it, right?
Scott: Because on the one hand it's a manga about people trying to be Right, so that manga about a manga thing really works.
Scott: Yo dog, I heard you like manga exactly but at the same time right there.
Scott: ultimate goal is to have their manga become animated right and then Have the girl voice acted so to have an anime about.
Scott: You know a manga adapted into an anime.
Scott: to have an anime about a manga being adapted to an anime That is itself a manga adapted to an anime.
Scott: is he could have this other Thing going on right with that extra double meta level double.
Scott: I heard you like meta in your meta So I put meta meta in your meta meta dog Right, but at the same time I guess my trouble was just that watching it felt Slower and full of less energy than the manga.
Rym: at least in my watching.
Scott: the pace of it was definitely slower because I can read through a manga right.
Scott: I read that one volume in less time than it took to watch this episode and the episode only covered half of the material in that volume.
Rym: and also like I said I feel like the main character was going off Character and many of the times where he would move around like his body language Didn't fit the image I had when I was reading them.
Scott: I thought I felt like it was pretty literal.
Rym: the other thing is a couple of times He would like get really Shinji ish for just a second or like.
Scott: the other thing is that two lines I really need to see right through the the next sort of major plot point to really judge the anime like how they portray.
Scott: You know them getting the.
Scott: I don't have a spoiler because it's in the first volume of the manga.
Rym: is it a spoiler that Takumi wins the first race in an initial D.
Scott: No No, it's that you know their parents right.
Scott: when he goes to ask his parents if he can become a mangaka They're like, yeah go do it and then they give him the uncle's studio.
Rym: See that's crazy cuz that never happens.
Rym: every anime.
Scott: It's always like I want to die.
Scott: No, that's why you have to go be sort of an early spoiler Right, but you know the when.
Scott: I want to see how that part is portrayed in the anime because that's the part where the manga Sort of shifts to being very talky and death note style where they're in the studio Just talking about making manga all the time.
Scott: Like no you have to do this.
Rym: That's my worry.
Rym: What did death?
Scott: No, I don't want to see how.
Rym: why did death note?
Rym: do it show light?
Rym: Talking and play music in the background and pan over stuff.
Scott: Yeah, I want to see how the anime portrays those scenes.
Rym: Them like drawing and writing while they talk.
Rym: cuz that'll be really boring.
Scott: I would be really boring and that's why I wanted they need to see that part of the story unfold to determine which Medium is really better for this story.
Rym: See what I would do is keep cutting.
Rym: This is just me I've.
Rym: no I doubt this is what they do is when whenever they're talking about if they're talking about like what they're writing or what?
Rym: They're doing Show like on the screen instead of showing like their characters talking writing in the room or whatever.
Rym: Show like the sketches crudely animated and getting more refined as they go and like keep showing the scenes They're writing.
Rym: Yeah, well stuff like that.
Rym: Yeah, that's the only way you could get me to watch the anime.
Rym: Otherwise, I'll just read the manga.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, it's it's you know, it's a good manga real good.
Scott: At least volume one is.
Scott: so so should definitely if you do one of the other at least, you know pick one.
Rym: so mm.
Rym: Exclamation point.
Scott: I downloaded it and I clicked on it and then I just sort of fast-forwarded through it and I saw like 10 seconds of Animation and I closed it because I was tired fast-forwarded through too.
Rym: So the subtitles never weren't really displaying because I wasn't catching like the start times on them.
Scott: I just I just got tired and I said fuck it.
Scott: I'm going to bed.
Rym: So I went all the way through, you know what the show is about what it's about.
Rym: It's about masochism.
Rym: Oh Yeah, it makes a lot more sense.
Scott: Why doesn't?
Scott: why didn't they call it SM?
Rym: Cuz he's just a masochist and that the girl is the sadist.
Rym: She's just indifferent and thinks he's kind of lame.
Scott: but it's about two masochists.
Scott: No one Why don't you just call it M?
Rym: the dude is a masochist.
Rym: I guess it's already something called him and he goes and This girl just beats him with a baseball bat and as far as I can tell that is the entire plot.
Scott: He likes it.
Rym: Yeah, but he doesn't want to like it.
Rym: He wants to not be a masochist anymore.
Scott: So I so he likes.
Rym: it was like trying to get her to disavow him of his masochism.
Scott: Dude, the same way you get rid of anything else.
Scott: You don't want it's not cold turkey to quote DMC.
Rym: I'm a masochist.
Scott: Yeah, of course, but he the guy in DMC was a masochist was all about.
Scott: he didn't want to get rid of It.
Scott: he loved himself.
Scott: He was like, yeah, he's like fuck.
Scott: Yeah masochism.
Scott: All right, let's stick with it.
Rym: But watching the show, you know, it was like, all right.
Rym: This guy's getting beat up by this girl.
Rym: What is this love?
Rym: You know still getting beat up still getting beat up and then Emily chimes and I'm like this.
Rym: It's almost like this some kind of masochism show and Emily who could actually understand because there were no subtitles I'm skipping through is like yeah, he's a masochist.
Rym: He said it like five times.
Rym: Okay, really for real.
Rym: Yeah, that's what this is about.
Rym: I guess that's better than true bra.
Scott: Is it like?
Scott: is it have to bra?
Scott: how does true bra compared to what?
Scott: what's another show with the city?
Scott: All right, you bra verse incest show.
Rym: true bra is funny Engaging and has a good message for young girls.
Rym: compared to incest the movie.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Oh, that was a movie.
Rym: I know it's a show.
Rym: Yo dog, I heard you like incest.
Scott: So it's mm.
Scott: better than both of those.
Rym: or mm was the best of those two shitty shows.
Scott: So, I mean like it's mm Porn or a comedy or you know, there was no porn.
Scott: it was I don't know what it was the audience for that.
Scott: The my estimation is the audience masochist or people who just like mm.
Rym: It's a comedy.
Rym: Okay, I see only.
Rym: well it's a comedy for people who are slightly perverted, okay, and Actively perverted.
Rym: No, it's for the same people who want cinemax in America.
Rym: They want to see titillating Scandalous stuff and they're totally all about incest, but they don't want to actually watch straight-up incest porn.
Scott: Well if they just want to see.
Scott: you know things that are maybe titillating even though there's no incest You know, they should watch elven bride GGG.
Rym: Okay You Know the way you did that and I felt like you were segueing into Waka Laka.
Rym: GGG DDD DDD DDD.
Rym: All right, I think we're done.
Rym: we're done.
Rym: We'll see you at the New York Comic Con New York and a visible burning wheel and burning will count and such.
Scott: After this weekend this busy nothing.
Rym: Yeah, and then project ST will resume in earnest.
Scott: mag this.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.