Rym: It's Wednesday April 28th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: I'm gonna say something really lame right now.
Rym: We talked about mo comics Comics that we got at the mocha.
Scott: You can just cut that second part out.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So this weekend Scott didn't participate.
Rym: He's not a karaoke kind of guy.
Rym: I don't really blame him for.
Rym: you have to be a certain kind of person to enjoy karaoke Someone who is Masochistic and or has quality singing skills, but you know I don't want to get.
Rym: I'm not gonna tell the whole story.
Rym: We had a good time doing some Japanese style karaoke in Astoria at a place We've never been to before.
Rym: they had a good selection of English and Japanese music, but some surprising highlights that bear noting.
Rym: Item the first our friend Natalie can sing the najibudis song.
Scott: Surprisingly well, what song is it?
Rym: the ones that ghost in the shell standalone complex, okay?
Rym: It was in there.
Rym: You know the song in Russian?
Rym: yeah, and I see it in the queue because it shows you at the bottom like here the next few songs.
Rym: I'm like Inner universe.
Rym: is that the ghost in the shell song?
Rym: who's gonna sing the Russian song?
Rym: and she sang it really well Hey item.
Rym: the second much more important.
Rym: We did springtime for Hitler an old classic and for In Germany don't be stupid be a smarty come and join the Nazi Party.
Rym: So oh well that is a fun song to do.
Rym: it is hilarious.
Rym: You know everything about.
Rym: it is great Unless the CD or whatever it is in the karaoke machine breaks Midway through the song.
Rym: uh-huh so we're singing it and suddenly.
Rym: There's no more music.
Rym: Carl you know uncle yo keep singing so I keep singing, but without the backing music.
Rym: It's kind of this very scary I don't know mildly offensive song.
Scott: It's always been crazy currently offensive with the music.
Scott: That's the point with the music.
Rym: It's not so offensive because you kind of it is obvious to even as someone who's never seen the the musical.
Rym: What is going on here?
Rym: But when there is no backing music and you're looking at the karaoke machine and the lyrics are I'm going to read the lyrics from This portion the fuhrer is coming.
Rym: Heil Hitler Heil Hitler Heil Hitler.
Rym: springtime for Hitler and Germany Heil Hitler yeah, of course we sang the entire song all the way through with no backing music.
Scott: Maybe that.
Scott: maybe though this will create some sort of mean we could do is we could take inverse karaoke tracks right lyric tracks from various songs and change the bat just replace the backing music and Then the whole song changes sort of like when they do the movie trailers And it makes it look like a psycho movie.
Scott: is you know a romantic cop or a feel-good or a buddy movie or whatever?
Rym: I think the best one of those was Shining.
Scott: yeah, we could you know so we could do that for just music straight up.
Rym: I think what made it eerie though?
Rym: the Heil Hitler part was just.
Rym: you know everyone down the hall is looking at our room like What the fuck?
Rym: But uncle yo can sing pretty damn well.
Rym: So he's kind of actually singing this thing with no music behind it And I don't know it was something that you had to see.
Scott: I mean you know that's what he practices being an entertainer.
Scott: Yeah, you know if you practice anything you will get skills at it.
Rym: God.
Rym: What about the harmonica?
Scott: You have to practice.
Scott: I said if you practice You have to practice it like Street Fighter, so what do you got for me?
Rym: I imagine your news is up better than my news.
Scott: Oh news.
Scott: I was still like in an opening bit mode.
Scott: There's not really any exciting news.
Scott: I mean there's some you know comicky like Foreshadowing of the San Diego comic-con because it's like two months out.
Scott: so the foreshadowing begins.
Scott: You know how that goes?
Rym: that's a x-men Misfits is done.
Scott: No whatever but we I'm so tired.
Rym: I don't know why but anyway didn't even do a show on Monday.
Scott: I had nothing to do with that.
Scott: I just not sleep in anyway.
Scott: Last week we went to this special event in the city at the Center for book arts Which I did not know existed, but apparently it is an awesome place, and if you want to learn like bookbinding or Like how to use a letterpress and do typesetting or anything that is you know book arts You can totally go there and pay for classes that are really reasonable.
Scott: And I'm thinking you know I didn't sign up because the class started the next day And I was like oh, I can't just start a class tomorrow.
Rym: Yep, especially cuz we're gonna have like if you do that or if we both do something like that We got a document the whole process because people don't know about this stuff.
Scott: No, but you know I think what I'm gonna.
Scott: Do is you know eventually right?
Scott: It's like you know I got to solely build up And I think starting that you know the next time they have a semester or a quarter or whatever they have.
Scott: you know I'm gonna Take a class and then I'm just.
Scott: I'm always.
Scott: I'm gonna try to always be in one class of some sort at some place.
Scott: cuz There is classes for everything in the city.
Scott: You can take a class at like the museum about like you know Digging up archaeology.
Scott: so you could take a class.
Rym: It's funny.
Scott: You know learn into any musical instrument.
Scott: You can imagine you could take a class in like oboe or you could go and take a about hobo.
Rym: you could take a hobo class.
Scott: I'm sure you can go.
Scott: You know work at the shelter and learn all about hobos and You know you could do any kind of class, so why do anything?
Scott: So why would I not you know given the opportunity go and just.
Scott: you know I know I don't need to like go to night School and become like a full-on something.
Scott: I don't have time or effort for that.
Scott: But to take a non graded non school class and just one thing at a time I can build up so many skills.
Scott: if you consider like each class taking like you know a few months in a year I can learn three skills Like way better than most people know them.
Scott: I mean how many people even know any letter press or typesetting at all?
Rym: not many of course.
Rym: There's a problem here you realize.
Rym: so you want to level up all these skills.
Rym: right.
Scott: the level That's right, but it'd be like taking level one of rogue when you're a wizard Just you know or taking level one a fighter when you're well.
Scott: Do you know the sorcerer just to get a fighter just to get the saving throw and just to get all those feats Right?
Scott: so this is what it is.
Scott: I'm basically get all these feats.
Rym: But the trouble is look at the burning wheel book.
Rym: you realize that training gives you like nothing compared to putting yourself in mortal danger.
Rym: if you if you had a guy appointed a gun at you said buying this book or You're dead.
Rym: You would level up a lot faster.
Scott: Well, I think the thing is is that you know I'm paying money for it.
Scott: So that is a you know it's like I'm paying for this.
Scott: It's not like college or someone else is paying for it or me paying for it indirectly.
Rym: There's like a direct paying that is I got a difference if I had taken cash out of my bank account and given it to RIT.
Scott: No you give it to each professor as you come into the class every day like an arcade even if you don't show up.
Rym: Yeah, I think I would have gone to a lot more class.
Rym: I would have felt real bad about skipping.
Scott: yeah If you skip a class you show up next time and he's basically like double cost you'd base pay for the class you missed And a late fee.
Rym: Like I'm not missing any but it was funny because I was independently thinking about all these classes And I've narrowed it down.
Rym: there are three different types of classes that I'm choosing between.
Rym: I don't know if I'll do the book arts hmm.
Rym: I either want to do kung fu again That's a good kind of class or I found parkour classes like straight-up class.
Rym: Yeah, they did okay.
Rym: Well, I'm gonna see because this weekend Phil's coming out, so we're gonna try to do some parkour.
Rym: I'm gonna see if I break my hip or not.
Scott: when's he coming out?
Scott: where are we gonna do some burning wheel on Saturday?
Rym: So I'm gonna schedule.
Rym: I'll figure all that out all right.
Rym: It doesn't seem like everyone is committed to doing it on that day.
Scott: Anyway, I don't know either.
Scott: We got to figure it out.
Rym: Maybe we'll push the burning dwarves back into something else.
Scott: We'll see.
Scott: we gotta do something.
Rym: Let's play Street Fighter, but the third parkour Third thing that I'm thinking about and I found a place.
Rym: It's real cheap, and I wanted to do this in Beacon.
Rym: the only reason I didn't was that it was a pain in the ass with the train.
Rym: I want to for real.
Rym: just finally take motorcycle lessons.
Rym: Yeah I want to do that because I Imagine I was talking to scojo this weekend about the shore and like going down to the shore for a weekend And I imagine just getting on my motorcycle and going down to the shore on like a Friday.
Scott: Well, here's what we can do right.
Scott: so check this out.
Scott: if You know you said you can just play.
Scott: put the motorcycle behind the building for free.
Rym: right one motorcycle.
Rym: I don't know about two.
Scott: Yeah, maybe the other thing we could do right.
Rym: We could split a parking space and park both motorcycles at.
Scott: well We could also.
Scott: you know motorcycles don't really need a parking space.
Scott: you could put them in like Manhattan mini storage.
Scott: Yeah, you know we could put them in like Jersey stories.
Rym: I'll just roll them into my building up the freight elevator.
Scott: basically take the path train.
Scott: You know cuz what do we?
Scott: you're not gonna need them to go around in the city.
Scott: We only need it when we leave and mostly to go right around in the city.
Rym: I'm actually thinking about getting a Vespa at some point.
Scott: No so not good.
Rym: Why what's wrong with the Vespa?
Rym: They're great for going to the grocery.
Scott: They're all.
Scott: no they're not.
Scott: you can't put any groceries in there.
Rym: Put a lot of groceries in there, and they're mad.
Rym: dorky Isn't your soul philosophy?
Rym: don't care what people think about you.
Rym: It's gig nights.
Scott: Are you gonna get a motorcycle with saddlebags?
Rym: I'm probably gonna get either a state like a half cruiser or some sort of cross rocket.
Rym: You know the forward Talk about no groceries.
Rym: The motorcycle is not for groceries the motorcycles for the shore.
Rym: Yeah, I'm gonna get Vespa is for groceries.
Scott: I'm gonna get a perfectly just normal.
Rym: Those you know the bikes that are the hybrid.
Rym: they have the electric engine so they're basically a motorcycle.
Scott: I'm talking about dorky.
Rym: They're cool.
Rym: No real cool.
Rym: You asked Steve Pomeroy or any of our friends at MIT They're gonna think it's cool.
Scott: Yeah, it but it practicality.
Rym: Imagine you're trying to bike over that stupid Queensborough Bridge, and you just turn on the the electric motor on the way up that hill.
Scott: Yeah, so now I look like a net in this.
Scott: Lance Armstrong comes buzzing by me near Who likes suits look stupid now?
Scott: At least if I'm pedaling it would be like all right you're trying.
Scott: Well, thank you're gonna you're gonna be you're gonna be Lance Armstrong one day.
Rym: But no if you now now now your lungs are not nearly freakishly large enough.
Scott: No, I actually have a speedometer on my bike now.
Scott: It's pretty it's pretty shit.
Scott: So I'm not sure.
Scott: if I'm not sure like do you know like like in the Tour de France like how fast do they go?
Rym: I don't in miles an hour on my bike like when I used to have a speedometer And I biked around a lot in high school.
Rym: I could easily maintain like 18 or 19 miles an hour Mmm, but that like on flats or whatever flats on hills.
Rym: I could get it up to like 40.
Scott: Yeah, my bike when I was coming down the Queensborough Bridge when it got to like 31 like basically Pedaling didn't do anything.
Scott: It was pretty much.
Scott: wind was was limiting and that was it.
Scott: you like no amount of pedaling You know.
Scott: no no if I cranked up to the maximum rpm of pedaling it would not have accelerated.
Rym: See I would never go that fast on either on a bike that wasn't a racing bike or that had a front suspension.
Rym: without one Of those two I would not do that.
Scott: hmm, but you know basically it's like.
Scott: you know it's like 15 going around the city, but I'm not sure if I have the Circumference of the wheel correct.
Rym: you know you need one of those giant wheels the ones that are like you know the big old man.
Scott: See now here's you ready.
Rym: here is our mustache.
Scott: I I accidentally made a stupid thought and then my co-worker made the same stupid thought.
Scott: right so you put a magnet on a spoke And you put the sensor on the fork and the the.
Scott: the magnet comes with really close to the sensor But doesn't touch it right and that's how it knows.
Scott: and then accounts the revolutions And you tell it the circumference of the wheel.
Scott: yeah, and that's pretty much all you got to do.
Scott: so The co-worker made the same stupid first thought.
Rym: don't you have to put it on the outside?
Scott: No is doesn't it matter like how far you know?
Scott: Yeah, if it's too close to the the hub or too close to the Rym won't it?
Scott: won't it be wrong.
Scott: It's like no An rpm is an rpm.
Scott: You know the if the magnets going to close.
Scott: if the magnet is farther away closer to the Rym and farther from the hub It'll be going faster But it'll still go in a complete circle in the same amount of time as it would if it was right next to the hub.
Scott: You know what.
Scott: our one revolution still takes the same amount of time all right that's and travels the same amount of distance.
Rym: That's a common unexpected mistake, so what's number two?
Scott: What do you mean number two?
Rym: I thought you said there were two mistakes.
Scott: no I said we both made the same initial mistake.
Rym: so two mistakes, but between two people the same mistake.
Scott: Ah, I don't know what I remember saying.
Scott: two mistakes.
Rym: well regardless miles.
Rym: Oh shit moment a second ago I have a GPS app that tracks like where I run.
Rym: So I tried it out rollerblading to see like how fast I go and where I slow down and speed up And I realized just now that I left it on.
Rym: so it basically is still tracking my time right over there right now.
Scott: Why did you like punch me in the face with the microphone because the booms got in my way?
Scott: move?
Scott: Anyway, oh right.
Scott: so the center of a book Talk about a tangent whoa That's great, so we went to the center for book arts because they have an exhibit there.
Scott: They have like a. you know you can go for classes, but they also have exhibits to sort of you know And that's actually a clever move.
Scott: It's like they have the space in their room They're not using.
Scott: they can get people to come in to look at cool exhibits appeal to different groups And then you come in for the exhibit, and then they sell you on their classes which totally worked.
Scott: so their exhibit is pretty is about Garo which is the Pretty much the original gecky gov manga magazine.
Scott: they had a whole set of Just every issue of the first decade of Garo from like the early 60s to the early 70s.
Scott: every single issue was there.
Rym: apparently They're not that hard to come by.
Scott: yeah, I asked the guy I was like where did you get all these like?
Scott: I went to Japan.
Scott: I went use bookstores.
Scott: I bought him.
Scott: he's like they're not hard to find and they're not expensive, and I was like holy shit.
Scott: I'm like this is fucking as old as spider-man Which is really expensive, but it's cheap and easy to get and better and better.
Scott: But you know there was some really amazing In there you know and it was a fascinating exhibit.
Rym: the only complaint I had was that we went to the the lecture afterward, and it was good, but it was basically kind of smarmy Doctorate guy trying to write a paper interviewing Japanese creator, and I can sum up every question He asked into one concise sentence.
Rym: Does this represent a penis?
Rym: Because it looks like it represents a penis.
Rym: and here are like ten examples Where you drew something that I think looks like a penis.
Scott: Yeah, I wasn't thinking about that when I made it.
Rym: He's like, but seriously look at this.
Rym: It's a penis.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, you know it was so great.
Scott: How he would you know.
Scott: pretty much all he did was he showed this lady's art?
Scott: Which is really great, and then he showed like comparisons with like you know other Japanese arts.
Rym: you know this one artist that she seemed to like like.
Rym: she'd admitted like she liked this artist and He pulls up here that guy's art, and he's like you really like this artist.
Rym: She's like oh the composition to whatever whatever and then he's like okay I got her to admit that she likes him and then he proceeds to show all the crazy Perverted like old man schoolgirl pseudo rape penis stuff that the guy had drawn, and he's like.
Rym: so what about this picture?
Rym: Did you like?
Rym: It was kind of awesome.
Scott: Yeah, the one picture that I just remember is the one where that the girl she drew and like the whole background is white.
Scott: But the background the girls like feet are off the bottom of the page and the background between the girls legs is like all these Flowers, and it's bright yellow and everything.
Scott: and he's like really so this is not sexual Or referring to menstruation in any way shape or form.
Rym: She's like nope.
Scott: No just sitting there I mean, you know it's I mean the Japanese guests at conventions are you know that we're pretty used to them like always avoiding any Hentai or sexual topics which you'll discuss more.
Scott: my thing of the day, but You know it's funny to see someone actually be like look there it is.
Scott: So you.
Scott: it's like if you went to Gabe you know Benny arcade and we're like.
Scott: so see you drew this penis here.
Rym: He'd be like yep Tell me about it.
Scott: It's a you know quite a large dog nice and hairy.
Rym: So I don't want to talk about this at length, but it kind of epitomizes the Surprising lack of professionalism.
Rym: Well, I guess it's not surprising anymore in the American anime industry.
Rym: So the president and CEO of bangzoom, which is a dubbing company, right?
Rym: Yep, they dubbed a ton of anime.
Rym: basically said we're done unless you assholes start buying our anime and not just pirating all of it.
Rym: And he said straight up anime is going to die.
Rym: and he goes.
Rym: he basically seems to blame Piracy and fan subs for the fact that their dubs are not making money.
Rym: and Of course the obvious response to this is but what about things like crunchyroll?
Rym: I mean you can get most of this anime that kids are watching today Completely legitimately and people do get it completely legitimately and for free.
Scott: because yeah I basically stopped getting fat.
Scott: I mean I would get a fan some of the show I really wanted but that it's on crunchyroll.
Scott: So even though there's some ads there There's not enough to be annoying, you know, people don't download TV shows.
Scott: they go to Hulu because it's easier Yeah, and yet not because it's not because they care about legality But because it's easier to just go click click and it starts playing as opposed to find a torrent.
Rym: Download it get the codex then play it, but he basically says you assholes have to buy DVDs, which One?
Rym: I take issue with that statement.
Rym: I'll get to why in a second.
Rym: But when confronted with the fact that you can get a lot of this stuff for free legally He basically says well so far there's no successful way to model it.
Rym: monetize online entertainment.
Scott: So Why is anyone doing it?
Rym: But his argument that you should buy DVDs fails too because I note that I only buy DVDs of anime when they're one box sets of an entire show and two wicked cheap less than $20.
Scott: Yeah wicked cheap.
Rym: I think $25 is the most I would spend and that is for a like standalone complex level of show.
Rym: Yeah, like maybe Baccano or Durara I would pay 25 bucks for the whole the whole thing.
Rym: It would have to be the entire thing all in thin packs.
Scott: Yep Anyway, or in like one of the bricks the brick said like, you know, cuz it's you don't?
Scott: they're all in one package.
Scott: Anyway, yeah, I don't know I would go and discuss this same topic yet again, but didn't we do an episode?
Scott: Like this is not a charity.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, so there we go.
Scott: It's done.
Scott: I don't want to waste my breath anymore on these kind of people.
Scott: The only thing I guess I gotta add is like hey, you know, if you know never blame the customer.
Scott: It's all if your business is having a problem.
Scott: It's the business person's fault.
Scott: And you know what if an industry is dying an Industry is dying.
Scott: Why are you in a shitty business?
Scott: Just go out of business.
Scott: I mean just because a business exists doesn't mean it has some right or need to stay in business.
Rym: I think there's a secondary thing here.
Scott: That's kind of go out of business.
Rym: So notice how it's the dubbing company that's having trouble.
Rym: I think part of the problem is that anime had a boom where a lot of like Semi mainstream people like a lot of people were just kind of watching anime on TV for a while and then that kind of faded.
Rym: The only time there's a market for dubs is when non anime fans watch anime on TV.
Rym: Anime fans like people who are into anime subtitles.
Rym: They're gonna watch subtitles and they're gonna go for fan subs if they can't get it any other way.
Scott: So look crunchyrolls all subtitles.
Scott: The dub is not making any money for the dub guy.
Rym: I think the dub guy is done anyway because what he needs to do is a lot of a lot of anime companies when they do release DVDs are doing sub only because DVDs are not gonna sell to anyone who wants to dub.
Rym: No The only people you can ever sell a dub to or TV networks and they're not selling it to TV networks the right ways.
Scott: That's the other thing right?
Scott: Is that look all the hot all the dubs that were actually on TV like late-night Cartoon Network.
Scott: We're from one dubbing place.
Scott: I don't know if that place that you know The same people that dubbed like ghost in the shell and cowboy bebop.
Scott: You know that one place that made all the high quality dubs and everyone else made the shitty ones that didn't get on TV.
Scott: So, oh they got on TV is bang zoom that the people who did the really good dubs or those the people who did some?
Scott: Shitty dubs.
Rym: I don't even know.
Scott: I don't even know either.
Rym: I have no idea.
Scott: So like if those are the ghosts in the shell cowboy bebop dubbing crew then oh then that's really in the shitter.
Scott: but if they're not that crew then Your dubs suck anyway.
Rym: So things of the day.
Rym: I would hope you've seen this but if you haven't I figure it's worth pointing out Basically in a special episode a special volume of new type in Japan, you know, there's no more new type USA Yeah But they had this whole thing about the otaku room in 1995 and today And it kind of has a depiction of like what a typical otaku's room looks like in these three eras.
Scott: And it's it's stereotypical yet accurate very accurate.
Rym: I would say like it like.
Rym: no one's room looked exactly like this I would say but the spirit of what everyone was like I think very much mirrors the way these Fictional rooms look.
Rym: it is just very interesting to note how the 1985 room looks pretty Happening and pretty relatively normal and cool and the 1995 room looks mostly the same just with better technology.
Rym: 2010 room half-naked girls moe crap pillows with naked girls on them.
Rym: It tells the tale these pictures and I'll leave it at that.
Scott: Hmm Yeah, so my thing today, you know, I think goes right along with that sort of right.
Scott: Basically what this dude did is he got some pixel art photoshopping skills, right?
Scott: He is talented.
Scott: so he took all these old screenshots from Famicom games and did something to them and he basically Photoshopped any girls and some guys and some guys and he basically erased shirts and added boobs.
Scott: Very like you would think that these were porn games.
Scott: because he did such a good job even animated some of them.
Rym: Scarily now Scott showed this to me and I thought it was just a collection of boobs from NES games.
Rym: Because they're so good I couldn't tell until I found a game that I recognized and I was like I don't remember the Ninja Turtles gang raping April at the end of that game.
Scott: Yeah The thing about this I think it makes a really good Contrast for like some of them moe stuff.
Scott: because while this is sort of you know Like it is kind of perverted but it's perverted in a sort of lull way and also, you know It took some artistic pixel art editing skills here.
Scott: But it's a pretty good contrast to like the chew bra right where it's like, okay in chew bra You never actually see any nakedness.
Scott: It's like they be cut.
Scott: They're so perverted and twisted and pedophilic, but they never actually show anything versus this where it's like Okay.
Scott: Yeah, you know what?
Scott: We're not pedophiles.
Scott: We're just gonna show you, you know actual boobs.
Scott: There we go.
Rym: Okay It's like Dennis a rat always says The most perverted and crazy people are that way because they can't see the pink.
Rym: just let him see it once or twice and they'll Calm down.
Scott: Well, I think what it is right is that When you let you have this person and I've started to maybe this is true or not, right?
Scott: Someone is is into something that is so sick, dude, right like pedophilia or something like whoa.
Rym: It's not buggachan.
Scott: Yeah, like like.
Scott: it's not cool to be into that right, but they're into it.
Scott: You can't actually give it to them like you can't actually give them bestiality right or whatever.
Rym: I would argue that the internet does.
Scott: it does but I'm saying right if you don't you know If you're someone making legitimate stuff and you want to sell it to pedophiles, you can't just sell them.
Scott: pet of you know Child porn.
Scott: it doesn't work.
Scott: Right?
Scott: So what do you do?
Scott: Well, we'll make child porn, but we'll remove.
Rym: well We'll unporn it until it's no longer porn there for just the plot It's the Phantom Edit of what is basically child porn, right?
Scott: So it's like well now we can sell this really sick thing by, you know covering up this and covering up that.
Rym: Well, the thing is what's so right?
Scott: where this right?
Scott: This is like, oh, well, we're not that sick We're just regular old people who like boobs and whatever.
Scott: So we're just gonna show you some sex.
Scott: That's totally normal because we're not sick pedophiles.
Rym: What's interesting just do is the change between it's like.
Scott: that is actually better, you know, just being like hey Here's some normal sex right out in the open.
Scott: Check it out.
Scott: I think that's a lot better than his pedophilia that we covered up So that we don't get arrested.
Rym: Well back in the day I remember before I knew about this whole Moe thing and I not even heard the term yet and the first time I saw The term I thought Moe three Stooges.
Rym: Yeah, right Someone already made a t-shirt like that so I can't.
Rym: that's not an original joke, but basically I remember watching binchotan.
Rym: We all watched it together and it was really really really really Moe.
Rym: But we didn't really know about this whole Moe thing.
Rym: And I remember watching it and thinking that was kind of mindless and really really really cute.
Rym: and I didn't.
Rym: I didn't like cast any Sinister aspersions on it whatsoever at face value.
Rym: It is just cute.
Rym: and then I learned about the way people like other people would kind of take that anime and the way they would perceive it.
Rym: and Suddenly watching it again It felt really really dirty and they went back and watched bottle fairies and it felt really Really dirty and my whole perception of all that stuff changed Because I learned how different people were kind of taking it and what the actual intended audience was.
Rym: But then with things like chubra even if you had no idea about Moe five minutes of that shit And you know exactly what is going on?
Scott: Yeah, it's not.
Rym: it's not like it doesn't even try Nope, so before we forget the meta Moment.
Rym: Oh, I remembered it for all of you asking we didn't put up our anime Boston coverage yet.
Rym: It's just not a high priority.
Scott: We have anime Boston coverage.
Rym: We cut.
Rym: we did an entire like hour-long show about anime Boston.
Rym: I just haven't put it up yet mainly Mainly so you all know because there's not that much to say.
Rym: we've been going to anime cons every year many of them since 2002 and Very little notable happens now in current anime cons versus like one from four years ago.
Scott: Yeah, there's nothing like.
Scott: there's no particular exciting things to report in ways of news.
Scott: We did the same panels.
Scott: You know the convention happened.
Scott: It was a convention.
Scott: What is you know, that's it.
Rym: The only things to note very briefly.
Rym: there's a sudden rise in high school anime clubs And I think there's going to be a huge anime boom in about four years As soon as all those high school kids get some money.
Scott: Yeah You know you don't think they're gonna stop liking anime because I mean it basically I think they're gonna keep liking it because I think There's a lot of people like you look at.
Scott: you know Some people like they were in high school and they were totally into mangas and whatever and they were reading them You know back in the Tokyo pop days, but that was during the day when it was shoved down their throats.
Scott: But then they got to college and they stopped caring about it.
Scott: They weren't lifelong fans.
Scott: They were just temporary fans.
Rym: But look we've gone back to kind of the niche market where the people who are into anime now Aren't the people who saw some on TV and kind of got into it for a while or other friends getting into it?
Rym: They're into it because it's just on the internet and it's just next to all the other free entertainment that they watch.
Rym: So they watch like an episode of something and they get into it.
Rym: But because it's and it's not accessible in the mainstream push-down-your-throat way it's accessible in the YouTube way.
Rym: I think these people are gonna just keep watching it in the YouTube way forever.
Rym: But the reason I think there's gonna be a boom is that there's this boom of people joining clubs Maybe and also high school anime clubs were impossible ten years ago.
Rym: Yeah, and suddenly they're everywhere.
Rym: Anyway, the I guess the only other thing about anime Boston is the whole second half of that show.
Rym: is us complaining about the lack of professionalism?
Scott: The what other metamoments?
Scott: the book club book is still Carl Sagan's cosmos.
Scott: We still have to read it Rym, I'm most of the way through it But I'm not gay if I wait and give you my coffee when I'm done Because unlike you I can read a book in like a handful of days.
Scott: Not how long you know, you haven't finished it in as since we announced it which was over a month ago You can buy your own goddamn books.
Scott: Would you want to do this episode?
Scott: We should have been doing it last Thursday.
Scott: the episode Yeah, you didn't read it.
Scott: how you never read anything on time.
Rym: you didn't read it though either.
Scott: It's cuz.
Rym: I think you're taking too long, but you realize if you buy it, I'll have it done long before you finish it.
Scott: No, hurry up.
Scott: I buy it.
Scott: I'll have it read in like three days and you still won't be done.
Rym: Well, let's see you better buy it first.
Rym: Anyway I've read it before.
Scott: So then why are you reading it again?
Scott: Cuz I like it is give it to me so I can read it.
Scott: We could do the show.
Rym: No, I'm reading it again.
Rym: I'm refreshing my memory.
Scott: So yeah, you're refreshing it very slowly But you couldn't.
Scott: you can't even probably to remember what was in the first chapter cuz it was like three months ago that you read It.
Scott: cuz you're going so slow.
Scott: So if you're gonna buy the book Why should I read it if we have a copy?
Rym: Well, what you mean?
Rym: Why should you buy it?
Scott: Anyway, what other metas are there?
Scott: we missed a show on Monday.
Rym: I had a fancy work thing that I really had some work stuff and by the way work stuff was codename for drinking with all my co-workers and And I don't think there's any more metas.
Scott: that's the end of the metas.
Scott: Why do you make it noises even oven a lot?
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: All right, no more meta.
Rym: So the mocha Comics.
Scott: we're all right.
Scott: We talked about the convention itself Last Wednesday show.
Rym: Yep, but we didn't talk about Individual comics.
Rym: at least we put it.
Scott: we put in the interviews of the creators though, right?
Rym: Yes Yeah, at least most of them.
Rym: I kind of just threw it up.
Rym: You know my tradition for the mocha show is to interview a whole bunch of people and then just string them all together Yep.
Scott: Anyway, I was gonna.
Scott: I haven't read Most of the ones that I bought pretty much because I was planning to read them today when we decided to do a show on It today, but I was gonna go to the DMV today.
Scott: I thought I was gonna have to take a day off fascinating because the DMV line takes forever.
Scott: So I thought I would need a whole personal day to go to the DMV.
Rym: Fascinating and an unknown fact Yep.
Scott: But I went to the special License Express DMV which I thought I couldn't go to originally because I thought it was licensed renewal only but apparently is licensed renewal and Plate surrender, which is the two things I needed to do.
Scott: The license Express DMV takes like 15 minutes.
Scott: It's there's no line.
Scott: It's amazing.
Scott: So 34th Street license Express if you only need to renew your license, that's a note for everybody in the city.
Rym: So without further ado we're good.
Scott: as a result, I was not able to sit home and read comics today.
Scott: I went to work.
Rym: That's fine.
Rym: We've got a nice collection of the very short or very small or art book kind of things.
Rym: We got at the mocha and I want to start right away with the one that you won't find on the internet At least it is not easy to search for.
Rym: it's called crazy lady.
Scott: I don't think there's anything about it on the internet because it was one of those 50 cent ones from the mystery.
Rym: So I googled for a crazy lady.
Rym: you find videos of crazy ladies.
Rym: Crazy lady in quotes comic book, New York City mocha still turns up primarily an episode of GeekNights for some reason and Videos of crazy ladies yelling on the subway.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, I mean, this is from the 50 cent mr.
Scott: T table.
Scott: So it's not.
Rym: they were more than 50 cents unless you put the money in mr.
Rym: T.
Scott: Yeah the point is is that You know, this wasn't exactly a table that was full of like, you know Relatively high-profile stuff that people cared a lot about.
Scott: it was like, you know, it's like a collective of people Just going like yeah, here's a bunch of stuff.
Scott: God 50 cents.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So they did you know, they were not.
Scott: not all of them were like students with websites and portfolios and that sort of thing.
Scott: You know, yeah, it's sad.
Rym: I won't read it online.
Rym: I don't want to give him spam or anything But the only way we have to track this guy down is that he put his actual email address in the comic Which is at Juneau?
Scott: Yeah Juneau was still around me either but I guess if you had one that you know It's still.
Rym: but the main reason I want to bring this one up is that it's a testament to the kind like the reason you want To go to the mocha.
Rym: I mean a lot of comics you can just buy on Amazon.
Rym: But this there's no way.
Rym: you would have known about this unless you went to the mocha and bought it.
Scott: There's pretty much no way to get it.
Scott: period ever.
Scott: It's like it was the only place you wouldn't even known it existed or gotten it in any way shape or form Unless you had been there.
Rym: So crazy lady by Chris Brown is a pretty much straight-up just factual nonfiction story of one of those crazy ladies in New York City and many of you might not live in cities, but Basically, there are certain kinds of crazy people who hang out in certain places And if you're in those areas on a regular basis, you will notice them and you will notice their habits.
Scott: Yeah, like if you like if you work in say a bodega, right then you would notice.
Scott: You know someone who's a crazy lady who sits out, you know, who is around your geographic area.
Scott: They would come around a lot buy a lottery ticket You know, maybe they you just see them walk back and forth all day.
Scott: while you're looking out the window You notice these sorts of things.
Scott: We're in like an office building and we're in Apartments that are up off the street.
Scott: So we don't really notice you know like specific crazy people that are in a specific area because we're not like sitting there watching them all day.
Scott: and If we look out from our balconies, we don't really see crazy people areas.
Scott: But we do notice, you know, we pass by multiple different crazy people as we walk around the street.
Scott: So but like for example when I walk to work, I would notice specific crazy people in their specific spots.
Scott: You know that they would always be in the same spot every day when I walk to work like the crazy guy who's on the The street with all the Jewish jewelry stores.
Scott: Is that one guy who was over there?
Scott: I noticed him.
Rym: Uh-huh There aren't the only lady I have and she's actually gone this year.
Rym: I don't know where she went was the woman who would stand in front of Grand Central at like 545 678 in the morning just yelling at Grand Central really.
Rym: She was really mad at it.
Scott: Wow, but yeah, this is you know, this story really gave me sort of that, you know It's obviously not will Eisner quality in art or in any you know writing or anything.
Scott: But the kind of story it is is that will Eisner kind of human story where he tells a story about?
Scott: Humanity that just feels like it's for real.
Scott: This is this is people living.
Rym: Oh shit Well, at least I know for a fact that it's real because the humanities there are huge manatees.
Rym: There are people exactly like this and we see them on a regular basis.
Rym: But I really like this and I'd recommend if you can find it somewhere that you read it.
Scott: Yeah, good luck.
Rym: So I guess I'll move right along cuz I have a pile of comics in front of me unless Scott has something I don't know.
Scott: Do you want to talk about the spider one?
Rym: I think we should.
Rym: that's not about spiders at all It's about dentists.
Rym: Oh, it's about Dennis and dragons and it is basically my of everything I got at the mocha.
Rym: It's my favorite thing.
Scott: Really?
Scott: Yeah, I really I think it's just weird.
Scott: I mean you basically these dragons, but the dragons are.
Rym: well, they're they're not.
Rym: they're sugar dragons.
Scott: Well, no, they're sugar spiders.
Scott: The book basically uses all these wrong names for things like there's some wolves and it's like oh no dentists.
Scott: And then when you finally the wolves finally get close they have like Dennis coats and floss.
Rym: But that was so.
Rym: it was so cool at the end with the whole, you know Making the dentist uniform and then they don't recognize the sugar spider.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean, it's basically just sort of like an Adam and Eve story.
Scott: You know that the wolf eats the apple and then it it says oh now we can see that you're a sugar spider.
Scott: Oh, but we can also see that you have no teeth see and there's no reason to chase you.
Rym: and you know I didn't quite take it with the Adam and Eve story.
Rym: I took it more.
Rym: is that some sort of like a case or something that is no longer necessary in a world?
Rym: I mean the real answer is that it was the brainchild of a comic artist doing the 24-hour comic and thinking about dentists.
Scott: Oh I didn't read the thing in the back.
Rym: Yeah, there's a whole story would have helped.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is I think one thing that was interesting was just how they like, you know They draw a dragon but throughout the whole book they keep saying spider.
Scott: They never say dragon and they call the dragons like sugar spiders.
Scott: So it's like.
Scott: I think that could be an interesting mechanic if you just set up a world Where you just fuck up the names of things, you know, but stay consistent.
Scott: And you know, it's sort of like, you know, I think there's some interesting literary things you can do with that.
Rym: I guess just this was unique and it tied itself together Really really well.
Rym: and also the dragons that really good facial expressions.
Scott: Yeah, so and I like the colors are nice the way it's like Watercolor ish.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know exactly the color was actually added after the fact that wasn't done in the 24-hour span Okay, but all the rest of it was mm-hmm, but Catan the spider by I R.
Scott: Well, that was at this table that all kinds of awesome stuff like bored angel.
Rym: bored angel is literally just a part angel.
Scott: Yeah, they also had some other.
Scott: I'm pretty sure this was also not a hundred percent sure But I'm pretty sure this is the table that had.
Scott: like these different things that let you build your own story But like spinning stuff around.
Scott: they had the book that like you could turn Sections of the book but no matter what combination you came up with the whole page always made sense.
Rym: That was pretty cool Partly - this was just very creative and out there and different But in a good way, actually, I expect I had to do much greater comics as time goes on.
Scott: Yeah, that's something to look for in the future years.
Rym: Yeah, I'll make my prediction now.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: so I picked up a couple art books and Tiny kitten teeth is something I always forget about.
Rym: and then I see the art and I remember like oh, yeah that art.
Scott: Oh, yeah that art.
Scott: Yeah, that looks like totally kitschies 50s 60s stuff.
Rym: Yeah, but I I really really really like it.
Rym: So I got the art book Becky dry stat.
Scott: Yeah, it's a webcomic that people read didn't?
Scott: they didn't?
Rym: she do like a penny arcade once I believe she did one of the lookouts.
Scott: Oh, yeah, was that her?
Rym: Okay, but I just I don't.
Rym: I really like this style and it was a cool art book.
Rym: It's also something that I haven't seen anywhere but something like the mocha.
Scott: Yeah, I like it because it looks like little golden books, you know At least some of them did and I wasn't.
Scott: I like the little golden books.
Rym: The comic is surreal.
Scott: Yeah, it is way I mean like what is up.
Scott: This is like a squirrel milkman bringing some milk To a tree stump where there's some sort of thing that lives there.
Scott: That's got a mushroom mailbox and at the bottom it says sorry.
Scott: I'm late.
Scott: I had the wrong stump.
Scott: Okay Alrighty then but the art is like whoa.
Scott: you made that kind of art for that comic.
Scott: That's crazy.
Scott: I'd like to see like how she does it too.
Scott: Like how do you tell you draw like that?
Scott: Well, I
Rym: don't know the characters in the comic like kind of the main plot thread Really remind me of the atmosphere in kevlar and clay when they're in the arty part of the beginning of the book Like when they're just getting into New York Like it's like those kinds of people.
Rym: But anyway, I thought it was neat.
Rym: the other kind of the exact opposite but also cool was the these shapes art art book shapes The new brethren.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: So we heading in the mocha and there's these guys who are just real excited and energetic right and excitable dudes.
Scott: They seem like our kind of people and apparently what their story was that when they were in high school or whatever.
Scott: I think it was high school.
Scott: one dude who had no who had relatively few art skills Right would draw a shape just outline a solid shape, you know And I just you know alright and the other guy would then take that shape and fill it in with high quality arts of some sort of.
Scott: You'd invent a character based on that shape, you know.
Scott: Inside the shape around the shape, right.
Scott: and then the first guy who drew the original shape would take it back and then he would name the character that was created.
Scott: and they did this a whole bunch of times and they did it so many times that they actually made like A friggin book out of it and they actually saved all these shapes.
Scott: They didn't lose any of them.
Scott: so it was totally crazy and awesome.
Scott: and the characters that they came up with are like Totally crazy awesome characters.
Scott: to like here name some of the guys that my favorite one is still slick chisel the rifle sniffer That's pretty great.
Rym: and ramburger the Chancellor.
Scott: Chancellor we had that's like from a different board game.
Rym: Yeah, of course Queen Nadia of Pollination.
Scott: Oh snap.
Scott: So yeah, if you go I don't know if these guys have a website or anything, but just like looking at all these faces It's like you could just keep looking at him and it's like I'll do.
Scott: lol.
Scott: oh look at that one and you look at the original shape and then you look at the face that came out of that shape.
Scott: and Sometimes like you look at the shape and you imagine in your brain what character would come from that shape.
Scott: right like you imagine like this area being a beard and that being an ear and then you'll look at it and like the ear will Be an eyeball and the beard will be like the nose and that you know, it'll be totally sideways like whoa.
Scott: That guy was really creative.
Scott: He did something totally different instead of the obvious thing with it.
Scott: Holy crap, you know pretty cool a lot of fun.
Rym: Got anything else over there?
Rym: Should I dip into the rest of my pile?
Scott: I got.
Scott: I got only two things left over here because all the comics that I have are at my house and I didn't finish reading Them all and I am NOT at my house right now.
Scott: So, let's see There's this tiny one hush by Mara Sternberg.
Rym: Oh, that was the one that I expected was going to be very sad and ended up being funny instead.
Scott: Yeah, it was just like on this fancy, you know sort of you know Nice glossy ish paper right very short.
Scott: It's a story about this girl.
Scott: She makes a snowman She tells the snowman all her secrets and then something happens and then there's an ending and it's like five pages And it's just one of those like, you know ultra mini comics.
Scott: It's only got like three colors like black white and brownish.
Rym: I'd say it's in the same category as bored angel.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much.
Scott: It's sort of like, you know, you take one joke, but you you know you just put the joke over a few pages and you got yourself a cute little comic that you can sell for a couple bucks at the mocha and It's not bad.
Scott: I'd like to see like this same Artie style but actually do a for real comic that's longer and maybe has a plot, you know as opposed to just one joke And that you know, I think that can be pretty interesting.
Scott: Also the binding with this one string is pretty good.
Scott: binding with the one string I like all the different ways people bind because obviously they did not all take classes in binding at the Center for book arts.
Scott: People, you know, some people do like binding and all sorts of different ways from.
Scott: you know Just staples to tape to glue to strings to.
Scott: you know, fancy Japanese.
Rym: There was no a preponderance plastic ring of straight up well bound like professionally machine bound hardcovers.
Rym: I think there's now a cheap way to do that.
Scott: I think this yeah I think there is some way that people have found to get like hardcovers printed because I saw a lot of like Small like 20 to 30 page hardcover type books around with some pretty nice covers on them.
Scott: And I wonder who's doing that and who the printer is and how much it costs.
Rym: though I do I want to get the Center for book arts to be at the mocha to do a little table or Me I were they not at the mocha.
Scott: Did we not notice them?
Scott: What's up with that?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: if they know.
Rym: it amazes me.
Scott: How could the Center for book arts not know about the museum for comic and cartoon arts?
Scott: It feels like it should almost be the same museum.
Rym: So Drawn to you was very.
Scott: you know, the mocha should have classes.
Scott: I mean there is there are places in the city where you get comic classes and writing and art and drawing and all sorts of Stuff, but I think the comic experience I think it might be is the place you can get comic classes.
Scott: But it's like why?
Scott: why isn't the mocha given like, you know I think the combination of classes and museum is a good mix that the con the Center for book arts has.
Scott: but like You know did the other museums really?
Scott: I don't think they have so many classes.
Scott: Can you go to the MoMA and get classes?
Scott: I don't think so.
Rym: It depends on the museum.
Rym: I mean the Natural History Museum.
Rym: are you know the science museum?
Scott: because I mean the museums are always asked for money, right?
Scott: And I guess the big museums get money from the admissions, right?
Scott: Because they can sell admissions or they get the suggested donation and most people do it.
Scott: But if you're a smaller museum It's like well you can have Classes to make the money because you can charge a lot for classes and you don't need that.
Rym: many depends on what you are.
Scott: Musing I mean If it's I think the correct word the correct verb is curating.
Rym: if it's old kenigits with swords, you're not.
Rym: what are you?
Rym: Yes, that's a great idea.
Scott: Smithing classes duh, I would totally go for some smithing.
Rym: actually that one listener in the forum is talking about his bladesmithing.
Rym: He's.
Scott: he's pretty awesome with his blades.
Rym: I'm not gonna do it because I know but I've known people who have done that.
Rym: but for about an hour I was thinking man.
Rym: I should totally get into that.
Scott: Yeah, you know get a little Forge in the back the balcony.
Rym: My neighbors would love that.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Rym: Okay, so drawn to you Erica Mon and Lucy Nisley is basically Two girls talking about the fact that they draw penises in some of their comics.
Rym: Not really, but really is that?
Scott: is that really literally in there?
Rym: No, it's made kind of.
Rym: it's very just meta about these two comic artists talking about themselves and their lives and their relationships and it's self-indulgent but in a in a very entertaining way and it does end with fraud erism and With them drawing themselves on a unicorn shooting Hitler,
Scott: okay, so, you know, that's the thing with the man.
Rym: Look at this fraud erism right there.
Scott: That's fraud erism.
Scott: All right That's the thing with the mocha is like you'll buy some comics and then like some of them will just be like strangely Like have some weird stuff you did not expect like.
Scott: there was this one I bought called hobby and I think it was European or you know Northern European I forget exactly European.
Rym: that might be your hobby.
Scott: But I bought it because they had this totally sweet art style that is totally like retro Cool, right?
Scott: That's the only reason I bought it.
Scott: It was that's real cool.
Rym: to what era like the 50s the 60s?
Scott: I can't really.
Scott: I can't really see.
Scott: you'd have to show it to you too free to understand.
Scott: but basically like I did not expect it to have the contents it had which is pretty much like Frustrated kid never getting it on with anybody story.
Scott: You know, I was like really that's this about whoa.
Scott: I thought it would be about like kids playing with messenger toys or something like that.
Scott: It totally was not.
Rym: But yeah that happens occasionally at the mocha which is kind of fun the fact that you know You're so used to seeing a certain art style kind of present to you a certain kind of story.
Rym: So whenever an art style doesn't present the story you expect there's this moment of shock and revelation And it really broadens people's horizons.
Rym: I mean remember that one Anime.
Rym: when they cry we watch the opening scene, you know, we always used to When we'd watch anime, we'd sit down like me Scott Emily, maybe some other people in.
Scott: that's the Higurashi.
Scott: No, not kokoro knee.
Scott: Yep, and not.
Scott: then there's the sequels, right?
Scott: It's like what the fuck are the sequels about?
Rym: but we'd watch the first like 10 seconds of a show to see if it was worth watching any more of and if it was Maybe we'd skip through it.
Rym: So we start this show and it's just a guy savagely beating someone to death with a baseball bat and We're like, wow kind of show was this?
Scott: that's a kind of.
Scott: it's a good show to me.
Rym: I'm kind of violent murder mystery.
Rym: Looks like he just murdered that girl with a baseball bat.
Rym: and then the opener happens and it's like the moe is Not moe, but it's just sort of just the happy cute normal that you know It's.
Scott: it's very much like Excel.
Rym: take the asa manga dial opener and make it more lucky star looking like really cute and just Not what you.
Rym: you did not expect baseball bat murder to be associated with that opener Those character design, but it's not.
Scott: it's not pedophile cute.
Scott: It's like regular anime cute, you know I don't know.
Rym: and then the baseball bat murder.
Scott: Yeah, whatever.
Rym: So, of course diarrhea diaries 3.
Rym: I think I already talked about that business the finale.
Rym: it is the finale.
Rym: ah shit literally I Read it, but I just have to again.
Rym: the parting words of this comic are words to live by you in your life.
Rym: Take heed.
Rym: in Closing let me leave you with this when a hard winds a-blowin Take heed and realize the storm.
Rym: She's a-comin.
Rym: Okay, I'm just so glad this guy was able to come to terms with his bow yular escape escapades by sharing them with the masses.
Scott: Yeah, I think diarrhea diaries like a thing like only we know.
Rym: uh, the only other one like that is our prison funnies.
Scott: Yeah, that's true.
Rym: I really liked prison funnies.
Scott: At least like it seems like some people know Teen Boat, right?
Scott: It's like Teen Boat gets around a little bit, you know, but you know Doesn't seem like diarrhea diaries gets around.
Scott: It's like who else is the audience for that besides us?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: So I think we have two more here.
Scott: Okay, we got two more.
Scott: Wow this episode kind of short Anyway, so this one Rym gave to me at a read it right before we did the show.
Rym: I will say straight up I bought this comic because of the way the giraffe looked on the cover.
Scott: I agree that the way the giraffe looks on the cover It looks like he's the awesomest giraffe and the giraffe is exactly what I expected.
Rym: He's basically Gauri from slayers the giraffe.
Scott: Yeah, so what this is?
Scott: it's hero's journey, right and you got this rabbit on the cover with a stick.
Scott: He's a he's an anthropomorphized rabbit and behind him is a smiling anthropomorphized awesome giraffe.
Scott: Basically, the story is like totally stereotypical fantasy.
Scott: Like I'm a normal dude living in the fantasy times.
Scott: I'm a peasant.
Scott: Oh shit an adventure comes out and bites me in the ass.
Scott: Now.
Scott: I gotta go on a quest.
Scott: I'm going on a quest.
Scott: It's sort of Alice in wonder.
Scott: I'm not Alice in Wonderland Wizard of Oz cuz.
Scott: he's meeting all these people on the quest like the giraffe and the pig Right.
Rym: Yep, a little bit of slayers feeling but just.
Rym: I think that all harkens back to the root which is stereotypical fantasy.
Scott: I mean slayers.
Scott: is Wizard of Oz like to write Lena inverse going on a quest.
Scott: Yeah people join the party.
Scott: Well join the party.
Rym: It's only like Wizard of Oz if the put her as a party could kick everyone's ass anyway, and she murders everyone.
Scott: She what's older Wizard of Oz or Lord of the Rings?
Scott: Chirp-chirp cuz like who invented the the?
Scott: join the party.
Scott: go on the quest story.
Rym: I'm pretty sure that that existed before both of those.
Scott: Yeah, but it's a who invented it.
Scott: I mean the Odyssey was one, dude It wasn't join the party.
Scott: It was just.
Rym: you know, well, he had his party with him.
Scott: Yeah, but it wasn't like the party had like quality characters, you know, it was.
Scott: it was a bunch of note.
Scott: You know side.
Rym: I gotta say this Odysseus is a jackass.
Rym: He's cunning, right?
Scott: But even that okay, so here's the thing though, right name one other person in his party.
Scott: There were dudes on the boat cuz they got off when they hit up the Cyclops.
Scott: Yeah, but who was on the boat with him?
Rym: The only other awesome people are all the people back home kicking ass, right?
Scott: So there were.
Scott: no.
Scott: no one else on the boat with him had a name so it wasn't really a join the party situation.
Scott: Yeah, so where was the first quest where people joined the party?
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Anyway, this is a generic story But the giraffe is sort of an awesome character because he's totally swinging not as awesome as King Cosmo And he's not awesome as he is on the cover.
Scott: like on the cover he's way cooler than he is in the book I don't know.
Scott: He's still pretty cool as you forget.
Rym: I think when he's dancing in that in.
Scott: no That's pretty much as he's shining moment in the Sun.
Scott: But you know, the art is pretty cool.
Scott: There's a some misspellings like they misspelled throne.
Scott: So it's like here's the.
Scott: I am next in line for the throne really.
Scott: So after the next guy is done, you're gonna get you know thrown like a baseball, right?
Rym: Like, you know maybe in Shadowgate right see what I would say is this is again one of those things that you'll only ever find at the mocha and There's a certain charm like.
Rym: obviously this is someone who like one of their earlier like I'm going to make a comic and I'm going to sell it here.
Rym: it is and It's passable quality.
Rym: It really is.
Scott: The only thing that bothers me about it is that it's part one.
Scott: It's like fuck you part one.
Scott: Now making me buy part two to find out what happens at the end of this incredibly generic Fantasy quest.
Rym: but I really do.
Rym: I like I honestly do want to know what happens at the end.
Scott: Stereotypical story.
Scott: one thing it does but then I cut you off and it's like fuck you Thank.
Scott: is this gonna continue to be stereotypical in every way shape and form and have a happy ending or maybe not?
Rym: I don't very few fantasy things.
Rym: I have read cut to the meat of what the heroes expect, you know in this It's the hero meets a dryad and wants to savor and I've read a lot of other fantasy stores with a similar vibe, but He pretty much straight-up just fantasizes about saving her and then totally making out with her Which is what is on the mind of every hero, but very few fantasy works kind of get right into that Like they don't make it obvious to you.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: He totally just wants to bone the princess.
Rym: That's why he's doing this.
Scott: He isn't doing it just because he wants to bone her.
Scott: He wants to save her and bone her.
Scott: You know if he saved her and didn't bone her he would be happier than if he failed to bone and failed to see.
Rym: Bonder didn't.
Rym: savor would be the bad guy right exactly.
Scott: He definitely does not want to do that either.
Scott: I don't think cuz.
Scott: then she would be dead and it would be necrophilia.
Scott: But it would be necrodendrophilia because she's a dryad, but she was originally like a water nymph mermaid.
Scott: So would it be aqua dendrite necrophilia?
Rym: So The last comic I would like to talk about Scott didn't read this.
Rym: I don't believe.
Scott: I wonder if anyone else in the entire history of the universe is said aqua dendrite necrophilia.
Rym: I gotta google it.
Scott: I will do it right now.
Rym: so while you do that the last comic I have here is mirror mine by Tori woolcott and There have been a lot of these comics lately and I think they're a good thing.
Rym: and this one's really well done a very sparse Like thick hard lines black and white style and it's the story of a girl who has dyslexia and kind of what that's like.
Rym: And apparently it portrays it so well and you're reading it.
Rym: It was very enjoyable I liked.
Rym: it's worth reading That a lot of schools and a lot of counselors are actually using this book to help kids who actually have dyslexia.
Rym: Deal with it.
Scott: That's pretty cool.
Rym: And it kind of the book all backwards No, but it has a really good section where it shows like why dyslexics specifically like why they have trouble.
Scott: That's sort of like those things where it's like.
Scott: this is what it looks like to a colorblind person, you know to help, you know Normal non-disabled people see what it's like to be disabled.
Scott: I remember when I was a kid like here sit in a wheelchair for a day.
Scott: We're gonna tie your legs to the chair so you can't use them off.
Scott: now I see how horrible.
Scott: there
Rym: was an exhibit of like different disabilities at a science museum in Detroit and they made a whole city street with an intersection and everything all indoors full-size
Scott: Mmm,
Rym: and you'd put on a blindfold and try to navigate it in any capacity with a blind walking stick
Scott: And then they showed your video of you walking around actually.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, you know what not easy.
Scott: No My search result is done Apparently an urban dictionary.
Scott: There is an entry For dendro necrophiliac and it says one who perform sexual intercourse with dead trees.
Rym: But there is no wouldn't that just a doubt?
Scott: a wooden dildo, but there is nothing.
Scott: Let's see if they have aqua filiac, but they don't have aqua dendro All right.
Scott: So they have.
Scott: aqua filia is on Wikipedia Which is a form of sexual fetishism which involves people swimming or posing underwater.
Rym: that could be cute, right?
Scott: Yeah, totally like hot mermaid chicks, but they have nothing.
Scott: Nothing about aqua dendro necrophilia, which would I suppose it'd be dead trees in the water after they went through the sawmill.
Rym: well There's a horrifying image from you for you.
Rym: I don't know how many of our listeners will get it But so you want to have sex with horrifying dead trees in the water?
Rym: I recall in the life and times of Scrooge McDuck a specific kind of tree like that.
Rym: No shit.
Scott: Yeah Well, actually I'm watching Captain Harlock where he's fighting against the Mazzone.
Scott: the evil plant aliens right from outer space And there's at one point where there is some seaweed Mazzone and those seaweed Mazzone totally get killed.
Scott: So is that another aqua dendro necrophilia situation?
Scott: Cuz all Mazzone are totally hot.
Scott: They look like totally hot ladies, even though they are all plant people.
Rym: So they're like space Guess I don't know.
Scott: evil plant people from outer space.
Scott: at least most of them and Some of them are seaweed and some of them are trees in the rainforest.
Rym: Wait till you finally get a hold of that old second ed D&D monster man.
Rym: I got it already because look up the kelpie.
Rym: It is a Strangely sexualized monster and it even has what monsters are not sexualized.
Scott: I mean, there's like what isn't time.
Scott: It is like ten pages of sexy beholder in that book.
Rym: I Don't know.
Rym: zombie Lord at the end not super sexy It is.
Rym: deal with kelpie.
Rym: as I recall it kind of points out the fact that if you wear like say a ring of underwater Breathing it really can't kill you and you can just enjoy yourself.
Scott: Yeah, yeah It's I like parts.
Scott: what I like about the book is how many monsters it's like totally friendly normal Dudes slumps and such.
Scott: so there's no plump in there.
Scott: I couldn't find now.
Rym: He's in the old old old one.
Rym: Yeah, but this reminds me and I think we can end on this talking about Speaking of having sex with mermaids.
Rym: So, you know, what song was straight up?
Rym: Oh, you know I'm sitting there.
Rym: I didn't know what song to do.
Rym: in the karaoke.
Rym: I'm flipping through and I think there's no way I'm on a boats in there.
Rym: So you look for Lonely Island flipped to L and there is in fact, I'm on a boat and like a boss Oh shit Lonely Island in the karaoke.
Scott: Did you do it?
Rym: I did it.
Scott: All right Both of them.
Rym: I only did I'm on a boat Because we were running out of time and we're still recovering from Heil Hitler Heil Hitler Heil Hitler.
Scott: There should be a way to just be like, you know The way those things work is like you can't just end a song.
Rym: be like aunt cancel Can you you can skip one in the middle?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Okay, cuz basically you cue them all up like there's a screen.
Scott: Yeah, but if like if you get in a situation we're like, you know, it's like.
Scott: okay This is not going so well, you should just skip.
Rym: Yeah, you're going it basically.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Oh, man, that'd be cool.
Scott: We should make a karaoke machine that is gong mode where everyone in the room has a gong.
Scott: So and if more than half the room pushes the gong you just had to sit down and I would gong you first.
Scott: I would just push it every time.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and brand.
Scott: Okay for the logos be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.