Rym: It's Tuesday October 26 2010.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights tonight civilization 5.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So I discovered in Filling out some government forms today that in fact The people living one floor above me in my building have a different zip code from me And in fact the people living on the ground floor have a different zip code.
Rym: yet again There are nine zip codes in my building.
Scott: How many floors are there?
Rym: ah?
Rym: 15.
Scott: oh so some builders some floors have the same and some have different.
Rym: There's the floor under me as the same zip code as me, but the next thing is there's a brand new zip code.
Scott: I don't it.
Scott: is it a different on the final four digits?
Scott: Or is it actually the first five digits the final four?
Rym: well you think it's the first five.
Scott: Yeah, well you know that.
Scott: then it's not really a different zip code.
Scott: Well.
Rym: It is that is part of the zip code.
Scott: It's a different.
Scott: zip plus four is the reason it's not zip code.
Scott: It's zip plus four.
Scott: right well Four is different.
Scott: that doesn't mean anything.
Scott: It's like okay.
Scott: Yeah, everyone it plus fours are like they change every few houses.
Rym: It's the actually depends on where you live.
Scott: like any actual zip code the first five digits is one proposed in many Populated areas.
Rym: the the board the last four they actually don't change nearly as often as you think it's because there's less people City.
Scott: so that makes perfect sense for the final board.
Scott: It's not a different zip code It's a different plus four.
Rym: the plus four is part of the zip code Scott.
Scott: No, it's not.
Scott: It's that's.
Scott: how can they don't just call it the zip code?
Scott: It's the zip.
Scott: well because the plus four was the plus four is an additional thing that is not part of the zip.
Scott: I know it is.
Rym: the fire was added to this.
Rym: it.
Rym: You don't know anything about the zip code.
Rym: What's it even stand for Scott?
Scott: It doesn't stand for anything.
Scott: It's zip.
Scott: It's haha.
Rym: Anyway, you got any video game news.
Scott: Oh, you're just rushing right to the news already.
Rym: well because you don't know anything about zip code We can't have this discussion.
Scott: What does no session have?
Scott: a zip code is one number per post office.
Scott: usually and It's that way they know which post office to go to without having to look at the address And then they only look at the address When you know they're actually at the post office, and then they can know which house to go to.
Rym: actually There's a lot more to it than that, but anyway anyway.
Scott: So let's see video game news.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: why don't we talk about the plastic instrument games all right?
Rym: I'm amazed that they're still going as strong as they are But they're definitely.
Rym: they lost a lot of steam like they don't get nearly as much Pressing plays they did a few years ago, but they're still very popular.
Scott: Yeah, it's it's weird.
Scott: It's like you figure that this would be a fad that would go away.
Scott: I think some of it.
Scott: some of the reason it hasn't gone away Is that there you know I mean it's sort of fun for everyone to do it.
Scott: But if most people get bored with it after a time, but there are some people who are just way into it, right?
Scott: So that's all right.
Rym: well much like DDR DDR reached pretty surprising highs back at the peak of DR went way up, and then it went way down.
Scott: But there was still some people who are way into it and will still do DDR forever.
Rym: there are now more DDR machines in the Midwest than there are in like California, New York combined anyway, so the plastic instrument games are sort of the same way.
Scott: But I think also they're being helped because a. they're a little bit more accessible than DDR You know and the music keeps people.
Scott: you know they keep releasing the DLCs that use people engaged and They also people invested in these plastic instruments.
Scott: a lot more people invested in those and events vested in dance pads.
Scott: So because they invested in the plastic instruments they want to keep using them And if they just sit there it makes people feel guilty yeah.
Rym: But at the same time a lot of people Claimed that the main reason the games were popular was because the rock star fantasy which is a big part of the games.
Rym: But I still maintained that the primary reason most people were playing not necessarily the hardcore fans But like the family or like that because even like people at my work like older people just have You know the cyst.
Rym: they have one of the games and they play it every now And then like when they have people over as a diversion, and I feel like they play it because It makes listening to music a more active activity.
Rym: I don't feel like many people at least in America in Current modern day listen to music as an active activity.
Rym: It's always a passive secondary active.
Scott: Yeah, it used to be that you would get your friend your hippie friends around and you would sit in a van or in your Basement whatever down by the river.
Scott: you'd put a record on and you would sit around listening to the record.
Scott: right and that would be An activity that you would do with people you know.
Rym: Go further back and the common thing to do was that the neighbors will all come together Sit around the piano someone would play a song and you'd all sing it.
Rym: yeah Well, that's singing that's different Yeah, but that was actually a very common activity among these families and people when they were bored and until you know We had records.
Scott: Yeah, but you know listening to music as an activity just listening not playing not Participating not karaoke ing not lip-syncing not writing you know it really is only sort of done in present times in this society.
Scott: at least if It's a concert right people don't or they do it as not as a group activity But as a. you constantly have music playing on your computer on your headphones, but then they're doing something else They're not really thinking about it.
Scott: Yeah, it's not.
Scott: listening to the music is not the primary activity in that case.
Rym: now at the same time There's definitely I mean people listen to a lot of music now.
Rym: And there are the audio files and the audio files And just people who are really into music who you know do that sort of thing.
Rym: still.
Rym: I mean I'll occasionally sit down and listen to an album as an activity much like I'd watch a movie.
Rym: But I feel like the music games in particular gave someone an excuse to listen like really listen to and be Participatory with in some fashion like olds that led Zeppelin that otherwise they wouldn't listen to or they'd hear a snatch of in the background On the iPod.
Scott: yeah Anyway, so the Rock Band 3 is coming out, and you know I'm sort of done with the plastic instruments.
Scott: I bought Guitar Hero 3 for the Wii.
Scott: yeah, we played it out.
Scott: You know as much as we were gonna play it.
Scott: I only have one plastic guitar.
Scott: didn't waste money on extra one.
Rym: well It amazed me like I knew I would get sick of it like I knew all right This will be fun eventually.
Scott: like it actually lasted quite a while well worth the money That was.
Rym: but it lasted far shorter than I expected About a month and a half.
Rym: then I was like yeah, and I kind of stopped doing it and then after about three months I was completely done.
Scott: I think it lasted about the amount of time I expected you know prepared to say DDR, which I'm actually playing more now than I have recently.
Scott: well I think Paul.
Scott: so part of that problem right was that we had the Wii version which did not constantly add new songs Whereas a DDR there were frequent updates that did not require changing of the equipment.
Scott: right.
Rym: well That was only because we pirated the game.
Scott: Exactly yeah, I guess we didn't pirate the Rock Band or a Guitar Hero right now And they didn't come out with more Guitar Heroes for the Wii either.
Scott: We went ahead.
Scott: if we would have started for example with Rock Band 1 on the 360 It would have basically been constantly new.
Scott: The game would just keep getting updated.
Scott: if we kept that we had kept playing it every day and actually paying attention all the new Stuff we probably would have remained hooked you know especially because it had four instruments to switch between there's a lot more value To.
Scott: you know you can play the guitar then you can play the drum then you could do the singing.
Rym: yeah But at the same time the experience was fun at first because it because it was this act.
Rym: you know we're playing on the easier modes.
Rym: I'm active and I'm engaged in the song that I'm also listening to as an activity.
Rym: and Then as I played and I started getting to the higher difficulties DDR had the physical aspect the exercise Aspect the full body movement really getting into it.
Rym: But plastic instrument games with the exception possibly of the drumming which I actually do kind of enjoy because it's kind of like real drumming Started to ring more and more hollow and just started to feel like I was really wasting my time.
Scott: Yeah, it also was you know far.
Scott: I mean DDR on stupid hard.
Scott: You can get pretty hard on DDR where it's still doable But I mean stupid hard and me in like the guitar portions is just.
Scott: it's just beyond anything.
Scott: That's worth my time to bother to master course.
Rym: we neither one of us ever mastered the ultra hard DDR either.
Rym: I mean we're like we can do maybe half the nine footers And I don't think any of us can pass more than one or two ten footers.
Scott: Yeah, but you know that's.
Scott: you know this is different.
Scott: This is like anything on the hardest mode.
Scott: forget it right?
Scott: so Anyway Rock Band 3 is coming out and one thing apparently that Rock Band 3 has is their pro mode and Apparently I was looking at pro mode and in pro mode.
Scott: well It also has a keyboard by the way.
Scott: But pro mode is actually playing a real guitar.
Scott: basically kind of they have a plastic guitar that you can buy That has a button on every single fret and every single string.
Scott: so it's number of frets times six Strings is the number of buttons they have on this thing and the buttons are long You know and thin so you can.
Scott: you know you can play guitar kind of you can play plastic guitar.
Scott: And then at the bottom they have six Partial strings.
Scott: right the strings don't go all the way up the neck.
Scott: that you're sort of.
Scott: only in the strumming area are six Strings that you can pick and whatever.
Scott: so it's sort of like it's a guitar But it's not because if you play it without Rock Band doesn't do anything.
Scott: It doesn't make any noise or anything like that.
Scott: So I'm like huh, that's actually playing guitar like you could play that thing for just 150 bucks in pro mode and learn a song And then get a real guitar and play the same exact fingerings and hand whatever and you would.
Scott: that would be it.
Scott: You're playing the song for reals.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is four hundred and fifty dollars.
Scott: You could buy a guitar.
Scott: So why would I buy a guitar that only does Rock Band when I could buy a guitar guitar well her the same money.
Rym: I don't think a lot of people.
Rym: I think have this kind of misunderstanding of how much guitars cost.
Scott: Yeah I mean like mo you know Well like if you want to buy a real guitar like the kind that you're gonna play if you're a professional That's gonna be at least a thousand dollars if not multiple thousands.
Rym: you want a guitar that kind of goes But you can e box.
Scott: you can buy an electric guitar with six strings and an amp and an amp that will work And in fact usually also with like a bag to carry it in and all kinds of you know all the stuff you need For a complete beginner that will work and serve you well to learn guitar for like a hundred bucks 150 bucks less than that right I think squire this Fender makes one and Gibson makes one and some other.
Scott: you know every guitar company pretty much has one.
Scott: That's like the entry-level Beginners electric guitar that comes in a box with an amp and the cable and everything that you need.
Scott: So if they're gonna charge 150 bucks for this thing.
Scott: It's like well screw that.
Scott: however I Saw on YouTube They are going to sell another pro guitar.
Scott: That is an Actual guitar, but it's also a rock band guitar.
Rym: How does the rock band guitar thing work though?
Rym: is it just MIDI and some sort of like?
Scott: I think what do you mean?
Rym: Like.
Rym: I wonder if I could just retrofit a real guitar to work with rock band.
Scott: Yeah, you'd probably need some sort of device to do that yeah, but that's something I could make.
Scott: Possibly you could make that device.
Scott: however They're gonna sell a guitar that basically has the device in it already.
Scott: That is also if you just don't plug it into a computer or you know a console is a guitar straight-up Completely normal in every way.
Scott: so depending on the price of that guitar I may be interested because suddenly right that that hollow Ringing is gone.
Scott: It's like hey I can actually learn to play real songs with this thing But it's also a real guitar.
Scott: that is not a complete waste of money right?
Scott: because you buy a plastic instrument like this pro guitar They're trying to sell for 150 bucks, and you get bored of rock band.
Scott: Well, you just wait you got this useless plastic guitar.
Scott: But if I buy a real guitar that also happens to play rock band.
Scott: I could buy the rock band game Play it until I'm not bored with it anymore, and then I have a real guitar.
Scott: So even if I never use it to play rock band again.
Scott: It's a guitar.
Scott: It's useful.
Scott: It's not a waste of money.
Rym: I predict a giant surge in the number of mediocre to guitar players walking into guitar center and playing stairway.
Scott: I Also agree that that will happen, but I mean it also depends right there.
Scott: charging 150 for the fit for the guitar.
Scott: that isn't a real guitar.
Scott: so you know the real ones gonna be more right.
Scott: Maybe not that much more, but if it's only like 200 250 tops I might get it.
Scott: But if it's like 300 fuck that.
Rym: I think it's gonna be pretty low because they know their demographic.
Rym: the demographic is definitely Affluent, but the demographic is not wealthy like if it's 250.
Scott: I'd be a little shaky.
Scott: I'd be like maybe I'd have to.
Scott: you know.
Scott: the thing is the song list is looking pretty good So I might go for it anyway.
Rym: Yeah, but and then it won't for 300. for 300 I just like fuck that you should buy it.
Rym: I'll come over to your place, and we'll play.
Scott: Yeah, well you go buy one.
Scott: you had to buy another one.
Scott: I'll take turns single-player I'm paying for it you pay half, and then we definitely get it even if it's 300.
Scott: But actually that would be really cool though if we had two of the real ones and played rock band We could do like wicked guitar solo, and then other paired guitar, so obviously no you got to do dueling banjos.
Scott: Oh, can we?
Scott: how awesome would that be?
Scott: that'd be the greatest right?
Scott: We had to do that if they actually came out if it was the right price.
Scott: Yeah,
Rym: yeah the thing is I think I posted in the forum But you know I was a trumpet player and then kind of half a piano player for much of my life and I I was 50/50 on going to school for technology or conservatory and At one point in high school.
Scott: Why do they call it a conservatory?
Scott: ah?
Scott: Because they do you don't know.
Rym: so at one point in high school I didn't have any classes left to take and I was really just waiting to go to college And I already took every AP class.
Rym: so I signed up for the orchestra Which was eighth period and I just never showed up to the orchestra and went home every day and the band Instructor never really noticed that I was even on his roster, so he never thought to mark me absent.
Rym: And about a month later.
Rym: He noticed and he told me that either.
Rym: I had to learn the cello or he's gonna flunk me.
Rym: And after a week of me attempting to learn the cello He set me aside and said that I have what he likes to call stupid fingers And that he never wants me to touch a stringed instrument for the rest of my life.
Rym: I then had to play the trumpet for the stupid orchestra for the rest of that year, huh?
Rym: So I don't know if I can actually play a guitar, and I don't know if anything will ever help me play a guitar.
Scott: Well, I mean I played guitar when I was in fifth grade right, and I actually was.
Scott: you know I've had this.
Scott: I could do that.
Scott: Right it's totally within my abilities.
Rym: Can you play stairway?
Scott: Hold on That was a nice stairway there, I know right you like that stairway.
Rym: the thing is or that was a phone call about football.
Rym: That's all right.
Scott: No, I mean like you know I was basically when I learned it in fifth grade.
Scott: It was like all right.
Scott: here is the book how to play guitar And it's like learn the first string learn the second string learn the thirds.
Scott: You know you'd learn one string at a time And then I got his.
Scott: you know I was progressing at a steady rate until I went to middle school and stopped To play the clarinet instead, and that was that was it.
Rym: well We'll see how you do.
Rym: I mean not to not to disparage And I watch you
Scott: if I do and I want
Rym: you to buy this game and play it and learn the guitar But the harmonica taunts you from a distance
Scott: yeah, but I mean the harmonica did not have harmonica To go with it.
Scott: so speaking of video games plus I could always just resell the shit on Amazon if it's no good.
Rym: scribble knots was a pathetic disaster of a game.
Scott: I know right that was like this greatest idea, but the fact is the actual execute.
Scott: I you know I bought it.
Scott: I paid real money for it.
Scott: the actual game was not So it's not what it.
Rym: I ignored the people who made it.
Rym: I ignored everything about it until penny arcade updated and Tycho talked about the new scribble knots game And there's a new one I'm going to quote Tycho of penny arcade super scribble knots features, and I am NOT joking about this.
Rym: Why would I joke about this?
Rym: the ability to use?
Rym: adjectives uh-huh a metal cock a Chocolate cock, but I mean okay a female cock.
Scott: so wait Can I apply any adjective to any noun?
Scott: they have every combination worked out.
Scott: probably see cuz that's the one thing actually doodle God.
Scott: You ever played doodle God.
Scott: now So doodle God is this game where basically you start out with the four?
Scott: sounds like something a five-year-old would say it's basically this Little game, it's a time waster.
Scott: It's not even a game where you have the four elements earth wind air and oh yeah Yeah, and you combine them to create new elements.
Scott: And you combine them to create new elements.
Scott: for you know until you figure out you find all the elements in the game.
Scott: the problem It doodle God is that it's really just a process of elimination.
Scott: right you just try every combination Until you you know and most of the combinations don't work.
Scott: is this?
Scott: nope that combination doesn't work.
Scott: the game would be much better if every Combination did something right
Rym: even if it did something bad like maybe Combinations that are bad hurt you or something or
Scott: maybe even if they just make the same exact thing or combinations of things you already Have like let's say person in fire makes fireman.
Scott: You know.
Scott: and then person and Magma makes well like water and snake makes a hose and the person hose also makes fireman.
Scott: You know just.
Scott: you don't need to come up with exponentially more combination things.
Rym: I Don't know why but all I can think is I got a snake man faded some beer man.
Scott: So you know the thing with doodle.
Scott: God is most combinations?
Scott: Don't do anything right.
Scott: and scribble knots had a pretty large selection of nouns.
Rym: It was pretty impressive, but the nouns were not sufficiently differentiated.
Rym: I make Zeus or Thor or Apollo and they all do the same thing.
Rym: There were really only a few things that were useful like ladder and According to YouTube there are only two things that were useful the vending machine and the handcuffs.
Rym: Uh-huh as you could beat every mission with the vending machine in the handcuffs Alrighty spot a vending machine next to the star like handcuff.
Rym: the star put it in.
Rym: take the vending machine back.
Rym: There was some dumb way.
Rym: There's a video you can watch that'll beat every single level in the game.
Scott: That's cool.
Rym: But anyway trouble with the game was that it shouldn't have like it being a puzzle game was okay But I realized the puzzles were boring and all that I cared about was making crazy shit happen.
Rym: Yeah, it should almost have been more of a sandbox.
Scott: Well.
Scott: You could you could use juice.
Scott: There was a sandbox room.
Scott: It was just this place you can go.
Scott: I think was on the home screen.
Scott: You just do anything.
Scott: There's a home screen.
Rym: yep But if they'd flesh the game out more in that regard and less in the puzzle regard and just made Interesting and crazy and wacky stuff the way to do it is multiplayer.
Scott: Yeah But it shouldn't have been online multiplayer Just been local Wi-Fi.
Scott: You know you go to this big area with some other people on a double screen and You you're both standing there, and you just do stuff.
Rym: But it's kind of like in.
Rym: taiko alluded to this and made me realize that When I played old games like quest for glory I remember the moment when I was I was trying to pick the lock.
Rym: I was like pick lock and I tried to pick a lock.
Rym: I sat there for a second And I was like hey, and I typed pick nose and it didn't just say I don't understand you it said you definitely insert the lock pick into your nose and Proceed to die of a brain hemorrhage.
Rym: you fuck wit.
Rym: yeah.
Rym: However, if your lock picking skill was high enough.
Rym: It would say congratulations.
Scott: You've successfully picked your nose Yeah, and there were little.
Rym: you have unlocked the torrent of snow As opposed to the previous torrent of blood yeah and brain.
Rym: But I feel like that was what would have made scribble knots as a raw concept.
Rym: great.
Rym: the the discovery of interesting things in Scribble knots was very very very wide But very shallow and the way they've implemented adjectives as far as I can tell is not actually any more deep.
Rym: I don't think a metal lion is any different than a wood lion.
Rym: No, it sounds like just maybe a wood lion will catch on fire, and maybe any condiment based lion can be eaten.
Scott: Yeah, it sounds like they just had a list of adjectives right like metal or wooden or whatever and they just applied.
Scott: it Looks different you know or maybe it has slightly different properties right anything wood and will set on fire You know and it's not like you actually need a wooden lion as opposed to a metal Helicopter you know to solve the puzzle any differently.
Scott: I would try to solve everything with flesh something Yeah, like you know flesh handcuffs or like you know a leaf Because they didn't even.
Rym: this is why role-playing games like to even Dungeons & Dragons Especially old D&D when the rules are kind of busted and fiddly and vague.
Rym: was that?
Rym: well I guess not.
Rym: fiddly because you do weird stuff But because you had an eye instead of an AI.
Rym: the game master would make crazy things happen.
Rym: You know many times people would cast stone to flesh.
Rym: I'm just like a wall.
Rym: Yeah, I mean it's just all right.
Rym: the entire wall is made of soft and supple flesh.
Scott: Great now what I use my sword to cut a hole in the wall that is now much softer than its former stone self.
Scott: Yeah Congratulations.
Scott: This wall is actually the edge of the dungeon and you find dirt on the other side.
Rym: Good job But I feel like there is so much potential and scribble knots barely scratched the surface Which is fine.
Rym: scratching the surface is fine, but the game is Crap, and I don't know if super scribble knots is going to.
Rym: I don't have any indication that it's going to be any less crap.
Scott: It's just another Game in the series of.
Scott: we have stuff that looks really good on the surface and it's really good novelty as a demo But isn't actually worth your money or a significant amount of time.
Scott: I feel like Lego universe.
Scott: see Batman.
Rym: Here's the thing.
Rym: remember that talk We didn't actually go to at PAX years ago that pointed out that if you have a game with a demo It actually sells much less especially small games because people get everything they wanted out of the demo.
Scott: Yeah, that's why this game doesn't have a demo.
Rym: However, the scribble knots had a demo in the sense that if you went there You're a hardcore gamer
Scott: as one is a demo and you
Rym: went to a convention You could try it out at the con and a lot of people played it at cons and were like, oh my god I'm gonna buy this game and I think the reason it worked was that it was so wide.
Rym: Play it long enough to realize how shallow was exactly.
Rym: they typed Zeus and a god appeared.
Rym: They're like, holy shit It's got everything.
Rym: and then they realize that Apollo Same God if you you people right?
Scott: It's like, you know, they say here's the thing, right?
Scott: You know, they say you got to hook someone in like the first like 30 seconds of a book, right?
Scott: So let's say I write a book and the book has a whole two chapters that are awesome But then the rest of the book is just the word fuck a hundred times and So if you get even if you give someone a demo that one awesome chapter is the demo.
Scott: So they go oh man, and they just they are really feeling they need more.
Scott: So they rush out and buy it and they read chapter 1 again.
Scott: I read chapter 2 and then off what?
Rym: All of my period exactly.
Scott: so that's the super secret.
Scott: That's what scribble knots one was was I played it a little bit then I bought it.
Scott: I played it even more and it took about 30 to 45 minutes before I was like.
Scott: Oh So now that super scribble knots is adjectives.
Scott: I'm pretty sure that it would only take me 15 to 20 minutes to exhaust that.
Scott: That'd be done.
Scott: However, I haven't played it though.
Scott: So maybe there is something extra there.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I don't think so But I don't I would predict.
Rym: not I am worryingly curious about his promise to try to install an IUD into a male shark.
Rym: Yeah, anyway anyway Things of the day, I'm sure you know, we link to College Humor a lot.
Rym: But they actually spun off a little site called dorkly.
Rym: That's the idea was and they actually they kind of announced this at PAX a while ago.
Rym: X East Yeah, the first PAX East.
Rym: Yeah that the idea was, you know College Humor is a lot of video game stuff But a lot of times it was Mortal Kombat was oh my god.
Rym: And I'm pretty sure the guy who played you out in the later years in Street Fighter the later years was at the New York Comic-con dressed as Zangief.
Rym: possibly there is no way it was not him if it was in fact not him.
Scott: Dude, Zangief.
Rym: There's a guy who looks just like you who is also dressing up as Zangief in New York City.
Rym: All righty, but they spun off dorkly with the idea that all right.
Rym: Sometimes we want to make the more Gamery joke like the joke.
Scott: Yeah, let's make a joke just like all these jokes We've been making but is so nerdy that you know, you'd have to really be a nerd to understand it.
Scott: You know a Street Fighter joke most people can sort of get it a Mario joke.
Scott: a lot of people can get that right.
Scott: but if you make a specific joke about like a specific bad guy in Ninja Gaiden 2 Then normal people are not gonna quite understand it if it's an inside joke.
Scott: It has a narrow appeal.
Scott: I even have to like Penny Arcade Even at PAX.
Rym: I have to explain what fucking Shadowgate is whenever I use that torch slide that I'm so famous for using in every panel.
Rym: Yeah, right, and I don't think many people actually recognize my I'll take you to a good place panel.
Scott: I'll take you to a good place.
Rym: So anyway my thing of the day, this is just I love I'll take you to a good place.
Rym: This is just one video, but you know, there'll be a link to all the other videos.
Rym: But Yoshi hates Mario and it's Jordan.
Rym: well done.
Scott: Yeah, so if you ever make a lot of people have been making video games.
Rym: Almost everybody right almost everybody has been making video games.
Rym: I don't believe that is in fact true.
Scott: A lot of people.
Rym: and the thing is we haven't even made video games.
Rym: one problem You made a square that could rotate around its own axis.
Scott: I've made video games before technically speaking.
Scott: I mean I made a combat a multi an ad-hoc networking multiplayer combat clone and we got an a in in a Ad-hoc networking class at RIT.
Rym: I made a pong clone.
Rym: I made a game where you tell a stick figure to sing and then he sings.
Rym: if you tell him do anything else He tries to kill you.
Scott: I've made text adventures.
Scott: I've made games that aren't really that are just sort of broken and don't do anything.
Scott: Yeah, I've met all kinds again.
Scott: Anyway, one problem.
Scott: I always had making games is making the sound effects, right?
Scott: Cuz it's like Yeah, what are you gonna do?
Scott: You're gonna get a microphone and go pew pew pew Yeah, exactly.
Rym: You usually do do, you know pull a an anime like voices of distant stars do it yourself.
Rym: Just go for it Yeah, and if your game's good, you can probably at that point trick someone else to do the sound effect.
Scott: I mean, you know The other thing you do is you get like some sort of chiptune thing.
Scott: you get the chip out of a audio chip from a Gameboy or a Commodore 64 or a Nintendo and you know, you just work that or you just emulate that shit.
Rym: Don't actually get the chip.
Scott: That's what I mean.
Scott: You can emulate it But anyway to make it even easier than that.
Scott: This guy has made something called it's at super flash brothers dotnet, but it's called the AS3 SFXR.
Scott: right and basically what it is is It's an emulation of one of those chips.
Scott: It can make a square wave a sawtooth a sine wave and a noise.
Scott: You know like, you know noise but In addition to giving you all the necessary settings to fiddle with those waves such as attack time sustain time decay time frequency slide vibrato Everything right.
Scott: phaser portamento filter low-pass filter high-pass filter repeats, you know It's got every setting you would need to make any sound that you can.
Scott: It's like a basic sin, yes, but on the side here's the great part on the left hand side There are seven buttons and the seven buttons are as follows pick up slash coin laser slash shoot explosion power up hit slash hurt jump and blip slash select.
Rym: Let me does it start you with a basic default?
Scott: No, it just know it randomly sort of with it this each one is sort of a limited parameter set, right?
Scott: So it basically says a blip slash select will have this setting between these areas and it randomly sets it between those areas.
Scott: So every time you click it it plays a different blip slash select.
Rym: noise at random, dude I'm gonna blip slash slice you right?
Scott: so if you need a jumping noise for your game just keep pushing the jump button to hear when you like and then tweak it A little bit and then push the export wave button and boom.
Scott: You've got a wave file of that jumping noise.
Rym: Not bad.
Scott: So if you're making a video game, especially a platformer that has these sort of, you know Or a shooter or any sort of game like, you know, and you want 8-bit old-school noises.
Scott: This is gonna give you all the noises you need really quickly.
Rym: I still think you're better off going with the Scottish Ava philosophy of helicopter blade helicopter blade helicopter blade Maybe if it was a poorly drawn stick figure game as opposed to a pixel.
Rym: No, I want to see a game that looks like counter-strike, but it's just pew pew pew pew pew Put put put.
Scott: Ah, no, we should make a game that looks.
Scott: we should make a game that looks like Atari combat, but sounds like fucking Star Wars in the movie.
Rym: We're not gonna make any of those things.
Rym: yeah, so meta Moment the book club book is World War Z by Max Brooks.
Rym: It's about world wars and zombies and all that shit you kids like.
Scott: Yeah, I have an additional meta.
Scott: It's probably a day too late on this but basically Malky and you know all these other people who are awesome webcomic writers the dinosaur comics guy And see I love dinosaur comics.
Scott: Yeah Matthew Bernardo Dave Malky who's of Wondermark?
Scott: and Ryan North, right?
Scott: They made this book called machine of death and It's a collection of stories about people who know how they will die?
Scott: because the machine tells them I guess And basically they had a campaign to.
Rym: I just I Imagine the book being.
Rym: every person goes to the machine and the machine says you will die by the hands of the machine and then It kills them.
Scott: That's not a suicide booth.
Scott: So this book came out and the cover price is $18, but the Amazon price is nine dollars.
Scott: No sense.
Scott: and they're having a special thing today.
Scott: They pushed really hard.
Scott: They said hey guys, let's make this the number one book on Amazon today October 26 2010.
Scott: And sure enough they did it.
Scott: It's the number one best-selling book in Amazon.
Scott: today, October 26 2010, of course Most people listen to our episode a day later because it's a night show so it'll be.
Rym: let's make it like the number eight book Tomorrow.
Scott: Yeah, but Regardless I ordered a copy.
Scott: I even paid shipping because I couldn't find anything else to get the order over $25.
Rym: I just made an Amazon order.
Scott: if you order quickly enough, it'll be added to your previous order already got shipped.
Rym: It shipped the same day.
Rym: Damn it.
Rym: Anyway, actually I made two separate orders because I also pre-ordered a bunch of stuff that I've been meaning to pre-order.
Scott: Yeah, just order a copy of machine of death.
Scott: It's probably gonna be good.
Scott: I mean, come on it's got huge awesome talents behind it, you know best webcomic writers out there among them and You know, the cover art is really good.
Rym: Also, we're gonna be at MAGFest as part of the the mag 9 also doing at least one panel on our own called losing Should be fun, which is an old classic slightly updated.
Scott: What other we do?
Rym: any other conventions Pax East Pax East We will be doing.
Rym: you should get a hopefully two panels.
Scott: You should get a hotel and a ticket today if you think you're gonna go.
Rym: Yeah I hope all the good hotels are already sold out.
Scott: You're already too late, but you can still maybe go.
Scott: kind of I don't know.
Scott: I can't really think of anything else.
Rym: That's it.
Rym: We're gonna be a free to be a Pax Prime.
Scott: Yeah, okay Be an anime Boston.
Scott: Sure Okay, so Civilization 5 we have played it enough at this point to do a show about it.
Rym: a little history.
Rym: So Civ games are some of my favorite games ever.
Rym: I probably spent more time playing Civ 2 than I've spent playing any game in my entire life With the possible exception of all counter-strikes combined.
Scott: I mean, I don't know if I can say that but I did basically Civ 1.
Scott: I played it like once or twice on a Mac at summer one.
Rym: I'd never played.
Scott: played on a Mac at summer camp once or twice and there was no instruction book and no one helped me.
Scott: So I don't even know what the hell was going on.
Rym: In fact, someone gave me Civ 2 and I didn't know what it was and I didn't have the instruction book.
Scott: I just installed this hack coffee See colonization my friend had for DOS.
Scott: I played it also once or twice didn't know what the hell was going on.
Scott: But when Civ 2 came out I went and bought like it on CD-ROM and I had a 486 and I freaking played the hell out of it.
Rym: I played Civ 2 every day and I put in my own CD.
Rym: So I would play my own music and I would just sit there playing Civ 2 for life.
Scott: I love the freaking the music.
Scott: I would try to get Leonardo's workshop.
Scott: just who would play the Leonardo's workshop music with the video?
Rym: I tried to get Leonardo's workshop because then you could upgrade all your units immediately.
Rym: I got musket men and I got workers.
Scott: I wish they still had that shit because paying money to upgrade guys is not fun.
Scott: I would get every science I could until I had to get.
Scott: It was so great because you just built a million warriors.
Scott: You got as many sciences as you could and then built Leonardo's workshop.
Rym: a Leonardo's workshop Oh my and the pyramids granaries in every granary and everything.
Scott: They were so powerful.
Rym: They weren't really that powerful.
Rym: I just didn't.
Rym: I hated having to build.
Scott: I meant I'm just saying wonders.
Scott: in general We're so much more powerful.
Scott: Oh, yeah today great.
Rym: Well, everyone has to offer.
Rym: Peace.
Scott: Yeah Hey you want this water and I have a great wall.
Scott: You have to offer me.
Scott: I don't have to build the military cuz you get attacked me.
Scott: I'll just build settlers.
Scott: we get there.
Rym: the game just had this beautiful balance between fiddliness and world-building and Abstraction that I would just play forever and it didn't really have multiplayer.
Rym: But I would play for like four six hours in a row While on the phone like a conference call with two of my friends who were all at their houses two or three friends.
Rym: They'd all be playing their own single-player games and we just be kind of sharing the narrative of our empires as we went along.
Scott: Well, I didn't do that But as we'd email save games to each other.
Scott: sieve three came out a long time later.
Scott: I was at RIT already and I bought it as soon as it came out.
Scott: I didn't buy it.
Scott: I didn't play it, but I didn't really play it all that much because I don't I just don't think it was as good.
Rym: I didn't get it.
Rym: mostly got it and he said it wasn't that good.
Scott: I mean, it was a significant improvement.
Scott: interface wise and technology wise, you know ran out of more modern computers And you know work.
Rym: it introduced a lot of interesting new mechanics.
Rym: that culture culture.
Scott: It was pretty nice and you know A lot of the things that were introduced in Civ 3 were carried on in Civ 4 and 5. but Civ 3 itself I don't I think really is sort of like the black sheep of the Civ series.
Scott: It's like nobody still plays Civ 3.
Rym: It was a missing link a progressive game between Civ 2 and Civ 4.
Rym: Yeah, Civ 4 was a masterstroke.
Scott: Yeah, Civ 4 was basically Civ 2 Plus.
Scott: this new stuff in Civ 3 play.
Scott: It was like.
Scott: it was like everything.
Scott: it was like let's put fucking every.
Scott: It's like you go to the store and you look at the board game shelf and there's that one board game that the box is Twice as big and it's 20,000 pieces.
Rym: It'll say how many pieces it has on the cover like that.
Scott: Yeah, something that's it for Civ 4 has fucking every possible thing Imaginable.
Rym: there was a time where I played Civ 4 for my like every train ride I had in both directions every day.
Scott: Yeah, I mean I basically I played some Civ 4.
Scott: I got into the game late.
Scott: I waited until Steam, you know, I mean it came out a while ago But I didn't buy it until Steam had it for way cheap and a huge bundle.
Rym: Yeah You played a couple of games with us because you wanted to get back into Civ and we all knew Civ 5 was coming.
Scott: So I didn't want to kill too much time.
Scott: And the thing is Civ 4 was pretty much like it was Civ 2 plus Civ 3 plus even more.
Scott: That was what it was and it was you know, it was great at what it was.
Scott: But at this point in my life, I like I wasn't feeling that not because it was bad but because Like you basically it had this, you know The fundamental things going on did not fit with what I was looking for in gaming, right?
Scott: It's like you had to build a million units and manage them all.
Scott: and because it has everything It's like you got to worry about the religion and you got to worry about You know your money and you got to worry about the taxes and you got to.
Scott: and I was just like.
Scott: I do not have The time for this I'm trying to.
Scott: I am, you know busy doing all this other stuff in my life.
Scott: I don't have time for Civ 4.
Rym: I still enjoy it and I still say, you know You want the short version of our review.
Rym: Civ 4 will continue to be a relevant game because Civ 5 is Not a replacement.
Rym: It is a different game.
Scott: It is definitely a different game and you know, both are good games.
Scott: But I think that Civ 5 has a place in my life that where Civ 4 does not.
Rym: Civ 5 is a revolution not to be Confused with civilization revolutions, which is baby Civ.
Scott: Yeah I have Civ Rev on my phone and I had it for the DS but it got stolen.
Rym: It's a little baby game.
Scott: It's a little baby game, but it's great to play like on your phone.
Scott: It's not good.
Scott: I don't know why you would get it for the Xbox or the PC.
Rym: Nah, but like I got.
Rym: I got a city I got an army unit the army units gonna go capture the barbarian.
Scott: Yeah But I mean actually I think one good thing they took from Civ Rev and put into Civ 5 was the better interface because Civ Rev Definitely had a far superior user interface to any previous Civ.
Rym: Civ 4 was pretty good.
Rym: It was okay But Civ 2 was actually great.
Rym: It was just cluttered looking but it was very usable.
Scott: Yeah, I think Civ 5 really has it down, right?
Scott: Cuz I mean Civ 5. a lot of people came to it from Civ 4 and like oh This is so.
Scott: this is like they're like it's.
Scott: it's only slightly more than Civ Rev.
Scott: It's like baby Civ with a little bit of stuff on it, but that's not true I don't think.
Scott: Civ 5 actually I think is just as you know, it doesn't have as much stuff But it's just as you know full of a game as any of the non rev Civs.
Scott: The thing is is they've simplified the user interface so much that it's just so much easier.
Scott: Well, you know you don't open up the city screen and see like a hundred icons of wheat and can't figure it out.
Scott: It said instead there's a green number that's like plus five food.
Rym: This is the kind of fundamental change and there are a bunch of articles saying basically the same thing so you've probably seen them.
Rym: but Civ 5 is more like a Good German style board game done with a complexity that a computer allows.
Rym: Then it is Civ 4 which was more like a world building simulation game.
Rym: Yeah, and while they both serve both purposes the fundamental difference in Civ 5 not that they changed to hexes or any of that it's that every decision you make every little thing you can do like if you zoom in all the way and Micromanage everything every individual decision matters a huge
Scott: amount.
Rym: Oh, yeah in Civ 4 the really zoomed in stuff did not matter that much unless you were trying to win like crazy Circumstances.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, I mean it's not so much the hexes right but it's the one unit per square.
Scott: Every unit is really valuable.
Scott: It took you like eight maybe you know, 14 turns to make that guy and every turn is a huge deal.
Scott: Right, and now if he dies, oh shit, right?
Scott: You just lost a unit.
Rym: or look at buildings instead of for build every goddamn building.
Rym: That's fast as you can.
Scott: every.
Scott: every Civ 1 through 4.
Scott: It was build every building you can as fast as you can while also somehow Having one city that only builds barracks and cranks out military units.
Scott: Yeah, but in Civ 5 you don't need to build every building.
Scott: You only need to build the buildings you need because the maintenance cost of that building is gonna bring you down Whereas, you know, you could deal with the maintenance cost in the earlier civs Yeah, but every building now does something that really matters.
Rym: like you build a granary plus two food Oh two food, holy shit, and it wasn't.
Scott: you know, you look at what some of the buildings did in the previous civs For example aqueduct right you they don't even have aqueduct anymore.
Scott: But it was like you need an aqueduct to grow your city beyond X and then in Civ 4 it was.
Scott: it reduces pollution Yeah, but now it's Listen, none of these buildings you need.
Scott: you don't need any of them.
Scott: You can choose to build them if you want to right.
Scott: so it's like do I need happiness?
Scott: Yes I'm minus three happiness.
Scott: Well, how can I decrease happiness?
Scott: I can get rid of a city.
Scott: I can decrease population.
Scott: somehow.
Rym: I think there should be more ways to get and lose happiness.
Rym: the one one or I can Try to reassign.
Scott: I can stop growing to maybe, you know before I get unhappy to prevent unhappiness.
Rym: Well, one thing that is pointedly missing from this is argue build a colosseum.
Rym: is unhappiness due to continuing to be at war?
Rym: Mmm, there's no penalty from just staying at war with someone for as long as you want to stay at war with them.
Rym: Yeah, in fact sometimes being at war makes you guys happier Yeah, but all that aside would like think about the with happiness, too.
Rym: They've made it a game where different styles of empires are much more viable Like one really big city with a bunch of satellite cities works because things like the economy and happiness are global Variables of the sieve.
Rym: it's not like this.
Rym: city's happy and this city's unhappy and I got to deal with all that bullshit.
Rym: It's my Empire's ex happy.
Rym: Yep, which made the game a lot more fun.
Rym: I will say straight up It makes it so much more easier to manage - it's it also made it less of a boolean thing.
Scott: We're liking simple hover over that happy face.
Scott: This is user interface stuff, right?
Scott: You hover over the happy face with your mouse and it tells you where all of your happiness points are coming from and where?
Scott: You're spending all your happiness points and that one little area.
Rym: It's it forward to that - it's really clear that for did that - but this is so much more clear.
Rym: But it was person was you hover over.
Rym: it was like plus five due to X plus two due to Y per city though This is for your whole city.
Scott: This is for your whole sieve.
Scott: You can just see all your happiness in a little square.
Scott: It's all see all your whole economy in this little.
Rym: it's also no longer a boolean state of like up.
Rym: now They're unhappy.
Rym: all the bullshit happens.
Rym: you're get unhappy which just slows down the growth rate.
Rym: Yep, and then you've got angry which is now there's trouble big trouble.
Scott: But yeah, I mean that's the one thing right that we've always complained about is with a lot of board games Right is we say oh man, this board game is a pretty good game Maybe but it's got too many fiddly bits.
Scott: Twilight struggle the Twilight struggle Twilight struggle I mean Twilight or even if a game is not a good game or it doesn't matter but it has a big setup time.
Scott: We got to set up all these pieces, you know, it takes so long to set it up.
Scott: I don't want to play it or I'll got the game takes.
Rym: All right, even Puerto Rico when we set it up They're like, oh, it's already set up.
Rym: We might as well play it four or five more times.
Scott: If five is that it's a German board game that is more complex than any German board game that you can buy on the shelves.
Scott: But because they use a computer instead of making you fiddle with pieces It totally works and because the user interfaces are streamlined you can process all that information.
Scott: You know, even if you're not You don't have a huge brain now.
Rym: Thus a fundamental for me at least like gameplay mechanism design aspect that I've noticed as I've played and I'm sure other people have noticed It too and I think it derives heavily from this kind of board game style design the idea that every decision should matter that you know Even little decisions come out over time and it's not just this kind of momentum thing of you know I build this and build this and build this.
Rym: I have to follow this progression everywhere all this fiddliness.
Rym: I Really?
Rym: try to win which is weird because in sieve - I never Tried to win like I'm going to win the game.
Rym: Yeah victory conditions.
Scott: I played because I just fucking like playing and so for one sieve - there were really only a couple ways to win Right is?
Scott: you could win with the UN voting, right?
Scott: You could win with score at the end of the game.
Rym: I don't think could win the game in sieve - you could.
Scott: you could win with the spaceship and you could win by just killing Everybody.
Scott: yeah in sieve 3 they added like a cultural victory sieve 4.
Rym: I had a bunch of victory conditions.
Scott: They're now they still.
Scott: they still have a bunch, you know, they have the cut that you can build.
Rym: Here's the big difference.
Rym: when I played sieve 4 I would just play to make my awesome Empire and then midway through the game.
Rym: I'd get to the mode.
Rym: We're alright, maybe I'll try to win.
Rym: what victory conditions I go for in sieve 5?
Rym: against the computer or against humans?
Rym: every round I'm thinking how am I going to win?
Rym: Oh, yeah, how am I going to win the game in the end?
Scott: Absolutely.
Rym: Am I going for culture?
Rym: Well, I got to do this.
Rym: What am I going to do to win?
Rym: I my brain Literally shifts into board game mode every second that I'm playing.
Rym: I've started.
Scott: I've just started playing the game in the in the hex view.
Rym: I don't because my video card is not up to the challenge.
Scott: Well, you can't.
Scott: the hex mode is easier on the video card.
Rym: No, the hex mode actually gives me more trouble.
Rym: really cuz I'm my last hope they gave me more trouble.
Rym: I just installed an Nvidia update that I didn't realize I hadn't installed.
Rym: I have not tried again.
Scott: But see I and my computer.
Scott: I desktop at home with a new video card.
Scott: I can play in either mode No problem, but on my laptop and with the integrated Intel piece of crap, right?
Scott: I play in DirectX 9 mode with the hexes and there's some grant.
Scott: There's some graphical glitches, but it's totally smooth and it doesn't interfere with the game.
Rym: See I tried it once with it when I was like one driver behind in Nvidia Which actually does fix some important things for sieve.
Rym: If you if you're having any trouble with sit five at all Go get the newest Nvidia drivers like seriously or whatever driver your video card is But specifically with Nvidia.
Rym: the most recent Nvidia drivers fix very specific issues.
Scott: that very if you're a gamer If you're a gamer of any kind, you need to upgrade your video card driver all the time.
Scott: Yes However, there's a new one.
Rym: There was a time when that wasn't true when I had my creative graphics blaster extreme I Upgraded the driver and that actually caused a serious problem with quake.
Scott: Anyway, no, let's talk about some of the things that yeah, I don't like in Civ 5.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So one thing I don't like is that the multiplayer first of all technologically has some issues, right?
Rym: Players always had issues.
Scott: What the fuck?
Rym: Why can't it spy?
Rym: Listen, I why?
Rym: games fine.
Scott: They're not using you So they're using steam.
Rym: the game spy logo is still there.
Scott: I don't know why the game spy logo is there because it completely uses steam for everything.
Rym: I'll bet under the hood.
Rym: He uses games five bullshit.
Scott: It possibly does which is bullshit.
Scott: And again, why?
Rym: why the fuck?
Rym: game spies terrible?
Scott: Yeah, but regardless whether it's game spy or not.
Scott: They're networking just doesn't really work.
Scott: The game is slow.
Scott: Why do they fucking fuck up networking?
Rym: Why do they turn off all the animations by default?
Rym: There's no real.
Rym: that's not what's slowing down the network play.
Scott: the network plays slow because your networking code is shitty.
Rym: Why does the game continuously just say I'm gonna restart and Everyone who's ever making a networked game.
Scott: You have to make the network code first.
Rym: hire an IT guy I don't know.
Scott: hire valves guys because Val games always fucking work.
Scott: Yeah, Darwin multi-winning it.
Scott: That was a game that got fucked up by bad networking.
Rym: Well also by the fact that they didn't have invert mouse by me.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean there are just so many games, you know, and s2 was having huge networking problems.
Scott: I think they've tweeted recently.
Scott: They finally figured out what I said.
Rym: No network problems at all.
Scott: Yeah valve never has networking problems.
Scott: counter-strike perfect.
Rym: Here's the amazing thing that really bothers me counter-strike and left for dead.
Rym: our real-time FPS is where it really matters.
Rym: on the latency.
Scott: This is a turn-based game here.
Scott: Yeah, dudes Another thing that bothers me in multiplayer, even when it works simultaneous the simultaneous mode, you know what I found out according to Asking a question on the gaming equivalent of Stack Overflow.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: It's apparently whoever clicks first goes.
Scott: Yes That's why I always bullshit.
Rym: Well, here's the problem.
Rym: Sieve for and before you could turn on or off Simultaneous turn-taking.
Rym: I didn't look to see if you can do it.
Scott: Here's the problem.
Scott: If you don't have simultaneous turn-taking I basically to wait for all you fuckers to take your turns in sequence.
Rym: Not only that but say I went first I will always go before you.
Rym: Yep, that'll matter when we're close to each other.
Scott: Maybe yeah, but the thing is it only matter like let's.
Scott: the thing is once the game gets going Let's say I attack you first.
Scott: Okay Well now I'm even though you went first.
Scott: you always have a turn and you know ahead of me in terms of how much stuff You've made in the entire game.
Scott: I'm sort of I have the initiative in the combat.
Scott: So I've you know, I attacked first.
Scott: It's not I'm always.
Scott: you're always gonna be reacting because I'm always going before you.
Scott: they could do something along lines of power grid Right where the the turn order is shuffled.
Scott: Yeah, everyone takes a turn and then we reshuffle the turn order.
Scott: what I would actually get two turns in a row.
Rym: I would have a hybrid mode where the game would be simultaneous turns all the time unless quote it matters.
Rym: Yeah Define situations where it matters like say
Scott: if you're
Rym: at war and any unit you have is within range of Being able to interact with any unit with the people you're at war with and maybe a whole bunch of other Situations like anywhere around a ruin where there's anyone within range of it all that stuff.
Rym: Then you switch into some sort of turn-based mode for movements and movement only.
Scott: Here's a here's an interesting question, right?
Scott: Let's say theoretically speaking right you are one turn away from completing the utopia project.
Scott: You as soon as you click next turn on that turn I click next turn first.
Scott: No, let's say you click next turn and on that next turn you will have won the game with cultural victory.
Scott: Let's say also for instance on the exact same turn Well, I'm one turn away from launching my spaceship on the next turn.
Scott: when I click next turn that turn after that My spaceship will have reached Alpha Centauri and I'll have won the game.
Rym: Yeah, you know what the answer is.
Rym: Fuck you I don't know.
Rym: It's gonna be terrible.
Rym: It's gonna break and we're not gonna know and some randomly Listen.
Scott: guys, you have to make multiplayer the priority here, right?
Scott: You know you have to think of multiplayer first and design the game around Multiplayer.
Scott: right because as it stands single-player multiplayer completely different games that I've almost nothing to do with each other.
Scott: Yep, and it's kind of bullshit.
Scott: I don't like it.
Rym: Yes me granted That is not why your entire collapsed in our recent multiplayer game.
Rym: Well, I mean because a quote my military advisor I think I saw Egypt's only military unit.
Rym: It looked lonely.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: I did have few units however, I would have Done a lot significantly better right if the simultaneous thing had not happened, right?
Rym: Yes, you would have.
Rym: you would have it would I would still have because because the military you were fighting against my Advisor said the same thing about him is his military was larger than mine.
Scott: But the different the thing was is my military was largely comply.
Scott: I was Egypt.
Scott: I mostly had the horse Archer Egypt guys who are ranged attacking units.
Scott: I am I. they were hiding behind some warriors and some spearmen and if I had been able to go first I could have Launched my range attacks doing significant damage to his guys before being rushed.
Scott: as it stands.
Scott: He rushed me and these units were basically completely useless if they get attacked.
Scott: So he just killed the guys before they had any chance to shoot.
Scott: So even you know meaning that it totally mattered.
Scott: and but because of simultaneous turns he clicked first.
Rym: So the option is always cue up move movements before you end your turn for the next turn.
Scott: Yeah, but I you know, it was.
Rym: I know it's bullshit.
Scott: It's bullshit.
Rym: It doesn't matter me or Scott Johnson They're gonna win that game.
Scott: Anyway, it doesn't matter.
Rym: Anyway, of course I do like the thing where domination victory and this is so board gamey only the capitals matter Because then you can get into situations where like in the game we're playing Scott's dead and icon and it's me and Scott Johnson.
Rym: I have like two massive empires and then Alex has a pretty good Empire he's conquering the rest of Scott's and consolidating.
Rym: if scojo and I go to war the two big like world empires and We end up taking both of each other's capitalism point Alex just wins.
Rym: Yeah, I like that.
Rym: that dynamic makes the game interesting Mmm, even though it's not necessarily realistic.
Scott: Oh, no, it's not realistic, but it's a German board game kind of thing, which I like.
Rym: Yeah, also Everyone's fears that the game's military would devolve into advanced wars are true But it's not who says devolve.
Scott: I think that's it.
Rym: Oh, yes, but it's true in that I've never lost a military conflict with anyone.
Scott: Yeah in any play multi kind of it's kind of sad and single-player.
Scott: if you don't turn up the difficulty to give the computer And even if you do their militaries are pitiful like it they'll declare war on me.
Scott: I'll have like because I you know They basically the computer declares war on you if you're too weak and you have good stuff that they want.
Scott: So you just huddle like four good units around where they're attacking.
Scott: they attack in one spot.
Scott: Maybe you have a great general out there Maybe even have it build a citadel.
Scott: you can basically hold off waves and waves of units unless they're significantly better.
Rym: Oh, oh, oh unrelatedly remember we were arguing about the benefits of the culture bomb.
Rym: culture bomb Citadel.
Rym: Oh I realized that ten seconds ago.
Rym: Oh shit.
Scott: Oh, man They know culture bombs are actually the problem.
Scott: reason I don't use that.
Scott: the problem with the culture bomb right is like I want to use it and if I'm at war someone I'll totally use it.
Scott: but it's like The time that I get a great artist.
Scott: I've probably we've already pushed our cultural borders right up next to each other right and there's no empty space.
Scott: So a culture bomb will get me some hexes, which is pretty good But it'll only get me hexes from someone I don't necessarily want to go to war with right now.
Rym: Let's go to war anyway, because as I've learned in single-player just declare war on the entire world.
Rym: There's nothing they can fucking do to you.
Rym: Yeah As long as you have advanced war skills.
Scott: Yeah, if you but you have to also build a military right if you'd build nothing but wonders and buildings You're gonna get crushed.
Rym: Yeah, if you're Gandhi, I like how Gandhi's really peaceable.
Rym: every game I see him and he's super nice to me and we're really friendly and we cooperate and trade and once he's got a Gigantic city full of wonders.
Rym: I conquer it like immediately and it's awesome But I feel bad and he really he rubs it in after you conquer him He's like, well, I hope you're happy having conquered a peaceful civilization with nothing but good intentions for you.
Rym: Yeah, and I feel bad for a minute and then I look at my wonders and you look at your score.
Scott: Yeah I'm gonna win this game.
Scott: That's that is.
Scott: one thing though That I think is a. perhaps the negative in Civ 5 is the military play is actually much better Because you don't have to manage it.
Scott: It's not about who has most units.
Scott: It's actually about moving the units.
Scott: It's about Rym wins Yeah, but the problem is is that military pretty much dominates everything else or I was going to win.
Rym: I've had two games where this happened.
Rym: I said I'm gonna go for culture victory.
Rym: I was going for culture victory like the whole game and I'm near culture victory like five to 20 turns from guaranteed cultural victory and I look and realize that I Can just go conquer like two capitals right now because the game in the game I'm playing right?
Scott: I'm trying out the new Genghis Khan, right?
Scott: He's got awesome mounted units.
Scott: So I got all these mounted units and a great general and some musket men marching around.
Scott: just I totally took Arabia.
Scott: I took every city they have except for one that's on the other side of Napoleon.
Scott: So then I made peace with them.
Rym: No you make peace with and then you get open.
Rym: game Is he march over?
Scott: hold on.
Scott: Genghis Khan has like 25% bonus of city-state.
Scott: So I can't.
Scott: I conquered every nearby city-state and the best thing is I puppeted them all.
Scott: I didn't actually annex anything.
Rym: Puppet everything cuz there's no penalty.
Scott: Yeah, who wants to freakin actually bother managing any?
Rym: unless you want to do military stuff I just puppet everything.
Scott: Yeah, if you want you can add you can switch from puppet to annex.
Rym: That's what I'm saying puppet everything and then later only like when you suddenly need to do something specific It's the only time you should ever annex.
Scott: Yeah, or I always annex capital Annex, make sure you do when you have a pile of money so you can get a courthouse.
Scott: Ah, yep Mad important anyway, but then I go and I check and I'm looking at the advisor menu And it says I'm looking at how strong everyone is and it's like Washington is on the other side of the world.
Scott: I just discovered him with my caravel.
Scott: It's like yeah, don't even fuck with Washington Yeah, and then but I look and Napoleon who's pretty much the only person sharing the content with me now Continent with me at this point.
Scott: It's like yeah, Napoleon's weak-ass.
Scott: You should go rape him.
Scott: I'm like Napoleon's Empire is three times the size of mine and I have like these five units.
Scott: They have been upgraded like crazy because they've been killing big destroyed.
Rym: It amazes me how a couple of horsemen and some like bowmen used effectively can take out entire empires.
Scott: Yeah, it's like they're just so experienced from getting all these upgrades.
Scott: I basically have every single upgrade that gives you plus if you have for on open terrain and then I've got plus 25%.
Scott: Mongo, you know plus 25%.
Scott: I have like a hundred plus 25% Plus.
Scott: they're near a great general plus another 25 and those stack on top of each other is basically like I shoot a guy.
Scott: Cuz the the the special unit as you know range attack the Keshiks.
Scott: Yeah, the Keshik is array as shoots arrows at guys from his horses.
Scott: Just boom any unit.
Scott: just shoot him with hours dead Right, so I'm like I'm gonna as soon as I load this game up I'm just gonna March these six guys over towards Napoleon and I'm gonna take over this.
Scott: I tired gigantic continent.
Scott: And basically the way the computer fights they'll send all the units after you.
Scott: So you have to actually have some extra units to begin with to fight off their army and as soon as you destroy their army Basically, they spit out one unit every few turns and you just go city to city.
Scott: You just go city to city puppet.
Rym: But it's only hard to take them if there's two cities within range of each other and they start double bombarding.
Scott: you know.
Scott: Yeah I hate that.
Rym: Usually I'll.
Scott: that is.
Scott: another thing that I really love about the game is that you used to have to build a spear man in Every city and then upgrade into a pikeman upgrade until musket upgrade, right?
Rym: Sometimes I'm sieve for even in multiplayer I just forget about a couple of you have to have multiple Johnson marches in with cavalry and I'm like, whatever my inventory will take care.
Rym: Oh my pikemen are not gonna take care of that.
Scott: I forgot to upgrade that.
Scott: I forgot to have enough guys in that city.
Scott: I forgot to upgrade the guys in that city.
Scott: now you can only have one unit in a city.
Scott: Anyways, you don't have to worry about.
Scott: Oh, I didn't have enough right but a city can defend itself.
Scott: It's even if you don't have any guys near the city.
Scott: It can shoot and do wicked damage and if it has walls or something It's gonna be pretty hard for them to just take your city.
Scott: They can't just sneak over with like the weak-ass military unit all in his own and just take your city because you left it empty.
Scott: Right, they actually have to attack a city with at least three or four guys to take it from you or to Companion cavalry.
Scott: it takes more than a turn to do it.
Scott: They can't just sneak in and snatch an entire city, right?
Scott: That's pretty unrealistic too, right?
Scott: Like there's a whole big city here and a tiny group of military guys just walk into the city and now it switches countries also.
Rym: No spies, I can't just go buy an enemy city.
Scott: Oh, yeah Oh, that's that glad they took that out right.
Scott: that sort of just was sort of annoying and fiddly to have spies.
Rym: Yeah You know I think I'll add it back in because one thing I really look forward to and I think this is going to be But this game is going to be the replacement for Civ 4. when Civ 5 I thought you said it wasn't.
Rym: When Civ 5 gets its equivalent of the Beyond the Sword expansion because that added Everything to Civ 4 and imagine Civ 5 with all that stuff just crammed into it Oh, yeah, that'd be pretty good.
Rym: other rider weird complaints.
Rym: I wish you could do more with city-states like trick them Independent ones into declaring war on people or make them like yeah I wish there's also more ways to gain favor with them.
Rym: Yeah just money or quests.
Scott: you can give them money or you can wait for them to randomly have a quest and Sometimes the quest is a huge pain in the ass, right?
Scott: Like someone on the other side of the world to be like, hey make a road to me and I'm like, no I'm like, you know how far that is?
Scott: You know how much I would have to pay for that fucking road?
Scott: Fuck you and tires just like yeah, whatever It's not worth it to get like 25 favor with you.
Scott: That's gonna run out pretty soon.
Scott: Anyway, yeah Just you know, maybe you'll give me a military unit or maybe you'll give me a few turns.
Rym: That's why I think a modern expansion.
Scott: when I could just say I get it upon city-states Why why would I make a road to you or kill barbarians for you when I could just conquer you with four military units?
Scott: Yeah, like three turns and then you'll give me everything you've got.
Rym: You know a lot of times they give you far less culture if you conquer them than if they're a cultural city-state and you Pay them.
Scott: I know right but then I had to pay freaking money.
Scott: Yeah, it's not worth it.
Rym: I also don't like I have to keep paying the money a lot of it all the time If this was a conscious decision on the designers part or just a mistake.
Rym: But how come whenever I tell a unit to go anywhere?
Rym: That's more than like a direct path.
Rym: like I click over a distance.
Rym: They will go way the fuck out of their way to go through enemy territory to go through city-state territory.
Rym: They'll embark like ten times on all.
Rym: they take the worst possible paths.
Scott: Yeah, they're not too good with the hex pathing.
Scott: the worst is if there's a road near a guy He'll like go out of his way like an extra hex to use the road.
Scott: It's like I have to tell him how to move one hex at a time to get the right way.
Rym: You'd think all right, maybe he did that because that's a more optimal path.
Rym: No, it never is.
Scott: no.
Rym: or worse the city-states.
Rym: There are two paths that are completely equal in cost.
Rym: He'll go through the city-state pissing it off.
Scott: I think what they need to do in their algorithm from what I can tell is Basically, it does a shortest path in terms of cost, right?
Scott: So it's like, okay It'll cost you three movement points to get here And if you want way and three if you go that way It doesn't.
Scott: what he needs to do is it also needs to pick the path that will use the fewest hexes.
Scott: Okay, these two paths from A to B are cost three movement points.
Scott: this one is two hexes.
Scott: This one is five hexes.
Scott: use the two hex one.
Scott: Not the five hex one.
Rym: That maybe one of them is more defensive and one of his more.
Rym: but then again if you want it if you care You'll go.
Rym: do it turn by turn.
Rym: Yeah The real trouble is why do they take they should wait city-state occupied territories that aren't allies Slightly negatively.
Rym: So my guys don't always wander in you have to build.
Scott: Oh, that's true.
Scott: Yeah, I mean like unless you're a reality.
Scott: that's one advantage like.
Scott: I hate.
Scott: it's sort of like one of those things I hate and I like right.
Scott: there are games that have annoyances.
Scott: there's a lot of games that just have annoyances and there are bonuses you can get in those games that do nothing but remove the Annoyance, they don't actually give you a bonus to winning like in those Final Fantasy 6 wearing the item That doesn't give you a bonus.
Rym: It just lets you walk fast.
Scott: Yeah, exactly, right?
Rym: It's like a bike in Pokemon.
Scott: This doesn't actually Give you any power in terms of winning and losing or any victory points or anything like that.
Scott: All it does is make the game more convenient to play.
Scott: It's like You should just give that for free to everybody.
Scott: Oh the game will be a lot more convenient if you didn't have to click this checkbox every turn.
Scott: Well, we're gonna.
Scott: here's a bonus that takes this annoyance away.
Scott: It's like it doesn't how everyone has the ability to click the checkbox every turn.
Scott: Everyone's gonna do it to make sure that they win but one guy just doesn't have to remember to click.
Scott: It's bullshit, right?
Rym: That you should not be things like that Game at all like the the the stuff not moving military units through city-states without pissing them off.
Rym: I like that mechanic.
Scott: Oh, yeah, but Alexander the Great has this thing where it's basically like oh, yeah be him.
Scott: So you don't do what you can just set your guys on auto-explore and not have to worry about them trespassing and everybody Yeah, but then everyone else has to manually move all the units.
Scott: that power really is.
Rym: I Also, once I've paid a city-state they stay mine for a long freaking time.
Scott: No, there's two different powers.
Scott: They're the same power.
Scott: No, he has a separate power, which is he can't trespass.
Rym: now They're under the same power.
Rym: There are two separate effects of you know, plus it's not that the trespassing doesn't happen It's that the problems caused by go back to normal at a rate.
Scott: That's faster Oh, I thought.
Scott: I thought it was that trust you just didn't no one cared.
Rym: if you dress bad You move towards zero faster from negative and towards zero slower from positive.
Scott: I thought that was what you get if you actually use the the social.
Scott: Oh, man, that's something I like a lot the friggin social Stuff that what you use your culture points to buy.
Scott: Yeah, the policies cuz frickin it It's all the other sieve games.
Scott: You had to change your governments and your religion and all that stuff and you had to go into Anarchy to do it and that was just so fiddly and bleh, but now the social policies.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: it's like.
Scott: just.
Rym: however, I did enjoy the mix-and-match nature of Civ 4.
Rym: We're like, I'm this but I'm also this and in Civ 5 is definitely more of a progressive thing.
Rym: It's more like an alternate additional tech tree.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Well, it's like getting.
Scott: it's like building buildings in Puerto Rico.
Scott: Yeah It's so board gamey.
Scott: I love that.
Rym: I do enjoy it.
Scott: I just I feel like they can expand upon it and it's so much easier to handle and it's so much easier to think about.
Scott: The user interface of the screen it lets you pick is so much more obvious what each one does and why you know, yeah It's good stuff.
Rym: We should probably wrap this up it.
Scott: I suffice it to say if you're not playing Civ 5 What the fuck the game is awesome.
Rym: It is fantastic.
Rym: It's not a Civ 4 replacement, but it is a game for all time.
Rym: I love it.
Rym: Single-player is a joke.
Rym: Don't think that that will prepare Multiplayer.
Scott: problem is if you put single-player on hard, right?
Rym: It's not that the AI is good.
Rym: is that the edge cheats?
Scott: Yeah, the AI.
Scott: just.
Scott: basically though if you put it on the hardest mode they start with like Extra war.
Scott: they start with like three settlers five workers and you know, it's like they just start with a huge head start.
Scott: It's not fair And they don't.
Scott: the AI is not any better.
Scott: So if you actually manage to catch up to their head start with your military, you just conquer them just as easily.
Scott: They're not any smarter at it.
Scott: They just have more big head start.
Rym: Yep, and I look forward to playing with all of you because multiplayer games in this because everyone's trying to win really hard and because you Can't have the chump.
Rym: Oh, I lost my city.
Rym: They're actually really fun if you get past these shit that code the simultaneous turn bullshit and The fact that is randomly gonna crash or like move Scott City one tile to the left Even though I don't really know it moved it really.
Rym: I don't know if that happened or not.
Scott: I swear to god I'm lying to you.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Why would I lie about that?
Rym: I don't know but it seems Literally all of a sudden Scott's like my city moved It's all the way over there now and my guy moved too and all of us are fine.
Rym: We're like, what the fuck Scott it moved.
Scott: Anyway, I'll draw you a map if you want.
Rym: Yes, if I'm this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web Design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.