Rym: It's Monday, September 12th, 2011.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott.
Scott: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, the tech news that wasn't.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: I'm at BK on Sunday and...
Scott: How many pirates did you have with them?
Scott: Nine?
Rym: Nine pirates with like eight hit points each.
Scott: If you just level up a little bit they can't touch you.
Rym: Nine hit points, Scott.
Rym: I'm saying I can beat those pirates at level two.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: In fact I was playing Final Fantasy 1 the other day.
Rym: You know why?
Scott: Why?
Rym: I leveled because Emily never seen it.
Rym: Like the original real deal one without any of the gimping or the graphic remakes or anything.
Rym: And I realized some things that are now quite archaic.
Rym: You realize most people have never seen the words "hold reset while you turn off the
Rym: power.".
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But yeah, level two is all you need to be to beat Garland.
Scott: Yeah, all to beat Garland, yeah.
Rym: And the pirates?
Rym: Way weaker than Garland.
Scott: Yeah, you think so?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: There's a lot of them, though.
Rym: You're guaranteed to kill three of them on the first round.
Scott: Oh, that's right, because you're all fighter, fighter, red mage, whatever.
Rym: I either play fighter, fighter, red mage, white mage, because black mage actually kind of sucks and magic actually kind of sucks later in the game like that.
Rym: Or fighter, black belt, red mage, white mage.
Rym: Or fighter, fighter, black mage, white mage.
Rym: Any one of those combinations is awesome.
Scott: I like to do fighter, black belt, black mage, white mage.
Scott: I'm not a red mage fan.
Rym: See, the thing is the red mage is pretty damn good because the mid-game is when you need all those spells.
Rym: You need to be able to cast lit two a bunch.
Scott: Yeah, but the point is would you rather at the end of the game would you rather have the red mage or the black mage?
Rym: The black mage is completely useless at the end of the game because whatever his spells are they're nothing compared to the damage a fighter or a black belt does.
Rym: That's right.
Rym: So really the best party would be fighter, fighter, white, well, fighter, red mage, white mage, white mage.
Rym: No.
Rym: I beat the game with that party.
Scott: Why don't you beat the game then with fighter, fighter, black belt, white mage?
Rym: Because I want, you need black magic in the early to mid-game.
Rym: Lit two on the boat is critical.
Scott: Right, and what I'm saying is even though the black mage, the magic is weak in the end game, right?
Scott: The black mage's black magic will be slightly better at the end game than the red mage's black magic.
Rym: No, it doesn't matter because it's the difference at the end game.
Rym: The red mage does more damage with his fucking sword than the black mage will ever do.
Scott: I don't know about that.
Rym: Scott, I played the ever-living fuck out of Final Fantasy 1 when I was a kid.
Scott: The red mage sword is not really that good.
Scott: I've beaten it more than ten times from scratch.
Rym: In fact, you know who I give the fucking Masamune to?
Scott: The white mage because you're...
Rym: No, the white mage has Thor's hammer.
Rym: The white mage doesn't attack anyway.
Scott: I know that.
Scott: I'm just trying to be...
Rym: Give it to the thief.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Who uses the fucking thief at all?
Scott: No, it's like we were arguing over here about like changing, right?
Scott: It's like no one uses thief.
Scott: Who uses thief?
Rym: Nobody.
Rym: The first time I played the game, not knowing any better, I used the thief because I was like, "Oh, he can totally run away and I can avoid
Rym: fights.".
Rym: Then I didn't level up and then...
Scott: The thief can't do anything.
Rym: No, he can wield the... There's one weapon he can wield.
Scott: Great.
Rym: Anyway, that weapon you don't get it till the end of the game.
Rym: Oh, he can cast some shitty like first and second level black magic when he's a ninja.
Scott: Awesome.
Rym: So, now I got a bike.
Rym: Well, I ordered a bike and, you know, my bike got stolen a while ago, so just got to buy a new bike.
Rym: and I realize now buying a bike in the fall is kind of awesome because much like cars, higher-end bikes have model years and they're trying to get rid of the 2011 model.
Scott: Well, you did the same thing with skis.
Rym: Yes, I did and you know what?
Rym: I spent half what I could have spent on skis.
Scott: See, this is the thing.
Scott: In the world, there are many seasonal goods such as fruits, right?
Scott: But the problem with fruits is that they spoil, so you can only buy them in season.
Scott: When they're out of season, you don't want to buy the fruit at all.
Rym: Now, my skis do turn black and eventually rot.
Rym: I... No, that doesn't happen.
Scott: Right, so, but there are certain other things that also have seasons such as clothing and sporting goods, but...
Rym: Yeah, how come no one has any foresight?
Rym: How come every store is selling shorts at like 80% off around now?
Rym: It's like, do they not understand that I can buy my shorts now and not buy them in the summer?
Rym: Or do the majority of people not have such simple foresight?
Scott: Well, it's not only that, but it's that next year, you know, people who actually care about clothes, the fashion will change.
Scott: So, the shorts that, you know, so even if they got, they wanted to get the shorts now to save money, those shorts are no good for them next year.
Rym: Oh, true.
Rym: No good for fashion-y people, but Walmart does this.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: There's no fashion in Walmart.
Scott: You'd be surprised.
Rym: There's no fashion there.
Scott: Anyway, you know, but sporting goods, right?
Scott: They also have seasons.
Rym: Now, here's the thing.
Scott: So, if you want to buy skis in the winter, when people are skiing, you're going to pay a lot of money.
Rym: The 2012 bikes are better overall than the 2011 bikes.
Scott: By a very slim margin, that won't matter to you.
Rym: The margin is not something I believe a human could perceive, especially this time around.
Rym: So, and I test-wrote a whole bunch of bikes, and to not belabor the point, I used to always ride a 19-inch frame mountain bike, totally not suitable to the city.
Rym: I got a 22-inch street bike, like a performance hybrid before, but I did not know what I needed, and that was the bike that was recommended.
Rym: It was pretty great for what it was.
Rym: But having ridden street bikes for a while now, and now I know the deal with them, which is way different from all the biking I've ever known in my life, I knew what I wanted, and I test-drove a whole bunch of bikes, and I'm getting a pretty fucking awesome bike, I think.
Scott: Eh, I'll just get stolen again.
Rym: Eh, no, because I'm never going to park it outside.
Scott: You're never going to use it.
Rym: I'm going to use it a lot, but only for recreational biking, or biking to work, where I can just park it in my fucking office.
Scott: Oh, you got a better office now.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Alright.
Rym: So yeah, getting a bike.
Scott: So, woman?
Rym: Uh, it's kind of warm out.
Scott: Not where I'm working.
Rym: No, but the odyssey continues.
Scott: So I'm sitting in his office, and the office is so freaking cold.
Scott: How hot cold is it?
Scott: I'm wearing my winter hat, and my hoodie, and I'm still cold.
Scott: Yeah, and look, look, I got winter socks on, I'm still cold.
Rym: Scott, you should file an HR complaint.
Scott: We did, we talked to the HR guy.
Rym: File a complaint, say you're not going to come into the office.
Scott: My throat is like scratchy from being in the cold office.
Rym: Tell him it's too cold, you have to work from home.
Scott: I'm, you know, I don't know, actually I might legitimately be slightly sick from being in the cold office.
Rym: Don't you get me sick.
Scott: It's just scratchy throat.
Rym: Because I kind of want to go to Wildwood this weekend if that is an option.
Scott: I would also take that option.
Scott: There's nothing that heals cold like a warm beach.
Rym: And some orangey.
Scott: Yeah, but yeah, we'll see, but it's like god damn it's cold.
Rym: So this is an issue that comes up a lot.
Rym: Many times in the tech world, a tech company will run afoul of some stupid ass law in some backwater country.
Rym: And because they're an international company that cares about, you know, growth markets or emerging markets or whatever.
Rym: They'll either cave in to this bullshit demand or they'll like partition things to people to handle it.
Scott: Yeah, I'm really hating this, right.
Scott: This happens a lot where, you know, a company makes a product, but because they're an internet company that product goes to the whole world.
Scott: And one country says, oh, your product breaks our law in our country so you have to change it.
Scott: So suddenly you got the whole, the rest of the world that doesn't have this stupid law is suffering with a shittier product because they have to change it for this one country that they care about.
Scott: Or what happens is they'll start diversifying and there'll be two versions of the product.
Scott: You know, the company is suffering because they had to spend more money maintaining multiple versions.
Rym: The way the internet works, Google is a big example of this.
Rym: So they have Google, you know, Korea Google and Germany Google and France Google.
Rym: Those Google portals follow all the rules of every country they're in because they do whatever business they do in that country.
Rym: But they don't ever compromise on the functionality of the real Google.
Rym: Which it's interesting that the
Rym: U.S.,
Rym: despite all the bullshit we go through, is pretty much the only country I trust with any internet anything when it comes to free speech of any kind.
Rym: Well, considering most of the internet is here anyway.
Scott: Well, at least the free speech, but not when it comes, right.
Scott: But it's weird because like if it's a straight up free speech issue, like someone has a political website or something, you'll always win in the U.S But they will allow people to have chilling effects via other avenues.
Scott: You can use intellectual property laws to chill free speech because it's not viewed as a free speech issue.
Scott: But if you can make it a free speech issue, you can win.
Rym: But anyway, tonight's backwater country is worst Korea.
Rym: South Korea has a law.
Scott: Well, it's the less worst Korea.
Rym: Scott, this is a meme you're obviously unaware of.
Rym: North Korea is best Korea.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Great.
Scott: Like Rarity's best pony?
Rym: Rarity is pretty good.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: Like North Korea.
Rym: Anyway, so Korea has this stupid law that has to do with defamation that takes effect on, I believe, April 1st.
Rym: For any site above a certain number of unique visitors per day.
Rym: And the deal is...
Scott: At least they're limiting it that way and not imposing it on every site period.
Rym: But the deal is they require anyone who's commenting to post their real name and their national ID card number.
Rym: Now, I gotta back up a little bit here.
Rym: I've run afoul of this before.
Rym: So has Scott.
Rym: In fact, back at RIT, we liked to play weird online games and many of them happen to be from Korea.
Scott: Yeah, because when you're in college, you learn about all this weird shit.
Scott: And it's like, you know, we know that the rest of the world has a lot of cool things that we want.
Scott: Especially, you know, the Asian world and Japan and South Korea.
Scott: And, you know, they have lots of cool things and games that we want that we can't get.
Scott: So we had some friends who would go out of their way to get these things and they tried to play Korean MMOs.
Scott: And in order to do so, you need a Korean national ID number, which is a social security number.
Rym: Now, here's the fucked up part.
Rym: I'm gonna grossly generalize, but basically it's like the equivalent of a social security number.
Rym: And if you're a Korean citizen, you've got one.
Rym: There's data coded into the number.
Rym: For example, you can determine from a number if someone is male or female.
Rym: Many Korean online games require this number to even make an account.
Rym: So it would be the equivalent of you have to publicly tie your SSN to your World of Warcraft account with your real name or you cannot play.
Scott: And then some of the games went even further.
Scott: is you could not play as the gender that you were not.
Scott: So if you're a dude, you have to play as a dude.
Scott: You can't be a girl.
Rym: This is because Korea is kind of fucked up.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, you know, South Korea is still pretty cool overall.
Scott: But, you know, much like the UK, which has scary police state cameras everywhere.
Rym: Or Australia, which if you look at just their internet law is a fascist state.
Rym: But the rest of their law is pretty...
Scott: Also video game censorship, right?
Scott: You know, Korea, while we think it's all pretty cool with their, you know, GGG and their Starcraft has plenty of their share of, you know, fucked up shit.
Scott: So we have fucked up airports and stuff like that.
Rym: And I just point out, as always, Google is doing the best thing they can do because they have a real business presence in Korea that they can't extricate themselves from.
Rym: They do stuff there.
Rym: So they're fully compliant with Korean law only on the tiny Korean version of Google and YouTube.
Rym: And anyone in Korea can just post a video to regular YouTube where all the normal internet citizens live and they don't have to deal with this BS.
Scott: But normal YouTube is in English.
Scott: if they don't speak it, they're in trouble.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: This is a broader problem that really I'm feeling more and more that the US internet in English is in some ways, like, surprisingly partitioned from the rest of the world's internet.
Rym: Just for the fact that most countries have these weird laws and these other services that comply with these laws, but kind of the consensus reality is in English, mostly hosted in the US.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I think it's sort of like it's.
Scott: this thing goes both ways, right?
Scott: On the one hand, you know, you have the, you know, you want to operate worldwide.
Scott: One country's laws suddenly affect you everywhere.
Scott: But on the other hand, you're the reverse, which is I'm not in your country.
Scott: Screw you.
Scott: Like VLC is hosted on some servers in France where it's okay.
Rym: I don't want a global regulatory body because I don't trust the majority of countries, let alone the majority of people.
Scott: I don't think there's, I think what we need is a non-country related regulatory body, an internet government that is the government of the internet.
Rym: Now I agree in principle, Scott.
Rym: I agree that the internet as a culture, as an entity should be a politically distinct unit.
Scott: And when that internet government is formed, it would immediately declare war against anyone who did not comply.
Scott: So China, Korea, Australia.
Rym: How the fuck do we have an internet election to see who is president of the internet?
Scott: If this was a fictional novel of the cyberpunk genre, it would go something along these lines.
Rym: A guy with a nuke in his motorcycle.
Scott: No.
Scott: Some guy wins a mega lottery or something, or maybe he starts some company and makes $20.
Rym: And lives in space?
Rym: Or Antarctica?
Scott: And he buys, with that money eventually, Cisco, AT&T, Verizon, and Sprint.
Rym: Scott, I think there's a better way to go about it.
Rym: I wrote, I don't have it anymore.
Rym: It's on that hard drive.
Rym: But in high school, I wrote a short fiction, a science fiction.
Scott: A cyberpunk internet government fiction?
Rym: No, so the opening scene was basically one day, I think I've said this on the show before, at like 11.08, or no, it was like right during morning rush hour in every major city in the world.
Scott: 1990, whatever, the end day.
Rym: Yeah, it was set in 20-something-something.
Rym: 20X, XCX.
Scott: It wasn't the end day?
Rym: No, October whatever, 1997.
Rym: I marched in a football game parade that day.
Rym: Anyway, on that morning, suddenly at every major intersection in every major city in the world, Yeah, a shopping cart full of gallon jugs and milk got shoved into the intersection.
Rym: And then a missive that was cryptographically signed came from the internet declaring sovereignty.
Rym: And then there was a whole cyber war following, and eventually the internet got a distributed anonymous seat, kind of like L in the first part of Death Note at the UN.
Rym: Yeah, however, that requires punk kids like 4chaners to organize cohesively.
Scott: And be in greater numbers.
Scott: The problem is the internet makes everything look bigger than it really is.
Rym: But at the same time, so does terrorism.
Scott: It sure does.
Rym: And I like the idea of prankful terrorism.
Scott: Yeah, not killing people's good.
Rym: Like one way anonymous, not anonymous, but something like anonymous, and we say lowercase anonymous could start something like this, would be to say, have a symbol.
Rym: that's fairly simple to make, that's generally agreed upon.
Scott: They've got like a hundred of them.
Rym: And then, yeah, but you need one that's generally agreed upon.
Rym: That isn't the troll face, fucking V-Mass.
Rym: And one day it just starts getting graffitied fucking everywhere.
Scott: Alright, great.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: Vandalism, that'll help.
Rym: Yeah, but it will in that it'll scare people a little bit.
Rym: Anyway, we digress.
Rym: That's a show topic.
Rym: Sure.
Rym: But you know what, Korea?
Rym: Fuck you.
Rym: That's right.
Rym: That's the moral of the story.
Scott: So check out this, right?
Scott: So some researchers, and thankfully I guess it was researchers depending on who you are, right?
Scott: They bought a bunch of domains, which is perfectly okay.
Scott: You can buy domains if you want.
Scott: But they bought domains that were slight misspellings of popular domains, right?
Rym: So instead of experts exchange, it was experts exchange.
Scott: That's exactly the same as spelling.
Rym: I know.
Scott: Instead of frontrowcrew.com, it was frontrowcraw.com, right?
Rym: Well, the other day I accidentally typed YouTube.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And you know what I went to?
Rym: The same thing, no.
Rym: No.
Rym: I went to horrible malware site.
Scott: Oh, because Google actually owns a lot of misspellings.
Rym: Yeah, but they don't own all of them.
Rym: They don't own YouTube.
Scott: So what they did is something that a lot of campers and squatters of misspellings don't do, is they actually set stuff up on those servers.
Scott: And what they set up was not websites.
Scott: Who wants websites?
Scott: They set up email servers.
Scott: So they pointed the MX records of all these misspelled domains at a mail server and started collecting mail, email, where the person sending the email mistyped the domain.
Scott: So for example, maybe somebody accidentally sent an email that was meant for me to me at frontrowcraw.com.
Scott: And this guy owned the domain and got it on his mail servers.
Scott: Now you thought you were emailing me, but you emailed this other guy.
Rym: Now what's interesting is that I don't honestly believe that there should be any legal problem with doing this.
Scott: Oh, there isn't.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I don't think there is, but it is a major security vulnerability.
Scott: For example, right?
Scott: Some of the examples they gave her like IBM, where people would do like subdomains.
Scott: So what would happen is instead of sending an email to like us.ibm.com, it would go to usibm.com.
Scott: So what happens is a lot of people are dumb and they send things in email that they shouldn't.
Rym: Now there's two ways around this.
Rym: One, the fuck are you doing ever typing an email address?
Rym: Yes, that's true.
Rym: Seriously, what the fuck are you ever going to... If you're typing an email address, you've already done something wrong.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Also, but I mean, what if, say for example, I click a mail to or a contact form and the guy who coded the contact form mistyped the email address.
Rym: Well, then that's point two.
Rym: Right.
Rym: If someone else caused the problem, the fuck are you doing sending anything important that could fuck you in an email?
Scott: That's definitely the big problem.
Rym: But for example... I work for broker dealers.
Rym: If you mailed a password and a credential in the same email... What the fuck?
Rym: Let alone a password in the same email, you're fired.
Scott: What if you sign up for Steam or something like Amazon and you, when you're signing up, put in the wrong email and now that signup mail that lets the person get into the account is going to some other domain.
Scott: Now that guy can reset the password on your account and he's got your account.
Rym: Now luckily, most of those sites require you to confirm the email address before you can do anything.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So the guy confirms it because he gets the original email.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Because you typed it wrong on registration.
Rym: Not so lucky now, is it?
Rym: Now if he's really evil, he then forwards on a confirmation to you and as a pastor, it's all the mail that you think you're, that you should be getting, you really are getting.
Rym: So he's transparently in your business, ready to take your credit card as soon as you've added it.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So now, you know, obviously if you're smart like us, this isn't going to hurt you because why are you typing an email?
Scott: Why are you sending something, right?
Scott: But if you're a gigantic mega corporation with thousands of employees, you can't keep them all from being dumb.
Scott: So some things you can do, for example, you know that your company is front row crew.
Scott: So you in your local DNS records at your company, you prevent employees from sending emails to the common misspellings of front row crew by directing the IP or, you know, something like that.
Scott: But that only goes so far.
Scott: Stupidity can still beat you and people, you know, from other companies sending email to your company can still, you know, screw up.
Rym: One difference here is that with a post office, there's at some point a human being looks at the envelope and goes, wait a minute, this guy clearly meant Shady Lane, not Shady Loo.
Scott: That's only if the computer can't read it.
Rym: Yeah, but at the same time, you also can't like, it's not the other way, you put up a cardboard house next to the real house with the misspelling on the street.
Rym: It's like Shady Power Book.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Power Books are sure are shady.
Rym: I don't know what to do about the problem.
Rym: I mean, you could do some sort of exchange identity trust where, kind of like how, kind of like how, not to talk about the technical details of it, because this is just the news, not a show.
Rym: When in Firefox, you're typing in a URL and there's a certificate for that domain, it shows up in green or not green, depending on whether or not.
Rym: It's a real simple answer.
Scott: As if you just encrypted the emails.
Rym: Oh yeah, but that is beyond the vast majority of humans.
Scott: Like PGP.
Rym: We have had relatively trivial identity trust and encryption integrated into mail fairly readily.
Scott: If you really care and you're willing to put forth a little bit of effort.
Rym: It's so little.
Rym: Dude, you want to email Wil Wheaton?
Rym: A lot of you might have ever tried to email him in the past.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: Go to his website, there's his public key.
Rym: He won't read email that isn't at least signed.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So if you want to send an email and encrypt it properly and maybe get Wil Wheaton to read it, right?
Scott: Go and get a public key with PGP and there's a Firefox plugin.
Scott: I don't know if it still exists.
Scott: It used to exist called Fire PGP and it would add PGP to your Gmail.
Scott: And basically all you do is when you want to send a Gmail to someone, you use, you push a few buttons extra when sending the email and when receiving the email.
Scott: And it'll be so encrypted, no government on earth can read it.
Scott: And only the person you are sending it to will be able to read it.
Scott: And if you type the email address wrong, the person who gets it, that's the wrong person, won't be able to read anything.
Rym: Here's the problem.
Rym: You need the people you're sending the mail to to also use the same thing.
Rym: And this is why this is impossible.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: But if you actually care and you coordinate with people, you can use this.
Scott: I've used it in the past.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But I warn you, it's not going to happen on any reasonable scale in the next 40 years.
Scott: Maybe I'm going to.
Scott: I'm going to.
Scott: I'm working on ways to to make encryption happen without the user having to do as much key copying and stuff.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: What do you got for me?
Scott: I don't know if I've talked about this on the show before.
Scott: I feel like I have, but there has been some changes to this department.
Scott: So I think it is OK to mention it and do it again, even though it may have been discussed in the past.
Scott: All right.
Scott: There is a Web site called If This Then That.
Scott: And it's actually the URL is IF.
Rym: So if we've talked about on the show, I've been using it for a while.
Rym: TTT.
Scott: So if this then that.
Rym: I'm going to stop using it because everything I thought that would be cool to do with it has not turned out the way I wanted.
Scott: Nearly all my stuff's working out pretty good and has been working pretty good for a long time.
Rym: I was mostly using it to capture links people tweeted of people I followed or things that people sent to me to then like have thing of the day fodder.
Rym: But it caused so much bullshit.
Rym: It wasn't even worth it.
Scott: Well, I think that's because you set it up to catch so much bullshit like.
Scott: I'm using it to like basically forward things between services.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So if I post a photo to Flickr, it'll tweet it.
Scott: Or if I, you know, post.
Rym: See, I can't do that because the way I post photos is once a month, I take my like four hundred photos and upload them all at once to Flickr.
Scott: You just had to configure it to, you know, to match your personal whatever.
Rym: The amount of configuration it takes to match what I want, what I do normally is more work and effort and fiddly bullshit than just do it.
Scott: It's a lot less effort than coding it, that's for sure.
Rym: That is true.
Rym: But I have not found a use for it.
Rym: that makes me like would make me mourn it disappearing.
Scott: I got a lot of uses for it.
Scott: The primary thing I use it for a lot is basically between Delicious and Twitter.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I got a lot going on.
Scott: So like if I favorite something on Twitter and there's a link in it, it automatically gets delicious.
Scott: That's really useful.
Scott: But anyway, so that's what this site does.
Scott: But the reason it's a thing of the day is because now it is no longer invite only.
Scott: You can just sign up.
Scott: Ho ho.
Scott: Not only that, but not only can you just sign up, but they remove the limits on it.
Scott: So you can just make as many tasks as you want.
Scott: It used to be there like a limit of how many you could have.
Scott: now you can have infinity jillion.
Rym: If my if this, then that updates.
Rym: update my.
Rym: if this, then that.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: And they also keep adding more.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: They keep.
Scott: you can make loops with it.
Scott: You can do Twitter, Facebook, Facebook, Twitter and have to get to get to get to get to get to.
Scott: And you're basically you'll hit the API limit on both of them and then you're done.
Scott: But yeah, this site, I imagine many useful for many people who use a lot of different Internet services and want them to all hook up.
Scott: You know, like if you're the kind of person who has a Twitter and a Facebook and you only really use one of them But you kind of want the stuff posted on the other one Then this is for you Has a lot of weird stuff like.
Scott: it can do emails SMS is Poster is oh, it's a cool thing.
Rym: Don't get me wrong.
Rym: I just I do think we've talked about this before.
Scott: I think we have but you know, it's it's worth.
Rym: so you've opened a door.
Scott: What door did I open?
Rym: So I can repeat a thing of the day if I think it warrants discussion, I don't think it was a thing of the day.
Scott: I Think it may have been discussed But I do not believe it was thing of the day.
Rym: so I can take all my previous things of the day and count them As news is going forward if they're new which they're not.
Rym: but this is new.
Scott: It is new because it is now open to the public with no invite, but shouldn't that be news?
Scott: No, because it's a cool thing.
Rym: You can't talk about anything cool in the news.
Scott: I didn't have anything cool to talk about.
Rym: so This has happened before my thing of the day.
Rym: watch this video and the whole time just remember just remember.
Rym: very clearly.
Rym: these people Do not realize what they do.
Scott: Who are these people?
Rym: so some high school football game, whatever.
Rym: someone had a big sign.
Rym: You know how you trash talk right like it.
Rym: RIT hockey.
Rym: after we scored the first goal against any team Some brave man would hang a got goalie sign behind the opposition's goal.
Rym: Oh, yeah, at one point a goalie turned around after seeing this saw it and started crying.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: There's more to that story, but he was crying and had to be taken off the ice.
Scott: We went through like three or four goalies in that game.
Rym: That was a pretty went
Scott: through goalies like Rym goes to me while
Rym: I have a lot of respect for that Newman goalie because when the 23rd goal got my him he did not cry and When the 24th one went through well the game was over by then so
Scott: He was not any less
Rym: score.
Rym: So someone hung one of those and what they hung was a sign that said you mad, bro.
Scott: Now excellent signage.
Rym: We're on the internet.
Rym: You know what that means.
Rym: I know what that means.
Rym: Everyone knows what that means.
Rym: These people think that it is clearly racist due to the mentioning of bro Which clearly refers to the African American player on the other team, right?
Rym: It's really guys like if you never heard of the internet like.
Scott: well, really it's this.
Scott: you know what this is.
Scott: This is the niggard Lee situation.
Scott: Right is to where one person thinks a word means one thing and another person thinks the word means another thing.
Rym: This however is beyond that because niggard Lee at least is a word that is not used commonly, but this is more like Jive talk almost like you mad bro is something on the internet that everyone knows what it means.
Rym: And yet these people are so out of touch
Scott: that not only well actually what it is is that most people are so out of touch but not
Rym: only do they not like Even think to try to figure out if there's anything else behind it or not only does any no one tell them no
Scott: If they were smart enough to do that, they would already know what it means.
Rym: No kids like dad that this is just something on the internet But that they immediately assume it's racist and raise a brouhaha.
Scott: Well, I think it also was because this happened to be used right?
Scott: So the you mad bro was hung by a predominantly white school after a game against a predominantly not white school.
Rym: But to me bro does not indicate African-american bro, if anything indicates college brag our pink shirted ass.
Scott: yeah, you know, this is you know a lot
Rym: of
Scott: racism sexism whatever accusations Not all obviously but many these days are due to a person saying something Not having any intent at least at that time of racism sexism, you know You know any sort of prejudice or discrimination, you know intent whatsoever, but using a word choice that is Interpreted improperly by the other people's thus resulting in you know, but I'm thinking
Rym: The one thing in this case It really just highlights the severe cultural divide between internet people
Scott: on the internet and people aren't
Rym: and everybody else.
Scott: It's about 50 years difference now.
Rym: this happened once before Not that long ago on FARC.
Rym: There was a big funny article about it, but basically a pool got shot down.
Rym: I think it was because someone pooped in it.
Scott: This wasn't the one where people died in it.
Rym: No No, it wasn't.
Rym: I don't even know what happened with that pool.
Rym: I've been waiting for the follow-up article.
Rym: But so pool got shut down for whatever reason.
Rym: so someone hung the pools closed sign at the pool.
Rym: Nice and Immediately the whole community was outraged at this racist caricature and this racist sign telling black people they can't swim in the community Pool, why is pools closed?
Scott: racist?
Rym: because the guy in the pools closed canonical picture has an afro And I guess that is the closest link they've got.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: It is true that the man depicted in the meme for pools closed Happens to be an african-american who happens to have a pretty bitchin afro.
Rym: Yeah I don't know.
Rym: I I'm always a little not closed the pool I don't know.
Rym: I'm always amused when stuff like this happens because I almost just want to go these people and be like Let me show you a world.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: It'd be like Willy Wonka We almost need like internet classes Like maybe that's.
Scott: maybe that should be a show.
Scott: that's odd network television like welcome to the internet.
Rym: They do things like that, but the people who do those shows don't know either.
Rym: Those are the shows where above The woman will stand there and be like does your child speak in code to hide things from you?
Rym: acronyms like L. O. L. or R.O.M.L.M.A.O.
Rym: which clearly has communist underpinnings, right?
Scott: I think the other thing is there are shows on TV I've seen for like a few seconds here and there, you know while you're in like a Restaurant that has a TV where it's like all they do is show funny YouTube videos on a TV.
Scott: Because for people who don't have YouTube right or don't know how to use it.
Rym: Yeah, cuz everyone has YouTube, right?
Scott: And I think that you know those shows are.
Scott: just the problem with them is that they're limited, right?
Scott: They can't take you that far down the rabbit hole.
Scott: They can just basically do America's funniest home video.
Rym: you realize know you're taking any submission.
Rym: No, your meme does a good job of this.
Scott: The thing is anyone who knows what that should be the show it should be know your meme.
Scott: It should be on time.
Scott: television thing is.
Scott: everyone who knows what know your meme is Doesn't need know your meme, but that's exactly what if know your meme was a TV show that was on prime time.
Rym: So have you ever watched?
Rym: know your meme because the problem with life only The problem with anyone is that if you don't understand the proper nouns I'm going to read for you what one of those sounds like to someone who doesn't already know the deal.
Rym: All right I'm just gonna read Jabberwocky because it's just gibberish.
Scott: Okay, but people have no idea what any of this stuff.
Scott: But as I'm saying is you could I could.
Scott: I could definitely make a show that taught normal people The ways of the internet if they watch.
Rym: so I have a second thing of the day now, so I gotta find the picture again.
Rym: I'll find it and link to it.
Rym: You know the tea party right and all their right-wing shenanigans.
Rym: Well some enterprising young man made a bunch of signs and internet ads that say lowercase T No, no, no, no politics.
Rym: Got you bitter and a picture of a lemon Says join the lemon party the party dot org.
Rym: I feel like that is the first step.
Scott: I salute that man and give him an internet medal.
Scott: if there was an internet government He would receive the second best thing to be.
Rym: I want to print like a hundred of these things out in color and just put them around New York City He wouldn't get the Internet Medal of Honor.
Scott: He would just get the internet second.
Scott: Not quite the Medal of Honor.
Rym: He gets the Silver Star.
Scott: yeah, whatever it is For Glorious service in name of the Internet.
Scott: So very briefly in the meta moment.
Rym: We were packs.
Rym: Most of our lectures are online.
Rym: In fact, all of our lectures from PAX Prime PAX East 2011 are online in the GeekNights stream YouTube channel.
Rym: The current book club book is the air the eye the arm by Nancy farmer.
Rym: I'll finish it as soon as I can because The worst webcomic contest is ending soon.
Rym: If you have an entry for the worst webcomic in the world noting that you're an asshole for submitting Unless you make a webcomic yourself.
Rym: Yep, and to The craziness of the author of the webcomic it factors in about equally to the actual band of the web.
Scott: Factoring will be entirely subjective on the part of us.
Rym: Two things one of many of you have used this opportunity to force me to read furry pornography.
Rym: I will come up with a way to prevent this in the future.
Rym: and Second don't submit control delete anymore.
Rym: We got it.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: You don't get tired of that joke Tired before you can use the Scott Expo.
Scott: I feel like there's another meta But you can just if you if you're wondering if you think you're missing something you can just come visit us on the Internet's.
Rym: Hey, you want some things?
Rym: The we're the next big gaming or techie or anything like that.
Rym: panels.
Rym: We're doing are pretty much magfest and PEX East Awesome.
Rym: Yeah also burning con and all that but that's coming down the road.
Scott: Come another one.
Rym: All right, so This is your rent.
Scott: Well, I think I think I've discussed this on the show before but we had such a dispute about it last night that we thought We could extend it into a longer show.
Scott: It started with an entertaining dispute for the listeners.
Rym: It started when I said innocently so Scott What should we do the Monday show on?
Rym: I was thinking and what I wanted to do just so you all know I'm curious if you're interested.
Rym: I just wanted to talk about, you know way back We did a show in like the IT toolkit like alright What are the things you need to know like basic stuff like?
Rym: I don't know Piping output and stuff in a terminal.
Scott: I don't even remember this show.
Scott: I don't remember.
Scott: I don't remember most of the shows.
Scott: That doesn't mean anything.
Rym: So I thought I'd tackle a couple of specific problems that I realized.
Rym: the majority of people out there listening Even techies have no idea how to use like no hop or screen.
Rym: But Scott didn't want to do it cuz he's a big baby.
Scott: No, it's because if you're gonna do a show, you know teaching specific details of terminal commands It's really a pain in the ass to do without visually showing someone.
Rym: now, you know, for example No hop.
Rym: ever have the problem punk kids where you want to run a program from the command line.
Rym: But then like you log out or you close the terminal or something and it dies because the terminal died That's because the terminal sent a hangup signal that shut down the process because the process you started was tied to the terminal you opened.
Rym: Yeah, you know you SSH somewhere you you run like a gigantic G on zip and then you you log out and then the GM zip Stops.
Rym: so you might think oh I put it into the background with the ampersand now still tied to the terminal.
Rym: No, yeah, either that the only real good ways around this is one.
Rym: no hop No hop is magic.
Rym: You just type whatever you wanted to type and you put an ampersand put in the background like before.
Rym: But in the beginning before your command you just type no hop You.
Scott: the thing is those commands or you type something in the beginning you can never remember like the time command.
Rym: You can never remember know how because the terminal hangs up on whatever bullshit you're trying to do.
Rym: No, hop says no hang up.
Rym: It can't be hung up on.
Rym: it'll run to the end no matter what someone kills it.
Scott: Okay, but still right.
Scott: This is not helping people who haven't who are not terminal experts in any way.
Scott: this terminal expert already knows that.
Rym: I'm pretty sure that at least one person is going to email us saying that really helped me.
Scott: Dude, if you if you need help with those sorts of things I'll give you five bucks.
Rym: go to email Scott and tell him that this helped you.
Scott: go to Google Not really go to Google and search for like Linux terminal tutorial commit unique.
Rym: That's not gonna help because most people the way they learn is they have a problem.
Scott: For example, their problem might be They don't know how to use Google.
Rym: No, dude.
Scott: Let me google that for you.
Rym: LMG E-T-F-Y Googling that if I'm an idiot, I'm gonna Google for like start program log out program keeps running Mm-hmm and see what happens.
Scott: You're really bad at googling.
Scott: We already know this Scott.
Rym: The people who are good at Google don't have these problems.
Scott: That's what I'm telling you.
Scott: and even then if you don't know any way your show ideas dumb show.
Rym: I think it was alright Scott.
Rym: So what was your show idea?
Scott: I didn't have a show idea because Most of the ideas you came up with were a dumb or B not technology and this is a rant I had I think before on the show.
Scott: is that so much stuff on the internet that is on technology sites is not actually So?
Rym: the news about the LHC or the stuff about fracking in no way involves technology.
Scott: It does involve technology, but per the definition of technology.
Scott: But a we are not deeply knowledgeable in those areas.
Rym: I've learned a lot about both of those by reading articles.
Scott: Yeah, that's not deeply knowledgeable.
Scott: Do a show?
Scott: No show where someone's gonna come and tell us how wrong we are.
Scott: Uh, maybe you Underestimate your ability to bullshit and pretend you know something when you don't.
Rym: it's not that hard to learn.
Rym: Do you realize Scott take any realm of knowledge in the world?
Rym: All you have to do is just barely scratch the surface just touch it a little bit.
Rym: You know more than the majority of people on that subject and are now effectively an expert as far as they're concerned.
Scott: That's true, but they could just read Wikipedia and as They wouldn't need you But they wouldn't need a podcast where we read a Wikipedia page.
Rym: Apparently they need that apparently because that's what they always ask for.
Scott: so rims doing a great job of insulting on listeners.
Rym: I hate show dude, you guys seriously the majority of shows you suggest are basically.
Rym: you've emailed us and said hey Would you read this Wikipedia article and summarize it for me?
Scott: Yeah, read it yourself.
Rym: Learn to read.
Rym: anyway, it's fundamental.
Scott: I guess if you're illiterate a podcast would really fucking help you.
Scott: No, I'm insulting listeners But anyway, I would go.
Scott: so I complained, you know as the usual complaint that so much tech news is not actually tech news.
Scott: It is business news or you know science news.
Rym: No, I agree with you on that front, but it won.
Rym: You know, it's Mondays is very specifically science.
Rym: Yes Technology.
Rym: Yes and neck beards.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: We don't we don't know much about the science or the neck.
Rym: But here's the thing.
Rym: you weren't arguing last night that oh, we shouldn't do these topics.
Rym: We don't know a lot about him But you said that was one of my argument.
Rym: or you say that technology in this implied arbitrary concept struck means only Linux related neckbeard computer technology bullshit.
Scott: That is the second.
Rym: Are you mean other technology?
Scott: there were two arguments that I had.
Scott: one was that we don't know about it and two That when people talk if you go to a tech news site, right that says it's tech news.
Scott: They might have bullshit business news about technology businesses, but it pretty much focuses on You know the consumer electronics and enterprise computing Industries primarily.
Scott: it does not ever focus, you know, cuz on any of the other things that are also technology.
Scott: right, you can't go to say slash dot and get a story about advances in some kind of new Technology.
Rym: a lot of the news on slash dot is non computer tech news.
Scott: Not very much.
Rym: What do you know?
Rym: You don't even know.
Scott: Anyway, I just picked a tech news site at random.
Rym: I know the point is last.
Rym: I was you should have picked dig then you would have been fine.
Scott: Dig isn't just tech news though.
Scott: It was right, but you're not gonna go to engadget and see something about.
Rym: you know medical news of medical technology Construction technology pages right now Using cloud computing and Watson stuff to treat cancer.
Scott: Yeah, but that's computing is What.
Rym: it's also biology.
Rym: it's yeah, it's but it's not about the battery storage with seaweed.
Scott: that's also Consumer electronics related because batteries have a very large bearing on consumer electronics.
Rym: Okay, 50 new exoplanets found billions more away.
Scott: That's just straight-up science, which is fine.
Scott: It's not even technology at all.
Scott: It's like we were.
Scott: you know, we were discussing just before things that are technology Per the definition of the word technology, but aren't technology as he.
Rym: but it depends.
Rym: What if that article is talking about the technology used to make the scientific discovery?
Scott: Is it?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I didn't read it.
Rym: Appropriations bill threatens future space science missions.
Rym: That is the effects of politics and technology.
Rym: political news But it's also technology news because if the government for example outlawed all technology Then that would.
Rym: I would argue that's technology news.
Scott: It is news related.
Scott: In fact, it might be the last technology news, but it is not raw it is not pure boring technology.
Rym: Glowing cats real take out making glowing cats.
Rym: That is technology.
Scott: biology and science is nothing technological about.
Rym: Yeah There is because the biology is understanding it the science is researching the technology is fucking doing it in a practical way And I have a glowing cat.
Scott: The point is you get you can any I could see by those kind of arguments.
Scott: You could say that anything is tech news.
Scott: I could be like hey, here's the scores the latest football game.
Scott: That's tech news.
Scott: Why?
Scott: because they use technology?
Rym: It's not because the article is about the technology and to keep time.
Rym: and now if the article were about the technology like say It talked about you know a time like a new way to score fencing with different technology.
Rym: That's more accurate.
Rym: That's tech news.
Scott: That would be.
Rym: or if it described how existing technology works That's tech commentary, but if it was just the scores of fencing with no discussion of the technology, that's not tech news.
Scott: But what if they're in the?
Scott: in these it was.
Scott: it was primarily fencing scores.
Scott: but at one point in the article they talked about how there was a dispute over a point and there was a. There was a technological difference.
Rym: That is a seed for technology discussion.
Rym: because you take the article and say look at this issue Look at this technological problem, which caused these Ramifications outside of the realm of tech.
Scott: Yeah, but you go after ethics classes.
Rym: I took at RIT basically boiled down to Technology.
Rym: bad if used badly.
Rym: look at what happened to society.
Scott: I took like five me and play took five of those classes at least me and play.
Scott: god I think I could have like minored in that.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: We always talked about.
Rym: In fact, I would say that the majority of the examples in those classes involve the Laplanders and snowmobiles a Anyway anyway Clever bot and the Turing test.
Scott: That is a technology news.
Scott: Okay, but the point is a lot of the technology news is that are actually pure Technology news.
Scott: right in the narrow area of the consumer right are wicked boring with nothing to discuss.
Rym: So why do we even have technology as a show topic if all we're gonna talk about is the fact that because 9.1 Was just released bitches.
Rym: It has serializable snapshot isolation and I'll bet none of you know what that means.
Scott: I don't even know what that means and I sure I probably should.
Rym: I use Postgres.
Rym: I actually used Postgres a lot the serializable snapshot isolation.
Scott: so I can understand what snapshot isolation is with serializable.
Scott: I guess the snapshots are in order, you know what order they're in The cereal.
Rym: here's the article.
Rym: the serializable isolation level provides the strictest transaction isolation.
Rym: this level emulates serial transaction Execution as if transactions had been executed one after another.
Rym: that is serially rather than concurrently.
Rym: However, like the repeatable read level applications using this level must be prepared to recharge transactions due to serialization failures.
Rym: In fact, this isolation level works exactly at the same as the repeatable read except that monitors for conditions where okay.
Rym: I don't think any of you care.
Scott: I understood it though now.
Scott: Yeah, but no one cares I'm talking about real technology.
Rym: news is undermine your argument.
Rym: if that is mostly.
Rym: If your argument is that that is what tech news is mostly and we are a tech news show by your definition Why the fuck are we doing this boring ass podcast?
Scott: Well, because we do the same thing that I complain about all the tech news sites doing which is we often take business news.
Rym: So shouldn't we do that?
Rym: What's the other option talk about?
Rym: I can go on.
Rym: let me go back into that Postgres article.
Scott: No, but if you go to a site like for onyx, oh shit Scott, it supports se Linux, that's good.
Rym: I've never seen anyone use se Linux.
Scott: It's on by default in some.
Rym: yes, and you know what?
Rym: Google for any problem and Se Linux?
Scott: and the answer is turn se Linux?
Rym: Oh, yes The first thing you will find is a tutorial on how to turn se Linux off and never turn it back or at least every single Thing it complains about.
Scott: you make an exception for that thing to turn off all those features that are in your way.
Rym: I've never seen someone use se Linux in production.
Scott: But anyway, I think the NSA does and people like that.
Rym: Yeah, but I haven't seen.
Rym: I mean, but think I worked on Wall Street and turning se Linux off was standard operating procedure.
Scott: Yeah, it's pretty much security.
Rym: Once where someone turned it on whoa, that's fuck that fuck some privacy.
Scott: This is this is real tech news.
Rym: That's not tech news.
Rym: That's guys got that's meta tech discussion.
Rym: cuz you said - it's not news.
Rym: We can't talk about what we do.
Rym: who says we're a news show?
Rym: we're not.
Scott: Yeah, we just have news bits at the front.
Rym: We could have tech commentary we can.
Rym: cuz that was my other idea.
Scott: Maybe I do show by se Linux.
Scott: We just did it.
Scott: It's over.
Rym: Yeah, anything else to say about exactly?
Scott: there's so many shows where there's a topic and we.
Scott: it's a good topic But there's just not enough to know.
Rym: we could talk about for example The kinds of problems I've faced in technology in the last like two years I think are really interesting examples of what high-level IT is.
Scott: Yeah, but I think that I don't want to do meta shows.
Rym: I just you draw from experience like MC front lines.
Scott: latest album is almost 90% of it is about MC front Like.
Rym: here's a problem.
Scott: It's great music.
Scott: It's sort of like a problem.
Scott: I know who you are get this album.
Rym: I have a big thing that does some map reduce shenanigans and solar and all.
Scott: yesterday You know my produce was.
Scott: did you read the Wikipedia on it today?
Scott: So you can tell me.
Rym: put it this way I knew what it was.
Rym: What I couldn't do is go into much depth on it because I don't really know a lot about data structures or anything because I'm not a coder.
Rym: but Basically the problem I actually had was that the Hadoop file system done got corrupted.
Rym: Oh shit, so and I had to uncorrupt it, you know how I did that the command that uncorrupts it.
Rym: now There isn't such a thing.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: So luckily you don't put anything that matters in that sort of file system persistently.
Rym: That's where you put the data while you're processing and then you put it somewhere else so To bring it back.
Rym: There's an edits file We and there's an edits dot new file and there's an image file.
Rym: The image is kind of like a base image of the virtualized distributed disk.
Rym: And then the edits files are the kind of like a transaction log.
Rym: It's like a meta file system.
Rym: So I replaced the edits log with a binary file with one blank line and just lost those edits Thus allowing the file system to pick up where it had left off before the transaction log got corrupt and I lost some data.
Rym: But I didn't need that data.
Scott: Mm-hmm BAM Uh-huh.
Scott: So yeah, actually, you know what?
Scott: I'm actually came up with a great show idea.
Scott: really.
Scott: this shows sort of turning into.
Scott: we collect a whole bunch of those tech topics Like that.
Scott: we only have five like a minute to discuss.
Scott: do them all and we combine them into one mega show.
Rym: We almost really cute like Rym and Scott.
Rym: when do you use no SQL dear listener?
Scott: Never because you know this good time season.
Rym: there are but mode.
Rym: the majority of people I've ever met.
Scott: They're using it because the buzzword.
Rym: Yes who want to use it.
Rym: They're like, yeah I got like a hundred megabytes of data.
Rym: So I put it in a do to map.
Scott: reduce it right here You want to.
Scott: you want me to explain.
Scott: map reduce to you?
Scott: It's real simple.
Scott: So here's how it works Don't you just bizarre?
Rym: Let's see if.
Rym: let's see if my high IT explanation makes sense.
Scott: Okay, so I got a really great way of explaining it.
Rym: so I get big data set and I have some calculations I want to do on it.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So hopefully not all those calculations depend on other cut.
Rym: It's not like one serial chain of calculation.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: So I break it up into as many chunks as I can and distribute the processing of those chunks Yep, and then I put the fucker back together, right?
Rym: But that's what I know.
Scott: which part is the map in which parts the reduce?
Rym: I'm gonna say that map is Figuring out the problem space breaking it up and reduce is reducing all the solution out of the condensate sort.
Scott: of right It's pretty that's pretty much all 90% right?
Rym: you realize that?
Rym: I answered that almost entirely based on guessing words Yeah and language.
Scott: So let's say you want to add 1 plus 2 plus 3 plus 4 plus 5 plus 6, right?
Scott: Well Adding you don't need to add the 1 and the 2 before you can add the 3 to it, right?
Scott: You can add them up all separately.
Scott: So what you do is first you map and what the map does is it'll break it up.
Scott: So it'll say hey you over there computer number 1 you do 1 plus 2.
Scott: Computer number 2 do 3 plus 4. computer number 3 do 5 plus 6.
Scott: So each of these three computers does its separate piece of work and then computer the original Computer that did that mapping and mapped the problem to all those separate computers gets back all the answers.
Scott: So the first computer says hey 3 the second computer says hey 7, you know, and the third computer says hey 11.
Rym: It was just right.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So then the starting computer says aha 3 7 11 that is 21. and that combining of the answers is the reduce.
Rym: All right.
Rym: I was correct.
Scott: That's pretty much how it works.
Scott: So Google invented this in 2004. ish, right?
Scott: So you think well, you know, how great is that?
Scott: Really?
Scott: Well, it's pretty great because you can use that for almost anything.
Scott: if you can find a way to redefine Your problem, right?
Scott: You can get that problem to be completed a lot faster by getting a whole bunch of computers to work together on it.
Scott: For example, you want to encode a video?
Scott: Well, you can just break up all the frames say computer number 1 render frame 1 computer number 2 render frame 2 computer number 3 render frame 3 and they all send the rendered frames back to the first computer and It's sort of like bit torrenting at your work, you know, it's like hey everyone out there do a little bit of work.
Scott: I broke up my homework into you know, one problem each for all of you.
Scott: everyone do one homework problem And then it'll be.
Scott: you know, let's say you had a thousand homework problems.
Scott: If you did them all in order, it would take a thousand times long.
Scott: But if everyone does one it'll take one long because everyone does the problem at the same time.
Rym: Now, of course once again the majority of people out there, especially if you're listening to GeekNights probably don't need that for anything.
Scott: No, but be aware that when you you know use computers that are big they're pretty much all doing that all the time.
Rym: But the real answer there is if you run into if you have problems with data like that You just have to google all the frameworks and figure out which one works best.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: There's tutorials and you'll have it running pretty quick.
Scott: Yeah, but let's say you're using something like couch TV and you want to.
Scott: you know Do some work on your couch DB.
Scott: write a view.
Scott: they actually make you write a map function and a reduce function Like it actually says right in the user interface like map Reduce and you write two functions and that's how you get stuff out of couch TV.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: It's pretty crazy.
Rym: I actually like couch DB.
Scott: That's all right.
Scott: They're adding they're gonna add this couch query language to it.
Scott: once that's in there It's gonna be hot because then you'll be able to do normal kind of queries Like give me all the documents that have a tag of this and order them by this.
Rym: It's so great for like rapid prototyping like you're writing like you're writing a quick proof of concept You don't have to worry about database schema.
Rym: You just get to what you're trying to do with the data and then when you're done with the prototype Well, now, you know what your schema are.
Rym: because look what your couch DB's got in it.
Scott: Yeah, once they add that couch query language, I might bust out with some stuff.
Scott: All right All right.
Rym: So what should we do the show on?
Scott: Well, I came up with that idea, but I think I haven't actually came with another show.
Rym: I'm game.
Scott: What if we did a show about benchmarking in general?
Rym: Oh, I don't think.
Rym: have we done a show on?
Scott: I don't think so.
Scott: We did show on overclocking but not benchmark.
Rym: All right, that's the next Monday show.
Scott: Discuss benchmarking in a sort of you know Conceptual way.
Rym: talk a little bit about this for any specific benchmark different algorithms because I'm happy that you know windows includes benchmarking now Though people don't often notice.
Scott: Well, it's not really sorta.
Scott: it is to a degree kinda Yeah, but let's not just let's not blow our load on it.
Scott: No, no too early Save it.
Rym: All right.
Rym: I kind of want to eat some foods.
Scott: I gotta get my laundry from the laundry service.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and brand.
Scott: Ok for the logos be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.