Rym: It's Monday, May 23rd, 2011.
Rym: I'm Rym and this is GeekNights tonight corporate training.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So last night we're hanging out, you know fancy dinner hanging out on the town and We start talking about.
Rym: my little pony just comes up But the conversation pretty much.
Rym: ponies come up and then Scott is like, oh my god.
Rym: Let me tell you all the reasons why my little pony is awesome.
Rym: one, two, three four.
Rym: It was a relating conversation.
Scott: You got to convince people.
Scott: Otherwise, they don't believe I Don't.
Rym: it was a. it was a surprising expression of enthusiasm not often seen from Scott.
Scott: Okay, but anyway, let it.
Scott: let me go through many small opening bits.
Rym: Yeah, a lot of stuff happens.
Rym: We long.
Scott: You're not gonna go that I'm gonna blow my whole load.
Scott: I can only use three.
Scott: save some of the load and you just use three small opening bits from today, right?
Scott: Opening bit number one.
Scott: Yeah warm today.
Rym: Well, I'm today indeed.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I didn't bike this morning because it was still wet.
Scott: also the truth for me as well But I got new hiking boots.
Rym: cuz this weekend I'm gonna climb another mile-high mountain.
Scott: Yeah, good for you.
Rym: Uh, I had to wear him in so I just ran home from work in my jeans.
Rym: Okay, and it didn't take that long.
Scott: Number two on the subway platform this morning on the way to work There was a crazy guy.
Scott: but you know how crazy like yelling crazy there's crazy guys all the time But this guy was particularly crazy.
Scott: That's why I'm that's why I'm mentioning him.
Scott: if he was just regular crazy He wouldn't have been noteworthy.
Rym: So what manner of crazy?
Rym: I mean, there's the agitated crazy guy who's like bothered about something.
Rym: There's just the screaming yelling like crazy woodley-woo guy.
Rym: There's the like quiet rocking themselves.
Rym: cuz someone should call the police and you know, take care of him crazy Check on the first two, but not the third one, right?
Rym: So yelling and crazy.
Scott: so I get there and there's a guy and I he's a guy sitting on the bench and there's a guy basically bent over saying something at him a whole lot and I can't really make it out cuz I got my headphones in and also When I took the headphones out, you couldn't really make out what the guy was saying.
Scott: Anyway, cuz he was a crazy guy.
Rym: Have it a jibbity-jubilee?
Scott: pretty much.
Scott: Yeah, but he was.
Scott: he was yelling jibbity-jubilee Alright, so I put my headphones in and I ignore him.
Scott: Alright, cuz you can't get involved with that shit.
Scott: Nope, eventually the guy sort of stops bending over and getting in the other guy's face and but the crazy guy You know once he gets out of the guy's face He's basically jumping up and down a little bit yelling his jibbity-jubilee.
Rym: Was he waving his arms?
Scott: No, but he had a cane and he was basically jumping and stomping and shaking.
Scott: It's like he was.
Scott: it's like he had punches in him and he was releasing the punches without punching anything, right?
Scott: but then he got like he got a little more crazy like he's pointing his cane at people and getting kind of weird.
Scott: and then when the train showed up like he like when there's this girl standing next to me and he basically goes behind her and Pushes the air but like but like he was gonna push her onto the tracks.
Rym: Whoa Which there was.
Rym: there was a big rat.
Rym: Well, not a big rash, but there was a time when that was a danger.
Rym: There was a small rash of crazy people just pushing people onto the tracks.
Scott: Yeah, but it's like the train was already there, but he like he pushes the air.
Rym: That's not good that that guy's practicing and the girl like goes like That guy's training.
Rym: Hmm.
Scott: Yeah, but it's like it was a crazy guy.
Scott: watch out crazy guy.
Scott: and the third thing there's a place that eat lunch sometimes called fresh & Co and they got Salad and sandwiches and the sandwiches they have a pretty good like.
Scott: they're not.
Scott: they won't fill you up that much But they're pretty cheap like six seven bucks.
Scott: and they put him in this incredibly hot convection oven and they taste they have like the most Flavor of any sandwich that you can get in the area.
Scott: Nah So they were tweeting.
Scott: they were like trivia win lunch and I won lunch by direct messaging a tweet.
Scott: So I got.
Scott: I got a sandwich in the water.
Rym: Well, that's how I got those tickets to Scott Pilgrim Wasn't because of fancy industry connections or anything.
Rym: I just won the Midtown Comics contest by tweeting Yeah, because apparently everyone's really slow but actually tweeting if something happens.
Scott: Yeah, so it knows.
Scott: so I actually you know.
Scott: So I was just asked my co-worker what the answer the trivia was and I just got it.
Rym: I got a minor geek bite considered a review of an app because you see until recently I had The palm free which had no apps to review.
Rym: Yeah now well there was one app because what I really needed one of the killer apps for a smartphone for me was Using GPS data to gather statistics like heat maps of where I go.
Rym: You know if I go hiking or running seeing a map of like how far I went how long I went if I'm like Exploring and I find a weird thing.
Rym: I can look back on the map and see where I was And I couldn't use latitude or anything.
Rym: So I end up using this thing called smart runner and it kind of sucks.
Rym: But it was the best one there was.
Rym: People use it and it was free.
Rym: I could pay the right price.
Rym: I mean I could have paid for like more stuff.
Rym: But the stuff that offered was kind of dumb and I had this website.
Rym: It all worked pretty well, except the app just kind of sucked.
Rym: So I get my new phone.
Rym: I install smart run around it cuz I already got a ton of data in it And it still sucks.
Rym: It wasn't that it sucked because it was on the pre.
Rym: it just sucks No, but even the pay app isn't any better.
Rym: you just get more features on the site.
Rym: Okay, not in the app.
Rym: All right, you gotta pay for like a membership to the site.
Scott: What sucks about it?
Rym: So you'll be running you turn it on right and first it just never seems to get a GPS sync Like it just doesn't use the API correctly.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Meanwhile, I turn on like latitude immediate sync maps immediate sync smart runner Red red red red.
Scott: So it's just a poorly coded piece of shit.
Rym: Or it would be like you're good to go Rym and I'd be like, okay smart runner and I'd start running.
Rym: And then I get home after like three hours of running and I look and it lost the sink like Ten feet out and not recorded anything else.
Rym: yeah, so I Was looking on the app sounds like not so smart runner.
Rym: Yeah, so I was looking on the App Store and I realized that Google does everything great.
Rym: So I just had Google into it and I just downloaded every Google app that would do anything I want.
Scott: it was made by Google.
Rym: Yes, actually made by Google.
Scott: That's usually the best thing to get.
Scott: you have a Google phone with the Google OS and a Google account Because none of that stuff could every every every app written by Google is probably gonna work pretty well.
Rym: So, of course, you know Google Translate is just great.
Rym: I said oh my why motion did it and got it immediately.
Scott: works exactly the same on iPhone.
Rym: Yep Yeah, and then I got I didn't even know this existed Google tracks Mm-hmm.
Rym: Google tracks is basically everything the smart runner pretended to be but actually works Really?
Scott: Well, let me see if that is an available option.
Rym: and basically it's Google latitude on crack.
Rym: You can set it to like what interval you want it to do.
Rym: GPS updates It draws this like perfect line of where you are and altitude and grade and speed.
Rym: and it's just.
Rym: and it's all.
Rym: you can Just export all the data for free to whatever format you want.
Rym: It's just.
Rym: it's fucking awesome.
Scott: Google tracks does Not exist for oh so sad So sad, so yeah Google track.
Rym: if you're looking for anything to track where you go in any kind of generalized sense Really just use Google latitude and Google track.
Rym: everything else sucks.
Rym: Okay, yeah, so that was my bite.
Rym: there's it's a Tuesday Monday.
Rym: It's it is Monday.
Scott: It's like the best inside joke of GeekNights is that whenever we record a show on the wrong day later early We all we never keep it hidden, even though we act like we're gonna keep it hidden, but we don't.
Rym: yeah We always like back.
Rym: date it like it.
Scott: This is the show for the 23rd of May 11 recorded on the 24th of May 11.
Rym: Yep, because we did something fun anyway.
Scott: So yeah There's this big deal going around about a patent troll that went after people making apps for the iPhone and the iPad.
Rym: The sort of thing happens all the time all the time.
Scott: so what happened here is that Apple added a feature to the the app API that you could make an app that had in-app purchases Which means you buy an app and the app might even be free But then in the app you might buy something else.
Scott: So like you could have a farm ville and then in the farm ville buy a plow for five bucks, right?
Scott: So they added that feature.
Scott: So apparently that feature is patented by a company named LOD SIS, which is a patent troll.
Scott: Yeah, they don't actually make anything.
Rym: Yeah you can pretty much always tell the patent trolls because they'll have a patent on something stupid that everyone already does and They don't actually have any products but lawsuits, right?
Scott: So LOD SIS sent out a bunch of cease and desist letters to people not Apple, but to companies that made Apps using this, you know, but in-app purchase feature a common tactic The the.
Rym: the biggest thing a patent troll will do is usually go after a lot of small Who can't do anything because those people can't fight against it.
Rym: They'll usually settle or they'll might they might fight it and they'll often lose because they don't have the resources to fight it.
Rym: one guy Thus lending legitimacy to the patent lawsuit.
Rym: So then they go to the final lawsuit.
Rym: They point back to all the people who settled or all the people who lost.
Scott: one guy Suggested right that when things like this happened that it's a risk.
Scott: He said it's a risky move.
Scott: He admitted it but one strategy might be to get all of the people who receive cease and desist letters To file on at the same exact time.
Scott: and it would cost about two thousand per person to do this filing.
Scott: but by filing all at the same time in unison, the troll would be forced to respond to all of those on the same day at Incredible expense and that that expense could actually outweigh any Possible, you know increase.
Scott: so instead of settling with the patent troll and giving them, you know thousands multiplied by everyone they sent a letter to you could give that.
Scott: you could give a few thousand to a bunch of lawyers all over the place and Basically, the patent troll would be crushed All right, and they wouldn't get anything but anyway.
Scott: So lots of sent out these letters and then it was quiet for a while as all these app developers didn't know what the fuck to do.
Scott: and then Apple finally came out today and they were like They sent a letter to Lozas and the letter was basically like look we licensed your fucking patent we gave you money already and Here is the.
Scott: here in fact is the text of that patent license that we bought from you.
Scott: and look it says that we can Transfer the license to this from this patent to our app developers.
Scott: So fuck you, right?
Scott: Stop harassing our developers or else.
Scott: And I imagine Apple has enough money to fight Lozas, but again, I want to ask the question Why did Apple license it in the first place?
Scott: Why didn't Apple just buy Lozas?
Rym: Outright why probably was cheaper to settle with them?
Scott: But it's like if you license the pen you're gonna have to keep licensing it until the patent is is done.
Scott: for was it 14 Years something like that.
Rym: Yeah still probably cheaper.
Rym: Also, I think there's a more fundamental question Why do patents like this even exist?
Scott: Why don't?
Scott: and it's like.
Scott: I know that all the tech companies basically have Armies of patents and that they all use.
Scott: they're all defensive patents, right?
Scott: It's like if I have enough patents against IBM and IBM has enough patents against me then we can't sue each other because then we'll both open up our you know.
Rym: Yeah I mean I filed.
Rym: you know there was huge pressure when I worked at IBM to get patents and I actually filed a Stupid patent because I was kind of told to buy my bosses and it's a student the stupidest thing ever.
Rym: But yet due to the way patents work and our messed up system of what is patentable It was eminently patentable to write a bash script that will look at the hardware of a system and come up with a unique Identifier to then be bait to be based on the MAC address to be used as a temporary DNS name for loading a box
Scott: Uh-huh.
Rym: Yeah, what kind of BS is that?
Rym: That's the patent.
Rym: I find that's complete bullshit.
Scott: Yep, but yeah It's like even if the patents exist if these companies all all the tech companies really hate the patents and they're really, you know Being honest that they just want them for defensive purposes then IBM Microsoft Google Apple.
Scott: That should be enough.
Scott: Maybe throw Oracle in there if those five get together and just say all right all our pet.
Scott: let's you know, let's take all our patents and We'll all simultaneously put him in the shredder.
Scott: right then know that.
Scott: because then the patent trolls Then they use their money to buy the patent trolls.
Scott: Oh put those in the shredder - no cuz buying the patent troll means they still win.
Rym: they get their money.
Rym: That's all they want is money.
Scott: No, because here's the thing, right?
Scott: So you are a pet.
Scott: you own a patent troll company.
Scott: Yes, I buy your company.
Rym: Yep, I fire you You buy my company I cash out.
Scott: No, the Money is part is the company's money.
Scott: It's not your money.
Rym: Yeah, and I you know, maybe the board of directors on a patent troll company like that They probably don't even have shareholders or if they do it might be a small number.
Scott: But it's like if you have Rym Co and I buy Rym Co.
Scott: All right.
Rym: So a million dollars.
Scott: that million dollars is property of Rym Co not property of Rym.
Scott: And then I fire Rym.
Scott: now Rym is homeless bond Scott.
Rym: Wait a minute.
Rym: You're not quite understanding how buying a company works.
Rym: Okay, so if I buy a startup company for a million dollars and the money is the mid companies then by your logic I just get that money back and I got the company for free.
Scott: Well, no good the money comes back in the company But it goes to the people who you know, who does it go?
Scott: to?
Scott: the shareholders of Rym Co?
Rym: Yeah so Rym Co the patent troll is probably just me and I probably only have three employees like a lawyer an Engineer and another lawyer.
Scott: Well, that's you know, I assume that there would be like all you know It would be a publicly traded one because it was private.
Rym: So is this company publicly traded?
Rym: You can I have right now?
Rym: I have no fucking clue because Even if it is how many shares are there?
Rym: and to what are the shareholders and the board of directors want?
Rym: I mean you could pay out a dividend to all the shareholders and Simultaneously pay a huge bonus to yourself.
Scott: Yeah, it doesn't look like it's public.
Rym: You know what?
Scott: I can't find it on Google.
Rym: I pay myself a huge bonus and then I quit.
Scott: see but what what point can we you know?
Scott: Not pay?
Scott: at what point does the ownership come to me?
Scott: so I can not pay you the huge bonus But you have to pay me the huge bonus.
Scott: who says I'm the boss I own the company now and what exactly does that mean?
Rym: What's the when's the date of that happening?
Rym: What contract are you gonna agree to after after you before you get the money?
Rym: I'm the boss Because I'm a patent holder my company.
Rym: I have the right to just say you know what?
Rym: I don't want to be bought and I'm not gonna license this to you.
Rym: So stop selling your product.
Rym: Mmm It's not quite as simple as you think and buying the patent trolls Just makes being a patent troll super awesome.
Scott: Yeah, but there has to be a way to just get rid of all of them.
Scott: Yes, there aren't that many there is.
Rym: it's a very simple way.
Rym: It's called patent law reform.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, yeah, that's another.
Scott: Unless the thing is I'm basically assuming here right that the government is useless as it's been useless and counterproductive.
Scott: So I'm trying to find ways to solve these problems without the government.
Rym: wait Hear me out rather than getting all the big companies who are relatively benign and intelligent and large and techy together And shredding the patents.
Rym: They should put all of those patents into a consortium Mm-hmm that are basically licensed for free to anyone and set up a system where they will only ever be enforced Against people who file lawsuits against people who join the consortium,
Scott: but the thing is those people who are filing lawsuits The patent trolls don't have anything.
Scott: They're not using any patents because they might.
Rym: you know The consortiums are large enough to where there's a good chance.
Rym: They are Also, you'd be very likely able to find a similar or almost identical patent in your own portfolio to hit back with.
Rym: maybe You could sue them for like using email to serve a notice about a patent.
Rym: So this article on slashdot and I don't want to get into all the details of what different states are doing But this is something that's been rumbling for a long long time There and there's a push and the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration is likely to announce soon Regulation requiring these devices in all cars and having penalties for disabling or removing them.
Rym: The device is being black boxes that in the event of a crash or other, you know an Incident where law enforcement gets involved could use a warrant to get the data and analyze as long as they had to use a warrant To get it.
Scott: What's the problem?
Rym: Let's forget the separate problem that pretty much anything involving technology doesn't need a warrant because our courts and legal system are so fucked.
Scott: Yeah, like how they was they ruled that like the FBI doesn't need a warrant to put a tracking device on your car.
Rym: Yeah, so let's ignore that problem because that's just an old people run Congress problem.
Rym: Okay independent of that the idea is that every car has to have a black box not one that phones home one that just records the data and Only keeps data from the moment of an accident back a certain amount of time.
Rym: You know telemetry data whether or not the gas pedal was hit or not?
Rym: How far it was whether or not the brakes were engaged how hard and when?
Scott: Whether or not people.
Scott: you gotta put them in police cars, that's definitely a good no question idea.
Rym: Yeah so the idea is to make it illegal to remove these devices and to put them in every single car and I am so Absolutely for this that I'm giddy.
Scott: It's a great idea.
Rym: point the first I Have never caused a traffic accident, but I have been involved in track win one traffic accident.
Rym: Actually, I was rear-ended like five times in high school But that was all in the high school parking lot because people would run stop signs behind me while I was stopped at them.
Rym: But I'm confident that if I'm ever driving in my entire life and there are black boxes in the cars I will be able to prove in court that the accident was not my fault.
Rym: Yep, - if we can prove that Who is at fault?
Rym: We can much better distribute the cost of recovering from traffic accidents, right?
Scott: Like if the black, you know right now we already have even without these black boxes Really excellent science to determine who was at fault.
Scott: accidents cops there are cops who specialize in this and they go there are detectives and they go down and they measure the skid marks on the Road and they look at the tires on the car Yeah and they look at how much damage is done to the car and nearby objects and they can pretty much 90% like exactly tell you what happened when how fast they were going when they hit the brake where the car what position it Was in when they hit the brake everything and that's without the black box.
Scott: If they had the black box, it's just like boom set in stone.
Scott: your fault.
Scott: You did it.
Scott: You were you know holding this gas pedal all the way down ignoring the red light.
Rym: So point the third I can't find the article.
Rym: So you'll have to take my word at this, but I'm sure you could find it.
Rym: I read an article it was years ago talking about how the vast majority as in the vast majority It was like over 90% of traffic collisions in the US where driver error and nothing else.
Rym: Of course driver error is pretty much the cause of almost every fatality on US highways.
Rym: Of course, and if we could prove who was at fault, then we could really in the long run Redistribute the cost of car insurance to the people who are causing the accidents.
Scott: Mmm, I guess yeah.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The thing is is that really gonna happen though?
Rym: I think it would in the long run.
Rym: because so right now let's say I'm involved in accident with you on the freeway and Your fault because there are no There's no like.
Rym: like the police can't clearly say who was at fault So they spread the blame 50/50 or 60/40 or something the insurance companies know All right, 60/40 and they base their metrics on that.
Rym: What if the metrics can prove?
Rym: Absolutely was rims fault 100% Mmm, then the insurance companies can much more heavily punish me in terms of premiums and not punish you at all.
Scott: That'd be fine.
Rym: Yeah I guess there's a lot of outrage from techies about this because they're afraid of government tracking and whatever And I don't know.
Rym: I'm just generally of the mind that certain kinds of surveillance and telemetry and tracking and things like this are very beneficial.
Rym: Not not from the angle of if you got nothing to hide, you know that sort of thing just from the angle of Every envisioning of an altercation I ever see myself engaged in Almost always involved someone else breaking the law or being adversarial or being at fault and me wishing I had some way to prove That fact in the court of law.
Scott: Well, isn't that exactly?
Scott: if you had nothing to hide you're basically saying I'm Rym I'm not breaking the law so I don't have anything to hide.
Rym: So what I'm saying is that because I have nothing to hide I Personally will make gather all this data and make it available.
Rym: if I was arrested for some sort of crime I would do anything to make sure like all that Google latitude data was in court for people to see.
Rym: Yeah, sure Unless I did it.
Rym: But especially because the people who are so worried about this they seem to think that the police are gonna start pulling you over and then Like checking the data to see if you were speeding earlier in the day.
Rym: Well, if you're black Or like a lot of people to this day claim that if you have an easy pass They will send you speeding tickets in the mail, which as far as I know has never happened.
Scott: They've never done that.
Scott: They'll send you drove through the toll booth without paying.
Rym: they'll also send you sped through the toll booth.
Rym: Yeah, you go through the toll booth at 80 miles an hour.
Rym: They're gonna send you a ticket for endangering the toll booth personnel.
Rym: Yep But anyway, I'm for this.
Rym: I see no reason not to do it.
Rym: So long as one you need a warrant to get the data unless the driver gives it up willingly Yep, and two they're not accessible from the outside.
Rym: They're a physical device that has to be accessed physically.
Scott: Yeah, yeah But what?
Scott: what keeps me from?
Scott: it has to also be secure enough so that the owner of the car can't tamper with it and modify The data.
Rym: Well, luckily that would be.
Rym: it'd be pretty easy to make something like that and to Having the laws such that I don't understand how it could be easy to do.
Scott: I mean, so it's how is it gonna check?
Scott: for example, how would it check the speed of the car?
Rym: How did cars currently check the speed?
Rym: You know how any of that works?
Scott: Yeah, it knows how.
Scott: how the dam the circumference of the wheels.
Scott: that's not how it does it and it knows how many times the Axis rotates.
Rym: Yeah, so one if you modify your car most likely from these articles There'll be laws saying that modifications to cars that would affect the telemetry gathering Have to also make sure that they update the telemetry gathering system properly and legally, right?
Scott: You're basically if the day there's no physical way to stop me from fucking with it.
Rym: Well from the data itself the black box It's really easy to make a physical device that if you mess with it It just it somehow notes that I've been messed with and nothing more.
Scott: No, but for example, right so it has some wires coming out of it.
Scott: They connect to the speedometer.
Scott: Yeah, I can just cut those wires and attach them to a phony spin a thing that simulates the speedometer.
Scott: Yep, so it's always going to speed.
Rym: So in the investigation, you know You're in an accident or the police subpoena the data they physically go to get it and they discover the evidence of this tamper.
Scott: I would obviously fix it before the cops got there.
Rym: Yeah, so you're in an accident and then you fix it right there.
Scott: No more like, you know, it would obviously be some sort of clever system right.
Scott: for example Something I could plug in really quickly push a button and it would record it.
Scott: would you know Re-record a whole bunch of speedometer data and then I would unplug it and throw it in the woods.
Rym: So you're I'm dubious that you'd actually be able to set up something like that.
Scott: I don't see how you could stop me from doing something like that.
Rym: I don't think you could set one up that wouldn't be pretty eminently detectable from the extant evidence on the scene of a crime for example.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: also by making it a crime to modify the device and Basically like making that illegal.
Scott: the thing is you basically even if even if it was detectable, right?
Scott: I can make it pretty hidden Like I could hide it behind like the the numbers on the speedometer or something like that, right?
Scott: So the cops would then be forced to like really take apart every piece of the car, you know to make sure.
Rym: It only matters if you're involved in a case where it did matter.
Rym: and now you've got intent You've got all this kind of premeditation.
Rym: So if you're caught for example, that is a much more serious crime than simply having broken the black.
Scott: But you're assuming if I'm caught this.
Scott: I'm so clever.
Scott: I'm actually I get off the hook.
Scott: Yeah, you're a hundred percent.
Rym: So so let's put it this way.
Rym: then one if your readings don't match up with what is seen in the other cars readings That's already a red flag.
Rym: the other car your car says I only drove 30.
Scott: Reasonable doubt.
Scott: the other car was the one that tampered with the data.
Rym: actually no It's probably not because you can't because remember what.
Rym: you remember those detectives you talked about who are so good.
Rym: So they investigate the scene, huh?
Rym: Scott's box says that he'd never exceeded 31 miles per hour and yet his tires were worn bald and melted slightly.
Rym: And look at these skid marks.
Rym: Oh and the other car matches perfectly with the extent data.
Scott: I could fuck with both cars.
Rym: my easier argument that I was avoiding until now Is that if you're going to argue that we shouldn't do some sort of forensic technique?
Rym: Because our really clever criminal might get out of it so much for our entire legal system I'm just saying is that they would.
Scott: I would be I would sell some sort of Devices.
Rym: we're gonna sell this online where the government can see it and then one no Buy your device and see how it works and know what to look for the same place.
Scott: They sell radar detectors and shit.
Rym: yeah radar detectors.
Rym: the police know exactly how radar detectors work.
Rym: I know and you know what.
Rym: they don't that well because everyone uses lidar.
Scott: radar detectors are shit.
Scott: But the point is that people buy radar detectors anyway, so people would buy my black box tamper.
Rym: Oh, you don't want to help the people you just want to make money.
Scott: No the people causing accidents I don't actually want to help them unless they're me.
Scott: I just wanted to take their money by selling them hacking devices.
Rym: So anyway things of the day Got a thing of the day.
Scott: I do.
Scott: I got this this it's a it's an advertisement.
Scott: Well actually it's a movie trailer.
Scott: Which is the same thing as an advertise.
Scott: really yeah green really?
Scott: So it's.
Scott: it's a romantic comedy movie.
Scott: But actually you know like there's probably not any romantic comedies that I could think of that I actually care about.
Rym: can you even name a rom-com?
Rym: This one name another one.
Rym: Nah you can't even name a single movie that you would call a romantic comedy.
Scott: Not one I mean you.
Scott: maybe you could mention the movie and I could tell you whether it was or wasn't.
Rym: would you consider say?
Rym: Pretty woman a romantic comedy, or is that something else?
Scott: Maybe have you ever seen pretty woman mm-hmm most of it.
Rym: Do you know what it's about?
Scott: horn Good.
Rym: Yeah, technically yeah, all right all right.
Rym: So Scott you're telling me that you think this movie a Romantic comedy.
Rym: I see a poster of a guy and a girl like walking through a forest.
Scott: Yeah, it's called.
Scott: It's called dream with envy, but the trailer I guarantee you know it's like normally.
Scott: You know you see trailers for these movies, and you're like whatever.
Scott: the trailer for this movie is so great.
Scott: It is so absolutely amazing that it will convince you to watch this movie Even if you are kind of like me and or like would never even consider watching it based on the poster.
Rym: God forgets girls anniversary.
Rym: That's the plot the trailer.
Rym: I'm reading the synopsis right now.
Scott: I guess girls anniversary.
Scott: I guarantee you that the trailer to this movie will make you want to watch the movie.
Scott: a hundred percent Guarantee if you trust me on ponies you have to trust me on this movie.
Rym: I Have seen the trailer, and I kind of do want to see the movie, but well, we'll see.
Rym: we'll see what you guys think This is.
Rym: this is an experiment.
Rym: We'll see what people have to say about that.
Rym: So my thing of the day is a man that Scott probably has never heard of.
Scott: I know who it is.
Rym: Do you know what is George Takei famous for Star Trek?
Rym: Oh wow really?
Rym: I don't.
Rym: so who'd he play in Star Trek?
Scott: The Asian guy with the blue uniform.
Rym: Do you know the guy's name?
Rym: or?
Scott: What is George Takei?
Rym: or what is what?
Rym: what his position was on the bridge token Asian guy?
Rym: was he even on the bridge?
Scott: Duh George Washington bridge which Star Trek is he from?
Rym: the first one the first one the first first one the oldest Possible one you're sure.
Scott: I'm guessing.
Rym: yeah, okay anyway, so George Takei is Pretty famous for being a gay activist among other things you know actor and whatnot also being gay and for being Cuz.
Rym: you could be a gay activist without being gay for being a generally funny, dude.
Rym: And he is you know he's also got.
Scott: he also has like the bestest voice.
Rym: He has a really good radio voice And he it's.
Scott: he's like.
Scott: he's just like Peter Fernandez where he still has it even though he's old yep.
Rym: And he has the radio voice even when he's not radio.
Rym: miked.
Rym: I mean Scott and I could have radio voices on GeekNights, but in real life.
Rym: We don't have radio voices and even in GeekNights We don't really have radio voices cuz we don't really like work at doing the microphone technique Just because it's pain in the ass to do that.
Rym: but he really in real life sounds like that.
Rym: and Basically Tennessee if you couldn't you know guess wasn't a state that may be a little bit homophobic And they tried to pass a law that basically well They are passing a law that doesn't let you talk about gayness in schools, okay?
Scott: What if you need to talk about history and there happens to be gayness in the history can't bring it up?
Scott: What if it's part of the curriculum?
Scott: Can't be part of the curriculum whether there's a national standardized test that asks about that history that involves gayness?
Rym: Oh, are you implying that perhaps students in Tennessee are not getting the best education compared to people in other states?
Scott: I don't think I'm implying.
Scott: I'm straight-up saying so.
Rym: George Takei is Basically campaigning against this and other things like it on the internet very funnily and I highly recommend you.
Scott: just it's hard to take It seriously.
Rym: seek out YouTube videos and things related to George Takei because he's a pretty cool guy.
Rym: To quote Wikipedia about him.
Rym: in November 2010 George Takei released a PSA blasting former Arkansas school board member Clint McCants.
Rym: in the video Takei repeatedly called mr.. McClants quotes a douchebag And it it's good stuff.
Rym: George Takei is a pretty cool.
Rym: Dude.
Rym: Maybe not as cool as the four horsemen, but So in the meta moment frosted tips and visors aside the book club book is still Isaac Asimov's foundation.
Rym: We'll get to it when we get to it.
Rym: We're gonna be at PAX Prime.
Rym: We might be a PAX dev doing a bunch of stuff.
Scott: ConnectiCon ConnectiCon is upcoming.
Rym: It's pretty much mostly too late for you to submit your panels.
Rym: Yes, I'm in the midst of scheduling them.
Scott: nerd NYC recesses on Saturday, June 18th.
Scott: Yep Saturday June 25th and 26 is game hack day in New York City.
Scott: How you like that?
Rym: Oh, I was.
Rym: you have any.
Scott: if you have any game programming or hacking skills.
Scott: You should be interested.
Rym: So what do you do with this event?
Scott: hex games and it's basically the way hack days tend to work.
Scott: is you?
Scott: you show up And maybe you have a team And you make a hack you make something and then the day two is usually presenting.
Scott: Uh-huh, and that's that's how the hack days tend to be structured.
Scott: Usually they're things where You know VCS come like this weekend competing with bar camp There was like tech crunch disrupt hack day And you know it's basically the VCS want you to make something so they can see if someone makes the best stuff and then they can try to convince them to Start up crap.
Scott: right, but it is game hack day So I imagine it will be less of that kind of bullshit and more making cool games that are quirky and awesome.
Rym: And of course follow us on Twitter join the forum go to the website forums.
Rym: Awesome.
Rym: People are hanging out in there.
Scott: Yep Not much of the other meta going on.
Scott: Not really.
Scott: It's slow meta times.
Rym: So this week instead of doing work.
Rym: I'm Taking a Python boot camp for the week.
Rym: All right, it's actually pretty good.
Scott: Have you learned anything?
Rym: I've learned a lot of Python.
Scott: Do any skills?
Rym: I'm getting there.
Rym: I actually already in the course of the class.
Rym: just you know, because there's a lot of free time during classes I wrote a pretty simple rules engine this multi-threaded app That'll take SNMP traps in and send formatted emails out based on set of arbitrary rules And I'm working on a web interface for that thing now.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Rym: Yeah, it's really easy to program.
Scott: Is it done?
Rym: Well, it's done.
Rym: Okay I'm not a great coder.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is it's like if you really what if anyone out there actually wants to learn Python You can just take.
Scott: I was telling some people this today and I've told other people in the past you can just take Classes online for free.
Scott: Well, you can go to MIT open courseware and take CS 101 at MIT Which happens to involve Python and you'll learn a whole lot.
Scott: if you take that class and you know all the material from that Class, you know more than most people who actually are hired as programmers.
Scott: Only that's only CS 101 at MIT.
Scott: So if you actually go to MIT you get three more years of that which is one two, three four five six seven more semesters.
Scott: You know what else you can do 1/8 of the MIT education.
Rym: You can buy an O'Reilly book and read it and do the stuff in it and learn Python.
Scott: Yeah, but you know, then you just learn a language, right?
Rym: It depends, for example the learning Python book which they sent me a copy of just in course the training so I have it.
Rym: I was reading it Actually does teach concepts More than it teaches language.
Scott: Yeah, but the CS 101 at MIT is gonna teach you, you know.
Rym: Yeah, well, I guess the O'Reilly book is more for someone really who already knows Programming concepts just needs to learn the language or isn't great at programming but already know like as long as you know Like what objects are and inheritance and like the basic concepts of programming?
Rym: but the point is what bothers me is that Most training like for example this class I'm taking it and I'm you know I'm Fixing all my Python knowledge like I'm filling in all the holes that I had because I kind of just learned it ad hoc as I Had to write stuff out of necessity in the course of my life.
Rym: The only language I knew really well was let's see Perl because I had to use it a lot of work.
Rym: bash Yeah bash because I had more than anything said.
Rym: an awk because I use those almost more than anything except bash.
Rym: and Basic because that was the working language in the IT department.
Rym: basic is so brain-dead anyone can do it I know and C sharp because I had to write a bunch of soap services.
Rym: So Python was kind of on the back burner, even though it's actually my preferred language.
Rym: Like I like it I enjoy using it more than every other language.
Rym: I know.
Rym: Yet I wasn't that good at it because I don't get a chance to use it that often.
Rym: so I wanted to learn it better.
Rym: I could have just spent a week Coding stuff and read through O'Reilly books and I would have learned the same stuff.
Scott: You could have spent I don't know how many how many lectures there are in the MIT open course.
Scott: we could have done to a day and then done the you know, the Done the lessons involved and taking the tests and then in cut in the time in between those lessons Just worked on a project using the knowledge You just learned.
Rym: so the trouble is it is very difficult in the modern world Especially in the US.
Rym: if you work for a company and they want you to learn a skill for the company For them to agree to say all right take a week off and we'll pay you and learn it or Come into the office for a week.
Rym: Don't do your normal work and learn this thing.
Rym: very few companies let people do that.
Scott: Well, I think the reason is is that you know, we are self learners, right?
Scott: I can just learn something, you know, and the other thing is right.
Scott: Why do you even need to take time off the job to learn a thing?
Scott: Right?
Rym: So for example Here's the good example in my job For example, their production thing could happen and I'm the senior engineer.
Rym: So if there's a serious problem, they would want to get me involved.
Rym: So if I'm in the office very often, whatever I'm learning or working on will be interrupted several times per day.
Scott: No, that's not what I'm asking.
Scott: What I'm asking is right.
Scott: so I needed I was doing a job once right and I need to do Some Ruby.
Scott: so it's not like I stopped to learn Ruby or I went to Ruby training.
Scott: I just was.
Scott: I. I was needed to do this work.
Scott: So I started doing the work and learn the Ruby simultaneous to doing the thing I needed to learn Ruby for.
Rym: Ah, you want to know why?
Scott: If you need Python for something at work Just start working on that thing and learn the Python as you do the thing.
Rym: No, because Scott you want to know why?
Rym: Unless you're actually a developer in a large company Like you're actually like your job is developer.
Rym: No one ever budgets time to even make stuff with any reasonable amount of time to make stuff let alone learn stuff.
Rym: So say you have to be learning is simultaneous at the making now because say you have to make a thing they'll budget it Assuming that you'll make it immediately and quickly with tools you already have.
Rym: So as a result like say I could like and say there's a huge thing I got to do.
Rym: I got to parse a bunch of data.
Rym: I could do it shoddily and bash really quickly But I could do it much better and make an extensible thing.
Rym: that would then be very useful down the road in Python.
Rym: But if I'm not super up on my Python it would take me maybe an extra day's worth of work to do it in Python Because I'd have to reference a lot of materials.
Rym: I mean, I don't need to look anything up.
Rym: if I'm writing a giant bash script I have to occasionally look things up when I'm working in Python.
Rym: Like how's that module work?
Scott: I have to look things up no matter what I'm using.
Rym: Yeah, but I have to look things up more.
Rym: I'm slower.
Rym: I'll forget like all right the iter items.
Rym: That's how you go through a dictionary and stuff like that.
Rym: so as a result very rarely do you have the opportunity to do anything where you'll also learn because By nature learning and doing at the same time is slightly slower Than doing shiddily with something you already know, even if what you do ends up being a worse thing Mm-hmm.
Rym: So unless you're a developer most companies will really never actually give you the opportunity To learn anything for real.
Rym: also I will argue that if you learn only by doing like oh, you've got to do that Like, uh, there's an example from my job.
Rym: there's a guy and we have to make a thing like a script basically and Say this guy does it in Perl or Python, which he doesn't know.
Rym: and alright He'll learn Perl or Python as he's making the thing, you know, he'll make the thing.
Rym: He'll learn the language at the same time.
Rym: yep, as a result what comes out is Very poorly written.
Rym: Yeah, and doesn't work that well and crashes.
Scott: Does it get the job done?
Rym: Barely.
Scott: Yeah, is it satisfactory?
Scott: Does it meet the requirement?
Rym: Yes, except that no one else could ever interface with it when I looked at it.
Scott: But is that is interfacing with a part of the requirement?
Rym: I hope he doesn't listen to this show, but is interfacing with it part of the requirement?
Rym: Well, no, they don't write requirement documents because people aren't Scott in the real world unless you're a developer.
Rym: Nobody ever gives you a requirements.
Scott: now I'm not saying does it meet?
Scott: and that doesn't have to be a document.
Scott: No, there's still.
Rym: there's an unwritten requirement Yes, but the unwritten requirements are.
Rym: it did the job and not things like without crashing or really?
Scott: That's not part of the unwritten requirement.
Scott: not crashing because I'm pretty in my in my eyes.
Scott: not crashing as part of the unwritten requirement?
Scott: Yeah, well because if it crashes you fail.
Rym: That's what happens when a non developer who doesn't know object oriented principles and doesn't really know programming languages is writing something in Perl And basically, wow, you're iterating through like ten nested arrays.
Scott: Okay, welcome here.
Rym: Here's a data dictionary.
Rym: do it that way instead, but basically If people who learn by doing who don't already know all the fundamentals will often learn very bad habits by taking a class or by training as you know, like budgeting in a project like alright a week of like a Django boot camp and then beginning the requirements building for this Django website The company has to build it's probably gonna be more fruitful for a group of developers.
Rym: then build this and learn it all at the same time.
Scott: Now here's the other thing right.
Scott: if you know training is all you really need to go from don't know what to do to be Able to do to the work right and how long is the training?
Scott: a week?
Rym: Yeah, this is a boot camp that basically is aimed at alright You're already a programmer and then in the by the end of this week, you will be a pretty average Python developer.
Scott: So why the fuck does anyone need to go to school for four years if they can go to boot camp for a week?
Rym: You want to know why because in in these training things like this at least all the enterprise ones I've been to that are about programming languages They assume that you already know all the fundamentals of computer science.
Rym: If you don't know about like iterations and flow control and data structures and all that stuff you're fucked.
Scott: But couldn't they then teach you that in a one-week boot camp as well?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: you could learn that in less than four years enough to take the thing.
Scott: That's for sure.
Rym: Yeah, you probably could.
Scott: So it's like, you know, what's the point?
Scott: You know if people can just if training is enough for companies to be willing to let you do something then why do they?
Scott: You know, what was the four years of college?
Rym: It's got.
Rym: why'd you go to our IT?
Scott: for the reasons besides education?
Rym: Yeah, that's why I went to our IT.
Rym: Yeah, here's the real benefits of college.
Rym: You have access to the stuff to the materials.
Rym: You need to actually learn if you want to learn.
Rym: You meet all the people who will eventually get you jobs and you get a piece of paper and you have your fun And you have and there's actually, you know, there are chances to become a professor.
Scott: or you know Do?
Scott: there are certain things that you can't do without the advanced learning of the college.
Scott: But if you if you want to do those things, well, you know like be a doctor.
Rym: let's narrow the discussion a little bit because basically When you think of corporate training like training like alright, I work here I'm going to technology training for a week or two to learn X or learn Y. or you know Very rarely are classes like that Fundamentals like learn object-oriented programming or learn conceptual design.
Rym: They're always.
Rym: they're always.
Rym: learn this specific product Yep, or learn this specific Acronym learn this tool and I think the the understanding is that in the industry you should already know the fundamentals you.
Rym: This is kind of training like alright, you need to learn this specific thing quickly.
Rym: We're gonna teach you the best practices and then you'll be good to go.
Rym: You won't learn bad practices You won't go off in the wrong direction.
Rym: But really I'm starting to feel pretty strongly that the majority of corporate style IT training is Bullshit, no It's only there because companies aren't willing to budget the time or trust their employees to learn on their own to learn stuff.
Scott: Well, I think this is training Me this.
Rym: if they've just said if they just said Alright, you don't have to work on anything, but learning Python really well and writing some apps this week I would have gotten the same out of it as this multi-thousand-dollar course.
Scott: We both know that either one of us can learn on our own if we want to right everyone.
Scott: I know other people.
Scott: can they do so?
Scott: Would you trust some strange guy that you hired that you only know through work and you've only got one ago?
Rym: I would not hire someone that I would not trust to learn on their own unless they were doing menial work in which case I Would never let them get training.
Rym: Because the thing is it's funny if you actually go to these training things.
Rym: Have you ever gone to like?
Rym: Corporate like a week or two training like out and not a week or two.
Scott: But I've gone to you know, like individual one-day classes things and they were always boring and useless.
Rym: so in those cases How many of the people who are in the class with you clearly didn't want to be there and weren't?
Rym: they were just surfing the net The whole time and not paying attention.
Scott: the vast majority.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, so if you give someone if you let someone come into the office and learn on their own It's a lot easier to kind of notice if they're actually learning or not.
Rym: Then if you send them flying off to Vegas for a week to go to a class where you can't keep an eye on them And that cost thousands of dollars more and probably has the same effect nothing.
Rym: I Just I'm.
Rym: I'm kind of sick of corporate training as a thing.
Scott: Well, I mean there are times when corporate training could be the real deal, right?
Scott: I mean it depends on exactly what you're being trained in like let's say, you know Like you go work at a job and and there's a machine involved and it's a very, you know Specific machine like some sort of manufacturing robot or something like that and it's got all sorts of crazy controls.
Scott: Well, you're gonna pay fucking attention.
Scott: that training so the robot doesn't like rip your arm off true, right?
Rym: You know at the same time that's operational training as opposed to development training.
Rym: There are very different things you think is different.
Rym: Yeah like for example.
Rym: think here's the difference between.
Rym: there's training like say that you want to teach someone how to Manage a clustered Linux environment.
Rym: That's very different from teaching someone how to design a clustered Linux environment.
Rym: I mean it.
Rym: they're very different skill sets.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: So that's like or a factory.
Rym: It's very different to teach someone how to operate the machine that pushes the widget in Versus troubleshoot the machine that pushes the widget in or build the machine that pushes the which.
Scott: but usually there would be like You know a document that tells you how to troubleshoot the machine like you get a copy machine and it's like it.
Scott: did this error Appear look at find it in this book.
Scott: follow these instructions, you know, what happened?
Scott: my turn to this page.
Scott: follow these instructions.
Rym: my experience In all my years of enterprise IT that instruction book for every printer in the world says the following Stand around looking at it poke at it a few times call the company and pay them to have someone come in and fix it.
Scott: No, it's already already.
Scott: Don't forget.
Rym: Don't forget the very important step.
Rym: roll it out and look at the back Ineffectually for like 10 minutes already paid for the service contract.
Scott: So call them without even poking it at all.
Rym: Yep That's a separate thing.
Rym: nobody in the goddamn world knows how to use their fancy printers.
Scott: But like if I was a company I would actually just buy those fancy printers straight up instead of getting there Easy to administer.
Scott: Yeah and fix and plus I'd buy the high-quality ones.
Rym: Yeah, cuz they're great, but no one knows how to use them.
Rym: I mean I print stuff double-sided.
Scott: It's like wizardry colors double-side folding binding.
Scott: Oh Collating and sorting.
Rym: actually ours doesn't collate or staple or any of that stuff.
Scott: Yeah We don't really need any of that cuz I don't print.
Rym: that.
Rym: in fact The only time I print is stupid like metric reports for people that I don't really care about I don't have.
Rym: my job became crystal reports.
Scott: I don't print.
Scott: I Wouldn't print if I didn't have to generate crystal reports for people and they need him print it out that you get his email them.
Rym: Yeah, don't get.
Scott: why don't they get some crystal reports training and then they could do it themselves?
Rym: Yeah, they want.
Rym: I wanted crystal reports training, but they didn't give it to me.
Rym: So I just Did it.
Rym: I just learned how to use it cuz it's not that hard.
Scott: You just learned how to use it on your own.
Rym: That's impossible Ah, but it took like four hours to make reports.
Scott: cuz crystal report sucks.
Rym: No, but I can't think of a better tool SQL.
Rym: Yeah, you're gonna make pretty fancy multi-dimensional graphs that actually do show data correlations just with SQL.
Scott: well No, I do the SQL.
Scott: then I would take the data that came from the query Yeah into the Excel and then use that to make the fancy charts.
Rym: Yeah, Excel makes shit charts.
Rym: No, you think so and for that kind of stuff.
Rym: Yeah I'll show you one of my charts.
Rym: I'll show you what I did.
Rym: They're actually pretty good.
Rym: But that's that's a separate discussion.
Rym: We should do a show on like data mining.
Scott: I think I don't know enough about data.
Rym: my really I do a lot of data mining Anyway, but I think you can actually split corporate training into you know, forget operational or whatever.
Rym: the real classes of it I think are classes that teach someone who already knows basic IT skills or CS skills a Specific tool to do something like.
Rym: you're already an IT guy.
Rym: Here's how to use red hat clustering.
Rym: Here's how to use the RBD Mm-hmm.
Rym: I think that kind of training is actually really useful.
Scott: I could use that the RBD trading.
Rym: I did a class on that.
Rym: We had a guy come in and teach us postgres and the RBD together like how to do that.
Rym: It was very focused and everyone knew what they were doing was like, alright, you want to do something like this?
Rym: Here's exactly how to do it how it works how to troubleshoot it.
Rym: We're done.
Rym: got any questions.
Scott: I Once that was like, you know, there's a new version of X coming out.
Scott: Here are the things that have changed in this new version.
Scott: right good what?
Scott: and any questions?
Scott: And by the way, I'm the guy who made this thing.
Rym: But then there are the enterprise tool classes like.
Rym: you bought this fancy enterprise monitoring system.
Rym: Here is the training that you bought.
Rym: that cost like ten thousand dollars to teach three of your employees how to use this piece of shit.
Rym: Every kind of training like that.
Rym: I've ever been to in all my years of IT has been absolutely worthless.
Scott: Yeah, I wish there was a way to like, you know Figure out before you get the training like if it's worthless or not.
Rym: I think it's really easy case in point.
Rym: Here's this how I do it.
Rym: one is the training.
Scott: it is a training review site or something like that.
Rym: is the training for a Proprietary enterprise product?
Rym: if yes training will be stupid.
Rym: I'm pretty sure that is without exception.
Scott: But the thing is a prize or enterprise product.
Scott: How can you learn how to use it without the training?
Rym: It's not like yeah And you know what the answer is.
Rym: nobody knows how to use it not even the trainer.
Rym: no no no I went to.
Rym: So service desk Express put up by BMC.
Rym: I'll call out their stupid names because whatever I hate them so much is possibly one of the worst ticketing systems in the world.
Rym: and The training basically the manuals useless.
Rym: It doesn't actually tell you how to use the product like half the stuff.
Rym: It tells you oh Here's how to do this won't actually work on any scale and it's inconsistent and things just don't work the way you expect.
Rym: So you have to take training to learn how to use the product because the training Almost all enterprise training is aimed at the lowest common denominator Like they expect people who aren't super techies to be showing up to this training.
Rym: So the training starts on a level that is pointless baby talk and usually doesn't get much farther than okay.
Rym: You started it.
Scott: click the X button to close the window.
Rym: Here's hot like and they always focus on very obtuse and Complicated parts of the software that no one cares about or will use and don't even talk about The very important things that aren't actually documented.
Rym: Those things yeah, and the instructors usually don't know or They do know and the answer they give you is usually prefaced by yeah Well, this isn't in the documentation But here's how you really do it and it's something complete like BS like yeah The ASP and insert your JavaScript or whatever.
Rym: Oh, yeah go on the back end and do this database update And the classes always start late and early and just suck and cost Ludicrous amounts of money.
Scott: Well, I mean, you know some come one company's stupid willing to pay for training.
Scott: Another company is gonna be smart.
Rym: Yeah, our jalopah training and you'll notice Many of the enterprise training I've been to.
Rym: if you ever go to this stuff You'll see half the people there have been using the product for a long time and the product doesn't work anymore.
Rym: Or they have problems and they were sent by their management to the training to learn what they were doing wrong.
Scott: Why don't?
Scott: but the thing is, you know, if something is broken you don't call you don't get training you get support.
Rym: Oh enterprise support is useless.
Rym: I've never gotten good support from any enterprise level product ever.
Scott: I don't know if it's enterprise level but there have been times where I've gotten good support like you call Developers.
Rym: on the other end Microsoft has pretty great support.
Scott: Microsoft does even Xbox support.
Rym: It's a great Twiki wiki of all things actually has pretty good support.
Scott: Like I've got an open source thing.
Scott: Nah, yeah, but sort of how do you get support for it?
Rym: There's there's Peter Tony and this other guy who are kind of like the main developers for it and you can post a bug and they'll Usually respond.
Rym: I emailed them and they responded once like they answered my questions.
Rym: Okay, actually contracted one of them I forget which one for like 70 pounds to write a like replication plug-in for me.
Scott: No work.
Rym: It did really well.
Rym: I eventually phased it out because there was a bug where one day our remote site wasn't available.
Rym: So it replicated nothing to the local share Destroying the entire Twiki.
Rym: and then when the remote site came back up it said oh there have been changes And it updated the whole thing again.
Rym: and then no there were changes.
Rym: So it replicated the empty Twiki to the remote site.
Rym: Yeah, I had to restore the whole thing from tape.
Scott: Tape whoa.
Scott: Yeah, you don't have like the reason you don't use tape for like the week old or at least month old But you got to keep the more recent ones on discs.
Rym: Yeah, I guess it's very rare for me to need a backup of anything, right?
Scott: But the point is like you got to keep the recentest backups on something.
Scott: that's fast.
Scott: So you otherwise tape.
Scott: It's.
Rym: yeah, it depends on how your tapes are set up.
Rym: What tape is fast, uh, depending on your automated cartridge systems I have had really fast access to tapes.
Rym: In fact at IBM.
Rym: We had a place where there was a robot a Gigantic robot that could fetch tapes with such speed that it was ludicrous.
Scott: Yeah But the point is to read to.
Scott: when you read a tape you have to read it straight through.
Scott: you can't scan.
Scott: You need to read the whole tape from beginning to end usually.
Scott: Yeah, so that could be a pain.
Rym: Well, I won't get into the details.
Rym: You want like ice it to style.
Rym: Enterprise training is mostly useless.
Rym: Yep You're better off hiring a consultant to teach you Cheaper how to use the product for real.
Rym: then you are getting official support.
Scott: Thing is I kind of want to you know.
Scott: Give training because I feel like I could give training on things.
Scott: I know that's really good.
Rym: I would be pretty qualified to give training on some of these bullshit enterprise products Yeah, and judging from the consulting and I would kind of like doing that if it paid enough Yeah, get to travel a lot.
Rym: I think it could be fun.
Rym: Yeah, I Just the third kind of corporate training is the soft training like leadership or project management.
Scott: Bullshit, they're just so.
Scott: space.
Scott: leap to conclusions crap.
Rym: The thing is they could be good.
Rym: I could imagine a class that teaches like project management.
Rym: That is like here's how to deal with sizing.
Rym: Here's not actually size an IT project.
Rym: Here's how budgeting really works and how to really do it.
Rym: Here's what you know as my experience 20 years being a project manager.
Rym: Here are the things that you'll always fuck up.
Rym: Here's how you can avoid fucking.
Scott: the main problem I have with things like that, right?
Scott: It's like somebody will teach you here's how to size a project right and they'll say take all these factors into account.
Scott: Right, like you don't got to worry about this.
Scott: You got to worry about this You got to worry about this, right?
Scott: But they don't actually tell you like follow these this exact process to come up with the exact You know fit number that you're looking for.
Scott: They'll never give you that because it doesn't exist, right?
Scott: There's no such thing.
Rym: So you want them to give you something that doesn't exist, right?
Scott: But that's that's the point.
Scott: It's like they're basically telling you, you know, this sort of my criticism is much more general.
Rym: I think there's a fundamental flaw in that kind of training.
Rym: I think the problem is and I noticed this first at RIT with the public speaking classes that I took Because I you know, I thought that'd be cool.
Rym: so I took a long class on public speaking and like oratory and rhetoric and By and large I found people who are drawn to classes that teach things like leadership or public speaking Tend to be terrible at leadership and public speaking and think that they can get better at it by taking a class.
Rym: so as a result classes like that tend to focus on things like Don't freak out if you're publicly speaking Don't stutter Don't like pee yourself on stage.
Rym: You don't get the advanced topics You don't get the people who are like don't actually make eye contact.
Rym: But look at everyone's eyebrows and you know You know look at the audience like 45% of the time between back and forth or you know All the tricks that I actually know as a pretty expert public speaker.
Scott: Yeah I mean there was this guy at bar camp this weekend and he was talking about how he's doing this sort of Collaborative training right where like his idea is that instead of having a trainer, right?
Scott: They still do have trainers and students.
Scott: But basically his idea is get the students to teach each other right as opposed to having a teacher teach the class, right?
Scott: so people will show up and you'll give them a Real project to do and they have to team up and do the projects, you know and in doing so we'll learn.
Rym: I had a class like that actually during the Democratic primaries.
Rym: while we're
Scott: like, yeah So if you wanted to teach someone Python, for example with this method, it would be like, alright Everyone shows up and you'd be like, alright, here's what you guys have to make in Python team up together and Do it and in doing so and all working together on it You will all you know by the end of taking many classes over the course of many weeks Learn the Python because you just used it to do a thing.
Rym: So in the lead-up to the Democratic primaries.
Rym: for while we were at RIT way back, you know, John Kerry and all that I took a seminar a seminar on political theory and there are only like eight people in the class.
Rym: Gah, gah.
Rym: So the professor was like, alright, we'll do this as a straight-up seminar and he broke the quarter up.
Rym: You know ten weeks into eight units and at each student teach a unit.
Scott: so easy for that teacher.
Rym: Yeah, and you know what?
Rym: He sat in the audience and asked tough-ass motherfucking questions.
Rym: Yeah, and that was possibly the most fun I had in all my time at our.
Scott: now.
Scott: see on paper That sounds like a good idea and I don't only works if everyone involved is motivated and intelligent.
Scott: Well, he did mention that a lot of people dropped out but the people who stayed were incredibly motivated actually would stay extra hours.
Scott: Right, and you know, I definitely believe that people do it in taking this sort of class will learn a lot You know and will make you know, we'll definitely make some significant progress.
Scott: The thing is Like just what you were saying.
Scott: the people who are in this thing are people who are way down low and at best it's gonna Bring them up to the middle level.
Rym: Mediating factor and instructor who guides.
Scott: Yeah, but even with the instructor who guides right?
Scott: It's like it's like you get people who are way down low mostly learning together with people who are way down low so they can Help each other, you know get to the finish line, but they're not gonna learn the ink.
Scott: You know, especially when it comes to technology there is this incredibly high-level Esoteric stuff no matter what you're doing that you're not gonna learn Scott The only way to learn that stuff in my opinion is to run into it doing real work.
Rym: Two things one by having a classical education.
Rym: So you have just a wide variety of knowledge and experience from school Yeah, or just from life, you know, you can get a classical education without going to school Yeah, and two just by being around long enough to see enough shit
Scott: Yeah, but that's the thing is like, you know.
Rym: so that's the thing.
Rym: people you people have misplaced expectations of training and I think the the reason they're misplaced is because they will see people who go to training and succeed.
Rym: I think the people who succeed as a result of training in most cases didn't need the training to begin with.
Rym: Yeah, they're self motivated enough to where they would have learned it on their own if given the time.
Rym: Yeah So the people who see that they have this mystical idea and you see this in colleges too that I don't know computers if I go To a computer school.
Rym: I'll graduate being a computer expert Kind of like the tourists who think if I go to New York City, New York City will entertain me.
Rym: Yeah, I think that's exactly what happens.
Rym: They think that training is magical that if I go to training I will come out knowing everything not realizing that it takes Almost the exact same amount of effort to learn in a training class as it does to learn on your own.
Rym: And if you don't have the motivation to you're not learn on your own You're not gonna do that.
Rym: Well in a class in most cases pretty
Scott: much the only thing the only value that I see in getting training Right as opposed to learn it on my own by doing or reading a book or both or internet or whatever Is that at the training you if the if the person giving the training is really an expert person Which is not always true.
Scott: But if they are really an expert person then you can ask them the questions that you know and get instant full answers You know with all the details fleshed out that you might not be able to get from say Stack Overflow or something like that.
Rym: Yep, like I had a question about because we're you know Python 3 versus 2 There are some differences and I had a question about one of the differences and the instructor who actually lectures if I can I can often was like oh and he basically had as Much depth as I wanted and there was probably a lot more there.
Scott: if I wanted to go deeper I've also heard stories right of people going to things like Apple Developer conference or Microsoft equivalent of the same thing, you know, whatever they call it these days right or you know, Google's What do they call it?
Scott: They just had it recently the Google I/o.
Scott: right and you go if you go to those things and you have something that's really really niche like you go to Microsoft and you're writing some Windows app and You've got a problem with this really deep down Like Windows something API Call somewhere and the MSDN documentation isn't enough and no one on Stack Overflow is helping you.
Rym: So the guy who wrote that is right.
Scott: It's not a training.
Scott: It's a developer conference.
Scott: But if you go there, you're going to Microsoft you're going to Google or to Apple You can find the guy whose job it is for that thing and you can get the magical answer that you've been looking for.
Scott: You know, it's not training But it's that it's in the same way that I think the value has the same value as training which is Direct access in person to the one or two people on earth who have the expert knowledge in the thing that you're looking for.
Scott: That is so specific, right?
Scott: So if it's a good trainer It almost doesn't matter if the training is worthless because if you have a problem You're basically paying those thousands whatever to get the answer to that question that you so desperately need.
Scott: So it's like, you know You can build up a whole list of questions if you get them all answered.
Scott: Look at the price and figure out if it was worth it.
Scott: Like would you have paid to get those hands?
Rym: Yeah Yeah, I guess my thesis.
Scott: but then again You could just do the same thing by hiring that trainer as a consultant for a day to ask him the questions.
Rym: There's a blurred line between.
Rym: when you go to training vert like a lot of training places offer Hey, we'll just send the instructor to your company.
Rym: However, many people you want to sit in the room can sit in the room and we'll do whatever you want me to do.
Rym: Yeah, that's actually usually I think a great idea.
Scott: it's the same thing as a consultant.
Rym: Oh, it is a concern.
Scott: you're hiring consultant.
Scott: You can tell that consultant to do work or you can tell them to.
Scott: you can just ask them questions Or you could have them trained.
Scott: you could have them do whatever you want.
Rym: Yeah, but I guess my thesis on all this because you know, I'm in training right now And it's actually pretty good, but I could have done without the training.
Rym: I am looking forward to.
Rym: in July I'm going to a C++ boot camp, which is basically it's actually Probably slightly above my level of coding C++, which is slowly fading Yes, but very slowly.
Scott: It's a slowest fade in the possible yeah universe.
Scott: it'll
Rym: be useful to me because in the enterprise world a lot of things are written in C++ and being an engineer in the manner that I am I often need to interface between guy who wrote a complex multi-threaded C++ or C or objective C demon and Someone who is not that technical and I have to be able to mediate between the two like say an operations guy Finds what he thinks is a bug, but he can't describe like he knows what's not going right But he doesn't know why it's not going right and the engineer who wrote the demon doesn't know enough about the business process To figure out what went wrong.
Rym: You need someone who knows the IT side and the business side and can actually look at the code and understand what the demon Was trying to do to explain to the developer.
Rym: Here's what really happened.
Rym: There's a thread condition.
Rym: that happening is I don't understand why you need Python training and C++ training Because I wanted C sharp training cuz that'll actually really useful to me and they said it.
Rym: then they decided that C sharp.
Rym: There wasn't a good business case for me learning it in the company.
Scott: But the thing is right.
Scott: why do you need training for more than one language period?
Scott: it's like if you can you know?
Rym: You just look up the syntax and you feel to read any language mostly because the boot camp for C++ I think would have really forced me to learn more better coding practices.
Scott: No, it doesn't.
Scott: C++ isn't gonna teach you good It's gonna teach you bad coding.
Scott: You see C++ is basically.
Scott: it's an object-oriented language But you can also write in C kinda and it's also.
Scott: the syntax is a complete mess.
Scott: There's all sorts of crazy symbols everywhere.
Rym: Yeah No, I like Python and this is the training I wanted.
Rym: C++ was kind of my silver medal because I couldn't get what I really wanted.
Scott: But you know if you can read, you know, if you can read any program language You can probably read the C++.
Scott: and if you see a weird symbol just look it up.
Scott: You don't need training for it Yeah, but that you know training happens is?
Rym: I work in enterprise?
Rym: But Anyway, I guess my thesis in all this is that training.
Rym: a lot of companies will send people on training when really They would be much better off giving the people the time to learn it either at home with like, okay Take a week off and learn this thing or hey, don't do any work, but learning this thing.
Rym: Because the people who are motivated will learn the thing regardless of whether they go to training or you give them time and the people Motivated aren't gonna learn any more at the training.
Rym: then they're gonna learn if you give them the time off.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: so really you should just figure out who you think is not motivated and never let them learn anything and If possible get rid of them and hire someone who is motivated.
Scott: But I mean what you know, there might be someone who you know, they might not be motivated to learn new things But they are good at a thing already and you need that thing that they're right.
Rym: But what if they need to learn something else and they're not motivated?
Rym: Don't send them to training if you know, they're not gonna learn.
Scott: that's obvious.
Rym: Yeah Definitely, but I think a lot of companies send people to training Thinking that that will somehow make them learn a lot of times.
Scott: She's better off hiring someone else who knows the thing that you need to know rather than training someone you already have Yep, or hiring a consultant or outsourcing or all those things.
Scott: Yeah, it's like hi.
Scott: I've got these guys.
Scott: They all know.
Scott: X I need.
Scott: Suddenly we got product.
Scott: why coming in here Do I train these guys in product?
Scott: why?
Scott: or just hire someone who already knows product?
Rym: Why that's so much easier time?
Rym: too many job postings require very specific knowledge of specific things that almost no one's actually gonna know.
Rym: Well, that's you know separate problem Yeah, but companies put way too much stock in training and don't trust their workers nearly enough.
Rym: if you're paying someone a lot of money because you Nominally Understand that they're intelligent you're paying them for the fact that they're an intelligent person who can make decisions.
Rym: if you then Like don't trust them to be motivated enough to learn something that's important to their job on their own Then why are you paying the smart person?
Rym: You could get someone less skilled to do the same job.
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Scott: if you don't if you're not gonna let someone make a decision Why do you need to hire someone who's smart enough to make a decision?
Scott: hire someone who is incapable of making decision?
Scott: And you'll pay them a lot less and you'll make all the decisions that you're already making.
Rym: And if your company ever buys really big and bloated enterprise software and you get to go to training Think of it as a week-long vacation somewhere boring.
Scott: It could be in Vegas.
Rym: Yeah, usually the training ends up being in North Carolina or down by DC.
Rym: Actually a lot of it's in the financial district.
Rym: So you get to go to New York.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.