Rym: It's Thursday, July 14th, 2011.
Scott: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: After a long hiatus, we are back to talk about fuckin' nothin'.
Rym: Let's do this.
Scott: It's all your idea.
Rym: It is my idea, 'cause you know what?
Rym: I had an idea.
Scott: It's all you.
Rym: No idea.
Rym: I got nothin'.
Scott: That's alright, we got nothin'.
Rym: We got nothin', we are nothin', we are.
Rym: So yeah, we are.
Scott: Why, and why is it that we have nothing?
Rym: Well, for a number of reasons.
Scott: What is the number one reason?
Rym: Number one reason is that, uh, stuff's happenin' in my, as in, you know, Rym's, personal life, involving work and possibly, uh, career changes and such that are a big deal, so I didn't finish reading Foundation.
Rym: You had how long?
Rym: I started reading it a day and a half ago.
Scott: How long ago, how long has this been the Book Club book?
Scott: A while.
Scott: How long have you had the book in your possession?
Rym: Uh, a while.
Scott: And how short is the book?
Rym: The book's gonna take me about another hour to read.
Scott: So, what, how many hours, uh, between when I announced the Book Club book and now, did you spend, say, for example, drawing boxes on your desktop?
Rym: I have not drawn yet one, more than one box on my desktop at a time because of that CollegeHumor video.
Scott: Okay, uh, playing Team Fortress 2, or generally, dickin' around.
Rym: I played Team Fortress 2 once in that entire span.
Scott: Alright, how long, how many hours did you spend, quote, "dickin' around"?
Rym: Uh, not so much, actually.
Rym: So, actually, I've been workin' on stuff.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Rym: Because, you know, we're, we're doin' our, you know, PAX stuff is comin' up, so I've been editing together the other two panels we did at PAX East last year to get them online.
Rym: So, rather than duplicating panels, as we always have every year, where if you go to PAX Prime, you basically see the old stuff now from PAX East.
Rym: We're gonna mix it up.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: But I'm trying to put a lot of the stuff that, you know, PAX people need to see, but they just couldn't get into the room or whatever online, so I'm workin' on that.
Rym: I'm workin' on some pony videos that I'd wanna finish now.
Scott: Didn't you say you would do them every Wednesday, but meanwhile, you've missed three Wednesdays.
Rym: Oh, not RFE, I gotta, we need to record some new ones before I wanna put up more old ones.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Rym: Yeah, yeah.
Rym: Mostly because we recorded them all in one go, so we keep goin' back to the same few, like, I gotta intersperse a different kind of episode in between all those episodes.
Rym: Anyway, plus we recorded that last few kinda hastily at the last second.
Rym: And, you know, Connecticut happened.
Rym: We're the heads of the panels and workshops department, which meant, you know, the week before the con, I was just dealin' with bullshit every day.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: Yeah, well, we're back in business now.
Rym: Yeah, we're back.
Rym: Returning to our regular schedule.
Rym: We would've done a Tuesday show.
Rym: Got a lot of Tuesday stuff to talk about.
Rym: But, uh, I had to go do something that, again, is related to careers and money and, and travelin' the world doin' exactly what it is that I wanna be doin'.
Scott: We did a, we did a, we would've done a Monday Wednesday this week, right?
Scott: Because, you know, we, we last did a Tuesday Thursday week, but the problem is, is we've now actually scheduled gaming every other Tuesday and every other Wednesday.
Scott: So, when we're not doing a Wednesday show, we're doing board games, and we're not doing a Tuesday show on Tuesday, we're doing a Burning Wheel.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So, the thing is, so now, because of that, we can't shift the GeekNights schedule.
Scott: It's locked in.
Scott: So, like, for example, if we do a Tuesday Thursday week, and we miss the next week, we're gonna do two Tuesday Thursday weeks in a row with a blank week in between and, you know, instead of- Blank, flank.
Scott: Where in the past, we would've switched to Monday Wednesday anyway.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So, lots of stuff.
Rym: Also, you know, ever since we scheduled those things, I've just been doin' a lot more.
Rym: I think it's because the sun is out, it's warm, I've been out doin' shit, like, every day.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: It's, I don't know, this is, I think, the busiest summer of my entire life.
Scott: We'll see what happens.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I've got, I realized I have more things I want to plan that require an entire weekend than there are weekends left of summer already.
Scott: That's why we gotta retire.
Rym: Yeah, we gotta, well, we'll see.
Rym: For this new job thing, we'll see how much money I have in a few years.
Scott: So, there's an interesting thing that happened, right?
Scott: This dude in Indonesia, right?
Scott: Was, uh, he had a camera.
Scott: And he left the camera in the woods.
Scott: Maybe by accident, maybe on purpose.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: He left the camera in the woods.
Scott: And some monkeys came, took the camera, and took photos of themselves.
Rym: Oh, good for them.
Scott: And the photos are pretty cute.
Scott: They're pretty cute monkeys.
Scott: Someone noticed that these photos had copyright notices on them, right?
Rym: Well, clearly, these are for the monkeys.
Rym: Because the monkeys took the pictures, they're pictures.
Scott: Right, so there was a discussion over who had the copyright.
Scott: But, the news agency of the journalist who owned the camera sent a message to the site where people were discussing this.
Rym: Right, it was what, TechDirt?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And was like, "Hey, take those down.
Scott: We own the copyright on
Scott: those.".
Rym: Oh, wow.
Rym: Not only that, it looks like TechDirt responded and saying basically, "We don't believe you have
Rym: copyright.".
Rym: And now they're refusing to talk to them.
Scott: Yeah, so this is really interesting, right?
Scott: Because it's like, okay, you know, what if I, let's say I was going to make a painting, right?
Scott: And all I did was I took a canvas, right?
Scott: And I took three buckets of paint, and I put them in front of the canvas, right?
Scott: And I put it in like a museum or something.
Scott: So there's three buckets of paint, three paint brushes, and a big empty canvas, and it's an art installation.
Scott: And I leave it there, right?
Scott: And then, of course, it's in a museum, and people come in and they start painting.
Scott: Do I own the copyright of the painting?
Scott: Well, in that case, I think it would depend- It's part of my art installation.
Rym: Do people have to agree to some sort of terms when they enter the museum or the exhibit?
Rym: I mean, maybe it says, you know, "Anything you do is now art and property of the museum," or something.
Scott: Alright, maybe.
Scott: Now what if I put the buckets of paint, say, I just leave them in a precarious position?
Rym: Ah, accidental art.
Scott: And some sort of, you know, I do it in California, and I wait for an earthquake, and it's basically set up so that when an earthquake happens, then the art's gonna be made.
Rym: Well, again, it's obvious.
Rym: The mole men get the copyright.
Rym: That's right.
Rym: I guess, I mean, accidental art is even separate from all this, because who gets the copyright on accidental art?
Rym: I don't know, and I don't know any lawyers who know.
Scott: Yeah, how about that photo that was around the internet yesterday or the day before of the accidental Western scene, you know, that was made by the water splashing up against this pier?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Poseidon can have whatever copyright he wants.
Rym: Yeah, you know what?
Scott: Poseidon, I don't- He shows up in court, and he says, "That belongs to me,".
Scott: then yeah, it does.
Rym: You don't fuck with Poseidon, because he's a dick.
Scott: He's my man.
Rym: He's the best.
Rym: Or what about?
Rym: there's that College Humor video of the seagull that stole that guy's camera?
Scott: Oh, yeah, right.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I don't know what the law is about that, but I don't think any human should have the right to copyright to accidental art.
Scott: Now, what if I steal something that belongs to you, right?
Scott: So, I steal your car.
Rym: All right, you steal my car.
Scott: And then I make a sculpture out of the car that I've stolen from you.
Rym: Obviously, I'm guilty of grand theft auto, but besides the point- I believe I get my car back, because whatever you do with stolen property, whoever ends up owning it, if it's determined to be stolen, they're fucked, and you just get it back.
Scott: But it is no longer your car.
Scott: It has been transformed, right?
Scott: So, while you do own the car, your car doesn't even exist anymore.
Scott: It is now a work of art that is a sculpture that intellectually belongs to me.
Scott: I'm still guilty of grand theft auto.
Rym: I think I should get the art.
Scott: You should get the art.
Rym: Even though- I think I should get the art.
Scott: There are other things that are in the art that weren't yours.
Rym: Where'd he get it?
Rym: Did he steal it from other people?
Scott: No, I bought the rest of the parts at Home Depot.
Rym: If I were a judge, and I had discretion, I would say- I would transfer the copyright to the guy who owned the most expensive thing that was stolen.
Scott: Yeah, that's just a common sense sort of eye for an eye situation, but I'm just saying, you know.
Rym: Let's use a simpler example.
Rym: I steal your air conditioner.
Rym: All right.
Rym: I take all the copper out of it.
Rym: I melt it down.
Rym: I sell it to a guy.
Rym: He then makes a different air conditioner out of it.
Rym: Do you get the air conditioner, or what?
Scott: How about you take the copper out of my air conditioner, melt it down, and make a statue out of it.
Scott: Ah.
Scott: Make a little mini bust.
Rym: Now, luckily, we have this thing called currency in a modern society.
Rym: So I think in all these cases, it comes down to, you get from the person who caused the crime, or committed the crime, money equivalent to what you lost.
Scott: That's an obvious solution.
Scott: I know.
Scott: But I'm talking about- So who owns the copyright?
Rym: Yeah, if you're gonna think copyright should exist- I think, well, in the statue case, in the statue case, the guy who made the statue has the copyright on the statue, even though the state's going to take the statue away from him.
Scott: Let's pretend it's a perfect world, or some sort of much, you know, copyright is reformed in the way that we nerds would like it to be reformed.
Scott: There's no copyright.
Rym: It doesn't matter then.
Scott: Well, you know, but who would you give attribution to?
Rym: Ah, the original artist.
Scott: Really?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: With the monkey?
Rym: In this case, I think yeah, because- Or the camera owner.
Rym: Does it come down, did the monkey do it on purpose?
Scott: Because if it's completely accidental, then you should know what- You can't know if a monkey did it on purpose or not.
Rym: Now, here's the same thing.
Rym: What if I set up a camera that's time-lapse, and I just get a time-lapse of a sunset?
Rym: Is that my art?
Rym: If I film a completely natural phenomena, I mean, I did the act of filming, our copyright law already covers that.
Rym: that's my work.
Rym: My picture of the sunset is mine, even though the sunset itself is not mine.
Scott: Well, this is the thing, right?
Scott: Remember the case that was pretty recent about the guy who had the album cover that was a pixelated version of a different album cover?
Rym: And it's not like.
Rym: he just put it in Photoshop and ran a filter.
Rym: It was a redrawn art that was clear parody of or homage to the original.
Scott: Yeah, but it's like, even if he did, it's still, you take one thing, you apply creativity and something else to that thing to create a new work of art, right?
Scott: It's a transformative act of, you know, creation.
Scott: You took something that existed, you added creativity to it, and then made something new.
Scott: Now, I feel that our copyright law- Yeah, how much the degree of transformation is completely subjective, right?
Scott: It's like, I could take a Monet and change one dot on it, right?
Rym: Now, I would argue the best way to define that would be a slightly loose definition that would give the courts more leeway.
Scott: I think the courts do have that leeway.
Rym: Yeah, but I'm saying the definition I would use is something along the lines of, if it could be, to a reasonable person, a full replacement for the original work, then it is not transformative.
Rym: It is, in fact, to be considered the original work.
Rym: So if I take, I don't know, Citizen Kane, and I add one pixel to it in the middle, it's still Citizen Kane, and I don't get any rights to that.
Rym: I don't get Citizen Kane and dots.
Rym: But if I change the end, then in the very least, if I make a new ending to Citizen Kane-
Scott: But the thing is, Citizen Kane and dot, you might think, okay, it's just a replacement for Citizen Kane, but if you could present it in such a way as to where it would be a really nose stuck up kind of work of art, like, you know, one pixel in this movie has been changed, can you find it?
Scott: You know, it's like, oh, if you presented it in the right way, you could, right?
Rym: It's not about what you actually- Ah, but, but, but, but, and here's my down argument.
Rym: What is the stated purpose of copyright?
Scott: For the progress of the useful arts and sciences?
Rym: So our only goal is to ensure that more works are made.
Rym: That's our goal.
Rym: We want artists to make more works.
Rym: We don't care why or how they make them.
Rym: All we care about is that more art is made.
Scott: Actually, it doesn't say anything about quantity.
Scott: It says progress.
Rym: So we want art to progress in some general fashion.
Scott: Yeah, progress doesn't mean more.
Scott: It just means progress.
Scott: Well, you could argue- Does progress mean more and or better or one or the other or both?
Rym: You could argue that it's at least one obvious- According to who?
Rym: One obvious reading of that would be- My progress is another man's deaconess.
Rym: We want painters to continue to make paintings.
Rym: We want scientists to continue to science.
Scott: Maybe we're better off without paintings.
Scott: That would be progress.
Scott: Someone might say, someone might say so.
Rym: I know, and I would look at them and I would just kind of laugh and smile and let them go on their merry idiot way.
Scott: I'm just saying, someone might say so.
Scott: It's subjective.
Rym: If our only goal is this, generally, we want people to continue to create regardless of the real world incentives.
Rym: We want there to be a system.
Rym: Copyright is there to get people to continue to create and to not just give up, to not just stop.
Rym: Because if there was zero copyright or zero patents or anything, then there's no reason to make something if it costs you anything to make it unless it's something you personally want to be made.
Scott: Well, there would still be plenty of people making stuff, but there would be some forms of making that would go away or some structures around forms of making that would go away.
Rym: But if this is our goal, one way to fix everything is to enslave all of the artists and scientists and force them to make.
Rym: That would, other than violating other amendments, it would violate some amendments to our constitution, that's for sure.
Rym: Or we could at least say that a natural work is not subject to copyright because no law will cause the earth to more or less make cool things happen.
Scott: Oh, that is an excellent point.
Rym: I'm very proud of that.
Rym: I was thinking about this all day.
Rym: I was looking at that Western scene and I was like...
Scott: Ideally, the idea is you're trying to create an incentive for people to create more work.
Scott: Well, accidental art doesn't need an incentive.
Scott: It will happen no matter what the law is.
Scott: And it won't happen in more or less quantity no matter what the law is.
Scott: So there's no reason to incentivize accidental art, therefore it's actually the greatest benefit to society to put all accidental art in the public domain.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Now the monkeys are a little trickier.
Rym: Would the monkeys have made taking pictures of themselves had the guy not put his camera there?
Scott: Well, what if he left the camera there by accident or on purpose?
Scott: Does it matter?
Rym: So if he left it there by accident, clearly there is no possible argument that he should get the copyright because it was accidental art.
Rym: He would not have been incentivized.
Scott: But do we need to give people an incentive to leave their cameras in the woods?
Rym: Ah, so what if he left it there on purpose?
Scott: And he did it in Indonesia.
Scott: Does that matter?
Rym: Oh, by Indonesia.
Rym: So say he did it on purpose.
Rym: He's like, "I'm going to get these monkeys to take pictures of
Rym: themselves.".
Rym: How do we want to incentivize that?
Rym: Because if he doesn't have the right to that copyright, then other people will be less inclined to do similar things.
Rym: And we will lose this precious monkey-driven art resource.
Scott: But at the same time, photography, I read this great article.
Scott: It was about the album cover.
Scott: We said, "Look, photography is really copying.
Scott: You're capturing something that exists.
Scott: You don't make the thing that you took a picture
Scott: of.".
Scott: But there is a significant artistic contribution in the lighting and the framing.
Rym: Anyone who disagrees with that, look at a picture taken by someone who knows what they're doing and then look at my Flickr.
Scott: And that is the reason that photography has copyright is because the photographer and also the filmmaker, whoever, puts a significant amount of extra things into it.
Scott: They are taking a copy of the real world, but adding a great deal to it to create an artistic image.
Rym: Having chosen the perspective.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Many, many things, right?
Rym: So what if the guy made a special camera designed for monkey shenanigans?
Scott: Oh, see that would get, right?
Scott: But the thing is, he didn't.
Scott: So in this case, it's really, he didn't act, even if you want to incentivize people leaving cameras in the woods, the guy didn't put any creativity into it.
Scott: The monkeys put all the creativity into it and work.
Scott: The monkeys were the artists.
Rym: There is already precedent for taking into account intent.
Rym: I mean, look, first degree murder is when you had malice of forethought as opposed to second degree murder, crime of passion.
Rym: So we already say you went out intending to kill versus you suddenly decided to kill versus manslaughter of.
Rym: you didn't go out intending to kill, but you ended up killing.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Like he didn't frame the shot.
Scott: He didn't light the shot.
Scott: He didn't do anything.
Scott: The monkeys did it.
Rym: So it's second degree copyright.
Rym: Second degree monkey shot.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Monkeys.
Rym: I keep thinking in my head, I just have that in the loop.
Scott: Let's just not say what that is.
Rym: Let's not say what that is.
Scott: Only cool people will know what that is.
Rym: They're all going to know.
Rym: So we could raise a more interesting question.
Scott: It's Thursday, though.
Rym: Monkeys.
Rym: You could argue pretty straight up that there are monkeys who are more intelligent on any human, like any standard that we would make, than some number of the human race.
Scott: You want to make monkey citizens?
Scott: They're not citizens.
Scott: It doesn't matter how intelligent they are.
Scott: There are dolphins that are more intelligent than children, but they're not citizens.
Rym: I'm not saying they're citizens, but you get copyright even if you're not a citizen.
Scott: No, you don't.
Scott: You don't have rights.
Scott: Period.
Rym: So no rights at all?
Rym: Not even basic human rights?
Rym: UN Charter?
Scott: No, not if you're an animal.
Rym: No, I didn't say animal.
Rym: I said citizen.
Scott: But they're not citizens.
Rym: What if you're just a human, but you're not a citizen?
Scott: I was talking about if you're an animal.
Rym: You just kept saying citizen.
Rym: Say I am a British citizen.
Rym: I'm in the US.
Rym: I make a work.
Rym: Where's that copyright?
Rym: Do I have a copyright in the US?
Scott: Yeah, because there's international treaties and shit.
Rym: What if I'm a stateless individual?
Rym: That's happened every now and then.
Rym: I have no nation.
Rym: that is my home.
Rym: I'm not a citizen of any nation.
Rym: I'm in the United States.
Rym: Somehow.
Rym: I make a copyright at work.
Rym: Do I get protection?
Rym: No.
Rym: Are you sure?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: What if I am robbed?
Rym: Do I have any recourse?
Rym: Can I go to police?
Scott: If you're stateless?
Rym: Yeah, if I'm stateless.
Scott: No, if you go to police, they'll just deport you.
Rym: Will they?
Rym: Are you sure?
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Where to?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: IMF will figure it out.
Scott: I mean, IMS.
Scott: Not International Monetary Fund.
Scott: Immigration.
Rym: I think you let slip.
Rym: Anyway.
Rym: But in the case of the monkey, if they have enough intelligence, I guess it would come down to if we could observe them creating, and we have observed them painting and things, at what point are humans going to be forced to recognize the intelligence of a non-human species?
Scott: When we could talk to them.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So when do you think that day will happen and what do you think it'll be?
Scott: It already happened.
Rym: When?
Rym: What?
Scott: Sign language monkey.
Rym: Sign language monkey.
Rym: So should that monkey be granted honorary US citizenship?
Scott: I would have.
Rym: Should we stop experimenting on chimpanzees?
Rym: Or should we at least heavily restrict it more so than we do now?
Scott: It depends.
Rym: Because it's kind of like doing brain experiments on babies.
Rym: Yeah, it does depend.
Rym: I don't have easy answers.
Rym: Notice how I'm the one asking all the questions and not saying, "Oh,
Rym: well."
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, all right.
Scott: Should we stop experimenting on chimpanzees?
Rym: I have a complex opinion.
Scott: Really?
Rym: That's surprising.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Do you have a thing of the day to go with your complex opinions?
Rym: It's not thing of the day time yet.
Rym: I want to talk about Internet Rage.
Scott: How is it not thing of the day time?
Rym: Internet Rage.
Rym: Because Netflix raised- I'll get every motherfucker in this room.
Rym: I love Internet Rage because it's so massive and so furious and yet so impotent.
Rym: So Netflix raised its prices from $10 a month to $15.98.
Rym: Shit.
Rym: And the internet went apeshit.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: Well, it only raised the prices depending on what you get.
Scott: Well, they removed- So they raised them on me because I have unlimited and one disk.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: That's what almost everyone had.
Scott: because people- They want you to get rid of the one disk.
Scott: The thing is before- Most of their one disks are scratched.
Rym: Basically, they're trying to, in my opinion, drop the DVD half of their business altogether.
Scott: No kidding.
Scott: And that's a great move.
Scott: Actually, now that I have Netflix, actually, the DVD part is actually more important than the streaming part.
Rym: Because there's a lot of stuff that isn't in the streaming.
Scott: Right, because the streaming selection is pretty weak sauce once you've watched all the good stuff.
Scott: And only a good new thing comes in pretty rarely.
Scott: And the thing is with the DVDs, I'm using those to go through IMDb Top 250, which the vast majority of which is- well, 100% of which is on DVD.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: And a very small percentage of it is on Netflix streaming.
Rym: All they have to do is with this price increase, if they just continue to add to the streaming repertoire, I'll be okay with it.
Rym: I mean, the price increase is negligible even to college students.
Scott: Yeah, if they use that extra money to get tons of content and the streaming actually becomes so good that I don't need the DVD anymore, I'll eventually cancel the DVD.
Scott: Or if the streaming gets even less quality, I'll probably keep the DVD and get Hulu Plus for at least a short period.
Scott: Because while Hulu Plus, whatever, it has the entire Criterion Collection.
Scott: So I can get it, watch the entire Criterion Collection, and then cancel it.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: This is something that's like, I think the major problem with a lot of these streaming services right now, is that, you know, they're kind of okay.
Scott: It's like, hey, you pay the low price and you get a whole ton of stuff.
Rym: Ah, but there's too much balkanization of content.
Scott: Right, there's too much balkanization of content and you don't want to pay for two at once.
Scott: You don't want to pay for something you're not using.
Scott: So you pay for one at a time, you use it until you've pretty much seen all the good stuff that's on there, then you just cancel it and go to a different one, see everything they got, and cancel that, and maybe go back to the first one.
Scott: You know, it's like, keep switching around, moving around, trying different things.
Scott: You don't need to have Hulu Plus and Netflix at the same time for the rest of your life.
Rym: Plus Hulu's not doing so well.
Rym: My guess is that within a year or so, Hulu's going to get bought by someone like Comcast.
Scott: May, who knows what's going to go on there.
Rym: My guess is a cable provider will buy Hulu and try to make it only available either for pay or for subscribers to their cable, or some bullshit like that.
Scott: I'm hoping that we will see a government bust up that will separate the media and content companies.
Rym: You know, net neutrality would be the first step to that.
Scott: I know, but we need, this is, I think that's going to be, right, how long did it take them to bust?
Scott: AT&T, a couple decades?
Rym: They've been, yeah.
Scott: Right, so the media, the media and content, you know, like mergers have only been since like '90, late '90s-ish.
Scott: They haven't been going on for that long, right?
Scott: So I'm hoping that, you know, within a decade or two, that will be the next bust up after the, just like the AT&T one.
Scott: And basically what will happen is, for example, Time Warner will be forced to break up, right?
Scott: So the internet will have to be a separate company, you know, the Time Warner cable will just have to be cable and that's it.
Scott: Only providing, you know, the infrastructure.
Rym: I'll go one step further, cable infrastructure, internet infrastructure should be a utility.
Scott: Yeah, and the TV channels and the newspapers and the magazines and the websites, all those things are going to have to separate and be their own thing, as opposed to all being one thing.
Scott: You know, it's interesting that maybe- And the movie companies all have to separate.
Rym: A decade ago, I would have been fairly indifferent to the sentiment you've just given.
Scott: But the thing is, there's fewer and fewer of these companies each day.
Scott: There's like four of them.
Rym: Having worked on Wall Street for almost four years and having learned a lot about business and a lot about corporations, I'm becoming surprisingly anti-corporate.
Rym: No.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, shocking, isn't it?
Rym: Shocking.
Rym: The more you learn about something, the more you become disgusted with the inherent problems in its system.
Scott: See, no one has a job, but JP Morgan profits went up to $5.4 billion a quarter.
Scott: That's over $20 billion a year.
Scott: Gee, man, we really need to cut their taxes because, you know, they just need more money because the reason they're not hiring people and creating jobs is because they don't have enough money just sitting around.
Rym: Except that's the Republican argument, right?
Rym: Oh, if we raise taxes, people won't make new jobs.
Rym: But the taxes they're talking about raising are income taxes on people, not corporations.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Companies, if the companies wanted to hire people, they could.
Scott: They have sitting on tons of cash.
Scott: What we need is some sort of incentive to make them spend the cash.
Scott: Like, spend the cash or we'll just tax it from you.
Scott: See, that's what we should do is you should raise their taxes if they don't use it to hire people.
Scott: If they use it to hire people, then that's okay.
Scott: Let them, don't tax that money they use to hire people.
Scott: Get rid of the payroll tax.
Scott: Just have capital gains tax instead.
Scott: Less payroll tax.
Scott: That way if you want to hire people, you get your money's worth if you're a company.
Rym: I paid capital gains taxes last year.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But if you're a company sitting on a pile of cash, then that actually hurts you because the government will just take that cash away if you don't start using it.
Scott: Force the companies to use their piles and piles of money because they don't need bigger piles of money.
Scott: They already have them.
Scott: They have plenty.
Scott: Google, Apple, everyone's sitting on a pile of cash they're not using.
Scott: If you lower their taxes, all that will happen is their piles of cash will grow and still continue to not be spent.
Scott: Because they have nothing to spend it on except buying other companies, which doesn't make jobs.
Scott: It reduces jobs because they just, you know, when you merge companies, jobs go away.
Rym: Well, there are the other fundamental problems if there isn't enough work to do in most places and.
Scott: Forget those problems for now.
Scott: This is we just need to get past things.
Scott: We just need to get to like 2020 here.
Rym: The skill gap for the smart people who aren't at the top of the skill boat are effectively at the bottom.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: If you, you know, we can make all sorts of rules, for example, just these are just random ideas that may or may not work.
Scott: If a company spends its money on training and education, that's tax free.
Scott: If a company spends its money on, you know, give, you know, hires a new employee for a position that did not exist, then, you know, payroll tax exempt on that position for X time.
Rym: Even if I fire all my employees and rehire them with a dot added to the end of all their titles?
Scott: Those are positions that did not exist.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, no, but they, they existed.
Rym: No, there's a new position.
Rym: Now there's a dot.
Rym: I added a pixel.
Scott: No, your total number of employees has to go up.
Scott: Close all loopholes of stupidity like that.
Rym: There's no way to close all loopholes.
Scott: Yeah, there is a way to close all loopholes.
Scott: You know what it's called?
Rym: What's it called?
Scott: Scott's the judge.
Rym: Ah, we know that works out.
Rym: It does.
Scott: You come into the court and Scott says, aha, I see you used a clever loophole.
Scott: I am Judge Scott.
Scott: Ah, you guessed technically by the reading of this law, everything you did is completely within the word of the law.
Scott: But you know what?
Scott: I'm common sense Judge Scott and I fuck you.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: You lose.
Rym: Fuck, right?
Rym: Fucking.
Rym: That's your, that's your only punishment?
Rym: You gonna fuck people?
Scott: Well, you know, not metaphorically.
Scott: [Laughing].
Rym: So things of the day.
Rym: We had ConnectiCon, you know, awesome con.
Rym: Things went really well.
Rym: All our panelists showed up.
Rym: We had what?
Rym: We had over 170 panels, workshops, and all that stuff scheduled.
Rym: And a good friend of ours in the forum ran a panel on video game music and he showed me a video.
Scott: Did you leave that CD-ROM CD in the car?
Scott: No, I have that CD.
Scott: Oh, I thought you left it in the car.
Rym: I took it out of the car.
Scott: I was sure you left it in the car.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: I had it with, it's in my kilt.
Rym: Alright.
Rym: That I wore.
Rym: Anyway, he showed me a video because I was- I was entertaining a crowd before a panel for guests because the guests were running late.
Rym: And I was like, "Alright, I'll show you some internet
Rym: shit.".
Rym: And he was like, "I got internet
Rym: And showed me some internet shit I'd never seen.
Rym: The Goldfish, pretty good band, is a music video.
Rym: Pretty good music video.
Rym: Music video is homage to everything you listeners like and it's pretty great.
Rym: and it's all about the jazz police.
Scott: Yeah, the song is, okay song.
Rym: I like the song.
Rym: Good song.
Scott: Not a song that would get in your head.
Rym: No, but it's a good like, if I'm cruising down the road, like I'd like to listen to this in the background while I'm cruising.
Scott: Okay, song.
Scott: But the video, excellente.
Rym: Jazz police, I just love.
Scott: I like jazz, I like anything called jazz police.
Scott: Alright.
Scott: So here is the thing of the day.
Scott: You know, I'm gonna be honest, it's not the greatest thing in the world, but it has special powers.
Scott: You see, a while ago, I noticed, right?
Scott: I just noticed that the Nyan Cat, I don't think I need to do the Nyan Cat, has the exact same bassline- It's in all your heads right now.
Scott: Of course.
Scott: Has the exact same bassline as the song "I Want You Back" by the Jackson 5, right?
Scott: You know, doo, doo, doo, doo, doo, doo, doo, right?
Scott: Nyan, nyan, nyan, nyan, nyan, nyan, nyan, nyan, nyan, nyan, nyan, nyan.
Scott: And it's nyan, nyan, nyan, nyan, nyan, nyan, nyan, nyan.
Scott: Right?
Rym: The end of the nyan- That's like the saddest Nyan Cat.
Scott: Right, so the end of the nyan matches up.
Scott: If you listen, if you actually were to take a low-pass filter on the Nyan Cat, you would hear that.
Scott: If you listen closely, you can hear it without the pass filter.
Scott: Anyway, so there was a nyan thread that appeared, and people in the forum were going nyan-crazy, even though it's been like a month since nyan happened.
Rym: There could be a whole study in the progression of memes, how things kind of like, just eh, eh, eh, eh, like they come and go, they pop up out of nowhere.
Scott: It was like it was the original nyan, people don't even remember with the anime girl going back and forth, right?
Scott: But the Nyan Cat was a while ago, but there's been a nyan resurgence, a rising nyan tide.
Scott: It went up, it went down, it's going up again.
Scott: In the forum, there's a huge nyan thread.
Rym: Well note, you're seeing the same thing in ponies.
Rym: There was the first like, push, and then it leveled off, like dropped a little bit.
Rym: And then there was the second waaave that went all the way through the end of the first season.
Scott: It's waning a little, it's leveling off.
Scott: I don't say it's going up or down right now, it's leveled off.
Scott: When that season starts, it's gonna be an esplode.
Rym: Yeah, ConnectiCon, three pony panels I scheduled.
Rym: I turned away two more pony panels.
Rym: Two of those panels filled up, and the third one was like Friday morning and almost filled.
Scott: So anyway, I casually mentioned this discovery of the matching baselines in the nyan thread.
Scott: And of course, somebody went ahead and comboed the audio remix.
Rym: The internet will always provide.
Scott: Yep, Cyclops Rock, what's up?
Scott: And then, uh, some guy, I guess on YouTube, I don't know, see the thing is their forum names don't match up with their other internet names, right?
Scott: So r3dk9 on YouTube took the, made a video of the Nyan Cat and he gave him a fro.
Scott: And he put the song on it, and here we have, you know, a proud front row crew GeekNights meme creation project.
Scott: that has succeeded.
Scott: Good for us.
Scott: So it's a homemade, it's a homemade thing of the day.
Scott: It's not one of those store bought.
Rym: You know, Scott, I picture in a far future, I just imagine this ad, somebody used to make us like a grandma sitting in a rocking chair and she's like, you know, sometimes you don't want a store bought meme, you want an old fashioned one, home cooked.
Scott: Yeah, I got myself a, uh, a pusher robot.
Scott: Be careful with it, it's an antique.
Rym: So metamoment, ConnectiCon is passed.
Rym: If you want to submit panels to ConnectiCon 2011, well, hold your horses, cause, uh, I gotta take a break.
Rym: But I am going to let you in on a secret, not a secret really, but ConnectiCon was a pretty big success.
Rym: We had John St.
Rym: John as a guest.
Rym: We had like, we had a team four star.
Rym: We had a lot of people who were really popular.
Scott: I never heard of team four star until this weekend.
Rym: They're really cool guys.
Scott: They were apparently really popular.
Rym: They were really cool and really easy to work with, despite the fact that due to a misunderstanding and a miscommunication, I, uh, canceled all their panels a week before the con.
Rym: And I had to reinstate them at con, but, uh, they were cool about it.
Rym: They, they, they did everything that I needed and they, they were awesome.
Rym: But, uh, ConnectiCon went pretty well and our department is expanding.
Rym: We're going to have more panel rooms.
Rym: The rooms that we have will be bigger and we will have more workshop rooms.
Scott: If you want to come to ConnectiCon and work for us being a slave dog, let us- We need some staff because I- Fill up a sign to let the panelists know when they have five minutes left.
Scott: More importantly- Write, write, fill out a form to, you know, rate the panels and how good they were.
Rym: Here's what you need to do for us.
Rym: You need to do for us what the enforcers in the theaters at PAX do for PAX.
Scott: Help them with the technology.
Rym: And also what we really need is I can't foist it off on the rest of the front row crew anymore because one, they're doing more and more panels and actual stuff at the con and two, one of the biggest complaints slash requests we got was that people wanted more of our panels.
Rym: We can't do panels when I got to listen to a radio to go deal with disasters all weekend.
Rym: So we need some staff.
Rym: If you would like to be staff for us at ConnectiCon, email us and we can talk.
Scott: ConnectiCon 2012.
Scott: That's a year from now.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Catch the quadle and all that.
Rym: End times.
Scott: Meanwhile, coming up in just a few weeks, the best convention of all time.
Scott: We don't need to say what it is.
Scott: Let's go on.
Rym: Scott, you know what the worst thing is?
Rym: Think back to this moment.
Rym: On Sunday, when it's over, you'll think back to this and be like, "God damn, that was
Rym: fast.".
Scott: I'll just be like, "Fuck yeah, six months,
Scott: bitches.".
Rym: Oh my God, there's going to be another PAX right after PAX.
Scott: Why'd you have to say what it was?
Scott: People know.
Rym: They know.
Rym: You say no.
Rym: Luckily, you can't get in.
Rym: It sold out.
Rym: It sold out so long ago, don't even try.
Rym: Is it?
Rym: I will say this, at PAX- Can't you buy like a Sunday pass?
Rym: I think everything is sold out.
Scott: Let me check it.
Rym: I'm pretty sure everything is sold out.
Scott: I'm checking it.
Rym: So, we are doing one big panel at PAX.
Rym: We are doing, at noon on Saturday, a brand new panel, well, lecture, titled "Discover the Forgotten
Rym: Masters.".
Rym: It will involve, at one point, me and Scott, playing Outlaw, the Atari game, in front of the entire crowd.
Scott: It sold out, sold out, sold out.
Rym: God damn.
Rym: We will also, we're working out the details, it is reasonably likely that we will be, along with a lot of other people you may have heard of, doing how to play sessions in a new workshop room.
Rym: that is an experiment at this year's PAX.
Scott: Are we 100% sure this is actually going to happen as we think it is?
Rym: The workshop room is already set.
Rym: I've been talking to Father Fletch, who's the head of that department and all that.
Scott: Is he actually a father?
Rym: Our involvement and all that stuff is still tentative.
Rym: We're working it all out.
Rym: But there's a good chance we and other cool people and some enforcers and everyone will be doing sessions like, "You want to learn how to play Tiger's New Freighties?
Rym: We will teach this entire
Rym: room.".
Scott: And then, "Oh look, there's a lot of copies of Tiger's New
Scott: Freighties.".
Scott: There have been many times at PAX where I've taught a game multiple times, or I taught three different people at three separate tables how to play Agricola simultaneously.
Rym: It was pretty amazing to watch.
Scott: Right, so, the thing, we were like, "Hey, let's just teach everyone how to play all these games one at a time in a room, and then they can break up and play them very
Scott: easily.".
Rym: And it turns out that PAX was already working on this concept.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Rym: So we'll see how this goes.
Rym: Uh, buh-buh-buh-buh, the Book Club book, which we will do a show on outside of the stream.
Scott: Yeah, Book Club is no longer a Thursday show.
Scott: It is now its own show, which means we're desperate for more Thursday show ideas.
Scott: If you couldn't tell by the fact that this is a show about nothing.
Rym: Show about stuff.
Scott: Yeah, good job, Rym.
Rym: Yeah!
Scott: Yeah!
Scott: It's all you.
Rym: It is all me.
Rym: So, we will do, from now on, we're gonna take all the old Book Club books, and we're gonna take- We're gonna hopefully do one Book Club per month, just a show on its own.
Scott: It'll appear on who knows what day, sometimes towards the end of the month.
Scott: Uh, and maybe, I guess towards the middle of the month, actually, 'cause what's today?
Scott: What, today's like July, what?
Rym: 15th, 14th.
Scott: Right, so around the middle of the month, a Book Club episode will just appear every month that won't actually be on any particular day.
Scott: It'll be its own episode.
Rym: But one thing I'm gonna do is take the audio that is just about the books out of the old Thursday shows we did on this shit, and put them in that feed.
Rym: So if you want to catch up on the Book Club, do the old Book Clubs, you don't have to wade through us talking about five-year-old news.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Yeah, I'm gonna do some website rearranging now that I'm not busy for a couple weekends.
Rym: Yeah, we have to finish that PAX event we're running.
Scott: Yeah, that's it though.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Oh, what else do we got?
Rym: Uh, PAX East is coming up in about seven months.
Rym: We'll be there.
Scott: MagFest is before then.
Rym: MagFest just launched its new website.
Rym: MagFest has stepped up its game.
Rym: They're in the Gaylord, which is a real hotel.
Rym: It probably won't smell like butt like the old one did.
Scott: It will be on January 5th through 8th.
Rym: 5th through 8th.
Rym: I'm already booking our travel and everything.
Rym: We are going to be there doing some panels and lectures.
Rym: John St.
Rym: John is gonna be a guest, as always.
Scott: MagFest X. Dun dun dun.
Rym: I'm actually pretty excited.
Rym: MagFest is like, other than PAX and PEX, it's my third favorite con right now.
Scott: Yeah, we get so much gaming done there.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: And for all the problems the con has, it goes really well because it's all people our age just kind of do what they're doing.
Rym: The only problem is that it smelled like a butt.
Scott: I think at this MagFest I've got a plan.
Rym: Got a plan?
Scott: One day is gonna be Day of Arcade.
Scott: One day is gonna be Day of RPG and one day is gonna be Day of Board.
Rym: There's four days.
Scott: Oh, fuck me.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I forgot MagFest was four days.
Rym: That was perhaps, the fact that it was four days is like what really tossed it for me.
Rym: Because I remember we got there Thursday and I stayed up until like 3 a.m.
Rym: Thursday night just playing games.
Rym: And then Friday until 3 a.m.
Rym: and then Saturday.
Scott: This is a hotel con.
Rym: Saturday I went to the con in the morning and I felt great and I was like, wait a minute.
Rym: It's only Saturday.
Scott: And this time we'll be in the hotel and not on a shuttle bus.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: No shuttle bus.
Scott: I wonder what the elevators would be like.
Rym: I don't even care.
Rym: Elevator party.
Scott: Elevator party.
Scott: So mister, this show about nothing.
Rym: So what you been up to Scott?
Rym: What you doing?
Scott: Going to work.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Coming home.
Rym: Coming home.
Rym: Riding your bike.
Scott: Doing cons.
Scott: Not having time to do laundry or clean my apartment.
Rym: My apartment?
Scott: I didn't even have time to push the button on the dishwasher that cleans the dishes.
Rym: You should see the room we're sitting in right now.
Rym: It looks like it has been destroyed.
Scott: It has been destroyed.
Rym: There is stuff piled up everywhere.
Rym: It's kind of a disaster.
Scott: You should see the pile of trash in front of my front door.
Scott: that is from boxes that have been destroyed.
Rym: I've got like 20 boxes scattered around the living room that need to be broken down and taken down to the recycling area.
Rym: I blame partly that we're doing these game nights and the NerdNYC stuff I'm going to again and cons.
Scott: Yeah, NerdNYC is a new website.
Rym: Yeah, NerdNYC is stepping up their game too.
Scott: I think it's the time of game up stepping.
Rym: Huh, maybe we'll be stepping up our game.
Rym: Maybe there's a thing in the nearing-ish future that we may be working on.
Scott: Hopefully this weekend.
Rym: I don't know what you're referring to.
Scott: I'm basically going to be, you know, now that I actually have weekends where there's nothing, I'm going to be spending all my weekend time pushing real hard.
Rym: Well, what do we got to push?
Rym: We got Turn Flicked.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: That's kind of our big, you know, every time we've been interviewed by other press, what they always ask is, "So, you guys are clearly experts on games.
Rym: How come you haven't made a
Rym: game?".
Scott: How come movie critics don't make food and food, I mean, movie critics don't make movies and food critics don't cook?
Rym: Yeah, so we're going to...
Scott: You're such a good food critic, why don't you go and open up a five-star restaurant?
Rym: So, we're going to do that.
Rym: We're going to be the food critic who opens a one-star restaurant.
Rym: That's right.
Rym: It's getting there.
Scott: It's a half-star restaurant right now.
Rym: But we're playing some pretty awesome, one pretty awesome, awesome in quotes, "old war game" to learn about old war games.
Rym: How old is it?
Scott: It's not that old.
Rym: It's old-ish.
Scott: No, it's like 2000-something.
Rym: It got re-released.
Scott: Oh, really?
Rym: I think it got re-released.
Rym: I was reading stuff about it.
Scott: Here comes Board Game Geek.
Rym: Ah, you should get the Board Game Geek.
Rym: But, aside from Turn Flicked, we got, you know...
Scott: Why are you talking about games on non-Tuesday?
Rym: You know, we always say that we want to run conventions better and we complain about conventions that are run poorly and we have a history of stepping up and putting up when people tell us to step up, put up, or shut up.
Rym: Games from 2007.
Rym: That's pretty old.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: Yeah, that's the re-release.
Rym: Yeah, when's the original game?
Rym: Oh, old.
Rym: Ancient.
Rym: In 2006, I had just left college.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I was working for IBM still, I think.
Rym: Yeah?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But, you know, Otakon doesn't really like us anymore.
Rym: They don't want us to come back.
Scott: Man, but actually, Otakon busted out their guest announcement at the last minute and I was sort of like, "The only one that really hurts, though...".
Scott: I mean, there's a lot of good ones, obviously, but the only one I really wanted to see very badly is Makoto Shinkai.
Scott: Otakon's actually this weekend.
Scott: As in, we are going right now to it.
Scott: Oh my god.
Scott: If we were going to it.
Rym: It does pain me.
Rym: It's been two Otakons we have not gone to.
Rym: And I do miss that ritual.
Rym: It was almost a decade of my life.
Rym: Otakon was like this culmination of the summer.
Rym: And, no.
Rym: But, Kinetakon said, "Hey, put
Rym: up.".
Rym: And now we're the heads of the department.
Rym: We run all the panels and workshops.
Rym: And sometimes people ask us why we don't run our own con.
Rym: And that's one of the things I've been working on.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: No details.
Rym: No date.
Rym: No, not saying anything other than that there will be, sometime in the nearing-ish future, an announcement that we are going to run a convention in New York City.
Scott: It could be a room with some tables and board games for an hour.
Scott: It could be a real convention.
Scott: It's somewhere in between the two.
Rym: My goal is to have a one-day convention that has some sort of panel or lecture-ish programming independent of a gaming area, and maybe a small vending area, and maybe 500 people.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: That's my goal.
Scott: In one of the five boroughs of Manhattan.
Rym: Yeah, I can tell you it's not going to be in Staten Island.
Scott: In one of the four real boroughs of Manhattan.
Scott: And not Yonkers.
Rym: Yeah, not Yonkers.
Rym: The sixth borough.
Rym: So, that's coming up along.
Rym: Inns, if you're interested in helping, don't bother me yet because the logistics are way ahead of that point.
Rym: Unless you have money.
Rym: If you want to help with money, you're welcome to help with money.
Scott: If you want to help with your hands, wait.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: If you want to help with being famous and want to be a guest, yeah, you can help then too.
Rym: But otherwise, no helping.
Scott: Yet.
Rym: So, I've been watching, notice how I'm threading this nothing show along, old Netflixes while I do stuff.
Rym: Because I can't watch Fist of the North Star while I'm working on stuff because they're subtitles.
Scott: I know, that is the one problem with subtitles is you can't watch them simultaneously.
Scott: Simultaneously.
Scott: You have to give it your full attentions.
Rym: So, I've been watching a whole bunch of old kids in the hall.
Scott: Uh huh.
Rym: I was ragging on them in the forum a while ago when I said that 80s comedy by and large sucks by today's standards.
Scott: Why would you say that?
Rym: Name good 80s comedy compared to bad 80s comedy.
Rym: There are huge exceptions.
Rym: George Carlin was hilarious in the 80s.
Scott: Did Richard Pryor count?
Rym: What bit are you thinking of and when did he first perform it?
Scott: He's so 70s 80s, it's tough.
Rym: I know, I know.
Rym: Like, Kids in the Hall, a lot of the stuff I liked from them was from the 90s.
Rym: And it's all over the place.
Rym: But anyway, I said something to the effect of, I don't know how well Kids in the Hall will hold up.
Rym: I think I have to rescind that.
Rym: It's holding up pretty well.
Rym: It's funnier than the whitest kids.
Rym: you know who are okay.
Rym: Yeah, alright.
Rym: It's okay.
Rym: I haven't found any new stand-up comedians lately.
Rym: I think Russell Peters is the last new stand-up comedian I know of.
Scott: They're mostly like, you know, it seems like people don't really do stand-up so much.
Scott: They mostly go, you know, because short internet videos have taken over, right?
Scott: So it's mostly about doing a skit or producing a funny video of some sort.
Scott: Which usually does not involve just standing there telling jokes, right?
Scott: I mean, I guess there was that guy who did the terrorist skeleton puppet.
Scott: Effectively, it's stand-up, but it's also ventriloquism.
Rym: Vaudeville.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: He got pretty popular.
Scott: He's okay, I guess.
Rym: Though I did see a good bit of Uncle Yo.
Rym: I was watching the video from Uncle Yo doing his stand-up at ConnectiCon since the room filled up.
Rym: It was pretty funny.
Rym: Pretty funny.
Scott: You practiced anything, you'd be good at it.
Scott: He practices comedy every day.
Rym: So, I was going to make a joke about Control Alt to leave, but I figure it's too soon.
Scott: No, he's very, very good at what he does.
Rym: Yeah, kind of like how a White Castle burger is extremely excellent at being a White Castle burger.
Scott: Yeah, I could work at a White Castle for a very long time, and I would become a master of making a slider.
Scott: I would not become the master of making- Right, exactly.
Scott: But I would not become the master of making the best burger in the world.
Rym: Even though I've made zillions of burgers.
Rym: So, good burger.
Rym: Sweet potato fries now.
Scott: Alright, because they're in season.
Rym: Yeah, you know what?
Rym: Pretty good.
Scott: Good burger's still a little bit too expensive.
Rym: Yeah, I got money.
Scott: I've been going to Island Burger.
Rym: I'm waiting for that Potbelly's to open up.
Rym: Island Burger.
Rym: My co-workers are talking about Island Burger.
Rym: We were talking about good burger joints.
Rym: I was like, "Schnippers, one of the
Rym: best.".
Rym: And they were like, "Island
Rym: Burger.".
Rym: And I was like, "Yeah, Island Burger's good, but it's too far
Rym: away.".
Scott: It's very close to me.
Rym: Yeah, not so close to me.
Scott: You should come over.
Rym: I should, but I might be further away starting sometime next week.
Scott: That's not my problem.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Of course, I'll be close enough to Chinatown to get five dumplings for a dollar instead of five dumplings for five dollars.
Scott: There's no Island Burger in Chinatown.
Rym: No, there's not.
Rym: There are similar things, though.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, Mr.
Scott: Show About Nothing.
Scott: So you got nothing?
Scott: You got nothing?
Scott: This is all you.
Rym: You can't just talk about something?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Does anything happen to you ever?
Scott: I bought a solid-state drive.
Rym: All right, so at Connecticut, right, John St.
Rym: John was a guest.
Rym: And he had to do his panel, which was in a tiny-ass room because I messed up the numbers.
Rym: I flopped a big room and a small room.
Rym: So all the stuff I put in the big room ended up being in the small room and vice versa.
Rym: Good job.
Rym: Yeah, that was probably my biggest failing ever.
Rym: But John St.
Rym: John came, I got him into the big room, filled the room anyway, giant crowd, and he forgot his iPad, which he needed to do one of the bits in his panel.
Rym: So he went to get it for, like, 20 minutes.
Rym: So I'm standing in the room at the front of the stage.
Rym: It's a Blues Brothers situation.
Rym: You know, everyone's waiting.
Rym: So I had to entertain the crowd for a while, and I realized that the best thing to do in that situation is to tell anecdotes about the person who is about to come back and prime the audience to fuck with them.
Scott: That's, we've done that often.
Scott: We have a great deal of practice in that department.
Scott: So I was like, yeah.
Scott: In our Anime Club days.
Rym: I was like, you should ask him about some ponies.
Rym: I hear he's a pony fan.
Rym: And people asked him about ponies.
Rym: I think someone posted that in our forum.
Scott: There was something, a video on YouTube of him reading, basically he was reading the song of My Little Pony, the lyric, he wasn't singing it.
Rym: They asked him to do that, to read it in his voice, and he did.
Scott: Yeah, why wouldn't he?
Rym: What was weird though, and it's funny because we're like D-level celebrities, me and Scott.
Rym: D minus.
Rym: John St.
Rym: John is like, he's a step and a half, two steps above us celebrity-wise.
Rym: He's up there compared to us.
Rym: So it's funny that we know each other, we're chill.
Rym: We're like, hey dude, hey dude.
Rym: If I walked by him in the hall and I was like, yo, and we like fist bump and just walk by, people who are walking with me, like panelists I'm taking to the room, be like, oh my god, you know John St.
Rym: John?
Rym: How do you, oh, oh, oh.
Rym: And it was kind of hilarious.
Rym: I was digging that, I'll be honest.
Rym: I was eating that up.
Rym: I was like, no, we cool, we cool.
Scott: I'm like, whatever.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I always enjoy watching people who haven't learned to deal with celebrities.
Rym: They don't realize that he's just a guy.
Rym: We're just guys.
Rym: We have fans that come up to us and don't know what to say.
Rym: They're like, sign my thing, please.
Scott: I'm like, what are you doing?
Rym: Granted, you seem to hate our fans.
Rym: Cute girls come up to us on a regular basis and they're like, we're huge fans of GeekNights, oh my god.
Rym: And Scott's like, what the fuck do you listen to GeekNights for?
Scott: That's right, why do you listen to GeekNights?
Scott: What the fuck is wrong with you?
Scott: You could do a lot better things than listen to this show.
Scott: Especially, especially this episode.
Scott: This episode is awful.
Rym: Can I have your autograph?
Rym: And Scott's like, what the fuck?
Scott: Why?
Rym: Do you want me to scribble on a piece of paper?
Scott: I don't understand why anyone wants any autograph.
Scott: Even if the most famous person in the world, I have no interest in having them scribble on a piece of paper.
Rym: I enjoy signing autographs because it's a thing that when other people see you signing an autograph, they wonder who the fuck you are.
Rym: There's something funny about that.
Scott: I have no interest in collecting anything.
Rym: Remember our first packs when we did that secret panel after our panel?
Rym: And Luke Crane was there and Jared Sorensen was there.
Rym: Some listeners came up to us and they had bought Burning Wheel because they had just played it because we told them to.
Rym: And they asked us to sign the Burning Wheel book when Luke Crane was standing right there.
Rym: And Luke looks over and I see him looking at me and I'm signing this book.
Rym: And I just look at his face and I'm like, why?
Rym: What the fuck?
Scott: But yeah, I don't understand any autographs, period.
Scott: If I meet a famous person that I actually care about, my number one interest is to ask them questions.
Scott: no one else has the balls to ask them.
Scott: That is what I do.
Rym: So how long is it?
Scott: Not questions like that.
Rym: No one else is asking those questions.
Scott: Questions like, you know, that they probably won't answer.
Rym: So you're famous for many anime, but in particular, when you voice acted as so-and-so on Crystal Triangle.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: That's the sort of angle you go for.
Scott: Ask them about the weird thing that no one else remembers.
Scott: Ask them about, you know, something they did.
Scott: or, you know, ask about inside things that people wouldn't normally know.
Scott: Like, for example, if I could talk to the pony people, I would be like, hey, look, everybody knows, you know, there's sort of like this mystique that there are executives, TV executives who hand down decrees that you must follow.
Scott: And there's a clash between the creative animators who want to go weeee and the executives who say sell toys.
Scott: But those executives are real people.
Scott: They're human beings.
Scott: Who are they?
Scott: What do they actually say to you?
Scott: You know, what are these decrees?
Scott: How do they come down?
Scott: How does that whole what's the reality of that relationship?
Scott: Right.
Scott: Nobody nobody asked that.
Scott: But that's that's the kind of thing that I would ask, you know, is like, I want to know how it really is.
Scott: You know, I want to know the deal.
Scott: No one else tries to find out the deal.
Scott: They ask stupid questions like, why are you so awesome?
Scott: How can I become a voice actor?
Scott: Tell me tell me a funny story.
Scott: Let me self promote myself and not actually ask a question.
Rym: I was about to say, very rarely do they do.
Rym: they ask, why are you so awesome?
Rym: They ask, I'm actually super awesome, too.
Scott: Tell me about something related to my awesomeness that may be related to you.
Rym: Actually, the question we've gotten most that is starting to get annoying and I feel like I need to specifically head this one off.
Rym: Any panel, doesn't matter what the topic is, anime, gaming, whatever.
Rym: Have you played X?
Scott: Have you seen X?
Rym: And the thing is, if those things were directly relevant to what we just talked about, like really strongly, that would be fine.
Rym: They never are.
Rym: Never ask that question of anyone ever.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Have you heard of this?
Scott: Have you heard of that?
Rym: Have you played this?
Rym: There's one exception.
Rym: When we were at that panel at the first MAGFest where the guy was like, so you might want to get like, what if you gave your players in the game a little bit of control of the narrative?
Rym: Like a little bit like you might break your game.
Scott: Have you have you heard of Burning Wind?
Rym: Scott Reisand.
Rym: Scott, you basically asked the question, you were like, have you ever heard of Burning Wheel, Inspectors, Lacuna, Dogs in the Vineyard?
Scott: Have you ever heard of any RPG besides D&D?
Scott: Maybe he's heard of White Wolf or something.
Rym: That guy was in trouble when he was like, I've been playing Dungeons and Dragons since 2002.
Scott: I was like, I've been playing Dungeons and Dragons since 1990.
Rym: I've owned the D&D books since the 80s.
Scott: Something.
Rym: I had the Dungeons and Dragons cyclopedia when I was fucking young.
Scott: And the weird thing is because he didn't seem that much younger than us.
Scott: But I've been playing D&D since 1990 something.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Elementary or middle school, I think I had something.
Rym: I was obsessed with it.
Rym: I owned it all.
Rym: I didn't really get to play a real game of D&D in my middle school.
Scott: I played it when I was 13.
Scott: So 1995, I played Dungeons and Dragons.
Rym: Middle school is when I really got to do it and then high school I had real D&D.
Scott: I played real second edition advanced Dungeons and Dragons in the year of 1995.
Rym: That was my favorite D&D.
Rym: Though I had the rules cyclopedia and I wanted to play regular Dungeons and Dragons, I never got anyone to play it with me.
Rym: I ran it for a few people but they always hated it.
Scott: I played it more seriously in 1997 or 98.
Rym: And then 2000 happened.
Scott: I think it was '97.
Rym: And we played it with Dammit Dwayne.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: Dammit Dwayne.
Scott: So '95, '97, and 2000 were my D&Ds.
Rym: I almost, almost want to play like an old school D&D game but then I remember how great Burning Wheel is.
Scott: I want to play an old school D&D game and not play it at all as a role playing game and play it only as a dungeon-y game and mostly concentrate on using, not just doing maximum average damage, but maybe like everyone's a wizard.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: Or sorcerer.
Rym: I use Mage Hand to turn the switch across from the pit.
Scott: Everyone has magical classes only and go relatively high levels so you can get tons of spells.
Scott: Or maybe fuck memorization, you can just cast your spells.
Rym: You know, we could just do a dungeon crawl.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is, I sort of feel like if we wanted to do the dungeon crawl only- No, micro dungeons, yes.
Scott: But you could do micro dungeons with Burning Wheel better.
Scott: But, do play maybe one of those stupid games like Descent or something.
Rym: No, because those abstracted too much.
Rym: They're too polished.
Rym: They're wow.
Rym: In those, it's so abstract you're not actually doing anything.
Rym: It's just, the abstracted action of attacking is all that matters.
Rym: In an old school D&D dungeon crawl, like Tomb of Horrors, it comes down to, I walk 15 feet forward and then I pull out my 10 foot pole and I stand on this square when I push the button.
Rym: That shit is what I want to do.
Rym: If I'm not at that level, I don't care.
Scott: You can do shit like, you know, "Alright, a large tree blocks your
Scott: path.".
Rym: I cast Bigby's Crushing Fist and get rid of that tree.
Scott: Yeah, or, you know, "Alright, I summon
Scott: termites.".
Scott: You know, it's like when you have D&D, you can get all creative with the magics and just come up with ridiculous shit.
Scott: "There's a gelatinous cube in the
Scott: hallway!".
Scott: You know, "I tricked the bad guys into going into
Scott: it.".
Scott: You know, stuff like that.
Rym: I remember the first D&D game I ran for the crew, I don't know if you were there or not, but Dammit Dwayne was supposed to run our D&D game.
Rym: He didn't show up.
Rym: It was like the first or second rwag.
Rym: And I remember I just made up this dungeon and the whole combination of it, because it was like I was doing off the top of my head, it was like 10 minutes long, was there was a skeleton that attacks the party, but really, it was a skeleton suspended in a gelatinous cube.
Scott: Gelatinous cube is my favorite if you couldn't tell.
Scott: Except for Death Knight, also good.
Rym: Death Knights are really good because they can just cast Fireball for some fucking reason.
Scott: Can't they cast Disintegrate?
Rym: They can Fireball you too, I'm pretty sure.
Rym: I'm pretty sure they can Disintegrate, yeah.
Rym: Pretty sure they can Fireball you.
Rym: Anyway.
Scott: They can also have the horrible touch of death, if I'm not mistaken.
Scott: I have to go check my monstrous manual when I get home.
Rym: Yeah?
Scott: I have a copy.
Rym: I think that's enough.
Rym: nothing.
Rym: It's about an hour worth of nothing.
Scott: Really?
Scott: You're done with the nothing episode?
Scott: It's been an hour.
Scott: The mishmash of all geekeries?
Scott: Yeah, you better come up with some Thursday ideas, otherwise, Geek Knights Thursday is gonna get cancelled.
Rym: I wanted to talk about swimming pools.
Scott: What were you gonna say about swimming pools?
Rym: How to find bodies in them, for one.
Scott: We already did that.
Rym: Other stuff.
Scott: Sorry for the crappy episode, blame Rym.
Rym: You know what's gonna be funny?
Rym: Every time we've done a crap episode, we've been like, this is shit.
Rym: People like it more than the episodes we think are good.
Scott: Blame Rym.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Blame me.
Scott: Or give credit to Rym.
Rym: It's all me.
Scott: And then we will return to regularly good Geek Knights again.
Rym: Regularly scheduled Geek Knights.
Rym: Next week.
Rym: Some radio-free.
Rym: Equestria is gonna start back up again.
Scott: Monday, Wednesday.
Rym: And all these other pony videos I promised.
Rym: And... PAX.
Rym: We won't do a show right before PAX.
Rym: No.
Rym: FYI.
Rym: No kidding.
Rym: This has been Geek Knights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, Geek Knights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: Geek Knights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: Geek Knights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.