Rym: It's Tuesday, October 18th, 2011.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight Video-game journalism as if you couldn't guess what we have to say.
Scott: Let's do this By happenstance.
Rym: I had a very fancy dinner at Benoit balls last night.
Rym: Oh Cuz you know our friend Phil and his friend Sarah are going on a world traveling wandering tour of Basically around the entire world on foot and bike and their bike.
Rym: they biked to New York from Providence Stayed with us for the weekend and now are currently on route to Fort Lauderdale, Florida on the same bikes mostly But at one thing led to another and basically Sarah had like her cousin or something was the manager of this restaurant called Benoit And Benoit was a very fancy French place.
Rym: That was very awesome.
Rym: So I had something I have not had in a long time flag right beef tartare.
Rym: Let me tell you that is one of the most delicious things you can ever have.
Scott: it's pretty good That's not foie gras.
Rym: No, it is not foie gras.
Rym: It's also not Pure sugar thing is though, you know, we had to pay for our food.
Rym: Obviously the manager is not gonna be like yeah free, you know multi hundred dollar dinner, but for the guy's cousin Yeah, but they brought out like we didn't order many appetizers.
Rym: They brought out like every appetizer.
Scott: They were all left over.
Scott: They would have thrown him out.
Rym: No, they made him.
Rym: They brought out every dessert and they brought out fancy champagne.
Rym: But I tested two of my theories.
Rym: one Like I always say the cheapest champagne and the most expensive champagne are both the good Champagne's and the expensive champagne was very good.
Rym: The cheapest wine on the menu is almost always perfectly adequate If not better than these slightly more expensive wines on the menu.
Rym: So, you know, there's all these different wines on the menu.
Rym: I ordered the $26 bottle and you know what?
Rym: It was pretty damn good.
Scott: is that I mean?
Scott: is even if you have a restaurant Are you gonna even have a wine on the menu?
Scott: That's not good period.
Scott: Usually it's the second but why would you why would you even have a bad one?
Scott: Why not have all good ones?
Rym: Well, what if?
Scott: and then just psychologically price them said the one you have the most of is the one that's priced to sell?
Rym: Well, it depends if you're a mediocre restaurant, right?
Rym: The cheapest wine is also probably the worst wine out in the market.
Rym: So what you do is you just buy the cheapest shit wine and you know charge eight bucks a glass for it?
Rym: Okay, I guess and be in a tourist town or something where no one will ever come back to your restaurant.
Scott: Anyway, maybe I don't know.
Scott: I don't know I can't imagine a place would have a bad wine or that even a winery would make a bad wine.
Rym: a place had some really Bad.
Rym: well, it was just a bad wine.
Rym: They recommend it.
Rym: It was terrible.
Rym: It wasn't corked.
Rym: It was just terrible.
Rym: It was that steak place.
Rym: We went to in beacon or in fish kill Uh-huh.
Rym: Remember the same place that wouldn't let us leave because we didn't order enough alcohol.
Scott: I Don't remember that happen.
Scott: Really?
Rym: You don't remember shit.
Scott: I remember going there, but I remember them not letting.
Rym: so we brought the whole crew one time there.
Rym: We had like 14 people around this big table and we had a gigantic dinner But no one ordered booze and no one wanted dessert.
Rym: So once it was apparent that we weren't gonna order like booze They basically never brought us menus for like ever and the service was the slowest possible and then they just wouldn't bring the check And everyone disappeared.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean it wasn't they did.
Scott: it wasn't them not letting us leave It was them trying to hit, you know, it wasn't like you can't leave until you buy alcohol.
Rym: Ah, but it was.
Rym: you can't leave until we bring the check and even asking for the check.
Rym: It did not appear.
Rym: Yep Well, I'll never get there again, okay, it's highly unlikely.
Scott: if we were to go there we would eat it cafe Maya and Kaibo Kaibo Whatever.
Scott: So let's just get this onwards like go home.
Scott: Uh So check this out.
Rym: I'm checking.
Scott: Remember that there was the Battle of the Scrolls versus the Elder Scrolls.
Scott: Yep, man trying to keep you down.
Rym: So elders What amazes me is how like?
Rym: Blatant this sort of infringement suit was.
Rym: I mean, it's kind of like if I if Apple computers went after the Apple farm.
Scott: Yeah, it's like they went after Apple Records.
Rym: There was a battle there, but that was fine because actually Apple Records had like.
Rym: the trademark stuff was very specific.
Scott: Anyway, but the point here is that so remember notch was like, hey, let's just play quake to settle this.
Scott: and they were like No, we're gonna go to court.
Scott: He's like, alright cuz he had money.
Scott: Yep Does your big first mistake is not just you know suing you.
Scott: either sue someone who doesn't care Like, you know some company or you sue someone who doesn't have money But does care.
Scott: you never sue someone who has money and cares because they will fight you.
Scott: and of course notch Won at least well, he got an interim injunction, which means he won.
Scott: but they can appeal.
Rym: but but that's that's very important.
Rym: A lot of people a lot of people always say that if you you know, like oh they can still appeal.
Rym: it appeals.
Scott: Appeals aren't what you think they are right.
Scott: an appeal isn't.
Scott: Do over an appeal is something was wrong with the court that I was just in.
Scott: not so, you know, so it's like Let's say I go to court and I'm guilty.
Scott: Of course.
Scott: I'm not a lawyer.
Scott: So some lawyers pregnant.
Rym: I'm also not a lawyer.
Scott: Nury was probably like just whatever from what I understand, right?
Scott: Let's say I go to court and I was I'm a murderer and I get found guilty.
Scott: If I want to appeal I can't just be like no seriously, I wasn't guilty.
Scott: You have to be like you'd be like.
Rym: the Constitution protects murder as a right.
Rym: No, yeah No, you can argue that I get the original law was unconstitutional.
Rym: No
Scott: But when you appeal
Rym: or you could argue that the process in the court was wrong like technicality when
Scott: you appeal That's what you have to do is you have to say like look that court that I was just in they chose the jurors wrong And we guys why we have to do it again?
Rym: Yep, the jury they they let the jury see me handcuffed which gave them a preconceived notion that I was guilty.
Scott: You need some reason to show that there was something wrong with the court that you were just in and that's why you need to do Over.
Scott: you can't get a do-over just because you didn't like the result.
Scott: But lawyers are very good and they always find a reason to appeal.
Scott: Yeah, if they need one.
Scott: or why?
Scott: if they amazing if you want to pay for the appeal They'll find a way to do it.
Rym: but we always say I mean we want people who are awesome who do awesome stuff when confronted with lawsuits like this to fight and Not.
Rym: you have my seal of approval for being one of the people who does that.
Scott: Yep Because he has the monies.
Rym: Yeah And he cares he does.
Rym: I just it's such like a bleep.
Scott: The thing I understand is why do they even care about?
Scott: Some other guy making a game called Scrolls when their game isn't even called Elder Scrolls.
Scott: It's called something something something.
Scott: Elder Scrolls number something.
Rym: Well, because you know, and I know that colloquially people know it as Elder Scrolls.
Scott: Yeah, the Elder Scrolls series.
Scott: Yeah elder scrolls Right, so why do they even care about someone else making in called Scrolls?
Scott: What do they seriously think that is gonna happen is gonna hurt them in any way?
Rym: I mean if I make a book like luscious vixens of the Amazon is Amazon gonna come after me, right?
Scott: It's like Amazon be retarded if they actually thought that that was gonna hurt or modify their business or any people's perception of them In any way shape or form.
Rym: so here's the question then why?
Rym: why do you think they even bothered with this lawsuit in the first place?
Scott: because I Think that there is a lawyer who works there who needs to do something.
Scott: Otherwise you what is he there for lawyers?
Scott: if you there's lawyers that work for companies And if you're a lawyer that works for a company as opposed to working for a law firm You need to do something.
Scott: So if I'm a lawyer who works for say Apple, I'm sitting there.
Scott: No one's suing Apple right now, so I don't need to defend Apple.
Scott: Well, what should I do?
Scott: I need to sue somebody so you got to look and look and look for someone to sue and Usually you find some patent or something and you say hey, I'm doing work here.
Scott: Don't fire me I'm a lawyer works at you.
Scott: Keep paying my salary.
Scott: I'm working and I found a way to make the company money Which is sue people Because if you're an employee of a company, you have to find a way to make that company money.
Scott: That's your job, right?
Scott: So some guy works for Bethesda Zenimax and he needs to find a way.
Scott: He's a lawyer there and he needs to find a way to make the money.
Scott: So he looks for someone to sue.
Scott: So you see someone comes out with the game called Scrolls and then in the gaming news and he says aha Here's maybe we can make a trademark suit and I can prove my worth.
Scott: I can win this I'm gonna go for it and he goes for it.
Rym: Another option is that they knew this was kind of a BS lawsuit, but it would generate a lot of buzz.
Rym: I mean everyone's talking about it.
Rym: I don't know, you know gamers all the time will say something like oh due to X I will now not buy.
Rym: why game?
Rym: that is never the truth never.
Rym: no one who says that means it.
Rym: Nope Anyway, it's hard to say anyway, so Speaking of gamers saying they will never do something again.
Rym: First.
Rym: I want to talk about a technological issue.
Rym: This is a kind of a Monday thing, but bear with me here.
Rym: There is an issue issue number 44,106. it's a lot of issues for chromium.
Rym: Ah, you know the Chrome web browser.
Rym: Yep So the issue is that they would like the tab bar To be able to be moved under the URL bar, I don't know why people want that.
Scott: I mean I've Suddenly, you know Firefox and Chrome both have tabs on top and I'm kind of just fine with it.
Rym: Well, it's weird because I've noticed complaining about this.
Scott: people use the mouse and you know what I say throw your mouse in the trash.
Scott: I use the keyboard baby.
Rym: I'm not complaining about it.
Rym: I think what it is is that and I was this way you were this way people who are between the ages of like 15 and 20 are this way if they use Linux you get this idea that I'm going to customize my computer a hundred fucking percent I'm gonna use like FVWM or whatever.
Scott: I'm gonna make like this super awesome my personal interface And I learned that was a dumbass idea because you waste all your time customizing your computer.
Scott: And so let's say let's say that I can say let's say it is more efficient Even though it's not.
Scott: but let's say it is that moving the tabs to the bottom makes me like a half a microsecond more efficient.
Scott: The amount of time it takes for me to check that setting box.
Scott: In order for me to break even on time savings and that efficiency I would have to like use the tab bar like 10 billion times for it to add up.
Scott: You know to be a break-even on the efficiency and you know what?
Scott: I'm very likely in that time period to have to install Chrome again and change the setting again thus ruining the efficiency.
Rym: So, I mean, it's very analogous to the whole Dvorak situation one There's no evidence that the Dvorak keyboard is in any way better.
Scott: There is only anecdotal evidence that it is more comfortable because you have to move your fingers less distance because the more Commonly used keys are closer to the house.
Rym: So we've got that's about it.
Rym: We've got vague anecdotal evidence.
Rym: Yes, but I would argue that even if it were slightly better from all those perspectives the Inconvenience and loss of productivity when you have to use any other fucking computer in the world
Scott: Yep more
Rym: than a ways the benefits of Dvorak, so there's no reason to ever use Dvorak unless you're an idiot
Scott: You know what?
Scott: They're dumbasses who use Dvorak layout on say iPhones and other touchscreen devices and you can you guys check the iPhone.
Scott: you can do It ah, but it's like why that's.
Scott: there's just no point at that point.
Rym: So this bug was entered.
Rym: Comment number one.
Rym: I think this bug should be rejected as design intent.
Rym: comment number two I think this bug should be given high priority as a design deficiency.
Rym: The shitstorm that ensued is Amazing and there is somewhere.
Rym: there was a comment near the end of this thing that I'm reading right now.
Rym: Quote I see a fork in this products future Chrome devs.
Rym: There are a hundred plus users here overruling your UI designers.
Rym: Give them the option now now now.
Rym: now before we talk about That comment I want to talk about another gaming related thing.
Rym: So counter-strike source a fairly venerable game a game that is kind of like it is completely mature.
Rym: It's the second most popular FPS on the internet sometimes the third most popular right now numbers one and two being Team Fortress 2 and counter-strike 1 6. and For the first time in a long time There was an update and it wasn't just bugs valve changed some shit in counter-strike.
Rym: Okay quote they reduce the standing and moving accuracy for pistols.
Scott: That's good because a lot of people just fucking headshot the pistols which too easily it should be much harder.
Rym: Well, it means now you have to get new position duck and shoot or stop running to shoot Decreased accuracy while moving with sniper rifles.
Scott: That's also good because a lot of people just freakin shoot from the hip and blow you right away And it's too easy to do that and I would do it all the time and it's probably not a good idea.
Rym: And they fixed a bug that has been in a long-standing bug where you could use Weapon switch cycles to fire the AWP more often than you otherwise would be able.
Scott: people were probably using that on me.
Scott: That's why I couldn't win the gun game there.
Scott: That's how come I couldn't get out of round.
Scott: one is because people read up reloading their AWPs too fast in that first round.
Rym: It's very telling that I've been playing count and I didn't know that trick.
Rym: We've both been playing counter-strike since like beta 5 because I don't do tricks like that.
Scott: I just play straight up.
Rym: I didn't know that trick exists me there.
Scott: other people try that shit.
Scott: That's why I think we get owned and they did.
Rym: Well, I don't get owned.
Scott: I get owned in gun game in the first round when the AWPs are out.
Rym: I'm okay with the AWP.
Rym: I think your problem is you don't snipe enough.
Rym: So you're not that good at it.
Rym: Once you get past the AWP You're fine.
Rym: Yeah, I am until you hit the scout.
Scott: There have been a few times where I got out of the AWP round very easily, but that you know, like right away.
Scott: But it's usually when someone's not looking at me and I'm hiding in a good spot And I just go.
Rym: yeah, you know what I would do jump out into the middle just firing wildly from the head.
Scott: Yeah, I've tried that to work sometimes.
Scott: I usually do that more better with the auto snipers.
Rym: So the forum the steam form because there was a problem with this rollout it.
Scott: this rather thing Is this has been going on since the year 2000. when encounter strike they would this counter-strike forms would be like remove AWP from the game Remove p90 from the game.
Rym: granted when the p90 was introduced It might as well have been called the automatic death machine P90 as in my hands is still the automatic death machine.
Scott: as long as it's not a big a map that's wide open If it has even one hallway where people are close in.
Rym: the p90 is automatic death machine But it was I guess machine across the map.
Scott: I don't think in any gun game.
Scott: I've ever played.
Scott: I've had the p90 for more than 30 seconds.
Rym: But anyway, I won't go through the details of the steam forum thread, but this update broke Counter-strike.
Rym: you could not play it now.
Rym: Good and the forum had all these dubious suggestions.
Rym: now me being smart.
Rym: I just looked figured out It was probably a problem with the download.
Rym: Cleared the cat, you know.
Scott: And you run the validate game file.
Rym: Yep, and that fixed it.
Rym: I started playing one.
Rym: I can tell that the majority of players could not figure that out right away.
Scott: Well, it is a little hidden option But if you know if you're a steam gamer You need to know that that option is there because you're gonna need to use it at least once.
Rym: so in the forum someone suggested That and someone else said lol troll.
Scott: in response to that Dude, no, it's a real.
Rym: Maybe that was a very clever meta troll May be causing people to doubt the legitimate non troll.
Rym: Maybe, you know, someone's like, how do I Reboot my computer?
Rym: and someone's like hit control.
Rym: I'll delete twice and the guys like lol troll.
Rym: So in that thread it devolved into.
Rym: oh This is gonna drive everyone back to 1/6 valve.
Rym: those fuckers they have no idea how to design games.
Rym: Why would they should get rid of that AWP exploit?
Rym: Oh my god, you fuckers.
Rym: You've ruined my game.
Rym: I will never buy another steam game ever.
Rym: I'm uninstalling.
Scott: Yeah, right kid you care enough to post in the forums.
Scott: you're never gonna install Steve.
Scott: you're gonna install it and go oh shit install It again.
Rym: Yep now these two Issues with chromium and counter-strike are the exact same issue and they dovetail into what happened to Team Fortress 2. not Team Fortress 2 tribes - Don't listen to anyone who plays your game.
Rym: They're not as good at UI design as you most likely Just do what you think is best.
Rym: and to to kind of like illustrate that I have a new job.
Rym: I'm the vice president of product management for a company and I design software interfaces.
Rym: It's one of the things I do.
Rym: We had software that has an interface With a whole bunch of like tabs in it.
Rym: Like there's these different views of different functionality little tabs built-in.
Rym: Originally, the interface was very open.
Rym: You could drag these tabs and these panels around arbitrarily.
Rym: Customize it exactly as you want pull tabs out of the window put them on different monitors save like this layout for your particular user all this craziness.
Rym: and What I found when I was watching people use this interface, which I did not design by the way It was designed before I got there was that the average person would accidentally drag a tab somewhere and never find it again.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: I made everybody happy by removing all of that functionality.
Rym: Yep Anyway, these are all just things to think about.
Rym: when you complain about games When you suggest changes to games when you whine and when you design interfaces
Scott: You don't know better than the people who do it for real right and this is part of Apple success while Apple gets many things wrong with their closeness and such right.
Scott: but then again, am I just the guy complaining?
Scott: But anyway, there's nothing to do with their design right?
Scott: is they just hand down the design.
Scott: They never do any focus groups or anything.
Scott: They just design it and say this is it.
Scott: This is what we think is great.
Scott: this is what you get no changing and Like it or not like it or leave it.
Rym: Oh, I feel like we could do a shark.
Rym: I almost want to go back you and me and we should play cs16 and Then see a source like back and forth a couple times and then I don't remember what cs16 is like.
Scott: I kind of remember but I haven't played.
Rym: I remember the visual field, but I it's been so long.
Scott: It's a lot faster and slipperier.
Rym: I don't think it's actually faster and I think one it's.
Rym: I think source is slipperier.
Rym: I want to go shoot the poop - But anyway things of the day.
Rym: so if you've got some fuck I'm gonna have some fuck laying around.
Rym: What do you do with it?
Rym: Well, maybe if you've got some shit and you put it down in a glass bowl put some fuck on it I'll have a fuck shit stack.
Rym: and that is the topic of this song which Surprisingly our friend Conrad had never heard and it's the kind of thing I would have expected him to hear.
Rym: so I wonder if any of you have not heard it.
Rym: The song is fuck shit stack, and I don't know if I want to say anything else about it Other than that.
Rym: it is by the.
Rym: I almost said late and great.
Rym: He's not dead Reggie Watts.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So this is all over the Internet's.
Scott: it's on College Humor now, but I saw it before.
Scott: it was on College Humor.
Scott: So this is not cut as a college humor thing falling down on the College Humor thing of the day.
Scott: Yes, sure, whatever.
Scott: So this dude does his little science project where he takes a superconductor and some magnets and liquid nitrogen And he freezes that superconductor so cold that it has a scientific phenomenon that I forget the name of called something locking Whatever.
Scott: Basically, I don't really understand what's going on here.
Scott: I tried to read it and I was like I don't get it.
Scott: But basically the magnetic fields get frozen or some shit and it hovers.
Scott: you can make things hover in The air if they're really cold Superconductors of a certain type.
Scott: there's like two types of superconductors has to be a certain type of superconductor It has to be really cold and has to have magnets and then it can hover.
Scott: but we can't actually develop any sort of floating cars or anything because they would have to be really cold and made of giant superconductors with giant magnets in the street and Liquid nitrogen all over the fuck and it wouldn't work All right.
Rym: Yeah This this thing of the day caused me to read over lunch.
Rym: the Wikipedia article is on pretty much everything related to superconductivity.
Scott: Can you explain this to me then?
Rym: and I forgot the majority of it.
Rym: It has to do with the fact There are two kinds of superconductors.
Rym: I figured out that part one is permeable to magnetic fields and one is not.
Scott: All right, so as a result Anyway It's real science is not bullshit though.
Rym: in the meta moment we were at the New York Comic Con.
Rym: as press We will have a review of it whenever we have time.
Rym: I am going to Japan with Emily for two weeks starting next week So the schedule for GeekNights might be a little wonky.
Scott: We only need four shows in the can.
Rym: the next conventions.
Rym: We will be at will be burning Apocalypse con.
Rym: Oh, yeah that on 11 11 11 11 11 12 11 12 11 and 11 13 11.
Rym: Yeah, I carried away with my 11s.
Rym: Yeah, it's all the way up.
Rym: And then we will be at mag fest.
Rym: Yep, mag fest.
Rym: Oh We are guests as we were last year.
Rym: I imagine that we will go to mag fest forever much like the penny arcade expo for as long as it exists and Doesn't fall apart like katsu-kan.
Scott: So also the book club selection is a double book.
Scott: Oh my god all the way one very tiny book the little prince by Antoine de Saint-Ejou Paris, which I assume I'm pronouncing correctly because no French people have yet to complain There aren't French people.
Scott: and also another book by him that you that takes more than 20 minutes to read Which is the wind sand and stars.
Scott: Also by Antoine de Saint-Ejou Paris.
Rym: I will point out not to advocate piracy, but I have a Kindle I just bought and I wanted to you get an e-book of the latter.
Rym: the former has pictures so don't you have two long plane rides to read and There is no official ebook.
Rym: If you google for that book, you will find a PDF right away.
Rym: I found physical books all over the place I know but I wanted an e-book and I'm saying if you google for the name of that book and the word ebook You will find a PDF.
Scott: I don't care if you buy the book.
Scott: I just care if you read it.
Scott: That's what book club is about reading a book.
Scott: Also visit us on the internet facebook.com slash front row crew twitter.com slash GeekNights for a crew calm and such.
Rym: and if you want us to Appear at a convention at a school at an event any of the things that you guys like us to come to?
Rym: Pretty much everyone I ran into with the New York comic-con says something to the effect of.
Rym: so when is your show?
Rym: To which I said, oh, we're not doing one.
Rym: So if you want us to appear at anything Don't contact us.
Rym: that will get you nowhere.
Rym: contact the thing you want us to be at now.
Rym: if you run the thing and Have the actual authority to invite us as opposed to yeah I'm a volunteer for the screenings department of a convention.
Rym: I will ask them to bring you.
Rym: then we'll talk but otherwise tell the event itself to invite us and As long as they're not dick bags is a good chance will come if you know they're not a million miles away and whatever.
Scott: yeah
Rym: I mean It depends
Scott: right
Rym: all right,
Scott: so we did do a show a long time ago
Rym: in 2007
Scott: about reviews in General not about game reviews specifically, but about reviews, and I'm sure there was much talk of game reviews in that show however But we really haven't done a show about specifically Video game journalism, which is a long-standing hot topic in the video game world especially because well you know people like to be meta and all your video game talk comes from video game journalists who talk about themselves and Because it's a relatively new field of journalism compared to other fields of journalism such as political journalism.
Scott: There's a lot of you know questions and uncertainties and because a lot of the people in the field are not professional journalists I mean they they do.
Scott: they do journalism as their professional job, but they weren't necessarily trained in journalism.
Scott: You know That thoroughly.
Scott: you know there's a lot of you know sort of murky areas, and it's not.
Scott: you know It's not the same.
Scott: reporting on video games is not the same as reporting on governments or other things.
Scott: So you know there's.
Scott: there's often much talk about many things in this department that are very controversial like Pay.
Scott: you know people getting paid for better review scores.
Rym: Yeah, there was just a story Today about how Dutch newspapers are being pressured by EA.
Rym: They basically if you wanted to review copy of the game you had to fill out a survey and the survey was like do You like the game?
Rym: What do you think of our primary competition?
Scott: Alright, so let's let's cover that to begin with right.
Scott: so You know the fundamental problem here Is that any video game journalism that exists right is usually on its own?
Scott: It's not like in a newspaper.
Scott: That's pretty rare right.
Scott: so it sometimes exists in a newspaper But usually it's in a video game website or a video game magazine like IGN or Kotaku and all the advertisers Or the vast majority of them are video games, and they don't want it.
Scott: You know if they lose those video game advertisers They're out of business.
Rym: Scott are you implying that there's a perverse incentive in the journalism of video games due to the fact that it's kind of this?
Scott: Huh right you know.
Scott: so look at the New York Times.
Scott: right the New York Times Doesn't really have political advertising in it.
Rym: now it may, but that's not its only source of advertising.
Rym: There's gonna be like.
Scott: main source of advertising.
Scott: is Macy's and shit like that?
Rym: yes, and even then Because you know being a respected source of journalism means that if you have an advertiser say Macy's and Macy's was like murdering babies You would cover that.
Scott: yeah, you would still say that Macy's is murdering babies.
Scott: You wouldn't give a shit you better.
Scott: But you know because video game you know magazines They're not.
Scott: you know these places don't make that much money They're not that stable.
Scott: and also the people there are you know I mean sure there's plenty of highly People with lots of integrity there and highly people with lots of I'm headed to say high integrity people But I got it backwards.
Rym: it happens Even if you know an individual journalist may say I am not influenced by that factor Which they may believe, but how many studies show that if you you know if doctors are given perks from a drug company they start Prescribing that drug more even if they don't actually believe that they were influenced by the gifts
Scott: exactly?
Scott: and It's just a psychological fact whether you acknowledge it or not.
Scott: if someone gives you free shit Even you know it's like in Prince of Nothing.
Scott: He sent you what.
Scott: no have you ever talked to him?
Scott: well Yeah, did you that he sent you?
Rym: It's the same thing.
Scott: It's the same thing.
Rym: So even if they say they're not and even if they believe they're not It looks bad kind of like how if you look at any major company they'll have rules about You know like business integrity or conflict of interests and usually the rules aren't like.
Rym: you know.
Rym: You can't have a conflict of interest.
Rym: They are you cannot have one.
Rym: nor can you have something that would appear to be one.
Rym: This definitely appears to be one.
Scott: well Yeah And the thing is is that the people while even individual journalists might care The people running say video game magazine at least.
Scott: I can't speak for all the magazines But there are clearly some and also websites.
Scott: They don't give a shit.
Scott: They're just like all right whatever I don't care about.
Scott: you know the integrity of our magazine or whatever.
Scott: Let's just.
Scott: you know you want to pass money.
Scott: sure this is a money-making business.
Scott: I just want to make money.
Scott: I don't care.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: we can couple this with the fact that the video game industry especially the major players I'm EA are like petulant babies when it comes to reviews.
Scott: Yeah, this is another thing Right.
Scott: so on the one hand you've got this problem of the reviewers.
Scott: Given people better scores.
Scott: if they pay more money and less scores they pay less money, okay, whatever.
Scott: Why the fuck do these companies actually think their review scores are important like this?
Rym: I think they have numbers showing that review scores correlate directly to sales, and I wouldn't be surprised if that were true.
Scott: It's possible But I highly doubt that it's the cut.
Scott: you know the cause and effect is Good.
Scott: is in that direction right?
Scott: if I put out a piece of shit game tomorrow Are you gonna seriously tell me that that piece of shit game if it gets all fives from some video game magazine is gonna Sell like crazy, or you know perfect scores.
Scott: It's it's not it get it.
Scott: Games sell more when they have more Marketing when they're more out there, and if they're more out there and they're better marketing the marketing Even if you didn't directly pay and be corrupt.
Scott: if you have tons of ads for your game all over the place And it's like this hot hot explosive game It's gonna change how people perceive it regardless of the content of the game itself.
Scott: You know like look at that firefall thing right.
Scott: it bags Advertised all over.
Scott: the fuck.
Rym: can you hire a guy to drive in a circle for three days?
Rym: Around a convention with a billboard on his truck right?
Scott: and the thing is even if the game Doesn't get the best scores right the fact is is that because they spent so much in marketing?
Scott: Every game magazine reviewing place is gonna review that game because it was advertised so much You know and because every place reviewed it that you're actually even if you gave it a bad score You're still giving more space more FaceTime to that game for the customers, and it's gonna sell more copies.
Rym: now I will bet a place where reviews like that especially scores matter heavily, but then again They're usually outsourced and not done by you know.
Rym: quote unquote professional Journalists our app stores like the iPhone game store droid whatever those customer reviews They're all I actually personally trust.
Scott: Amazon reviews kind of probably too much Yeah, like ones also, but especially when it comes to video games.
Rym: It's there's so much shit Where it's not even like crap where it's just shit where on The iPhone and Android that unless someone I know and trust said try this game There is no game.
Rym: I will try especially because they're not free.
Rym: nor are there demos most of the time.
Rym: So as a result if I do want to try a game And I want to look for something like random the only way to look Short of finding someone else recommending something which again is a sea of shit is to go by the reviews in the system.
Rym: What are the top rated or most downloaded games?
Scott: and they're usually crap yeah?
Rym: They are.
Scott: you don't want those.
Rym: That's a separate problem, right?
Rym: So you know what are the things people always complain about?
Rym: they people you know people who hate on video game journalism because I don't Wanted this to be just us hating on it because well I can tell you there's really only one thing I personally hate about game journalism because you know what.
Scott: I don't look at scores So I don't care if they're you know I don't really read reviews either So I really don't give a shit about if they're corrupt or not.
Scott: the one thing that bothers me most about game journalism is game Journalists who don't know anything about games, right?
Scott: It's like your only job or at least your major job here is to write about games.
Scott: You should know more about games than me.
Scott: my job is computer science and writing computer programs.
Scott: I just play games.
Scott: You know.
Scott: that's like if you know when I listen to say sports casts right or watch sports TV shows or Sports Center Those people always know more about sports than I do right.
Scott: I just watch sports I don't you know.
Scott: I know as much as I know which is probably more than Your job is not to watch sports and write about it.
Scott: these guys always know a fuck ton more than me.
Scott: They say names of people and then I go look up who those people were like.
Scott: cuz I didn't know who they were.
Scott: like Rod Laver.
Scott: I didn't know Rod Laver was.
Scott: Rod Laver is the best tennis player to ever exist.
Scott: Well, I mean look at I don't know who he was But then I listened to a sports cast and I learned something when I read game journalism.
Scott: I've rarely if ever learned anything from any article in any game magazine or game website ever Except for when they're about things that are like Japanese, which is why I didn't know about them Which is why I tend to like Kotaku better because they actually have Japanese correspond.
Scott: Ashcraft is over there digging up the Japanese dirts that I don't see in the US, you know.
Scott: But it's like they don't teach me anything cuz I know more than them Which means they don't know enough.
Scott: because even though I know a lot there is a lot more to know than I know You know, so it's like if I know more than you you're not qualified for this job And I haven't really found anyone who is qualified and eat and it's not.
Rym: there are a few out there people.
Rym: There are people wear the journalist hat and who simultaneously Play games or design games But that's it.
Rym: They also design and play games and thus know but they're not the the kind of prominent game journalists Yeah, the big-name game journalists and are usually really good at writing, you know people like N guy crow or Steven DiTillo.
Scott: Right, and I've met law.
Rym: I mean they're.
Rym: they're writing style.
Rym: They're writing.
Scott: They're great.
Scott: They're great at writing.
Scott: I've met them in person at PAX for like a minute.
Rym: They're great guys.
Scott: They're good They're good guys, but the fact is, you know and guy crow started gaming when the PlayStation 1 came out, you know I mean, he's probably gone back and played some classics But he doesn't know.
Scott: he doesn't have that incredibly deep knowledge of the history of gaming and all sorts of crazy shit.
Scott: and Steven DiTillo Never played doom until relatively recently.
Scott: He wrote a big thing on Kotaku about how he tried to play doom and he couldn't get it to work.
Scott: and all this I mean, I'm like, how can you be like this preeminent game review journalist guy if you've never played doom?
Scott: You would never.
Scott: you couldn't even be a movie critic for the town newspaper If you have never seen Citizen Kane dude never played doom, but he's like top game journalist Meanwhile bullshit.
Rym: Mike and Jerry, you know game in taiko penny arcade.
Rym: They basically spend their lives, you know other than family and eating and sleeping and all that Making a comic running conventions and playing video games and their you know reviews of games They play are actually usually very spot-on because they do.
Rym: they do know a lot about games.
Scott: They're they know what you know, but they're not they don't.
Scott: they still don't know as much as me, but you know They know that a challenge.
Scott: Yeah, I mean they're not.
Scott: you know, it's like.
Scott: they know, you know, they go back Scott.
Rym: What year was doom published?
Scott: Doom one doom one 1991 to 1991 or 1992?
Rym: you're saying yes three 1993 close close.
Rym: You're close close.
Scott: Anyway, you didn't know I'm not good at years Trivia that that's not knowledge of gamery.
Scott: That's knowledge of you.
Rym: But the thing is guys they have a pretty deep knowledge and the reviews are very good.
Rym: my only complaint with their game journalism is that They review all games from their perspective.
Rym: Being two people whose lives center around playing games and don't have a lot of other responsibilities Mmm, so they will love a game that I can play and say wow I would love this if I had 20 hours a day to play video games.
Scott: Yeah It's another thing is that you know when people review a game at least the vast majority of reviews.
Scott: Right, it pretty much comes down to the same kind of reviews that punk kids write in forums on the internet or on their blogs.
Scott: Which is?
Scott: I like this game because X Y Z right or you know They'll judge games because oh it didn't it wasn't innovative or it didn't do anything new or they'll actually care about the graphics.
Scott: So, you know?
Scott: No, actually, you know, it's like though do those things matter?
Scott: It's you know.
Scott: Are you actually judging whether it's a good game or not?
Scott: and they kind of are kind of are.
Rym: here's the thing It's it's like there isn't?
Scott: you know, this sort of formula of here's the things you have.
Rym: What I was getting at with what people complain about.
Rym: people love to hate on video game journalism But their complaints are often kind of dumb or invalid like they'll add they'll say video game journalism isn't objective.
Rym: I want objective reviews only.
Scott: well, there's no such thing as objective review.
Scott: first of all Unless you had
Rym: simply a list of facts about the game and unaltered screenshots of the game
Scott: No, and if we had a list of criteria by which to judge all games
Rym: like graphics Maybe we count how the total the maximum number of colors on the screen to any one time throughout the whole game And we have a metric based on that color ability or colorfulness Yeah, then we could say this game is more colorful than this game
Scott: great
Rym: by these criteria.
Rym: Sure The other side that people complain about is they get mad when someone reviews a game and Gives it a score like people get really mad like.
Rym: so it's like the hip thing to say.
Rym: Oh fucking scoring games.
Rym: That's like the bullshit way to review things.
Rym: Scores are not inherently bad.
Rym: I just think they're often used very poorly and the categories are not are very ill-defined.
Rym: I mean, I've just found this random IGN review of Super Mario 3 on the Wii.
Rym: Okay, it was broken out into five numbers presentation Graphics, how is presentation different from graphics sound?
Rym: Okay gameplay lasting appeal mm-hmm, so Gameplay is one fifth of the metric but that should be 90% of the score.
Rym: and yet Appeal is separate from gameplay.
Scott: It's like if it has good gameplay that it also necessarily has lasting appeal.
Scott: kind of right.
Rym: I mean, all right Let's go through our presentation.
Rym: It gets a nine point.
Scott: Oh, well, this is this Mario 3 as in Super Mario 3.
Scott: Yes, goon tail yellow.
Rym: Yes, but on the Wii.
Scott: so the virtual console version.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Okay, so 9.0 is the presentation out of 10 and out of 10 and it has some text here.
Rym: quote Mario's world was greatly expanded through Super Mario Brothers 3. the adventure is more epic and several new lands and enemies to encounter.
Rym: fantastic.
Rym: So what separates it from a nine point one?
Rym: Yeah, what did it need to go up or down one point?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: do they do point one?
Scott: Here's what bothers me.
Scott: They just do.
Scott: do they just do whole numbers.
Rym: No, they don't just do whole numbers.
Scott: Can it possibly be nine point one?
Rym: graphics 8.0 some of the best 8-bit work ever done.
Rym: Yet an 8.0.
Rym: Okay, seeing Mario encounter the oversized enemies of giant land still impresses me to this day.
Rym: How come that's an 8?
Rym: if it impresses you to this day and it's some of the best 8-bit work ever done?
Scott: What what's a 9?
Rym: And also is this an objective scale?
Rym: Normalized to modern games like wouldn't Mario 3 be a 2.0 compared to like crisis?
Scott: That is something that happens a lot right is that people judge, you know, and you sort of you have to judge Agree by the time it comes out.
Scott: right like if I take you know, say I don't know what a relatively mediocre move Not even by the time it comes out.
Rym: you you you rate it more by How well it achieves its purpose with just an understanding of the limitations of the but also understanding not just what the you know The technologies of the time but the other art of the time.
Rym: But at the same time the counter-argument is that a movie that is amazingly made from the 20s But is just like visually difficult to follow because of the camera problems that they had is Objectively worse in that regard.
Rym: had it been made with modern equipment.
Rym: It would have been a better movie true.
Scott: But I'm talking about saying, you know, I could take something from today.
Scott: I could take a crappy video game that just came out today and I could bring it back to you in 1986 and it would be the greatest game of all time Even though it's crappy today because compared to other things that came out today It's not so good.
Scott: A lot of times what you'll see is a game will come out.
Scott: That'll be a huge hit And you'll see a sequel come out that will streamline the original and be much better.
Scott: But compared to other games that have come out since in that interim period the sequel isn't better Than some other game that came out the same way like case in point.
Scott: It's better than the game that came before it.
Scott: So it's an improvement, but it doesn't beat other games at that time.
Scott: So even though it's a better game it actually gets a worse score than the original game even though it's better than the original game because it's worse than some other game that Is also out at that time.
Scott: So for example half-life 2 might be better than half-life 1 but half-life 1 came out in what?
Scott: 97 98 something like that 96 and half-life 1 was better than all the other FPS is at that time that it was released.
Scott: But maybe half-life 2 it was still better than all the other.
Rym: but I'm saying pretend I guess it means you have to define your turn 10.
Scott: There was a quake 7 that came out at the same time as half-life 2 and even though half-life 2 was a million times better Than half-life 1 quake 7 was a million times better than half-life 2 came out at the same time as half-life 2.
Scott: Therefore half-life 2 ends up with a worse score than half-life 1 even though it's better than half-life 1.
Rym: So maybe one way to go around this is if you have a graphic score from 1 to 10 You need to say what a 10 is and what a 1 is exactly.
Rym: then.
Rym: but then you get in the situation where something exceeds in either direction and then what you do is Rebalance the scale with that being the new one.
Rym: Yep, and squeeze everything else in.
Rym: change everything else's numbers like this game Redefined what worst game means to our journalistic outlet.
Scott: Yeah What I would do if I had some sort of reviewing site is I would just have a chart and the first game I ever Reviewed would be number one and the second game I ever reviewed would either be number one or number two and the number.
Scott: if it was one the number one former number one Get pushed down to two.
Rym: I don't rank everything But based on what criteria?
Rym: because this you know.
Rym: overall Mario 3 gets a 9.5 on this.
Rym: but what does overall mean?
Rym: I mean Mario 3 is a better overall game in what sense compared to some other type of ranking should pretty much be worth.
Scott: Spending your time on assuming what's not.
Rym: super meat boy great game, but not for some people.
Rym: Yeah, so what do you do with games that are for an audience?
Rym: There are ten for that guy, but there are one for me personally.
Scott: no, you know, that's just how it is.
Rym: Yeah, so what do you do?
Rym: because the reviews I like you read the fucking text and the reviews I strive for when I do Review things are to be able to say on a on a kind of semi objective artistic standpoint.
Rym: I feel like this is a you know, a reasonable neutral review as to the qualities of a thing.
Rym: Independently.
Rym: Here's who I think it is good for.
Rym: here's what I think it is bad for to be able to say I Personally think this game is shit.
Rym: But if you like this kind of stuff this game is awesome.
Scott: Well, you know, it's.
Scott: it's pretty much like, you know, look at the game of go right the board game.
Rym: I don't like go I don't like go.
Scott: Of all time playing go but go Mathematically and in every other fashion is amazing.
Scott: I just personally can't stand playing it I don't want to spend any time on it but it's Amazing in great in every possible way.
Scott: and if you might be the kind of person who will spend your entire life studying it Reading all the go book studying the patterns and good for you, but I'm not that guy you know, so, you know super meat boy, well if you have no skills and No fingers probably shouldn't play super meat boy.
Scott: But if you have skills and fingers get that shit now and you're highly tolerant to frustration But not quite as much frustration as necessary as in games.
Scott: Like I want to be the guy or ninja Gaiden Yeah, it's not that bad.
Rym: Yeah I'm kind of feeling this kind of an aside.
Rym: I kind of Maybe just because I've watched a whole bunch of retro game master, but I kind of want to play One of those fuck you games play that play the incredibly hard ones like cat Mario or the flash.
Rym: No, because Mario is just memorizing.
Rym: I don't want that.
Scott: I Like the one.
Scott: I think you should just play the Modern impossible ones like the flash games that are just like up spikes out of nowhere up, you know this thing, you know It's like I might.
Rym: I think some games are like.
Rym: I think I might start with God hand which I didn't actually play.
Scott: I don't think God hands that kind of you.
Rym: I don't know now that you're thinking of that kind of game in terms of the fuck you impossible Nintendo hard style.
Rym: I'm just thinking in terms of a game that's gonna piss me off to no end.
Rym: But I will not let defeat me because I haven't done that in a long time.
Rym: I tend to let games defeat me If I get like.
Rym: if I sat down today Having never played Zelda 2 before and was gonna play it I would get to the hammer part and be like, yeah, fuck this and just go on to counter strike.
Rym: I could do it I could but I don't know if I would put the effort into a game of that difficulty.
Scott: It all depends, you know giving up on games.
Scott: I guess it's sort of a separate show, but it all depends on the reason that the game is fucking me, right?
Scott: It's like if it's fucking me because I just can't make it like super meat boy Then I'm gonna keep going for it.
Scott: But if it's a game where you know The reason I can't make it is cuz some bullshit then I will give up on it because the game is broken not me.
Scott: You know if I'm broken I'll fix me if the game is broken.
Scott: Fuck it.
Scott: I got other shit to do.
Rym: So Scott, what do we do about game journalism?
Scott: I think number one Things we can do now as gamers fucking ignore the goddamn scores.
Scott: They're stupid and we start to be you know and make it known that you don't give a shit about the scores either.
Scott: Right, and it's even worse is that metacritic site that like averages all the scores together and then steam puts the scores in steam.
Scott: It's like oh, come on.
Scott: Really, you know, it's like get rid of the fucking scores.
Scott: Just get them out of here.
Scott: You don't see, you know movies.
Scott: It's like thumbs up thumbs down and five stars.
Scott: But it's like game scores are like all over the fucking place.
Scott: You know, it's ridiculous.
Scott: Also, if you're are gonna keep the scores because I know we're not gonna actually get rid of them, right?
Scott: There's that ten-point problem where everything gets between a five and a seven, right?
Scott: Five stars is the optimal number to rate anything and don't use any fractions.
Rym: I would argue that a five-star system has one flaw in that you can always go for the third middle star.
Rym: I. There is an argument to be made that when you're reviewing anything you should force the review to be slightly good or slightly bad.
Rym: Yeah, because it prevents laziness then you need a four star system.
Scott: Well, well you can you know, the thing is you can force our systems.
Scott: not bad either but that you know.
Rym: I guess I'm just saying there's an argument to be made there.
Rym: Yeah I guess I found you know using to go into enterprising land doing ticketing systems and everything.
Rym: I would originally use five levels of severity, you know, five four three two one one two You know critical at the top trivial at the bottom something like that and things tended to always either be critical or the middle
Scott: three Just like video game reviews is like five seven ten.
Scott: That's the other thing with five seven nine because you don't want to give it a ten.
Rym: Maybe we need to change the scale because we kind of have great inflation where you know If a game is less than like seventy five percent or whatever that's considered that it's garbage.
Scott: Well a lot of you know, like when we review in the comics, you know, and some other podcast do the same thing.
Scott: They do like, you know, buy borrow and ignore you'll actively destroy, right?
Scott: So it's like your recommendation like I recommend that you go out immediately pay full price for this game And you know that should be the recommendation list.
Scott: You're like the top possible recommendation is buy this immediately for full price and play the fuck out of it right under that is you know.
Scott: Okay, maybe try to get it at a slight discount and maybe play it a lot kind of if you really want to You know.
Scott: and then under that you can have you know Like okay wait for this to be discounted at you know a year from now or wait for all the DLC to come out or you Know they give an actual recommendation like get this for free somehow and play it if you like it or try the demo And you know, maybe an actual recommendation.
Rym: we go back.
Rym: we go back to an idea of you have a journalistic outlet.
Rym: However, you do it where every game has like ten Recommendations and each and and each of these recommendations is from a different perspective.
Scott: There have been magazines that have done that.
Scott: there have been and we're usually one person writes the article who is like.
Scott: Usually the person writing the article is a specialist in that kind of game like the platformer guy reviews the platform game but then all the you know, a bunch of people like five different people play the game and Give it a score and a slight
Rym: and we go based on mechanics like for a platformer.
Rym: You know, this is how it is if you like for the details of the platformer player Like if you're like super meat boy, if you love platformers, it's great.
Rym: If you don't like platformers It's possibly the worst game you could ever play.
Scott: Yep Yeah, it's like if you just had you know a specialist in a genre.
Scott: But then the thing I hate is that even more enforces the genre fication of games, which I hate and I want to see go Away.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Well, that's why you need specialist because you need the specialist perspective because there are specialist gamers.
Rym: You also need the generic.
Rym: Uh, I don't want to say enlightened but the kind of the mass I mean, we're even.
Rym: you know, Scott and I are very guilty of.
Rym: there are Arenas of games that we generally don't like so we tend not to review them because we tend not to play them that much Yep.
Scott: Also, what do you do when say for example a you know a game?
Scott: Has problems that aren't really the fault of the people making the game, right?
Scott: So what if for example some guy made a game for PlayStation and it was great but the PlayStation Network was down so it didn't work, you know, or Someone made a game but then Everyone started cheating at the game ruining it?
Rym: But that's the game design flaw sort of.
Scott: but you get my idea right.
Scott: like there's something else outside of the game That is causing it a problem.
Rym: You could argue that most of those things outside of the game are still the fault of the game designer.
Rym: They are in some way gave a lecture to that.
Scott: Like if you have a shitty community, you know It's cuz you made your netcode is bad.
Rym: You only have one server.
Scott: Yeah but there are still you know many things that could happen.
Scott: like what if I put a game out on steam?
Scott: and what if valve Fucks up and like, you know The downloading of it is all screwed up and I have to put out patches or something.
Scott: But it wasn't my fault.
Scott: or I put a game on Apple and then you know, the they change something on me.
Scott: You know, there's there's all sorts of technological and other issues that could happen to a game that would make it bad.
Scott: that aren't your fault.
Scott: Yeah might give you a negative review.
Rym: otherwise, you know, you know, I'll do from my perspective.
Rym: I don't read any game journalism.
Scott: What if?
Scott: what if I make a movie and I put it in the movie theater and the movie theaters all have shitty projectors And the bulbs are dim, right?
Rym: I should have taken that into account.
Rym: I would have known if they all have dim bulbs, then you got to account for dim fucking bulb.
Scott: That's the kind of thing that happens, right?
Scott: So, um, I made a game and Man, it just doesn't work with this weird-ass video card that I couldn't test, you know The one that everyone has.
Rym: I should have tested it.
Scott: No a rare one, but that happens to be the one the reviewer has.
Rym: Yeah, usually the reviewer will say hey your game didn't fucking work.
Scott: Yeah, you know.
Scott: There's also the the fact that you know reviewers even if there's no shady business of advertisers pressuring them or any of that kind of stuff right They.
Scott: if you get a game for free, you know Cuz it's a review copy or something even if it's the same exact game as the final copy You didn't pay for it.
Scott: So not paying for it, you know gives you a completely different mental.
Scott: You know thing on the game right like if I pay for something and I don't play it I feel bad.
Scott: like you have different feelings about something when you've paid for it then if you've gotten it for free and That difference in feelings results in the review even if you really identify with that reviewer and you're very similar in your taste is Gonna have a different perspective than you who has to pay 50 bucks for it, you know.
Scott: and in that way I sort of feel like video game reviewers Should sort of have to pay for the game, you know when you if you're a movie reviewer Don't they pay for a movie ticket usually?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I don't know either.
Scott: I know people do get review copies of books But the thing is with a book even though you're not paying for it There's a significant time investment to read the whole thing and some games do have the time investment But some games don't.
Scott: so I don't know.
Rym: Well, I think we've gone on long enough.
Rym: But that's not only and you know you touched on this earlier I Don't read game journalism.
Rym: And the only thing that would get me to is if when I read game journalism I learned something that I would not have just learned on my own.
Scott: Yeah, I tend.
Scott: if I'm reading game journalism It's usually something that is you know Historical or it's not something that's like a review of a game or something like that or a list of facts because a list of facts I get from anywhere like the game has this multiplayer or not.
Rym: this publisher comes out in this day that everyone has that right?
Scott: It's usually something like hey Check out, you know the This guy.
Scott: this is a great designer.
Scott: No one ever heard of.
Scott: he made these games back in the day.
Scott: Let's interview him.
Scott: What was it like back in those days?
Scott: What made you do this?
Scott: You know something educational something like a documentary this the Super Mario 3 review.
Rym: Is that for people who if you don't know what Mario 3 is.
Rym: it?
Rym: Gives you a lot of info on like what Mario 3 is and kind of why it was important and when it came out and that's Good, but at the same time it's not for me.
Rym: I know it all of it and it doesn't talk a lot about anything obscure.
Rym: It's kind of like Just a description of what the game is like.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Another thing one more thing.
Scott: I want to add here.
Scott: That's is that You know game reviewers if you're good, even though we already talked about doing the thing We have a bunch of different reviewers or specialists in different areas or stuff like that, right?
Scott: We need more reviewers from different demographics, right?
Scott: Where is the?
Scott: you need the the five-year-old kid reviewing the game, right?
Scott: You need the the 80 year old lady review in the game, right?
Scott: Because different people are gonna have different, you know From different demographics and different skill levels and different genders and different whatevers are gonna have different perspectives on a game, you know Especially different ages, you know and people generally.
Scott: most game reviewing people tend to be 20 to 40 year old dudes and that's it and occasionally ladies And not too many old people and not too many kids really and If you're a kid and some 35 year old dude really thinks this game is awesome.
Scott: Does that mean you're gonna think it's awesome as a 12 year old?
Scott: Probably not.
Scott: You probably don't have a lot in common with that guy.
Scott: He probably thinks pokemons are really boring.
Scott: you think pokemons the best thing ever.
Rym: I find pokemons really boring nowadays.
Scott: Yeah, right But it would if if you played the new pokemons if I gave if I went back in time and gave 12-year-old Rym the brand new pokemons That would have been the best game ever, right?
Scott: It's exactly so.
Scott: you need the 12 year old to tell the 12 year old what game is good.
Rym: I guess what we're missing from game journalism that I don't see anywhere and if anyone can point me at it Maybe I just haven't found it because I've you know, I've given up on it for.
Scott: so don't look at it.
Rym: Yeah is otakuusa Like that level of like insight into video games that we see into with them talking about anime Mm-hmm, because that's the kind of reviewing I want that I just don't see for video games.
Rym: Yep This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and brand.
Scott: Okay For the logos be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.