Scott: It's Wednesday February the 2nd 2011.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Scott: I'm Rym, and this is the night tonight the century ancient incredibly old battle of the dub and the sub.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: I.
Rym: Yeah, I know Scott that you said the year.
Rym: have you given up on that battle.
Scott: Do you notice?
Scott: I said 2011 and not?
Scott: 2011. yeah, the Daily Show says 2011.
Rym: They're wrong.
Rym: They're right.
Rym: you said if it was the year 1911 would you say?
Scott: 1911 or would you say 1911 depends?
Scott: What do you mean depends?
Scott: sometimes I say?
Scott: 1948.
Rym: you said 1991 1992 19 all through your whole life.
Scott: It was 19 and that number.
Scott: so now it is 20.
Scott: And then the number.
Rym: yeah 22,000. they're pretty much the same.
Scott: only in the first decade 2001 2002 as soon as you get that was one D.
Rym: That was the arts.
Rym: no 2010 that was 20 on one.
Scott: you could do that to 20 on to jerk, but it as soon as you get to 2010 It's funny said that I can't use.
Rym: I will probably never live to see the day where I can use on a guarantee.
Scott: You will never live to use odd again.
Scott: if you use odd again I will give you all my money except possibly referring to the past.
Scott: I will give if you use it hit it to refer to the present year correctly ever again in your entire life And I am alive and you are alive.
Scott: I'll give you every money.
Rym: I own so anyway There's not a lot of you know weird.
Rym: It's Wednesday anime manga comics all that stuff and yet there usually isn't that much news lately.
Rym: that well We at least care about.
Scott: well actually there is a comic news.
Scott: You want to hear this comic news?
Rym: I'll hear this comic news.
Scott: I also have a geek bite, but I want to do both.
Scott: is that okay?
Scott: You can do both.
Scott: alright It's a comic news.
Scott: you ready.
Scott: I'm ready.
Scott: You probably no one.
Scott: This is weird because it's sort of like this thing.
Scott: well That that was true for a long time, but wasn't completely true.
Scott: and basically now It's completely true.
Scott: so Superman's dead.
Scott: no wizard magazine is no more wizard magazine.
Scott: It is existed.
Scott: it is ceased to be.
Rym: no really wizard still exists.
Scott: also toy fair magazine.
Scott: How about scribe?
Rym: is scribe still going?
Scott: that's dead a long time Yeah, but basically right.
Scott: the wizard whole thing was going downhill for a long time and people you know used to love it in The 90s but now more recently they were hating it and they were like oh wizard and wizards been doing a lot of bad shit With their conventions to real bad.
Scott: right.
Rym: but remember Philly wizard world.
Scott: yeah, that was that was right before they got real bad.
Rym: Yeah, that was honestly one of the most boring and depressing conventions I have ever seen.
Scott: but anyway, you know so the whole wizard thing they're pretty much gone.
Scott: They've hit rock bottom now, and it's it's game over, but you know it's like back in the day like wizard.
Scott: You know it's.
Scott: it's one of those things where it's like.
Scott: it was such a gradual decline.
Scott: You know it's not like newspapers.
Scott: It's gonna be the same situation right.
Scott: such a gradual decline That the day they die is gonna be so unmomentous because they basically been shindeiru for many many years.
Scott: It's like you know.
Scott: you know.
Scott: it's like.
Scott: It's like when five years ago Kentro went what that that that hit wizard in the in the neck.
Scott: But today they just exploded.
Scott: so it's like we knew that finally go out of business.
Rym: We won't like who would.
Rym: how would I even know if AOL went out of business?
Scott: Yeah, it's like it by the time that they go out of business.
Scott: They're gonna be so tiny already.
Scott: It's like you know they shrink so much I don't know.
Rym: well that actually dovetails quite nicely into my news because while you know wizard that whole aspect of comic-dom was Basically on the decline forever.
Rym: not forever, but for all of modern history Reed and the New York Comic Con and all those things have actually been on the upswing.
Rym: Reed is kind of taking the New York Comic Con and the shell of what remains of the New York Anime Festival and turn them into An SDCC competitor.
Scott: well they're pretty much That's always what they wanted and now they're.
Scott: they're going even farther to pretty much copy the San Diego Comic Con in every conceivable way.
Rym: And that is the news.
Rym: the New York Comic Con is officially now not one not two not three But four days.
Scott: well the fourth day is really a preview night.
Scott: It's not a full day.
Scott: where else have we seen a fourth day preview night, San Diego, Comicon And they even call it preview night.
Scott: They're calling it the exact same thing.
Rym: yeah I'm not very conflicted about this.
Rym: I do not fault Reed for making this decision.
Scott: Yeah, if you're a pro for-profit con you did it's gonna make you money.
Scott: How could you not do it?
Scott: it, but I but it does.
Rym: it service the fans now well well well well It does in a way, but does it service the industry?
Rym: it doesn't service the same fans because there's different kind.
Rym: There's like three kinds of conventions that at least Scott and I care about these days.
Rym: They're the only ones we go to.
Rym: there's either the real deal professional convention run by people who know what they're doing.
Rym: Yeah, like the New York Comic Con, New York Anime Festival.
Rym: You know all the Reed cons.
Rym: There's the fan run con that has a lot of spirit, but is run by incompetent morons.
Rym: Maybe I shouldn't name names those cons You know like the Otakons and as much as I love ConnectiCon we're staff.
Rym: We were directors of programming and stuff and even we have trouble there, and and then there's Pax Which just does everything perfectly?
Rym: yeah, I says like all the benefits of the fan con and all the benefits of the pro con with pretty much no drawbacks.
Rym: and Nope, what bothers me is that the New York Comic Con and Reed?
Rym: They're doing everything right.
Rym: if they came to me and said Rym How can we make more money with this con and make it more popular?
Rym: I would say do everything that you just did.
Rym: yeah, but it makes the con way less fun for people like us.
Rym: It's fun for the Hollywood types the people who go to see a famous person or to see the guy who's playing the superhero in The superhero movie based on the comic they didn't read.
Scott: it's also fun for people who are like you know They want to dig around in bins of comics for a long time and see like absolutely amazing.
Scott: You know that kind of stuff, but you know there are other places to do that.
Scott: It doesn't it's not exclusive in that regard.
Rym: It's also fun for the I don't want to say casual fan because that is such a misnomer And it has too much connotation.
Scott: Yeah, if you were like a slight fan of nerdy stuff, and you went to this it would just blow your mind like oh Like.
Rym: I have a lot of co-workers.
Rym: They're not into comics or into anime or into gaming But they do and consume all of those things and they don't think anything of it.
Rym: so they hear oh, there's a comic-con I'll go for a day, and it's big and flashy and there's crazy stuff everywhere, and they have an awesome time.
Rym: It's basically only not fun for what I would almost call the advanced fan who is not single minded and single focused.
Scott: Yeah, I mean if you're an advanced the thing is there are advanced fans who have you know some sort of?
Scott: you know?
Scott: They like to spend money.
Scott: right because it's your comic con Yeah, the whole convention.
Scott: if you gear the convention towards making money Then what you're gonna Do is you're gonna make it most appealing to the fan who likes to spend money?
Scott: So the kind of fan who's not a big spender someone who's not interested in shopping or paying for art from artists You know.
Scott: or and pretty much you know Buying DVDs and paying to see get autographs and all that you know.
Scott: someone who's not going to pay money someone who's there to Participate in sort of community things right.
Scott: look at the conventions like PAX and even Otakon.
Scott: how many community meetups.
Scott: and go in the forums.
Scott: Let's get together and play Pokemon.
Rym: There's the surface level flash kind of show me stuff.
Rym: There's the Programming like actual discrete programming not just like the big floor, but like go to this panel go to this event Yeah, and then there's the hang out with like-minded people and we know we've said this a lot And we have a lot of like-minded people.
Scott: doesn't make the convention more money so that is minimized.
Rym: Well, we have a lot of evidence at least anecdotal evidence from the last decade of going to conventions that by and large Comic-con attendees.
Rym: any comic-con are not there nearly as much for the community.
Rym: well actually heard to anime fans who are only there for the community.
Scott: well one thing I have noticed right is that the Many of the people who are there for the community right are the people behind the tables right?
Scott: It's like if you're some guy who's like a podcaster will be there behind the table And he's friends all these artists who are behind tables and they're friends with vendors who are behind tables And they're friends with other people who are behind in the expo hall right and there's a community there.
Scott: And there's also a community between people who are you know sort of into the same thing right.
Scott: so a whole bunch of people might be in line for an artist and they're all fans of the same thing and this community in that respect or Maybe a whole bunch of people are fans of the same.
Scott: You know Publisher or something so they'll be all around that.
Scott: publishers You know dealer area yep, or they'll be the guys who are in a community of Trading comics that are sealed in plastic.
Scott: so at the table where they seal stuff in plastic those guys are all together right?
Rym: But there isn't community like you know Triwizard drinking tournament community yep Or it was most stark last year the New York comic-con New York anime festival win if you walked around any part of the con.
Rym: But the anime ghetto it was basically a giant crowd of people shuffling and looking walking around looking around walking around looking around Standing in a lot of money, and if you went to the anime ghetto it was just as crowded.
Rym: But it was people like in big Clobs just talking to each other and hanging out and dicking around and running around and hitting each other and just like sitting in Circles good and bad good and bad.
Rym: I'm not gonna say that it's all good, but then again I'm an old man who's too old for that shit.
Rym: That's right, but it's very.
Rym: They're so diametrically opposed and while our Programming like the stuff didn't eyes what we do like our real lectures Really fit more on the professional comic-con side like you do the professional panel.
Scott: it's more fun to hang out in the anime side and Consequently and even though the even though the presentation of our panel is professional the content is more geared towards Than you know not the comic people.
Rym: yeah well it was very telling that the because the comic and the anime panels last year were kind of separated and Every time I walked over to the comic area unless it was Famous guy talking about his thing there was literally like two people in every room.
Scott: Yeah, they were like panels over there were either crazy full or crazy empty.
Rym: I mean most of the anime panels at least the ones I saw were actually really Crowded like all of them.
Rym: just there was a solid group of people that were just going to every panel.
Rym: Yeah, and the end result of this is that I don't know where the New York comic-con is going other than that It's becoming SDCC in NYC.
Scott: That's what it is.
Scott: Yeah, that's pretty much it and We'll see what happens.
Rym: last year We were gonna really up our content, and then we we ended up only doing one panel in the anime side Which was fun, but it made me realize this weird aside It's kind of a GeekNights meta thing.
Rym: we haven't been to many anime cons in the last year.
Rym: No, I mean we ditched on Otakon because they didn't like they didn't have anything for us and We didn't go to a lot of smaller anime cons that invited us out.
Rym: I think Zenkai Con is the next anime con we're going to since anime Boston.
Scott: Anime Boston Zenkai Con.
Scott: we're down And ConnectiCon is has anime content.
Scott: Yeah, ConnectiCon has anime, but it's an everything con anyway.
Scott: So I'm gonna do a geek bite here.
Scott: Alright, so this normally it's a video game, but this is not a video game for video game people.
Scott: It's basically for anime manga.
Rym: It's not for you alright.
Scott: The game is it's a DS game, and I'm sure you might have heard of it.
Scott: It's called.
Scott: Well it's nine person.
Scott: I'm not sure which nine persons.
Scott: nine don't know.
Scott: nine hours nine persons nine doors.
Scott: I forget which order it's like hours persons doors or persons doors hours, but anyway.
Scott: It's nine nine nine.
Rym: What's the equation is like door hours per person?
Scott: It's nine nine nine nine hours nine persons nine doors.
Scott: That's the game and this is It's an adventure game right on the DS when it's very very focused on story And it's pretty much got you know anime characters, which are pretty well designed and a very good Naoki Urasawa.
Scott: ish kind of story right or it's one of those.
Scott: you know.
Scott: It's in the genre of sort of Death Note where there's a crazy scenario.
Scott: it basically the crazy scenario is You're some guy Junpei.
Scott: you got you know Ether.
Scott: oh no you wake up in a room on a boat And there's a number five on the door And you've got a wristband with the number five on it also sort of a battle royale kind of situation.
Scott: you know same kind of thing also, and then you realize there's a whole bunch of people on this boat with wristbands with numbers and You can only give you there's a number.
Scott: you have to get out and In order to get out you to go through.
Scott: you know these numbered doors and solve puzzles and then there's a lot of plot and you got it's a choose your own adventure book where Occasionally you have to stop and solve a bunch of puzzles, and then you know more.
Scott: choose your own adventure occurs.
Scott: Now I don't want to talk about the game too much except to say this one thing The number one problem in the game is slow text speed.
Scott: But there are multiple endings and if you play through again any text you've already seen you can fast forward.
Scott: Ah, however when you play through again If you do the same puzzle again if you choose say the same path And there's a puzzle you've already solved you do the puzzle again You can do it again really fast because it's the same puzzle.
Scott: I would hope but you had to do it again.
Scott: anyway Here's the thing about this game.
Scott: I said alright for my first playthrough cuz Conrad sort of you know told me what was up with it before.
Scott: You know he was like.
Scott: I do not know what is up, but he didn't tell me all that was up.
Scott: He just told me that it was.
Scott: sort of you know it was annoying with all these different endings like he's like.
Scott: all the first Time I played I got that shit ending and then the second time I played I got the to be continued ending and I was like Oh great So I played it and I said I'm just gonna do whatever I feel is right and see what ending I get.
Rym: that's the best Way to play a game like.
Scott: so I got at the.
Scott: I beat it yesterday.
Rym: That's how I played.
Scott: one chance I beat it yesterday, and I got quote-unquote the coffin ending right, so I said all right I got the coffin ending.
Scott: it said to be continued.
Scott: I was like aha I didn't die on the first ending.
Scott: that's better than the coffee.
Scott: here I got the hit.
Scott: I did better than Conrad.
Scott: So then I'm like all right time to go to game facts.
Scott: so into game facts and look at a list of endings you ready For some bullshit.
Scott: Uh-huh here's the bullshit the coffin ending.
Scott: I guess this is a minor spoiler.
Scott: the coffin ending is The true ending.
Scott: in order to get the quote true ending you have to do the exact same thing.
Scott: you have to do to get The coffin ending.
Scott: however, it's simply that you can't get the true ending on your first playthrough.
Scott: There is no way.
Scott: so in order for me to get the true ending at a place of play the exact same game again Making the exact same decision no no no no you don't.
Rym: what you have to do is type true ending into YouTube.
Scott: hello That's what I did last night.
Scott: all right But get this.
Scott: so you're ready for this.
Scott: so I typed true ending into YouTube And there was a guy.
Scott: he made like a at least 40 or 50 part video of the whole game Including the true ending right every single second of the game.
Scott: wow so I was just watching from the part where the coffin is forward at through that you know past the to be continued to through the true ending.
Scott: and If you're doing the true ending basically there's a whole fuck ton of game beyond that point.
Scott: like there are multiple puzzles.
Rym: Wait so it's a Castlevania situation.
Scott: Yeah, but pretty much the only way to get to the upside-down castle is to beat the game twice the exact same way.
Rym: I guess I'll have to deal with that.
Scott: and no I just kept watching on YouTube.
Scott: I wrote down.
Scott: I couldn't even finish it cuz it was so long.
Scott: I'm gonna go home, and I'm gonna pick up at part 42 And keep going until I see the end because there is no way I'm gonna play the exact same game again even with fast-forwarding The text.
Rym: what's funny is based on a vague reading of what the plot is.
Scott: Pretty good death note battle royale and Arasawa kind of suspense.
Rym: there's a movie I watched recently just randomly because it was on Netflix while I was like cleaning up the apartment called exam.
Rym: It's from 2009. eight dudes locked in a room to take an exam, and that's the whole movie.
Scott: Yeah It's a similar.
Scott: It's one of those weird scenario Sci-fi thriller mystery situations that you know it always seems to work out really well.
Scott: I mean They were 11.
Rym: Yeah, actually they were 11 and exam kind of similar.
Scott: It's a. it's a whole.
Scott: it's a genre that I'm getting sort of keen on.
Scott: you know I mean death note.
Scott: I think sort of really.
Rym: I hear by dub it.
Rym: I hereby dub it the 12 angry men.
Scott: genre 12 angry men is not really the same genre because it doesn't have these sci-fi mystery thriller even though it does have a scenario.
Rym: Right yeah, but I think it's the closed scenario limited number of people.
Rym: They don't know what the answer is and you don't know what the answer is.
Rym: whatever no whatever there is to answer.
Rym: hmm anyway Or the I mean some of these are the.
Rym: you're in one room for the entire movie.
Scott: No, because what death note is not that right death note is there's you know a weird sci-fi or supernatural Scenario.
Scott: ah.
Scott: but and then the suspense and mystery.
Rym: there's the difference I think between these the scenario that set in the world versus the scenario that's completely cut off from the world.
Rym: I feel like they're two very different kinds of movies.
Scott: now This is pretty much gives this game gives you the same feeling as death note.
Scott: the same feeling is like a 20th century boys.
Scott: They're definitely in the same wheelhouse.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: maybe you should watch the exam.
Rym: well just exam wasn't great But it wasn't bad.
Scott: I got there great things to watch on the list.
Scott: so fuck the exam until.
Rym: So things of the day, what do you got for me Scott in?
Rym: 2011?
Scott: oh snap.
Scott: so Everybody knows Kate Beaton is the most awesome.
Scott: that is not a secret.
Scott: if it's a secret to you Then you are nobody because it's a secret to everybody.
Rym: they'd beaten Consistently makes me laugh more than most people I've ever everybody.
Scott: so anyway.
Scott: So her webcomic is hearts artist.
Scott: hark a vagrant is the best webcomic anyway.
Scott: So you may remember in the olden days penny arcade once did a thing where?
Scott: Some guy took penny arcade strips and erased all the words and then had his students fill in the words.
Scott: as you know a learning lesson right to these blank speech bubble comics And it was hilarity Lowell.
Scott: well it was a guy he teaches English in Korea who's a friend of Kate Beaton.
Scott: he took Kate Beaton's comics erased the words out of the speech bubbles and had the students fill him in and Hilarity.
Scott: I mean this has been done a lot of time.
Scott: any arcade did it.
Scott: yeah a lot of people have done this But this is the most hilarious of all times.
Scott: I have seen it done, so it is a thing of the day worthy.
Rym: So Stanley fish.
Rym: you may not know who Stanley.
Scott: Stanley Spider-man.
Scott: Stanley fish fish spider-man.
Rym: He was a literary critic a legal scholar works for the New York Times all these sorts of things.
Rym: And he shares something at least with me and with I think some of our listeners the number four or not for a mites?
Rym: Yes, just one That he's very much enamored with language and diction and prose and sentences and grammar and all that sort of stuff that I find fascinating.
Rym: all right and He has a book entitled how to write a sentence.
Rym: so what I have for you.
Rym: This is a website talking about it.
Rym: He has a list of what he describes as five of the greatest Sentences ever written in what makes a sentence great.
Scott: Well that you could.
Rym: I'm gonna read the book.
Rym: I already ordered it.
Rym: I'm curious to see what he says.
Scott: is it the content of what the sentence is saying or is it simply the structure?
Rym: it is the structure of the sentence the the manner in which it reveals to you its nature and its truth the beauty of it the symmetry of It all those things combined.
Scott: and I gotta tell you these are some pretty good sentences All right, well let me hear these sentences all right Or do I have to see them to see the punctuation to really get them?
Rym: I think I can read the punctuation pretty pretty solidly.
Scott: all right, so sentence number one.
Rym: Last week I saw a woman flayed and you will hardly believe how much it altered her appearance for the worse.
Scott: Uh-huh all right this one's okay.
Rym: This is from 1678.
Rym: Now he had not run far from his own door But his wife and children perceiving it began crying after him to return.
Rym: But the man put his fingers in his ears and ran on crying.
Rym: life life eternal life That's smart man.
Rym: all one sentence.
Rym: yep I read one more.
Scott: I like how a lot of people.
Scott: this you know reminds me of something.
Scott: a lot of people right there Either don't know run-on sentences, so they write them all the time, or they never write a long sentence.
Scott: They never they.
Scott: they're worried about run-on sentences, so they never write a long sentence.
Scott: I tell you friend.
Scott: I tell you go look at the Constitution or Declaration of Independence.
Scott: We hold these truths to be self-evident that all You can write a fucking long ass sentence and still it would be legitimately one sentence.
Scott: I do it all time.
Rym: also if you want to be tricky There's always the semi colonic sentence.
Rym: semi colons are your friend.
Rym: it just lets you cram sentences into a sentence.
Scott: Not really you can only do it if the set if those separate sentences with it the semicolon are actually part of the same idea.
Rym: Yes, same idea, but not directly related.
Rym: the colon is the directly related right colon.
Rym: is the this therefore this or something to that effect?
Rym: The semi colon is the basically two related sentences.
Scott: right, but you can't be like you know say yet two completely unrelated sentences.
Scott: like you know see spot run and Scott likes.
Rym: Well, I can say this I cannot imagine a very nice sentence that involves a semicolon that is simultaneously imperative.
Rym: I I don't think that can work.
Rym: Yeah, I'll read one more.
Rym: I think this is my favorite one and I shall go on talking in a low voice while the sea sounds in the distance and overhead the great black flood of wind polishes the bright stars.
Rym: Uh-huh, I here's the excerpt from the book.
Rym: in this sentence the personal voice of the narrator is absorbed by the sea sounds a delivered Pun that begin as background and end by taking over the sentence the scene of writing.
Scott: that is a very good Sentence.
Scott: that itself is a good sentence if I see what he did there.
Scott: Yeah, that's very good Lava girl, so It's not a college humor But I mean the fact that you had to make a big deal of the fact that it wasn't is telling Illustrative of the problem.
Rym: so we will be met a moment at the penny arcade expo doing not one two three four But five panels three of which collapsed into one panel right for a total of three panels.
Scott: There's a whole bunch of conventions the Zenkai con the week after PAX East anime Boston's like a month after that.
Rym: Next weekend February 11th Friday.
Rym: We'll be at nerd NYC board game night at think coffee in Manhattan.
Rym: I only say this and keep saying it because we are there at almost every one of these and a lot of listeners show up.
Rym: If you want to meet us hang out with us.
Rym: if you want to play modern art with me and Scott next Friday We'll be there.
Scott: All right You should go to our website.
Scott: It's broker calm.
Scott: You should Go to the forum forum the broker calm.
Rym: you should read the GeekNights book club book, which is currently Michio Kaku's Hyperspace.
Scott: Yeah, you should follow us on the Twitter's and all those sorts of things like that.
Scott: You know Internet's people Internet's and That's enough metamome for now.
Rym: So many of you are probably thinking Rym and Scott.
Scott: Why are you talking about an issue that's been dead for a decade because we couldn't come up with any other idea for a show Today and I came up with it and we never did a show on It.
Scott: so it deserves a show.
Rym: I think it's also.
Rym: I mean, it's a debate like nowadays.
Rym: I don't think anime fans remember the bullshit that used to go on.
Scott: Well, I mean some of them some of them don't remember some of them don't care but it's definitely.
Scott: it's always there at the bottom.
Scott: It's just you know, there are some issues right that They're.
Scott: they're pervasive issues, right.
Scott: and the number one pervasive issue for the last decade and a half is copyright.
Scott: but the thing is the copyright issue keeps rearing its head and coming back and coming back and coming back because New things keep happening to it and it keeps rearing and rearing and rearing.
Scott: but sub and dub was a big issue especially in the VHS days because you when you bought VHS had to pick you had to pick and The sub usually cost five to ten bucks more.
Scott: Yep, not less and also many times you wouldn't have a choice Right, so it was a big issue then and more recently it was become less of an issue because DVD.
Rym: you buy the DVD and Everyone gets their own personal preference and it was a huge like people would get weird about it Like it was like the old school of fans like how dare you watch the dog?
Rym: We could watch this job be perfect.
Rym: And then the new fans like whatever.
Rym: I just wanna watch my show.
Rym: Leave me alone you old fat nerd.
Scott: Yeah But yeah, basically, you know The fundamental thing here is you want you got a show some sort of piece of entertainment, right?
Scott: I mean we did do the show with the with the Oda King, right?
Scott: You talked about subtitling.
Scott: a lot did you know and he but he was mostly complaining about the low quality of the fan subs And their method of subtitling and not whether subtitling or dubbing was better or worse.
Rym: I mean to do that that we could talk about fan dubbing if we really wanted.
Scott: no No, I mean the fundamental issue here right?
Scott: is you have some sort of artwork primarily, you know a video game or you know An anime right and you need to translate it so that people who do not speak the language It was originally creating can understand it.
Rym: It's also a problem.
Rym: That's very particular to visual moving media.
Rym: I mean, you're not gonna put subtitles on a book.
Rym: You're just gonna translate it in most cases.
Scott: Yeah, you know, no one's gonna complain about what was your method of translating the book?
Scott: You know, it was translated.
Rym: what I would like that.
Rym: I'm actually surprised.
Rym: No one does.
Rym: this is Subtitles for audio dramas just timed subtitles.
Rym: that are just subtitles that I can watch while I'm listening to an audio drama.
Scott: Why?
Rym: because there are a lot of audio dramas that are not translated that are actually supposedly good.
Scott: Oh I see what.
Scott: yeah, like basically the good listen You could listen to a Japanese audio drama while reading a translation of it because I could print out a translation But without the timing.
Rym: that's actually really hard to do.
Scott: Yeah, you have to figure out which line you're on.
Rym: I mean, I've watched anime where I had just a script printed out and I'm watching it.
Rym: Yeah, and that was not Pleasant.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean, you know the fundamental problem is the other thing.
Scott: you might translate it, right?
Scott: But you also in the translation, right?
Scott: Do you want how much do you want to be lost in the translation?
Scott: right and the Subtitle people?
Scott: their main arguments are like look.
Scott: Okay, the subtitle at worst covers up a small part of the artwork, right?
Scott: but maybe you can even do a letterbox and get it underneath or something right and Once you know how to read subtitles, it doesn't really distract your eyes from the from the picture at all.
Rym: That's a weird argument.
Rym: I always was amazed by the people who would say that this they couldn't catch up with the subtitle.
Scott: You just can't read.
Scott: Yeah, you got to hear not smart.
Rym: But then again part of that I was reading an article kind of relatedly a few days ago talking about maybe if
Scott: I problems or Something I don't know
Rym: talking about how a lot in most foreign countries subtitles are very very very common just for everyone even little kids even little kids.
Rym: cartoons will often have subtitles in a lot of places because America makes a lot of the media.
Rym: that's in the world.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean there's plenty of dubs like how many Simpsons Seinfeld dubs have you seen?
Rym: But I'm saying for every dub.
Rym: There's a ton of subs and I don't see people complaining about Subtitles in other countries.
Scott: No, it's only in the US.
Scott: I've ever seen people complain that there are subtitles.
Scott: They're never subtitles on the US TV pretty much ever ever.
Scott: For like a crazy showing of a foreign film that's on like a weird foreign film, you know channel.
Scott: That's for you know, people who like that sort of thing.
Rym: Meanwhile, I mean look at us anime fans There was a time when we would watch live-action American like English things like the ratio hornblower and we would turn on the subtitles just because we were used to it.
Scott: Well, it was also because we'd be so loud while watching it So you wouldn't get you would have to pause it and rewind because you didn't hear that ratio.
Rym: But I'd always be startled when I didn't see subtitles, but I don't know it's.
Rym: it's weird how Vitreolic it got.
Rym: like being in the RIT anime club a very large anime club.
Rym: There would be bitter arguments and like lost friendships over this sort of thing.
Rym: like the club would always show things subtitled because we had kind of this side reason of the fact that RIT is the NTID the National Technical Institute for the Deaf and the RIT anime club was actually very popular among deaf students because they could just watch the anime.
Scott: Yeah, and the thing was is we would always have the subtitles on no matter what because of the deaf Attendance.
Rym: however as an aside, you should all know that subtitles and closed captioning are completely different.
Scott: That's correct.
Rym: They're very different things.
Rym: closed captioning will also note things like sound effects or noises.
Rym: Yeah, the subtitles do not by default.
Rym: if they do they're not really subtitles anymore.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: However, we would always have the subtitles on you know for those people because I don't know how many anime DVDs had full closed captioning On them.
Scott: right, but and that was fine.
Scott: No one complained, you know, the deaf people were satisfied with that.
Scott: However You know that sometimes I remember at least two or three incidents We would have the dub with subtitles on because you know the audience for every reason wanted to watch the dub.
Scott: But you know the policy of the club was generally Japanese language with subtitles.
Rym: now I mean my argument.
Rym: I mean I was on the eboard I was the president of the club I voted and we debated that sort of thing a lot.
Rym: my argument for pretty much always showing subtitles was the one English dubs of Japanese Animation are some of the most god-awful pieces of shit I have ever heard in my life.
Scott: Yeah, I mean not all of them are bad.
Scott: There are many good ones.
Scott: However, you can have a discussion about how about which ones they are because there's so few of them, right?
Scott: There's you know, the cowboy bebop.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Some of the Disney Miyazakis are pretty good I'll sing had a surprisingly good dub.
Scott: some people like the ghost in the shell stand a little complex ones.
Scott: Okay, you know There are a lot of people who have a lot of nostalgia for like you get all the way down to hi I'm Fasha Stampede.
Scott: Yeah, I mean there's some people have a lot of nostalgia.
Rym: The worst dub ever to this day is Armitage the third poly matrix with Kiefer Sutherland.
Scott: No, you forgot about He.
Rym: literally a girl is like being shot and falling off of a cliff and on the screen the characters like Desperately jumping and reaching for and Kiefer Sutherland says no No, you got it.
Scott: What about the the gassaraki?
Rym: Oh my god that one extra.
Rym: The thing is the rest of the dub was actually pretty good It was alright, and there's that one guy who is like what's the matter you shiro?
Rym: Yeah, remember, of course What's funny too is a lot of the older dubs and it's not just nostalgia.
Rym: A lot of people say oh you just think the older dubs are better because that's what you grew up watching.
Rym: The older dubs were a lot freer and looser with the translation and as a result the acting I think was a lot better.
Scott: Yeah, the acting you know in many of them was was more and it was better in ways Actually worked pretty well.
Scott: Yeah, there was a lot less stiffness and other sorts of acting related problems.
Scott: But I dub is hilarious, but in terms of you know purity to the original work, you know They had some serious issues, you know, pretty much most of well I mean there are some dubs that don't have such issues.
Scott: But is that the older dubs definitely had those issues and part of the one thing that made your contributor is the insistence on not Only translating but sticking to you know making everything match the moving lips of the characters really
Rym: funny when you because
Scott: the Japanese people don't even try to do that in the original.
Rym: Yeah, you watch the original and nothing matches up at all I mean, there's no relation.
Scott: Yeah, the Japanese the original audio track didn't match.
Scott: So why should the dub match?
Scott: Why should even matter, you know, I mean obviously if saying it in English Completely translated is gonna take ten times as long or a fraction of the time You still the time is still an issue, right?
Scott: Like if you translate.
Scott: if someone says like, you know a word in Japanese and that somehow I don't know You know that translates to a sentence in English It's gonna be problematic or vice versa.
Scott: right if something's a big sentence in Japanese and you can just translate it to you know Fuck you or something like that That's a problem, but you don't have to match the actual syllables, you know.
Scott: You just have to make sure it's the right length of time in there.
Rym: Well, I remember this one time at RIT anime when we switched the dub on cowboy bebop.
Rym: She watched the sub most of the way through and the club was like, hey the dub here is actually really good You want to.
Scott: well, there's a particular episode that you have to watch the mushroom Mushroom.
Rym: Yeah, so we watched that episode dub and then we just left the dub on yep And actually some people walked out like people walked out of that showing once the dub was turned on.
Scott: I don't remember that.
Rym: remember a hoagie.
Rym: Steve walked out.
Rym: I don't remember.
Rym: He got super pissed when we changed it.
Rym: We voted yeah, and him the whole room voted and a few other people I could name.
Rym: they all walked out and They were mad about it.
Rym: They were mad that we switched.
Scott: I don't remember them.
Rym: anyone walking out perfectly Bible dub and One of them his sighted reason and he grumbled about it for a while Loudly before he just left was that during the the beta mags VCR episode of the VHS in the beta.
Rym: Mm-hmm There's this one scene where the guy who has the VCR is going on this long rant about technology that no one cares about like Well back in the day beta was this bla bla bla bla.
Rym: She's like this long rant and it's funny.
Rym: the subtitles did not match what the guy was saying in the dub and This fanboy was like see see the dub is way off from the subtitles.
Rym: the dub.
Rym: Oh, you're accurate.
Scott: You're assuming that the subtitle is correct also.
Rym: Yeah, the subtitles were also way off because it was a translation of something that it didn't even matter what the guy was saying.
Rym: Yeah, I guess what bothered me.
Scott: that is the thing is if you don't know the original language There's sort of this assumption that the subtitle be you know is a is a the best translation, right?
Scott: You just assume that because it's it has this authoritarian.
Scott: It's just it's in a position of authority.
Scott: So if a dub doesn't match it that the assumption is that the dub is wrong more wrong than the subtitle always.
Scott: Yep, but you know, it could just be.
Scott: they're two different translations of the same thing and They're both equally off in different directions and you have to look at each case Individually and you have to know the original language to make a judgment call.
Rym: But that's what bothers me.
Rym: almost every bitch like intelligent people can argue the merits of both Intelligently and come to a conclusion.
Rym: I have my preferences I can articulate them I can understand other people's preferences, but the fanboys on both sides would Basically be wrong about the technical aspects of translation.
Scott: They didn't know Japanese usually and They would basically just argue from this position if you know Japanese you don't care if it's dub or so as you can just do either way.
Rym: my stance though, is that When in doubt unless you have a reason to watch the dub like for example If you're doing something else and you're watching the anime casually the dubs fine But if you actually want to see the real show you should watch the subs.
Rym: But I think the dub is better for someone who does not watch a lot of like.
Rym: if it's anime Who doesn't watch a lot of anime in Japanese?
Rym: They don't like.
Rym: get the language like.
Rym: I don't understand Japanese that well at all me.
Scott: Hey there but why?
Rym: having watched anime for the last 20 years I Can understand the inflection like if I hear Japanese being spoken and I see a translation that is accurate next to it I understand all the emotion you can kind of feel it.
Rym: you understand all these kind of subtle aspects of the language even without understanding the individual words and Dubs translate that better for someone who is not familiar with the Japanese language.
Scott: well if they're if they're done well right and I think that pretty much means that you shouldn't start someone who's never watched anime before who might be a fan of it is Coming into it shouldn't watch a bad show right.
Scott: and if if they if you know if they're gonna start with a dub I mean we started with dubs right on TV.
Scott: They didn't start with no subs.
Rym: Yeah, vampire hunter D.
Scott: Kashawn robot hunter project echo You got to watch something where you know that if the dub is not good Then if they're going to watch a dub show no matter what then that's not a good show.
Scott: They have to watch something different.
Rym: Well, the trouble is what I run into is there were a lot of people who weren't anime fans So I would try to get into the anime and I didn't want to show them dubs.
Rym: This was like high school and middle school because the dubs were god-awful and I could even tell they were god-awful.
Rym: Yep, because and think of this if you say you hear a show on in the other room You can always tell if it's an American anime dub versus any other kind of show just by listening to it For
Scott: like a second just based on the way the people talk.
Scott: because they don't you know They're not talking the same way regular people talk.
Rym: They're not talking the way voice actors and anything but anime talk.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: Well video games also.
Rym: video games are just as bad.
Rym: That's a bad, you know, you're right, but Basically everyone I tried to show anime to I couldn't show him the dubs because the dubs were terrible.
Rym: And if I tried to show him a sub they'd say the fuck are these subtitles and they refused to watch.
Scott: Yeah, that's that's the thing.
Scott: It's like you got both sides, right?
Scott: There's the fanboy.
Scott: who's such a fanboy?
Scott: he refused to watch a dub and he's stupid for his own reasons.
Scott: But then the person who says I refuse to watch this, you know subtitles.
Scott: They're stupid for their own reasons You know, it's like you got these.
Scott: it's stupid versus stupid.
Scott: And the truth is is that you should probably watch subtitles most of the time But it does not.
Scott: all dubs are bad.
Scott: There are good dubs.
Scott: They exist.
Scott: They're not gonna kill anybody.
Scott: Right, there's reasons for them to exist.
Rym: For example a show that is very like certain kinds of shows probably would be better served by a well-done dub Because the well-done dub is more natural to anyone who isn't fluent in the language.
Rym: However, there are almost no well-done dubs.
Rym: So it's kind of like arguing about whether or not unicorns are blue or red Or the size of Gandalf's dick, I just can't seven inches.
Rym: I cannot express to you how Crazy this argument used to be.
Rym: you young anime fans have no idea Like I wish.
Rym: I wish I could just take like go back in time and film like RIT anime in the year 2000 1999 oh my god, like it was fierce But to this day.
Rym: like look at conventions and all the people still fight about it But only the fanboys fight about it because not that many people watch anime at conventions anymore.
Rym: I think that's.
Rym: part of the reason why it's not an issue is that the culture is not a culture of watching collectively.
Rym: it's a culture of watching your fans subs on your own watch your country roll on your own and Then if you get together you get together at a con and just hang out.
Scott: Yeah I do think that it's sort of like, you know There's a good part and a bad part to the fact that you know the.
Scott: because of the collapse of the anime industry There's not that much dubbing going on as it used to be.
Scott: only the few animes that get on DVD are dubbed and even now You know, there's been more recently some subtitle only DVD releases towards the at least towards the end days.
Rym: Guarantee of a dub is if it's gonna be on TV right or they're trying to get it on TV.
Scott: but in most of the all the animes that are on crunchyroll and Streaming on the funimation in the anime news network and fan subbed and all these shows right are pretty much Subtitle only.
Scott: and I think this is good in a way Because the car the modern anime fans are watching shows now or going back to watch old shows Right are getting you know, the better truer subtitled Experience and there's no weird bad dubs to turn them off or anything like that.
Scott: You know, so the people who are watching anime now I think you're getting a better appreciation for anime and the Japanese language and these sorts of things.
Scott: however, I think it's actually it's sort of like.
Scott: it's sort of like a Closing the door, right?
Scott: It's like anime went downhill.
Scott: So now it's subtitled only and now anime can't go back uphill because there's no dubs to get new people.
Rym: At the same time so many people won't watch some.
Rym: among youth culture I found just looking around more and more.
Rym: Is that references to anime are just a general understanding of knowing what Naruto is like?
Rym: this kind of It's very widely known among young kids you know if they don't watch a lot of anime almost every punk kid you ever run into has seen some anime knows what it Is and treats it just like they'd create any other TV.
Rym: in a way the anime fans that were trying so hard to make anime regular basically mainstream.
Rym: One in that as anime became more and more accepted and more and more mainstream the culture around it disappeared because There's very little real culture except for the hardcore people around the Simpsons in America.
Rym: I mean, you know, that's that hardcore Simpsons fanboy.
Rym: They exist.
Rym: Most people just watch the Simpsons.
Rym: They're not gonna go to a Simpsons convention.
Scott: Yeah only the super hardcore people are gonna go to a Simpsons convention.
Rym: but people who know about TV might go to a TV convention cuz.
Rym: oh, yeah, they go to the Simpsons there.
Scott: I'll go see that and there might be some Simpsons action there.
Scott: Yeah at a TV convention.
Rym: But I think anime cons have gone down the same road and I think this is part of the reason why the dub sub debate Has disappeared because the collective watching of anime is no more popular now than the collective watching of TV.
Rym: Yeah, you watched anime the same way.
Rym: you watch TV mostly alone maybe with one person on your computer.
Scott: Yeah But yeah, I mean, you know there there are issues in terms of the quality of subtitling but we discussed that in Don't watch crappy fans with the Oda King right back in the day.
Scott: Yeah, you know, and there's also the issues of What's it called with two different kinds of translations?
Scott: Well, no, we talked about that also with the Oda King.
Scott: Oh, what do you got?
Rym: What do you get?
Rym: Nothing?
Rym: You got nothing?
Scott: Right like sometimes right like on the the the Gundam the Z Gundam.
Scott: Right, the subtitles are just like all busted and you know, they fixed them on the other disc, right?
Scott: So it's like a mother, you know You some.
Scott: just cuz it's subtitles right doesn't mean that it's good either.
Scott: There are plenty of bad Subtitles out there, you know a lot of people to sort of take for granted The subtitles are right and good or whatever, but that is not always the case.
Scott: So, you know and especially in the olden days if there were bad subtitles, right?
Scott: You paid more for that VHS with subtitles than the dub one than the dub VHS.
Scott: You would be hella pissed off.
Rym: Yeah It is interesting that the subtitled ones were more expensive because there was less demand for them.
Scott: yet They were cheaper to make.
Rym: yet at the same time anime fanboys by and large preferred subtitles Yeah Which meant that a lot of non anime hardcore fanboys were buying anime back when it was 30 bucks a tape Four episodes.
Scott: Well, maybe two episodes But some of the thing is a lot of the VHS tapes most of the sales were to like blockbusters.
Scott: Yeah, so and a lot of those things were so it were you know That were released early on.
Scott: VHS were mega popular things like Akira that everyone and their mother would buy.
Rym: Yeah, the anime section of blockbuster when I was a kid was bigger than the anime section of blockbuster when I was in college.
Scott: the Akira dub VHS definitely sold way way more than this the rare subtitle VHS even though I've seen that subtitle VHS plenty.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.
Scott: but yeah dub for some sub verse dub.