Rym: It's Thursday September 22nd 2011.
Rym: I'm Rym and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We talk about weddings.
Rym: Let's do this Much like Pinkie Pie.
Rym: I like to party.
Rym: I like to go to parties a lot, and it's funny that I like to go to parties a lot more.
Scott: They like to go to work.
Rym: It's funny.
Rym: How when we were in college We did not party like we very rarely had like.
Rym: this is a party.
Rym: we basically just hung out And did stuff or usually didn't do stuff.
Rym: That's a party or just played games.
Scott: How is that not a party now?
Rym: Well see what I think of party.
Rym: I differentiate it from hanging out.
Rym: when I say let's hang out I invite specific people to do something or I have a general invite, but no no agenda No, nothing, and I don't provide any food.
Rym: to me party means wherever I am They're providing food and drink and a larger number of people possibly people.
Rym: I don't know are invited.
Scott: How many people makes a party?
Rym: I think it depends more on whether or not the host is providing food and drink and Entertainment.
Rym: like is it provided entertainment or a provided thing?
Rym: or are you just at their house?
Rym: And you're stealing their orange juice when they're not looking.
Scott: What if you come over to my house, and I pour you the orange juice?
Scott: If you if it was planned ahead of time - is kind of important like if you said hey Rym on Thursday come over you come Over to my house is just you and me and you've been but the orange juice is already poured when you show up.
Rym: ah there's one more step.
Rym: to make it a party it has to be not an open invite to the public, but a Generally either a generally open invite or some sort of RSVP system like and it has to be broken down like the family unit Or the friend unit group like if you say I
Scott: send you a written Invitation to come over to my house for orange juice and tomorrow and the orange juice is already poured and show up
Rym: And that is party.
Scott: okay even though it's two people.
Rym: yes Okay, you can have a party with one person as we learned in my little pony, okay?
Rym: There you go, so the trouble I had is that I for a long time was the one who was always hosting all the fucking parties Which means one.
Rym: it costs a lot of money?
Rym: and to Visigoths
Scott: well, I mean the price of a party varies greatly But
Rym: even a crap Oh party like when we like we had everyone for New Year's right and we want to have dinner for one That was a couple hundred bucks worth of catering
Scott: yep,
Rym: which was a lot more money to us back then than it is now.
Rym: Well, that's your.
Scott: I mean, that's no different than going to a restaurant.
Scott: It's just you're paying for everybody.
Scott: now If everyone you made everyone pay then it wouldn't be so expensive.
Rym: But at the same time that's much more of a pain in the ass to manage it is.
Rym: and also what if someone says no Then you can't get in.
Scott: and I found cover charge.
Rym: I found something to pay me for the door bitches.
Rym: That's right, but I found something more interesting.
Rym: if you expect people to pay for the food Then they will have an opinion on what foods you get and you know what?
Rym: I no longer have the patience in my life to deal with anyone's preferences on anything.
Scott: Yeah even when I'm at a restaurant and there's people there I'm with or even people at an adjacent table that are strangers if They like have trouble ordering or have to like be like say oh don't do this You know, give me this without this ingredient, you know, and it's not for an allergy.
Scott: it's like Dude, just pregnant order something.
Rym: No, no to be fair.
Rym: That's okay at crappy restaurants sometimes but it's a fine line.
Rym: It's a really crappy restaurant.
Scott: I mean, there's a limit Scott.
Rym: if you're at McDonald's you're like, can I get extra sauce on this burger?
Rym: It's like dude, come on.
Rym: But at the same time if you're an ultra fancy restaurant You're paying that chef to do what he does best if you know better than him.
Rym: Why you at his restaurant?
Rym: Yeah, you know I feel like it's okay to say yeah, can I not have bacon on the salad, please?
Scott: Mostly it's you know, the.
Rym: the annoyance depends on how much time you spend deciding true But when it comes to me providing food for people if I say like hey, we'll get catering.
Rym: What do you all want?
Rym: I believe that if I take my entire circle of friends and everyone gets to veto one and only one thing Every possible food will be vetoed except gruel and then no one will want to eat gruel.
Rym: Yep, but you only get one veto people use their first.
Scott: the first person to veto will veto gruel.
Scott: that actually is a little before we get into the main topic and Then the other thing that person doesn't like is the one that's gonna get picked.
Rym: before we get into the main topic I have a word of advice for all of you punk kids who are going through the steps We went through forming your own crews out there.
Rym: eat all food.
Rym: Well Everyone will eat Mediocre lukewarm delivery Chinese, that's true because if you're ordering mediocre lukewarm delivery Chinese You're hungry enough to where it doesn't matter.
Rym: But more importantly if you do have to order food as a group and it's pizza For example use the one veto system works very well.
Rym: Just go around the room first.
Scott: eliminate anything with allergies like celiac or whatever because you can't blame someone for at least You know, if you have enough people you're gonna be ordering multiple pizzas Chinese food.
Rym: you're gonna order multiple dishes true, but if you're ordering like come you like even pizza though all right bigger people - maybe three pizzas if Through three people have specific requirements.
Rym: You're kind of fucked already and one of those pizzas are gonna be plain cheese.
Rym: Yeah, you don't want one of your pizzas to be plain cheese.
Rym: That means you failed as a group of friends.
Scott: Just get one plain cheese and then get an extra meat pizza that you can have something.
Rym: No, because if you have a friend who will only eat plain cheese pizza, what the hell that's true.
Scott: Don't be that guy.
Scott: unless you're allergic and you can't.
Rym: you're allergic to everything in the world, but bread and cheese And sauce.
Rym: But anyway go around the room pick an order and say everyone gets to veto one topping Mmm, you will be surprised how well that works.
Scott: as long as the group is more than like four people and less than like 12 And as long as enough of your friends are reasonable because half the more than half of our people are like I veto nothing Yep, which makes it even easier.
Scott: like, you know, and the thing is also, you know, everyone has tastes right?
Scott: Like.
Scott: I really like sausage or ham or pineapple on pizza.
Rym: I love pineapple in general Yep, but I want fruit on the which is trouble because I my favorite kind of pizza is Hawaiian pizza.
Scott: How is that your favorite?
Scott: disgusting?
Scott: It's awesome But it's like I'm not gonna.
Scott: you know, sometimes they get a pizza with sausage and I just eat it anyway.
Scott: Cuz I'm not a little baby.
Scott: Don't be a baby.
Rym: I feel like I can eat it.
Rym: you would not eat a Hawaiian pizza?
Rym: I don't think.
Scott: probably not but it's like.
Rym: no, you know what you would do with my answers.
Rym: God, I know you.
Rym: you just pick the pineapple and the ham off and then it's just a mediocre slightly wet pizza Maybe.
Scott: but the point is I wouldn't cry and moan about it or do anything like that.
Rym: This is a good exercise for you as the man up Of your group of friends to one assert your dominance by taking charge of the situation to by doing the game.
Rym: You can now use mechanism design to influence the way your friends choose in order to get your desired outcome Which is no hassle one.
Rym: You have to say because and quotes because I am sorting out the bullshit with the toppings.
Rym: you picky-ass motherfuckers.
Rym: Someone else has to call the pizza place And To use peer pressure.
Rym: Someone's gonna be like I want to veto more than one thing and just peer pressure will end that.
Rym: you can't say no go home Yep, get the fuck out.
Rym: That's right, or maybe trade some futures.
Rym: Like I will sell you my veto for $10.
Rym: Anyway, the point of all this is that I really like parties but it sucks to run parties.
Scott: No kidding.
Rym: The answer is to go to other people's weddings.
Rym: Shit because forget let's forget about the.
Rym: you know, there's a whole discussion about whether or not or any sort.
Scott: You know bar mitzvah is also good.
Scott: Yep, pretty much anyone else throwing a party at their expense if I'm going fuck.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: so Weddings in particular.
Rym: now, I don't really want to get into just yet the whole thing about.
Rym: you know, diamonds aren't worth anything.
Scott: or You can talk about how diamonds aren't worth anything.
Rym: They're worth nothing.
Rym: Yeah, or you know, you spent $80,000 on a wedding that you could have had for $20,000.
Rym: if you just been a little more judicious in your plan.
Scott: you spent $20,000 on a wedding.
Scott: you could have spent two.
Scott: What did you waste?
Scott: $18,000.
Scott: now granted I can imagine a $20,000 party.
Scott: it would have to be a fucking week long Or it should I have to be one day a few days long, but you're paying for everyone's hotel rooms and transportation.
Scott: It could just be one day But one epic day and you're paying for their plane tickets or you're paying for a fucking cruise ship.
Rym: to me $20,000 means you had a live band that is actually known by people who aren't you?
Scott: Yes, as in you paid the appearance fee of a famous person for an hour.
Scott: I know some famous people have appearance fees greater than that, but you can get a semi-famous purse.
Rym: you can get c-list.
Scott: Yes, definitely.
Rym: You can get fucking B list you If they're local yeah, and they're a little desperate.
Scott: you can also get tons of crazy shit.
Scott: That's this you.
Scott: you would not believe some of the party shit that is available out there.
Scott: if you want to blow your money And there's a lot better ways to spend that party money then on Useless decorations you're gonna throw away.
Scott: You know a DJ that's you know.
Scott: You could just got.
Scott: you could have bought a whole Serato system for the amount of money you spent on the DJ to do it For one day.
Rym: Well, the key is to just get a friend to do it Mediocrally competent and it's not that hard in these.
Rym: don't ask ab just go for it.
Scott: Yeah, it's not like in the olden days.
Scott: you needed someone with fancy equipment.
Scott: just about every DJ These days is an amplifier two big speakers and some sort of you know two laptops or two iPods and one make dude I?
Rym: DJed my mom's wedding.
Rym: yeah, you know what it cost me nothing.
Rym: You know how much music.
Rym: I had all of it because Napster was around.
Scott: Yeah, I know like bar mitzvah sometimes people pay for like dancers.
Scott: It's like really anyway What kind of dancers like you'll get dancers to go with the DJ.
Scott: the DJ has dancers that you pay and they come with him.
Rym: What I've never seen.
Rym: that at any event on the level low enough to be something I would attend.
Rym: that wasn't like some sort of like events like a media event.
Scott: Yeah imagine if like you're going and you're gonna do the the horror or something or you're gonna do the electric slide and There's like dancers like leading everyone in the electric slide.
Scott: you paid for them And they also go and they usually have like.
Scott: they'll usually come with like two hot girls and two hot guys And they'll like drag people onto the dance floor who are the shy.
Scott: Wow like that's their job.
Rym: I've never encountered professional party dancers I was picturing like backup dancers like just at the front of the room behind the DJ.
Scott: no they like they.
Scott: you know They're like the DJ's like right and left hand people but we don't.
Rym: there have been a number of weddings in the crew and actually it's kind of fun that Weddings in the crew have more often than not been officiated by people in the crew and everyone in our crew Happens to know and be with both sides of the aisle bride and groom.
Rym: So it's kind of like every wedding I've been to in most of my life has been all of my friends having a party on someone else's dime.
Rym: Well, there's all these other people there at least recently Yeah, also family ones Family wedding.
Scott: there haven't been a whole lot of weddings in my family.
Rym: I've not in my lifetime been to two family weddings.
Rym: one of them was my mom getting remarried Which was awesome because like all my friends from town just kind of showed up and ate the pig and Some friend of the family got married once and I just went and got really drunk because my parents kept giving me alcohol And all the middle-aged ladies kept giving me alcohol.
Rym: And it was awesome.
Scott: all the people in my family who are married were married before I was born My close family and none of the people of my generation.
Rym: for me all the weddings I've been to have been the same like this the people I hang out with at the wedding of the same people I'd hang out With anyway, but yet there's a party and catered food and unlimited alcohol that I didn't pay for.
Scott: Alright, but at the same time right.
Scott: while it's awesome to go to someone else's wedding Most weddings are Unreasonably expensive and even reasonable ones are still somewhat unreasonably expensive now It is a lot of money to throw a party and I could understand you would want to throw a party and it costs a lot of money, but some people Overpaid notably on the aforementioned useless
Rym: rocks.
Scott: Yep, and useless one-time dresses and Tuxedo rentals and crap like that.
Scott: And so sometimes what you know.
Scott: wedding venues when you could have just had it in someone's backyard.
Rym: Some venues could be worth it something nice enough.
Rym: I mean venue.
Rym: what one of our friends got married in a pretty rocking castle.
Scott: actually Yeah, but I mean how much did the castle cost?
Rym: actually my favorite party?
Scott: It's like a castle is awesome party.
Scott: I would totally party in a castle.
Rym: The thing is my favorite part.
Scott: how much would I pay to party in a castle?
Rym: at the venue at night that we'd they let us Like use the venue all night long and we just had a bonfire and just sat around drinking.
Scott: That was an excellent a venue that I'm sure was much less money than the castle.
Scott: That was a very great venue excellent day.
Scott: But you know, it's like, you know, I think our friends are the most part.
Scott: I've had more weddings on the reasonable side of cost.
Scott: Yeah most people Seem to spend a lot more money and also a lot of you will get ripped off because when they go to have a wedding.
Scott: Right, it's like you go if you try going to get catering and then try to go get catering But let the caterer know you're having a wedding.
Rym: Yes, like have like have two people called the same set of caterers for the exact same party But one of them says it's a wedding and one of them doesn't say it's a wedding.
Scott: They charge you more because it's a wedding because of the same reason.
Scott: funeral parlors charge you a ton of money because there's this Emotional grasp they have on you like it's your special day.
Scott: Actually the same way you want your special day to be so great, isn't it worth it?
Scott: your one special day You'll remember for the rest of your life.
Scott: It's worth that extra five thousand watch.
Rym: This is when I was a kid.
Rym: I remember seeing this, you know back when local news did a lot more investigative journalism And I saw a local news thing where they went to flower providers, you know botanists, I guess not botanists florists Yeah, I don't know.
Rym: I feel like you.
Rym: into a botanist you get much more interesting flowers, maybe.
Rym: Yeah so you go to a florist and what they did is they went to pretty much every florist in our area like in the suburb of you know Detroit and They would have one where a guy would go and say like he's doing it for some event and he wouldn't say what he'd say like some political function and a girl would go and say it was for a wedding.
Rym: a Guy would go and say it was for a wedding and they videoed with a hidden camera how the people treated these three different People trying to get flowers.
Rym: if her girl went to a wedding it was literally.
Rym: but it's your special day.
Rym: These black roses are only a hundred thousand dollars more, but you'll only have one wedding.
Rym: It's your special day.
Rym: Yeah ripped off to the guy and this actually kind of pissed me off.
Rym: They'd be like do you want her to be happy?
Rym: How will your honeymoon be if she isn't happy?
Rym: What if she regrets that you didn't get the better flowers?
Rym: She'll know.
Scott: you know, what?
Scott: don't buy any fucking flowers.
Scott: How are the power is gonna make the party any better or worse for the for the go to party fucking city?
Scott: It's cheap and you can get some streamers and you know what.
Scott: if you know how to work a streamer it can look fucking awesome.
Rym: Actually, nobody's gonna complain at the wedding We just went to.
Rym: I was very pleased that it was real flowers because having been in the wedding real flower if you're if you are Gonna get flowers real flowers are very important.
Rym: Yes fake flowers.
Rym: I've had fake boutonnieres before and let me tell you fuck those things also when you do get you know That sort of stuff.
Scott: most of the problem with expensive shit at weddings Is that it's a useless or be one-time use.
Scott: right dress is not useless, but it is mostly one-time use which is like Uh, but if you're gonna reuse that dress a whole bunch and it wasn't ludicrously expensive like this.
Scott: wedding dresses for multiple thousands.
Scott: Yeah, if you get a few hundred dollar wedding dress and you reuse it many times Dresses cost few hundred dollars.
Rym: You say a few hundred dollars.
Rym: I mean I've spent over four hundred dollars on an okay suit.
Scott: I've been three hundred dollars in a coat and three hundred dollars in a kilt, but I get you sad of them.
Scott: Yep, if I spent three hundred dollars on the coat and wore it once my whole life That would be fucking crazy.
Rym: the most recent wedding We went to the bride.
Scott: that would be like buying an Xbox and playing one game for four hours and never using the Xbox ever.
Rym: I Scott bought a PlayStation 1 Sure, not that long.
Scott: Did you use it for only four hours?
Rym: I used it for only one day.
Rym: use it for one game.
Scott: That's not the same.
Scott: this dance dance revolution is wearing a dress for one day for four hours.
Rym: It is telling that I put a mod ship in it before I'd ever plugged it in or turned it on.
Scott: You know a ring with a diamond in it is a useless rock and also a work but first off.
Rym: so The wedding we most recently went to the bride had actually an amazing dress like.
Scott: it was pretty awesome Like it is hard for me to not be amazed But it also gets mad props for being it like, you know workable.
Scott: a lot of people get you know.
Scott: Especially women's fashion is often like high heels.
Rym: You cannot walk in them Yep, or a train so long that you need attendance to carry it right like they'll get stuff.
Scott: That is not feasible clothing.
Scott: It just doesn't work as clothing.
Scott: but this dress worked.
Scott: like you just walk around.
Rym: yep, and I'm in general all of our friends who have gotten married have gotten pretty nice dresses that were either very cheap and Good-looking or will be reusable and we're just awesome.
Scott: I haven't seen anyone reuse it yet though They'll see.
Scott: watch for at least you know, if you can hand it down thing is we need.
Scott: But the question is like if you were gonna hand it down.
Scott: Why weren't you wearing the handed down one from your mom?
Rym: Because styles change.
Scott: yeah, okay big deal.
Rym: Yeah, part of that is.
Rym: I like how non-traditional like non-traditional ceremonies are way more fun to me than traditional old You know standard way.
Scott: Well, I mean, I hate tradition.
Scott: in general.
Scott: tradition is never a good reason to do something if it's the only reason.
Scott: So if something is not a traditional way of doing something it automatically gets props for me no matter what Almost always and you know, I mean, all right, I'm beating flash now.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I'm gonna be quick man first.
Scott: That's not a tradition.
Scott: I'm saying that you know, if you're doing something and your only reason that you're doing something, you know Or the only reason you're doing something in a particular way is because of tradition that is usually a bad reason to do it.
Scott: And instead you should figure out you know What is the best way to do something or the best thing to do regardless of any traditions that may exist?
Rym: But yeah under the rock.
Rym: we've talked about this on GeekNights a lot But not recently probably in like the 2006-2007.
Rym: It's been a long time since we talked about this because in 2006-2007 for whatever reason that was just a hot issue for us.
Rym: diamonds Mm-hmm fuck diamonds.
Rym: They're worth nothing.
Scott: Yeah people if you don't know right diamonds are worthless rocks.
Scott: They dig them out of the ground for you know often with very harsh labor, but sometimes not.
Scott: you can get it certified You know mined by not slaves if you want.
Scott: it cost more though, of course And there's bajillions of them.
Scott: It's.
Scott: they're not rare in any way or shape or form.
Scott: They're as rare as the rocks in your backyard.
Scott: Not only that we can just fucking make them and I don't mean make them like oh, it's a kirby zirconia It's not really a diamond.
Scott: No, we can make really a diamond never mind the fact that Genesis or other people you can make real diamonds.
Rym: I defy Anyone who is not a jeweler to be.
Rym: you know Walking down the street see a ring someone's got on and be like.
Rym: that's not a diamond.
Rym: That's a cubic zirconia.
Rym: I can tell by.
Scott: you have to get real close to tell and you know what.
Scott: in fact the fake ones or the ones that We make are usually better than ones that were randomly dug up out of the ground not to mention the fact that basically the reason diamonds are expensive is because the only people digging diamonds out of the ground is One giant company de beers and they put all the diamonds in a big safe in London.
Scott: This safe has just a bajillion diamonds in it a bajillion bajillion and what they do is every once in a while They take a handful of diamonds out in like a briefcase and given to some jewelers and that's they have a very so.
Scott: it seems As if the world is a very slow trickle of increased diamond supply.
Rym: You don't need to take any of this on faith.
Rym: a much better way to illustrate the truth as many documentaries and books.
Rym: There's a very simple way take any piece of jewelry.
Rym: That's legitimate as in.
Rym: you know, it's a real diamond or whatever and get it appraised and See what they say like oh, this is worth X tens of thousands of dollars, right?
Rym: So go to then go to any pawn shop or any jewelry store and ask them how much they will give you for it.
Rym: there will usually be a couple orders of magnitude difference between the quote appraised value and The value anyone in the world is actually willing to give you for it.
Scott: Yeah, GameStop right is is not even close to how jewelry goes right.
Scott: you think GameStop is ripping you off.
Rym: If you want a really nice ring and you actually for whatever reason wanted to be real Get a used ring from an estate sale.
Scott: That's a good idea.
Scott: other good ideas number one Don't get any rare metals or gems whatsoever.
Scott: get something else such as maybe someone on Etsy will make you something, right?
Scott: Why do you even need rings?
Scott: It's because it's a tradition.
Scott: Maybe you can do something else.
Scott: Maybe not do anything.
Scott: maybe get necklaces or earrings or Nothing or tattoos or You got to give.
Rym: you got exchange sets of D&D dice, it's a good deal.
Scott: hewn from something.
Scott: you'll use excellent computer mice keyboards find something to exchange.
Rym: If I saw a wedding ceremony where they exchanged an IBM AT keyboard and like a DOS keyboard That's my wedding.
Scott: That's A kind of lame anyway.
Scott: and but the thing is you can still if you really want to if you have some emotional attachment to do with rings or Jewelry or something like that.
Rym: Seriously, you can at least get something.
Scott: Valuable diamonds are worthless, but you know what?
Scott: gold platinum especially Emeralds rubies all are actually rare and valuable.
Scott: as long as they don't have blood on the rubies can be Manufactured - they can be.
Scott: but they're still actually somewhat rare and valuable.
Rym: and as long as they don't blood on them the thing is I feel like a resin jewel of any kind is a Fully functional equivalent for just about any jewel in almost any situation.
Scott: Yeah, you can also get you know, various polished stones I mean my class that are not the shiny gems But you know stone from high school, by the way punk kids many of you are in high school.
Rym: Don't buy your class ring.
Rym: You'll regret it.
Rym: You'll never look at it again after your freshman year of college.
Rym: Yep, if your parents try to make you buy it ask them to give you cash instead.
Rym: Yep Seriously worthless rocks, but my class ring looks really nice.
Rym: It has all gigantic fake.
Rym: general general You know what mine - looks fine.
Scott: Well, I got the India cut - gigantic fake I guess clear jam, which I it's not really diamond clear That was I guess I don't know.
Rym: I got I got a green one because I liked emeralds and I also like green.
Rym: Anyway, yeah, and what was on the side of your class ring.
Scott: one side had like a rocket ship That was like 2000 and the other side had a computer.
Rym: Ah mine We had a dragon, but one side was a trumpet.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Yeah trumpet and a French horn and it said brass Brass and the other side was the dragon dragon.
Rym: No, it doesn't No, never never doing.
Scott: But yeah, what else you know, mainly just in general most people Spend way too much wet money on weddings bar mitzvahs and other sorts of parties than they should.
Scott: they could have a lot more Fun for a lot less money just like I think it would.
Scott: then it was it a thing of the day.
Scott: once these people on Reddit we're gonna have their wedding in a mansion and the guy who owned the mansion Canceled on them at the last minute.
Scott: So they that they went on reddit and they said help us.
Scott: reddit said have it in a field.
Scott: They called up their uncle who had a farm.
Scott: They had the wedding with some bouncy castles on the field of the farm for nothing because it's the uncle's field.
Scott: They had horses that were just there so people pet the horses and It was the amazing wedding that cost almost nothing compared to the mansion that they were gonna pay a fortune for.
Scott: So, you know, it's just you know, it's like nothing wrong with having a party.
Scott: Getting married is a good occasion to have a party.
Scott: any occasion is a good occasion to have a party.
Scott: How about we have a party about getting up or going to sleep?
Scott: Those are good reasons, but if you're gonna have any party, it doesn't matter what the reason.
Scott: don't spend moronic amounts of money on it.
Scott: Make it reasonable.
Rym: Hmm Though in terms of maximize fun going to weddings money spent I have noticed many things and that now I have having a wedding most recently on the mind that I actually find kind of interesting.
Rym: You can tell the Masters from the professionals.
Scott: That's for sure.
Rym: the a Master will drink a lot of alcohol in the course of the wedding.
Rym: The professionals are lined up.
Scott: everyone who's not a teetotaler like me will drink a lot of alcohol during any wedding.
Scott: If the bar is open.
Rym: they do not line up before the bar is open.
Rym: the alcoholics line up before the bar is open.
Rym: Let's see professionals appear out of nowhere.
Rym: The second the first drink is poured.
Rym: Yep ceremonies over there in line somehow.
Rym: Yeah, you don't know how they got there.
Rym: It's uncle Jim.
Rym: He's 400 pounds.
Rym: How did he beat you there?
Rym: The middle-aged people the fathers and the mothers and the younger grandfathers and the uncles will be Surprisingly all touchy-feely with the spouses of all their friends male and female.
Rym: I've noticed that every wedding I've been to hmm, which is Only horrifying until you get old and then it's kind of awesome The ceremony will have some amount of derpitude in it.
Rym: Yeah, there is no way to not have some amount of derpitude because it's really hard to treat anything seriously Anything especially.
Scott: it doesn't matter what culture you are or anything You know, I guess maybe the incredibly seriously religious can keep it serious.
Scott: the whole time though
Rym: I was very proud of our friend Nury because there were readings during the wedding we just went to and she read a speech from Babylon 5 and rather than changing the names of all the Languages and races to be real ones just to make the speech kind of normal It was a reading about the Minbari and such and the fact that she did it super cereal was kind of amazing.
Rym: I almost cracked up and I was standing up there just trying not to laugh.
Scott: Yeah, I was just looking at a Rym the whole time.
Scott: He was making his don't laugh face.
Scott: I was like don't laugh where he makes his mouth completely fat But you get flat but you can see the corners going up and sometimes you can see the corners going down really firmly.
Scott: Yeah as he wins as he starts to win against his fight You'll see my cheekbone stick out as my.
Rym: I clench my whole jaw followed by Our friend Pete - Every wedding he's officiated has been way nerdy.
Scott: He's making use of his church universe.
Scott: Oh, by the way, when you need someone to officiate your wedding, right if you're not religious and you don't you know Want the wedding to be about God instead of being you might know a captain a captain's.
Scott: a good idea.
Scott: But basically, you know, even if you are religious, right if you go and get your wedding officiated by a religious person what ends up happening most of the time is How well do you know that person?
Scott: maybe you know You're really churchy and you're really good friends of the minister and they know you and you see him every week And you actually talk to him.
Rym: then yeah, go for it.
Scott: But a lot of times people go and they get married by like, you know The priest or whatever and you barely know this guy.
Scott: you just go to that church once or twice a year for the important times You're supposed to go or the rabbi, you know, you go to the Jewish temple on the High Holidays.
Scott: You don't really know the guy so the wedding ends up being you know, the official yating tends to be generic More about God than about you, even if you believe in God You.
Scott: so I would suggest even if you do believe in God to try to get people You know to do it and not some person doesn't know you people about you.
Rym: He did a really good job at this one.
Rym: He's done all their weddings too in our crew.
Scott: All right, the point I was really trying to make is Pete does it because he got the thing from the universal life Church.
Scott: I also got it which you can get if you just you know.
Scott: If you need someone to officiate pick the person and if they can't do it Send them to the universal life Church where they can get this thing.
Scott: that lets them do it.
Rym: nice aside I I joined the universalized life Church a long time ago and whenever I get hotel rooms or reservations for anything I put Reverend as my title.
Rym: Yeah one time this saved my bacon.
Rym: Yeah, we were at between PAX East the first PAX East and anime Boston.
Rym: They were like opposite weekends, so we just stayed in Boston the whole week and did a whole bunch of awesome shit.
Scott: That was good times.
Rym: I accidentally had one of the hotel reservations a day too long in.
Rym: for all of our travels I would have been out like 200 bucks.
Rym: So I called him up and I'm like, hey, can I just cut this short?
Rym: I know I'm past the deadline And at first I like no no, no, no, no, but then she the lady on the other end pauses and say oh Reverend give me a moment and then the manager comes on lines like Reverend to cost her.
Rym: We've made all the arrangements or anything else I can do for you.
Rym: Yeah, so Yeah, being a reverend is kind of awesome.
Rym: Yep, and it's oh, by the way I hereby forgive all the sins of every everyone who hears this right now.
Rym: if you're in the universal life Church I don't know even if you're not the power to do that.
Rym: There you go.
Scott: But what if they denied the Holy Spirit?
Scott: They can't be forgiven.
Scott: You know what?
Rym: That's fine.
Rym: There's no at least if they're Christians.
Rym: There's no Holy Spirit And if you believe and if you suddenly believe there is one for you.
Rym: Yeah, there is just for you.
Rym: I hereby make them all sure Cannon.
Rym: Yeah, I'm a priest.
Scott: Okay, and you're married.
Rym: No Yeah, you're all married to each other.
Rym: That's right.
Rym: Good luck sorting that one out.
Scott: everybody one big blob.
Scott: It's it's marriage instrumentality.
Rym: Yep wedding cakes.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I'm a fan of the traditional wedding cake actually flavor wise Like that white wedding cake I really like.
Rym: But every wedding I've ever been to had shit-ass ice cream.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: They don't use expensive ice cream.
Rym: They use the cheapest possible.
Scott: I mean ice cream is real expensive to get good stuff in bulk.
Rym: Also forget that this reminded me of the things that piss me off one.
Rym: I Know there's that stupid tradition where like the bride or groom shove the cake in each other's faces.
Rym: It's stupid.
Rym: Don't do it.
Scott: Okay, do.
Rym: if you ever Take a fork and bang it against the glass because you think that's cool I hope you take the fork in your eye.
Rym: I just I hope you die.
Scott: Yeah, that needs you not clink the glasses.
Scott: you can however If you are drunk run your finger around the top of the glass that saying that is awesome That's okay but no clicking with your silverware to get them to kiss if I'm ever getting married somehow and There's clinking going on.
Rym: I'm ignoring it.
Rym: I'm just sitting there.
Scott: No, you should kick whoever clinks out.
Rym: No, I'll just wait.
Rym: I'll stare them all down Fluttershy style give him the finger.
Rym: however One person and only one person in all of history gets forgiven for clinking for Scott Johnson who was getting married was dancing with his mom Which is both an inside joke and literally what was going on and someone starts clinking.
Scott: That was an appropriate joke.
Rym: that was.
Rym: that was fantastic.
Rym: That was kind of like how when the cake came out they play the portal song and you know It's lame.
Rym: to make a cake is a lie joke.
Rym: unless there is literally a cake and some sort of like truth about it That can be revealed.
Scott: Yep What are the things?
Scott: there's a lot, you know, there's a lot of small things out there.
Scott: actually I'm a big fan of the.
Scott: You know, I said I don't like traditions, but I actually like the throwing and catching parts Because it is like a sport and I think weddings need more sport like activities.
Scott: I know that like a kids bar mitzvahs usually and you know, I guess also what are the the confirmation parties and things?
Scott: They'll do things like play games such as Coke and Pepsi and whatever which are kind of dumb games But at least they're like structured sport like activities.
Scott: I think more weddings need like, you know, like I said the bouncy castle maybe some kickball dodgeball Gladiator jousting X. Yep, those things they do the sumo suits.
Scott: I'm a big fan of all those things Especially because remember it's a wedding party activities.
Rym: It's a wedding.
Rym: It's gonna be you and all your friends and All of your middle-aged drunk uncles.
Scott: Well, that's another thing I'm not in favor.
Scott: usually these parties even if they're not weddings you are charged based on the number of people.
Scott: I am NOT in favor of inviting people you do not know Right, it's like people they'll invite like a distant cousin like your mom's second cousin someone you maybe saw once or twice in your life.
Scott: Right, you know, they exist.
Scott: Maybe I use.
Rym: those people are not invited by the people who are getting married.
Rym: They're invited by the family members.
Scott: Yeah, a lot of people, right?
Scott: I know like your parents will pay for the wedding and stuff like that because they're so traditional Right.
Scott: It's like don't don't let them do that shit.
Scott: take control of your own shit.
Scott: Do it the way you want to do it invite who you want to invite.
Scott: now Some people will be like, oh they're play this game where it's like, well, the person's gonna give a gift.
Scott: So if it costs less to invite them than the gift they give It's a good deal.
Scott: Listen, it's not about getting, you know profiting.
Scott: if you want a profit You could have taken all the money you spent on this party and invested it in a business or something, right?
Scott: You're not looking to profit.
Scott: you're looking to have an awesome party.
Scott: don't invite schmucks.
Scott: You don't know They're not gonna help your party be any better.
Scott: I only invite people you know and actually care about to your thing.
Scott: and even if that's not a lot of people who cares That'd be more fun without those other people there.
Scott: They're just gonna you know, and plus those people you don't know We're always a risk.
Scott: It's all.
Scott: there's always someone who's maybe you know is taboo or Makes trouble or something and it's that distant guy that you know, it's like the drunken second third uncle grandpa's Third brother, I have a feeling that the majority of drama at weddings comes from the closer relations.
Scott: Yeah, but you can't not invite the closer relation to the party.
Rym: That's like Yeah, well one of our friends weddings They did the traditional Chinese like challenges for the groom like he had to beat all the bridesmaids at something or we couldn't get married.
Scott: Yeah, that's fun.
Scott: Yeah, anything that is fun regardless, you know.
Scott: when I said, you know, I don't like tradition It's not you know You're only doing something because it's tradition.
Scott: that's the problem like the chair if something also Good, if something is good and in tradition will do it because it's good not because it's you know tradition though I have a very important admission to make.
Rym: poop came out of my mouth.
Rym: I should talked.
Rym: I broke a vow All right, you might remember some time ago on GeekNights.
Rym: I went to a wedding.
Rym: It was a fine wedding.
Rym: I was in the I was one of the groomsmen But I had to rent a tuxedo and just due to the logistics of renting that tuxedo It was an unholy nightmare that consumed like eight total hours of my life.
Rym: Yep, so I vowed I would never wear a tuxedo again unless I owned it.
Rym: Mm-hmm I ended up renting a tuxedo for this wedding.
Scott: Yeah, that's another bullshit, right?
Scott: It's like people have these weddings and they want all the like the people in the wedding party to wear like the same Clothes and they'll force you to go and rent a tuxedo or something, but they'll make you fucking pay for it.
Rym: I got around that I deducted the cost of the tuxedo from my gift nice.
Rym: I had a gift I'd planned.
Rym: I saw the cost of the tuxedo and I deducted it.
Scott: Good job I even told him as much I was like minus cost of tuxedo nice, but it's like, you know, I If you can't make someone else pay for your party, right a party is either Everyone pays collectively or one person pays.
Rym: if I bring you know What.
Rym: if you had a game where people the losers had to pay for the at least it's a fair some fair structure, right?
Scott: It's if I'm having a New Year's party I can't be like, alright, listen you ten people who are close to me You're all gonna pay for part of this but all these other people are gonna get in the party for free.
Scott: Well, do I get any benefits for paying for extra in this party?
Scott: No, in fact you get a penalty.
Scott: you have to wear these horribly fitting ugly clothes.
Rym: Ah The closest thing to a benefit was like we got drink service while we were doing all the pictures independent of the professionals in line.
Scott: a Few minutes of extra drink service when there's unlimited drinks now.
Rym: great now there's unlimited drinks to a time.
Scott: Would you have paid the cost of the tuxedo for that drink service now?
Scott: No, yeah, so you got ripped off.
Scott: You can't make someone else pay for your shit.
Rym: if you want people to do something for your party I point out that they'll all do it anyway.
Scott: That's only because they feel obligated.
Scott: I would be like, you know, if you ask me I'd be like fuck you Which is why I was gonna which is why nobody asked me.
Rym: I was gonna to get around that.
Scott: It's the same as in the the.
Scott: you know, it's I attack only one.
Scott: Nobody will fuck gang up on me.
Rym: because they know I was going to consider getting the fancy utila kilt the dress one and wearing that Under the red the top of the tux.
Rym: that would have been cool.
Rym: then I would have kind of gotten around my shit talk.
Scott: I had to match the tux.
Rym: It would have matched pretty well.
Rym: I like.
Rym: I kind of specked it out, but I The utila kilt nice like.
Rym: they're already a little overpriced, but I like they're.
Rym: they're good for what they ours.
Rym: That's why I own a couple.
Rym: but the fancy utila kilt is not worth the 800 whatever dollars.
Scott: I didn't know.
Scott: I thought the fancy utility.
Scott: It was actually cheaper.
Rym: No, it's pretty expensive.
Rym: That sucks $750 fuck that for basically a Skirt and it's even less utila kilty than the real utila kill.
Scott: Yeah, we talked about you know money spent on clothing versus the number of times and how often you're gonna use it.
Rym: I spent three by two more of the fanciest kilt they've got rather than the tuxedo Money left.
Scott: I spent 300 plus on a kilt that I use often.
Scott: the tuxedo one cost twice that and I would use it Far far far less often.
Scott: so it is a bad idea.
Scott: Yep Anyway, but yeah parties are awesome.
Scott: Just make them reasonable and don't blow your whole money because of a tradition.
Scott: use it on something reasonable instead Like, you know a vacation something worthwhile.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.