Rym: It's Wednesday, December 7th, 2011.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: And I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight we talk about a bunch of anime.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Tonight we have three mini reviews.
Rym: Drops of God, Welcome to the Space Show, and Children who chase lost voices from deep below.
Rym: I'm thinking about not paying for Xbox Live Gold anymore.
Scott: Really?
Rym: Because I realize they don't use it for anything.
Rym: Except, I guess, leaderboards and the Netflix thing.
Rym: And they basically fucked the Netflix thing.
Scott: I haven't checked out the Netflix thing.
Rym: I haven't actually checked out the new one, but all the people noted the exact changes they made.
Rym: Seems like they just made it worse with no benefit whatsoever.
Rym: And I already have a computer hooked up to my TV running Boxxy.
Scott: Well, I've got it for a while, you know, without having to pay again.
Rym: I still have it for a while, but I see no reason to renew it.
Scott: Well, you know, it's like, you say that, and then eventually you get a game that has multiplayer, like Street Fighter or something, and you're like, "Oh,
Scott: fuck.".
Rym: Playing Street Fighter online with strangers was never fun.
Rym: It's really only fun to play it in person.
Scott: I played it online with non-strangers.
Rym: Do you still do that?
Scott: No.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Scott: But you never know.
Rym: When was the last time you used Xbox Live Gold for anything?
Scott: I Netflixed something.
Scott: Netflix?
Rym: Don't you have a computer?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Is it running Windows?
Scott: Huh.
Scott: I use whichever one is already switched, so I need to reduce switching.
Rym: I do have this trouble that...
Scott: If the computer's currently switched, I'll use that.
Scott: If the Xbox is currently switched, I'll use that.
Rym: You do still need the computer, the actual normal computer with a real web browser hooked up to the TV, because so many online services are going further and further into preventing things like Boxxy from actually showing their content.
Rym: Or like Hulu, there's a Boxxy app, but if you watch Hulu through the Boxxy app, the commercials are a billion decibels and cannot be muted or made quieter.
Rym: Doesn't that happen on regular Hulu?
Rym: No.
Scott: What do you mean?
Scott: they can't be muted?
Rym: So the volume control on the remote is disabled in Boxxy.
Scott: Why don't you push mute on your TV?
Rym: Because that's a different remote.
Scott: Oh, no.
Rym: That remote is basically like a vestigial feature of my television at this point.
Scott: I have a separate remote just for controlling my little speaker system, and the mute button is perhaps the second most used button after the power button.
Rym: But think about this.
Rym: So if you go to the website and just hit play, it just works fine, and you can do whatever you want.
Rym: But if you use Boxxy, they actively remove a feature of Boxxy in the misguided attempt to get you to pay attention to the shitty commercial?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: The moral is hook up a computer to your TV, because no device that isn't a computer.
Scott: We said that about a billion times.
Rym: Yeah, but it bears repeating.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Plus, we say it usually on Monday, and this is Wednesday.
Rym: Wednesday is when the people listening to Wednesday GeekNights are the ones who tend to watch a lot of stuff on their TV via a computer.
Scott: Get a real, dedicated, real computer connected to your television in your living room.
Scott: If you want to play games, get a real Windows computer.
Scott: If you don't care about playing games on it at all, then you can get a Mac Mini if you want.
Rym: Yeah, you can.
Scott: But a Windows computer is better.
Rym: Except for the hardware, by and large.
Scott: Yeah, but whatever.
Scott: It'll be bigger and less quiet.
Rym: So, I guess your news is the only real news, so I'm going to start with the Geek Byte.
Rym: We'll do something happy before we do something sad.
Rym: Wolverine and the X-Men.
Scott: Wolverine, oh shit.
Rym: Oh shit, it's Wolverine.
Rym: Scott hasn't seen Wolverine and the X-Men.
Rym: I've watched it three times because it's actually- The whole show?
Rym: Yes, it's actually- How many episodes is it?
Rym: It's actually pretty fucking good.
Scott: You've watched 26 episodes three times.
Rym: I've also watched Madoka three times.
Rym: It's 13 episodes.
Rym: I've seen Utena, I don't know, five times?
Scott: What?
Scott: I haven't seen Utena one time.
Rym: I've seen Utena, really?
Rym: Only once?
Scott: Well, and change.
Rym: And change.
Rym: You've got to watch it all the way through again.
Scott: Eventually.
Scott: Ava, five.
Rym: Escaflowne, only three.
Scott: Yeah, okay.
Rym: Bebop, three.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But Wolverine and the X-Men is actually pretty great.
Rym: And the sad story of it is that it was made.
Rym: Steve Blum, aka the voice of Spike Spiegel, is the voice of Wolverine.
Rym: And it's fun reversal in that the plot is basically that the X-Men all split up and separate and quit.
Rym: So Wolverine, you know, the lone badass, tough and cool, is the one who has to go and gather everyone back together and be the leader, but he doesn't want to be the leader.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: It's pretty good.
Rym: Also, Emma Frost is kind of awesome.
Scott: Not really a fan.
Scott: Really?
Scott: No.
Rym: So do you know anything about Wolverine and the X-Men?
Rym: Like where it's at, what it's about?
Scott: I know who Emma Frost is.
Scott: I know who Wolverine is.
Scott: I know who the X-Men are.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: There you go.
Rym: Wow.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Maybe I should get the other Scott on to review this because he was the one who showed it to me.
Rym: We watched it twice at the show.
Scott: You watched 52 episodes in one go?
Rym: Yeah, actually.
Scott: What the fuck is wrong with you?
Rym: Because we got kind of drunk toward the end.
Rym: Didn't remember a lot of it.
Scott: How much time is that?
Scott: You could have been on the beach.
Rym: Yeah, you know what?
Rym: It was on while we were playing games.
Scott: I'm going to calculate this.
Scott: 52 times .5 is 26 friggin' hours.
Rym: It was only three minute episodes for one.
Scott: 26 hours you spent over a day of your life.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: We were doing other stuff simultaneously.
Scott: How many days were you there?
Rym: The greatest.
Rym: It was like the week and a half, you know, the big trip.
Scott: How many days were you there?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Six, seven?
Scott: If you were there for seven days, that means you watched three, four, five, six.
Scott: You watched like eight episodes a day on average.
Rym: I think we actually skipped the first like ten, the second run through because it wasn't until ten or so in that everyone was too drunk to remember what was happening.
Scott: Okay, that's a little bit better, but still.
Rym: But anyway, Wolverine the X-Men is pretty fucking good.
Rym: And you know why I know it's good?
Rym: Because it completely failed financially.
Rym: It didn't make any money at all and the second season was cancelled.
Rym: Like happens, Hasbro bought the rights to the toys.
Scott: So by that logic, ponies is awful.
Rym: So ponies, while it got a second season and everything, the merchandising isn't even being attempted at this point.
Rym: Meanwhile, this show, they tried to merchandise it and then they gave up.
Rym: But I don't know what else I can say.
Rym: If you're even close to a fan of anything even vaguely related to the X-Men, this is probably the best moving visual representation of the X-Men there's ever been made.
Rym: I don't like the live action movies that much.
Rym: The original cartoon is only great if you never watch it again.
Scott: Wait, what do you mean original cartoon?
Rym: Well, when I say original, I mean the first one I ever saw, the 90s X-Men.
Scott: Yeah, there is an X-Men older than that.
Scott: You know what?
Rym: That's in the same category as most of M. Night Shyamalan's movies.
Scott: There's also Spider-Man and His Amazing Friends, which has- That's on Netflix now.
Rym: I almost clicked on that.
Scott: It has some episodes with the X-Men, but Iceman is one of Spider-Man's amazing friends.
Scott: He's in almost pretty much every episode.
Rym: Iceman is also in Wolverine and the X-Men.
Scott: So one third of that is an X-Men cartoon.
Scott: The thing is Wolverine and the X-Men- Greater than a third because there are episodes with all the X-Men in it.
Rym: It is animated pretty well.
Rym: The voice acting is good.
Rym: It doesn't sound like a crappy- like it's actually good voice actors.
Rym: I mean Stephen Blum and all these people.
Rym: It's a good story.
Rym: and of course it's Phoenix Saga because Phoenix Saga seems to be the only thing anyone ever does when they do the X-Men.
Scott: Because every other X-Men story is a convoluted mess that no one can understand unless they've read every X-Men comic ever.
Rym: But they did a good job of taking the kind of plot points from the actual X-Men comic and re-representing them in a way that doesn't make them seem nearly as stupid as they actually were.
Rym: Like Master Mold is this AI controller for the Sentinels.
Rym: Master Mold is not just a sentinel so big that sentinels come out of its stomach.
Scott: No, but that's so much more awesome!
Scott: See, that disappoints me.
Rym: The only reason to really watch this is because the MRD guys have this heads up display in their helmets.
Rym: And it's like, "Human.
Rym: Mutant."
Rym: And we decided about halfway through that they should have a third option.
Rym: Oh shit, it's Wolverine.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Scott's blasé about everything.
Rym: All of you should watch this and I'll review it on the show with the other better Scott who actually has taste.
Scott: All you lowbrow people.
Rym: This is a good show.
Rym: I don't know why you're so resistant to it.
Scott: Lowbrow.
Rym: Scott, you showed me a picture you linked to Madoka Magica and you were like, "Let's watch this
Rym: show.".
Rym: And I was like, "Fuck
Rym: you!".
Scott: Would you say that the show now, having seen it, is low or highbrow?
Rym: What?
Scott: What is the elevation of Madoka's brow?
Rym: Oh, it's a very highbrow.
Scott: There you go.
Rym: But I'm saying that if you judge that cover...
Scott: What would you say is the elevation of Wolverine's brow, having seen it?
Rym: It's an upper middle brow.
Scott: You don't think it's an upper middle brow?
Rym: It's a middle brow.
Rym: It's a middle brow?
Rym: Yeah, it's a middle brow.
Scott: Middle brow, huh?
Rym: It's okay.
Scott: You think so?
Rym: Scott, it is better than the average B anime.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: It's better than initial D. I'm gonna say that right now.
Scott: It's better than initial D. What's not better than initial D?
Scott: The initial D's brow is in the dirt.
Scott: The initial D's brow is in the Marianas Trench.
Rym: It's like the difference between chocolate and shit.
Scott: Initial D's brow is like in China because it's just...
Rym: Anyway, kids, Scott's a hater.
Rym: Watch Wolverine and the X-Men.
Rym: It's on Netflix.
Rym: It's pretty great.
Rym: You'll enjoy it.
Scott: So in anime news, right?
Scott: I don't know if people know this, but we saw Satoshi Kon once when he was alive, and he had one picture on display of the movie that he was making at the time, which is called The Dream Machine, and it featured a robot or some robot people.
Scott: And I was like, "Aw, shit.
Scott: Can't wait for
Scott: that.".
Scott: And then a couple of years later, like last year, right?
Scott: He died, and the movie was not done.
Scott: And he said, "Hey, I did as much work as I could on this movie.
Scott: Finish
Scott: it.".
Scott: And then whatever.
Scott: And so Madhouse started to try to finish it, and they put a guy in charge of it, and he was working on it.
Scott: And then he sort of stopped working on it.
Scott: And now the website is down.
Scott: So it's like,
Scott: "No.".
Rym: Now, the saddest thing is Scott links me, his news, and I'm just going through it, preparing for the show.
Scott: Not reading.
Rym: I didn't read it.
Rym: I'm just clicking on the links, and I see, "Oh, Dream
Rym: Machine.".
Rym: And I'm looking at the screenshot, and I say something to the effect of, "Man, once this movie comes out, I don't know what I'll do, because that's it.
Rym: There's no
Rym: more.".
Rym: And then I see the headline, and I'm like, "Oh, oh,
Rym: oh.".
Scott: So the thing is, us anime people on the Twitter, we're basically like,
Scott: "Hey.".
Scott: Basically the reason they're not going through with it is because his movies were expensive to make, because they were pretty much prestige-type things, and they didn't make a lot of money.
Scott: And they can't really afford to make it.
Scott: And if he's not there to push it, it's not going to happen.
Scott: Guys, kickstart that shit.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: It's like, we're all like, "Hey, don't Japanese people...".
Rym: I would donate a lot of money to make that, just so I can see the movie.
Scott: Don't Japanese people know about Kickstarter?
Scott: It's like, this would be the perfect example of someone to actually try to use Kickstarter for something big, right?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: most people try to use Kickstarter for something relatively small, and they only ask for some thousands.
Scott: They should try to kickstart this and ask for, what do they need, a million, two millions?
Scott: Ask for the millions on Kickstarter, give out amazing prizes, like top prize, $1,000 will give you a fistful of, I guess they don't have cells, but you know what I'm saying?
Scott: Just amazing shit.
Scott: You know, give out the big prizes that are big, but don't actually cost them anything.
Rym: I guess one question is, the only factor that you really don't know is how much work is actually done on it already.
Scott: People say a third, and someone else was like, "Hey, well, if you've already done a third of the work and you're not going to finish it, just put the third of the work you've done on YouTube in its raw form, you don't give a
Scott: shit.".
Rym: Or just edit it onto a DVD and sell it for like 10 bucks as a final, you know, whatever.
Scott: Yeah, or give that as like one of the Kickstarter, just do something.
Scott: It's like, you know, these people aren't trying, you know, they're just not trying to try, you know, they just don't put any effort into it, they don't give a shit.
Scott: It's like they just give up and that's it.
Scott: It's like, come on, there are like 10 billion things you can try to do, at least try, however long does it take to go to Kickstarter and click a few times and type in some things.
Rym: There might be some legal issues involved.
Scott: It doesn't matter, you can work it out, it won't take that much, you know, effort.
Scott: You've already, you know, I mean, it's on cost fallacy, you should just sort of give up, but, you know, don't put the good dollars after the bad.
Rym: But don't give up if I care about it.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Also, uh, it would just, you know, it's it.
Rym: What?
Rym: No, that's it?
Rym: That's it.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So speaking of X-Men, I found this video on Dorkly, X-Men Sentinels can't do anything right.
Rym: Now the Sentinels in the new Wolverine and the X-Men, which isn't that new, are, you know, they're pretty scary and they're pretty competent.
Rym: The Sentinels in the original 90s cartoon were pretty crap, but I didn't realize until I watched this compilation how amazingly shockwave-esque they are.
Scott: They're about the same as stormtroopers.
Scott: They can't hit anything.
Rym: A stormtrooper never cut its own head off by running full steam into an overhanging I-beam.
Scott: They have hit their head on the top of, uh... That they have.
Scott: Well, technically that was not, that was a person in a stormtrooper costume, it was not a trained stormtrooper.
Rym: I think my favorite one of these is when there's like ten of them and they're standing around looking at a card on the ground.
Rym: They're like, this object appears to be an ace of spades and then Gambit's card explodes.
Scott: I like how his card, the amount of explosion in his cards varies wildly and what triggers them exploding.
Scott: It's like they could be a time bomb or most of the time when they hit something, they blow up as long as it's not Gambit that they hit.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I like how he also has the power of survive being knocked like across the room into a brick wall by a giant robot.
Scott: But the sentinel can't even survive hitting its head on a piece of metal.
Rym: I also, you know, Wolverine is a badass.
Rym: And they always show...
Scott: These things are like made of the same shit that like friggin' you know, Ghost and Goblin's guy's armor is made of.
Scott: It's just like, doink, up, they just fall to pieces.
Rym: But I knowed something, it's always bothered me, Wolverine, right?
Rym: Even the original cartoon and the new one in the comics, it's always like you see him jump up and then a sentinel's head falls down with him like riding it.
Scott: Right.
Rym: How the fuck does he pull that off?
Scott: He takes his claw and he goes around the neck.
Rym: But his claw doesn't get that far into it.
Rym: It's a really big neck.
Scott: He goes around the neck.
Scott: He gets all, you know, ding ding ding ding.
Rym: Scott, that would be like me ringing a tree.
Rym: It doesn't cut the tree down.
Rym: I didn't get all the way to the core of the tree.
Scott: You don't have to because now there's just this little tiny bit in the middle.
Rym: I think there's a bunch of cables and stuff there.
Rym: And somehow Wolverine has torn all of them.
Scott: Well, first of all, Wolverine, you know, he doesn't have Superman's strength, but he's pretty strong.
Scott: He's not as strong as Spider-Man even, but he's still way stronger than normal people.
Rym: Plus, Scott, depending on what, you know, what second of animation you're watching, the sentinels in the 90s X-Men are either eight feet tall or 80 feet tall.
Scott: Well, I always thought it was weird that in the X-Men arcade game they were kind of small and there was only one boss that was actual sentinel size.
Scott: But in fact, all the sentinels are supposed to be the size of that boss.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: Anyway, this video is actually pretty funny.
Scott: So, here is some awesome fan arts that are pretty cool.
Scott: Some, one of them combines Star Wars and Totoro and is the awesomest.
Scott: Some of them are like Cowboy Bebop.
Rym: I like the Kiki one the most.
Scott: Some of them are.
Scott: That's a good one.
Scott: I like the Castle in the Sky one the most, actually, because, you know, it's whatever.
Scott: But the robot.
Rym: You know, they have that robot at the Ghibli Museum.
Scott: I know.
Rym: It's pretty good.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: He's just hanging out on the roof.
Scott: He doesn't move around, though.
Rym: No, he's just hanging out.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: No, you got to get the one that moves around.
Rym: From where?
Rym: Where am I going to get the one that moves around?
Scott: Lupin's got it.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Cool fan arts here.
Scott: They're cool enough, and there are enough of them, that they are worthy of Thing of the Day.
Rym: So, in the meta moment, the book club books are...
Scott: The Little Prince by Antoine de Saint-Ejupéry, and also Wind, Sand, and Stars by Antoine de Saint-Ejupéry.
Scott: And read both of them.
Scott: One of them will take you almost no time at all.
Scott: Like a couple hours.
Rym: And the other one is also pretty good.
Scott: Unless you're a three-year-old.
Scott: If you're like in elementary school, you only have to read The Little Prince.
Scott: You don't have to read the other one.
Scott: If you are in high school or above...
Rym: If you're in elementary school and your parents are letting you listen to us...
Scott: If you are in high school or above, you must read both books.
Rym: Now, if you're in elementary school, your parents wouldn't even know what you were listening to because you're on the internet and they have no clue.
Scott: You must also read the Wikipedia page about Antoine de Saint-Ejupéry.
Rym: You might think, "Oh, he might be a cool guy.
Rym: He wrote about cool stuff.
Scott: He's way
Scott: cooler.".
Scott: The coolest dude to ever live.
Rym: Than you will ever imagine.
Scott: Cooler than Miles Davis.
Rym: Tomorrow, Thursday, December 8th, we will be at a nerd night in Brooklyn in Dumbo at a place called Galapagos doing one 20-minute lecture entitled "Losing Should Be Fun," which is the 20-minute version of the hour-long lecture we've run at, I believe, two Penny Arcade Expos and a bunch of other conventions.
Rym: If you want to go, I believe it costs $10, but there are two other lectures other than us, so you do have a reason to go, possibly.
Scott: Maybe it's worth paying for those other people.
Scott: I think it's sold out, though, isn't it?
Rym: I heard it was sold out, but I don't know.
Rym: Go to the website.
Rym: I'll link to it.
Scott: January 5, 6, 7, 8 is- Hot!
Scott: Hot!
Rym: Fucking go.
Rym: Oh, my God.
Scott: You suck.
Rym: We are doing "Beyond Dungeons and Dragons," the reboot, and we're also going to be on two intellectual gamer discussion panels.
Scott: And we're going to play some fucking games.
Scott: If you
Rym: want to play, like, "Burning Wheel" or "Mouseguard" or "Free Market" or German board games with me, Scott, and a bunch of the FRC, this is pretty much your best shot, because "Magfest" is one of the only cons that we go to primarily to hang out and play games.
Scott: The week after that, the 14th and 15th of January, I don't know if I'm going to be going, but there's another Nerd NYC double recess.
Rym: If I go, I'm going to run the same game for four people, "Burning Wheel," that I ran at "Burning Apocalypse Con," because- You could run that game.
Scott: Or come up with a game.
Rym: You could run that game.
Rym: I can give you my notes.
Scott: Maybe I'll come up with a game.
Rym: You should come up with a game.
Scott: I was thinking, here's my idea that I came up with for a game.
Rym: Oh, you got an idea?
Scott: It's just a seed of an idea.
Scott: The idea is, there's a really powerful bad guy, right?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And he's not dumb like in the movies.
Scott: He just fucking kills you.
Scott: And you got to somehow not die and beat the bad guy.
Scott: But he's not a dumb bad guy.
Scott: He'll just fucking kill you.
Scott: He won't even let you talk.
Scott: He won't tell you his story.
Scott: He's just a bad guy.
Scott: And he's going to do his bad thing, and he's awesome powerful.
Scott: So- You're also powerful as good guys, obviously.
Scott: So you're not just peasants, and you just get disintegrated in two seconds.
Rym: So it's going to be.
Rym: Rezo casts the spell immediately.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: That's the game.
Scott: It's the Rezo game.
Rym: I think that was the moment when I went from, "I like slayers," to, "I fucking love
Rym: slayers.".
Scott: Rezo's like, "Oh
Scott: shit!".
Scott: Just runs up the hallway,
Scott: "Oh!".
Rym: Locks the door, summons the- oh my god.
Scott: Well, the thing is, Rezo has nothing on- Copy.
Rym: Rezo.
Scott: Spoiler.
Scott: Ozymandias.
Scott: Rezo's like, "I'm doing it right
Scott: now.".
Scott: Ozymandias is like, "I did that shit before you came in the
Scott: room.".
Rym: Also, we'll be at PAX East.
Rym: We'll be at- we should be at Anime Boston, even though it's at the same time as PAX East.
Scott: And check us out on the internets and all the places on the internets besides iTunes or wherever you got this episode from.
Rym: The GeekNights Rym YouTube account has many of our previous lectures up, and a whole bunch of other stuff, like Radio Free Equestrian, video from PAX.
Rym: Make
Scott: sure to go to FrontRowCrew.com, which I hope to have finished updating it to be newer and better before the end of the year, because I'm gonna have a vacation, and that could be shit talk, and also go to Facebook, Google+, Twitter, whichever place you like the most, we will go to that place.
Scott: If you have any other places that you like the most, we'll go to those places too.
Scott: Just tell me where they are.
Rym: So, Drops of God.
Scott: Oh shit, son.
Rym: Drops of God is one of those kinds of manga that I'd be in like Hinokuni or something with Emily, and we'd be walking around, and I see all these manga that are not in English.
Scott: That are about crazy things.
Rym: It's like, wow, that's about golf, that's about politicians, that's clearly some Yakuza doing something awesome.
Scott: That's about wine.
Rym: So there's one that was- it looked like Initial D of Wine.
Scott: Right, so I never read it, but then Vertical, the best manga publisher in the United States in English, they decided to publish Drops of God, and it's like, wow, they could've published any of those, they could've published the golf one or the business one, but they chose this wine one, which means there must be something good about it.
Scott: And I don't drink wine, but I read this, and just like every other shounen manga in the universe, it makes you want to do whatever it's about.
Scott: Initial D makes you want to drive a car, Hajime no Ippo makes you want to punch people in the face and get punched in the face.
Rym: Oh my god, I remember when I was watching Initial D like second and third stage while I was living up in the mountains, and I actually had to drive down a mountain road every day to get to work.
Rym: It wasn't necessarily good for me to have been doing those two things at the same time.
Scott: Drops of God makes me want to drink wine, even though I'm probably not gonna.
Scott: You should, you gotta taste the terroir.
Scott: I think I'll be alright with my non-terroir.
Scott: I love how, like I- But I wish people would make apple juice with so much, you know, intensity as they make- The shounen fighting- The dirt that you plant the apple trees in, it's so important.
Rym: The shounen fighting genre has, you know, there's many different sub-genres within it, but the overall genre, the shows that I found I like, are the ones where there's someone who's good at something, but hates the thing they're good at, or doesn't care about the thing they're good at, but are forced to do it anyway, and come to love it.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But not right away.
Scott: It's pretty much the formula.
Scott: It's also the same formula as Initial D in that he got good at it because his dad made him do all this stuff that he didn't like doing.
Scott: I want you to lick this belt and chew on this pencil and- Yeah, somehow he can, you know, you can implant amazing skills in your children, even though they don't want these skills, and then they'll thank you for it later when they have great skills.
Rym: So Scott, when you have kids, you're gonna be like, "Alright kid, before you get dinner, you gotta beat Mario
Rym: 1.".
Rym: What, Mario 1?
Scott: That's pretty much it.
Scott: He's gonna beat Contra before breakfast.
Scott: He'll thank me for it when he's like, "Starcraft God of the world making mad monies for playing video
Scott: games.".
Rym: But this is such a... Like I read it, and I like it, but at the same time, it's pandering to me so much, and it's... And you know what?
Rym: You know what this goes all the way back to?
Scott: They pander.
Rym: All these things that we like, like Initial D and now Drops of God, Nodame, they all go back to C.S.
Rym: Forest or Horatio Hornblower, because you read a Horatio Hornblower book- Anytime Rym opens his mouth, it goes back to C.S.
Scott: Forest.
Rym: No, seriously, you read those books, right?
Rym: And by the end of one, like you're reading this action scene, you're like, "Aw shit son, I wanna go
Rym: sailing.".
Scott: You wanna get flogged?
Rym: I know, nah.
Scott: You wanna get keelhauled?
Rym: He doesn't get keelhauled.
Rym: You wanna get cannonballed?
Rym: Scott, you watch the Initial D race.
Scott: You feel like- You wanna marry like ten ladies with all sorts of BD?
Rym: I wanna do that, and I could do it.
Rym: I understand how that drift works.
Rym: I know what's going on.
Rym: You read the wine manga, and you're like, "Aw shit, I know all about the Toa, and all about all these- You don't know shit.
Rym: Guys, you read a C.S.
Rym: Forrester book, and you feel like you know exactly what the deal is with sailing.
Rym: You know like, "Oh, he furled the topsails or whatever, and it's
Rym: awesome.".
Scott: You don't know shit.
Rym: If you take anyone, have them read one of those scenes, and ask them how well they feel like they understood what happened, they'll be like 100%.
Rym: Show them a picture of a ship, and ask them to point out any of the things named in the book, and they will get none of them.
Rym: That's right.
Rym: That is the real key.
Rym: You have to get someone to feel like they understand this thing, even though they have no goddamn idea, and this is just crazy, over-the-top bullshit.
Rym: that's happening.
Scott: But in a way, it's the best marketing in the universe to get people interested in a thing.
Scott: It just doesn't work when there's so many people using the same method.
Scott: But I feel like there are many countries in the world where this method is not being used, and if we could perhaps ... You know, people here don't read manga, but if we could make TV shows with this formula about specific things, that we could get people really interested in things.
Scott: So, for example, we could ...
Rym: Read or die.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Maybe we want to sell wine, and we could make a TV show, an American one, of Drops of God, and suddenly, wine sales would go through the roof, because all these people watching that show would start buying crazy wine.
Rym: You know, actually, Drops of God would make a good HBO kind of show.
Scott: It would make a good just regular show.
Rym: Well, by HBO kind of show, I mean the shows that are made kind of to be sold, like to a premium channel.
Rym: Like, they're made as a unit, they're not an ongoing forever show, they have a plot that actually will end.
Scott: But anyway, here's a short plot summary of Drops of God.
Scott: You got this girl, and she's a sommelier in a small, kind of nice restaurant.
Rym: She's an apprentice sommelier.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: And you know, she's pretty good at sommeliering, but you know what, she's not ... She's a normal person, right?
Scott: She's not perfect, she's not amazing, she doesn't have superpowers, right?
Scott: And she's pretty cool.
Scott: I really like her a lot, because it's like, she's not like some of those anime characters that are intentionally extra, extra clumsy.
Scott: She's just normal clumsy.
Scott: It's like, yeah, if I was an apprentice sommelier, I'd probably drop one at some point.
Scott: You know, I'd mess up at some point.
Scott: But I wouldn't be messing up all over the place, you know?
Scott: She's pretty confident, and she's normal and not crazy or stupid or dramatic or anything.
Scott: And then, so she's having trouble with the customer, and this dude helps with his decanting.
Scott: And he has the amazing decanting of God, even though he doesn't drink wine.
Scott: Finds out that he is the son of this amazing wine critic, like the most famous wine critic that ever was.
Rym: Oh, but wait, with the decanting, one of the most important aspects of the shounen fighting manga is the two-page spread of the thing being done.
Rym: It doesn't matter what that thing is, that two-page spread is gonna be amazing.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: So, there's a two-page spread of his, you know, decanting.
Scott: So she finds out that he has these amazing wine skills, and he's the son of this guy, but he doesn't like wine or drink wine, and she actually resents his dad making him learn all that shit, just like Initial D. Then, his dad dies, the famous wine critic dad.
Scott: But before he died, he adopted this other guy, the rival, the evil, also wine critic guy, who was like the most skilled wine critic there is, besides the dad who died.
Scott: But the real son doesn't want that jerk to get the wine that his dad is letting him inherit.
Scott: So he's gotta beat him at this wine contest, and in the wine contest, you have to identify the twelve disciples and the drops of God, and then you will win the wine inheritance.
Rym: Now, you talk about your advertising.
Scott: So this guy doesn't like wine, he doesn't care about wine, but he has the innate skills from his dad, and he's gotta, you know, and he really, really suddenly doesn't want this other guy to get the wine collection.
Scott: So he actually learns to like wine, and tries to win.
Rym: I predict right now, I haven't read anything about the first, like, big trade, so this is just, it's not a spoiler if I guess it.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: I think they're actually brothers.
Scott: It could be.
Rym: Straight up, they're actually brothers.
Scott: That's not possible.
Scott: I wasn't even thinking of that.
Rym: I was thinking of- I thought of that, like, as soon, like, I don't know, 40 pages in, I was like, they're clearly actually brothers.
Scott: Maybe, but the actual, my guess is that the drops of God, like, all the twelve disciples are gonna be actual wines.
Scott: I think the drops of God is gonna be something like the grape juice, you know, that grows outside his house, or, you know, regular ass grape juice, or his mom's breast milk, or something, you know, something like that, something that's personal and isn't really the greatest wine in the whole world.
Rym: It's gonna be Monishevitz.
Scott: It's gonna be something, right, the drops of God is going to be something that has like a personal meaning for that, it's not, you know, it's not gonna be, what's the guy's name?
Scott: Henry Jaller?
Rym: Really?
Scott: Jaller?
Scott: What was the name?
Scott: I forget the name.
Scott: Henry something.
Scott: But it's not gonna be some amazing wine.
Scott: that's really the drop of God, it's gonna be something that's, you know, story related.
Rym: I wonder, actually.
Scott: That's what I'm guessing.
Scott: It's a guess.
Scott: I've read one volume.
Scott: What do you want from me?
Rym: Yeah, Wikipedia, apparently, they've gotten through eight of the apostles so far.
Scott: Oh, in the Japanese?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: That's good.
Scott: That means that it moved, how many volumes is that?
Rym: I have no idea, because I'm trying not to look.
Rym: Because it spoils a bunch of stuff.
Scott: Just on the right, in the little box, it should say the number of volumes.
Scott: Twenty-eight.
Scott: Oh, that's kind of eh.
Scott: That's a lot of volumes.
Rym: That is a lot of volumes.
Scott: Twenty-eight volumes is only eight disciples.
Rym: It's running me.
Rym: I wonder if only, I know this doesn't happen, if there were a crossover that linked that Ghost in the Shell episode with Aramaki and the wine.
Scott: There should be a crossover with One Piece and they drink rum.
Scott: Anyway, this manga is pretty awesome if you're willing to hold out for twenty-eight plus volumes to find out what the disciples are and the drops of God.
Rym: If anything, a manga like this is something where you read the first volume just to prove to yourself that the shounen fighting genre, the perfection of it, will work for anything.
Scott: Yeah, I'm actually kind of just satisfied reading the first volume.
Scott: You don't find out any disciples, but even if you don't plan to read the whole thing, you don't think you can hold out, you should just read volume one and you stop right there, which you won't be suffering on a horrible cliffhanger or anything like that.
Rym: It's like watching God, not God of Cookery.
Scott: It's a pretty big volume from Vertical that I think it might actually be two Japanese volumes in one US volume.
Rym: I think it is.
Rym: But like Cooking Master Boy, I don't need to watch all of Cooking Master Boy, but I watched the first couple episodes and I was good.
Scott: Oh man, I'm gonna get Chinese food for dinner.
Rym: Chinese food for dinner?
Rym: I was gonna reheat the Indian food from Burning Wheel last night.
Scott: Is this leftover?
Rym: There's a shit ton of it.
Scott: Oh, I thought there wasn't any.
Rym: No, there was like enough food to feed the entire gaming group again.
Scott: Oh, then I will stay here and eat some of that shit.
Rym: Alright, I'll reheat that shit as soon as we're done with the show.
Scott: Which kinds are left?
Rym: All of them except one of them.
Scott: The peppery one that I had?
Rym: I don't remember.
Rym: Anyway.
Rym: So, very briefly then, we'll do some kind of follow-up Geek Bytes because when it comes to an anime movie, I'm loathe to do a detailed review because you're just gonna go watch it.
Rym: I don't need to tell you much about it.
Rym: So all I really want to do is convince you to watch it.
Rym: Now some movies I could see as doing a final thoughts or kind of deep analysis.
Scott: It's possible that there could be an anime movie that is so bad that will say do not watch this under any circumstance, but that is so rare because like the worst anime movie that's gonna come out- Harmageddon?
Rym: Doom Megalopolis?
Rym: No.
Scott: That's gonna come out nowadays, right?
Scott: Is gonna be something like, you know, the one piece the movie number 55 or Pokemon the movie number 150.
Rym: Actually, I'll bet those are pretty watchable.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And those are probably pretty watchable.
Scott: So, and that's the worst anime movie that's gonna come out.
Scott: Then you should pretty much, and there's only like 10 or so a year at most, you should pretty much just watch every Japanese anime professional full length motion picture animated feature that comes out because they won't take you that long to watch them all.
Scott: You know, their longest ones are going to be two and a half hours and most of them are going to be 90 minutes or less.
Scott: And there are many of them.
Scott: You can watch them all if you're an anime nerd.
Rym: Finally you're like, yeah, most of them are going to be 90 minutes or less.
Rym: Both the movies we're talking about are two hours plus.
Scott: I'm saying, you know, even two hours, oh, big four hours.
Scott: That's less time than you spent watching Wolverine the X-Men and it was better than that.
Scott: But- Well, better than I assume that that is.
Rym: But I guess what I was saying is that I could see us doing some shows down the road.
Rym: Like I kind of want to rewatch Akira and or the original Ghost in the Shell just cause I haven't seen him in forever.
Scott: Uh, I've seen them like a thousand times.
Rym: But uh, we, you know, we could do like a kind of, you've already seen it final thoughts episode and really talk about the movie.
Rym: But uh, for here, welcome to the space show and I got to get the full title.
Rym: I usually make, I usually make a joke about the title to where I'd forgotten the real title.
Rym: Children who chase lost voices from deep below.
Scott: That's the English title.
Scott: I heard that that was a mistranslation of the Japanese title.
Rym: Literally it's children who chase stars.
Rym: Hoshi.
Rym: Oh, Koto.
Scott: Hoshi is star.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So start with welcome to the space show.
Rym: It's goofy adventure in space.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much really well animated.
Rym: It's a gigantic colors are really studying kind of like set pieces.
Rym: There's a lot of atmosphere stuff.
Rym: It's one of those really long.
Rym: Let's go on an adventure movies.
Rym: that's just really satisfying to watch.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, it doesn't have a whole lot of like, you know, deep substance.
Scott: You can see, you know, there's no surprise.
Scott: You can see the twist coming from the thousand light years away.
Rym: Literally there's a couple of twists.
Rym: The story of welcome to the space show roughly is that on earth there's people, right?
Rym: Some kids and they go to a camp just like in Bocorano, but in space there's a gigantic Futurama style space society, but they don't talk to people on earth because people on earth aren't good enough yet.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: And there's some plot where there's something on earth that is very desirable out there that people are smuggling out and some hijinks ensue and these pretty much space drugs grow on earth and you can't find them anywhere else in the universe.
Rym: So these kids end up saving.
Rym: one of the investigators is working on this and he's like, all right, I'll take you up to the moon as thanks and they'll send you back down to earth.
Rym: And then shit goes down and two hours later you've watched a pretty solid fulfilling movie about space.
Scott: It's like they get to the moon and, you know, you know, there's like.
Scott: then suddenly they're stuck there and then adventure happens.
Rym: It's kind of like there's a lot of like adventuresome slice of life.
Rym: I mean, they run out of money so they all start getting jobs as like delivery people and such to save up their space dollars to buy the ticket home.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like the actual plot of the movie is pretty much straightforward.
Scott: It does the typical thing of meet a bunch of characters who then only at the end, all the characters you met along the way come together at the last minute.
Rym: They're all pretty great characters like it's yeah, they're pretty cool.
Rym: It's very simple.
Scott: They're not deep characters.
Scott: They're just like.
Scott: they're more like, you know, just aspects like, oh, man, that guy's got, you know, does this really cool thing.
Scott: And that's what he does.
Rym: It reminds me a lot in terms of almost like Mega Man bosses as a lot of those kind of like the old space shows we like.
Rym: But you know, those often have meaning or something like cats.
Rym: Cats on a train.
Rym: And those were now, here's why it reminds me of cats on a train, because cats on a train, a.k.a.
Rym: Night on the Galactic Railroad, was long and atmospheric and you watch it and it's just kind of like this long adventure.
Rym: It lulls you in and kind of forget about the outside world for a couple of hours.
Rym: And then it kind of lets you back out at the end.
Rym: It also reminds me of that because a lot of people will not have enough goddamn patience to watch this movie.
Scott: Hmm.
Rym: A lot of people I know did not have enough goddamn patience to watch this movie.
Rym: And if you don't have the patience to watch this, then I actually think a lot of anime movies are not up your alley.
Scott: A lot of things, period, are not up your alley.
Rym: I mean, Skycrawlers, that's very long, very slow, very repetitive.
Scott: People, you got to have real attention spans to appreciate the arts.
Rym: But here's the other reason why the show is great.
Rym: Welcome.
Rym: There is a space show because as a backdrop to all this adventure these kids are having, there is a pirate television show in space called The Space Show.
Rym: It is the most popular media in the entire collected universe.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: It is illegal and broadcast from some mystery place.
Rym: And it is just crazy, crazy like it is basically condensed red line.
Rym: So, yeah, the space show and these kids and everything all collides into a gigantic, epic conclusion with extremely lush, beautiful, colorful animation.
Rym: Great kids, great colors, pionkichi.
Scott: The most basically the fun of it is not that big plot, right?
Scott: The fun is basically exploring this space society that they've come up
Rym: like seeing weird stuff like currency, the food, the nationality,
Scott: you know, like all these kids get jobs on the moon and you get to just throughout these two and a half hours, you just keep seeing little slices of different aspects of this gigantic space society to see how this, you know, how things work out there.
Scott: And it's just this cool world that you're being exposed to, just like the kids are being exposed to it after being taken from Earth and thrown into a galactic civilization.
Rym: There's a ton of great set pieces, like they ride this kind of biological spaceship at one point where all the doors inside that are basically sphincters.
Scott: Yeah, there's just a lot, you know, there's all kinds of crazy aliens.
Rym: I think my favorite part is when they all have to get space passports.
Scott: Oh, yeah, and the thing like questions.
Rym: Yeah, they all get interviewed.
Rym: They basically ask them questions like if a race of benevolent aliens came down to your planet and offered you all the technology in the universe to make your lives awesome, would you accept it?
Rym: If you answer correctly, you get a space passport.
Rym: If you answer incorrectly, I guess we lock you up forever.
Rym: Yeah, and it's fun.
Rym: I'm really trying to avoid saying much more about it because you just fucking watch it.
Scott: Yeah, it's only two and a half hours.
Rym: You can just pirate it.
Rym: It's just that it's just on the Internet.
Rym: You can just watch it.
Scott: Make sure you get the HDs, though, or else you'll be missing a lot.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Watch this on a big screen.
Scott: Well, it doesn't need to be big.
Scott: It needs to be HD.
Rym: Real screen.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So children who chase lost voices from deep below is the most recent Makoto Shinkai effort.
Rym: And we watched it at the New York Comic Con at it from here.
Rym: And then we got to see him and he talked a lot about it.
Rym: He seems like a really chill guy.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I liked his answers to all the questions.
Scott: I like it when the people are common sense guys and not crazy people or, you know, weird artsy partsy, you know, what's it called?
Rym: So funny hats.
Rym: If you know anything about beret wearing people, Makoto Shinkai, you could guess that this movie is about lovers separated by space and time.
Scott: Oh, no.
Rym: In this case, it's the story of lovers separated by death.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: He's just like, well, I've separated you by space and time.
Scott: Now I'm just going to separate your period.
Rym: But at the same time, this is a pretty straightforward Miyazaki-esque fantasy adventure story.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So pretty much is this girl and she likes to, you know, make a little radio, sort of like Carl Sagan's Contact.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And she goes up on the mountain near behind her house in the woods, you know, like adventuring in the woods a little bit.
Scott: And, you know, she listens to the thing and she keeps hearing this thing on a radio.
Rym: This music from somewhere.
Scott: From somewhere.
Rym: It's not a radio station like.
Rym: it's something she can't explain it and it makes her happy.
Rym: So she goes and listens to this all the time.
Scott: And then one day she sees this dude up on the mountain and is like, oh, what's up with that dude?
Scott: And then suddenly you've sort of got this situation where the dude is mystical and the government's after him and something, something you're not quite sure.
Scott: So she's in this situation and then she basically the dude gets owned by some monster and she gets to.
Rym: I believe he also may have owned the monster.
Scott: It was a double ownage, double K. So she sort of fell in love with the dude.
Scott: You know, this weird mystical, you know, plot dude from another world.
Scott: But now he's dead.
Rym: So she's sort of like, that's the best summary of a movie ever.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: All right.
Scott: And then she goes on the adventure into the other world because she thinks there's a chance to see him again.
Rym: It is really interesting watching this because it it cribs so heavily from Ghibli that I could see if someone didn't know who made this movie.
Scott: Well, you could tell by the way it looks that it's not.
Rym: But at the same time, it's so close, like the character designs are echoes of Ghibli stuff.
Rym: The whole world, the way that world that they travel to is portrayed and the kind of the the metaphysics of it and the mythology of it is very Ghibli.
Rym: It's a very straightforward movie with a very kind of almost heavy handed moral at the end.
Rym: But at the same time, the movie did surprise me more than once, like it did a few times.
Rym: I kind of got lulled into the sense of, all right, I see where this is going.
Rym: And then it didn't do a 180, but it went forty five degrees off course.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, you know, you go in and it's like, you know, there are many different aspects that are very Ghibli, like the animal guardians are very mononoke ish.
Scott: And the other world is very Laputa ish.
Rym: There's a lot of Nausicaa in the other world.
Scott: The girl is sort of like Nausicaa, you know, she's got her technologies.
Rym: And you can feel almost like Makoto Shinkai was like, I got to have some of this and some of this and some of this and some of this.
Scott: I want all these things.
Scott: They meet that like the doctor guy.
Rym: He's like, check it off all the things he wants in his fantasy world adventure.
Rym: Yeah, it's beautiful to behold.
Rym: the animation and the characters and the colors are just breathtaking and the story is pretty good.
Rym: It's not great.
Rym: It's not the best movie I've ever seen.
Rym: But you know what?
Rym: It's a solid movie.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And, you know, I was kind of expecting, like, you know, as it went along that, you know, like just amazing shit would happen, but it wasn't.
Scott: But at the same time, I was actually kind of thankful that it wasn't sort of all existential and weird.
Scott: Like it was.
Scott: it was it was very straightforward.
Scott: You know, it was like.
Scott: this is the thing that happens and it happened and you're good.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: The actual end of the plot didn't go the way I expected at all.
Scott: No, not at all.
Rym: Again, we're being cagey here because you should watch this movie.
Rym: I don't want to spoil it for you.
Rym: There's no reason to.
Rym: You should just see it.
Rym: Nothing I say should convince you to see it.
Rym: You should just go see it.
Rym: Otherwise, why are you listening to the anime manga comics?
Scott: I wasted more time listening to GeekNights that you could have spent watching this movie.
Scott: Seriously, what the fuck?
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows, SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.