Rym: It's Tuesday, August 9th, 2011.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, two games, Taluva and Reef Encounter.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Poking around on the Kotaku and I saw an article that was, I don't know, I feel like I have to say something about this.
Rym: Alright.
Rym: So the title was Dammit Zynga and it was by Kirk Hamilton and he's basically- I agree, I agree, for Facebook games.
Rym: but I've played Farmville a little bit which I take issue with that phrasing because you don't really play Farmville.
Scott: But the point is he checked it out for research purposes at least.
Rym: But the gist of this article is that there is The Sims Social Game, the Facebook game that's kind of like modeled on the Zynga stuff.
Scott: Right, but it's not actually made by Will Wright.
Rym: No, it's made by EA.
Scott: Yeah, he doesn't work at EA anymore so EA just took a brand they own and slapped it on a Farmville clone, right?
Rym: Yep, so here's this guy's complaint.
Rym: He wanted a Sims Facebook game that was awesome and he played this Sims Facebook game based on Zynga bullshit made by EA.
Rym: You know, Facebook game, social game, all the buzzwords for shitty-ass game design.
Rym: And he complained that it was shitty and spammy and looked exactly like a Zynga game.
Scott: Was he just stupid?
Rym: There's like 20 paragraphs here on what's annoying about the game.
Rym: Every time I try to do something it keeps popping up to share this with friends.
Scott: Because it's a Facebook game.
Scott: It's like just because it says Sims- It's not a Facebook game.
Rym: I would argue that games like Zynga and The Sims Social are almost viruses.
Scott: But the point is, it's like, why did he think that just because it was called The Sims it was going to be anything like The Sims?
Scott: Why do you even- Why not just play the real Sims?
Scott: If he likes it, I'm sure he already has it.
Rym: He does make an argument that one thing that could be said is that you could make, theoretically, a cool Sims Social game.
Scott: Imagine if you had- How would it be different from regular Sims?
Rym: Imagine if you had, say, Facebook, right?
Rym: It's got all your friends.
Rym: Say it made a Sim based on every one of your friends.
Rym: And then you could basically have a dollhouse of your friends like, "Oh, Scott keeps making out with Rainbow Dash.
Rym: Ha ha ha ha.
Rym: Oh look, Pete and my coworker keep fighting because they disagree on political
Rym: stuff.".
Rym: But I would argue that there was no possibility of that being made because one, it's EA.
Rym: Two, it's a social game.
Rym: Social meaning.
Rym: we're cloning Zynga's bullshit.
Scott: This is yet more of that never-ending discussion about people confusing the surface level parts of a game with, you know, it's like people can't look past it.
Scott: When I see a game, all that stuff that's on top, you know, Puerto Rico, if I look at Puerto Rico, all the boats and all that stuff just disappears.
Rym: No, here's what he said.
Rym: I'll sum up his article.
Rym: I bought a smelly, dodgy looking burrito from a hobo who I know was watching other hobos make poop burritos.
Rym: The burrito was surprisingly filled with poop.
Rym: And then I'm going to complain about how Chipotle has awesome burritos.
Rym: Why didn't he have a Chipotle?
Scott: He put a Chipotle sticker on it that he stole from a Chipotle.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: No, but it wouldn't even be that.
Rym: It would be as though someone...
Scott: No, he wrapped it in gold foil just like Chipotle.
Rym: It's not even gold foil.
Rym: I'm going to be blunt.
Rym: It's very rare that I will have unqualified opinions on things like this.
Rym: Zynga, not even Zynga, anyone who makes a social game where they say it is a social game is a bad person and the game they're making is a virus.
Scott: I should make a good game and just call it a social game.
Rym: But why?
Rym: That word is tainted.
Rym: It's gone.
Rym: We've lost it.
Rym: There's no way to get that word back.
Scott: Just be... No, not to get it back.
Scott: Who wants the word back?
Scott: Just to fuck with people, right?
Scott: Making games that's not an RPG, call it an RPG.
Scott: Just be like, "Yeah, your terms mean nothing to
Scott: me.".
Rym: One way around that is, what is Half Minute Hero?
Rym: On the surface, it's kind of a JRPG.
Scott: No, I think it's a... I think it's a light action puzzler.
Rym: I would agree, but you could argue that it is a...
Scott: Because the puzzles are extremely light.
Scott: They pretty much come down to follow, do what people say.
Rym: But it has all the trimmings of a JRPG.
Rym: In fact, you know what I was doing last night?
Rym: Emily had never really seen or played Final Fantasy.
Scott: One?
Rym: One.
Rym: In its original form.
Rym: So I got the emulators working because I needed to get a bunch of videos for our upcoming PAX panel.
Scott: Hello, Garland.
Scott: Ah, Garland.
Rym: I will knock you all down.
Scott: Talk to bat in corner.
Rym: So you know what's funny?
Rym: I started playing Final Fantasy 1 for like a minute.
Rym: I was like, "Yeah, here's what it looks
Rym: like.".
Rym: And I kind of kept playing.
Scott: Yeah, but you could only make it as far as the Elf Town before you're like, "Fuck this
Scott: shit.".
Rym: You know what?
Rym: You know what's really funny?
Rym: I was grinding and enjoying it, and I got to the Elf Town, and I saved my game, and then I went in to the store.
Rym: And I was like, "Oh, the silver
Rym: sword!".
Scott: Yeah, that's where...
Rym: Yeah, because suddenly my memory zoomed back of hours and hours and hours to buy one fucking silver sword.
Rym: Never mind going to that goddamn marsh cave.
Rym: And that was the end of that.
Rym: But you know what?
Rym: There's something to that formula.
Rym: Even to this day, I can get sucked in, and I had to like reach this moment of...
Scott: Just cheat.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You're in an emulator, use the Game Genie part of the emulator to give yourself a zillion levels and a zillion gold, and just buy the silver whatever.
Rym: But just to say that had I not been inoculated and remembered really what that was like, or had I not had this kind of meta knowledge of why grinding is stupid in the modern era, I might've just kept playing Final Fantasy 1.
Rym: It's a powerful pull if you're not ready for it.
Scott: No, it's one of those things where even if you know about it, it still works on you.
Scott: Even though you know it's a Skinner box, it doesn't somehow make you immune.
Rym: Yeah, I was about to stop.
Rym: And then I see BK, and I'm like, "Hey, Emily, you know who this
Rym: is?".
Rym: She's like a pirate.
Rym: I was like, "Not just any
Rym: pirate.".
Rym: It's BK.
Rym: And I got the pirate ship.
Rym: I'm like, "Aw shit, I can go get to the elf town
Rym: now.".
Rym: And I got really excited, kind of legit excited.
Scott: She's got funny dwarves.
Rym: Oh my god, I love the dwarves.
Rym: You realize you get the key from the elves that opens that door in Canaria Castle.
Rym: that gets you the TNT that you give to the dwarves.
Rym: Think about the kind of unstated story there.
Rym: The elves gave the humans this weapon of unimaginable magic power, and they locked it in their castle, but they kept the key for dire days in the future.
Rym: But yet, the item they gave them is not magical.
Rym: It is simply science that the humans are too dumb to understand.
Rym: And even then, they locked it away from the humans so they wouldn't use it until the time was right.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know.
Rym: I got nothing else there.
Scott: Actually, speaking of emulators, I read this interesting thing today.
Scott: They were talking about, it was on Ars Technica, it was about talking about emulator authenticity.
Scott: And actually it was like, we just use emulators, and for our eyeballs, they're actually pretty damn close to being the real deal.
Rym: Well, I've seen some emulators do things like you can turn on or off scanline flicker or like sprite flicker and all that.
Scott: But no, but this is like, there's actually things you don't even notice.
Scott: Like you don't even know.
Scott: And apparently, like Nesticle was way not good.
Scott: And Nestopia these days is pretty good, but there's this guy making something called BSNES.
Scott: I think I'm going to switch to it, but it's basically ultra accurate.
Scott: Like for example, you wouldn't realize this, but the spinning Triforce spins too fast in like SNES9X or SNES.
Scott: There's a video you can watch.
Scott: they have there that shows a time cop and it's way off in ZSNES.
Rym: So there is, I think, a space for both kinds of emulation because sometimes I want to play the game, but I'm okay with the emulator kind of not being accurate or more importantly, letting me like fast forward through the BS.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But or, you know, save stage because I don't want to actually be...
Scott: Well no, it's not, the emulator is not, you know, I don't think the BSNES, I'm not having used it yet, but I don't think it prevents you from doing those things.
Scott: It's just, you know, the audio, the video and the timing are all accurate.
Rym: I guess I say more conceptually, like an example would be you could have an emulator that emulates the sprite flicker exactly so that, you know, it does the same thing that the physical fucking NES does.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: You could even make an emulator that would emulate the common physical problems that would happen because those, you know, it's pretty well established what kinds of artifacting happen in different situations.
Rym: Like I think it would be worth emulating that from a historical standpoint, but simultaneously I don't mind playing say the old super dodgeball with no sprite flicker.
Scott: I think the point is, is that, you know, the point of the article was that to get the emulator to actually be so incredibly accurate, you need to have such, you know, ridiculous synchronized timing of all the different bits such that, you know, BSNES has insane system requirements, even though it's an SNES emulator.
Scott: Whereas there are Nintendo 64 emulators that don't give a shit about being accurate, that have almost, you know, poop system requirements like Pentium 2.
Scott: But, you know, to make an accurate N64 emulator would be ungodly, like the computer doesn't even exist.
Scott: And they even talked about how there's a Pong emulator, right, that emulates a Pong machine at the transistor level.
Scott: Whoa.
Scott: And is like, requires like these insane system requirements just to play original Pong.
Rym: These are important though.
Rym: We need, there's definitely, there's the, there's two distinct almost opposed paths of emulation that we definitely need both.
Rym: And I don't think there's enough attention being put to it.
Scott: But it calculates like, you know, the resistances in every transistor.
Rym: I really want to see an NES emulator that has options for physical defects.
Scott: Yeah, I'm sure everything you want exists.
Rym: Yeah, or will come.
Scott: But yeah, Nestopia is pretty much the shit.
Scott: But I'm going to try, I've been using SNES 9x.
Scott: I'm going to try to use BSNES.
Rym: Oh, I used to always use ZSNES.
Scott: Well, no, ZSNES isn't really that good.
Rym: No, it isn't.
Rym: It has not been updated.
Rym: I was using it the other day.
Scott: I'm going to try, I'm going to try this BSNES, see how it's like.
Rym: I did realize though, going back through all the old ROMs again, because I got it set up on the HDPC, I really fucking like those Koushibosawa collections.
Scott: Which ones are those?
Rym: Like Gemfire, Arrowbiz.
Rym: Here's like the Executive Series and the Imagination Series and like all these different series of games.
Rym: And they come down to games Rym-liked.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: So did you hear about all this Diablo crap?
Scott: Uh, maybe.
Scott: Everybody heard about it, pretty much.
Rym: Yeah, we're on kind of a longer cycle, so we haven't talked about it on GeekNights.
Scott: No, not really.
Rym: We haven't even really talked about it, me and Scott, together.
Scott: So if you don't know, the deal is, right, Diablo 3 is coming out eventually, pretty soon now.
Scott: Maybe less than a year away, who knows.
Scott: I played Diablo 2 actually back in the day.
Scott: As did I. I played it a lot actually, I beat it more than once, and it wasn't until later that I realized, oh, this game is just click click click click.
Rym: I did not play it a lot.
Scott: This was, I was pretty bored in the year of 1999 and 2000.
Rym: Guys, see by then, I would still be playing Civ 2, like why would I play Diablo?
Scott: I was playing Civ 2 in '97, '98.
Rym: Yeah, and I kept playing it, '99, 2000, 2000, 1, 2, 3, 4.
Scott: No you didn't.
Rym: Yeah, I was playing it at RIT.
Scott: Anyway, you didn't play it that much.
Scott: I didn't play it like 12 hours at a time.
Scott: Basically, if you don't, I've never played Diablo, all it is is a game where you walk around and click on monsters and occasionally they drop loot, right?
Scott: And usually there's some number of levels and each level ends with a boss and you beat the game.
Scott: And then you beat the game again on harder difficulty and then again on harder difficulty and you keep your equips, right?
Scott: So you have this character and all you really do is beat this single player game over and over again.
Scott: In Diablo 2, they had two kinds of multiplayer.
Scott: They had open battle net and official battle net.
Scott: So in open battle net, you could take your single player character and just go nuts.
Scott: But anything that happened to your character in open battle net stuck to your character, right?
Scott: So if you, you know, you could do PvP, but that was basically just.
Scott: you're playing the single player game and other people happened to be there also playing the single player game with you and you could try to attack them if you wanted to.
Scott: And if someone killed you, all your shit dropped on the ground and they could take it because you were just like any other bad guy.
Scott: And if that happened to you and you went to play single player game, your shit would be gone.
Scott: Battle net, a real battle net, if you didn't hack it or do something shady, made you connect to Blizzard servers where you would play Diablo and you had to start with a new character.
Scott: And that new character started off as blank and you could only play that character on blank on battle net.
Scott: So you basically, if you wanted to play for serious, you had to play on battle net all the time, right?
Scott: For whatever, with other people.
Scott: And there'd be no cheating and to be ultra secure and whatever.
Rym: No cheating in quotes, but in quotes.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Anyway, so it was kind of weird, though, because people do is they would just cheat on their single player character, but to make like infinite awesome items or whatever other kind of stuff, you know, because a single player, no one gave a fuck.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And then you go into open battle net and you trade stuff with other people that you would and there would be hacks to duplicate items.
Scott: So it was like this item that was the best item in the game, some kind of ring and everyone would just get enough of them to fully max out everything.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: It was a surprising realm of kind of like old world, like shit cockery.
Rym: It was a weird place.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But anyway, so Diablo three is coming out and, you know, Blizzard decided that they were going to make it so you could only play online, period.
Scott: You cannot play offline.
Rym: They made a big deal about how the reason they're doing this.
Rym: The main reason is that they don't want you to have to, you know, say you're playing the game by yourself and you're all cool and then you decide you want to play online.
Rym: They don't want you to have to start over.
Scott: Yeah, but they also want to stop cheating.
Rym: Yeah, but they have to stop cheating, especially if they want to take the same character offline, online.
Rym: And people care about the sort of I don't want to say competition, but the, I guess, fairness of the persistence of a character in an online player versus player space.
Scott: It's not a player versus player space, primarily a co-op space where you just have it's like River City Ransom is player versus player.
Rym: Now, think about how rapidly the rationalization for this kind of breaks down.
Rym: They don't want people to cheat in a game that's either going to be co-op online or mostly single player at home.
Scott: I thought it was funny how most of the gaming news outlets focused on the, you know, pretty much the story that Blizzard is trying to really wants just DRM aspects, which is part of it.
Rym: Now, they said definitely part of it.
Scott: And it's bullshit because, you know, what if I want to play on an airplane and there's no Wi-Fi on the airplane?
Scott: or, you know, all these, you know, that's the thing that most people covered.
Scott: Only Jerry at Penny Arcade, you know, came up to the same conclusion I did, which is, you know, by their own, I'll read his paragraph, by their own admission.
Scott: This is this is Jerry at Penny Arcade.
Scott: By their own admission, Diablo is not really focused around the PvP experience.
Scott: If you're playing with someone who has duped items or whatever, all it means is that you'll be more likely to defeat Satan without a means to gain advantage over another.
Scott: Cheating as a concept becomes substantially more opaque.
Scott: Who is the cheated party?
Scott: Precisely Satan the devil.
Scott: Fuck him.
Scott: Who cares?
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like you're cheating in a single player game, just like I told you to cheat at Final Fantasy to skip over grinding for this episode.
Rym: I mean, is that did I cheat Garland?
Rym: Is Garland like, oh, man, spoilers.
Rym: Oh, you know what?
Rym: By the way, it's way easy to beat Garland at first level if you got two fighters and a red mage in your party.
Scott: But, you know, the point is, like, who are you cheating?
Scott: Right.
Scott: Well, what is the point?
Scott: It's one thing to stop cheating in Counter-Strike because you're cheating another human being.
Scott: That guy is getting owned because you're using aimbot and he's not.
Scott: Ah, but Scott, Satan is not a real person.
Rym: That's the.
Scott: that's the who cares.
Rym: So who is being cheated?
Scott: And you know what?
Scott: I can go and watch the ending of the game on YouTube the day it comes out.
Scott: Am I cheating?
Rym: No, it only be cheating if you watch it with someone else, because that's co-op.
Rym: OK, so here's who's really being cheated.
Rym: Well, because they've got this auction house, that's the real reason they did all this.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So they're trying to make money, but it's one thing to make money by selling you stuff for World of Warcraft.
Rym: that makes a little bit of sense, like as much as I hate the fucking hats, at least it's B.S.
Rym: that you're buying to share with other people online.
Scott: Right.
Scott: This is like you're buying something to play in a, you know, a single player game.
Scott: That's like if I'm playing River City Ransom and I give someone real money to get a lead pipe right now.
Rym: Mario three, world one one.
Rym: Hey, want a hammer suit?
Scott: Ten bucks.
Rym: No actual dollars, not coins, bitches.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Actual ten bucks playing Mario three on your own to get a hammer suit.
Scott: Fuck that.
Scott: Are you shitting me?
Rym: Interestingly, and we're you know, we're working on a panel for some future packs about this, but look at all the things that came out of turn.
Scott: kind of turn real life pennies into real life rupees in your single player Zelda game.
Rym: But look, there's other things, too.
Rym: There are no bonds.
Rym: They're not allowing modding, no bots.
Rym: They're not allowing bots.
Rym: OK, now, why can't they allow bots?
Rym: Because bots could be used to farm and then sell stuff on the auction, devaluing everything.
Scott: It's like they why not?
Scott: Here's an idea.
Scott: You ready?
Scott: It's a single player fucking game.
Rym: Sell it for 50 bucks and that's it?
Scott: No.
Scott: Why are you letting people fucking trade shit with each other like that?
Rym: Oh, because they also have the online co-op thing.
Rym: And really, you know, I'll skip all the rationalization I was going to try to pull out of my ass.
Rym: Really, it comes down to.
Scott: they want to make money on this market and they think that, you know, there's another way to completely eliminate, you know, basically their rationalization was there's going to be a second hand market for stuff anyway.
Scott: So better that we handle it than some, you know, shady operations all set up and take all this money.
Scott: The money is going to move anyway.
Scott: Might as well move to us because we're legit.
Scott: You know what?
Rym: Here's a quote from Blizzard on this.
Rym: OK.
Rym: Ultimately, players want it.
Rym: If Blizzard doesn't do this system, I'm not so naive to think that third party auctions are not going to happen.
Rym: In the past, we've really taken a hard line stance of.
Rym: we will try to stamp it down every place we can.
Scott: Here's a way to completely eliminate it.
Scott: Guaranteed there will be absolutely no marketplace for traded goods.
Scott: You ready for this?
Scott: Just let people fucking cheat.
Scott: Put cheat codes right in the game.
Scott: Like Doom, Doom, IDDQD.
Scott: You couldn't sell some Doom rocket launcher.
Scott: Why?
Scott: Because they could type ADKFA anytime they wanted.
Scott: If you just let people put a cheat menu right in the game, just on the front of the screen, don't even hide it.
Scott: Just be like, click here to cheat.
Scott: You click there.
Scott: And there's a menu where you can create any item with any stats you want and just give it to your fucking character.
Rym: But Scott, then we won't make as much money on bullshit microtransactions and we won't have an excuse to push our always online DRM.
Scott: It's fine if you want to do those things.
Scott: In fact, you know, Blizzard, I don't really have a problem with you doing those things in your game.
Scott: But you know what I do have a problem with is basically just fucking lying.
Scott: At least come out and say it.
Scott: We just want to make more fucking money.
Rym: That's why we did this.
Scott: They're not actually trying to act like the good guy.
Scott: Scott, you're not.
Scott: They're not actually lying because all the things that Zenga doesn't do, that Zenga is like, fuck, yeah, Farmville, give us money.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The Diablo.
Scott: Why do you got to be trying to act like you're a good guy, Blizzard?
Scott: You're no different.
Scott: Stop trying to pretend.
Scott: Now, that's my problem.
Rym: I would be now if you wanted to be forget the business language because of whatever business language is business language.
Rym: I don't fault people for omitting the truth because they're not actively lying.
Rym: They're just they're saying things that are technically true in the most bare sense of the truth.
Scott: The other part of the truth is we just want to make money green.
Scott: Why not Washington?
Rym: Why not set up some sort of?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: You buy the game for like 50 bucks and if you want to play online, you have to make another goddamn character like every other game.
Rym: Well, Borderlands and then have an auction house for that, because again, then they wouldn't have an excuse to not have offline mode or the same thing.
Scott: So the same thing is Diablo two.
Rym: Now, I wonder if because they're not allowing mods.
Rym: I wonder if they're going to at some point have blessed mods that they make or get people to make mods in a marketplace or some B.S.
Rym: like that.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Are we going to have to start jailbreaking games?
Scott: He has another idea.
Scott: If they wanted to have this not be a problem, just make it a fucking console game instead.
Rym: That's not going to work for much longer.
Scott: It would actually be a lot more comfortable to play Diablo as a console game.
Rym: That won't work for that much longer, though, because I really think Microsoft is going to continue to push toward eventually having PCs and Xboxes.
Scott: The point is, this game is coming out now.
Scott: It doesn't matter.
Scott: The future matters, right?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I think this might give some of the similar games that are coming out a little bit of an advantage, because I think there will be a surprising amount of outrage about this game compared to other similar games.
Scott: I have a thing is I just think Torchlight two actually has a huge advantage here.
Scott: And if they play the move right, they could actually kick Diablo three.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: They could be its equal or better.
Rym: You know what would kick it absolutely over the top?
Rym: If Torchlight had the best goddamn support for mods the world had ever seen.
Scott: I think, you know, they could mod it, especially if you can't mod the same game.
Scott: It's just click on bad guys.
Rym: I mean, look at how popular Dota was.
Rym: There's what?
Rym: A billion remakes of it coming out right now.
Rym: It's because you could mod those games.
Rym: If you can't mod Diablo three, you can't mod it.
Rym: And that whole market disappears.
Rym: And if Blizzard thinks they can sell what is basically mods as downloadable content when Torchlight exists, I think they got another thing coming.
Scott: We'll see.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: You know, the problem is I know semantically what should be done from the, I guess, what is all is good and just in the world standpoint.
Scott: But that is not going to win you the money.
Rym: If it makes money, it makes money.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Why does this go all Zynga?
Rym: and just when you install the game, it plays some sort of like pattern that hacks your brain.
Rym: It just makes you give them your credit card number.
Scott: You could do that.
Scott: Or you have to give them a credit card number to prove age.
Scott: And then they just in the fine print, they take like one hundred dollars.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: You just sign away like your house.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Who knows?
Rym: So briefly, I do want to geek by it.
Rym: I bought the official Gameloft, you know, Android app that is Catan.
Rym: Settlers of Catan.
Scott: I thought Microsoft owned the license for Catan.
Scott: How does Gameloft make?
Rym: There's this whole.
Rym: I'm trying to figure out how this doesn't have the Microsoft logo on it anywhere.
Rym: No, it doesn't have any logos on it.
Scott: Really?
Rym: It just says interesting.
Rym: But basically what happened in the game, I bought the game and I've been playing it.
Rym: And it's basically just Settlers.
Scott: What did you think it was going to be?
Rym: With some surprising limitations.
Scott: What are the limitations?
Scott: I mean, it's Settlers.
Rym: You can't play it online with anyone.
Scott: Ever?
Rym: You know, it's.
Rym: you either play it locally, hot seat or with bots.
Scott: You know, Settlers on the iPhone uses like the game center and you can play it online or you can also do like local Wi-Fi.
Scott: If other people have iPhones, you can sit around playing games.
Rym: You know, you can't do anything.
Scott: I don't know if you can do that specifically with Settlers because I've never really actually played German games on the iPhone, but I know there are games that use both of those features.
Scott: In fact, Dixit had those features.
Rym: You can't do any of that shit with this.
Rym: It's basically just single player Settlers or maybe hot seat.
Rym: They'll get sick of the hot seat in like five minutes and quit because it's stupid.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And there's a lot of kind of microtransaction stuff in it.
Scott: Oh, what can there be for a microtransaction in Settlers?
Rym: They've got a campaign.
Rym: We got to pay for that.
Scott: What do you mean a campaign?
Rym: There's a campaign.
Scott: How could there be a campaign of Settlers?
Scott: There's a campaign.
Scott: You have to play 10 games in a row and they play videos in between them?
Rym: There's a campaign.
Scott: What is the campaign like?
Scott: Fuck if I know.
Scott: I didn't buy it.
Scott: Oh, right.
Rym: There's also.
Rym: you can get.
Rym: they've got seafarers.
Rym: You can buy that.
Scott: That makes that make sense.
Scott: It makes sense.
Scott: Cities and Knights.
Rym: They've got that's not in there yet.
Scott: Five and six player expansion.
Rym: They've got some alternate tile sets.
Rym: Some are free Settlers of Canaan, some not so free.
Scott: OK, that's that's makes sense.
Rym: Yeah, but all that aside, it's a pretty like.
Rym: the game works pretty well.
Rym: The training mechanic.
Rym: How's the interface?
Rym: It's actually really good.
Rym: It just works.
Scott: And are the rules accurate?
Rym: The rules are accurate, though.
Rym: They added some rules that I have been advocating for fucking ever.
Scott: It's OK.
Scott: So they changed the rules.
Rym: But you can play straight Settlers, but they have options like you can change.
Rym: It has dice, which is just dice, you know, to do six.
Rym: You can also use something they call the stack, which is the thing I always recommend for games like this.
Rym: Make a deck of 2D6, maybe two decks of it.
Rym: So there's two of each of the odds.
Rym: be the same to guarantee fairness.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, that's that's something we can't believe.
Scott: that they thought of that.
Rym: It allows you to really do interesting stuff.
Rym: Strategy wise, like seven has been coming up a whole bunch.
Rym: There's only so many sevens before it resets.
Scott: Yeah, that people don't realize this, but or two is going to get rolled.
Scott: Imagine if you have 2D6, right?
Scott: Any number could come up two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, ten, eleven, twelve.
Scott: And you know, the odds seven is the most likely two and twelve are the least likely.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Well, you better if you're a gamer.
Rym: Right.
Scott: But what if you had a deck of cards?
Scott: and in that deck of cards, you had all the numbers two, three, four, five, six, seven, eight, nine, ten, eleven, twelve.
Scott: And the deck was mostly sevens.
Scott: You know, it would have the same proportion as 2D6.
Scott: But there's a difference here, even though the odds of any number coming up are the same.
Scott: The fact is, when you have a deck, you're going through the deck exactly once.
Scott: Which means there is a two in the deck somewhere.
Scott: It's going to show up at some point.
Scott: Rolling 2D6, it could be just seven every time forever.
Scott: That's possible.
Rym: Now, the thing is, you have to.
Rym: you can tweak it.
Rym: It's kind of like blackjack.
Rym: How many decks do you use?
Rym: by expanding the deck?
Rym: You can make it to where it's less deterministic as the number of decks you use.
Scott: You know, the smallest deck that had the same proportion would have exactly one, two and one.
Rym: You could count cards and being like four is going to get rolled three more times in the next five rounds.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So it's like if you're counting the cards, you know, the rest of the deck is all five.
Rym: Now they have another option, which is actually really interesting.
Rym: It's another thing that I kind of was expecting, though they did it slightly differently from how I would do it.
Rym: They call it stack five.
Rym: You have a deck.
Rym: Five values are randomly and secretly removed.
Scott: Oh, just period.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So it could be two might never get rolled.
Scott: It could be twos, sevens, tens.
Scott: So maybe sevens.
Rym: It could be five.
Rym: sevens got removed.
Scott: Oh, five five cards.
Scott: Oh, I thought it was five numbers are removed.
Rym: No, that's kind of crazy.
Scott: This deck has no threes.
Rym: No, it also has options.
Rym: Like you can start with cities and you can start with a lot of the kind of house rules that people will start with for like abbreviated games.
Rym: You can increase the victory point requirements.
Rym: And there's a bunch of kind of like fiddly things.
Scott: Not a fan.
Scott: They're all there.
Scott: I'm only a fan of the stack.
Rym: So the
Rym: A.I.,
Rym: I've noticed that it's retarded.
Rym: if I like uninstall and reinstall the game and play.
Rym: I always win the first game.
Rym: I think the game has a slight learning.
Rym: I think it does.
Scott: I think it cheats and pretty much let's try to play the first game and just try to be a moron, like just build your settlements far away from each other.
Scott: Don't just hold on to a zillion cards and hardly ever build anything.
Scott: Build like just a bunch of disconnected roads all over the place.
Rym: But after that, the
Rym: A.I.,
Rym: I mean, it's not that hard to make a perfect day for settlers, but the problem is it tends to hold on to a lot of cards like.
Rym: it'll sit there with like 20 resources.
Rym: And then the robber gets rolled like, great, dude, good game, good job.
Rym: Or it'll do stuff like you'll see it in like trade.
Rym: It'll.
Rym: it'll surprisingly not trade that often.
Rym: It kind of trades semi optimally.
Scott: And it won't trading.
Scott: just doesn't make sense when you have A.I.
Rym: and it won't trade with the front runner.
Scott: It doesn't work.
Rym: Now it won't trade with the front runner.
Rym: It works pretty well, but it really, really picks on the human player to probably make the game more playable without just always winning.
Rym: It'll rob the human player pretty much constantly, even when the human player is in like third, fourth place.
Scott: So it always robs you.
Rym: It seems to always go after me like pretty hardcore, even when I am not winning.
Rym: All right, that's it.
Rym: It's a pretty solid implementation, but don't be fooled.
Rym: It doesn't have any form of non-local multiplayer, thus making it kind of useless.
Scott: I would suggest just buying a settler's set.
Rym: I would also suggest that they're not that expensive or there you could.
Rym: There's a bunch of places to play settlers online with people kind of bootleggy or free.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Wasn't there enough?
Scott: Isn't there?
Scott: And you're going to play the Xbox, too, with people.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Do that.
Rym: Oh, so I got to say I was doing a quick look because I didn't realize who'd made it.
Rym: So I was like, oh, Gameloft.
Rym: But then I looked.
Rym: Gameloft has that other game, The Settlers on Droid.
Scott: Well, The Settlers is not Catan.
Rym: I know.
Rym: That's what I just said.
Rym: Because I was looking through the Google.
Rym: This was made by some company I've never heard of, actually, but it's the official one.
Rym: So it's some German company, it looks like.
Scott: OK.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway, so things of the day, what do you got?
Scott: So here's a video and this is a cosplay that requires video and it's a cosplay, by the way.
Scott: This is the most genius cosplay I've seen in a long time, perhaps a year or two.
Scott: And that's all I got.
Scott: And you just watch it and that's all there is to it.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Well, I got my own.
Rym: It's a meme that many of you may not have run into, but it's surprisingly popular.
Rym: There's like six hundred and something thousand views on the video here and there's a ton of remixes and it's advice that the Internet really needs.
Rym: It's OK to not like things.
Rym: Yeah, it's kind of stuck in my head.
Rym: The little song.
Rym: OK, that's it.
Rym: All right.
Rym: It's a thing.
Rym: You should watch it.
Scott: We got a metamoment.
Scott: situation.
Rym: We do have a metamoment.
Scott: We got a Twitter.
Scott: Twitter.com/GeekNights.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: We got a Facebook.
Scott: Facebook.com/FrontRowCrew because GeekNights is like occupied by the interest of Facebook.
Scott: Anyway, we got we got a website.
Scott: We got a website, frontrowcrew.com.
Scott: It has a forum at forum.frontrowcrew.com.
Rym: We have two YouTube channels.
Rym: The GeekNights one, which is not updating for reasons I don't want to get into.
Scott: Don't just don't worry about which channel to go on YouTube.
Scott: Just go to YouTube and search for GeekNights or whatever.
Rym: But really, the GeekNights Rym one is the official YouTube channel of me, which happens to have a lot of our panels as I'm slowly uploading them.
Scott: You want to go and read the book club book, which is the ear, the eye, the arm.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: The hand, the foot, not the hand, the ear, the eye and the arm.
Scott: Did you ever put up the book club?
Rym: I was actually going to finish that tonight and get it up.
Scott: All right.
Rym: We are going to be at the Penny Arcade Expo this year in Seattle doing a panel Discover the Forgotten Masters at noon on Saturday at 6 p.m.
Rym: on Saturday.
Rym: We will also be doing in the new workshop area for tabletop.
Rym: I still have to sort out the exact name of this area.
Rym: We will be teaching people how to play Spotted, Seven Wonders, Carcassonne and a Game To Be Determined.
Scott: This Friday at seven o'clock is Nerd NYC board game night at Think Coffee, New York City.
Rym: We will be there.
Scott: Saturday the 13th, which is this Saturday, is the second summer streets.
Scott: from seven to one p.m.
Scott: There's basically the roads are closed to cars between Central Park and 72nd Street.
Rym: to Friday, the 19th, not this Friday, but next Friday is the JOCO mini cruise in New York.
Scott: So if you go to that and you go to PAX, it's double JOCO one one one one week and one the next week.
Rym: And also we will be on this little mini New York cruise.
Rym: It's like a three or four hour thing.
Scott: That way I won't have to see JOCO the next week.
Scott: Yeah, I can go play games instead of going to a concert.
Rym: So if you want to hang out with us, I mean, other than the concert, it's just food and drinks hanging out.
Scott: Plus, it's a concert on a boat.
Scott: So it's not like a typical concert where you sit there listening to music the whole time.
Scott: You know, you're on a boat, so you go and you hang out on the deck.
Scott: You go eat some food.
Rym: I like being on a boat.
Scott: You go and listen to some music, you know.
Rym: I swear to God, if he doesn't do a cover of I'm on a boat on the boat, I'll be very disappointed.
Scott: And then the third summer streets is the day after that.
Rym: Been a while since we've talked about some tabletop in depth, so I figured it'd be a good opportunity to cover a couple of games.
Rym: People are looking for new stuff to play.
Rym: You've already bought every game we've ever recommended.
Rym: You haven't should.
Scott: Well, these are two actually somewhat old games that we just hadn't really played a lot until recently there.
Scott: Well, there's somewhat old.
Scott: So let's have a reefing counter, which is from 2004.
Scott: So Scott played this at what?
Scott: No, I played this online at spiel by spiel by web dot com, which I think you can still do.
Scott: S.P.I.E.L Yup, spiel by web.
Rym: I was playing.
Rym: I was playing Hacienda there.
Scott: Yeah, that website has Hacienda, Hoity Toity, Reef Encounter, Santiago, Tikal, Wallenstein and bus.
Scott: And it's actually a pretty good interface and it just emails you when it's your turn.
Scott: You go to the website, you take your turn.
Scott: So I played and learned how to play reefing counter there, but I didn't play it that much.
Scott: And I kept wanting to buy the game and I just didn't until eventually.
Scott: I'm like, you know what?
Scott: I just fucking buy it because it's really cute little wooden shrimp.
Rym: Oh, my God.
Rym: The little googly eyes.
Scott: There's little wooden shrimps in this game that have googly eyes.
Scott: They are the cutest game piece I've ever seen.
Rym: You guys don't understand because I never played this game online to Scott did.
Rym: And he kept telling me about it and he kept coming up.
Rym: And every now and then we'd be like, blah, blah, blah, board game.
Rym: He's like, oh, I should get reef encounter.
Rym: It has the best shrimp.
Scott: It does.
Rym: And you put him in your.
Rym: what's the fish?
Rym: The parrotfish?
Scott: The parrotfish.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: It's not.
Rym: you know what I what I think what I like about it.
Rym: And we can explain what.
Rym: what goes on.
Rym: It is a lot of mechanics and they're all pretty distinct from similar looking or similar feeling games like it.
Rym: It's kind of in a space on its own in terms of German style euro game.
Scott: Yeah, I don't I can't think of another game.
Scott: It's like, you know, a lot of games.
Scott: You can be like, oh, yeah, you know, Le Havre, that's Kalis plus Agricola or, you know, whatever.
Scott: You know, that's what it is.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But you look at, you know, reef encounter like, well, what is that?
Scott: Well, it's got some sort.
Scott: it's got sort of an action system, sort of like to call, but there's no action points.
Scott: You can just go nuts on your actions.
Rym: Yeah, I love this.
Rym: You've got you can take.
Rym: you know, you've got one action.
Rym: You can take that infinity time.
Scott: Yeah, basically there's like on your turn, there's all.
Scott: this is chart that shows all the actions you can do.
Scott: So there's one action you have to do.
Scott: You can do it at most once at the beginning of your turn.
Scott: There's another action you must do once at the end of your turn, everything in the middle.
Scott: There's like two actions or three or two or three actions you can do at most once at any time during your turn.
Scott: There's a bunch of other actions that you can do as many times as you are able to during your turn in any order.
Scott: And then this action number five, which you can do infinity times any time during your turn, even in the middle of another action,
Rym: you'll find that players will constantly make the joke of they'll move one of their algaes like one of their one of their shrimps, an infinite number of times.
Rym: It stops getting funny really quick.
Rym: Yeah, do it anyway, especially if Scott's playing.
Scott: But the point is, you have a ridiculous number of things you can do on your turn in different combinations.
Scott: And you think, oh, you must be able to just win the game in one stroke.
Scott: Well, not really, because you're so limited in your resource.
Scott: It's really, you know, a lot of games say the resource management games, which means collect a bunch of resources and then spend them wisely.
Rym: But rarely are those actually like the driving force of the game.
Scott: This isn't just, you know, buy a get as many resources as possible and spend them wisely.
Scott: It's it's.
Scott: there's all sorts of different resources and they all do all sorts of different things.
Scott: But the only thing that matters in terms of winning is getting corals in your parrotfish.
Rym: That's all you want, right?
Scott: So the key in this game is you want to get corals in the parrotfish.
Rym: That's it.
Scott: So the other game, but you're going to get corals of different colors and you only get to put things in the fish at most four times.
Scott: So at the end of the game, your parrotfish, maybe you ate three shrimps, you got five white, two yellow and a pink in there.
Scott: Well, each tile could be worth anywhere from one to five points, depending on how you managed the open seaboard.
Rym: Now, the open seaboard has this cool thing in that it in turn controls multiple things.
Rym: It controls the points at the end of the game.
Rym: It also controls which algae can eat other corals, can eat other corals.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So let's say that on the open seaboard, white is beating orange.
Scott: That means that white at the end of the game, a white coral will be worth one more point and an orange will be worth one less point.
Scott: It also means that right now during the game at this moment in time, a white coral can consume an orange coral, but not vice versa.
Rym: One thing you can spend actions on and resources is locking those fuckers in or flipping them.
Scott: So you could flip the orange to be stronger than the white or you could lock it in so that orange will never, ever be stronger than white ever again for the rest of the game.
Rym: But the flipping itself is slightly complex, kind of like a Rubik's Cube.
Rym: Yeah, it's like you need to move other things.
Scott: You want to flip it.
Scott: Well, that means that you need a consumed polyp tile to turn into an algae cylinder.
Rym: It's like, oh, my God, it's really about timing and what other opponents are doing.
Rym: Like, say it's early in the game and I eat a whole bunch of white and I lock in white to be worth a ton of points at the end of the game.
Rym: Everyone else is just going to get a whole bunch of white now, too, because they know it's worth a lot.
Scott: Yeah, and they've got a whole rest of the game to get white.
Rym: I've also locked white in as being powerful, so it's kind of pointless at that point.
Scott: So it's really, well, actually, on the other hand, it would be really easy to consume other colors with white.
Scott: But because you've locked in white as being powerful, it's hard to consume white, which would make it harder to get white larva cubes.
Rym: But there are other ways to get larva cubes.
Scott: There are, but it would still be hard to play because the competition for the white larva cube in the open seaboard would be very high.
Scott: So it wouldn't come with a lot of polyp tiles.
Rym: It's very easy.
Scott: This game is so strange.
Scott: It's got so many different bits all over the place and it's just like, what the fuck?
Scott: You're not.
Scott: I'm not going to be able to teach you this game now.
Scott: You're not going to understand how the game works on the podcast.
Scott: The only way I recommend going to spiel by web, reading the rules, that's the only way you're going to understand it.
Rym: But it is a game the way we used to describe Puerto Rico to people who weren't familiar with this kind of game.
Rym: But this is like that to a T. You've got this giant mixer board in front of you with all these sliders.
Rym: You move one a little bit and all the other ones move all over the place.
Scott: You got all sorts of just crazy shit.
Scott: There's this polyp tile, shrimp is free.
Scott: What's the free token space?
Rym: Oh, I don't remember what it was.
Scott: It's like the free stone.
Scott: And you got.
Scott: you got the ocean tiles, you got the ocean seaport, you got a pair of fish, you got alga cylinders, larva cubes, consumed polyp tiles.
Rym: I think this game has my favorite set of proper nouns of any board game I've played.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And it's weird because while they actually made a really good game, even though this seemed it's one of those, you know, people always play German board games, even less complicated ones and they seem complicated.
Scott: They get afraid of them.
Scott: But what?
Scott: and even when you're reading the rules, it'll still be complicated.
Scott: But once you actually play, all the complexity just goes away.
Scott: It's like, oh, this isn't actually complex.
Scott: It just seems complex right up until the moment you actually take your turn.
Scott: Yeah, because you don't actually get to do all that ridiculous shit in one turn because you don't have the stuff to do all that ridiculous shit in one turn.
Scott: So Reef Encounter is highly recommended.
Rym: It's great fun.
Scott: And just there is an expansion.
Rym: I have not played just because it's so different from a lot of the games you've already got.
Scott: And actually does a pretty good job of simulating, you know, or teaching you about a real coral reef.
Rym: It's a surprisingly educational game that actually does pretty accurately incorporate the reality of what it's teaching.
Scott: But I'm not.
Scott: the problem is in order to learn anything about coral reefs, you'd actually have to be thinking about learning about coral reefs while playing.
Scott: I'm thinking about winning.
Scott: So I don't really learn anything, but I already know how coral reef works.
Rym: So how do you now?
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Where's the parrot fish come in?
Rym: He how about the free algae space?
Rym: So the other like this is a lighter game, but we played this game.
Rym: We kept forgetting what it was called.
Scott: Alex seems to be really good at going to board game libraries and conventions, finding the good game that none of us noticed.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: First it was battle line.
Scott: Now at ConnectiCon, he went to the library and he got Toluva.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And it's.
Rym: it reminded me right away of this other game, you know, Tikal and Mexico.
Rym: Well, Java was the third of those three games.
Scott: It reminded me more of what's it called?
Scott: Samurai, but the the Reiner Knizia Samurai.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: There's like ten games called Samurai.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But the one with the Buddha.
Rym: Yeah, the one with the Buddha.
Rym: That's a really good game.
Rym: I should say I can get it.
Scott: Go get it.
Scott: You can get it easily.
Rym: But anyway.
Rym: But it also reminded me of Java because it had the hex tiles that stack.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Stacking hexes.
Rym: In three dimensions.
Rym: We should probably do a show on that trilogy of Mexico Tikal and Java at.
Scott: We should get three games named Samurai.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: Do a show on Samurai.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Anyway, but Toluva is a game, if you didn't know, it's about volcanoes.
Scott: So every hex tile has three spots, three hexes on it.
Scott: And one of those hexes is a volcano.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And it's like and the rest of it is like jungles or clearings or rocks.
Scott: So on your turn or whatever, on your turn, it's sort of like Carcassonne, right?
Scott: Or were the tiles bigger than that?
Scott: I'm trying to remember.
Rym: They're three tile and you play a tile just like Carcassonne.
Rym: And then you must build something.
Rym: And there's three kinds of things to build temples, towers and huts, just like Carcassonne.
Rym: So the way it works, only three kinds of meeples, is by default, you've got these, you know, there's like 12 temples, eight towers and like 80 huts in the game.
Rym: And you each have your own set of them.
Scott: The game, I think each person has two towers, three temples and a fistful of huts.
Rym: But the way the game goes is there's 48 volcano tiles.
Rym: And every time, you know, you draw a volcano tile, you play it and you play your stuff down.
Rym: You must play a building.
Rym: And when we run out of stuff, like when there's no more tiles and the game is over, then whoever has the most temples wins.
Rym: But wait a minute, temples are in the middle of that set of three.
Rym: Like there's more temples than towers per player.
Scott: Yeah, there's three temples and two towers.
Rym: So, yeah, if you're tied on temples, then the tiebreaker is towers.
Rym: If you're tied on towers, the tiebreaker is huts.
Rym: All right.
Rym: But the game rarely ends that way.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: It ended that way a couple of times when you played it.
Rym: If any player gets all of two kinds of his buildings out on the board, he immediately wins.
Scott: So you get both towers and all three temples on the board.
Scott: You immediately win at that instant.
Scott: If you get all your huts and all your temples or all your huts and all your towers on the board at the same time, you immediately instantly win.
Rym: So think about it, because, you know, you want to go for the temples if you think the game's going to get all the way to the end.
Rym: But if you want to end the game early, you got to go kind of for the towers first, because they're the hardest to place and there's the fewest of them.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Now, the other great part about this game is that when you play the volcano tiles, they're motherfucking volcano.
Rym: So you just play them on top of other people's shit.
Scott: Well, you can only play them on top if they line up with an existing volcano.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And they're not lining up with a tile directly.
Scott: So you can't just stack tiles straight up.
Scott: You have to stack them sort of at angles.
Rym: The lava always comes out of different directions.
Rym: And there's a fiddly rule.
Rym: You cannot volcano something that would completely destroy a player's settlement.
Rym: So you can't just wipe someone off the board.
Scott: But you can destroy some stuff, including your own stuff with them.
Scott: You just can't destroy an entire settlement.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So you can't.
Rym: But it means you can stick one little hut somewhere and that hut might prevent people from volcanoing things that you don't want them to volcano.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: Because if there's only one hut all by itself, volcanoing it would destroy an entire settlement, meaning no one can volcano that spot now.
Rym: Now, the cool thing is that there's different rules like, you know, the game stacks up.
Rym: It's three dimensional as the tiles get on top of each other.
Rym: You're volcanoing while you're expanding outward.
Rym: Towers can only go on places that are three or higher.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Temples can only go on already large settlements.
Rym: And if you expand a settlement with huts, every space that you build into in that round based on like what's on the tiles, you get one settlement, one hut in that tile space per level.
Rym: So it's four high.
Rym: You get four fuckers.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: If you can somehow expand your settlement using the expand maneuver onto a very tall space, you can play a ton of huts very quickly.
Rym: The end result is that it's a chaotic and fiddly strategic game.
Scott: You basically have to be constantly on the lookout for everyone's stuff, thinking what move they're going to make.
Scott: You know, oh, he has the opportunity to build a tower.
Scott: How can I block it?
Scott: He has the opportunity to build a temple.
Scott: I need to make an opportunity for myself to build a temple.
Scott: Where can I do it without getting blocked?
Rym: It's very difficult to formulate coherent strategies just because the act of placing volcanoes is so disruptive to the board and one gets played every turn.
Scott: The other thing, though, is like you need to play something on your turn, no matter what.
Rym: Yes, that's the third.
Scott: Otherwise, you just lose.
Rym: So the game ends when you run out of tiles and then it's just, you know, whoever has the most of each thing.
Rym: The game also ends if someone wins by getting two of their three sets of buildings out there.
Rym: An individual player is eliminated if on their turn they cannot play.
Rym: So you might think, I'm just going to get all my huts out there.
Rym: Say you get all your huts out there and you don't have a place.
Rym: You can play a valid tower or tell up.
Rym: You're done.
Rym: Game over.
Rym: Yeah, you're just kicked out.
Scott: So that's the thing is that it might be really easy to play a ton of huts or to, you know, something like that.
Scott: But the hut, you can almost always on your turn play a hut.
Scott: So you need to always hold on to a few huts because if you run out of them, it's very, you know, it's very likely that on your turn you won't be able to play a temple or a tower and you'll just lose.
Scott: So but it's so easy to play so many huts.
Scott: You might accidentally play them all.
Scott: You have none left.
Scott: You'll take a turn.
Scott: You won't be able to use a temple or a tower and you lose.
Rym: And I mean, there's not that much else to say.
Rym: It's a fun game.
Scott: I'd only recommend it.
Scott: It's relatively quick.
Scott: And in fact, more players makes it sort of faster.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But even though you wait longer for your turn to come around, there's only so many tiles in the game.
Scott: So I don't recommend it necessarily.
Rym: Like if you're just building out your board game collection, it's not one of the must haves.
Rym: It's not like you need this game.
Rym: There are other games you should buy first.
Scott: Yeah, I think I would take a brief encounter over Toluva, but Toluva is pretty good.
Rym: Toluva is a good game to own.
Rym: If you, for example, go to places where you're just constantly like teaching people relatively light games, you have to teach them quickly because it is quick to teach and play.
Rym: Quick to set up, quick to tear down.
Scott: It is kind of nice.
Scott: It falls into that Carcassonne department, right?
Scott: Where it's not spot it, trivial banana grams, throw away warm up game.
Scott: But it's also not ultra hard core, two hour, Agricola, Calist, Puerto Rico game.
Scott: I would also recommend it.
Rym: if you're like us and you own every game and you just want something different, like it's good enough to be, oh, I'll buy it because I'll play it every now and then.
Scott: Yeah, I don't think it's in print, but I see right now.
Scott: So on Board Game Geek, you can get one for twenty dollars and ninety nine because it's somewhat refreshing in the same way that Reef Encounter was refreshing just because it's so different.
Rym: And this game is refreshing because it's so chaotic.
Rym: It's been a long time since I played a game that was just as full of chaos, like game changers every round.
Rym: It's like Alhambra expanded in that respect.
Scott: Yeah, it's like on one turn you might make a move like, all right, I'm going to set up a temple build with this board by the next turn.
Rym: Someone volcanoed you and it might as well be an entirely new game.
Scott: Yeah, you're like, all right, now I'm going to because it's like that's.
Scott: the other thing is like almost anything you want to do with it for a temple or a tower requires a setup move, right?
Scott: You want to build a tower.
Scott: That means on this turn, you've got to put a tile down to make the third level, right, or to make the second level.
Scott: that enables the third level on the next turn.
Scott: Well, you do that setup move on one turn, but everyone else now gets a turn to destroy your setup and you need another.
Scott: So how can you possibly build a temple or a tower?
Scott: It's very, very difficult.
Scott: Much like how in Dickerson Euphrates, and then you had three actions.
Scott: So if you can't pull it off, you're forced to play something.
Scott: You play a hut because you can almost always play a hut.
Scott: So you're forced to play huts.
Scott: And if you can't get your temples and your towers out, you're forced to play all your huts and then you volcano your own huts just to get some back.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: And shit gets crazy.
Rym: Actually, I think volcano and huts go away.
Scott: I forget.
Rym: Yeah, they go away.
Scott: I think I thought you got them back.
Rym: Covered huts are returned to the box.
Scott: I think we fucked that up.
Rym: Yeah, I think you did.
Scott: Oh, shit.
Rym: I didn't read the rules or you guys taught me.
Rym: So it's all you and Alex that that changes everything.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I'm reading your volcanic eruption.
Rym: The overview plays volcano tile on top of existing tiles.
Rym: Volcano on volcano that has different direction.
Rym: No free space may be left beneath the tile.
Rym: covered huts are returned to the box.
Rym: Whoa.
Rym: No covering of temples or towers.
Rym: No covering of complete settlements.
Rym: Also, it's a Hanseong gluck game, so.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: All good.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music.
Rym: Kat Lee for Web Design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew dot com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.