Rym: It's Thursday, June 2nd, 2011.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight at the game shows Let's do this.
Rym: Been biking to work every day as I say a lot at the beginning of the show, but I've run into some trouble Mm-hmm.
Rym: So I don't ride my real bike because due to my building's Union Shenanigan bullshit, I can't actually take it up into the building and there's no way.
Rym: I'm parking my expensive bike out on the street in Midtown in the most bike steel in a city in the country.
Scott: Yeah, my building.
Scott: between the hours of 8 and 6 I can ride the elevator with my bike.
Scott: So I do yep.
Rym: So I ride my mountain bike and I park it outside and I tie it to the.
Rym: you know How?
Rym: there's municipal like.
Rym: you can just tie your bike to almost anything unless it's something that you obviously can't like.
Rym: you can't put it On the fence outside a subway station.
Scott: You can't tie it to the antenna on top of the Empire State Building.
Scott: It's out of reach.
Rym: Yeah, and it's a little too big but like if you put it around certain kinds of private property They're you know, you can't do that.
Rym: There's laws against that but there are Places you can guarantee to be able to do it for a bike rack the municipal bike racks and the municipal bike poles.
Rym: Yeah and one thing the city did a while ago and they're old but they're still there is on a lot of light poles at the Bottom is a little thing.
Rym: You can put your bike lock through and it has this bike logo on it and everything.
Rym: Yep, so there's a bunch of them right around my building one grand central place.
Rym: Yeah, aka the former Lincoln building.
Rym: so I parked my bike there outside.
Rym: and Every day these union assholes come out of the building and yell at me and threaten to cut my bike down.
Rym: They don't want me parking my bike anywhere near their building.
Scott: call police.
Rym: So what I did?
Rym: because the guy came out and actually threatened to cut my bike down one.
Rym: I took a picture of him which freaked him the fuck out and then I was like I'm gonna call the police right now if you threaten me again.
Scott: Yeah, what do you say to that?
Rym: Then he's like, come on blah blah blah.
Rym: It's my job.
Rym: I'm like, I don't care if my bike's gone.
Rym: I got a picture of you.
Rym: I've got a picture of the bike.
Rym: I'll call the police.
Rym: Yeah, if my bike is fucking and I and you know what my bike was still there.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: So I lodged a complaint with the city and I lodged a complaint with the building through my HR department.
Rym: But I saw them over lunch today harassing some poor bike messenger who tied his bike to another municipal thing again next to the building.
Rym: So fuck those guys fuck those guys But I'll win this one.
Scott: that's that's the thing.
Scott: You know.
Rym: my bike seat is worth more than my bike and I carry the bike seat with me.
Rym: so if they actually do steal my bike, I Will go all out to fuck them.
Scott: Let's you know who did it and I'm not really out much Yeah, but yeah, it's in New York.
Scott: There's a lot of.
Scott: there's a lot of rules and You know, the unions are very strong here.
Scott: But there are some rules that hold them back and hold various people back like taxis.
Scott: They have to take you somewhere.
Rym: However, I often pull bullshit to get anywhere out of the Javits.
Rym: This isn't the airport.
Rym: You basically have to lie and be like, yeah I'm going to the airport and we're just getting the cab be like actually no take me here And you got to be willing to call the police when they won't do it?
Scott: Oh, no, actually don't need to call the police.
Rym: You call that number in the cab.
Scott: Well, you call three one one, right in New York You can always call three one one if it's not nine one one.
Scott: But you still need to call something right.
Rym: the other thing the cabbies do mess with people.
Rym: They always quote unquote break their credit card machine.
Rym: They're like, ah, it's not working and then they freak out and attack you if you don't have or won't give them cash.
Scott: Yeah, so it's like you just got to fight for it.
Scott: Sometimes if you're not willing to fight for it, you're gonna lose out.
Rym: but the cool thing about Gotham Is that the laws are.
Rym: if you know what the laws are you do win in the end?
Scott: Yeah, so that they you know, and there's not.
Scott: you know, there's.
Scott: of course it's impossible to know all the laws Yeah, but there are.
Scott: but there's plenty of laws that you can learn.
Scott: that are the ones that matter for everyday Geekery.
Rym: if you're an anime geek, you know about your anime.
Rym: if you're a I don't know hentai geek.
Rym: You know about the laws related to hentai in your jurisdiction.
Rym: So if you're a biker, don't give me that jurors my addiction.
Rym: I think there's a hentai about jurors in your dick.
Rym: Anyway, so if you're a biker you got to know pretty much like you should be an expert on the bike laws.
Rym: Yeah in your town if you'd have a car and you own it in Manhattan You'd better damn well know where you can park.
Rym: cuz I don't know.
Scott: So anyway, I was speaking of biking yesterday.
Rym: Oh, and I saw a guy riding a bike over the Queensborough Bridge on my way home And he was carrying another larger bike over his back.
Scott: Nice.
Scott: I was biking to work yesterday, right and There's like there's a crowd of people standing around and a guy laying on the ground.
Scott: So I'm like up.
Scott: is this guy having trouble?
Scott: What's wrong with this guy?
Scott: All right, so I stopped to check out and see what's wrong with this guy and I don't know He might have had a heat stroke or a very minor heart attack or who knows what right?
Scott: He's complaining of chest pain couldn't breathe, you know, whatever.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So some people calling on one one.
Scott: I'm standing around thinking I know CPR and if he stops breathing, you know, I'll help him out.
Scott: Plus I had read recently just supposed to do chest compressions and forget the whole mouth thing and then they have a better chance of survival.
Scott: So I was like up.
Scott: Well, we'll see what happens.
Scott: Yeah, so I'm waiting there and his people around And then one guy's like I gotta go to work.
Scott: You know the guys like I'm gonna go down and talk to the traffic cop at the end of the bridge.
Scott: Another guy so suddenly just me and this guy.
Scott: basically we're New Yorkers.
Rym: We get bored quickly Like anything crazy is happening.
Rym: everybody stops for like a second like whoa Okay, I gotta get to work.
Scott: All right, so basically I'm standing with this guy and he's you know, he's recovering.
Scott: He didn't he didn't die or need CPR, right?
Scott: He was just probably heat-stroked and extremely exhausted.
Scott: Right and he recovered.
Scott: but I was basically standing there waiting for an ambulance to show up on the pedestrian part of the bridge for like over a half hour and It never showed lesson.
Scott: Don't hurt yourself on the pedestrian part of the bridge because the ambulance will not get there.
Scott: You know what?
Rym: I'm very alone with the ambulance driving on the pedestrian part of that bridge to get to you.
Scott: It didn't even but it didn't even like show that we didn't hear a siren nothing.
Scott: There was no no no cops No, no, no one tried to come even though 911 was called Almost like 45 minutes to an hour.
Scott: I left before it showed up.
Rym: I think the moral there is don't ever need an ambulance.
Scott: But I mean, it's like, you know, I guess it was the morning rush hour Who knows but it never it.
Scott: I had to leave before it showed up But the guy was able to recover and walk down because to the end of the bridge yesterday
Rym: I was walking to lunch and an old guy just like like he was walking in front of me and he just like fell Yeah on nothing and he was fine.
Rym: I helped him up and he was.
Scott: he tripped.
Rym: He didn't like no there was nothing to trip on walking and he didn't trip.
Rym: It wasn't like his foot like went and then he thought it was but it was a fall It wasn't an aneurysm or he just felt a stroke.
Rym: He fell straight down.
Rym: All right, like.
Rym: Then he got up and I was like you okay, and he's like leave me alone.
Rym: And then I just like a fading goat Yeah, he didn't even faint just kind of like fell.
Scott: All right, it was kind of I don't know Maybe it was a very minor seizure.
Rym: and also today I saw a dude who was biking.
Rym: Yep, and he just fell.
Rym: Yeah, like he didn't hit anything.
Rym: He was like riding and then his front he just like wobble falls over.
Rym: Yeah All right.
Rym: I don't know what happened there.
Rym: He was like he was young Reasonably fit on a normal bike bike was fine.
Rym: I don't know what his deal was, but he just fell.
Scott: that happens.
Scott: Yeah All right.
Rym: All right, so There's some irony in my news today.
Rym: It's this Thursday.
Rym: It's the lounge.
Rym: So The irony I'll get to in a second.
Rym: But here's an article pointing out that phone books are actually still a pretty big problem because people keep delivering them Despite the fact that no one uses them.
Scott: No one uses what phone books.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: Yes, now the cool thing is I?
Rym: well, I forgot that there's two kinds of phone books.
Rym: There's the yellow pages and the white pages.
Rym: So apparently no one uses the white pages like no one.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: and the yellow pages?
Rym: Well, basically here's the deal.
Rym: the article is talking about how the phone book delivery system is finally coming down.
Rym: Books are finally starting to disappear.
Rym: check out this obsolete antiquated shit finally going away.
Rym: Yeah, you know who's reporting that USA today?
Rym: Yeah, but some gems from this article because I didn't really I better.
Scott: I better report on this.
Scott: You know these newfangled iPods.
Scott: here it the news reports coming over the ticker.
Scott: Apparently People are getting music in some sort of digital format.
Rym: So apparently get this the people who are really pushing for this because apparently took legislation to bring this stupid industry down.
Scott: Oh, thank god.
Rym: So a quote from the article.
Rym: There's a guy who's works for the product Stewardship Institute Which is a nonprofit whose sole goal is to limit the environmental impact of consumer products.
Rym: All right, he basically said we all know if you were in fever people to use the phone book every year.
Rym: It's an antiquated antiquated industry.
Rym: We should get rid of it.
Rym: and Basically some laws were passed in Seattle Yeah Seattle saying that people should be allowed to opt out of the delivery of any phone book yellow or white Simple law that people should have the right to opt out.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: A similar law was passed.
Scott: What's the penalty for giving someone a phone book who opted out?
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: Is there penalty?
Rym: Yes.
Rym: I'm as I assume so, okay.
Rym: So San Francisco passed a similar law and The phone book companies the private company lost their tribute.
Rym: them Filed lawsuits against these laws saying there's a violation of free speech to allow people to opt out of receiving their phone books.
Rym: Okay So think about this.
Rym: how whenever has an industry in one stroke?
Rym: Both fought against its demise and proved why it needs to go away in a single sentence.
Scott: But I mean, okay, so if you say it's free speech Let's say they win.
Scott: It's free speech - for the phone book, right?
Scott: You can't opt out of it.
Scott: That means I can drop anything on everyone's porch no matter what even if they have a sign.
Scott: This is no soliciting or don't leave your menus here it.
Scott: that means it's legal for me to drop anything I want.
Scott: that is speech on anyone's doorstep and they're not allowed to say no forget that.
Rym: let's go a little closer.
Scott: I'm gonna go and make something some sort of art.
Scott: It's an artistic piece of dog poop, right?
Scott: It's.
Scott: it's a dog poop sculpture.
Scott: It's it's speech.
Scott: It's art and I'm gonna leave it on everyone's doorstep because that's part of the artistic message.
Rym: Simpler argument.
Rym: All right They're saying that they want the right to deliver phone books to people who don't want them so badly That they will file paperwork to make sure they don't get them.
Rym: Now clearly the people who get them who don't want them are not going to open them.
Rym: So this industry is Proving that all it is doing is using its fake circulation numbers to trick people who don't know better to buying ads.
Scott: It's all advertising is the same way.
Rym: So that's pretty much it.
Rym: I just thought it was interesting And I thought that the fact that the phone book companies are suing for the right to foist their garbage upon people is kind of amazing.
Scott: Nothing surprised me anymore.
Scott: I've been seeing the same thing for 15 years.
Rym: Remember every year they would bring the phone books on a big pallet and put him in Gracie's and anyone who wanted a phone book would just take him and Pretty much no one took him and they all went into the dumpster.
Scott: I mean, this is yet another one of those things where it's like it took this long.
Scott: It's like I could have you know.
Scott: So behind the times this should have been done in like 1997 not 2012 Mm-hmm.
Scott: The thing is the.
Rym: there's a quote from the article to from the industry itself saying that they believe they don't Believe.
Rym: they say that seventy five percent of people Actively use the yellow pages and I call bullshit on that.
Scott: That's absolutely bullshit.
Rym: There's no way I have not used a yellow page.
Scott: Okay, someone who buys in yellow pages ad should sue them for false advertise.
Rym: I can't imagine the last time I used a yellow pages for anything.
Scott: I think I used it in Beacon once.
Rym: Yeah, I did.
Rym: I looked up.
Rym: I was looking for what.
Rym: was it a plumber or something?
Rym: So once in ten years Plus I Decided a long time ago and I've stuck to this Unless I walk past a place or I specifically know about it due to some other means.
Rym: Pretty much no one who doesn't have a website is ever gonna get business for me ever.
Scott: That's pretty much it.
Scott: So yeah, the biggest news of today Was YouTube adding creative common support right now.
Scott: This is you know, it's like well, what's the big deal?
Scott: Well Flickr has always had creative common support and the way flickers stuff worked was that you could go and mark your photos With a creative commons license any creative commons license you desired and then it would clearly display on your photo What license it had and would also put the appropriate metadata in the HTML so someone could programmatically Determine, you know, which flicker photos were licensed with which you know restrictions and whatnot in which terms which you know.
Scott: YouTube has now added that and I'm like good god.
Scott: It's like you flicker had that Decade ago, why isn't YouTube had that?
Scott: but they finally have it.
Scott: but What they've added is pretty much just one license.
Scott: It's the same license.
Scott: We have attribution only which is great.
Scott: Because I really don't you know, there's a reason I picked that one.
Scott: Yeah And would also be kind of difficult for them to add the no commercial license because then YouTube couldn't put an ad on your video And it would be a little difficult for them to do, you know, the share alike license, you know, because it's like well Would
Rym: be really easy for them to do it because there's nothing for them to do.
Scott: Well the point I think that other thing is that they wanted to keep it simple for the user.
Scott: Yeah, you know, they why it's just creative commons or not?
Scott: right?
Scott: not pick a license, duh?
Rym: Well, I also like think about this the subtle it.
Rym: by using this as the intelligent default It just people who don't know better will end up giving up more rights They would have.
Scott: they'll use the most permissive best license the one that everyone should use for almost everything.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: But so that's you know, they added basically the same thing that flicker has kinda.
Scott: so it's like, okay Well, what's so exciting about that?
Scott: What's exciting is the other feature they have added.
Scott: if you don't know this There's actually a sort of mediocre video editor built into YouTube right like.
Scott: you can edit videos right in your web browser and This video editor now searches through YouTube for all the creative commons license videos Right and allows you to edit them together.
Scott: And if you're looking if you're watching a video that is creative commons license You can click a button to start editing it right away right in the browser.
Rym: So, you know, what's gonna happen here?
Rym: See, yes, I think you know what's gonna happen here a creative explosion.
Scott: I know what flicker really needs to do right is They need to make it so that when you click on a photo that's creative commons license as an in-browser Photoshop.
Scott: kind of situation going on.
Scott: That would be pretty awesome.
Rym: Well, something's got to happen because I'm not paying for any more Adobe Premiere after the version I've got now.
Rym: Yeah, and it it amazes me that premiere to this day cannot deal with a vast majority of formats of video out there.
Scott: I know right.
Scott: It's like it was funny because today we got an intern at work And he had an Ubuntu machine and he was like the video player was like install a codec.
Scott: Yes No, and I was like, oh, that's right.
Scott: like Ubuntu the open source stuff just Automatically gets any codec in the universe for every kind of video and plays it all perfectly.
Scott: and it's only on Windows and Mac That you need to go get some other video.
Rym: Also weird codec packs are the worst Adobe that you know.
Rym: people always excuse them.
Rym: Adobe themselves usually say things like oh well It's for professionals not amateurs and professionals only use X format and Y form.
Scott: It's like the commercial software is the one that's missing all the codecs and all the features in the open source software as every codec In the universe.
Rym: the other argument they'll make is that oh well format X or container Y is not suited to Frame by frame editing to which my answer is so why don't you just have it important convert?
Scott: Because that would be more work for them and it wouldn't sell them any more copies.
Scott: Yeah, that's what you always say.
Scott: They would.
Scott: they sell it if they added MKV support.
Scott: how many more copies of premiere would that sell them?
Rym: I know I know that's why I have premiere now because it's still better than any open source thing there is.
Rym: But that's not gonna be the case forever and I just got a hold out on this shit ass version of premiere.
Scott: Until the open source world is good enough for me to edit together videos of Rainbow Dash What happens right is they wouldn't sell any more copies or premiere But someone else has a business selling a premiere plug-in that makes MKV's work.
Rym: Oh good So we were sorry.
Scott: premiere added that feature.
Scott: All they would do is put that other company out of business, but they wouldn't make any more money for themselves.
Rym: You know what really grinds my gears.
Rym: Yeah that but let's zoom out because a better example that people are more familiar with is Twitter.
Rym: Twitter has a thing people might use it.
Rym: It's called Twitter.
Rym: You can tweet and there's an API that lets you do cool stuff that Twitter doesn't do by default.
Rym: So a lot of people built whole Businesses around providing little features that Twitter didn't provide and then Twitter then provides those features and those people are now mad Claiming that Twitter is unfairly competing with them or driving them out of business or somehow tricked them.
Scott: This isn't really your.
Rym: their dumb ass is for even thinking that that was a viable business model.
Scott: Yeah, this is an old old story in the software world, right?
Scott: I mean, I think the best example is Visual Studio.
Scott: right Visual Studio as many versions I mean.
Scott: when I was in high school We were using Visual Studio like five and now they're on Visual Studio 2011 or 2010 or who knows what right?
Rym: I installed the newest free version on my computer at work and I really like it anyway.
Scott: But the point is is that Visual Studio has lots of plugins for all sorts of shit, right?
Scott: Cuz it has to integrate with all sorts of different development things, you know, if you're developing some particular thing Well, you know instead of say, you know Writing your own development environment You just make a Visual Studio plug-in so that people can then use Visual Studio to develop software for whatever your weird platform is right and there's tons and tons of plugins out there.
Scott: and this whole business is that survived by making Visual Studio plugins and doing things that Visual Studio doesn't do and Occasionally as you can imagine over many many years 10 plus years of Visual Studio, maybe even 15 years.
Scott: I don't know It's really old.
Scott: they've added a lot of features to Visual Studio that have made a lot of those plugins useless and made basically a lot of those companies that make those plugins Not need to exist anymore.
Scott: And it's just a reality.
Rym: This is what happens and nothing of value was lost.
Scott: Yeah This is what happens when you build a business Based on someone else's business.
Scott: that business that is underneath you can owns you right?
Scott: It's like if I made an accessory for Ford cars and then Ford change the design of their cars so that my accessory doesn't work Anymore or they provide that feature in the car already so that my accessory is no longer necessary.
Scott: Well, I basically my business depended on Ford.
Scott: So am I pretty much my hopes are Ford buys me and I become part of Ford and or they ignore me.
Scott: You know, I'm basically putting a whole bunch of risk because this other company.
Scott: I'm dependent on them You.
Scott: if you want to have a long-term business, you need to be dependent on nobody but yourself.
Rym: Well and the general economy?
Scott: Yeah, of course, that's but that's true with any business.
Scott: But you know, it's especially true in software where a lot of things are plugins.
Scott: I mean even making something simple, right?
Scott: Like if you make a video game and you use DirectX and you make you make a Windows video game, right?
Scott: Using DirectX.
Scott: Well, guess what Microsoft owns you if they decide to just discontinue DirectX or remove it from Windows or Who know?
Rym: The same time they go?
Scott: it's unlikely.
Rym: I'm saying that's not a great example because that's more like using Like.
Rym: that's a platform for developing and you understand the consequences of the platform these people.
Scott: I'm saying it's obviously that is a low-risk a very low-risk situation, right?
Scott: But the point is you are still.
Scott: there is an extremely tiny but existing risk that you are dependent on.
Rym: Microsoft Congress is gonna make your entire industry illegal.
Scott: That's also always true Right, but the you know, you ought to reduce those risks.
Scott: so don't build something that like.
Scott: if you're making a website using You know, it's okay to integrate with Facebook, right?
Scott: But you probably don't want Facebook connect being your only means of logging in because then Facebook can totally owns your company basically Indirectly.
Scott: you need to also have your own logging in.
Scott: in case Facebook connect dicks you over You can just drop them and your website will still work.
Rym: So speaking of dicks is time for things of the day.
Rym: So I was trying to think oh, wow, that's actually really relevant to your thing of the day.
Scott: Intentionally, I was trying to think of a classic thing of the day, right?
Scott: Cuz I couldn't.
Scott: there have been any new things of the day that aren't College Humor.
Scott: lately.
Rym: We've got College Humor's down right now.
Scott: Is it really because it worked for me a few minutes ago?
Rym: Maybe it just came back out.
Rym: We've got some old classics that we've already done like here born to be alive.
Scott: yeah, I tried to go and look up some classics and figure out if we hadn't done them like Kakugo Jui Chi or push a robot shovel robot secret of space or You know, have we done all your base or belong to us?
Scott: Right?
Scott: and it was like we've done all those things in the day, right?
Scott: I couldn't find any things of the day.
Scott: We haven't used except for one I think and I realized Oh, this is something that is sort of an inside joke and we always bring it up.
Scott: It's horrible It's in the show.
Scott: We bring it up all the time.
Scott: This is one of those people probably don't know what the hell we're talking to.
Rym: You've probably heard us on the show say It's a little bit more obscure than it's goofy time, right?
Scott: So it's like, you know, we say that the dragon does all the time But I don't think most.
Scott: I think pretty sure most people have no idea what we're referring even in our crew.
Rym: About half the crew either don't know what we're talking about.
Rym: a few of them know vaguely what we're talking about in that They know it's a horrifying thing that they don't actually want to see.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Well if you are curious, here's the YouTube video.
Scott: We're gonna reveal the inside joke my year.
Scott: This is what happened during with the dragon.
Scott: and What what the dragon does.
Rym: I'm the dragon.
Rym: this I have made it.
Rym: I just didn't finish it yet, but I'm mashing that up with spike in my little pony.
Rym: Nice.
Scott: That's horrible.
Scott: That's the greatest.
Rym: There's one deeper.
Rym: It's like goofy.
Rym: time is like this level and then under that is the dragon the year.
Rym: You know what's under that?
Scott: Which the Basically there's.
Scott: this is not a thing of the day because we can't actually find it.
Rym: I don't think it's on the internet ride and to my credit trying to find that is a trying process.
Rym: There was like the things you see in Google.
Scott: There was a really really shitty flash animation that was poorly drawn in MS Paint by like a teenager.
Rym: But it started out, you know back when flash animations.
Rym: It was basically just the Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles theme with some kind of mediocre from the year 2000 of they of it.
Rym: and it starts out benign like okay This is lame.
Rym: and then little penises like pop up like for a second.
Rym: You're like was that a penis?
Rym: and you're not sure and then it just goes full tilt from there like Michelangelo Is a party dude and we can't.
Scott: there's a flash animation.
Scott: That's this horrifying Ninja Turtles.
Rym: hard It is the search for this.
Rym: What am I gonna search for?
Rym: horrible Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles gay porn?
Rym: Turn up what I'm looking for.
Scott: No, it doesn't.
Scott: flash animation gay Ninja Turtles Michelangelo party dude sex penis.
Scott: Yeah, does it?
Scott: so that's not a thing of the day because he can't find it.
Rym: But if you find it, you'll get a free GeekNights t-shirt.
Scott: My year with the dragon is a thing of the day.
Scott: and what's rims thing of the day?
Rym: My thing of the day is Emily works with and knows a lot of talented people and she went to the NYU School of Film and Animation.
Rym: so what I have for you and it's a link to our forum post that has three of them in a row.
Rym: Three of her co-workers have three of their animation theses from SVA And they're pretty goddamn bad ass.
Scott: If you don't know SVA is the School of Visual Arts in New York City and basically everyone who goes there is like the best Artist in the world school for visual awesome.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much you go to like mocha festival and there's like just like a row of SVA students and it's like how do you?
Scott: What are they teaching you at this school?
Scott: I have no art skills.
Scott: if I went to this school Would I suddenly be like Van Gogh?
Scott: I don't know how this shit works.
Rym: I have a feeling It's like RIT.
Rym: if you don't already know how to code when you get to RIT You're not coming out knowing how to code.
Scott: Yeah But SVA is some kind of magic.
Scott: everyone who goes there is the best artist ever.
Rym: Naomi George and Eugene Made three videos three animations.
Rym: They're pretty great.
Rym: I'm linking to them.
Scott: How could they if they were you just tell me it doesn't matter who they are.
Scott: So and so what school they go to SVA?
Scott: Yeah, I want to see whatever art they did because it's the best.
Scott: So of course in the meta unless they failed out we're talking about people great.
Scott: I'm sure they're horrible artists who fail out.
Scott: Maybe that's their trick is they just kill everyone.
Scott: Yeah, who's bad?
Scott: Just maintain the reputation.
Rym: So the book club book is still Isaac Asimov's foundation.
Rym: We'll do the show on it at some point.
Rym: the unofficial book Book is the entirety of the Prince of Nothing series by our Scott backer because we're gonna do more shows on it.
Rym: Yeah, that deserves a set of dedicated shows that we could almost make.
Rym: that will be pod.
Scott: We'll be doing shows on it for years.
Rym: Yeah, it's a perennial favorite.
Rym: I don't know what else.
Scott: I should say It's like it's the front row crew book, right?
Scott: It's not that it's not the best fantasy book ever but it's great and it's it, you know, it has special meaning for listeners
Rym: are proving my expectations right because about every month or so Someone will post in the forum or email us and be like, I finally read that fucking our Scott backer book.
Rym: Why'd I wait this long?
Rym: Jesus Christ?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Oh man when ne'er died.
Scott: Yeah Everyone's favorite scene lately is is With it with the Emperor being like yeah your guards are outside mine.
Rym: Oh, that is one of my favorite scenes, too.
Rym: That was an any kiss the Emperor's ring when I read that scene when I first read the book That was the moment when I stopped and went.
Scott: Hells yeah, cuz like they play.
Scott: play the Emperor like he's a crazy, you know, almost like, you know nutty inbred Roman guy.
Scott: But then it's like oh, there's a reason he's still the Emperor and not dead already.
Scott: He's more like with this.
Scott: he's more like a Stalin.
Rym: only should I stack.
Scott: It's more like a Stalin in the paranoia sense and not in the killing everybody's or in the chest.
Rym: I don't think I could behead him the ceremonial sword.
Rym: Isn't that sharp?
Rym: Oh Man that's some good stuff.
Rym: We're gonna be at PAX not prices conference.
Rym: Probably a PAX dev Connecticut will be at not at Otakon, but that's their call not ours.
Scott: Anyway That's enough.
Scott: Oh, let's talk about e-commerce right ram.
Scott: Have you sent t-shirts to everyone who's supposed to get them?
Rym: They're going out actually this week.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Scott: You're a little slow there.
Rym: I am a little slow.
Scott: Did you get the international shipping work?
Rym: Oh, I have two people who request international orders.
Rym: I tested with one of them to see if it would work and it looks like it'll work Alright, so all the people all the people have already posted in the forum or emailed me about international orders.
Rym: Those should go out by Saturday and you'll get an invoice from Google checkout.
Scott: So if somebody can it so can somebody just go to the shop front recruit calm and buy something internationally.
Rym: Well, you want an international shipping of a t-shirt.
Rym: You have to email me.
Scott: Rym at front recruit calm.
Scott: Yep I'll maybe I'll make shop at front recruit calm and make it point to you.
Rym: Yeah, we might have already done something like that.
Rym: I forget what we did with the shot.
Rym: I got a look in the head.
Rym: Anyway, so anyone who has a t-shirt order pending if you don't receive it with within about a week of today then something went wrong.
Scott: Yeah, and then as soon as the merch runs out, we're gonna have about three of them left.
Rym: after I ship the outstanding order We'll get.
Scott: we'll get new merch.
Rym: We got some.
Scott: we'll make it a higher priority.
Rym: Maybe we should make it dragon.
Rym: Let's do it.
Scott: Maybe we could do it in time for not ConnectiCon but PAX West.
Rym: Ah, actually what I want to do for the next PAX East is make GeekNights trading cards.
Scott: We could do that.
Scott: Good getting with all the other trading card people.
Rym: Yeah our buttons I don't know both.
Rym: we can make some buttons for prime we but we always say we'll do that and someone else did it for Us and then it's a month before the car.
Scott: some awesome people.
Rym: I know cuz we're not awesome enough.
Rym: every year I'm like, yeah, I'm gonna make buttons and then it's a week before packs and I'm like, oh right buttons.
Scott: Yeah, anyway, that's enough meta.
Scott: That's enough.
Scott: So game shows Alright, so this status feels like a show we've done before but I extensively searched the archives for a show about TV game shows And I did not find one.
Scott: if this is a repeat.
Scott: I'm sorry.
Scott: Call me out and you are right.
Rym: No, because they people have been requesting repeats.
Rym: We've been planning to do this for a while.
Rym: We just haven't bought.
Scott: but the thing doesn't matter cuz I'm pretty sure it's not a repeat like 99% sure cuz.
Scott: I searched Extensively.
Rym: but one last meta.
Rym: something we were planning to do at some point is go take a particular random old episode of GeekNights From like - nothing you were planning to do not me.
Rym: the listeners want it and I want it.
Rym: I think it'd be cool.
Scott: Yeah, you always want this weird to take a top.
Rym: take a show we did in like 2005 2006 right take the exact same topic Record it again and then you know, listen to the old show and see if our opinions have changed.
Scott: Probably.
Scott: yeah find any show.
Scott: We're like.
Scott: PC gaming is dead Nintendo.
Rym: I disagree.
Rym: we weren't wrong then because then PC gaming was dead.
Rym: I'm just saying it is having a renaissance.
Rym: I'm just saying which we did not say could not happen.
Rym: I'm just saying but I digress now.
Rym: We argued at length before recording this whether or not this was a Tuesday or a Thursday show.
Rym: The reasons why we were doing it on Thursday are one.
Rym: We needed a Thursday show.
Scott: That's right Number.
Scott: that's the number one reason.
Rym: I have some.
Rym: that's the number one answer.
Rym: I have some post-hoc reasons.
Rym: If we were going to do a show on game shows, that was a Tuesday We'd talk more about the mechanics of the shows and the strategy and individual shows in great mechanical detail Mm-hmm, but we're not talking about that.
Rym: We're talking about them as television shows as entertainment as us at home watching.
Scott: That's a post-hoc.
Scott: Excuse the real it's.
Scott: the real reason is we need Thursday shows.
Rym: I did not say it was not a post-hoc excuse.
Rym: In fact, I already had that disclaimer there.
Rym: I'm just saying me I'm the king of post-hoc trash talk.
Scott: That is right.
Scott: So you're you're in fact not the king of No, you're the god of post-hoc trash talk.
Scott: you go down.
Scott: it's like Thor lightning.
Scott: Mm-hmm Rym.
Scott: post-hoc trash talk.
Scott: Scott giant penises.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: It's very rare that I will say I'm gonna win this game before the game.
Rym: I rarely will pull the Babe Ruth and point out over the outfield After the game's over.
Rym: I'll be like.
Rym: I knew I was gonna win the whole time.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Anyway, so so TV game shows.
Scott: it's weird.
Scott: We were when we were preparing for this show Which we spent about five minutes on.
Rym: we went to Wikipedia and found a list of TV game shows And I right-clicked on every one that I watched and I clicked on like 30 game show.
Scott: I couldn't figure out it's like.
Scott: I didn't Realize it until now just like how much I liked TV game shows.
Scott: when I watch TV It's like I didn't like.
Scott: I didn't realize that was actually sort of a moderate to major Geekery of mine because I didn't even it was just.
Scott: it's just sort of like always there.
Scott: the same way that like when I was A kid Disney afternoon was like always there and I wasn't like.
Scott: you asked me if I was a big fan of it I would have been like no, it's just the thing I Every goddamn day it was on.
Scott: yeah, so it's like game shows.
Scott: I realized just now just within the past hour that they're one of those things that I just sort of always watched.
Scott: Never felt like I was a big fan.
Scott: I've never you know Expressed never wore t-shirts about them or bought merch for them or anything like that to be on them desperately.
Scott: Oh, yeah, of course cuz I knew if I was on the Price is Right.
Scott: I was gonna kill I was gonna win everything.
Rym: Oh my god Legend of the Hidden Temple.
Scott: I know I'd win all that when that to watch that guard out Nick arcade Win that shit, but when Nick arcade Nick and broken anyway, it's true, but I would have done better than those punk kids.
Scott: But it's like I didn't realize that I was actually such a big fan of them.
Scott: and there's like so many that I liked and watched Frequently.
Scott: and it's actually kind of sad because even though I don't watch TV now I realize just from what I know, you know I guess from being one or two spaces away from TV that most there aren't really that many game shows Left.
Scott: a lot of them are changed and aren't what they want to work.
Scott: Well to think this one to a lot of reality shows now are actually game shows that they just call reality show.
Rym: Well, that's what I noticed when I was looking through the list.
Rym: It's that there was like this Boom of game shows in the 60s and another boom in the 80s.
Rym: and then in the 90s There was like this weird like side boom where all the game shows got very slick but also very gimmicky and less gamey.
Rym: Yeah, and it was we and like I remember this whole era of that like remember who wants to be a millionaire?
Rym: Like these very high production value game shows that were actually less Entertaining to me as game shows.
Scott: Yeah, like the like, you know, there are the things that were still game shows, right?
Scott: Like let's make not let's meet it.
Rym: Let's make a deal is like my face.
Scott: What's the one with the suitcases?
Scott: Oh dealer no deal and I knew I had the workshop I knew I had the word deal in it, but now I learned about that show.
Rym: This is how disconnected I am from from television reality now, you know back because it's an arcade machine.
Scott: No, I knew about pen radio How he was on pen radio.
Rym: Yeah, he talked about how he hated the game and was tricked into being on it as the host and then he liked it.
Rym: Yep but anyway Look at that game show Dealer no deal and it's like.
Rym: alright the optimal strategy Basically involves ignoring what anyone says and choosing randomly and then stopping when you've either won enough money or have a possibility of winning enough Money.
Scott: Yep, that there was a guy in a Forum that I frequent right who was on a more recent episode of who wants to be a millionaire And he just went on and answered questions and he made it to like 60k or something like that.
Scott: And he's just like, you know what?
Scott: I'm stopping.
Rym: I would do that.
Scott: I was like I was like hell.
Scott: I went in the forum and I was like cuz.
Scott: he posted a YouTube bit of his appearance And I was like dude, you're the awesomest you did the smartest thing ever.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Don't go over the million dollars.
Scott: What kind of moron are you?
Scott: it's like 60,000 for 15 minutes work and there's a risk if you keep going that you're gonna lose it all.
Scott: How would you possibly not stop and take the money home?
Rym: So that's game theory and mechanism design.
Scott: Okay, the psychology the mechanisms, but they also have psychology of the sets.
Scott: It's like a casino right where the the the audio video lighting of the of the place Yeah makes you do.
Scott: they're trying to trick you into doing certain behaviors and the guy totally didn't fall for it.
Scott: Anyway, yeah, so what I think the my favoritest game show of all time?
Rym: Oh the one that we have to break this up because there's favoritest and there's also most watched.
Scott: Well, I think they're both the same.
Rym: price is right.
Rym: Absolutely.
Scott: Yeah, whenever I was home from school at 11 o'clock I'd watch the price is right and watch lunch if I was home for school from school for any reason.
Rym: Reruns of the price is right.
Scott: It doesn't matter.
Rym: It's not like you can remember the episode Yeah, and I remember thinking as a kid that I was really good at it.
Rym: And I think nowadays I would be terrible at it.
Scott: Well, the problem is is that a lot of the products that you to know the price of right are probably they wonder the manufacturers suggested retail price.
Rym: as a kid for some reason I always knew when I finally figured out why a Lot of the stuff which things were things you've seen grocery stores and in malls.
Rym: Yeah, I spent a lot of time as a kid in grocery stores following my parents around buying stuff.
Rym: But the point is that because you never pay manufacturer suggested retail price but MSRP was usually listed on the labels of things and because I was a bored kid who Couldn't walk and play my game gear at the same time because the battery only lasted like 10 minutes.
Rym: Anyway, I was reading everything that I could read because I just I needed something.
Scott: My the reason I knew the prices is because I watch the prices right a lot and I didn't actually know prices of things in Stores.
Scott: and then when I you know now I sort of know the prices because I buy things I credit the price is right with a very important like first step toward game theory mastery.
Rym: when I was a little kid I learned how to be.
Scott: you knew when to bid $1.
Rym: because one day when I was watching the show one day and someone bid a Dollar and I was like what and then it dawned on me Yeah, and then I learned a lot from watching that show.
Rym: and I remember one day a guy bid $1.
Rym: He was the second to last person.
Scott: the second guy bid the last guy bid $2.
Rym: Yep And the first guy like the guy who bid $1 didn't seem to understand what his mistake was.
Scott: Come on old ladies wouldn't even make that mistake and old ladies can spin the wheel.
Rym: Yeah You know usually makes the worst mistakes.
Rym: were the the people who are in there like 30s 40s who are these super Excitable like Bob Barker's there and they're just like.
Scott: Yeah, they fuck up all the time.
Scott: but the other thing about that show right is the thing I actually like the most.
Scott: for all the weird games like Plinko or Punching the holes to grab the money.
Rym: I always like the mountain climber.
Rym: We got a mountain climber.
Rym: Ah, I like this because a surprising number of people were so stupid.
Rym: They let him fall off the top.
Scott: Oh, yeah, I don't understand that.
Scott: at least if you're gonna Go to the top stop.
Scott: I'm at the very.
Scott: it was a tiny tiny chance.
Scott: You could be right.
Rym: I guess I like the show because it was a real like.
Rym: it was a test of knowledge and skill Mostly skill.
Rym: it wasn't that random.
Scott: Yeah, there was.
Scott: you know, I mean the mini golf game right you the putt.
Scott: You actually just had the fucking putt.
Rym: I love how he would always putt and he'd always get it in.
Scott: I of course, you know, he practiced it.
Scott: But you know, he's avid golfer.
Rym: Did you see happy Gilmore?
Scott: Yeah prices, right was the shit?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I think as I nowadays I don't know if it's the shit anymore.
Scott: I mean we.
Scott: I remember I had a thing of the day once Whatever.
Rym: It's just Bob Barker was so perfect in that role.
Scott: He's the best guy.
Scott: Little microphone No one no one can touch.
Scott: the original price is right.
Scott: It's just like the untouchable best game show there ever was.
Rym: it was also funny.
Rym: It had this good mix of just everything going for it.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: It's like, you know, it didn't even matter, you know.
Scott: It wasn't like a competition between people like jeopardy where there's winners and losers after in the showcase showdown.
Scott: Yeah, but even then you're in the showcase.
Scott: that means you won something.
Rym: Yeah Well, there's there's a split in game shows to between.
Rym: there's some game shows especially older game shows.
Rym: where?
Rym: Winner takes a whole bunch of stuff home and the loser gets buckets.
Rym: Yeah, but now I'll like dealer no deal.
Rym: There are shows where the odds are.
Rym: if you get on the show in the first place.
Rym: You've already won You're already gonna get a whole pile of money.
Rym: It's just a matter of how much money you get.
Scott: I mean even shows.
Scott: if you ever watch like double dare, right?
Scott: You'd always you didn't pay.
Scott: really pay so much attention to this, but I do remember it.
Scott: It's like you'd watch and one family be eliminated and be like and then there would be like this announcement Totally ignore.
Scott: their parting gift is a bunch of bicycles or their parting gift is a bunch of video games Because those were all ads.
Scott: those are all ads paid for by the people giving out the prizes obviously But you know, it's like you didn't pay attention to it.
Scott: But there were parting gifts for pretty much everyone who lost at every stage of the way same thing on legends of hidden temple Every part every kid that was eliminated.
Scott: the more stages you went in the prizes got better Better and better.
Scott: So it's like if you had eliminated immediately in the water crossing part You got like some video tapes and if you got to the next part you maybe got a bicycle.
Scott: and if you won Then you won like a trip.
Rym: so they don't just like take you out back.
Scott: Yeah, you won like a trip.
Scott: you wouldn't like a trip, you know back to Florida again or something like that.
Rym: You know, I think you know I price is right.
Rym: I watched the most and I got the most total enjoyment out of it.
Rym: just cuz I watched so much of it But really I enjoyed.
Rym: let's make a deal a lot more really you think?
Scott: so cuz I actually didn't watch that all that much.
Scott: I've only watched it maybe like less less than 30 times the host and the psychology of it.
Rym: Monty Hall was just a genius and it was.
Scott: he was indeed a genius.
Rym: There's something about that like, you know, there's different eras of comedy.
Rym: There's a certain level of this kind of.
Rym: I'm a game show host from the 70s 80s or early 90s Especially like early 80s mid 80s and late 70s.
Rym: that just is different from other kinds of game show hosts.
Rym: The only part of it is a certain amount of snark and a certain amount of like.
Rym: we know we're taking the piss But we're doing this anyway.
Scott: the only part of the show though that really stands out for me is like the great part was when he would go into the Audience and be like I'll treat you who's got like a coffee cup.
Scott: Yeah, you know and people would start bringing weird shit just in case he would say that, you know Anyway, I got a handkerchief.
Scott: you got a handkerchief.
Scott: All right you I will trade you such-and-such for the handkerchief.
Rym: So Scott, do you remember the mathematical solution to the Monty Hall of question?
Rym: No, do you remember the Monty Hall problem?
Rym: No, what do you always do is give you a choice of three doors, I know the three doors Yeah, so you pick one, right?
Rym: Yep, and then you could either know and then he'd reveal one of them Mm-hmm, and then he'd be like you want to switch?
Rym: Yeah, so there's an absolute answer whether or not you should switch.
Scott: Well, it depends what he revealed.
Scott: What if you revealed like the best thing ever?
Scott: Of course, I'll take it.
Rym: No, if you reveal all that anyway So well you should look up the Wikipedia not you but you the audience of GeekNights the Monty Hall problem.
Rym: because Don't like spoil it for yourself.
Rym: Just read on the internet what the question is.
Rym: See if you can work out the answer for yourself and then read the answer because you know what all those game theory books I Bought that's all they do.
Rym: Here's the problem.
Rym: solve it then they're like, here's the answer.
Rym: Here's the man Isn't it?
Scott: You should always switch no matter what.
Scott: I don't want to spoil it for the people But the point is if he reveals something that's like the best thing ever.
Scott: How could you not go to it?
Scott: It's like You know, it all depends on what's revealed.
Rym: You should read how the Monty Hall question works.
Rym: But anyway, I like to snort like the match game.
Scott: Yeah match game was.
Scott: the match game wasn't really about winning It was just about the humor of making That level like that kind of.
Rym: I'm a game show host except it's a whole bunch of people all playing that game.
Scott: Yep Yeah, it's weird.
Scott: It's like, you know every.
Scott: even though these game shows all all they really have in common is that you had people Competing in some sort of way doing something to win prizes, right even you know Like stuff that didn't even really seem like it was a game show like Takeshi's Castle like you can't win There's.
Rym: there's no winner except the audience, right?
Rym: You know, I really like Takeshi's Castle.
Scott: it's pretty much people do something.
Scott: then there's a potential prize.
Scott: But really the goal was to make Entertainment right?
Scott: It was crafting a game where spectating was you know?
Scott: the Sports sort of have this right but sports also tend to try to make a competition and Entertainment.
Scott: at the same time and a lot of times, you know Like a game will be boring because it was just a bad game.
Scott: But a game show is pretty much a crafted experience to always be entertaining.
Scott: Here's the game fail.
Rym: Here's an idea.
Rym: game shows are entertainment, right?
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I Think someone should do now they kind of do this with reality TV, but I say make a straight-up game show.
Rym: That and you know ahead of time it's not you hide it.
Rym: It's like a basically professional wrestling of a game show a staged all Actors game show.
Rym: that itself is basically a comedy drama.
Scott: You know what it is for wrestling.
Scott: No, you know it is.
Scott: It's called the gong show.
Rym: Oh the gong show.
Scott: Hey, dude, you go up and you perfect who can entertain.
Rym: Was not that the gong show was more of a sort of like talent competition?
Scott: Yeah, exactly, but it was all about being able to entertain the audience.
Rym: People like it like it made like.
Rym: the reason the match game worked is that it was all people who were good at that.
Rym: They were good actors They had jokes ready and it was basically the game show was just kind of like the setting For this comedy of all these people.
Scott: well Hollywood Squares is the same thing also exactly.
Rym: But someone should go one step further and not like make a straight-up Fabricated game show that is a TV show because the gimmick of that alone would probably make it weirdly retro popular on TV.
Scott: Well, they do have.
Scott: there are some reality shows that like only have famous people on them or at least semi-famous people, right?
Scott: So that's you know, a reality show.
Scott: most reality shows aren't actually reality shows.
Scott: They're game shows, right?
Scott: Like look at Survivor, right?
Scott: Like I've never actually watched Survivor, but I know how it works.
Scott: They put people on an island and make them do certain game show.
Rym: Yes, basically, what would you do?
Scott: Yeah, it's like alright everyone.
Scott: now you have to eat now you have to eat nasty bugs and it's like wait a minute.
Scott: That's not reality.
Scott: That's a game show and then you know The person who's left at the end is the winner and they win a prize.
Scott: That's a game show.
Scott: If it was a reality show it would be we're dumping you on an island that has hidden cameras everywhere.
Scott: You can do anything you want except tamper with the cameras.
Scott: Whoever's alive.
Scott: That's a reality show.
Scott: Yeah, a game show.
Scott: everything is so scripted and this you know specific tasks you have to achieve and prizes.
Scott: That's a game show.
Rym: I Really really liked Family Feud - Family Feud is alright.
Scott: I like playing.
Rym: Family Feud is the best one to play but to actually Watch it is okay.
Rym: I actually really like playing the old NES SNES versions of it.
Scott: I like it when we set up one to do anime Family Feud at an at a you know Anime Club or oh my god, this is kind of a tangent, but it's a tragedy.
Rym: but back at RIT anime, right?
Rym: we used to run Family Feud, but it was anime Feud and Because fanboy feud.
Rym: Yep, because the people in this anime club actually Watched anime unlike people who go to anime conventions.
Rym: We had some pretty inside baseball questions and topics and people would do surprisingly Well, like if it was something like I don't know How many episodes is an anime on average people in like.
Rym: the top answer is 26 13?
Rym: Like people would give answers that made sense.
Rym: We try to run Fanboy feud equivalents and match games at modern anime conventions and we'll be like name a Pokemon and people that whisper to me as the host.
Scott: They're like, what's Pokemon?
Rym: Yeah, we're like name a character from anime who eats too much and they'll be like, uh Pikachu Gee couldn't think of any character.
Scott: He's too much even though pretty much every anime has 10 Cuz Eating is their favorite joke.
Rym: But family feud I also enjoyed because people would give some dumb fucking answers.
Scott: Well, I don't care about the dumb answers.
Scott: what I always cared about were the slip-up answers.
Scott: You can always see these on YouTube, which is why I don't need to watch Family Feud.
Scott: But it's like, you know name something's on grandma.
Scott: People always accidentally give a match game answer when they're on Family Feud.
Rym: I love how match game it was.
Rym: it would quote unquote accidentally like they say something raunchy when really if you look at the questions They were all pre-scripted to do nothing but make as much reference to sex as they could without getting in trouble.
Scott: Yeah, the family feud thing was like name something that the last thing a burglar wants to see is when he breaks into a house naked.
Rym: grandma Used to watch wheel of fortune, but it made me feel really smart and made me really not like other people.
Scott: Yeah wheel of fortune is.
Rym: I don't think it's that great Pat Sajak, yeah for some reason I like Pat Sajak really I don't.
Scott: I really actually kind of didn't like him.
Scott: I mean, he's not like a bad guy, but it's like the way he came off.
Scott: He didn't come up as like he was like excited came off as one.
Rym: It's a job.
Rym: Yeah - he's better than these people and he is being degraded by doing this show.
Rym: Yeah, that is why I liked him because you could see all of that through his fake smile.
Scott: Yeah, but see Alex Trebek was the same sort of way, but it's like I hear he's actually a huge jerk.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I just that's what I hear but Fit the feel of jeopardy.
Rym: Pat Sajak fit the pathetic miss of wheel of fortune.
Scott: They definitely do fit their shows but that just because they've done those shows actually.
Rym: because if you want look at you to ever for like wheel of fortune fail because Pat Sajak couldn't like rip into someone who was stupid.
Rym: So when someone gave like amazingly Disastrous answers or they guess like X when there's only one spot left in afraid he would always like kind of make this smile and be like Like he'd sigh on the inside like a part of him died.
Rym: Yeah, and then he'd be like Frayed.
Rym: that doesn't quite cut it or nope.
Scott: Nope You're spitting so-and-so number three.
Rym: I never liked jeopardy though.
Rym: I'll be honest.
Scott: Well, I mean jeopardy is sort of you know, it's got its good Little kid.
Rym: I never knew the answers.
Scott: It's got good parts and bad parts, right?
Scott: You know, it's like it was weird cuz like you'd.
Scott: either you know You crush a category or you wouldn't.
Scott: or to be about something so obscure That's like only some genius guy.
Rym: Well, once I learned how they prepare people for jeopardy and how the selection process works as a kid I was one much less impressed very much less impressive once I saw learned the buzzer matters a lot more than you know The answer.
Rym: and even as a kid I hated the fact that you couldn't just buzz in early and then as when I got into high school and join quiz bowl I hated it even more.
Scott: Yeah But yeah, you know jeopardy is it's sort of fun because you couldn't.
Scott: you know, it's like you can play along at home.
Scott: But then why not just do Trivial Pursuit?
Rym: or why not play jeopardy on the SNES?
Scott: Because you run out of answers.
Scott: like I had I had junior jeopardy for the NES.
Scott: I learned over time.
Scott: I learned every single answer.
Rym: I had wheel of fortune the board game.
Rym: My cousin's had that had this huge board with this complicated mechanism for loading up the the phrases and these clickers.
Rym: Yep, it was a surprisingly complex game.
Scott: my cousin with my cousin's also had jeopardy.
Scott: the board game Is.
Scott: I never understood why you needed a board game?
Rym: It's weird.
Rym: I watched a lot of shows kind of half-assed Lee like I watch anything.
Scott: when you're watching a game show It's like you never really give it your full attention.
Rym: Yeah, like I'd always watch win lose or draw just because it was on before golden girls, which I watch.
Scott: Yeah, you know We always watch like wheel of fortune in jeopardy because they were on before or after the evening news.
Scott: On in the kitchen they're eating during dinner, you know I watched Price is Right because it was on after the early morning cartoons and I was home from school and I was eating lunch.
Scott: Yeah, and you know, I couldn't play video games while holding a sandwich but like finders keepers.
Rym: I hate it.
Rym: I thought it was a stupid like.
Scott: really I actually kind of like that one.
Rym: I didn't like it mostly because it I always caught that tail end of it and it was toward the end of its run.
Rym: So it looked kind of chintzy compared to it shows that came on after.
Scott: it did look chintzy But the thing I liked about it was all was pretty much the tear apart the room looking for shit part.
Scott: The other parts didn't really care about but it wasn't that that was even great entertainment.
Scott: It's just at that age.
Scott: I really wanted to do that like a part of room.
Scott: Yeah, go into some fake room that was full of shit and tear it apart looking for something That was actually actually well hidden But not it was like not so hidden that you could never find much better than the find the flag in the goop on double dare.
Rym: That was my.
Scott: that was Yeah, double dare was so hit or miss with like.
Rym: some of the challenges were really good challenges and some of them were just Sort of broken, but it was funny because when they were broken It's like everyone on the set knew it was broken and laughed about it.
Rym: Yeah, like it was like Oh, wow, those you can't really actually throw those chickens.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, you know, they sling, you know use the the slingshot to get the eggs in the bowl.
Scott: It's like you get half an egg in the bowl.
Scott: you won because no one could possibly do that.
Rym: at least Double dare the questions looking back.
Rym: I remember again really hating the kids up there who never knew the answers to anything.
Scott: I don't know why double dare even bothered with the questions.
Scott: They should just done physical challenges all the time Yeah and they should.
Rym: it had like three levels every now and then you'd see like there'd be a smart kid or like two smart kids and They were just answer every question to do no physical challenges and win.
Scott: But at least but at least on double dare the obstacle course always actually worked pretty well.
Rym: Oh my god, I want that to be the omegathon finale.
Scott: I don't like obstacle course like the hidden temple where incompetent people would just go in and be like derp derp derp.
Scott: No one really derped the double dare Obstacle course, they would just physically fail.
Scott: Yeah, they wouldn't derp it out of losing.
Scott: You know not knowing what the fuck to do I
Rym: always was vaguely like I wanted to be on double dare because some of the things were really crazy And I just wanted to do them like the the bubble gum Machine where you jump into the top and like just fall through that funnel.
Scott: Yeah Some of them were pretty good.
Scott: You know some of the most fun ones like were the ones you stayed clean was like the big The the gopher wheel or the hurt the hamster hamster wheel.
Scott: Yeah Well, there's a hamster maze also the wheel where you just run in the wheel enough to get out all the way through.
Scott: But then some of the ones that were actually tricky like here is a slippery surface covered in like chocolate syrup make it to the Other end.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: I was like, oh, yeah, let's do that.
Scott: But yeah, man there was a. it's weird because there was like this whole job.
Scott: It was like two genres like the whole kids game shows versus the adult game shows.
Scott: But I watched both even though it was the same age Yeah And I watched a lot of reruns.
Rym: and like when I was little I watched like press your luck Mm-hmm, and I didn't even pay attention to it enough to really understand the rules.
Rym: I just watched it.
Scott: Yeah, all I remember is no, I mean, oh, let me hit the button at the right time The little whammy animation would happen.
Scott: Yeah, it was always fun to watch the way of animation.
Rym: Yeah, it's weird It's kind of like I want.
Rym: when I was really young I watched game shows the same way that I played video games.
Rym: Wasn't really trying to win or paying attention?
Rym: just kind of doing what kids do not 100% sent you.
Scott: Well, I mean I was.
Scott: I wasn't trying to win because like I wasn't playing but I was yelling by the time the Hidden Temple was On.
Scott: I was yelling.
Scott: I was like, are you stupid?
Scott: How could you not know how to put together the fucking silver monkey, you know Why have you not even watched this show if I was there?
Rym: I'm Scott if
Scott: my partner failed to put together the silver monkey and then when they came out of there I want to punch them in the face so hard kicked him right in the junk
Rym: Silver
Scott: my I would have taken the silver monkey and shoved it right down his throat like you cost me fucking trip to.
Scott: oh my god I kill you being slightly older.
Rym: I at least know now that they filmed it all in one go So the kids on it couldn't have seen it.
Scott: I'm just saying in the second end by season two then in season two You should have fucking known how to put together the silver fucking monkey.
Rym: worse than that I think and I hate amazing me that I'll say it was worse than that where the kids on Nick arcade.
Rym: They just like kids you've never played a video game in their lives The final battle where you go inside the video game and it was that crappy blue screen.
Rym: Yeah kids just like didn't listen to the host at all.
Rym: He'd be like like this one this one video I watched again recently because I remembered it from my childhood.
Rym: there's this one kid and He's one.
Rym: all he has to do is reach up and touch something Yeah, and there's like 20 seconds left with all the monsters pause before they start up again.
Rym: He just kind of stands there like looking around and the guy's like all you have to do Come on, just put your hand up.
Rym: all you just put just grab it all you.
Rym: I'll just put your head and then the kid dies and loses.
Rym: He's like, ah, you gave it your best.
Scott: That was your best.
Scott: kill yourself, where's that kid now?
Rym: There's no way.
Scott: he made an interview him on nerd alert.
Scott: They seem to love interviewing people who are like, you know, we should suggest that.
Scott: But anyway, I never liked like.
Scott: I remember it was a busy.
Scott: It's just frustrating in general, right?
Scott: Even if it's not a game show to watch somebody fail at something that is so easy for you yourself to do Right, even if you're just watching someone play Mario 1 and they run to the first Goomba.
Scott: It's just frustrated babies.
Rym: You can't swing this high.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, you know You watch someone try to ride a bicycle and they just keep falling over and it's like oh, come on.
Scott: Really?
Scott: Come on.
Scott: Or watch someone swimming in a pool in the drowning.
Scott: It's like really kick.
Scott: Is it kick?
Scott: Kick.
Rym: I guess what bothered me the most wasn't the uncommon.
Rym: so simple because that was more that was entertaining to be so angry at these children But it was.
Rym: I hated the game shows when I realized that there was no skill involved or that the initial rounds didn't matter.
Rym: Anything that had a poorly designed game?
Scott: Really bothered me like yeah, cuz like you'd watch something like guts right and some of the things on guts.
Scott: Well, actually like pretty cool, you know, like the obstacle course part None of it mattered.
Rym: the agro Craig was worth more points than fucking anything.
Scott: I know that we had to get to the agro Craig, right?
Scott: Yeah, but hey, but there were other things that were kind of boring Like like bungee jump basketball.
Scott: It's like alright boring.
Scott: Why do they even have that here?
Scott: You know, it should have been more like American gladiators Was on right after Saturday morning cartoons and right before pro wrestling and it was the perfect cross between the two.
Scott: I love that shit so much because it was the closest thing.
Rym: But all those gladiators run roids so much to gladiatorial combat the fact that it was direct direct fucking competition.
Rym: It was the kind of thing that you always wanted to do I mean as a kid.
Scott: even then some of the games are more entertaining than some of the others are like joust was the shit?
Scott: Yes, but like put.
Scott: you know, the volleyballs in the basket.
Scott: That was okay, but it wasn't as good as you know, the cages into the things was great.
Scott: That was okay.
Scott: It was okay.
Rym: I also like the one where you had to get on the the hanging suspended rings and make your way across Because no one ever made it across and they grab you with their legs.
Rym: Just pull you down.
Scott: Oh the one where you had to there was the sea of And the guy was coming after you.
Scott: Yeah, I seen it.
Scott: The thing is it was so awesome at American gladiators when there's a hard game like that and the the the competitor was just so Good, they actually did it.
Scott: It was like fuck.
Scott: Yeah, look at that guy.
Scott: He totally did it and it was the thing about American gladiators.
Scott: It was sort of like You know that the the Japanese thing.
Scott: what's it called?
Rym: Takeshi's castle?
Scott: No, the one that Nagano won.
Scott: Yeah, what the hell is that?
Rym: Ninja warrior?
Scott: Yeah, but it's it's what's it really called because it begins with an S. I'm gonna look it up real quick.
Scott: Okay, Sasuke It's sort of like it was.
Scott: Sasuke was like designed to be really impossible But American gladiator was like, you know Sasuke is also on your own.
Scott: It's like what can you do on your own?
Scott: but American gladiator was like versus Sasuke against these Steroid lunatics and I really like direct competition.
Scott: Yes, but also the games were less ridiculous.
Scott: It's like they were balls hard, but they weren't impossible hard.
Scott: My favorite I think was the one with the guns and you had yeah, you had to go from station to station shooting different pieces of
Rym: No one almost almost no one ever hit with anything and had to get all the way to the end like throw the grenades up There the
Scott: tennis balls.
Scott: Yep I loved it though in something you would shoot the gladiator to disrupt them right with that with like the the air-powered like missile.
Scott: But I was always impressed when somebody would just go up there grab the first weapon and shoot the target and be like dang.
Scott: And he'd be like, yeah, that's right bitches yep, but I love they always gave me that last chance to escape and That tennis ball that the gladiator shot you with had to hurt us like oh my god.
Rym: I saw a replay where hit a guy on an ankle.
Rym: He had a bruise.
Rym: That was it was amazing.
Scott: Yeah, you'd sue if that game show still exists.
Scott: But yeah, no man there was Like.
Scott: it's so surprising.
Scott: It's like you don't realize it, but there were so many of these game shows And I liked almost all of them.
Rym: I mean as wild and crazy kids that was.
Scott: I didn't like it that much.
Scott: I watched it cuz it was on my watch.
Rym: It was on before.
Scott: something like It was on when you got home from school and it actually was.
Scott: they were only a few episodes and they showed him over and over again.
Rym: Uh Who can forget the acapella ditty?
Rym: from where in the world is Carmen Sandiego?
Scott: Yeah, people forget that that was a game show.
Scott: right the game show was actually the first thing and it was the biggest thing.
Scott: But everyone remembers like the video game and mostly now.
Scott: but the game show was actually really great.
Rym: Just the music the cast was funny They had a high production values for what it was.
Scott: and that was yet again the kids were stupid.
Scott: yet again the frustrating Final event where you had to put the sticks on the countries and because I had watched the show I knew every fucking country.
Scott: And these kids just didn't fucking know it.
Scott: and it was the worst thing.
Scott: kids didn't even know.
Scott: it's like their own state.
Scott: It was like you just need to go die in a fire.
Scott: You don't know.
Scott: you got us map is your final challenge.
Scott: It's not like they gave you.
Scott: you know Africa or Asia right you got us state and you failed it.
Scott: you suck.
Scott: Anyway, yeah game shows made of win.
Scott: we need to.
Scott: I think we need to bring back more of the these older game shows and Less of the reality shows.
Rym: I just want more.
Rym: I want different kinds of game shows.
Rym: I want unique stuff I want like the Monopoly game.
Scott: That's awful.
Rym: I loved Monopoly the board game as a kid when I was stupid and I heard oh There's gonna be in a Monopoly game show and I was just excited.
Scott: I really wanted to watch it.
Scott: real bad.
Rym: the opening theme Oh and oh P o ly and I'm halfway through it and I realized that at no point the skill or Intelligence have anything to do with who win.
Scott: I really wanted to watch and I was able to watch it like once or twice.
Scott: I don't remember how it worked But like it was something about the timing of it or like it got replaced with other shows so quickly because it was so bad I didn't get to see it that much.
Scott: But yeah, it's like I really wanted to watch it very badly.
Scott: You know when I was when I knew it was coming out?
Rym: Oh, well, so Scott I had to get the years before I called you on this.
Rym: You said that Carmen Sandiego the game show was the first.
Rym: Carmen Sandiego was I wrong?
Rym: you're wrong so hard.
Scott: Oh my god, I can't believe that because I was.
Scott: I was very.
Scott: I was so sure.
Rym: show debuted in 1991.
Scott: I was so sure that all of the video games and everything else were based on the game show on TV.
Scott: Yeah, really?
Scott: I guess I was totally wrong.
Rym: You're wrong.
Scott: Why did the first video game come out?
Rym: So, alright, so the program aired on PBS.
Rym: Yep from 1991 until 1995.
Rym: All right, the first video game came out.
Rym: Well, it was proposed in 1983 and The first game came out in 1985.
Rym: Oh, I fail.
Scott: I Can't believe.
Scott: that's weird.
Rym: It's not that weird.
Scott: It's weird.
Scott: It's Broderbund Yeah, but it's like.
Scott: the thing is is like the these.
Scott: the format of the video game and the format of the gate of the Game show are actually so similar That I was so sure that the video game was based off the game show because
Rym: it was very rare For a game show based on anything to in any way resemble the thing it was based on Mm-hmm.
Rym: That's why some of the best video games were.
Scott: the Game shows were the ones that weren't based on yeah I guess you could categorize game shows right just things that were based on other things and things that were based on nothing like prices.
Scott: Right isn't based on anything, but there was a game show for Scrabble.
Scott: remember that It was actually pretty bad hit a really bad time slot but like $100,000 pyramid was based on nothing Yeah, you know except itself.
Rym: That was all right getting Egypt.
Scott: But yeah, I guess I think the best game shows though if I think back are the ones that are based on nothing but themselves.
Rym: Yeah, they're also the ones that either were Contrived like match game where we're basically just funny the whole time.
Rym: Yeah ones that were actual games Mm-hmm.
Scott: We need to we need to come up with something, you know We'll see hopper.
Scott: There are.
Scott: yeah, there's also those video games like you don't know Jack Which is sort of like a game show that didn't exist one verse 100.
Scott: That was an actual game.
Scott: Yeah, that was only those in software form.
Scott: Yeah, I never got to play it sadly.
Rym: Oh well This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.