Rym: It's Wednesday, September 14th, 2011.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, some final thoughts on Madoka Magica.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Also known as...
Scott: Well, Mr.
Rym: Say-The-Full-Name-Of-The-Show.
Scott: I was being sarcastic.
Rym: What is the full name of the show, Scott?
Scott: Puella Magi Madoka Magica.
Scott: Alright, alright.
Scott: But the point is that you usually put too many words in the opening.
Scott: And I'm always like, you could have said that with less words.
Scott: So this time I was pulling a reverse for the funny.
Scott: I was saying, "Why don't you use more
Scott: words?".
Rym: Now, therefore, what's going on here, the incentive for me is to ignore anything you say about the opener.
Scott: The incentive for me is to pester and troll with a face that's like,
Scott: "Ayyy.".
Scott: You mad?
Scott: You mad, bro?
Scott: You mad, co-host?
Rym: So anyway, we actually started the show tonight a little late because I got my new bike.
Rym: But as is typical with any bike shop in the world, and car mechanics, anything, when they say, oh, they leave a voicemail saying, "Hey, it'll be done.
Rym: Come by any time after
Rym: X.".
Rym: Whatever X time is.
Rym: It will not be done if you show up five minutes after X. It will never be done when they say it was done.
Rym: Because they don't think you'll be there when they say it was done.
Scott: Really?
Scott: My laundry, they said it would have been done at five, and I got it at five.
Scott: And by the way, did I tell the story on the show?
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: Anyway, so both laundry machines in my building were out of order.
Scott: So I'm like, shit, I gotta go to the laundromat.
Scott: But then I realized, shit, if I go to the laundromat, it's not like it's in my building.
Scott: I have to sit there and watch the laundry.
Scott: It's not like a college where you can go into dorms or you can go back to your apartment or your dorm and go back to the laundromat.
Scott: You gotta sit there with the clothes.
Rym: Granted, occasionally, even in dorms, going back to the room meant you'd come back and find all your clothes in a heap wet because some jackass decided they wanted to use the dryer.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Well, it depends on how.
Scott: I always use them at down, not peak times when there was less competition.
Scott: But anyway, in laundromat, a public one, you know, it's a real place of business.
Scott: You got to sit there with the clothes.
Scott: And I'm like, fuck me, it's Sunday.
Scott: I want to watch football.
Scott: I do not want to sit here.
Scott: Thanks to the watch clothes spin around in a circle.
Scott: So I was like, wait a minute.
Scott: Laundry service.
Scott: Oh, shit.
Scott: Life of luxury.
Scott: You give someone money, which I have extra, and they do your fucking laundry for you and they fucking fold it.
Scott: I was like, oh, shit, son, doing this.
Scott: So I did that.
Scott: It was like 30 pounds of laundry because I don't do laundry until all my clothes are dirty.
Scott: And it cost me like twenty six dollars or whatever.
Scott: And you know what?
Scott: They did a really great job and they folded my freaking clothes for me.
Scott: But yeah, there were only two negatives.
Scott: Well, and a positive.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So negative.
Scott: Well, that's actually one negative and a positive.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Whatever.
Scott: The point is, the only thing they did do that I did not like was they used fabric softener, which made my clothes smell.
Scott: And it wasn't a bad smell.
Rym: Never use fabric softener.
Scott: It wasn't a bad smell.
Scott: It was, you know, but it wasn't a good smell either.
Scott: It was sort of a laundry smell.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like my clothes smell like laundromat, you know, and I don't use fabric softener.
Scott: So it's like a smell that was used to keep going.
Rym: But just so you know, this is fascinating.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But the benefit was fabric softener actually made my clothes real soft, which is like fascinating.
Scott: It was.
Scott: And if your laundry machines are out of order, I highly recommend laundry service, especially when it's like right next door to your apartment to carry the clothes that far.
Rym: But anyway, I got my new bike and it's pretty fucking awesome.
Rym: Yeah, it was a way fast.
Rym: Great.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: OK.
Rym: I got here from Avenue C and 14th Street in like 16 minutes.
Scott: What bike shop did you go to?
Scott: on Avenue C?
Rym: It's actually just past first.
Rym: It's between First Avenue and Avenue A on 14th Street.
Rym: What's it called?
Rym: Uh, Beshiro Bikes or something.
Rym: They have like five branches.
Rym: That's just the one.
Rym: I know the guys.
Scott: I usually go to Bicycle Habitat, which is like that's like the activist, you know, like it's the happening bike shop.
Rym: This place is pretty happening, too.
Rym: It's all chill dudes.
Rym: They're all pretty cool hanging out, talking to them.
Scott: There's also delivery.
Rym: guys are like fixing their bikes with their tools.
Rym: They don't care.
Scott: There's also Sid's Bikes, which is sort of like the the yuppie bike shop where everything is like, you know, it's like it's almost like it's a professional store, like everything shiny and modern.
Scott: And, you know, it looks like, you know, a you know, like not not low rent.
Scott: You know, most bike shops are just like, you know, in some pre-war building.
Scott: This isn't like.
Scott: it's like modern building, you know, whatever.
Scott: Anyway, very briefly, if you haven't seen, it's like the difference between a stop and shop and a path mark.
Rym: But exactly one week ago today, an interview with Atsuhira Iwakami was posted to the Anime News Network.
Rym: I'm going to link to it.
Rym: You probably don't know who that is, but it's the dude who produced Madoka Magica.
Rym: So if you liked Madoka or if you're an idiot, meaning you hated Madoka and you listen to our final thoughts and you want a little bit more from maybe someone who actually had a creative hand in it.
Rym: Well, here you go.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: There's spoilers.
Scott: The interview is OK.
Scott: It was all right.
Scott: It's not like fascinating, but, you know, it's all right.
Rym: It's worth reading.
Rym: Some of the questions are a little like, so whose idea was it?
Rym: to do blah?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Why did you do blah?
Scott: Anyway, right.
Scott: So in lieu of news, because you always trouble getting Wednesday news anyway, and it's usually not that exciting.
Scott: Right.
Scott: We've got a preview, as you may know, a Geek Byte preview, as you may or may not know.
Scott: This month, the month that we are currently in, September of 2011, DC Comics has, quote, relaunched everything.
Scott: Every single DC comic there is was canceled and restarted at number one.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And there are now 52 DC Comics and they all the number one issues of every single one of those will be released over the course of the month of September.
Scott: And since I think there's already been two Wednesdays, like about half of them are already out.
Scott: I won't be getting any of them until the beginning of October when they come in the box in the mail.
Scott: I'll get them all at once.
Rym: Now, the but well, there's buzz on the Internet already.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: But because there are people who go to the comic shop and they read them as soon as they come out on Wednesday.
Rym: But it's amazing how much of that buzz is.
Rym: fanboys complaining.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But one of the 52 comics was released at the end of August instead of in September.
Scott: That, you know, the premiere one, the Justice League number one, written by Geoff Johns and art by Jim Lee, came out and I had it in the previous box.
Scott: So rather than do it on Scott's box, since we're going to talk about the rest of them, you know, the other 51 on this show, we'll do this first one on this show as the preview.
Scott: So me and Ram both read this Justice League number one.
Rym: So we have to pretend we're going to because, you know, we're going to review this in a fairly objective manner.
Rym: So going to pretend that nothing exists prior to or in parallel with this.
Scott: Well, I do actually.
Scott: That is one thing that I think they did a good job, right, is like they said relaunch.
Scott: They didn't say reset.
Scott: They didn't.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So I was like, what are they going to keep and what are they going to throw away?
Scott: They made it sound like they were going to keep some of the DC Comics history and get rid of some other stuff.
Scott: But in actuality, it was a 100 percent clean slate.
Scott: Right.
Scott: This is like Batman and Green Lantern.
Scott: They like Green Lantern is like, you're real, like they had never met.
Scott: You know, they like.
Scott: it's completely nothing from any previous DC comic matters at all.
Scott: You don't need to know.
Rym: I mean, they're talking about aliens and then one's like, oh, like that guy.
Rym: And they're referring to Superman.
Rym: They're like, oh, like that one I heard about.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I also think that it's pretty cool that they reset.
Scott: Everything.
Scott: And they didn't start with origin stories.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Because usually when you reset, they always do the origin story again.
Scott: But here they don't start with the origin story of any of the characters.
Scott: You don't have like Batman's parents getting killed.
Scott: You don't have green.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Everyone's already a superhero.
Scott: It's just that they don't know each other.
Scott: So it is sort of origin of Justice League, which is the title of the comic.
Scott: But it's not origin of Batman, origin of Superman, origin of Green Lantern.
Rym: But it is five years ago.
Rym: Oh, is it?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Rym: Well, then, so it starts in media res and the beginning of that even then is not the origin stories.
Rym: However, I just want to note this.
Rym: It kind of bothers me.
Rym: The five years ago is in the second panel.
Rym: So you see a bunch of police with sniper rifles in a helicopter basically saying we have Batman in our sights.
Rym: Then it says five years ago and it shows a bunch of helicopters chasing Batman with sniper rifles.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: That five years ago should have been in the first panel.
Rym: Or maybe it's going to in some future like it's.
Rym: like the next issue is going to be like today.
Rym: And it's a different sniper fight with Batman.
Scott: It could be.
Scott: That would be cool.
Scott: But somehow I don't think that's what I don't think that either.
Rym: But I mean, I don't know.
Rym: I'm feeling this because right away it's Batman fucking some shit up and he's kind of I don't know.
Rym: There's a lot of snark.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: From everybody.
Rym: I mean, Batman is kind of he's like idiots.
Rym: He's just throwing stuff.
Rym: Really?
Scott: It's like the thing is, it's like one of the personalities of these characters is just different levels and flavors of jerkiness.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like everyone's, you know, almost wants to be dead.
Rym: But it's so stereotypical.
Rym: Batman's fight, like chasing the supervillain and the police are chasing him and he knocks the supervillain over.
Rym: You know what he says to him?
Rym: What were you doing at the docks?
Scott: It's so bad.
Rym: It's like really this alien like war machine was at the docks doing something.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: OK.
Rym: But so Page four, there's Batman and he looks different.
Rym: And at the bottom of that page, all those panels lead you to an ad.
Rym: And then I remembered I was reading an issue and not a trade paperback.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: This is why you read trades.
Scott: Basically, I think the way I'm going to score these issues, right, is it's going to be two possible scores.
Scott: One is I will buy the trade.
Scott: Two is I will never read it again because there's no way.
Scott: any of these comics, you know, even if there was the best thing in the universe, well, I'll buy the trade.
Scott: Right.
Scott: If it's not the best thing in the universe, I don't need to read it.
Scott: There's no comic where I would buy the issues of it ever.
Scott: So that's my score.
Scott: You know, so you know whether to read or if you agree with my tastes.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That's how I will score them.
Rym: So in this book, and there aren't that many pages, ten of the pages are ads.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Three, four, five, six, seven.
Rym: Seven more of the pages are just BS.
Rym: There's nothing to do with the comic.
Rym: And then up one more ad.
Rym: So eleven pages of ads and a bunch of pages of non-comic.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: If you bought that comic at face value, which I did not, I got four dollars.
Scott: Yeah, I paid less than two dollars.
Scott: I think we paid 80 bucks for the whole thing and there's 52 comics.
Rym: So Batman, I can dig.
Rym: And I kind of like how the Green Lantern's like, what do you mean?
Rym: you don't have any powers?
Rym: Really?
Scott: Yeah, that was that was probably the best part of it.
Scott: The second best part of the whole thing was in Green Lantern is like, don't fucking tell me you're just a guy in a batsuit.
Rym: But simultaneously, the Green Lantern is kind of an all powerful God compared to Batman in this.
Scott: Well, he is.
Scott: But he also.
Scott: I didn't really I don't have any reason to like the Green Lantern.
Scott: He was just so.
Rym: he's great and he's helping everybody.
Rym: Yeah, Batman's actually the one giving him shit.
Scott: Yeah, but agree.
Scott: He was just sort of dopey and you know, you know, obviously his powers.
Rym: How is he dopey?
Rym: He's like, whatever, I'm invincible.
Scott: Yeah, which is kind of dopey.
Rym: That's not dopey.
Rym: That's just.
Rym: I mean, if you're invincible.
Rym: It's like, why would you use fucking fire engines, right?
Rym: That's what I wondered about.
Rym: How come he makes everything in analog?
Rym: Maybe you know what it is.
Rym: So in the Prince of Nothing, maybe he's not creative.
Rym: In the Prince of Nothing, there's the analogy magic and then there's the abstract magic.
Rym: Spoilers.
Rym: You can only do analogies.
Scott: Actually, I think you got it wrong, but the analogies are part of them anyway.
Rym: No.
Scott: Anyway, regardless.
Rym: Anyway, but I don't know.
Rym: Superman appears and he's a little too snarky.
Scott: He is.
Scott: But actually, I was kind of liking that.
Rym: I like that too.
Rym: But they're all snarky.
Rym: Like they're all snarky in the same way, except Batman, who's just Batman.
Rym: So everybody's Batman except, well, Batman.
Rym: Batman is Batman and everybody else is snarky superhero.
Scott: We already went over this, that of the 52 comics, like over 25 percent of them are Batman or Batman related.
Rym: I hereby declare that Batman is DC's Wolverine.
Rym: He's on everybody's team.
Scott: That's not news.
Scott: That's been that way for a while.
Scott: But the point is they reset and they kept it that way.
Scott: Even though, despite resetting, and Green Lantern was sort of their more popular thing lately.
Scott: So they reset and they still went full Batman.
Scott: It's like, really?
Scott: You could have toned back and the suit is barely anything.
Rym: But Scott, really could you?
Rym: I mean, what's compelling about Aquaman compared to Batman?
Scott: The thing with Aquaman is no one tries to make him awesome and actually succeeds.
Scott: I could do it.
Rym: Because Aquaman is the same problem that Nightboat has.
Rym: If the crime doesn't occur on the water or near a conveniently located canal.
Scott: So you make the entire story underwater.
Rym: But they never do that.
Rym: He's just like the lame guy hanging around with the real kids.
Scott: Like fucking Little Mermaid.
Scott: Hello?
Scott: Anyway, most of the people who read superhero comics are not suspecting readers like us.
Scott: They just pretty much have a hero they care about.
Scott: And I'll see people, literally, they'll go into the comic shop and they're Spider-Man guys.
Scott: They literally just walk down the aisle and every comic that's on the new comic shelf that has Spider-Man on it, or any spider anything, they take.
Scott: And then they go directly to the checkout.
Scott: They don't look at anything else.
Scott: So there's people who go to the comic shop, a lot of them, who just walk down the aisle.
Scott: And anything that's bat anything, they take.
Scott: And they go to the checkout.
Scott: And that's all they do.
Scott: Every month.
Scott: So that's why there's a lot of Batman comics.
Scott: That's the only reason.
Scott: Overall, I gotta say, I've never liked a Geoff Johns comic ever.
Scott: I'm usually way down on him.
Scott: He wrote four fanboys.
Scott: He is a fanboy.
Scott: Remember he wrote that Green Lantern Rebirth, which was awful?
Rym: Oh my god.
Scott: Which started off the whole Green Lantern comic.
Rym: That was your fault.
Rym: You handed that to me and you're like, "We gotta review
Rym: this.".
Scott: Yeah, we did.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And pretty much all his comics are like that.
Rym: Didn't you go to all those comic guys and they were like, "This is good.
Rym: This is something you should
Rym: read.".
Scott: Yeah, I was like, because the Green Lantern was so popular.
Scott: So I was like, "This Green Lantern is so popular.
Scott: Everyone's reading it.
Scott: I gotta see what the deal
Scott: is.".
Scott: So I'm like, "Where does it
Scott: begin?".
Scott: They're like, "You gotta start with the Green Lantern Rebirth.
Scott: That's where it begins.
Scott: That's where it all
Scott: starts.".
Scott: And I read it and I was like, "Wow, that's
Scott: awful.".
Scott: But I think here what happens is you had Geoff Johns and they forced him to reset.
Scott: And by forcing him to reset, the primary thing that was wrong with his writing was his fanboy pandering, which is also self-pandering because he's a fanboy.
Scott: And by forcing him to reset, you took away his primary negative writing trait, which was dropping things for fanboys.
Scott: And therefore, I mean, this isn't great.
Scott: I'm not going to buy the trait of this or read any more of it, but it was the best Geoff Johns comic I've read.
Scott: And also the Jim Lee art is still pretty great.
Scott: I like the colors, especially.
Rym: But they're already going a little cliche in that the title of the next one says, and I quote, "Batman vs.
Rym: Superman.".
Scott: Dun dun dun.
Scott: There's a reason I'm not buying any trains.
Rym: No, Superman's kind of a dick.
Scott: I like Dick Superman better than regular old, you know, American Pie Superman.
Rym: I really worry he's going to be the exact same kind of dick that the Green Lantern is.
Scott: But that's the other thing is that being a dick doesn't work if everyone's a dick.
Scott: You need people to suffer the trolling.
Scott: You can't just have a bunch of trolls, right?
Scott: There has to be someone who gets... It'll be Aquaman.
Rym: He'll be like, "Guys, come
Rym: on!".
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, troll-estia doesn't work if it's also troll-light-sparkle and troll-dash.
Scott: It doesn't work.
Scott: It only works when it's just troll-estia.
Rym: So, we'll see.
Rym: We'll read the rest of these and have detailed reviews.
Rym: Notice I did not say anything unnecessarily disparaging because if I ignore every other DC comic that has ever existed, and just to read this, I am kind of curious what happens on the next page.
Scott: Yeah, this is not awful.
Rym: And the art's okay.
Rym: I like the art.
Scott: Yeah, this is not so bad.
Scott: I haven't read any Justice League ever, but this is better than any Justice League I've ever read.
Scott: It's better than Super Friends.
Scott: That's a plus.
Rym: So there is one more very important news.
Rym: This weekend, the second season of a show called My Little Pony, Friendship is Magic, is going to air.
Scott: It's a Saturday morning cartoon now on The Hub 9 a.m.
Scott: Eastern, 6 a.m.
Scott: Pacific.
Rym: It is safe to say that I've been looking forward to this more than I've looked forward to any season of any show since I saw a trailer to Escaflowne when I was still in high school.
Scott: I mean, even shows...
Rym: When I heard there was going to be a second gig to Stand Alone Complex, I was equally excited.
Scott: Even if you told me that there was another Stand Alone Complex gig, a third gig, right?
Scott: I'd probably wait until the whole thing was done and watch it all in a big blob.
Scott: Only for ponies.
Scott: am I going to need to go on YouTube on Saturday afternoon after someone uploads it and watch it immediately.
Rym: Yeah, you realize that if I have access to a TV that I can change the channel on...
Scott: And it has The Hub?
Rym: I'm going to watch it live on TV.
Rym: That'll be the first show.
Scott: On Saturday at 9 a.m.
Rym: I have a watch.
Scott: With little girl commercials.
Rym: We'll see what the commercials are.
Scott: You going to watch Pound Puppies after?
Rym: No.
Rym: Are you kidding?
Rym: Fuck that.
Scott: You know, the same people make both the shows.
Scott: Don't care.
Rym: I don't trust that Pound Puppies at all.
Scott: Actually, there were some commercials that they had on Equestria Daily.
Scott: that were promotional commercials for the new pony season.
Rym: Nobody has moves like the girls with the hooves.
Scott: No, they were also Pound Puppy commercials.
Scott: They were promoting that whole block of two shows on Saturday morning.
Rym: Why can't My Little Pony just be on Toonami?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Someone even made a trailer that was like Toonami with My Little Pony.
Scott: Yeah, anyway.
Scott: Why can't they just put it directly on fucking YouTube themselves instead of having...
Rym: You know what?
Rym: If I could just buy the episodes with the correct colors... For a dollar.
Rym: For a dollar.
Rym: I would pay a dollar.
Scott: But they're charging a zillion dollars on iTunes.
Rym: But they're charging a zillion dollars.
Rym: and the colors...
Scott: And it's also 720p what they're charging for, not 1080p.
Scott: And the colors are all fucked up.
Scott: Give me 1080p's with the right colors for a dollar.
Rym: Or at least sell some DVDs.
Scott: Ten dollar season pass.
Rym: Anyway, yeah, we like ponies and it's coming.
Rym: You should watch it.
Scott: Ponies.
Scott: The return of the ponies.
Scott: Internet explode.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: I'm gonna already declare victory.
Scott: We managed to carry... This tells you the power of the pony.
Scott: That, you know, it was big, but we managed to carry that stone.
Scott: Sisyphus pushed the pony rock up the hill to the next season.
Rym: The fact that the PMVs... Not only did they keep being made for this entire duration, but the frequency increased.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: There has been... They have made a Draw Friend post on Equestria Daily every single day.
Rym: For how long?
Scott: At least a long time.
Rym: We could probably... We're not doing this.
Rym: Shut up, kids.
Rym: No.
Rym: I feel like if we turned the news on Wednesdays into just ponies, we'd have enough to talk about.
Scott: Maybe.
Rym: Every week.
Scott: No more pony.
Scott: All the pony is now relegated to a separate show.
Rym: Called Radio Free Equestria.
Scott: No more pony in the show.
Rym: That you should watch.
Scott: None.
Scott: Except for occasional jokes.
Rym: But anyway, very briefly, things of the day.
Rym: So, not technically a College Humor, but a Darkly, but of this kind of joke?
Scott: It's College Humor.
Rym: This is very... I could link to the Darkly one.
Rym: It's on Darkly as well.
Scott: Which is the same people as College Humor.
Rym: It's a different site.
Scott: It's the same office.
Rym: So?
Rym: Anyway, it's linked with a portal gun, but it is actually extremely well done, and you will enjoy this.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Possibly more so if you've actually played A Link to the Past, and if you haven't, well... What the fuck?
Rym: That's really a shame.
Scott: If you haven't, that is your assignment.
Scott: Unless you also haven't played Super Metroid, in which case that is your first assignment.
Rym: I would start with Link to the Past.
Rym: I prefer games like this to games like Metroid.
Scott: Super Metroid.
Rym: Anyway.
Scott: Best.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: So.
Scott: Cats.
Scott: They're funny.
Scott: They are.
Scott: All internet funniness comes from cat.
Scott: Cat is like, if there was a... Cat is like, you know, protons.
Scott: It's a primordial element.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like protons.
Scott: If you're making internet humor, figuring out internet humor science, you get your microscope, you zoom way in, cat.
Scott: No matter what it is, you could be zooming in on like, you know, two girls, one cup, and you zoom way in, way in, way in, and you'll see it's just made of cat.
Scott: So, here is some raw internet hilarity.
Scott: They take in many classic paintings that are the kind that you find in museums.
Scott: You know, famous ones.
Scott: And they replaced the primary or perhaps secondary characters, or whatever one was most humorous, with cat.
Scott: But not any cat.
Scott: This one particular orange cat.
Scott: In a variety of poses, matching the poses in the picture.
Scott: It is the funny.
Scott: I encourage you to make more in this vein.
Rym: It is very reminiscent of the old...
Scott: They have not fully explored this particular combination of humor, and I think there are great opportunities for Lowell.
Rym: It's in the style of the old Photoshop Fridays that I used to be a huge fan of.
Scott: It's more of a comedy goldmine.
Rym: Ah, yeah.
Rym: It depends, because the old Photoshop Friday would be, here's a picture, do something funny to it.
Rym: And the comedy goldmine would be, here's an element, do something funny with it.
Scott: Right, but I think this is more, you know, Photoshop Friday was, here's a picture, do whatever.
Scott: This is, do this specific thing.
Rym: But to any picture.
Scott: Ah, true.
Rym: Yeah, they're two sides of the same coin.
Scott: It's more, maybe it's a worth 1000?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: There's so many differences.
Rym: Regardless, I laughed out loud.
Rym: This is pretty good.
Scott: This is good.
Scott: Check it.
Rym: I feel like the only way to make this better is to turn it into on the go.
Scott: You and your on the go.
Rym: I love on the go.
Scott: Alright, metamoments.
Scott: The metamoments.
Rym: The Book Club book is The Year of the Hour by Nancy Farr.
Rym: We'll do the show as soon as I finish reading it.
Rym: I didn't read it yet because it didn't get delivered to me until a week and a half ago.
Scott: Why did I get mine?
Scott: It's weird because I ordered mine on Amazon and I got it immediately.
Scott: I know.
Scott: And nobody else did.
Scott: Even though they all also ordered it on Amazon immediately.
Rym: I know, like we ordered it the same fucking day.
Rym: So, anyway.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Other meta things.
Rym: Radio Free Equestria is coming back.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: For real.
Rym: Well, coming back.
Scott: We already discussed that.
Rym: Yes, but it's meta now.
Rym: So, Google or YouTube for Radio Free Equestria.
Scott: There is going to be, on 11/11/11, November 11th, that weekend, the Burning Apocalypse Con.
Scott: It's going to be a Burning Wheel, Luke Crane-ish convention of roleplaying in New York City, but also a Vince Baker Apocalypse World roleplay.
Scott: Two indie RPG guys come together to make one weekend of roleplaying off the hook, 11/11/11.
Scott: And if you can get to New York City, registration is going to be opening mad soon.
Scott: If any of my friends want to come to it, we've got couches.
Rym: Only so many couches.
Scott: Three couches.
Scott: Cut it out.
Scott: Check us out on the internets.
Scott: And worst webcomic contest, next Wednesday show.
Scott: That's what that's going to be.
Scott: Well, I guess actually two Wednesday shows from now.
Rym: Next Wednesday, we're cutting off submissions.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, I think we said we knew that before.
Scott: Whatever.
Scott: The next Wednesday show we record is going to be that show.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: We're going to cut off submissions arbitrarily at some point.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: So if you haven't entered yet and you want to, well, do it now or you'll miss it.
Scott: Can we think of anything else?
Scott: There's no swags, the next conventions are next year, other than Burning Apocalypse Con.
Scott: MAGFest is the biggest one.
Scott: The New York Comic Con is coming, but it doesn't look like we're doing anything there.
Rym: Yeah, a lot of people aren't doing stuff there.
Rym: The short answer, having talked to a lot of people on their side, is that you know how cons sell out?
Rym: It's a sold out and not as in it's out of batches.
Scott: No, sold out like the monkeys.
Scott: I'm going to the Giants game Monday night against St.
Scott: Louis.
Scott: If you're going to be there, call me.
Scott: We can say hi at the stadium.
Rym: We used to do a lot more final thoughts episodes.
Scott: We hardly did any ever.
Scott: We started doing them.
Scott: We did a handful of them in the entire history of these guys.
Rym: But we haven't done them in a while, so I feel like this warning is very important.
Rym: If you have not seen every single episode of Puella Magica, every single episode of the original show, do not listen to this episode.
Rym: Do not fucking spoil the show.
Scott: Actually, I just want to add a minor note.
Scott: We can discuss this later.
Scott: I think we already did a show about spoilers, but you know, I always say, hey, look, if a show can be ruined by spoilers, then that means the only thing the show had going for it was that it had the element of surprise.
Scott: And, you know, if surprise is all you got, that's pretty cheap and such.
Scott: There was actually a study, a scientific study, where they had people read stories and judge them and say how much they liked them and stuff like that.
Scott: And some of them had spoilers up front and some of them didn't.
Scott: People thought it's like people's expectation is that a spoiler will ruin something.
Scott: But in reality, they like it more.
Scott: They enjoy it more when it is spoiled, because when you know more about something, you can, you know, pay more closer attention and get more out of it, which is why you should watch Madoka twice.
Rym: But at the same time, I saw Cowboy Bebop in its entirety and nothing had been spoiled for me.
Rym: Neither the deaths nor the end nor non deaths.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Everything along the way.
Rym: Nothing was spoiled.
Rym: So I had about three moments of shock during the show.
Rym: And I'm glad that I got to experience that.
Scott: The thing was, is like, even though I also was not spoiled, I saw them coming like a zillion miles away.
Rym: One of them, it was the kind of thing where I expected something to happen as the end of the show.
Rym: And the fact that it happened out of nowhere, suddenly with no fanfare in the middle, like that really took me by surprise anyway.
Scott: But the point is, you know, the only, you know, I don't think spoiling is that actually bad.
Scott: So maybe you're someone who agrees with me and you believe in science and you know that spoiling will actually make you enjoy the show more.
Scott: It might be OK for you to listen to this.
Scott: I would still recommend you don't.
Rym: And then go watch it.
Rym: I really recommend you don't, because the layers of what happens in episode 10 are pretty great.
Scott: So now we're going to spoil this.
Rym: We're going to spoil the crap out of the show.
Rym: We're assuming that you've seen all of Madoka Magica.
Rym: We don't need to research, like do the whole plot.
Scott: Or I'm assuming you don't care about being spoiled.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So the Groundhog Day thing really got me right.
Scott: So the thing that the Groundhog Day I thought was so fascinating was that, you know, you think Groundhog Day is so cliche and so famous and such a great movie that everyone knows that nobody else would ever dare to make a Groundhog Day.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Like if I made a show and in it I pulled a Groundhog Day or I wrote a comic book and in it I pulled a Groundhog Day.
Scott: People just be like, oh, you're pulling a Groundhog Day.
Scott: It wasn't even on my radar.
Rym: And when that episode starts up and I see Homura looking nerdy at the front of the room, I thought I was like, oh, shit, I know what happened.
Rym: She went back.
Rym: She met Madoka, who is a magical girl, and went back in time or something like she to save her.
Scott: Because the thing you knew from early in the show was that somehow she knew these things.
Scott: She knew where the nurse's office was.
Scott: She knew Madoka's name.
Rym: I expected that she'd become a magical girl and her wish was to save Madoka from some tragedy.
Rym: that probably was the dream from the beginning.
Rym: That's what I thought.
Scott: Yeah, or something.
Rym: And then when?
Rym: that Groundhog Day again, again.
Scott: But the difference here, right, is that number one, Groundhog Day, the movie, Bill Murray.
Scott: Groundhog Day, right, is about one guy.
Scott: It's from his perspective doing the Groundhog Day and it's, you know, the Groundhog Day is happening throughout the entire movie, right, as the viewer, and he's doing it at least from the start for selfish reasons.
Scott: He's trying to improve himself, you know, he's trying to achieve some goal on his own.
Scott: In Madoka, you're from the perspective of someone else, you don't see the Groundhog Day happening, so it's like you're the girl in Groundhog Day, not Bill Murray, and you're just living one of the Groundhog Days, not all of them.
Rym: Well, specifically the last one.
Scott: Yes, the last Groundhog Day, only.
Scott: You don't see all the Groundhog Days that came before until episode 10.
Rym: And I definitely get the impression that Homura lived through hundreds if not thousands of these.
Scott: Yeah, lots of them.
Rym: That was a crushing series of failures along the way.
Scott: And on top of that, the Groundhog Day is not, instead of being, you know, this self, it still has that character.
Scott: who's doing the Groundhog Day is improving themselves, their skills, their abilities, right?
Scott: But one person is doing it sort of for themselves, at least, you know, until Bill Murray's doing it mostly for himself.
Scott: Homura's not doing it for herself at all, at all, right?
Scott: She's doing the whole thing for someone else.
Scott: And also, she's doing it in an adventure action way, right?
Scott: Bill Murray wasn't improving his gun shooting and bomb skills, he was improving his piano.
Rym: Well, early on, that was the thing, you know, suddenly when she rips out a grenade, I'm like,
Rym: "What?".
Rym: And then when she shoots Kyubey right before Madoka was about to become a magical girl, and she drops the gun.
Rym: And as she's dropping it, all I remember thinking was, "That gun is a pistol, and yet all those bullet holes appeared on Kyubey
Rym: simultaneously.".
Scott: Yeah, and it's like they give you those hints, too, throughout the show.
Rym: But then even right there, Kyubey's like, "You're not from this timeline, are you?
Rym: It's some sort of time
Rym: manipulation.".
Scott: Yeah, and it's like she uses the time.
Scott: stop, you know, everyone's magical power is related to the wish they made, you know, and their soul gem is related to the wish they made, you know, like how, what's the green hair girl's name?
Rym: You already forgot what you told me.
Rym: Her hair's blue.
Rym: It's green.
Rym: It's blue.
Scott: Anyway, so Sayaka, she wishes, you know, for the musical kid to get better, right?
Scott: So all her magic, she has swords, and all her magic has like musical notes all over it, you know, and it's all related to the thing that she wished for.
Scott: You know, in the same way that, you know, Homura wished to go back in time, well, so all her magic is time related, you know?
Rym: I just, I couldn't, it was really hard to watch all the, like, every iteration along the way, and I like how they showed you a lot of them, and how it's like you can see- And they showed you ones that were really meaningful, right?
Scott: They showed you ones where she significantly improved her skills.
Scott: They showed you, you know, past, they showed you why.
Scott: It's like from the beginning of the show, you're like, Homura obviously knows something.
Scott: Why doesn't she just come out with it?
Scott: Well, because the last time she tried that, it didn't work.
Scott: That's why she's not trying it this time.
Rym: Well, not just the last time, every time.
Rym: You see how every time she lives through this, it ends in horrible tragedy, some worse than others.
Scott: Yeah, she tries something different every time, and it doesn't work.
Rym: The most crushing ones for me were the one where Mami murders Kyoko after they figure out that they're going to turn into witches, and then Madoka has to kill Kyoko before she kills Homura.
Rym: Yeah, right.
Rym: Like, that was rough.
Scott: That was rough.
Scott: But no, the rougher one was where Madoka is going to turn into a witch, and then Homura has to kill her before she goes back in time.
Rym: But even in the timeline we saw, Kyoko realized what was going on and killed herself to destroy Sayaka as a witch to save her.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: And her blue hair!
Rym: See?
Rym: Blue.
Scott: Whatever.
Rym: That's blue, Scott.
Rym: Not green.
Scott: I can't really see it from here.
Rym: He told me he had green hair, and she didn't really matter.
Scott: It's greenish blue.
Rym: It's not.
Rym: It's blue.
Scott: Whatever.
Scott: So, what else can we say about the show?
Rym: Well, I pretty much had guessed from pretty early on that the whole thing was going to come down to, you know, in a past life or in another world somewhere.
Rym: I thought it was actually going to be, like, Bokerano style, like there's another world where Madoka was a magical girl, and Homura became a magical girl wishing to spare her this fate.
Rym: And that in this world, Kyubey now appears and tries to get Madoka anyway, because that wouldn't technically be breaking the wish if Madoka wished it again.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: That's a crazy thinking.
Rym: That's what I expected.
Rym: And it was actually really close, just I did not suspect the degree or nature or the Groundhog Day.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, I was pretty much the whole time, right?
Scott: I was like, well, you get a wish, right?
Scott: So I was like, why don't you, you know, nobody tried to wish for more wishes or wish to be a magical girl, but not have your soul gem ever run out or wish to be a magical girl.
Scott: But or I was thinking, why don't you make a wish that all magical girls are invincible and immortal?
Scott: You know, make that your wish.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But we already knew that there must be a balance in the world between hope and despair.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it wasn't ever, you know, they never make the rules super clear like they do in Death Note and Kyubey's, you know, I mean, you look at the Bokerano, at least he tells you all the rules, you know, but or Death Note.
Scott: They tell you all the rules.
Scott: In this one, Kyubey is just a jerk straight up.
Rym: I love the second time through, I noticed how pretty much everything Madoka does.
Rym: He's like, you know, you can make a contract with me.
Scott: Yeah, Kyubey, he personally intentionally gets them into situations where they, you know, it's like he's like, Sayaka, let's go into the marble before Mommy shows up and wait there.
Rym: Oh, by the way, there happens to be a grief seed right here.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: If anything bad happens in there or Mommy doesn't show up on time, you can always make the contract and become a magical.
Rym: I imagine walking around like Madoka drops her parfait and Kyubey is like, I could fix that.
Scott: It's like if Madoka and Sayaka just didn't go near any fucking grief seeds or go into any of those reality marbles and just kept going to school.
Scott: But could they?
Rym: I would argue that part of the story here is that it's the Bilbo Baggins.
Rym: Once you're Bilbo, there is no way back.
Rym: There's no way home.
Scott: Well, the thing is, you could have wished, for example, you could be like, I wish I never knew about these reality marbles or wishes and I stopped seeing them because clearly not everyone sees them.
Rym: Wait.
Rym: But to get that wish, you now become a magical girl.
Scott: I know that's why it would be fucked up.
Rym: paradox, you know, how the paradoxes resolve themselves.
Rym: They're monkeys.
Rym: Pause.
Rym: Despair and hope are always balanced.
Rym: Homer made her wish to live it over again.
Scott: That's a full mental alchemist right there.
Rym: But by wishing to live it over again, equal exchange, the outcome could not be different.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: It would always end in tragedy.
Rym: I mean, look, one time they beat the witch just fine.
Rym: But now everyone else is dead and the two of them are going to become witches like there's there's no way.
Rym: Though I like how in this in the main universe, like the last one we see, Madoka is kind of normal and yet everyone says she has so much potential.
Rym: I like how there was actually a really rational explanation for that.
Scott: They don't leave anything like why, you know, it's like you're saying, you know, one thing I was like, why did Homer just tell everyone?
Scott: Well, they explained to you in episode 10.
Scott: She's tried that.
Scott: It didn't work.
Rym: But also, why?
Scott: How does she know the Westburg is night is coming?
Scott: Well, Pergus.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: While Pergus night is coming.
Scott: Well, because it comes at the same time.
Rym: But also, I like how in the worlds where Madoka is a magical girl, she is super competent and she's also like a really strong person.
Rym: Like the time when they beat the witch, but the two of them are laying there dying.
Rym: Madoka whips out the grief seed she hidden that she still has and taps it on Homer's soul gem before she could even react.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Well, I mean, that's another thing, right?
Scott: In the very first universe of episode 10, right, Homura is the weak, timid one.
Scott: And Madoka is just like, hey, what's up?
Rym: Yeah, Madoka, Mami, Sayaka are all just magical girls together.
Rym: And I like how Kyoko joins them on the team.
Rym: Like they're all just chill.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But then in the, you know, the universe that most of the show takes place in, you know, the current timeline against the final timeline, the real one, you know, Madoka is a little bit timid, not super timid, but a little bit, you know, where Homura is the ultimate.
Rym: But at the same time, she seems strong.
Rym: Like she you get this sense, like there's almost this boy in her life.
Scott: She is her mom's daughter.
Scott: Her mom is the best.
Rym: Not just that, but there's there's a million universes or at least a thousand or so where she is a magical girl hero.
Rym: In one of them, she takes out that Walpurgis Night Witch with one shot.
Scott: And then becomes the biggest witch ever.
Rym: But think about all those universes are like tugging at her soul and her being as her being a hero in every sense.
Rym: And now she's just a normal girl.
Rym: In fact, there's someone trying to prevent her from being the hero.
Rym: Yeah, I really like Mommy, too.
Rym: She had this kind of otherworldly.
Rym: She reminded me of the Outer Senshi from Sailor Moon a lot.
Scott: Well, it's always kind of weird, right?
Scott: Because it's like you're trying to judge, you know, you sort of have this thing in your brain, like who's good and who's bad.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's like, well, Mommy, on the one hand was like, yeah, becoming magical girl.
Scott: She was like trying to make them become magical girls.
Scott: But you sort of had a sense the cuba was evil.
Scott: So you're like, is Mommy evil?
Rym: But no, Mommy really believed in all this.
Rym: Mommy was a really good person.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But it's like but she was still trying to get them to become magical girls.
Scott: But Homura seemed like she was up to no good, at least on the very surface, seemed like she was up to no good.
Scott: But you knew she was actually right.
Rym: Sayaka was the saddest, though, because she went like.
Rym: she's the one who came into this with kind of the most good intentions.
Rym: And it's interesting how that always ended up the worst possible outcome.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: She also didn't use her wish very well.
Scott: She was there to show you like the typical, you know, what I imagine what most magical girls think.
Rym: that was typical, because look at when you get the flashback to how Mommy decided she's dying, bleeding to death after having been in a car accident.
Rym: And Kyubey appears like, hey, you can wish to not die.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Sayaka is one of the few people who had a choice.
Scott: But if you look, Kyoko also had a similar wish.
Rym: And she had a pretty epic wish.
Rym: that again, despair and hope.
Scott: No, those those wishes weren't, you know, epic.
Scott: I mean, wishing to not die is something you can understand in the heat of the moment.
Scott: But but think about it.
Rym: Kyoko and Sayaka both had an alternate thing.
Scott: They were thinking, I wish for X, but their wishes are still just sort of in the context of their existing lives.
Scott: They were in the context of the grand scheme of the universe.
Rym: They didn't need to be, because as far as they could see, the grand scheme of things once was.
Rym: I also will become a magical girl and protect people from this evil.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, that's a pretty great thing to be Madoka.
Scott: What did she want to wish for?
Scott: She wanted to be a magical girl.
Rym: Yeah, I thought that originally.
Rym: I thought that was why she was the most powerful.
Scott: I thought it was bad subtitles the first time.
Rym: I thought she was going to wish to be a magical girl and somehow that was going to break Qubei's bullshit.
Scott: That would be weird.
Rym: That was my early guess.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I really didn't trust Qubei from the start.
Scott: Well, you can't after you see Bokerano.
Scott: There's no way you trust any weird creature that's trying to get people to sign contracts.
Scott: Seriously, the first time I watched the show.
Scott: You know it's a trap.
Rym: Qubei, like I was a little unsure.
Rym: The second time through, like it is so painfully obvious how much of a dick is the one ending where Madoka becomes the like the most powerful witch in the world to destroy the earth in about 10 days.
Rym: And Qubei is like, well, that's your problem now.
Scott: We finished our energy quota.
Scott: See you.
Scott: Yeah, it has that typical sci fi thing with, you know, the aliens gathering energy from whatever it's like.
Scott: that was sort of black, but at least it didn't play a big part.
Rym: No, no, because it was.
Rym: it was much like it's a tiny spoiler, but it is very tiny.
Rym: But it's a very similar plot.
Rym: And I like the fact that both of these shows edge into this territory, much like how we bebop at the gate disaster of here's the world.
Rym: The main characters exist in this world and have a huge plot, but simultaneously there are things that are beyond their reach.
Scott: Yeah, the universe is vast.
Scott: You're tiny and insignificant, you know, even though you're not tiny and significant in the scope of this anime.
Scott: In the universe.
Rym: But think about this.
Rym: I love at the end in the kind of remade world where Homer is feeding Qubei and she's the only one who remembers Madoka and she's kind of tossing the stuff in the air and Qubei is being all cute.
Rym: And he's like, this witch's thing sounds really intriguing.
Rym: I wonder if we could do use it to do something to make more energy.
Rym: And she's like, yeah, you dick.
Rym: I have a feeling our relationship would be much more treacherous.
Rym: Yeah, that was just a nice touch at the end.
Scott: It was.
Rym: I was driven to tears many times, pretty much from episode 10 to the end.
Scott: Well, I think that's by design.
Scott: The end was epic to an amazing degree.
Rym: Remember way back when Qubei was like, you could even be an omnipotent God.
Scott: And I kind of like how that it's like she didn't wish to be an omnipotent God.
Scott: It was just sort of like, well, you're going to become an omnipotent God.
Scott: She's like, that's fine.
Rym: But it's very important.
Rym: She could have wished to get rid of the like.
Rym: just destroy magical girls like there are no magical girls.
Rym: Everyone leads a normal life.
Rym: But I like how.
Rym: instead she went epic because if magical girls still exist, then miracles still exist.
Rym: And that was the whole thing with Sayaka, the fact that she dies.
Rym: that time, that timeline in the final remade world is basically Homura, Mami, Sayaka and Kyoko being magical girls.
Rym: Sayaka dies, but gets her wish.
Rym: And that was very touching to me.
Scott: I don't think she even really existed in that timeline.
Rym: I think she did.
Scott: And I think because she was like, look, you know, it seemed like because he watched when Madoka was like saving all the magical girls.
Scott: No, no, no.
Scott: Because some of them disappeared.
Rym: No, because, you know, when she was saving them, those were the magical girls who were going to turn who turned into witches in the past.
Rym: Every magical girl throughout all of history who had turned into a witch, she intervened in time the moment before they became a witch and spared them that by taking all of the grief into herself.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Sayaka, because remember, there are.
Scott: but she was like, you know, your own circular logic, whatever.
Rym: No, but Sayaka, she got her wish.
Rym: The boy was healed.
Rym: So that miracle did happen.
Rym: It did.
Scott: But I don't think, you know, I think they may be in that time.
Rym: No, it was clear it did, because think about two of the universes where everything ends up badly.
Rym: In one of them, Sayaka becomes a witch and Kyoko kills herself to spare Sayaka the fate of continuing to be a witch.
Rym: In one of the flashback ones, the same thing happens and Mami freaks out and kills Kyoko and then Madoka has to like in some of them.
Scott: Sayaka wasn't even there, though, at all.
Rym: Well, no, she we didn't.
Rym: That was earlier.
Rym: Sayaka doesn't become a magical girl till later.
Rym: And we don't see those scenes from later.
Rym: I think she's a part of the team in most of those universes, though maybe I can see Homura preventing that, trying to save her and eventually.
Scott: Yeah, I'm sure that there was some time she was.
Rym: The fact that Homura in the second most recent end was constantly telling Madoka, give up on Sayaka, give up on her, because she just knows this.
Scott: Basically, she's like, yeah, there's nothing you can do about Sayaka.
Rym: That implies to me that she's seen Sayaka die a zillion times.
Rym: She tried to pull.
Rym: She tried to save the hobo.
Scott: And she also wasn't upset about Mami dying so early in episode three, because that was a much better fate than Mami later.
Scott: Yeah, because she had seen what Mami usually ends up doing much later on.
Rym: Yes, Mami dying is much better for Mami than Mami becoming a witch or Mami killing Kyoko.
Rym: Yeah, because she needed Kyoko in case she had to fight Walpurgis night.
Rym: Yeah, but Sayaka, she got.
Scott: I think it was just that your plan was like, well, this time let's try getting Kyoko to the end.
Scott: But not only did Sayaka get her wish, it's like playing a video game this time.
Rym: Let's try this.
Rym: When Homura wakes up in the new universe, the scene she wakes up in is everyone except Madoka, who is not in that universe, being said that they couldn't save Sayaka, that she died.
Rym: And the only difference, Homura is the only one who knows Madoka.
Rym: So that is why I believe in this final universe, everything Sayaka did still happened, except no witches.
Rym: She just died.
Scott: Maybe.
Scott: Either way, what else are we going to say about the show?
Scott: The fact that some of my favorite scenes in the show, right?
Scott: So where she's fighting the Walpurgis night and she does all the crazy explosions.
Rym: That is Neo guns times ten.
Scott: So she does the rocket launchers, the scene with the time stop in the universe, she does the mortars, then she does the bus off the bridge, then she does it falls into the pit with the C4 all around when the C4 turns on.
Scott: It's like shit, son.
Rym: I like when she comes back the first time and she's going to fix everything and she shows off her powers and mommy's like, oh, it's clearly time stop.
Scott: Yeah, she's that was a good line, at least in this.
Scott: I don't know how I think the subtitles were a little janky, a little bit.
Rym: Emily was correcting them a lot while we were watching.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Another scene I really liked actually was when the teacher and the mom were talking, getting that was cool because that was unexpected.
Scott: But because early in the show, you know, the very first episode, the mom asks about the teacher.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And Madoka's talk is, you know, the teacher and the mom know each other and have some sort of relationship, even though it's hardly explored at all.
Scott: But it's still.
Scott: it's like.
Scott: that's why they're talking to each other in that later episode.
Scott: And the mom is still.
Scott: the mom is just so awesome all the time.
Scott: And that scene where like the mom is like, Madoka, stay with you.
Scott: And I'm like, oh, yeah, take the mom with you.
Scott: That'll be sweet.
Rym: I was really hoping the mom would go with her.
Scott: Yeah, I was like, oh, I thought something was going to happen there.
Scott: Yeah, but no, it was just like, all right.
Rym: But even then, that I really you know, that was Madoka being the strong character from every other universe really coming out.
Rym: Yeah, I really like the mom's advice of sometimes you have to do the wrong thing.
Scott: That was a good one, too.
Scott: And it's like, I like.
Scott: the way the thing was is I was like, oh, I can't wait to see what wrong thing she does.
Scott: And then I stopped thinking about it.
Scott: And then she did the wrong thing immediately.
Scott: The size and it was the wrongest thing.
Scott: It was really wrong.
Scott: But it was also advantageous because it allowed them to learn something.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It was that in this universe, the fact that all those magical girls learned that in that universe, I think was a key.
Rym: Well, look what it did in that universe that mommy doesn't exist anymore.
Rym: So she well, she's dead.
Rym: So she won't go crazy and kill people.
Rym: when she figures it out.
Rym: Sayaka learns and Kyoko no longer is trying to kill Sayaka.
Scott: But no, see, mommy went crazy and killed everyone in that other in that old universe when she learned that they turn into witches, not when she learns that the soul gem is actually you.
Rym: But I wonder if she might have figured it out, because I feel like she was.
Scott: there were both things that pissed them off.
Rym: Mommy was very, I don't know, canny about everything and very of course, this kind of aside, I like how she was so otherworldly and so calm all the time.
Rym: But yet in the flashbacks, you see what causes her to break down.
Rym: And in the real show, the one time when Motoko is like, I won't forget you, I'll fight with you.
Rym: And that was going to be her wish.
Rym: How happy mommy was and how she breaks down.
Scott: She was crying.
Scott: Her whole family was dead in whatever accident.
Scott: She was the only one who survived.
Scott: She lived alone, you know, as a magical girl, whatever, you know.
Scott: So it's just a lonely existence.
Scott: But she was a good person trying to help people just happen to be a very lonely life.
Rym: But of course, watching the show and having people have said things like, yeah, it's like Boca Rado with magical girls.
Rym: As soon as she said, I'm so happy.
Rym: All I could think was she's going to die.
Rym: She's going to die.
Scott: She's going to die there for as much as this show kept things a secret and had good, you know, you didn't.
Scott: things you couldn't expect.
Scott: There are plenty of things you could see coming a mile away that you are trained in the anime.
Rym: that led to one of my favorite scenes, which is just Motoko and Sayaka sitting on the roof afterward.
Rym: And their conversation is basically we've been bilboed.
Rym: There's no way back.
Scott: Yeah, but it was also, yeah, I guess we're not going to become magical girls.
Rym: But it wasn't really.
Rym: They didn't really say they're not going to do it.
Rym: They were really they.
Rym: that was.
Rym: they said that because that was the logical thing.
Rym: But it was obvious that both of them were still considering it like they couldn't just walk away from that world.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: There I mean, there were just so many other good scenes, both short and long, like when Madoka is about to finally become a magical girl and then you make a shot.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I like in the flashbacks the one where she's already killed Akibe and yet there's already another one like on his way after Madoka.
Scott: And it's like that's.
Scott: another thing is like the show is called Puella Magi Madoka Magica in the opener.
Scott: It's all Madoka as a magical girl.
Rym: Yet she's not a magical girl until the end.
Scott: You start you start watching the show and the first conflict they introduce within a minute is is Madoka to become a magical girl or not?
Scott: She can be formed this contract, but she was just told not to.
Scott: Is is she going to do it?
Scott: If so, when?
Scott: And I was assuming the first time I watched it, that within a few episodes she would do it and make some wish and the rest of the show would be about the conflicts that happen after.
Scott: I didn't think that that would be the conflict of the whole show, even though it was a short show.
Scott: I didn't think that would be the 12 episode conflict.
Scott: But in fact, it was.
Scott: she doesn't become a magical girl until episode 12.
Scott: It's like, come on.
Scott: Though pursuant to that, I did not expect that would be like insane.
Scott: I'd be like, if in Sailor Moon, you didn't say whatever her name is, Usagi.
Scott: Usagi didn't become Sailor Moon until the final episode of Sailor Moon.
Rym: One of them said, I almost said Serena.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Or if you watched, you know, Princess Tutu and it was just a duck and Ahiru until the very final episode, Princess Tutu, you know, you've never seen that happen.
Scott: This is the transformation.
Scott: Voltron didn't form into the complete Voltron until the very last episode of Voltron.
Rym: Well, Shinji didn't form into a complete man until the very end.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Imagine if like Ava zero one didn't even activate until episode twenty six.
Scott: You know, that's what this is.
Scott: You know, it's crazy.
Scott: Unbelievable.
Scott: No one's ever had the boss do something like that before.
Rym: Oh, so I like the scene when Sayaka is like, I don't know about this time spot.
Rym: Stop.
Rym: All she does is drop bombs.
Rym: I'm the only close in fighter.
Rym: It's kind of dangerous for me.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: They were sort of practically the next.
Scott: It's true.
Scott: That's like.
Scott: that's the reveal everything.
Scott: episode, episode 10, the reveal everything.
Scott: Groundhog Day episode, and somehow they're managing to fit into that episode.
Scott: Pretty straightforward, like tactical magical girl fighting discussions.
Rym: The show, if you just look at this show, you see five magical girls who fit the stereotypes of a magical girl team.
Rym: And yet the entire show, there's no hint of that magical girl team except the opener.
Rym: Until you get the flashback and also the and then the fact that at the end of the show and that episode 10, they play the opener to the show at the end.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Episodes 10, 11 and 12.
Scott: The closer is pretty much gone, right?
Scott: They just play the opener.
Rym: That was brilliant because it's kind of like.
Rym: it's almost like a New Testament of magical girls.
Rym: You know, with her becoming a goddess is kind of true.
Rym: It's like there's a new world order.
Rym: There's a new contract.
Scott: There is still bad things in the world, but the bad things are magical demons that come from the darkness and magical girls only bring good.
Scott: They come and they fight for good and then they die.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And sometimes that was what I thought.
Rym: I didn't expect.
Rym: until once I saw the grief seeds work, I suspected something bad with witches because notice how she takes the grief seed and she taps it against her soul gem and blackness comes out of the soul gem into the grief seed.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Think about how fucked up that is.
Rym: That means that every one of those grief seeds is already the tormented soul of a former magical girl damned to this for eternity.
Rym: But then they are doing they're killing them.
Scott: That is sort of weird.
Scott: It's like Cubase trying to get energy.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But he gets the energy from the filled grief seeds.
Scott: But he's that's what he collects in his ass.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But he said that the energy is.
Scott: it was it was I think.
Rym: he said the energy is released when they become a witch.
Rym: So it's like in the Golden Compass, which you haven't read.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway, it's like that.
Scott: But it's like, so why is he collecting these fill?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I think he was collecting them just to put him back out in the world.
Rym: Who knows?
Scott: But there was, you know, that's another thing is like every even every little thing can be explained, you know, like, well, if it takes a magical girl to become a witch, how come there's like, you know, it seems like there's plenty of witches for them to fight.
Scott: Well, because witch fragments can happen.
Scott: That's why this is.
Scott: That's how come there's such a great quantity of witches.
Scott: Notice something even though there's way more witches than magical.
Rym: Qubay says and a lot of them like Yoko knew this, that a fragment becomes a witch once it's killed.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So Sayaka, I think, killed those guys on the train.
Scott: Probably.
Rym: And the reason I think this is look at her as a witch.
Rym: It's half the motif of her life.
Rym: You know, Madoka and the boy and the music.
Rym: The other half of the motif is trains.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, her weapon is the train wheels.
Scott: It's true, which they were sort of wagon wheels.
Rym: Yeah, but they were also the trains going in the background.
Rym: So I looked at all the other witches and every witch has two distinct elements together.
Rym: And I I am pretty sure the writers thought of that very tightly.
Scott: It was very intentional.
Scott: The style of every witch was representing, you know, something very specific and essentially episode 10 where there's like a whole ton of witches because you see like the one that's on the clotheslines and all kinds of.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Scott: You know, it was like it was like a feast of witches.
Rym: It also had that old anime thing.
Scott: It was almost fan service because like witches.
Rym: The Groundhog Day reveals had the other big part of not just Groundhog Day, but Cleopatra.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, that was actually.
Scott: you saw that in episode nine, really.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But once you get all of that, that's a lot like Ursa and Sura too.
Rym: When at the end, the dream eaters like all throughout history, Adolf Hitler.
Rym: That was me.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I like that kind of shit because it ties it in, you know, even though it's a future world, it ties it to the real world somehow.
Rym: But seriously, how many shows have the main character in the end wishing to become a god?
Rym: And that actually happens and that is the end.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Well, she didn't wish to become a god.
Scott: She wished that magical girl that there were no there were no witches and that she would destroy all the.
Rym: she wished that she would destroy every witch that had ever been and ever would be, which immediately implied that she would take all the grief of the world into herself.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And then she makes a gigantic soul gem.
Rym: So think about this.
Rym: She is now basically a goddess who can who has all the grief of the world and all the hope of the world in herself.
Rym: She doles out the hope through magical girls and she doles out the grief as demons for the magical girls to fight.
Scott: And there's that one really quick thing that you that you have to really you know, it's it's sort of quick, but you have to really pay attention to it.
Scott: In episode 12, where she did the giant, you see the giant soul gem.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's like, oh, she's collected all the despair.
Scott: And also all the, you know, the hope all at once.
Scott: And then it's like, well, you know, and then there's like the giant witch with like the sun moon face that grabs the whole earth.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And then she's like, well, no, if my witch comes true, I kill this one, too.
Scott: And she holds that one, too.
Rym: I like how even Cubase, like when when she makes the witch, it's like the almost the first time when I almost detected a slight bit of consternation on his part.
Rym: He's like, ah, this might not be good.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: That was really touching, though, when I like a homeroom remembers her, which is very important.
Scott: And the whole the whole ribbon thing.
Rym: Yeah, the ribbon thing.
Rym: And then the little brother.
Scott: And she talks to Madoka's mom, the best character in the show.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: That was just really touching.
Scott: If there's any girls out there who are like Madoka's mom, call me.
Rym: There are.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, she has a lot of the aspects of characters like that we've liked, but she also has responsibility.
Rym: I mean, in Ava, we may have liked certain characters, but they were not the most responsible.
Scott: That's actually, you know, Madoka's mom is like a grown up, a more grown up Masato who is not crazy and doesn't really have emotional problems.
Scott: That's exactly what she's like, has the same kind of personality and hotness.
Scott: Right.
Scott: She's you know, they both have really important positions in big organizations.
Rym: Like, why don't you become the CEO?
Rym: And she's like, huh, well, if I get Baldy out of the way and I do this, I like that action.
Scott: That was good.
Rym: And just that scene again where her mom confronts her, like, you know what's up.
Rym: And Madoka puts on her adult face, which really harkens back to the scene where, you know, her mom's drinking whiskey at night.
Rym: And she's like and Madoka is like, I really want to drink whiskey with you someday, mom.
Rym: And the mom's like, you should go for it.
Rym: Growing up is kind of sucks, but it's also kind of fun.
Rym: And that's kind of my sentiment.
Rym: But then when she tells her mom, like, I have to do this and her mom is like, I trust you.
Rym: And she lets her go.
Rym: That was.
Rym: you never see that in anime.
Scott: And in the mom, even they even said like sensible things, the kind of sensible things you don't hear, which is like, let the firefighters hit, you know, because as far as the mom didn't know, as well, Pergus Knight, the mom thought it was, you know, a tsunami, not
Rym: a tsunami, which basically fucks everything up.
Scott: They thought it was just a really big typhoon.
Rym: They didn't think it was just little things like when Kyoko is like, how do you know while Pergus Knight is going to be there this time?
Rym: She's like, statistics.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Rym: She's really funny.
Scott: She's bullshitting.
Rym: Well, you know, you could argue with statistics 100 percent of my sample.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: Well, Pergus Knight always fucking shows up every goddamn time.
Scott: I don't know what else is there to say.
Rym: There's so much, but I love this show.
Scott: We could probably talk for a long time.
Rym: I guess the difference between this and a show like Utena or Big O season two is that while there's so much to it, it was very straightforward.
Rym: Like the plot at the end.
Rym: There's no loose ends for us to really have to like rationalize.
Scott: Yeah, it wasn't one of those, you know, while it had the same sort of mood as an Ava.
Rym: What's the real life moral of this show?
Scott: The real life moral of this show is that you shouldn't give up hope, obviously.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Or that you should draw hope from despair.
Rym: There is.
Rym: if there is a balance of hope and despair in the world, then the more despair you have, the more hope you need to have.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But also right when you hope for something right.
Scott: You know, it's also to be careful.
Rym: if you hope for something too much, you'll build despair in yourself as it becomes increasingly impossible.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But also, if you hope that something might happen, that thing happening might, you know, be the thing you hope for.
Scott: It might be great for you, but also might not be great for someone else.
Scott: You know, it's like.
Scott: I really hope X happens.
Scott: OK, X happened.
Scott: Yay.
Scott: But that X happening makes someone else sad.
Rym: Case in point, Kyoko's wish.
Scott: Right.
Rym: That was when I figured out that magical girls become witches.
Rym: Because when she was describing what happened to her and why she became a magical girl and, you know, the horrible consequences that was told through a puppet show that looked just like a witch.
Scott: Yeah, I was like, oh, which is another?
Scott: the sub moral, like the moral of psycho.
Scott: is that?
Scott: like she made it.
Scott: she made the wish, you know, to heal the kid.
Scott: But it was like, did you actually just want him to be better or did you want to be the one to make him better?
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's like it's not the same day.
Rym: Well, Qme says that straight up, even he's like, hey, you sure?
Rym: I love how mommy's like, well, if you want to be a magical girl anyway, at least wish for some cake.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Rym: It'd be a really good cake.
Scott: And then it was cake right away.
Scott: The witch was cake.
Scott: Yeah, it was the cake witch.
Scott: I like how when you fight the witches, that weird witch's name appears in some weird font that you're not supposed to read.
Rym: That was really cool.
Scott: And it's just sort of like.
Scott: it was just sort of like I think that's the kind of stuff like poking fanboys in the ribs, like poke poke.
Rym: I was going to say I'm older now, but when I was younger, like that's the kind of stuff.
Scott: That would have driven you nuts.
Rym: I know.
Rym: I would have been like I would have been comparing screencaps.
Scott: You would have been going online to look up the names of all the witches.
Rym: I mean, I did that with Ava the first time I watched it.
Rym: I was like going frame by frame through the opener, like what's going on?
Scott: What's the name of all the angels?
Rym: Yeah, I was reading like like old Kabbalah stuff and looking at the tree of life and trying to figure it out.
Scott: All right.
Rym: I'm past that point in my life.
Scott: Me too.
Scott: I can accept that they just wanted to use a stylistic font and make it, you know, names.
Rym: But the thing is, I bet it is consistent.
Rym: They probably did have some rationale behind it.
Scott: I think they just made it look sort of like...
Rym: No, no, because that's the best way to make a consistent universe.
Rym: is you just figure out as a writer, like, all right, this is the real deal.
Rym: Just so you know, like whenever you have a question like what would happen here, you can look at your real deal notes.
Rym: and if you just follow your real deal notes as though that's the reality, all the stuff you add to the story as you write, even if the real deal notes are never in the story, will be consistent.
Scott: Nah.
Rym: And I'm pretty sure that people do stuff like that.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know.
Rym: It's the kind of thing where if I had a studio, I'd take my like creative interns, I'd be like, "Design a witch.
Rym: Just tell me why this person's a witch and we'll run with it from
Rym: there.".
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And the show, you don't need to reveal that, but it gives you a really interesting, consistent narrative.
Scott: It does.
Rym: God, this show was awesome.
Scott: It's a pretty good show.
Scott: There's a lot, this is pretty good for 12 episodes, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: What other show gets that much in 12 episodes?
Rym: I know, not many.
Scott: Not any.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I can't even think of one.
Scott: Maybe best 12 episode show.
Rym: I think we're done.
Rym: I mean, I can't analyze it more because it's really straightforward.
Rym: The interesting non-straightforward parts are really just the execution and the individual events.
Rym: After that whole scene we were talking about where Sokka's complaining about how she's, the bombs are dangerous to her as a close range fighter.
Rym: The next scene is that she's time stopped and she's walking through the Yakuza headquarters just stealing their pistols.
Scott: And then she goes to the armory of the SDF and just takes all the guns and she sticks them all inside her little shield thingy.
Scott: That's another thing, right?
Scott: She groundhog dayed all those times, but that means she lived to the end all those times.
Scott: If she would have died in any one of those, she wouldn't have been able to use the time stop to go back.
Rym: And she even got close in a few.
Rym: They were both dying.
Scott: Yeah, you could tell she would have given up right there, that would have been it.
Rym: But I didn't think about, you know, I kept thinking like, wow, she's kind of trapped.
Rym: It's much like when I was a kid playing Final Fantasy 5.
Scott: It's like, no, she has to make it because this isn't how it ends.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But in Final Fantasy 5, I had the blue mage who had a power, he had a spell you could cast that would reset the battle.
Rym: you were in as though it hadn't happened, but you were still in the battle.
Rym: I was fighting the shield dragon.
Rym: I was not powerful enough to beat the shield dragon.
Rym: I had that spell.
Rym: I couldn't give up.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You just kept resetting the battle and refighting the shield dragon.
Scott: And you know what?
Scott: There was no chance of beating the shield dragon because you were not high level enough.
Rym: After some, after like an hour and a half, I gave up.
Scott: See what they should have done though and to fix Final Fantasy was you get experience even for the amount of the shield dragon you beat.
Scott: But I'm saying, but again, if the blue, the blue mage would have died, you wouldn't be able to reset.
Rym: Even after all these reveals, there's something I did not consider.
Rym: Like I should have considered it.
Rym: I feel dumb for not having considered it.
Rym: But when Cubay was like, this is the, this is the last reality.
Rym: And I was like, what?
Rym: And then when her soul gem is darkening and she's about to give up, I realized like, oh wait, yeah, she might eventually give up or she might be forced to because she'll become a witch.
Scott: I mean, I don't think there was anything that like that was guaranteeing that that was the last chance, but I think you may figure it out.
Scott: It was the last chance, but it's like, yeah, but Cubay was like, look, she's going to give up hope at some point and that will be the end.
Scott: And that just happened to be also be the time she was giving up hope.
Rym: I just get the impression she tried like every combination of saving people and it was the Walpurgis Knight was the thing that really screwed it up other than the fact that they'd all become witches someday.
Scott: But yeah, well because it's like if you have to fight a more powerful witch, you have to use all your magic to beat it, which means you're going to, that's going to be the end of you.
Rym: And you know, I feel like Walpurgis Knight was by design Cubay.
Scott: I think it was actually more like it was, if you looked at the design of it, right, it was almost like a combination, like a bunch of witches had been combined together to make Walpurgis Knight.
Scott: Like it attacks, it had like that whole group of dancing shadow girls around it.
Scott: And it also had like it after she blew it up pretty good.
Scott: It sent like three shadow girls flying after her at once.
Scott: It was like Walpurgis Knight was almost like a witch army as opposed to just being one witch.
Scott: It was just like one big witch in the middle of a witch army.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: All right.
Rym: I think we're done.
Scott: I think we've been long enough.
Rym: It's not like Utena where we have the literary analysis.
Rym: So I love the show.
Rym: And the thing is, I've already seen it twice.
Rym: I can't watch it again.
Scott: I can watch it again many years down the road.
Scott: It's a show that hopefully someone else will make a show like this.
Rym: It's a show.
Rym: It's one of those rare shows that I will buy because I want to own a copy of it to give to other people and say, hey, watch this.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: It depends on how they sell it.
Rym: Well, right now I've got a pirated set of 12 episodes.
Scott: That's good enough.
Scott: Enter HD.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando Kay for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.