Rym: It's Wednesday, May 11th, 2011.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, how we got into all this stuff.
Rym: Let's do this.
Scott: So a couple days ago, biking over the bridge.
Rym: Biking over the bridge like you do.
Scott: Coming over here, and I see this guy on a bike.
Scott: And it's a normal bike with two wheels, pedals, seat, handlebars.
Rym: And clearly some other factor.
Scott: The seats and handlebars were like at least six or seven feet off the ground.
Scott: And I'm like, look at this fucking hipster.
Rym: So it wasn't a bike with one really big wheel and one really tiny wheel.
Scott: Nope.
Scott: It was a perfectly normal bike.
Scott: It just happened to be that the seat and handlebars and I guess pedals were elevated.
Scott: You know, it was basically a very tall frame, you know.
Rym: I'd be worried I'd hit my head on that bridge.
Scott: I also would, but I guess he didn't.
Scott: I don't know how he got on the bike to begin with.
Scott: But I was like, look at this fucking hipster.
Scott: And I wanted to take a picture and put him on that website.
Scott: Look at this fucking hipster.
Scott: But I was biking, so now...
Rym: Now why is it that someone like that is now a hipster?
Rym: When at RIT, someone like that was just a guy.
Rym: Because there were people who did crap like that.
Scott: No, they had unicycles, which were normal.
Rym: Ah, they also, apparently now, there's that picture of that weird ass cow bike.
Scott: Cow bike?
Scott: Oh yeah, that's art.
Rym: Is it art or is it a hipster?
Rym: It's art.
Rym: Hipster or art?
Scott: The point is, now I'm thinking, right, I gotta get one of those, you know, sporty, wearing your helmet camera things.
Scott: Whatever.
Rym: They're not that expensive.
Scott: No, but what's the one that the guy was wearing when he accidentally fell off the mountain and survived?
Rym: Oh, I don't remember offhand.
Scott: Because all the videos you see with that one are like ultra HD awesome.
Rym: I saw a lot of people when I was skiing, right?
Rym: They had flip cameras and they had things designed to hold a flip camera on their helmets.
Scott: I don't want to do that.
Scott: I want one of the ones that's designed to do that.
Scott: And I don't want it to look dorky.
Scott: It's gotta be, you know, it can't be like sticking out like an antenna.
Scott: It's gotta be, you know, normal.
Rym: See, I don't know.
Rym: I thought it'd be cool in one way, but at the same time, I don't mountain bike anymore.
Rym: So what are you gonna see?
Rym: You're gonna see the same thing a car sees when it goes around New York.
Scott: Well, no, but the point is, you actually see a lot more than what a car sees because you don't have a roof, right?
Scott: So you have a much wider angle of view in general, even though a camera has a less angle of view than my eyeballs.
Rym: But I'm saying in terms of me biking to work, you're gonna see what a car sees.
Scott: Right, but basically what you'll do is, you know, I'll just leave it on whenever I'm biking around.
Rym: Oh, and then if something happens, you go back.
Scott: And if something happens, like look at this fucking hipster, then when I get home, I'll just edit that out and put it on YouTube and delete everything else on the camera.
Scott: I'm not gonna, you know, make a video of going to work.
Scott: That's boring as hell.
Rym: Not a bad idea.
Scott: Yeah, plus I can make videos like, "Look, this is how to get on the secret
Scott: stairs.".
Rym: I heard you finally found the secret stairs.
Scott: I found the secret stairs.
Rym: You see how they're kind of not obvious.
Scott: Incredibly not obvious.
Scott: There's no one even anywhere near them, which I don't think anyone uses them, which is why they're...
Rym: I've never seen someone going in, but I've seen many people coming out as I was coming out.
Scott: No, I'm going in.
Rym: When am I gonna be able to go in?
Rym: This weekend we're playing diplomacy and then I'm going to Spotcastle.
Scott: I might go this weekend.
Scott: Oh.
Scott: 'Cause I'm definitely not going next weekend.
Scott: No chance.
Scott: Maybe the weekend after that I could go again.
Rym: What is next weekend?
Scott: What?
Rym: Alright, bar camp.
Scott: Bar camp and also library overnight.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Come on, you can fit it in between the library and the bar camp.
Scott: All two hours in between.
Rym: Two hours, you could make it over the RFK and back down.
Scott: Uh, from the library?
Rym: Go from the library.
Rym: Where's bar camp?
Scott: Uh, on 50-something on 6th Avenue?
Rym: I think in two hours you could go from the library, up...
Scott: After being up all night?
Rym: Yeah, over the RFK, back around, back to bar camp.
Scott: Yeah, no.
Rym: One time when I was in high school, I had more than 48 hours of not sleeping because I had an all-night party after school.
Rym: Like a rollerblading all-night thing.
Rym: And then the next day at a Quiz Bowl tournament, like in the morning, that was all day.
Rym: And then that night, I went back to the school and we broke into the band director's office and painted it.
Rym: All night.
Rym: And then the next morning, as I was driving home, I ran a bunch of stop lights and then I fell asleep in my car, just parked on the street.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Well, the library thing does have a sleeping room, but it's only for power naps, apparently.
Scott: And, uh, yeah.
Rym: You're not gonna wanna sleep through that.
Scott: I might take the Friday off and sleep and wake up and go to the library.
Rym: Ahhh.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: Anyway.
Rym: So, it's Wednesday.
Rym: Tons of anime news.
Rym: The industry is just abuzz with activity currently.
Scott: Oh, I'm sure.
Rym: So, I wanna talk a little bit about, you know, I think the only reason it's becoming popular in our forum, in that people are talking about it, is 'cause there's no ponies anymore.
Rym: I feel like ponies were drawing a lot of our forum's energy, and now that ponies are somewhat subsided temporarily, people are looking at other things.
Rym: They're trying to get their fix.
Rym: Well, I mean, I tried- Any way they can.
Scott: I mean, this pony energy, right?
Scott: It was so forceful and it had direction, right?
Scott: But now that the ponies have faded and it's going into another season, I tried to manually steer and funnel that energy in a different direction.
Scott: And the direction I attempted to steer it was the best direction, Hajime no Ippo.
Rym: Ahhh.
Scott: I have transferred my pony energies in that direction.
Rym: I have transferred mine into not consuming, like some people do, not simply watching what others have done, but making things myself.
Scott: I'm also making things.
Rym: While I'm behind on that pony video I've been working on for a while, it's almost done.
Rym: And that other pony thing is almost done.
Scott: Yeah, your pony energy has faded, huh?
Rym: Now, they actually are almost done.
Scott: Yeah, I have.
Scott: The first 90% takes 90% of the time, and the last 10% takes the other 90% of the time.
Rym: I have a third pony thing that interrupted them momentarily, and ConnectiCon.
Rym: But the third pony thing is actually really easy to make, and much like Kanie a Pony does not have to be good because the concept is it.
Scott: The Kanie a Pony was real good though.
Rym: Yeah, but that was minimum effort.
Rym: That was like BS effort.
Scott: That was pretty good.
Rym: Huh?
Rym: Well.
Scott: It was more well done than a lot of the videos out there.
Rym: Yeah, it's not saying that much though.
Rym: But I'm gonna mash up Fluttershy and the dragon.
Scott: Alright.
Rym: With my year with the dragon.
Rym: Good move.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: You could also do Pete's Dragon.
Rym: Oh my god, I wanna watch Pete's Dragon and do a show on it now.
Scott: Or Puff the Magic Dragon.
Scott: Eh.
Scott: Or I am the last one.
Rym: You know, as much as I hated that movie, I loved that movie.
Scott: I know you loved that movie.
Rym: Yeah, because the movie was bad in every possible way.
Rym: The plot was bullshit.
Rym: But it had Sean Connery playing a dragon.
Scott: Usually the video, except instead of using either one of the two big dragons, do Spike or he's the last one.
Rym: So anyway, Wakfu is basically, I saw this forever.
Rym: There were ads and stuff about it.
Rym: It was one of those things where you'd see it and say wow, that's a thing that someone is trying to promote.
Scott: I thought it was a word that meant something like weeaboo or you know.
Scott: Really?
Scott: Yeah, I didn't know.
Rym: I remember just at PAX there'd be gigantic things about this.
Rym: It was like a turn-based tactical RPG MMO something.
Rym: And I'd see this crazy art and I remember always thinking wow, that reeks of effort and ignoring it.
Rym: Like just completely ignoring it.
Rym: I mean, I ignore most things.
Rym: It's not really a, I don't know, a complaint about a thing that I have ignored it because I have ignored the majority of things ever.
Rym: And apparently among all the media blitz there is a cartoon in France.
Rym: In French.
Rym: And I watched an episode of it.
Rym: It was okay.
Scott: But isn't this like a Square Enix thing?
Scott: So why is the cartoon French?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I don't know much about it.
Rym: But the cartoon is French.
Rym: I guess they outsourced it to France because France is where most of the good animation that isn't coming from.
Rym: Japan comes from.
Rym: And America obviously.
Rym: France is like big on the animation.
Rym: And the cartoon is actually kind of funny.
Rym: I don't know what I mean.
Rym: I'm not even going to geek bite it yet.
Rym: This is like a pre-geek bite.
Rym: It might fill my need to watch something on this level until ponies come back.
Rym: But it's not nearly as good as ponies.
Scott: Hajime no Ippo.
Scott: What the fuck?
Rym: I'm also watching that.
Scott: Alright.
Scott: You haven't even finished watching Okotoro Cat, have you?
Rym: I'm also watching that.
Rym: But you know what?
Rym: Unlike some people, I'm creating.
Scott: I'm also making things slowly.
Rym: Yeah, also slowly.
Scott: It's harder for me to make a program than it is for you to make a Kanye video.
Rym: Yeah, well I've been making programs too.
Scott: Yeah, you're not making the difficult programs I'm making.
Rym: Not yet, no.
Scott: Anyway, so.
Scott: Blackjack.
Scott: Everyone knows Blackjack.
Scott: If you don't, what the fuck?
Rym: You should watch some Blackjack.
Scott: And read some Blackjack.
Scott: But anyway.
Rym: If you like house, you'll like Blackjack.
Scott: Anyway, there's a Blackjack OAV, and it's ten episodes.
Scott: So ten separate VHS tapes or DVDs were released over the course of the years from 1993 to 2000.
Scott: So yeah, they're probably VHS tapes.
Scott: And it was one episode per tape, right?
Scott: But for now, they're going to release an eleventh and final OAV.
Scott: Ten years after volume ten, we're gonna get volume eleven.
Scott: Wow.
Scott: How about that?
Scott: That's crazy.
Rym: Was it done recently?
Rym: Was it like in a hopper?
Rym: Is it new?
Scott: No, it says the Blackjack original video anime series by the late Osamu Dezaki will get an eleventh and final volume more than a decade after the previous volume.
Scott: And the original voice actors for Blackjack and Pinocchio will reprise their roles, and they will record their lines during a live stream on Niko Nikodoga on Saturday, May 14th.
Rym: That's actually pretty cool.
Scott: Japan time, 1 a.m.
Scott: Eastern.
Scott: So if you're up at 1 a.m.
Scott: and you go to Niko Niko, you can watch the voice actors record the lines for this eleventh...
Rym: So I heard what happens in this episode, actually.
Rym: It resolves Princess Knight.
Rym: We gotta finish Astro Boy 80s, too, while we're at it.
Scott: It's a good one.
Rym: 'Cause we got most of the way through.
Scott: I forget what episode we were on then.
Rym: I don't even know.
Scott: We watched the one where there was a train in the wilderness with all the whole class of kids.
Rym: It went to the moon, all that stuff.
Scott: Was that the same one with the bees, or was the bees a different one?
Rym: The bees was before that, I think.
Scott: I can't, I don't know.
Rym: Let's pick a random, we should watch the end and go backwards.
Rym: That's the easiest way.
Scott: I think that's a bad idea, but yeah.
Rym: Or Hokodona can, I kinda just guess, 'cause I always think, "Oh, I just watched episode
Rym: 24.".
Rym: "I will remember this, and then the next day I
Rym: forget.".
Scott: Here's a secret of space.
Scott: Wikipedia has a list of episodes for pretty much every show.
Rym: You just go and find the synopsis and be like, "Oh, I remember
Rym: that.".
Scott: Yeah, so anytime there's a long show, I just go wiki, space, list of My Little Pony episodes, for example.
Scott: And then I look down the list and I find the episode that I'm on, and then I watch it.
Scott: It works really well for Hokodona can episodes, 'cause there's 150 of them.
Scott: Good luck remembering.
Rym: So things of the day.
Rym: This is not the greatest thing in and of itself.
Rym: The product, the thing, that is my thing of the day, is a cool concept, executed, I would say, the bare minimum required.
Rym: Like, this is the bottom of this kind of thing.
Rym: But I think there's going to be a huge wave of this, like in the next five, six years or so, in terms of active prosthetics.
Rym: Mostly for costumers, cosplayers, and furries.
Rym: Basically, they're, you know, Nekomimi, the cat ears that people wear on their head.
Rym: But they're a little different.
Rym: They're robotic.
Rym: They move.
Rym: They move around.
Rym: They'll twitch, they'll go flat, they'll perk up, they'll turn at things.
Rym: But the way they do this isn't just random or with switches.
Rym: It actually has one of those kind of toy-level, shit-tier brainwave readers.
Scott: Does it really read your brainwaves, or does it just say it does and it just sort of does things randomly?
Rym: It's actually really easy to do that.
Rym: Like, remember that toy that I think Dorkly did, or not Dorkly, before Bleepboop?
Rym: They actually reviewed the Star Wars Force Trainer.
Scott: The Star Wars Force thing, yeah.
Scott: Isn't that just random and bullshit also?
Scott: No.
Rym: It's really easy.
Rym: I mean, basically you look for certain basic patterns in the overall brainwaves.
Rym: That sort of stuff is actually kind of easy to do.
Scott: Cos I remember, you remember back in the day there was a thing you could put on your finger that you were supposed to control the computer mouse with it?
Scott: That they was like, this was in the mid-90s.
Rym: The things that we use now that do that and actually work are based on the same principles.
Scott: I still have a hard time believing this principle isn't complete bullshit.
Rym: You're completely wrong.
Rym: Just absolutely.
Scott: There's no way that it can actually be precise enough to where you're actually consciously controlling something.
Rym: You're not consciously controlling them.
Rym: Here's the thing.
Rym: I said shit-tier.
Rym: This is the bottom type.
Rym: The Star Wars Force Trainer and things like that, they basically read the most overall frequencies.
Rym: Because it's pretty trivial.
Rym: We could very easily build equipment that could scan that level of brainwave.
Rym: You can tell if someone is excited, relaxed.
Rym: That's about it.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So basically what these things do is if your activity goes up at all, they perk up.
Rym: And if it goes down, they go flat.
Rym: And I don't know what causes them to twitch.
Rym: But it's kind of cute.
Rym: And while this is not the best product, I really think that there's going to be a big wave of active prosthetics within the next decade.
Scott: All I'm saying is I could make one that does things randomly and no one would be able to tell the difference.
Rym: At the same time, while that is possibly true for now, it'd be pretty easy to engage in tests to prove how it's reacting.
Scott: When we get to the point where someone can wear them and I could say, "Put them
Scott: down."
Scott: And they put them down.
Scott: And I can put them up.
Scott: And they put them up.
Scott: Then that is...
Rym: That's an entirely different kind of thing.
Rym: And two, there are games, a whole class of games, they don't work that well, but they work okay, where you can learn to do things like that.
Scott: Yeah, if you have like an fMRI and not a pair of cat ears.
Rym: Actually, no, you don't need an fMRI to do things like that.
Rym: Anyway, your ignorance aside, what do you have?
Scott: So, I didn't have a good thing of the day.
Scott: So I didn't want to use CollegeHumor as is our fallback.
Scott: So I went to fallback number two, cinematicmassacre.com.
Rym: Ah, shit.
Scott: I haven't talked about them in a while, but I just want to remind everyone, there's a guy named James Rolfe.
Scott: He is the awesome.
Scott: He is like us.
Scott: He is our kindred type person.
Scott: Even though we didn't meet him, even at MAGFest, we wanted to meet him.
Scott: And he was there.
Scott: And he is the Angry Video Game Nerd, if you did not know.
Scott: If you don't know the Angry Video Game Nerd, well, guess what?
Rym: You know what?
Rym: He's going to take you back to the past to play the shitty games that sucked ass.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Well, they still suck ass.
Rym: That song will get stuck in your head and you'll catch yourself humming.
Rym: He'd rather let a buffalo take a diarrhea dump in his ear.
Scott: He's been coming out pretty, you know, he used to come out with videos pretty irregularly, right?
Scott: Except for the month of October, we had a video every day.
Scott: He's been coming out with videos much more regularly as of late.
Scott: At least one video every day.
Scott: He'll even put out like a crap video or something that he just threw together just to put something out almost every weekday.
Scott: And what he's been doing a lot lately is Ninja Turtles, animated Ninja Turtles.
Scott: I think it's because he's rewatching animated Ninja Turtles, all of it.
Scott: So it's on his brain, so he's making a lot of videos.
Rym: I have this weird feeling that that show will not be as good as I remember it being.
Scott: No, I don't think you should actually rewatch the show like he is.
Scott: I think you should just watch his reviews of the show, where he's cut out clips and put them in an entertaining context.
Scott: However, there's one particular Ninja Turtle video that is my thing of the day that he has put up, his most recent video as of this podcast.
Scott: And it is Michelangelo's Pizza Taste Test.
Scott: If you remember, during the Ninja Turtle show, Michelangelo would, you know, the animation at least, Michelangelo would- Was a party dude.
Scott: He was a party dude, and he would always order pizzas.
Scott: He was, he cared about, all the turtles loved pizza, but Michelangelo loved it ten times as much.
Rym: Kind of like how in the Mario cartoon, they all cared about lasagna and pasta.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Well, Michelangelo, if you don't remember, he always got crazy fucked up pizzas.
Scott: Like pepperoni and marshmallow, or avocado, chili pepper- That sounds really good.
Scott: Clam sauce pizza.
Rym: That still sounds really good.
Scott: So, James Rolfe and a bunch of his friends had a party, where they ordered a whole bunch of plain cheese pizzas, and they made every single one of Michelangelo's crazy pizzas by applying the toppings to the plain cheese delivery pizza, and I guess heating it up a bit.
Scott: And then they took a pizza slicer and cut, you know, one slice of pizza into a bunch of little bits.
Scott: So they each had pretty much a few bites of each nasty pizza.
Scott: That way they had enough room in the stomach to try all of them.
Scott: And he shows you pretty much a clip of Michelangelo saying what the pizza is, and then them eating it, and judging the different flavors.
Scott: And it gets, uh, some of them are pretty nasty, some of them are not as nasty.
Scott: Apparently anything with hot fudge was the worst.
Rym: Yeah, that sounds about right.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: This video's awesome.
Rym: So, I'm hungry now.
Rym: And it goes- I want that avocado chili pepper pizza.
Scott: It goes very much in line with our Hacking the Boardwalk episode of, you know- Oh my god, I got a link to that now.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So, get to the meta moment.
Rym: This is meta because it involves us.
Rym: But many years ago, and the fact that it was many years ago makes me feel really old, we were in Wildwood, our kind of perennial summer writer's retreat hangout where we dick around and don't do anything except sleep on the beach and eat Russo's Subs, 99 cent pizza.
Rym: And one day, we just, you know, there's a place that has like deep fried Oreos, deep fried, you know, whatever.
Scott: They're retelling a story that was already in a podcast that people can just listen to.
Rym: Because that wasn't a podcast for many, many, many years ago?
Scott: It's still there.
Rym: Anyway, briefly.
Rym: So, the guy was like, you know, he has all this stuff and he'll fry whatever.
Rym: So, we go up to him, we're like, "If we bring you a slice of pepperoni pizza, will you deep fry
Rym: it?".
Rym: And we photoblogged us going through all of this and eventually eating the deep fried pepperoni pizza.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: It was pretty epic and it tasted like a Hot Pocket.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much.
Rym: But this weekend, on Friday, is the Nerd NYC board game night where you're always at, at Think Coffee downtown.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: If you wanna hang out with us and actually hang out, as many listeners have been doing recently, come down, play some games.
Rym: We'll be there.
Rym: We're friendly.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Already mentioned, BarCamp NYC is May 21st and 22nd.
Scott: You gotta go to the BarCamp NYC 6 website to register.
Scott: It's free and then you just gotta show up.
Rym: Tomorrow, Thursday, May 12th, from 7pm until whenever.
Rym: I don't know exactly when.
Scott: I thought that was Friday the 13th at 7pm.
Rym: No.
Scott: No?
Rym: No, it's May 12th.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: 7pm, no quarter exhibition of games.
Rym: This is in New York City on Broadway, 721 Broadway.
Rym: It is an exhibition of games.
Scott: Alright.
Rym: It looks really cool.
Rym: It's NYU's Game Center.
Scott: Nice.
Scott: Recess, Nerd NYC Recess is June 18th and that's all the events we'll talk about for now.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: PAX, PAX Dev, all that.
Rym: We'll probably be at 'em.
Scott: That's a long time from now.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: And you can't come, but this weekend we're playing an epic game of diplomacy for the worldwide championship belt.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: We'll have some pictures of the winner, maybe some video.
Scott: Maybe.
Scott: And you should join our forum.
Rym: Forum's rockin'.
Scott: If you, you know, a lot of people out there, you're lurkers or maybe you don't do internet forums or you think you don't do internet forums.
Rym: Don't do internet forums.
Rym: They all suck.
Rym: Accept ours.
Scott: Change your ways and go to forum.frontrowcrew.com, sign up, make sure you just, you can type something in the box that says "Why are you
Scott: joining?".
Scott: Just type, it doesn't matter what you type, you just have to type something.
Scott: that makes me believe that you are not a robot, that you are an actual human being.
Scott: And then you will be approved and then you can talk to everybody.
Scott: and people are talking all the time about ponies.
Rym: The real reason our forum is better than all the others, and you should know this going in, we have very few rules.
Rym: You can do whatever you want as long as you do it with correct grammar and spelling.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: That's really it.
Rym: So we did a slightly similar show a long time ago about how to get into all these things.
Scott: How to get into, you know, it was a how to get into, I think, a week, right?
Scott: It was how to get into, right?
Scott: And it was basically, if you haven't done XGeekery, here is how to start doing XGeekery.
Scott: And the thing is, the answer almost always is...
Rym: Start doing it.
Scott: Do whatever it is.
Scott: I want to get into playing flute.
Scott: Flute!
Scott: Well, you know what?
Scott: Go get yourself a flute and start playing it.
Scott: And go and get some flute instructional videos and search for how to play flute on Google and read the instructions and do it.
Scott: And replace flute with anything, you know?
Scott: I want to do electronics.
Scott: Go buy an Arduino and just go to the websites, read what it says, and follow the instructions.
Scott: That's how you do things.
Scott: But we don't actually do a whole lot of, you know, personal reflection kind of podcasts on GeekNights.
Rym: Even though people want it.
Rym: And I think what happened was we used to a lot more in the old days.
Rym: Because we had a gigantic store...
Scott: Oh yeah, we had Geek Fables were very...
Rym: We had a store of anecdotes reaching back decades.
Scott: And we... We used most of the notable and memorable ones.
Rym: In well over 700 episodes of GeekNights, we have talked about the bamboo.
Rym: We've talked about the vision.
Rym: We've talked about...
Scott: The vision and the bamboo go together.
Rym: Oh my god, the vision happened.
Rym: Well, the vision precursor was before the bamboo.
Rym: But the vision culminated...
Scott: Without the vision, there would have been no bamboo.
Rym: That bamboo was one of the darker visions.
Rym: That was perhaps the worst thing that has ever happened.
Rym: What do you see?
Rym: Bamboo!
Rym: What do you smell?
Scott: No.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: You know, but the other thing is, you know, I've said this before.
Scott: But I want to try to make it so that, you know, if there's a GeekNights episode, that anyone who... Even if it's your... Any episode should be able to be someone's first episode.
Scott: So we shouldn't talk about anything that's like community based or so personal that it excludes...
Rym: Like, "Oh, Amnushu was doing something on the
Rym: farm.".
Rym: Right.
Scott: So anyone who isn't already a GeekNights listener doesn't give two shits about that.
Scott: But this, you know, if we talk about our own personal stories, how did you start... How did you discover X?
Rym: No, Scott, I'm worried here.
Rym: We're starting this show by rationalizing why we're doing this show.
Rym: We're like, "Don't worry.
Rym: Don't worry.
Rym: Here's why we're doing it.
Scott: It's
Scott: okay.".
Scott: Well, because if any time you do something contrary to your philosophy on the internet, you risk being called out.
Rym: How is this in any way contrary?
Rym: No, in fact, people like the anecdotes.
Rym: The only time people get mad and call us out is when you talk about politics.
Scott: Which I don't want to talk about.
Rym: I always do.
Rym: I can hit Scogeal on here.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: So, let's start with comics.
Rym: Regular superhero comics.
Scott: Well, it doesn't have to be superhero.
Scott: I mean, comics are comics, right?
Rym: Ah, but I got into... Well, I had three levels of comics.
Rym: The first comics I got into were actually just, you know, Foxtrot kind of comics.
Rym: Bloom County.
Scott: I think everyone was that way.
Scott: Reading comics in the newspaper before reading any other sorts of comics.
Rym: If I think way back, the first newspaper comics that I was aware of... Like, I, as a sentient human, recognized that what I was reading was a comic in a newspaper, and that I was enjoying, was Calvin and Hobbes, probably.
Rym: Yeah, probably.
Rym: Maybe a lot of that crap like High and Lowest and Cathy, because it was just there, and I'd read it.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean, like, in those early days, reading comics in the newspaper, it was like a lot...
Rym: I'd just read them all.
Scott: I hated... I just, like, ignored the vast majority of them.
Rym: I hated them all.
Rym: Almost.
Rym: But I read them all anyway.
Rym: You know why?
Rym: Because I was sitting at the table, eating a bowl of cereal.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: When you're eight...
Scott: What are you gonna read?
Rym: When you're eight, eating a bowl of cereal might as well take four years.
Scott: You're gonna read it?
Scott: Is he gonna read the cereal box?
Rym: That is infinite time.
Rym: You've already read the cereal box.
Scott: And you've already done the mini page.
Rym: There's this great cyanide and happiness recently.
Rym: A guy goes into the shitter to take a shit, right?
Rym: He sits down and he's like, "Oh, no.
Rym: I forgot my smartphone.
Rym: What'll I
Rym: do?".
Rym: And then it has this series of frames of, like, zooming in on his eye, and then his eye becomes stars, and endless cosmos has come and go.
Rym: The infinite passing of epochs.
Rym: Yeah, but you think we're impatient now?
Rym: When I was eight?
Rym: So I'd read the entirety of the funnies, and I don't know why.
Scott: I skipped over the Rex Morgan MDs and the funky winker beans.
Rym: The thing is, Rex Morgan, there were two words in the whole comic.
Scott: Or apartment 3Gs.
Rym: So you say you don't read.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I read them because there was nothing in them.
Rym: I did not process.
Rym: I saw, but did not see.
Scott: What always did bother me, though, was some newspapers that have some comics and others wouldn't.
Rym: Oh, that was the worst, because we got the Detroit News.
Scott: Sometimes you'd get a comic on Sunday, but you wouldn't get it during the week.
Rym: Ah, we got the Detroit News and the Detroit Free Press, so we got all the good comics.
Rym: But if I went to anyone else's house and they got some shit newspaper, I'd stay over at a friend's house and they'd have USA Today.
Scott: It was weird, though, right?
Scott: Because even though I read comics in the newspaper, I had absolutely no interest in actual comic books.
Scott: I knew they existed, and I knew who these characters were because I watched 60s Batman reruns on TV.
Scott: So I knew when I saw Batman '89.
Scott: I knew who all these superheroes were.
Scott: Superman.
Scott: Of course I knew who Superman and Spider-Man were.
Scott: But I had absolutely no interest in reading comics.
Scott: I looked down on comics.
Scott: I didn't want to read comic books.
Rym: Well, see, I had this weird thing.
Scott: I don't know why.
Scott: I just didn't want to read them.
Rym: The moment where I went from reading the newspaper comics because, literally, I had infinite amounts of time and I had to do something or I would have gone crazy.
Rym: I was when my parents would buy the Bloom County compilation, the big book of Calvin and Hobbes.
Scott: Yeah, we never bought any of those.
Rym: We bought all of those.
Rym: So basically, as soon as those appeared in my life, I read them and comics went from this kind of nothing activity to something I actively seeked out.
Rym: And as a result, I only sought these specific comics that were good.
Rym: From then on, I really only read Calvin and Hobbes, Foxtrot, Overboard.
Rym: For some reason, I have this weird fondness for Overboard.
Scott: I don't even know what Overboard is.
Scott: Really?
Scott: It was about pirates.
Scott: We don't have that one, but now I wish we had that one because it's about pirates.
Rym: It's about pirates.
Rym: Imagine if Dilbert were about pirates.
Rym: That's really the best way I can describe it.
Scott: I even had one of my friends gave me an X-Men coloring book that was early '80s X-Men.
Scott: I was like, "Who the hell are the
Scott: X-Men?".
Rym: I also had, maybe it was just my family, we had every Mad Magazine going back to almost the beginning.
Scott: My mom still has them.
Rym: Every goddamn Mad Magazine.
Scott: Did not have any Mad Magazines.
Scott: But I knew that it existed and I had no interest.
Rym: In fact, a lot of them are pretty valuable today because they're all in me condition.
Rym: So as a kid, shortly after that, after reading all these other comics, I found this Mad collection.
Rym: I read every one of them.
Rym: We also had these old, they smelled like old people books of peanuts.
Rym: I've read almost every Peanuts comic ever.
Scott: I read those in my elementary school library.
Scott: They're like little paperback ones.
Rym: Yeah, the little paperback ones that smelled bad and fell apart.
Scott: Yep, exactly.
Scott: Same ones.
Rym: So that is how I got into comics.
Rym: In fact, my mom had all these old Fantastic Fours that I didn't like, but they were there.
Rym: I really only liked Peanuts and Overboard and Bloom County and all that.
Rym: That's actually kind of an aside.
Rym: That's how I got into politics.
Rym: Because as a kid, you don't really know.
Rym: When I was young, I didn't know right wing, left wing, Republican, anything at all.
Scott: I didn't either.
Rym: I knew the Soviets want Anukas and the basic things that kids know.
Scott: I didn't even know that until at that time.
Rym: And I was really interested in the Gulf War because I was convinced that I knew how to fix it.
Rym: And that it was my duty to tell President Bush.
Rym: And I got kind of frustrated and disturbed as a kid.
Rym: I was worried that if I didn't tell an adult, that the war would keep going.
Rym: And I started to feel responsible for the war.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: I was a weird kid.
Rym: But I got into politics because I read Bloom County so much that I knew all the proper nouns of 80s politics in the US.
Scott: See, because I read a lot of those comics and I didn't even understand that they were political.
Scott: Because a lot of them all basically have other jokes at the same time.
Rym: Yeah, I guess I got interested in both.
Rym: Or at least I'd recognize names of people.
Scott: This is elementary school we're talking about.
Rym: So that's how I got into politics.
Rym: But that's also how I got into comics, reading these big compilation books.
Scott: See, what happened to me, right?
Rym: Didn't read superheroes because I thought they were stupid.
Rym: Even as a little kid, I thought Superman was stupid.
Scott: Yeah, I did too.
Scott: But it's like, I didn't actively think he was stupid.
Scott: I just kind of didn't care at all.
Rym: I thought superheroes were stupid as a kid.
Rym: I just thought they were a dumb thing and I wasn't interested in them.
Scott: I mean, I liked 60s Batman when I was in elementary school.
Rym: With Adam West, I watched that movie endlessly.
Scott: I never actually saw that until much later.
Scott: But the '89 Batman I liked.
Rym: We had a VHS tape of it that I'd watch every now and then.
Scott: But it wasn't until like in the early 90s, like '91, right?
Scott: I guess it was '09 or '10, '08, '09, '10, something like that, right?
Scott: My friend down the street who I'd go over to his house, he suddenly was reading comic books.
Scott: And I was like, what?
Scott: Because no one I knew had ever read comic books.
Scott: And I didn't care.
Rym: There were like one or two nerdy kids in my school who, you know, I was nerdy but in different ways, who read comics.
Rym: And everyone else, just no one cared about comics.
Scott: It's like I saw Dennis the Menace reading comics in cartoons.
Scott: Or I saw Calvin reading comics.
Rym: I had this weird impression of superhero comics.
Rym: Maybe it's just because the only comics in my house were really, really old comics.
Rym: And I'd only ever see comics in old comics, referring to people reading comics.
Rym: Comics were a thing that kids in the 20s read that nobody cares about today.
Rym: I thought they were like this archaic, lost art form.
Scott: Yeah, I'd never actually seen people with comic books.
Scott: Even though I sort of knew they existed, I didn't want or care to read them.
Scott: But then a kid down the street got them and he was reading like Iron Man and Moon Knight.
Rym: Moon Knight?
Scott: You know Moon Knight?
Rym: I know about Moon Knight.
Scott: And like Infinity Gauntlet and Morbius and all this stuff.
Scott: And I was like, okay, whatever.
Scott: And I didn't really read them, but you know what I did do?
Scott: I started collecting, obviously this was the early 90s.
Rym: The cards?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I collected the cards before I learned who the X-Men were from collecting the X-Men cards because those cards had stats on the back.
Rym: Yup, yup.
Rym: And for some reason I was like, whoa, Wolverine has the strength of that?
Rym: But this Jean Grey character?
Rym: Yup, yup.
Rym: And I got really interested based on that and that alone.
Scott: So in the early 90s, right, there was sort of this explosion.
Scott: Like friend down the street is reading comics.
Scott: I didn't really read any of his comics, but I saw that he was reading them.
Scott: And then comic book shock opens in the mall, right near my house.
Scott: And then I went to the comic shop in the mall and I was collecting baseball cards.
Scott: at the time, you know, because I had been doing that.
Rym: I never collected those.
Scott: Well, my dad basically would like buy a pack every week and so it just built up.
Scott: I also would do like those sticker books.
Scott: Like I have an Alf sticker book that has 3D glasses.
Rym: I had a Teenage Mutant Ninja Turtles one.
Scott: I had that one.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And those were basically cards, but every, you know, the cards had two stickers.
Rym: I collected a lot of weird things along those lines.
Rym: Like Beavis and Butthead, there was a trading card series that I just had.
Scott: I had an Alf trading card series.
Rym: I had all the Nintendo ones.
Scott: I didn't have Nintendo ones.
Rym: But it's weird that we collected those cards for the comic books, but didn't read the comic books.
Scott: Well, I did.
Scott: See, it was basically shortly after, right?
Scott: So it's like the X-Men cartoon came onto TV.
Scott: You know, my friend down the street was reading comics.
Rym: X-Men cartoon is.
Rym: what did it for me.
Scott: I was going to the comic book store to buy these cards, right?
Scott: And then, you know, I bought, I started buying comics.
Scott: And basically the thing was I didn't have a lot of money as a punk kid, right?
Scott: And I spent most of the money on the cards, which are actually really expensive.
Scott: So the only two comics I read as a kid were Spider-Man 2099 and Adjectiveless X-Men.
Scott: And barely anything else at all.
Rym: Ah, for me it was the Uncanny X-Men and X-Men, and X-Factor and X-Force.
Rym: Because basically I knew, by then I knew about the X-Men and I was collecting the cards, but I didn't read the comics at all.
Rym: And independently, you know, when the cartoon came out, I got really into the cartoon, but not anything else.
Rym: Like just the cartoon was all I liked.
Rym: I didn't care about the comics related to it.
Rym: But, around all those times, comic books got suddenly popular.
Rym: Like suddenly I started seeing everyone around reading them.
Scott: Well, it was because people, you know, there was a huge speculation boom going on.
Scott: Which was pretty much the story of comics in the 90s.
Rym: So I was into board games.
Scott: Of course, being young impressionable 10 year olds, we got caught up in that real easily.
Rym: But I was into board games, right?
Rym: So I got this X-Men board game.
Rym: And it was pretty shit.
Rym: But it came with all these figures that I painted poorly.
Rym: And it came with one copy of X-Men.
Rym: And it was right after the end of the Executioner's Song was where that comic was.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: Executioner's Song trade paperback is coming out real soon.
Scott: I'm ordering it.
Rym: Oh shit, I should read that.
Rym: That's the only, that is the only story in all of X-Men I've read all the way through.
Scott: Ever.
Rym: So basically, this comic that came with the game was like the denouement to that.
Rym: It was like Beast and Cyclops just talking about all the shit that went down.
Rym: And I was like, this isn't what I expected.
Rym: It's mostly words.
Scott: Well, that was, you know, it was probably Claremont who was the wordiest, you know, Claremont and Burn are the wordiest motherfuckers in the universe.
Rym: And as a result, I got this mistaken impression.
Rym: I was like, oh, comics are actually kind of erudite.
Rym: Look at all that metaphor.
Rym: Mmm.
Scott: They were trying to be.
Rym: Yeah, I didn't know better.
Rym: So then I went and I bought the comic that came before that one.
Rym: And then I realized there was this story and I had to buy a bunch of X-Factors and X-Forces and all this bullshit.
Rym: And I got it all.
Rym: And I read it all.
Rym: And I kept reading X-Men from that point until about Phalanx, all that stuff.
Rym: And then I just stopped.
Rym: I couldn't tell you why.
Scott: I stopped.
Scott: I can tell you exactly why I stopped.
Scott: Because the comic book store in the mall went out of business.
Scott: So I couldn't get, I couldn't get the next comic.
Scott: So then basically I just, you know, it's weird.
Scott: It's like the comic store disappeared.
Scott: And I was just like, uh, I mean, X, something happened in X-Men, uh, like around issue 30, 31, where it's like one issue, like skipped a bunch of plot.
Scott: And I was like, what the fuck?
Scott: or whatever.
Scott: And I really only cared about Spider-Man 2099 because X-Men dicked me over like that.
Scott: But then the comic store closed and I couldn't get the next issue.
Scott: And I tried like a little bit and then I gave up until the year like 2001.
Scott: Right.
Scott: In the year 2001, I can tell you exactly what happened because it's much more recent.
Scott: Uh, I was already back into the animes, right?
Scott: We were at RIT and, uh, we went to Borders a lot to look at the mangas there.
Scott: And because of the anime, we were looking at mangas.
Scott: And what I saw on the comic shelf, they had, you know, over by the magazine racks, not by the manga shelf, but by the magazine racks, it was Ghost in the Shell 2 number one.
Scott: So I picked that up and I was actually going to Borders to buy that comic book and that comic book only.
Scott: And then, uh, in our second year at RIT, my friend Ian shows up, right?
Scott: Uh, cause he went to RIT also.
Rym: Oh right, that's when you guys would go to the secret mall.
Rym: And he said, hey, you want to go to the comic shop?
Scott: And I'm like, yeah, I'd need the next issue of Ghost in the Shell.
Scott: If they have it there, then, you know, I won't have to go to Borders and maybe it'll be better there.
Rym: That was when I learned of the comic shop culture because that was the shop where, like, Luke and everybody had their account.
Scott: Well, no, they went to a different shop than us.
Scott: They went to, uh, they went to Comic Book Heaven, which is run by an old guy.
Rym: Yeah, because there was drama between that guy and the anime club I had to deal with.
Scott: Yeah, no, that was a different one.
Scott: That was, uh, Empire Comics.
Scott: That was the third shop.
Rym: I didn't know there was a third shop.
Rym: The only one I actually ever went to to buy comics was the one in Hippie Mall.
Scott: Comics was the drama.
Scott: Comic Book Heaven was the old guy.
Scott: The one that I went to in the Hippie Mall was comic books, et cetera.
Scott: Rochester had a lot of nerdy stuff because it was in Millennium Games.
Rym: That Hippie Mall was pretty great.
Scott: The Hippie Mall was pretty great.
Scott: Comic, et cetera, was a pretty great shop.
Scott: I liked the way they were organized by sort of feel, you know.
Scott: And the thing is that when I went to comics, et cetera, right, I tried, I basically wanted to ignore the Marvel and the DC stuff because I didn't, you know, I was money conscious and I didn't want to get caught up in, you know, these crossovers and all that bullshit that I knew was going on.
Scott: So I was, I would only buy like mini series if it was a Marvel or DC thing, you know, like I bought, uh, and I basically just looked at the shelf and picked stuff out.
Scott: Like I read this, uh, it was a series mostly for kids, Sentinel.
Scott: It was a self-contained series about a Sentinel.
Scott: This kid finds a Sentinel in his backyard.
Scott: It's, I still have it.
Scott: It's pretty awesome.
Scott: I liked it.
Scott: There was a Voltron comic.
Scott: That was pretty good.
Scott: Uh, and I was also starting to, you know, see what mangas were coming out.
Scott: Like, you know, I bought all of Akira for the first time.
Scott: I just finished buying it for the second time.
Rym: I have a much, it's weird.
Rym: I have such an like older and spotty history of manga because anime I get into, you know, when I was eight, fourth grade, my mom made me watch vampire hunter D against my will.
Rym: But around, I watched all the anime I could get forever.
Rym: And then it wasn't until high school.
Rym: Cause I knew vaguely around like my freshman year of high school that manga existed.
Rym: I heard of it.
Rym: I was like, I heard that anime was all based on Japanese comics and I got really interested in that and you couldn't get it.
Rym: It just wasn't anywhere.
Scott: Well, actually the thing was is in the comic shop that I went to as a kid that didn't close yet, there was one small area that I always completely ignored.
Scott: that had a whole bunch of Ranma half tapes.
Scott: And probably, you know, they probably had all those like Viz manga that were in individual issues, you know, uh, and they probably had, you know, the, the, all that stuff.
Rym: Ah, see the comic shops near me didn't have anything like that.
Scott: And I just completely ignored it and didn't give a shit.
Rym: The first manga I ever saw.
Scott: Just like I ignored all those image comics.
Scott: I basically, I was, I was really, I guess it was cause I didn't have enough money to buy all the comics.
Scott: That there was just something in me that's like I, when I was a kid, I like completely ignored and like I was really judging before trying almost everything.
Scott: Well, for me, the first.
Scott: And if I hadn't done that, I probably would have ended up buying.
Rym: I wanted manga.
Scott: A bunch of cool stuff.
Rym: And I would have bought it all.
Rym: It just wasn't available.
Rym: And then one day I was in Florida with a marching band trip.
Rym: I think it was 10th grade.
Scott: And you found a manga.
Rym: And we, the last day, like we're going to fly out like late in the afternoon.
Rym: So we were all supposed to go into like Disney world or something or just like stay in the hotel.
Rym: We totally just ran off and went like downtown and went all over the place.
Rym: And eventually we ended up in the Virgin Megastore and they had a gigantic manga section.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Virgin Megastore was always weird.
Scott: We went to the one in New York before it closed.
Scott: Uh, at least the time square one.
Scott: Remember?
Rym: And I remember I'm looking at her.
Rym: Yeah, I do remember that.
Scott: And the thing was is they had, you know, it's, they only sell, it's basically a giant FYE, but they have absolutely everything.
Scott: So they even have the manga.
Rym: So I see the manga and I'm like, holy shit.
Rym: And my couple of friends who were in anime are like, holy shit, manga.
Rym: And we're looking at it and looking at it and I didn't have much money left and they didn't have much money left.
Rym: And I saw in the middle of all of it, a Tenchi manga.
Rym: And I was really into Tenchi Muya.
Scott: Oh, good guy.
Rym: So I was like, fuck yeah.
Rym: And I bought it.
Scott: Nice.
Rym: It was the first manga I ever bought.
Rym: And then I just kept reading manga from that point onward.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, I mean, you know, anime is a sort of different, you know, I mean, I got into manga because I was in the anime club at RIT and we went to Borders and I saw manga there and I was already, I was already in the anime.
Scott: So there you go.
Scott: It was already super into anime.
Scott: It went right across the table.
Rym: Like anime club at RIT, my thought was, all right, I'll meet more than a handful of people who are super into anime.
Rym: Little did I know, I thought I was hardcore until I got to RIT anime.
Scott: We weren't even hardcore when we left RIT yet.
Rym: I know.
Scott: But yeah, it's like I got into anime sort of like gradually, like it wasn't something that it was the forefront of my mind.
Scott: It was sort of just like, you know, I mean, obviously I watched the Transformers and the Voltron as a kid, which, you know, and all those sorts of things and Thundercats and, you know, things that were sort of anime sort of weren't, you know, depending on what it was.
Scott: And then I knew animes existed and I kind of wanted to watch them.
Scott: Like, you know, in the late 80s, like Akira was in the newspaper and I knew that it existed.
Scott: And I was like, oh, I kind of want to watch that.
Scott: But it wasn't actually until like Toonami when I would, you know, actually, you know, like, I mean, the local station, like syndicate Sailor Moon, but I didn't watch Sailor Moon.
Scott: I was like, fuck Sailor Moon.
Rym: By the time of Toonami, I already had a sizable VHS anime collection.
Rym: I had already bought hundreds and hundreds and hundreds of dollars worth of fansubs.
Scott: Yeah, not at all.
Rym: So when, you know, Toonami rolled around, I started watching, you know, and also when Sci-Fi Channel, you know, did their thing, you know, like I spent like 400 bucks to get all of Sailor Moon because I had to get SVHS tapes and mail them to a dude.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't know about fansubs existing until I got to RIT.
Rym: And that's in fact, that's where I got End of Eva.
Rym: I didn't know what Evangelion was, but I got End of Eva and I was like, hey, I got this anime movie and all my friends, we sat down and watched it.
Rym: And at the end they were like, Rym, what the fuck?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: That was great.
Rym: Especially when later I finally like learned what Eva was and I started watching it.
Rym: And then I thought after a few episodes, like, wait a minute.
Rym: I know how this ends.
Rym: Oh, oh.
Rym: But it's like in high school and even pretty much from fourth grade on, I was super into anime.
Rym: Anime was my second geekery.
Rym: The only thing more important than anime was gaming.
Rym: So I watched all the anime I could get.
Rym: I rented every goddamn anime from Blockbuster.
Rym: I just constantly, me and my little brother got into it.
Rym: I got my parents into it.
Rym: I'd watch Vampire Hunter D when I was a little kid over and over and over again.
Rym: I'd wanted to dress up as him for Halloween.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: You know, I slowly towards late, you know, once Toonami came out, there was slowly more animes, right?
Scott: I would watch more on sci-fi channel.
Scott: There was a week of Godzilla followed by a week of anime.
Scott: I was watching the week of Godzilla movies and the next week just happened to be week of anime movies.
Scott: And I watched like Galaxy Express and Fatal Fury.
Scott: Fatal Fury is not so good.
Scott: It's awful.
Scott: You know, and then I was sort of like, all right.
Scott: I was sort of like, like anime was the thing I wanted, but I didn't know or care enough like to try a whole bunch to get more.
Scott: But like I saw RIT Anime Club and I was like, oh, that's where I can get more animes.
Scott: All right.
Rym: And we were already all through high school, our D&D group would meet every Sunday and play for like 12 hours.
Rym: Like all day, every Sunday we'd just play D&D.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: There weren't enough nerds to play D&D by me.
Scott: So I had to be like, you know, when I got to RIT, I was like, all right, now I can play some fucking D&D.
Scott: Which is the only reason we're here today.
Rym: At like 10 a.m.
Rym: we'd all meet and go to the grocery store and buy like a hundred dollars worth of shit.
Rym: And then we'd all converge in the basement of whoever's house.
Rym: We like rotated around and we'd dick around and I want to do them for like a couple of hours.
Rym: Then we'd play D&D forever, get food.
Rym: And then we'd watch whatever anime we were watching.
Rym: And we just would get a VHS tape of every show.
Rym: And we'd always say, we'll watch one episode.
Scott: And we watched all the episodes.
Rym: We'd watch every episode on the VHS tape.
Scott: I think the only anime I watched on a VHS before RIT was a dubbed Akira.
Scott: Someone Let Me.
Rym: I watched at least 50 anime completely on VHS before I got to RIT.
Rym: Probably.
Rym: If you count all the movies and all the OAVs individually.
Rym: Yeah, probably.
Rym: A lot of it was shit.
Rym: Like some of it was great though.
Rym: Like Project Aco has such a, like, it's dear to me watching that stuff.
Scott: I wonder if you hadn't seen Project Aco then and you only saw it now.
Rym: I've met people who've watched it recently because we told them to in those Anime You Should See panels and they loved it.
Rym: And I watched the first one again recently.
Rym: It's goddamn hilarious.
Rym: It really is.
Rym: It holds up funnily the same way that like Mahou Tsekai Tae holds up.
Rym: Like that level of comedy.
Rym: That's fun.
Rym: Of course I didn't know back then until recently when Gerald taught us the origin of Project Aco.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But I even had lulls.
Rym: Like I got into anime and then I'd seen everything I could get my hands on.
Rym: so I had this lull where I didn't watch a lot of anime until I learned I could get fansubs.
Scott: I didn't learn about fansubs until RIT and by then it was just Anime Club Library and then digital fansubs came.
Scott: So it was digital fansubs.
Scott: and then there was like Episode of Gatekeeper and it was like, "Oh, digital
Scott: fansubs!".
Scott: And then we're still at that point.
Rym: See that's how anime fandom and manga fandom for me leveled up.
Rym: It was from casual fan to voracious fan immediately.
Rym: And then the next level up was when I realized there were fansubs.
Scott: Yeah, but think about how I was in that late high school where I was just watching whatever was on TV.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: That's how most people are.
Scott: Period.
Scott: They never advanced beyond that.
Scott: I only advanced because I actively went to RIT Anime Club.
Rym: Now this is my problem with conventions like Otakon.
Rym: To bring it back around.
Rym: Because you know we always complain, it's not the punk kids that bother me.
Rym: It's not, you know, the kids can have their fun.
Rym: There's nothing wrong with all that convention culture.
Rym: What bothers me is that the conventions, as they are run, do not in any way gently push people toward getting more into anime.
Scott: Yeah, the RIT Anime Club succeeded in leveling me up, if not for it.
Scott: If I had gone to some other school, I would have pretty much just been watching anime on TV, not even realizing dubs vs subs was an issue kind of guy.
Rym: And instead, look what happened.
Rym: We did GeekNights.
Rym: We lecture in front of thousands of anime conventions.
Scott: Now I know more about anime than most people in this country.
Rym: In fact, we were complimented by a professor who studies anime and someone who worked on Minky Momo.
Rym: In fact, was the main person behind Minky Momo on our surprising knowledge of anime.
Rym: I wish I could have introduced that guy to Gerald Surratt, Gerald and Clarissa.
Rym: Or Mike Tull.
Scott: Yeah, because we know more than most in this country.
Scott: It's not saying much because there are a zillion people who know more than we do.
Rym: Anime, we're like a B6, like Black Shade 6, I'd say.
Rym: Gerald, they're like Gray 5.
Scott: Yeah, who knows.
Scott: Yeah, but I don't know.
Rym: But anyway, I guess the conventions don't do a good job of pushing people.
Rym: And you know why we leveled up at RIT Anime?
Rym: It was very simple.
Rym: They would tell us a little bit about the show.
Rym: They'd show us a random show and they'd be like, "Yeah, this was done by so and
Rym: so.".
Scott: They didn't do enough, though.
Rym: No, they did the bare minimum, though.
Rym: They'd make in-jokes even if you didn't get them.
Rym: They'd show us the touch movie and they'd be like, "This is probably one of the most depressing things you're ever going to see outside of
Rym: EVA.".
Scott: Yeah, but I mean, it's like Anime World Order was the second level up, right?
Scott: As soon as you listen to their show, it's like, "Oh, I should pay attention to who the director
Scott: is.".
Scott: And then you're fully leveled up.
Rym: But go back to RIT Anime.
Rym: when you wanted to check out tapes.
Rym: After I'd watched every show I already knew about, I'd be looking around and one of the older guys who was running the club at the time, because we were just young punk freshmen.
Rym: We were called the Front Row Crew because we were a group of assholes who sat in the front row and heckled and made noise.
Rym: And they thought about kicking us out of the club.
Rym: And then we took the club over and ran it for many years.
Rym: But we were just punk kids and I'd be standing there looking through the anime and I didn't recognize any of it.
Rym: And the older guys would be like, "Hey, you should watch
Rym: this.".
Rym: And they'd give me K.O.
Rym: Century Beasts.
Rym: I'd be like, "What's it
Rym: about?".
Rym: They'd be like, "Just watch
Rym: it.".
Rym: And I did.
Rym: And that alone got me into whole swaths of anime that I never would have seen.
Scott: I did watch a whole bunch of stuff at RIT Anime Club that I never would have seen.
Scott: Like, say, Kishinkou.
Scott: Kuu.
Scott: Which I still can't find.
Scott: Kuu for the life of me.
Scott: If I hadn't seen it there, I never would have seen it.
Scott: Or Horror's Prince of Sun, right?
Scott: But it was like, I still didn't really fully get them until later.
Rym: No, Anime World Order was the next level up.
Scott: It wasn't until much later that I appreciated what I had seen.
Rym: I mean, I think back that I had access to all of such classics as Marmalade Boy or Kimiguri Orange Road.
Scott: Yeah, right?
Rym: I mean, I watched a lot of that anime and it was because people just told me to.
Rym: And I was like, "Okay, I trust these people.
Rym: They know more than I
Rym: do.".
Rym: And manga, that was the same thing.
Rym: Like, I was into manga, but I only read manga that I already knew.
Scott: Yeah, I pretty much started out buying mangas that went along with animes that I already was watching.
Scott: Like, I bought the Initial D manga.
Scott: I bought the Akira manga.
Rym: My level up was very specific.
Rym: It was Luke and Scojo.
Rym: One day we were at a convention, like an Otakon, and we were walking around and one of them said something like, "You gotta look in the dollar bins.
Rym: That's where you find the crazy stuff like
Rym: Sanctuary.".
Rym: And I was like, "What's
Rym: Sanctuary?".
Rym: And I read the first volume of Sanctuary.
Rym: And that was the moment of revelation.
Rym: I was like, "There's manga like
Rym: this?".
Scott: I believe it was more something along the lines of someone was like, "Yeah, there's a manga about a yakuza and a politician and something,
Scott: something.".
Scott: And we eventually found it, and then we were in business.
Rym: It was mostly that we were told to look in discount bins because you'll find the good stuff there.
Rym: And we were given a small list of awesome titles, which led us to other awesome titles, which eventually led us to...
Scott: Yeah, well, they definitely led us to the eagle direction as well.
Rym: And then eventually we started to notice who wrote things.
Scott: That wasn't until much later.
Rym: Yeah, but it happened.
Scott: But yeah, mangas, I bought them at Borders, and I was only buying a few.
Scott: And then I started going to the comic shop, so I was seeing some more mangas at the comic shop and also media play.
Scott: But there were only so many that I was actually interested in, and I was pretty picky.
Scott: But then, finally, when I got out of RIT and I had a whole pile of money, I was going to the physical comic shop in New York City every week.
Scott: And then eventually, when I couldn't go there anymore because I moved to Beacon, I was doing a mail order from the same shop.
Scott: And then I said, "Wait a minute.
Scott: If I'm mail ordering, I can mail order from this other place for half
Scott: price.".
Scott: But because I was doing that, I was seeing the order form.
Scott: So I knew at that point every single manga that was coming out every single month.
Scott: Because a lot of people, even comic fans, right?
Scott: They're basically the equivalent of what I was to anime in high school.
Scott: They'll watch it on TV.
Scott: So these people in comics, they go to the comic shop and they look at the shelf every week, right?
Scott: And they just buy what they see, what they like, like I was doing at Comics Etc.
Scott: in Rochester.
Scott: And the problem with that is that the vast majority of comic shops, like 99%, don't buy everything there is.
Scott: They can't afford to buy everything there is.
Scott: So if you just look at the shelf, you won't know everything there is.
Scott: And the only way for you to know everything there is, is to get that stupid fucking catalog for four dollars.
Scott: Or do the online ordering with the place that gives you the spreadsheet that I get.
Scott: Right?
Scott: Or, and even then, they'll sell you the stupid catalog.
Scott: Or send you free copies of the stupid catalog without you asking for it and filling up your trash bin.
Scott: But once you get that, you can see everything that's coming out.
Scott: And you can say, "Look at all these mangas that are being printed in English that I don't even know
Scott: existed.".
Scott: Or, "Look at all these comics coming out from indie publishers that I don't even know
Rym: Ah, the indie publishers.
Scott: And that is like the highest level that you can get, is now you see with your eyeballs every comic that is available to you.
Scott: And also the webcomics, don't leave out the webcomics either, right?
Scott: Which I started reading.
Scott: since the year 2000, I've been reading many, many webcomics every single day.
Rym: It was really at RIT.
Rym: You know what got us into webcomics?
Rym: Like, for real?
Rym: It was back then, Mega Tokyo and Penny Arcade.
Rym: And real life comics.
Scott: I gotta be perfectly honest, it was pretty much just Mega Tokyo.
Scott: Somehow I ended up at it, and I was reading it every day.
Rym: We all read it and talked about it.
Rym: We were like, "Oh man, did you read Mega Tokyo?
Rym: Yeah, I wonder what's gonna happen.
Rym: Oh man,
Rym: Margo.".
Scott: And even in those earliest of days, like for a couple months, I was like, "Fuck your 8-bit theater and your Penny
Scott: Arcade.".
Rym: Yeah, I was reading 8-bit theater because I found that shit hilarious.
Scott: But not everyone else did.
Scott: I was not a fan of those immediately.
Scott: I think I was against them the same way I was against all the other comics in the comic shop.
Rym: Yeah, it was basically, I hit Mega Tokyo and I was like, "Oh shit!
Rym: Webcomics!".
Rym: And then I read a million webcomics, realized they all sucked, parroted it down, pretty much like real life, 8-bit theater.
Scott: I added all these webcomics because I was like, "Webcomics are a
Scott: thing!".
Scott: So I started getting a whole bunch of them, and then I got rid of a bunch of them.
Scott: And some of them ended and some of them started.
Scott: Do you remember?
Rym: 8 Bad Boys of Computer Science.
Rym: That's right!
Rym: We gave that fucker from the Bad Boys of Computer Science money.
Scott: The greatest, worst webcomic in all of history.
Rym: It wasn't that great, but one.
Scott: Actually, it was pretty great.
Scott: Not you too, Tribes 2.
Rym: Other than the fact that they drank heavily, the characters, it was very similar to our experiences at RIT.
Rym: And they also were as obsessed with Tribes 2 as we were.
Rym: That was it.
Rym: That's the main reason.
Scott: Bad Boys of Computer Science was the shit.
Rym: It was that, real life, 8-bit theater.
Rym: I read College Roomies from Hell.
Rym: So did Greg.
Rym: Almost no one else did.
Scott: I didn't read that.
Rym: I remember reading a lot of weird stuff, like Not Gonna Take It.
Rym: That was done by Meredith Grin back in the day.
Scott: Alright, so here's the webcomics I'm reading right now.
Scott: Ready?
Scott: Those are all newspaper comics that happen also on the web.
Rym: Dr.
Rym: McGinja.
Scott: Alright, so real life, Penny Arcade, Dr.
Scott: McGinja, XKCD, Wondermark, Johnny Wander, Order of the Stick, Freak Angels, Gun Show, Hark of Vagrant, Axe Cop, Gastrophobia, which I talked about recently.
Rym: I really like Gastrophobia.
Rym: And do you know what has returned?
Rym: What has returned?
Scott: The greatest webcomic of all time.
Rym: The Bad Boys of Computer Science?
Scott: No.
Scott: The Boy on a Stick.
Scott: Oh.
Scott: And Slither.
Rym: I've given up on Boases.
Scott: He's got a new art style too.
Rym: We used to be really into Boases.
Scott: Yeah, he's got a new art style and everything.
Scott: It's pretty awesome.
Scott: Alright.
Rym: Yeah, you like that?
Rym: But all that started from Mega Tokyo.
Rym: So, never ever actually legitimately make fun of some kid who gets into anime from Naruto, because that's how most people get into everything.
Scott: Yeah, there's nothing wrong, right, with the guy who gets into something through something stupid, right?
Scott: Who moves on to the hardcore from a casual thing, right?
Scott: Everyone, even the hardest core guy, started out with something lame, right?
Scott: No one starts out just playing Battletech out of the womb, right?
Scott: They played Monopoly and then Risk and then something else, right?
Scott: I mean, who plays Battletech first thing?
Rym: I was into board games for most of my life.
Rym: I was hardcore into Monopoly.
Rym: I would play full Monopoly games against myself to try and solve it.
Scott: I mean, all that time that I was buying those superhero cards and those comic books, you know what I was spending even more money on?
Scott: Magic the fucking gathering.
Scott: So, I mean, while I look down on it now, it was still, it had its purpose.
Scott: And the only thing you gotta look down on is not starting in these things.
Scott: They shouldn't exist.
Scott: It's that failing to move on from those things.
Scott: If I was still playing Magic now, that would be sad.
Rym: I can't blame people who don't move on because they're never presented with it.
Rym: Because look at all the things we're into.
Scott: If I was still reading Mega Tokyo now, that'd be sad.
Rym: But at the same time, look at us.
Rym: Most of our leveling ups were external things.
Rym: Like, we would put in the first half of the effort, like, I'll go to RIT anime.
Rym: But RIT anime returned with the second half.
Rym: Mega Tokyo still exists.
Rym: Here's some shit.
Rym: Like, here's stuff.
Rym: There was this kind of event that would push us to the next level at every step of the way.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, I put in one half of the effort, which was, this RIT is clearly a nerdy school.
Scott: It has an anime club, it has computers, I wanna go there.
Scott: And then I actually went to those clubs, and that was the extent of my beginning efforts.
Rym: So look at conventions.
Scott: Oh, and when I went to the RWAG, I said, I wanna play D&D and raise my hand.
Scott: That was the extent of my efforts.
Rym: Yup, and RWAG said, here's a guy who's smoked more weed than he should've, who's going to run one and a half awesome sessions of Dungeons & Dragons.
Scott: And if that guy was a horrible guy, dammit that guy.
Rym: You know what?
Scott: If not for that guy, we would not be here today.
Rym: No GeekNights, no front row crew, none of this would've happened.
Scott: If not for that lame guy.
Scott: So it is always a lame thing that is going to get you somehow started in the awesomeness.
Rym: So let's end on, cause we know it's Wednesday, getting into conventions.
Scott: Something like X-Men TV show.
Rym: Because I just complained about how I don't think anime conventions do a good job of providing the second half of the effort to get people more into it.
Rym: And as a result, they're kind of falling in many ways.
Rym: But look at a con like the Penny Arcade Expo.
Rym: A lot of people go there and say things like, I've never played an indie RPG, but holy shit, look at those indie RPGs.
Scott: Yeah, but there also are a lot of people who go to those conventions and they'll sit there and they'll just do the one thing that they want to do and that's it.
Rym: But they don't put forth the effort.
Rym: They don't put forth the first half and say, I wanna try something new.
Scott: The first half was coming to PAX, that was the first half.
Rym: I don't know, I feel like now you've gotta settle for the first half is expressing even the tiniest of interest in anything.
Rym: And you gotta just follow up from there.
Scott: I mean, how many guys go to PAX and stay in the expo hall the entirety of the time and never leave it?
Rym: I think a lot of the people I see who are playing the single player games at the conventions, it's really an issue of.
Rym: they're not super social and they came to the con alone.
Rym: They don't know how to strike up a conversation.
Scott: Well, also think about this, right?
Scott: If I was a little kid, right?
Scott: When you would go to Toys R Us, there would be like a Super Nintendo there with Super Metroid and you'd be like, oh motherfucker.
Rym: I'd be there until my parents dragged me out.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Now, imagine if you still had that mindset and you went to PAX, you could go into the console free play, ask for all these games that your parents wouldn't buy you that you don't have.
Scott: You could check them out and just play them.
Rym: Yeah, but these dudes are like 30.
Scott: I'm just saying is that, you know, that would be, you know, if you still had that mindset of stay at the Super Nintendo demo machine for three hours, then console free play at PAX is freaking amazing to you.
Scott: Because you could just be like, give me give me a fucking fucking Soul Calibur and you just, oh my God, I got Soul Calibur.
Rym: So, but how did we start with all this though?
Rym: You know, we never heard as much as I was into anime.
Rym: I didn't even know anime conventions existed.
Scott: Well, I mean, I sort of understood, you know, from watching TV that there was like Star Trek conventions.
Rym: Exactly.
Rym: I knew that there were two, there were three kinds of conventions, professional conventions that were boring, Star Trek conventions and gaming cons.
Rym: because I went to gaming cons from little kids of mine.
Scott: I did go to a Magic the Gathering tournament event once.
Rym: I went to many of those.
Scott: Right, in middle school.
Rym: But I also went to like Michicon, just straight up, this was a con where you pay per event and I played like eight hour D&D games.
Rym: Everyone there was fat and 40.
Scott: I didn't know that kind of thing existed until much later.
Rym: I knew, but I didn't know there was anime.
Rym: Like it never even crossed my mind that there would be an anime equivalent of those gaming cons.
Scott: I didn't even fully understand that there was a convention.
Scott: Like I saw on TV there would be references to Star Trek conventions, not, you know, like in other shows that were nerdy.
Scott: So I was like, oh, I guess there are Star Trek things.
Scott: I didn't like Star Trek, so I didn't care.
Rym: I didn't know until I went to one.
Rym: The first Michicon I went to, I brought all my D&D books and I brought all these characters because I was like, what I have to, I think I thought I had to bring my characters and I brought all my Magic cards.
Rym: And I look, I didn't, I was like, how do I play a game?
Rym: And this fat guy was like, you got to go sign up.
Rym: So I go and I pay my like five bucks and I signed up for this Magic tournament that I lost.
Rym: And then I signed up for this eight hour long D&D game that was part of a tournament.
Rym: And this Dungeon Master dude ran this tournament D&D session where we like busted into a pyramid.
Rym: And that was like this moment of realization.
Rym: I was like, this is the awesomest thing ever.
Rym: I'm here far away from home.
Rym: It's like two in the morning, no parents.
Rym: I'm playing D&D.
Rym: Oh my God.
Rym: And I just kept going to gaming cons.
Rym: And then at RIT one day someone was like, hey, you want to go to an anime convention?
Scott: Well, I mean like at RIT, they always during the announcements, they would say things about conventions, right?
Rym: But they would say like Otakon is coming and I'd be like, I didn't know what that was.
Scott: They weren't exactly explicit.
Scott: Like no one ever said like there is a thing called a convention, a whole bunch of nerds get together in a hotel or convention center, you pay an admission fee and all these things are there.
Rym: And this might sound crazy.
Rym: They were so unexpected that I didn't know.
Rym: I feel like we're going to Otakon.
Rym: And I was like, I don't even know what that is.
Scott: I completely glossed over what they were saying, like I didn't care and I didn't get it.
Scott: And they weren't.
Scott: so, you know, they didn't say it very well.
Scott: So I didn't comprehend it completely.
Scott: And then somehow someone was like, we're going to Ohio con, you know, do you want to go to Ohio con?
Scott: And I was like, and I sort of finally got it.
Scott: Like there's going to be some sort of anime event.
Rym: Here's what I was told.
Rym: I remember this pretty clearly.
Rym: I don't remember which of the upperclassmen who are now part of the front row crew told us this, but I remember because, you know, back then I didn't know them.
Rym: So they're just like faceless entities that told me stuff all the time, vaguely authoritative.
Scott: Perhaps they were a blur?
Rym: There was a time.
Rym: Oh my God.
Rym: I forgot all about him.
Rym: Ken Hashimoto, the blur, who stole mosh mosh revolution from us, which is fine.
Rym: You're allowed to.
Rym: Ideas are worth nothing, but took credit for it himself.
Rym: Anyway.
Rym: So one of those people, I mean, we used to look up to Scott Johnson as an authority figure.
Rym: So I got, I was under the impression from these people that anime conventions, Ohio con would consist of the following.
Rym: There's tons of girls there in cosplay.
Rym: What is that?
Rym: They're cute.
Rym: There's gaming there.
Rym: There is a place where artists just draw anime shit and you can buy it.
Rym: And it's awesome.
Rym: You can buy anime shit and it's awesome.
Rym: You'll get laid.
Rym: I was told all these things.
Rym: Oh, and you can watch anime there.
Scott: See, I had gone to youth group conventions in high school where you were also told that you would be laid, but there was no nerdiness going on there.
Scott: It was just awesomeness.
Rym: So what do we do?
Rym: We're so pumped.
Rym: The whole, almost like half the front row crew, we all go to this convention in Ohio.
Scott: And most of what we wanted to do was play DDR.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So because DDR, like there were no DDR machines.
Scott: That was when the DDR iron was the hottest.
Rym: There were no DDR machines.
Rym: We were like desperate.
Rym: We would like freak out.
Rym: Like I'd get, someone would IM me on aim and be like, I heard there's DDR and people would like flock to a mall to find a broken pump it up machine.
Rym: So we go to this con, we drive to goddamn motherfucking Ohio to go to Ohio con and we walk in.
Rym: And it was one of the most disappointing experiences of my entire life.
Scott: I wasn't really, I don't know.
Scott: I wasn't disappointed at the time, right?
Scott: But over time of being there, I realized that it was kind of crummy, but it was also the first anime con and there was stuff there that I had not seen.
Scott: It was like this small sampling.
Scott: It was like, it was like, it was like you go there expecting a chocolate bar, like a whole Hershey bar and you get just one square of a Hershey bar.
Rym: But it had everything.
Rym: Like there was an artist alley.
Rym: I'd never seen that before.
Rym: Dealers room, never seen that before.
Rym: I bought fan art and it was awesome.
Scott: I didn't even think I bought actually a pretty good a Unicron fan art.
Rym: Yeah, I bought this thing.
Rym: It was like Vasht the Stampede and knives as punk kids.
Scott: I bought a volume of Trigun Dojinshi that I thought was actual Trigun manga, but wasn't.
Rym: Yeah, I remember that.
Scott: I bought a Apollo World that you can zip her up into a Pokeball for a dollar.
Rym: But all is not lost because while it, you know, we say it was this worst convention, really in retrospect, it was just very poorly run.
Scott: Really poorly run?
Rym: The number of anecdotes that came out of that convention was legendary.
Rym: That's where the Duck Hunt tournament happened.
Rym: That we all won.
Scott: That's where we played Settlers and Midget Whores.
Scott: No exaggeration, no hyperbole whatsoever.
Rym: I can't believe, to this day I look back on that and I'm like, that's the kind of bullshit story I would make up.
Rym: And yet, not only did it happen, but you were there.
Rym: And you would call me on it if we made that shit up.
Scott: We absolutely, 100%, no exaggeration or hyperbole or lying or anything, played Settlers of Catan with a midget whore and a non-midget ugly whore.
Rym: She wasn't that ugly, she was just old.
Scott: I mean, you know, she wasn't a hot whore.
Scott: She was a whore.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Straight up.
Scott: A whore and a midget whore.
Rym: Oh my god, the whores.
Rym: There were so many whores.
Scott: We're not even exact, literally whores.
Rym: And independently, cosplay girls trying to "hook up" with people but really didn't have rooms and just needed somewhere to sleep.
Scott: Oh, and there was Stevie Beast's Catgirls.
Rym: Oh my god.
Scott: And there was the really tall Sailor Moon crossdress and Sailor Bubba and yeah.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Rym: But then, from there we levelled up.
Rym: We gave AnimeCon a second chance.
Rym: Someone was like, "No, we gotta go to
Rym: Otakon.".
Scott: And we went to Otakon 02.
Rym: And it was mind-blowing.
Scott: That was the real deal.
Rym: And I remember we got so excited because eventually we were like, "They're gonna let us be panelists.
Rym: We're gonna be on the Anime Club Summit.
Rym: Oh my
Rym: god!".
Rym: And now, we basically... Well, Otakon probably won't ever let us come back.
Scott: No, but other people do.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But, you know, that's how we got into doing panels and how GeekNights kind of formed as well.
Rym: I think we've talked enough.
Scott: We've talked enough.
Scott: The point is, you know, we all started with stupid shit.
Scott: But, don't make a mistake.
Scott: A lot of people, you know, they think, "Aha, I started with something stupid and I want to introduce this person to my
Scott: geekery.".
Scott: Don't start them off with something stupid.
Rym: Unless you're an expert.
Rym: Experts can start people with something stupid.
Scott: Yeah, it's like I started...
Rym: I mean, Fist of the North Star is stupid.
Rym: Don't even pretend it's not.
Rym: I love it, but it is stupid.
Scott: It's like the first anime I ever saw was a bad dub of some piece of crap on, like, you know, Project Aco.
Scott: Well, what happens?
Rym: Here's the failing.
Rym: One, the dub's not that bad.
Scott: Yeah, no, but I'm saying, you know, that doesn't mean that you should start your friend off on Project Aco.
Rym: Well, here's why I'm saying experts.
Rym: Only pros can get away with that, because it wasn't the crappy fan sub of Aco that was the moment.
Rym: Like, that wasn't good in and of itself.
Rym: You have to recreate the whole experience.
Rym: Like, a lot of the crappy anime that I watched early on, the reason it worked and made me more interested in anime is because I watched it late at night after playing D&D in a dark basement with a bunch of my nerd friends.
Scott: And also because it was rare.
Rym: Yeah, it was weird.
Scott: It was no other way to get it.
Scott: Weird, different, and difficult to obtain.
Rym: So unless you can replicate all those factors, showing someone the crappy fan sub, anime that itself is crap objectively, it's not going to work.
Rym: So unless you're a pro, show them Cowboy Bebop.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: Or a road to Godoji.