Rym: It's Thursday, October 6th, 2011.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight we talk about Scott's shoes and handbag.
Scott: Rym's handbag.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So many years ago, we were traveling from Otakon in Baltimore to Wildwood.
Scott: Why are you jumping to the main bit?
Rym: This is just, I'm talking about an anecdote.
Rym: I'm not talking about shoes and handbags specifically.
Rym: It is just an anecdote.
Scott: No, this is definitely main bit material.
Scott: Somewhat related.
Rym: So, Scott's trying to cover up for the fact that me and Pete were ready to go to the beach.
Scott: Why don't you save the shit for the main bit when it's relevant?
Rym: It's Thursday, it's the lounge.
Rym: Whatever we want.
Scott: Yeah, okay.
Scott: Shove the lounge up your ass.
Rym: Basically, Scott made us wait for him to go to a mall and look at shoes.
Rym: You're already in the mall.
Scott: Before we could go to the beach.
Rym: We were ready to leave.
Rym: I'm like, "Scott, let's get in the car and drive to the
Rym: beach.".
Rym: She's like, "No, I need shoes.
Rym: Right the fuck
Rym: now.".
Rym: Then he goes to the mall and dicks around.
Scott: We were already in the mall.
Rym: Because none of the shoes match his handbag.
Scott: And you couldn't save this for the main bit.
Rym: Me and Pete are like, "We're going to go to GameStop.
Scott: Tell us what you've done with the
Scott: shoes.".
Scott: What are we going to say during the main bit now that we spent it all in the early bit and this is already in a previous episode?
Rym: I'm going to talk about your taste in shoes because it took you so fucking long and you didn't even buy any because none of them matched.
Rym: Did you buy shoes?
Scott: Fine, let's get past your moronic opening bit.
Rym: Did you buy shoes that day?
Scott: I don't even remember.
Scott: No, you didn't.
Scott: So, right now we've got some problems in this country.
Rym: We do.
Scott: Hurting everybody.
Scott: Deep in every people.
Scott: They took her germs.
Rym: They took her germs.
Scott: All the germs taken by the foreigners.
Scott: Taking their germs.
Rym: What would happen, and you see stories like this every now and then, if we just had people who were out of work in America.
Rym: Natural-born citizens do all this work that supposedly these immigrants are stealing.
Scott: Right, it's kind of like, you know, people always wonder, "Well, what if you opened a shoe factory in the US?
Scott: Would anyone work at
Scott: it?".
Scott: Or, you know, would it actually be economically feasible?
Scott: How would it work out if you had a shoe factory here?
Rym: Never mind the fact that there actually is a lot of manufacturing in America.
Rym: The problem is, for employment, that higher-end manufacturing is more skilled labor that requires fewer actual people.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: But I digress.
Scott: Anyway, so, you know, this question keeps being brought up, and people argue about it, but I've never seen anyone actually do it.
Scott: Like, open up, like, the textile mill in the US.
Scott: recently, you know?
Scott: I've seen a lot of, like, some guy move the candy factory to Canada where the sugar tariff is cheaper.
Scott: I've seen that go on.
Scott: But I've never seen anyone try to, you know, get low-end labor in the US and not use illegal immigrants and whatever.
Scott: So, here's the story.
Scott: This farmer, right?
Scott: He goes, and he's trying to figure out how many people he needed to hire to harvest his thousand acres of corn and onions in Colorado.
Scott: So he's like, "Well, you know what?
Scott: Gosh darn
Scott: it.".
Scott: Maybe he's probably not a gosh darn it guy, but anyway.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: He's just, you know, and he goes, he's like, "Look, I'm gonna try to hire Americans, right?
Scott: And pay them the wage that they should
Scott: get.".
Scott: So he's gonna pay him $10.50 an hour, right, to work on this farm, harvesting the corn and the onions.
Scott: So he goes out and he hires people, and you know what?
Scott: They fuckin' lined up.
Scott: He got plenty of people to show up.
Scott: Six hours later, right, what happens?
Scott: Well, they all quit.
Scott: Or at least the vast majority of them quit.
Scott: Most of them just left and never said anything.
Scott: Twenty-five of them said specifically, according to farm records, the work was too hard.
Scott: So he shipped in another truckload of Mexicans to get the job done.
Scott: And they were just happy to finish doing all that work, despite it being so hard.
Rym: Yeah?
Rym: Now, not to say that there is plenty of employment for everyone in America.
Rym: No.
Rym: Because I know that's not true.
Scott: Of course.
Rym: But someone on FARC, very, you know, in the middle of all the discussion about this article, said something very simple and I think very poignant.
Rym: They said, "I think tomatoes and onions should probably be a lot more expensive than they
Rym: are.".
Scott: Well, that's a separate issue of subsidies, and there was a big issue of slave labor to pick crappy Florida tomatoes.
Scott: Go read about Florida tomatoes.
Scott: This is fucked up shit.
Scott: Basically, they're growing tomatoes at a season in Florida.
Scott: It really sucks.
Scott: The tomatoes taste like nothing.
Scott: They pick them when they're green.
Scott: Well, you know, in New York even, Scott- They use chemicals to change the color to red, but they still don't taste like anything.
Rym: Scott, they do use chemicals to prevent the ripening of apples and bananas, too.
Rym: That's a common thing.
Scott: In fact- And we're going to spray chemicals to change the color, but they don't taste like anything.
Rym: Um, I don't know.
Rym: I'd have to read something about that.
Scott: Yeah, at least that's what I read.
Rym: I'm dubious, Scott, of your claim.
Scott: Anyway, that's what I read.
Rym: Okay, I'm just saying.
Rym: It's not a record.
Rym: Public record.
Rym: R.I.M.
Rym: is dubious.
Scott: It's some guy on the internet who's not dubious, right?
Scott: I mean, come on.
Scott: But, you know, the slave labor picking those tomatoes is a huge problem, so here you go.
Rym: Scott, I can tell you who's not dubious.
Rym: The guy- Who wrote the article?
Rym: The guy at the protest, you know, the Wall Street protest, who I walked past today, getting lunch, who is holding up a sign that said, "Frankenfood
Rym: kills.".
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, dude.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Kills what?
Rym: I mean, Wall Street?
Scott: Kills non-Frankenfood?
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: Uh, yeah, that would have been a better opening bit.
Rym: Well, there was that, uh, the Mike Rowe TED Talk that we bring up kind of often, because it's a great TED Talk, where he basically says that Americans are allergic to and afraid of hard work.
Rym: And, personally, I think we have a really messed up world where the jobs that are the shittiest, that hurt you the most, that are the most mind-numbing, the most tedious, also pay the least.
Rym: Right, and it's like, you know, those people- And yet the most fun jobs, like race car driver, a professional hockey player, pay the most.
Scott: Well, I mean, I can sort of agree with those also paying a lot.
Scott: I mean, they probably pay more than they should, but they should still pay a lot, you know, because it's incredibly hard to do, and people are willing to pay to see it.
Scott: You know, part of how much you get paid is how much people are willing to pay for you to do it, right?
Scott: So maybe the answer is that people should be willing to pay more- How much are you willing to pay to have someone remove the trash from the sidewalk?
Rym: All the money.
Rym: I will give up on every luxury I have rather than face the prospect of the poop and trash not disappearing.
Scott: That's correct.
Rym: That is probably my number one thing.
Scott: But the sanitation guys are willing to do it for whatever they are currently getting paid?
Rym: Except when they strike.
Scott: Right, but they're not striking right now, which means they must be happy with their current deal, which means everything's cool, right?
Rym: I guess.
Scott: They're not demanding baseball player money.
Scott: They want their trash to get removed too.
Rym: Yeah, of course we have the problem where if people are desperate enough for work, they will do shitty jobs for very little money.
Rym: But what's interesting is that despite all the claims that our economy is, uh, fuck the fuck up.
Rym: Yeah, fuck the fuck up.
Rym: Still.
Scott: It is still.
Rym: That, uh, a guy can't pay people almost eleven bucks an hour to work six hours a day doing something that's easy.
Rym: if, uh, mind-numbing and body-crushing to do.
Scott: Yeah, well, it's not easy.
Scott: I'm not gonna say that.
Scott: It's not easy.
Scott: But you know what?
Scott: If I had to, I would do it.
Scott: And even if I passed out, I would just force myself to do it.
Scott: I... If that was the job that was available to me...
Rym: I think I might just resort to crime.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Rym: Because I remember at RIT that one summer when I, uh, I didn't work at DiBella's again.
Scott: You worked in the pie factory?
Rym: I worked for a temp agency.
Rym: So every day, like, they'd call me and be like, "Hey, we got a gig for today.
Rym: Do you want
Rym: it?".
Rym: I worked a machine that fed pie tins into another machine that made apple pies.
Scott: Did you get any pies?
Scott: No.
Scott: Not even one pie?
Rym: One of the most horrifying things... They're frozen apple pies.
Rym: Oh.
Rym: The most horrifying thing about this was that, basically, the way the machine worked is.
Rym: I loaded in pie tins.
Rym: I probably loaded in a hundred thousand pie tins.
Scott: That many?
Scott: There's no way.
Rym: Seriously, literally, what I would do is I'd take a box that had, like, a thousand pie tins in it, cut it open, take all the pie tins out, climb up a ladder, and throw them into a machine.
Scott: It didn't matter how they went in the machine?
Scott: It sorted them out?
Scott: Well, no.
Rym: They were, like, stacked.
Rym: I had to put them in these big, like, tracks.
Rym: There were four tracks that I'd keep all the tracks full.
Scott: All right.
Rym: And as fast as I could do this, someone else was bringing more boxes, each with a thousand pie tins in it.
Scott: Did the pies come out that fast?
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Wow.
Rym: So, down the line, other stuff happened, and there was a cooker and a freezer and all this stuff, but there was the apple pie slurry.
Rym: It was a tank bigger than you can possibly imagine, filled with a horrifying mixture of apple pie.
Scott: Did it smell like apple pie at least?
Rym: It smelled like burning cinnamon chemical, as far as I could tell.
Scott: That's not too bad.
Rym: And sickly sweet apple.
Scott: That's pretty good.
Rym: And syrup.
Rym: And basically, the slurry was going blorp, blorp, blorp, blorp, blorp into all these pie tins.
Rym: But every now and then, it would get clogged, and an engineer would come over with a stick and shove it into the slurry mixer.
Scott: Was it a clean stick?
Rym: I guess.
Rym: It was covered in apple.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: That's fine.
Rym: And it was soul-crushing and mind-numbing and paid, I think, $6.75 an hour.
Scott: This is $10.50.
Scott: This is significantly better than that.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: There hasn't been that much inflation since then.
Scott: This pays more.
Rym: And the worst part is, I was doing the job way fast, and the guys who worked there full-time were like, "Slow down, man, or they'll send half of us
Rym: home.".
Scott: Whoa.
Rym: Because they didn't even need all those employees.
Rym: The guys worked slow, because otherwise half of them didn't need to be there.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: I don't know what I would do.
Rym: If that was my life, I wouldn't resort to crime right away.
Rym: But I would do anything to not have to do that.
Scott: But someone has to do it, otherwise society won't function.
Scott: I know, but at the same time- So who's gonna be that someone?
Scott: At the same time, six whatever an hour- But if everyone agrees with you and says, "I'm not doing it,".
Scott: then what?
Rym: Well, then the- No one eats.
Rym: No, then the hourly rate has to go up.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: You pay.
Rym: And what did Adam Smith say in Wealth of Nations?
Rym: That any job that is not worth paying a living wage to do- Isn't worth doing.
Rym: Is not valued enough by the society to be done.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Anyway, we're not economists.
Rym: We're just-.
Rym: I don't think we have a point here.
Scott: The point is, Americans are pussies, right?
Scott: And there are jobs out there.
Scott: I have seen places that are hiring, but people just don't want those jobs.
Rym: Dude, in New York right now, it is so hard to get good tech workers, despite the fact that Wall Street just laid off like 10,000 people.
Rym: Right.
Scott: There's plenty of empty jobs if you A, have skills, or B, are just willing to suck it up and do a job you don't think you want to do.
Rym: It's not just that.
Scott: There's so many people, they had a job playing solitaire all day, they got laid off, and now they don't want to work at Home Depot, which is hiring, and so what do they do?
Scott: Nothing.
Scott: They sit at home and cry.
Rym: So, the other trouble is that most people are not willing to relocate.
Scott: That's also true.
Rym: I mean, look at people who graduated from RIT.
Scott: You can go work on this farm if you move to western Colorado.
Scott: You'll pick corn and onions.
Rym: All these people we knew at RIT who got the same degree as we did, but they stayed in Rochester, where the job pool's not that great because every RIT student also wants to stay in Rochester.
Rym: If they move anywhere, they can get a job.
Rym: Well, anywhere real.
Scott: Well, people are willing to relocate to sit in the street and protest, but they're not willing to relocate to work.
Rym: Oh my god, I could not get out of my office because the protest came up to surround my block.
Rym: There's a park across the street, which I think they put in gaslights, but I literally had to shove the door of my building open into people, like pushing them physically out of the way, and push and shove my way through a crowd just to get home.
Rym: And I got a lot of dirty looks.
Scott: For once, I'm kind of glad that I'm in the touristy area and not in the Wall Street area.
Rym: But it wasn't the angry yelling kid protesters with no shirts smelling of incense.
Rym: It was all old union guys.
Scott: Old union guys, what's up?
Scott: And you know what?
Rym: While I'm pessimistic because the protests don't seem to have any goal other than saying we're discontent, they've got old people on their side now, and seeing that gigantic march of 30 to 50 year old union guys, it looks like an actual movement now.
Rym: Looks like.
Scott: See, here's the thing.
Scott: We've got to measure it by how far it goes.
Scott: When it gets to the streets with numbers.
Scott: Streets with numbers, not avenues with numbers.
Scott: When it's so big it's touching streets with numbers, then I'll go down there every day.
Rym: Actually, you know what I'd like to see?
Rym: If they formed a council or something and made a list of demands that was reasonable?
Scott: That's not necessary.
Scott: I think it's better to just keep it the Internet way.
Scott: Don't try to bring it into the realm of the old people.
Scott: Don't go down to their level.
Scott: Force them to come and interact the Internet way.
Scott: Don't go.
Rym: What I'd love to see is some Democratic senators should just go down and be like, all right, I'll talk to you.
Scott: What's he going to say?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Just get them to talk to him and then he'll get a lot of good PR.
Rym: And that will give the movement legitimacy.
Scott: Legitimacy because someone came and talked to you?
Rym: Yeah, if the government comes and talks to you, that actually counts for a lot of senators like, all right, that doesn't mean he's going to do anything.
Rym: No, but it means that if the left wing or centrist or objective media had even one testicle between them, they could report on it with some air of legitimacy.
Scott: No, no.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway, they could.
Scott: You got any news over there?
Rym: I do.
Rym: So speaking of legitimacy, there's been a movement lately and Reebok and all these shoe companies.
Scott: Why don't you save this for the fucking main bit?
Scott: You're like, we're using all your shoe bits now and you're not going to have any shoe bits when it actually comes time for the real show.
Rym: Scott, I think you underestimate how many shoe bits I have.
Scott: Clearly too many.
Rym: I got a lot to say about shoes.
Scott: Well, you can just carry the whole show then.
Rym: Because unlike you, when I go to buy shoes, I don't prevent other people from getting to the beach and I don't dither forever debating which shoe looks better.
Scott: Right.
Scott: OK.
Rym: Captain took forever to not buy shoes.
Scott: Sure.
Rym: So there's all these shoes lately that are like.
Rym: they make claims like, oh, they make your balance better.
Rym: They tone your muscles better.
Rym: They put they do stuff.
Scott: And it's like they just have a giant soul that's sort of rounded to force you to walk in a weird way.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And I know a lot of people who've said, oh, I'm wearing these shoes for various reasons.
Scott: I've seen I saw ads for the shoes months and months, maybe over a year ago.
Rym: Straight up claims like we have science that says these shoes.
Scott: The first time I ever saw one of those ads, I saw the ad before I ever saw the shoe.
Scott: The first time I ever saw one of those ads in the subway, I looked at it.
Scott: And two seconds later, I'm like, there's no way.
Scott: That's bullshit.
Rym: I was like, that is complete bullshit.
Scott: And then I saw people doing it and I was like, all right, whatever, dude.
Scott: That's bullshit.
Rym: I know some people who are wearing them, but I just said, like, you know, I'm dubious.
Rym: I don't think these do what you think they do.
Rym: But, you know, if you believe the.
Rym: You spent your money on them.
Rym: Well, guess what?
Rym: The FTC came down like a ton of bricks on Reebok, and they have to refund $25 million in these shoes because every claim they made is complete bullshit.
Rym: No.
Rym: Good job, FTC.
Rym: Now, if you just go after the homeopathy.
Scott: Yeah, FTC.
Scott: FTC is weird because, like, once in a while, they hammer someone for false advertising, right?
Scott: But they either don't do a complete hammering and they don't hammer enough.
Rym: Well, here's the thing.
Rym: They did a complete hammer of Reebok.
Rym: Yeah, which is a unit of Adidas, if you didn't know that.
Scott: I didn't know Adidas bought them.
Scott: I thought Reebok was number three.
Rym: Basically, the FTC was like, yeah, your claims are all bullshit.
Rym: Fuck you.
Rym: And they also made a general statement saying all you other people selling similar shoes.
Rym: Yeah, we're coming.
Rym: So Skechers is probably also going to get shut down by this because as far as I can tell, there is no legitimate evidence that any of these funny shoes have any benefits.
Scott: Well, I mean, maybe you personally just think they're more comfortable.
Scott: That's fine.
Rym: But anyone claiming that they, you know, increase muscle tone or help with back problems.
Scott: Yeah, walking with wearing weird shoes does not give more exercise than walking.
Scott: You know what gives more exercise?
Scott: More walking.
Rym: I have seen some studies talking about if you walk around barefoot, your muscles grow faster and some stuff.
Rym: But that's barefoot.
Rym: That's not a funny looking shoe.
Rym: And also, while walking around barefoot may have some benefits.
Rym: At the same time, if you're running a race, running shoes will make you faster than running barefoot, probably.
Scott: Otherwise, the Olympians wouldn't fucking wear them.
Scott: If going barefoot was so great, then Olympians, you know, it's like people always like, oh, what's the best?
Scott: And I'm just like, well, if you're ever wondering what the best is, look at the people who are the best in the world and whatever they're doing is probably what it is.
Scott: Like, what's the best bathing suit?
Scott: That one that the Olympians use.
Scott: What's the best car?
Scott: The F1 car that Michael Schumacher used to drive.
Scott: You know, what's the best shoe?
Scott: Whatever shoe that, you know, Usain Bolt is wearing, that's probably the best shoe there is.
Scott: You should get that one.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's not hard to come up, figure out what the best shoe is.
Rym: So anyway, once again, if you trust anything you see in an advertisement that doesn't have science behind it, you can pretty much assume that as soon as you saw that ad, I appear behind you and said, it's probably bullshit.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: In fact, you can just take and get an MP3 of us saying that's bullshit.
Scott: Yeah, probably bullshit.
Scott: Most definitely bullshit.
Scott: We are dubious.
Scott: That is bullshit.
Scott: Just keep it on repeat and have it on all the time on your headphones.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Just all day.
Rym: So things of the day.
Rym: I like cupcakes.
Rym: You like cupcakes?
Scott: Cupcakes.
Rym: So nothing's better than epic cupcakes.
Rym: This is a cooking video of how to make epic cupcakes and it's pretty great.
Scott: Pretty great?
Rym: It's pretty great.
Rym: I laughed at this and even if you don't like the content of this other than the fact that it's about making cupcakes, I think you'll enjoy it.
Scott: Uh huh.
Rym: Also, it was a collaborative project and it was poking around and I found what looks like the animatic for the people who made this thing.
Scott: This is an animated cupcake.
Scott: It is.
Scott: This is smelling of pony.
Rym: You suggested I use this as a thing of the day.
Scott: I did not suggest it.
Scott: You did.
Scott: Seriously.
Scott: I suggested it sarcastically.
Rym: Uh huh.
Scott: Uh huh.
Scott: And then you legitimately used it and you have thus destroyed the streak of keeping the pony out of the show.
Rym: Pony?
Scott: That's right.
Rym: Regardless, this is pretty great.
Scott: It is pretty great.
Rym: The voice acting.
Scott: Keep it out of, keep the pony out of the show.
Rym: The voice acting is surprisingly.
Scott: It's not the original voice actors, but it might as well be.
Rym: It's really great.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Okay, so, you ever seen that sign that says keep calm and carry on with the picture of the crown?
Rym: Yep.
Scott: And you see it on t-shirts and you see it on all kinds of shit all over the place.
Scott: Well, you ever wonder where the fuck that came from?
Rym: Uh, not until just now.
Scott: Well, I did wonder- Because you wouldn't bring it up unless there was some story here.
Scott: I did wonder where the fuck it came from, but I never found out until finally this article showed up randomly and I was like, "Oh, finally I found out where the fuck this thing came
Scott: from.".
Scott: And actually, it's sort of an incredible story.
Scott: Basically, to sum it up, you can read this to get all the details.
Scott: Some guy in a used bookstore or something found the poster.
Scott: It was an old British war poster that never got used.
Scott: They just, they made them, but they never used them and there are only, like, not many remaining.
Scott: They used these other ones instead that were not as cool, such as the other ones that they did use said, "Freedom is in peril.
Scott: Defend it with all your
Scott: might.".
Rym: And- See, it's funny because when I saw, when I first saw this- When I first saw Keep Calm and Carry On, I thought it was kind of- A protest against people flipping out about this terrorism BS.
Rym: I thought it was like, "Just
Rym: relax.".
Scott: No, it was a legitimate World War II Hitler's bombing us, but Keep Calm poster that never got used.
Rym: So, a question for you, Scott.
Scott: It just got printed, yeah.
Rym: How come we as a society can't go back to that mindset when we have enemies?
Rym: Because, remember in those days- How come we can't just say, you know, stiff upper lip- We can't even pick fucking onions.
Scott: How are we supposed to Keep Calm and Carry On when Hitler is fucking bombing us?
Scott: Scott, to be fair, it's really hard to pick onions.
Rym: 25 people said so.
Scott: Pussy, pussy.
Scott: Alright, so some guy found this poster.
Scott: He hung it up in his store.
Scott: Everyone thought it was cool.
Scott: So, he started making merch with the thing on it and he said, "Listen, I don't care if anyone else uses this sign because I didn't even make it.
Scott: Just give me credit for discovering
Scott: it.".
Scott: You know, because he sort of rediscovered it, right?
Scott: It was lost to history.
Scott: But then some other people basically took it and made merch to sell.
Scott: Didn't give him credit for discovering it.
Scott: And tried to trademark it.
Scott: And the guy even asked the crown, you know, if he could use it.
Scott: You know, the British crown.
Scott: And they were like, "Yeah, sure.
Scott: Go
Scott: ahead.".
Scott: It's sort of this big, sordid tale.
Scott: And it's best summed up by this one post here, this Metafilter comment.
Scott: "Worried about your livelihood printing these posters that you didn't create?
Scott: Keep calm and fuck
Scott: off.".
Scott: So yeah, you should read this thing because it's a pretty fascinating history of something that is a pretty popular slogan and... I guess, logo?
Scott: Slogan thing?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Very briefly, in the meta moment, we'll be at the New York Comic Con as press and professionals only.
Rym: If you want to hang out with us, email us or tweet us and we will possibly be able to hang out with you a little bit.
Rym: The Book Club book was The Ear, The Eye, The Arm.
Rym: The episode about it will be up shortly!
Scott: Go visit us on the internets and all the internet places.
Scott: Look for GeekNights or Front Row Crew on the Facebooks, Twitters.
Rym: Yes, our YouTube channel, which is actually my YouTube channel.
Rym: GeekNights Rym, which we link to periodically, has all of our lectures from PAX East 2011, a bunch of other videos from us, and another show we launched called Radio Free Equestria.
Scott: And next year, MAGFest.
Rym: Oh my god.
Scott: Oh, and this Saturday is Nerd NYC Recess, but we probably won't go...
Rym: We might not go, because it's going to be really warm outside, but...
Scott: Nerd NYC Recess is this Saturday.
Rym: Yes, in New York.
Scott: As in Saturday, October 8th.
Rym: Burning Apocalypse Con is on 11/11/11.
Rym: We will be there!
Rym: I will be running a game.
Scott: Yeah, October 8th is recess.
Rym: In fact, everyone who goes will be running a game.
Scott: That's how it works.
Rym: Even though, as much as I love you, Luke Crane, your math on how many games need to be run is not correct.
Scott: That's correct.
Rym: And I foresee trouble toward the evening on the last day.
Scott: Yeah, no kidding.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: That aside, I'll just tell you all now, I know many times we get invited to conventions, and we often don't go, usually because we have other commitments, but if you want us to attend a convention that you attend, or you just, you know...
Scott: Or you run.
Rym: Or you're some weirdo, and you're trying to get us to attend some con that you've never actually been to, contact the con rather than contacting us, because you tell us, "Hey, you should go to
Rym: X-Con.".
Rym: I'm not going to take any action on that.
Rym: But if you say, "Hey, X-Con, the GeekNights guys are awesome, get them as guests," and X-Con comes to us and says, "Hey, would you like to be
Rym: guests?"
Rym: It is much more likely we will say yes.
Scott: Because it is much more likely they'll give us transportation and lodging.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Now, if you want to get us transportation and lodging, I mean, for PAX.
Rym: one year, we paid to fly John St.
Rym: John to PAX.
Scott: So if you want to pay for us to fly wherever the hell and give us a hotel room, I'll go fucking Madagascar for a convention.
Scott: I don't give a shit.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: I'll hang out with you personally for at least one of the dinners, and then the rest of the time I'm going to disappear, because that's what guests do.
Scott: But yeah, it can happen.
Scott: Do you have monies?
Rym: So, do you ever find shoes, Scott?
Scott: To match that handbag?
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Seriously, he just took for fucking ever, and me and Pete are just standing there like, "Scott, come on, let's
Rym: go.".
Scott: You're greatly exaggerating.
Scott: this five-minute incident has become this epic--.
Rym: Scott's like, "No, I really need
Rym: shoes.".
Rym: And Pete's like, "To match your handbag?
Rym: God, we'll be in
Rym: GameStop.".
Scott: You're greatly exaggerating this ten-minute incident.
Rym: that it was this epic-- You mean the ten minutes when you couldn't decide what shoe to get?
Scott: Right.
Rym: Because it didn't fit, and it didn't match your handbag?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Is that enough?
Rym: Why did you even need shoes like that desperately?
Scott: I don't even remember.
Scott: When the fuck was that?
Scott: It was at least '09, if not earlier.
Scott: Perhaps '08.
Rym: '09?
Rym: That was like '04.
Scott: It was a long time ago.
Rym: That was before GeekNights.
Scott: You're going to the beach, I might have needed new sandals, I think.
Rym: Wow, I realized '04 was technically before GeekNights, but not that much before GeekNights.
Scott: I don't remember when the fuck this was.
Scott: I think it was during GeekNights, because we came back and then you complained about it on GeekNights.
Scott: I complained about it a lot.
Scott: I think it might have been '06, '07, '08.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: So anyway, shoes.
Rym: Oh my gosh.
Rym: I don't want to stereotype, but many of the girls I know personally in the front row crew, I'm making fun of you all right now.
Scott: Many girls I know, period, regardless of front row crew or not.
Rym: Own so many shoes.
Scott: Too many shoes.
Scott: I don't care.
Scott: It's like, you know, okay, women's fashion, whatever, whatever, whatever.
Scott: You do not need more.
Scott: No human being needs more than the following.
Scott: A, a boot for the snow and the dirt.
Rym: No, Scott, I have multiple kinds of boots.
Scott: That is crazy.
Rym: Two.
Rym: Scott, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
Rym: So boots, right?
Rym: One, I need winter snow boots.
Rym: As in they go up around my ankles.
Rym: They're waterproof.
Rym: They're warm.
Rym: They don't slip when I walk on ice and snow.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I need those.
Rym: I also need hiking boots, which are very different from waterproof.
Rym: Same boot.
Rym: No, that's really stupid.
Rym: to use the same boot for both.
Scott: No, it's not stupid.
Scott: Same boot.
Rym: No, I have an Overland low cut.
Rym: It looks like a shoe, but it's actually a boot.
Scott: That's not a boot if it looks like a shoe.
Rym: It's a boot.
Scott: It's not a boot.
Rym: It's a hiking boot.
Scott: You know, it's a boot like the trunk of your car is a boot.
Rym: What?
Rym: That doesn't make any sense.
Scott: How not?
Rym: Because they're not related in any way, nor are you British.
Scott: I said it's a boot like the trunk of your car is a boot.
Scott: As in the trunk of your car is not a boot.
Scott: Therefore, it is also not a boot.
Rym: Scott, the trunk of my car is a boot.
Scott: It's not.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Anyway, I also have fancy boots.
Scott: Conclusion.
Scott: Rims a woman.
Rym: At least I didn't take for fucking ever to get shoes to match my handbag on the way to the beach.
Scott: You need a boot, a slipper, an everyday shoe, which is also a sneaker.
Rym: What's an everyday shoe?
Rym: A sneaker.
Scott: An athletic shoe.
Rym: Scott, what do you mean by sneaker?
Rym: Because for one, you realize in most of the country, like the entire middle of the country, they say tennis shoe to mean- They're retarded.
Rym: Generic shoe.
Scott: Only the east coast is the real place.
Scott: Every other place is not a real place, right?
Scott: They can shut the fuck up.
Rym: But that aside, so I have running shoes.
Rym: I can't just wear those walking around.
Rym: They'll wear out and they also have holes in the bottom, so I've stepped in a puddle, you know, my foot gets wet.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Are these like specialized Usain Bolt sprinting shoes?
Rym: Actually, yeah.
Rym: They're really nice running shoes that I replace every year because I wear them out.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Whatever.
Rym: Because I run all the fucking time.
Scott: Most normal people just buy a sneaker, like a Nike shoe.
Rym: Well, what kind of Nike shoe, Scott?
Rym: Like a cross trainer?
Scott: Whatever kind you like.
Rym: A tennis shoe.
Scott: All that differences are all just bullshit, except for basketball, which needs to be a high top because you hurt your ankle.
Rym: Scott, they actually are all different.
Scott: It's bullshit.
Rym: Scott, what is a cross trainer?
Rym: Do you know what that is?
Scott: It's just a word they use to sell fucking shoes.
Rym: Scott, so you actually believe that?
Rym: Yes.
Rym: As opposed to a running shoe?
Scott: The shoe is a shoe.
Rym: Nope.
Rym: Running shoes are lighter.
Rym: They tend to be narrower.
Rym: They tend to have a more forward, like pronated posture.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: You can run in any fucking shoe.
Scott: You're not a professional runner.
Scott: It doesn't fucking matter.
Rym: It does matter, Scott.
Scott: People fucking run in like the marathon wearing like dress shoes.
Rym: No, that not many people do and the people who do, one, ruin their dress shoes.
Scott: Like for example- There are dress shoe companies that advertise that you can run the marathon in the dress shoes.
Rym: And maybe they're running shoes instead.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Rym: Plus dress shoe is not the same kind of class as cross trainer.
Rym: You could have a cross trainer that looks like a dress shoe or a running shoe that looks like a dress shoe.
Scott: None of that shit matters.
Scott: It's just bullshit to sell you more shoes to women like you.
Rym: Scott, what's the longest distance you've run in the last decade in one go without stopping?
Scott: Probably when we were at RIT and we did that thing.
Rym: Oh, the Chase Corporate Challenge?
Rym: How long was that?
Rym: Scott, I recall beating you by like a half hour.
Scott: That has nothing to do with what shoe we were wearing.
Scott: If I wore Usain Bolt's shoe, I would still have been losing by a half hour.
Rym: So Scott, what I'm saying is that when I run like 10 miles, if I ran 10 miles in say my fencing shoes when I was fencing before or like a tennis shoe or a high top, that would suck ass and I'd have blisters and it would suck.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Scott: Have you done this?
Rym: Uh, yes.
Rym: I've run long distances and high tops before.
Rym: You know what?
Scott: But high top is a different shoe.
Rym: Yes, a different kind of shoe.
Scott: So I have a running shoe.
Scott: There is no difference between like a running shoe and a cross trading shoe.
Scott: They're low top sneakers.
Scott: They're all the same.
Rym: Cross trainers are less like foreign- You're not a professional Olympian.
Scott: It doesn't fucking matter.
Scott: Just like getting to different golf clubs doesn't matter because you're not Tiger Woods.
Rym: So Scott, why don't you buy a shitty old bike?
Rym: because it doesn't matter.
Scott: Because it actually doesn't.
Scott: if you just have the gears are what matters more than anything else.
Rym: Uh, no.
Rym: Other things matter too.
Rym: A steel frame bike is way slower than an aluminum frame bike.
Scott: It matters very little if you're not Lance Armstrong.
Rym: Uh, actually it matters a lot more than you think.
Scott: No, it's psychological.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Anyway- Mister doesn't do any sports.
Rym: Uh- Doesn't know anything about them.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Mister woman who has too many shoes.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: Like I was saying, any normal person needs a boot, a sneaker, that is your everyday shoe, a dress shoe for the dressy times- Actually Scott, my every- My everyday shoe- A handle- Is usually, because I wear the kilt all the time, a boot that I wear.
Rym: Because wearing tennis shoes with a kilt looks fucking stupid.
Scott: It's alright.
Rym: Uh, no.
Rym: It looks crazy bad.
Scott: Who gives a shit?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I kind of care about my appearance.
Rym: I like to look good.
Scott: You're a woman.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: That's all you need.
Scott: Those are the only shoes anyone needs.
Scott: One of each.
Scott: And when one wears out, as in it has holes in it and it is destroyed, then you may replace it.
Rym: What do you wear biking?
Scott: Uh, the shoes that I wear every day.
Rym: Alright, so you're not going to get like clipless shoes to go on clipless pedals?
Scott: Well, that is a different situation because- So now you need another shoe?
Rym: No.
Scott: I thought it didn't fucking matter.
Scott: Because if you get SPD, you can get regular shoes that also happen to have the built-in clamp bracket thingy.
Scott: Yes, but so- It's also a regular shoe, as opposed to the ones that have like the big clamp that sticks out where you can only use it for biking and you cannot use it for any non-biking activities.
Rym: But Scott, I will point out to you that really, if you get a shoe that's good for biking, where you clip in with the little clipless things, I like how I can clip into something that is called a clipless pedal.
Rym: But I digress.
Scott: Well, because the clips are the ones that go over the foot.
Rym: I know, but I can still, most people call it clipping in.
Scott: It's not a clip.
Rym: It's- I know, but you say clipping in or unclipping.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: Which, it means something entirely different if I type ID clip.
Scott: IDDQD is what you really need.
Rym: IDKFA is pretty fun too.
Rym: Or just IDFA.
Scott: Well, I don't know why they had IDFA when IDKFA existed.
Rym: Here's the difference.
Rym: IDKFA is, I just want it fucking all.
Rym: IDFA is, I want all the weapons, but I still want to have to go through the whole mission.
Rym: That's the reason.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: Anyway, that's very important.
Rym: No.
Rym: You need an IDFA and an IDKFA.
Scott: You don't.
Rym: Yes, you do.
Rym: They're different things.
Scott: Could have just done the K. They are different, but you could have just kept the K one.
Rym: So Scott, biking shoes that are good for long distance, like hardcore biking?
Scott: Yeah, of course.
Scott: If you are a specialist in a thing.
Rym: Scott, even biking like 50 miles, if you're going to use a clip shoe?
Scott: No one who bikes 50 miles is not a specialist.
Rym: Scott, 50 miles is not that far.
Rym: I have biked 50 miles.
Scott: Then you are a specialist.
Scott: What percentage of the population do you think bikes 50 miles in their lives?
Rym: Wait a minute, wait a minute.
Rym: So, you're saying that because of the way I bike, I'm a specialist, so I'm allowed, I get like a waiver to get one additional kind of shoe.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: If you are a specialist.
Rym: Scott, I argue that I am also, by your definition, a specialist at running.
Rym: I run a lot.
Scott: I do not believe you are a specialist in running.
Scott: There are many, the percentage of the population that runs, you are far from.
Rym: Wait, Scott, so what is the criteria for a specialist runner?
Rym: Because you already said that if I bike 50 miles, I'm a specialist biker.
Scott: At once.
Scott: I mean, 50 miles, if you add up your whole life, that's not enough.
Rym: 50 miles at once is not that far.
Scott: I didn't say it's that far, but what percentage of the population do you think has ever or will ever bike?
Scott: I'm not talking about other people.
Scott: 50 miles in one go.
Rym: I'm talking about me.
Scott: I'm saying, what percentage of the population of the world do you think will ever or has ever biked 50 miles at once?
Rym: Oh, Scott, that rounds down to zero.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's almost nobody.
Rym: I know.
Scott: That's beside the point.
Scott: Therefore, anyone who is in that class is a specialist.
Rym: So, Scott, what is the line for a specialist runner?
Scott: You have to be whatever that same percentage of the population is.
Scott: Scott, I probably run- Translated to running.
Rym: I run 99% of people.
Scott: Then you may be a specialist at running.
Rym: Yes, I'm saying I am.
Rym: I have a running shoe, which is separate from my walk around shoe because otherwise I have.
Scott: You're also a specialist at ego increasing by pretending you're a specialist at everything.
Rym: Scott, I do not want to claim I'm a specialist.
Rym: This is your stupid definition.
Scott: Regardless, if you are a specialist at something that requires a shoe, then you are permitted the extra shoe for your specialty.
Scott: For example, if you are a skiing specialist, you can buy a skiing boot.
Rym: I have a ski boot right there.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: If you are a skateboarding specialist, you need a skateboarding shoe, the flat ones.
Scott: Otherwise it's not, you know, try skateboarding without the stupid skateboarding shoes.
Rym: I guess rollerblades count.
Scott: Rollerblades, ice skates.
Rym: Yep, ice skates.
Scott: All specialized shoes that are allowable if you are a specialist.
Rym: All right.
Scott: Because otherwise, if you're not a specialist, it is not economical to actually buy the thing.
Rym: So Scott, going back to the first point of contention, my overland hiking boot is specialist equipment.
Scott: I don't think you know if you're a specialist hiker.
Rym: The last time I went hiking, it was 18 miles over the mountains and we hiked down a mountain in driving range where there was six inches of water pouring through me as I'm going down a steep, muddy, rocky, disastrous decline into a valley of death.
Scott: I did much hiking and I always used the same boot I used in winter and it was never a problem.
Rym: I don't think you've done the kind of hiking that I do.
Scott: I hiked in many places, up and down mountains in the olden days before the year 2000.
Rym: Some years ago I went with our friend James and some other people up in the Adirondacks and we hiked 26 miles and climbed four mountains in one go.
Rym: The fourth mountain was almost a mile high and we had to rappel down like, anyway, it was crazy.
Rym: It took all day.
Rym: It was grueling.
Scott: I walked through an entire desert for two days.
Rym: So I wore, I had two pairs of brand new tennis shoes on me, like pretty good, like $80 brand new tennis shoes.
Rym: By the end of this hike, they were both destroyed.
Scott: I think there is something also wrong with the way you walk because I have walked great distances in other shoes.
Rym: Scott, you have not walked great distances over sharp rocks and through six inch deep sucking mud and snow.
Rym: I
Scott: have walked through nasty shit in the olden days and you know what, the shoes that I started with were just fine at the end, except for one time when I was wearing boots and I literally marched in a river, I guess it wasn't a river because you didn't drown in it, but it was a heavy stream.
Scott: that was white waters, but maybe a foot deep.
Scott: So your basic feet were completely submerged as you were walking and that was able to destroy the shoe from water damage, but never from tread wear in a single go.
Rym: Scott, walking through water like that has happened on every major hike I've ever done.
Scott: Well, water damage is completely different from the tread is disintegrated.
Rym: The tread will disintegrate if you hike over sharp rocks.
Scott: I have hiked over sharp rocks and down.
Rym: You clearly have not.
Scott: I have and my shoe is still alive at the end.
Rym: Anyway, I have.
Scott: I think you walk a weird way.
Scott: Did anyone else have this problem?
Rym: They all had specialist hiking boots.
Rym: I was the only one who was not wearing specialist hiking equipment on that trip.
Scott: So the next trip, if I bought a specialist hiking boot, you could also use that boot as your winner.
Scott: It's snowing.
Rym: No, I couldn't because it's not high enough.
Rym: So it would be very snow would get into it.
Scott: They make hiking boots that are high.
Rym: No, but I did not want it to be high because for the overland hiking, I wanted to have all the benefits of a running cross trainer shoe with also having the durability.
Scott: You're thinking too much about it.
Scott: It would not make that much of a difference.
Rym: It makes a huge difference.
Scott: It's psychological.
Rym: Uh, no, mister.
Rym: Doesn't do sports.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, so how many shoes do you have in your closet?
Rym: So Scott, let's go over my shoes.
Rym: I have one pair of running shoes, one pair of everyday boots that I wear under that kilt all the time.
Rym: I have one pair of overland hiking shoes.
Rym: I have one pair of specialized climbing shoes that are only good for climbing rocks.
Rym: They can't walk in them.
Rym: They're so uncomfortable.
Rym: I have my V brooms, which I also run in.
Rym: If I want to be barefoot and I wear all the time, I have window.
Scott: You started off by complaining about women who have too many shoes and now you have more shoes than them.
Rym: Scott, the women I'm talking about have an order of magnitude more shoes than me.
Scott: See, I know that they have hundreds of shoes.
Scott: Perhaps even Kate.
Rym: I love Kate, but her shoot, we have to remove.
Rym: at one point the number of shoes that she had was like like it was startling to the point that I was standing there in awe.
Rym: I did not know what to say.
Scott: The thing that's even worse is like people who have like money problems yet they have all these shoes or people have shoes that they just never wear.
Scott: It's like it's one thing if you if you're like Rym and you're yuppie and you're going to buy ten thousand shoes, you can buy ten thousand womanly shoes and you wear them each in the back.
Scott: You know, you actually use all those shoes.
Rym: I do.
Rym: In fact, at least once a year, my dress shoes are so fucked right now.
Rym: I need a new pair.
Scott: Use them at least once a year, at least.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You ski at least once a year.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: To have a shoe that you've like never used and to keep it.
Scott: It's like just know if you haven't used you use the shoe in three and sixty five days, it's out right to have to the same shoe in two different colors.
Scott: What the fuck?
Rym: Well, seriously, but many men, many men, I'd say the majority of men, if pair of brown dress issues, just wear the black ones all the time.
Rym: Uh, no, because some people, for whatever reason, like to wear brown dress shoes or loafers, even though I think they look stupid.
Scott: They're women.
Scott: You know, it's really stupid.
Scott: Here's some.
Scott: Let's talk about shoes that should not exist and they have no purpose.
Scott: You're right.
Scott: No.
Scott: Well, yes.
Scott: But here's my first one.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Those men dress the male dress shoes that have little tassels on them.
Rym: What the fuck?
Rym: Those are silly.
Scott: Who the fuck wears?
Rym: what I see, you know, it's like why would you ever wear one guy and packs wearing those shoes, ironically, and it looked great.
Scott: Really?
Rym: It worked with the kilt.
Rym: OK, I'll give him that one.
Rym: It's like, dude, you win.
Rym: You get.
Scott: But it's like they're so like.
Scott: why do those even exist?
Scott: I'm sure someone is like some fashion expert is going to say why they exist.
Rym: Well, seriously, when I was a kid, you know, it's really popular at the Catholic school with the uniform penny loafers.
Scott: Well, if you're a little kid, you're a little, you know, you're a little ten year old boy.
Scott: That's great.
Scott: If you're wearing a uniform.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: No wonder why there's one kid who put dimes in his nice shit.
Rym: He walked around with those dimes and he'd call attention to him.
Rym: He'd be like, check out my shoes.
Scott: Should have put some half dollars in there.
Scott: I don't think they'd fit now.
Scott: But yeah, but yeah, that's that's fine.
Scott: But if you're over the age of twelve, no, that should not.
Scott: that you did.
Scott: They shouldn't even make it.
Scott: Oh, my God.
Rym: Scott, why aren't the hipsters wearing penny loafers?
Rym: We got to get out of them.
Rym: Do I have not seen this?
Scott: OK, I've seen some.
Rym: I feel like I can make money on penny loafers.
Rym: OK.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: What other shoe should not exist besides the high heel?
Rym: The thing is, the high heel has one purpose.
Rym: I can't.
Rym: There are times when uncomfortable dress clothes look good for a photo or an opportunity.
Rym: My only complaint about high heels is that if you ever wear them and you have to walk more than 50 feet at a time and you complain even once, you should not have worn the high heels in the first place.
Scott: And you deserve it.
Rym: You should actually come to New York City.
Rym: Don't fucking wear high heels here.
Rym: It does not work.
Scott: I don't.
Rym: even women do not wear high heels.
Scott: But it is.
Scott: the thing is like people say, oh, but they look so good.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: I'm sure that, you know, they're clearly there are dudes out there who like that shit because many hoes be wearing gigantic heels and dudes be picking them up.
Scott: But you know what?
Scott: I have not once ever thought a high heel was hot.
Scott: I think it's just sort of really kind of freaky and not hot in any way, shape or form.
Scott: You know, it's you know, it's way hotter, a regular fucking everyday sneaker with a really thick, tall, scrunched up sock.
Scott: It doesn't matter.
Scott: Just, you know, a regular fucking shoe, because that means you're a regular person.
Rym: Let's talk about something more important.
Rym: If you wear shoes without socks, the fuck's wrong with you?
Rym: Well, everyone I know who does this, unless you're wearing climbing shoes or like Vibram or sandals or sandals shoes, their sandals.
Scott: A sandal is a shoe, shoes, not subset of shoe now.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Anyway.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, you can't wear socks with sandals.
Scott: That's correct.
Scott: But unless of those Japanese ones with the two sticks at the bottom.
Rym: But everyone occasionally in my life, I have been in a hurry and put on like tennis shoes without having socks in them.
Rym: Your foot smells like a butt at the end of the day.
Rym: Your shoes smell like a butt forever.
Rym: It's uncomfortable.
Rym: What the fuck's wrong with you people?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: How can you do that?
Scott: Now, climbing shoes, you can always get the socks that are just incredibly short and like stop below the ankles and know what it looks like.
Scott: You don't wear a sock, but also climbing shoes.
Rym: You pretty much can't.
Rym: You don't want to wear socks in them because otherwise it's like they don't work as well.
Rym: They're not as comfortable.
Rym: They're they're more uncomfortable.
Rym: I can't say that they're comfortable.
Rym: They basically mash your toes into a point and they have like a funny little ballet shoe.
Scott: The specialized shoe.
Scott: Another shoe that shouldn't exist.
Scott: The clog.
Rym: What's wrong with clogs?
Rym: They shouldn't exist.
Rym: I have seen hipsters wearing legit clogs.
Scott: What the fuck, dude?
Rym: Actually, you know what?
Rym: That's kind of cool.
Rym: Plus, Scott, think about a time before we had mass manufacturing.
Scott: Clog is not that bad of a shoe.
Scott: Not in those days.
Scott: Nowadays, it's an awful shoe.
Rym: But you don't see anyone but hipsters and traditionalists.
Scott: But here's the thing is people be wearing this shit and like for fashion's sake.
Scott: Well, you know what?
Scott: Yeah, tell the podiatrist for fashion's sake.
Scott: Now, who's laughing now?
Scott: Mr.
Scott: Foot is fucked up beyond belief.
Scott: Bunions and all kinds of other.
Rym: I think most of the people who have these problems just don't wash their feet because I read no bunions are not from unwashed.
Scott: Oh, no, I'm saying it's what is from unwashed.
Rym: I'm saying in general, I saw some study that said, like, two thirds of Americans have major fungal related problems in their feet and like serious foot odor.
Scott: You ever see those people like toenails that are like a half inch thick?
Scott: It's like, what the fuck?
Rym: But but like a surprising majority of people seem to have these problems.
Rym: And you'll notice those are the people who always want to wear their shoes inside or they never take off their socks in public and their feet smell like a. but when they actually do that, the people where they take off their shoes in your car and you like put that shit back on.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: What the fuck, dude?
Rym: But I really don't understand it.
Rym: But I mean, you know what I do when I come home and if I wash my feet.
Rym: In the shower, I just wash my feet.
Scott: I just wash my feet whenever I shower.
Rym: Sometimes I wash my feet when I get home, like if I'm running barefoot, I wash my feet.
Scott: Well, I wash my feet as something nasty gets on.
Scott: I'm like, I was walking barefoot through the slime.
Scott: Then I'll wash my feet.
Scott: But yeah, I'm talking about like bunions and hammertoes and that kind of fucked up shit.
Scott: It's like, you know, I guess flat footed is genetic, right?
Scott: But a lot of these other ones are not genetic.
Scott: A lot, you know, it's from wearing fucked up shoes and not walking properly.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: this is why you don't choose shoes for fashion.
Scott: You choose for comfort.
Scott: primarily, even if it's, you know, you can find a shoe that is sufficiently comfortable and then get some more fashion in there without any expense of decreasing comfort.
Scott: But to go for full on fashion and disregard comfort, it's like you're fucking up your foot, an incredibly important part of your body.
Scott: You're going to permanently ruin it and cause yourself pain for the rest of your days.
Scott: For the sake of fashion, you're retarded, right?
Scott: You know, regardless, you know, whatever you want to say about, well, fashion is, you know, whatever you fucked up your foot permanent beauty before duty.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That's insane.
Rym: Like a culture before comfort.
Scott: You know, it's like both.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It is a line.
Scott: It's like, OK, you want to wear that T-shirt because it's fashionable.
Scott: Great.
Scott: It's a T-shirt, but it's fashionable.
Scott: Cool.
Scott: You want to fucking inject fucking Botox into your face.
Scott: What the fuck is wrong with you?
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's the same shit.
Scott: Don't fuck up your body permanently for that shit.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So what's the line?
Rym: I mean, I have an ear piercing.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Is that bad?
Scott: Is it fucked up your body beyond recognition and cause you pain for the rest of your days?
Rym: It causes no pain.
Rym: I used to have.
Scott: Does it hurt you in any way, shape or form?
Rym: When I first got it, OK, for like a week, it really hurt.
Rym: And then it stopped hurting.
Rym: It never hurt again.
Scott: All right.
Scott: But I mean, has it caused you any permanent, irrevocable negative consequence damage?
Rym: No, other than that, when I don't wear an earring, there's a little hole in my ear.
Scott: All right.
Rym: See, I can.
Rym: you can stick.
Rym: I can stick like a pencil lead through it.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Is that as bad as, say, it hurts to walk forever?
Scott: No.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You can see the difference there.
Rym: I got a piercing on the upper part of my ear once I got rid of it because it didn't stop hurting after a week.
Rym: Yeah, I was like, yeah, it's done.
Scott: This is what I'm talking about.
Scott: Right.
Rym: I'm thinking about doing that again, though, because I like the way that looks.
Scott: Do whatever you want.
Scott: As long as you don't fuck up your body forever in a painful way that is permanently damaging.
Rym: So what about handbags?
Rym: What do you want?
Rym: I have a Timbuktu messenger bag.
Scott: And me too.
Scott: I also have a camelback mule.
Scott: I also have a camelback and I have an old L.L.Bean regular backpack that can carry a ton of shit.
Rym: I have a generic briefcase messenger bag that I use for things when I need just like a bunch of generic crap independent.
Scott: I have a giant L.L.Bean duffle bag for luggage.
Rym: I have many different luggages, depending on where I'm going.
Scott: You have womanly luggage.
Scott: How?
Rym: I have one really big luggage.
Scott: Does it have wheels on it?
Scott: Yes.
Scott: You're a woman.
Rym: Scott, you know what?
Rym: Every time we travel, you're like, yeah, I guess I guess it'd be sexist to call you a woman.
Scott: You're a little boy.
Scott: And yet you're like a three year old boy who can't carry his luggage.
Rym: Scott, you're the one with the heavy duffle bag who slams into obstacles because you can't see where you're going because it's so heavy and you're so like burdened by this thing.
Scott: Yeah, but I'm carrying it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And you know what?
Scott: And do I get where I'm going?
Rym: Scott, so why are you using a GUI?
Rym: Just command line all the way.
Rym: Why?
Rym: Why use?
Rym: you should use links because it's clearly the more manly way to get the job done.
Scott: You can't see the pictures.
Rym: All right, so download that shit separately and open it up.
Rym: in fact, it doesn't work.
Rym: Yeah, it does.
Rym: It doesn't open them up in fact.
Scott: How would you know where they belong on the page?
Scott: So you go to fag, you download it.
Scott: It's an image of like the logo for the website.
Scott: OK, the next one is a red line.
Rym: Did you really need to see all that stuff?
Rym: Does it really matter?
Scott: Yeah, kind of.
Rym: I see no problem with wheels on luggage because they're nothing but a convenience for sissies.
Rym: OK, you know what?
Rym: I don't care what you say because it's comfortable.
Rym: This is I just want everyone to remember.
Rym: Carrying Scott about aesthetics or fashion or all that BS.
Rym: I use what's comfortable.
Scott: Yeah, I use what's comfortable carrying my own shit.
Rym: Yeah, except you're slow as shit when you're carrying your shit.
Scott: I just want to point out that in the beginning of the show, right, I was the one who was going to pick the onions if I had to and Rym is the one who's going to resort to crime.
Rym: Jesus sissy.
Scott: You'd rather rob people than do hard work.
Rym: Robbing people is so fun, though.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: When I rob people, I carry that money on my own bag.
Scott: I don't put it in a wheelie bag.
Rym: I get a wheelie bag with a dollar sign on it.
Rym: You know what?
Scott: If I'm going to steal a bar of gold, I'm going to fucking carry that shit.
Rym: I'd like to see you carry a bar of gold.
Scott: I could carry half a bar of gold if I had to in a bag.
Rym: So one thing I've noticed, a lot of people on the Internet say something to the effect of what is the deal with your New York people in your messenger bags?
Rym: It's fashion bullshit.
Rym: Uh, what do you mean?
Rym: A lot of people seem to hate on messenger bags.
Scott: What's wrong with the mess?
Rym: They always say, why don't you just have a backpack?
Scott: Uh, OK, why?
Rym: I see this a lot and it's weird.
Scott: So I've never seen this really.
Scott: It's strange.
Rym: I see it all the time.
Scott: Why would you even think that?
Rym: So I want to rebut it right now.
Rym: You can't get into your backpack without unbackpacking it and opening it.
Rym: A messenger bag.
Rym: You just go, whoop.
Rym: And now it's in the front.
Scott: That's the reason messengers use that bag, is that when they arrive and they're delivering their message, they can just go swing it around, grab the message, hand it to the person and get on their way.
Scott: If you have a backpack with the two arm straps, yes, it distributes the weight more evenly across the back and such, but you have to bring it out, unzip it.
Scott: It's much harder to get things in and out of it, even if you keep it in the front like a dork.
Scott: Now, the other thing, backpacks do have more carrying capacity, but you don't need that fucking carrying capacity because you're not carrying that much shit.
Rym: And if you are, yeah, backpack.
Scott: That's why I have both.
Scott: Nothing.
Scott: I have a backpack, too.
Scott: Why not?
Scott: Sometimes you need that shit.
Rym: So, Scott, here's a very important question.
Scott: When you were a kid and you know what, if you need to distribute the weight evenly, you can hike your messenger bag up and attach the extra through the front strap.
Scott: And now it's going full on.
Rym: So, Scott, when you were a kid, let's say middle school, high school.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: You had a backpack, I assume.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: For books.
Rym: Was it over one shoulder or both shoulders?
Scott: Depended.
Rym: On what?
Scott: The day.
Scott: OK.
Rym: What made you choose one over the other?
Scott: How many books are fucking in there?
Rym: So why did you ever put it over just one shoulder?
Scott: Because there was barely nothing in it.
Rym: But why?
Rym: Two shoulders doesn't take any more effort and it's more stable because one shoulder more you occasionally have to go.
Scott: It was it was more comfortable with the one shoulder.
Rym: You sure you didn't just do it because all the cool kids did it that way?
Scott: I didn't even think about it.
Scott: Really?
Rym: Because I noticed very pointedly throughout all of my life, the kids who were hip or in the know or popular or just not picked on invariably almost always had their backpack on one shoulder, even
Scott: if it was full of books,
Rym: even if it was full of books,
Scott: like so many books, all the books.
Rym: Well, one, those kids generally books didn't have that many books in their back.
Scott: OK, well, that's for sure.
Rym: But to invariably the kids who were picked on never use just one shoulder, even when there was nothing in it.
Rym: It's anecdotal, but I've seen this through the eyes of many different people.
Scott: I think it's just that when a backpack, you know, if it's not heavy, putting on both shoulder straps.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it sort of leans back because, you know, even if you pike it up.
Scott: It's sort of like the chafe.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But there's not so much weight on them.
Scott: So they're sort of bouncing and hitting your neck.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So if you do the one shoulder, it's more like just a messenger bag because you didn't bring your messenger bag with you.
Scott: But if there's a ton of stuff in there, you got to go both shoulder to carry the weight.
Scott: No, that's how I roll.
Rym: It is how you roll.
Rym: What about the fanny pack?
Scott: Fanny packs should never be used ever.
Rym: I actually used to occasionally use a fanny pack.
Scott: You're a dork.
Rym: You know where I used it?
Rym: At amusement parks.
Scott: I used a fanny pack at amusement park once.
Scott: And you know what?
Scott: Then I switched it up.
Scott: There's a better thing you can use.
Rym: What's your thing?
Scott: The necklace cylinder.
Rym: The necklace cylinder is the stupidest looking crap thing.
Scott: The necklace cylinder is the key at water parks.
Scott: Wait, Scott.
Rym: What do you put in your necklace cylinder?
Scott: Money and credit cards.
Rym: So what do you do with your wallet?
Scott: The rest, everything else goes into the locker that you rent.
Rym: So more importantly, you had a necklace cylinder big enough to hold a credit card.
Rym: That's so stupid looking.
Scott: It actually had like a little credit card sort of slot.
Rym: I learned the real secret a long time ago when I used fanny packs at amusement parks.
Rym: Then one day I realized, why don't I just not fucking bring anything to the amusement park except one credit card and some cash?
Scott: That's exactly the thing.
Scott: That's why the cylinder is so great.
Scott: No, pocket.
Scott: It's in my pocket.
Scott: You can't.
Scott: OK, what's going to happen on the water slide, Mr.
Scott: Pocket?
Rym: Scott, water slide is in a water park.
Rym: If I'm in the water park, I have nothing on me but swimsuit.
Scott: See that if you have the cylinder, right.
Rym: Why would I ever want to carry anything but my swimsuit in the water park?
Scott: Because when you get off, you're going down the slide.
Scott: You get to the bottom of the slide.
Rym: I go right back up to go down the slide again.
Scott: And while you're waiting in fucking line.
Rym: There's no fucking line unless you go to a shitty water park.
Scott: All the water parks are made of lines.
Scott: You get to the bottom.
Scott: You buy a fucking hot dog.
Scott: You wait in line eating the hot dog.
Scott: You work it.
Rym: But I already ate a hot dog before I put my swimsuit on.
Scott: Oh, that was a mistake.
Scott: See, I'm saving time.
Scott: I actually got on the slide earlier because I just went straight for the slide and I'm eating the hot dog in line riding more slides.
Rym: The real key was Cedar Point shut down at like eleven o'clock.
Rym: As in they shut off all the lines.
Rym: Ten fifty eight.
Rym: Buy as much food as you can all carry.
Rym: Ten fifty nine.
Rym: Get in the longest ass line.
Rym: One am be the last kids on the roller coaster.
Rym: Everyone in the park who's an employee hates your fucking guts and wants you to die.
Scott: OK.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to D.J.
Rym: Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew dot com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.