Rym: It's Monday, March 12th, 2012.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights Tonight, Network Mounted Storage.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Oh my gosh, we're back.
Rym: I feel like it wasn't that long ago.
Rym: we did a We're Back show, but we're back again.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Yep, I was in India.
Scott: And we're gonna be away again once PAX East shows up in a few weeks.
Rym: Yep, but PAX East is not most of the normal week.
Rym: I mean, we'll be back Monday.
Rym: We could still do a show, I guess.
Scott: Maybe.
Scott: I was at the Duane Reade today and I saw some Easter candy and I was like, "Oh my god,
Scott: PAX.".
Rym: So, unrelatedly...
Scott: I bought one egg.
Scott: It was 89 cents.
Rym: One of my co-workers is like, "Hey, you wanna try some
Rym: candy?".
Rym: And I'm like, "What do you have that is going to surprise
Rym: me?".
Rym: "Turkish
Rym: Pever?".
Rym: He busted out some Salmiakki.
Rym: and I'm like, "Let me tell you about Salmiakki,
Rym: son.".
Scott: I've had that shit.
Rym: Oh, Turkish Pever.
Rym: But PAX is coming.
Scott: Which kind did he have?
Rym: He had the normal.
Rym: The same kind that we get.
Scott: Oh, you didn't have the racing wheel?
Rym: No, I was like, "So you haven't had Dragster or whatever or Death's Head or Turkish
Rym: Pever.".
Scott: Was he shocked that you knew what this was?
Rym: Not really, 'cause I have a reputation for...
Scott: Now they've gotten used to the fact that we are on the internet.
Scott: We're worldly people.
Scott: We know things.
Scott: You can't surprise me with some secret candy from a foreign land.
Rym: This guy is one of the smart, young, and cool developers who is going to be at PAX.
Rym: And in fact, his girlfriend is making their costumes because they are cosplaying.
Scott: As what?
Rym: I think Megaman and Rock or something.
Rym: Not bad.
Rym: I forget.
Rym: Megaman and Roll?
Rym: Something.
Scott: Rike is Megaman.
Rym: I said Megaman, but I should have said Rock and Roll, but not everyone would know what that is, 'cause this is Monday and not Tuesday.
Scott: I know what that is.
Rym: But anyway, I was in India, and we will do a show at some point on a Thursday about my experiences in India.
Rym: It was awesome.
Scott: And you'll try to cut back on the racist stereotypes.
Rym: Indian food, pretty great in India.
Rym: Drinking water, not so great in India.
Rym: No kidding.
Rym: But the biggest thing I have to say, and I say this every time I leave the country, I was in India.
Rym: In fact, I was in Mumbai and Hyderabad.
Rym: Mumbai was not that long ago wracked with pretty serious recent terrorist attacks.
Rym: This is a city and a nation that has a real problem with actual terrorist attacks.
Rym: So when I got on a plane to fly from Mumbai, where terrorist attacks just happened, to Hyderabad, I go to the airport.
Rym: I did not have to take off my shoes.
Rym: I did not have to go through a body scanner or get groped.
Rym: The security line from start to "I can get on the plane" took less than a minute and a half.
Rym: So you know what?
Scott: What did they do?
Scott: You just walked through a metal detector?
Rym: I walked through a metal detector.
Rym: It beeped.
Rym: And you know what the guy did?
Rym: He said, "Come
Rym: here.".
Rym: He waved a metal detector, a hand one, over me for like two seconds.
Scott: You mean what they used to do in the year 2000 in the United States?
Scott: He found the beep.
Rym: The beep was my cell phone in my pocket.
Scott: That you should have taken out.
Rym: No, they didn't care.
Rym: He touched it from the outside, touched his big lump, used his human skills to determine that it was probably a cell phone and not in fact a gun, did not even ask me to take it out of my pocket.
Scott: Was there an x-ray for your goods?
Rym: Yes, my bag went through an x-ray.
Rym: Did not have to take my laptop out of my bag.
Rym: My bag in fact included a giant lithium ion battery, a bigger lithium ion battery, a Kindle, a DS, a laptop, and a laptop charger.
Scott: A bunch of bombs.
Rym: And the x-ray guy looked at it and I saw what his screen looks like.
Scott: A bunch of colors on a white background.
Rym: The guy looked at it, he paused on my bag, kind of like looked at the screen for a few seconds, and then waved it through.
Scott: So he was actually doing his job.
Rym: He was.
Rym: You know what?
Scott: Otherwise he wouldn't have stopped.
Scott: You know what the moral of all this is?
Scott: If I had that job I'd just hold the button down and be like, fall asleep.
Rym: You know what the moral of this is?
Rym: Fuck you TSA, I'm sick of your motherfucking bullshit.
Scott: That's not a new moral.
Rym: Seriously, countries with real terrorists do not go through the level of inane security theater bullshit that you make me go through.
Scott: This isn't news.
Rym: I'm not saying it's news.
Rym: I'm just, every time I leave America.
Scott: It's 10 years old, this news.
Rym: It only pisses me off more.
Rym: I cannot deal with the TSA.
Rym: And in fact, the international flight back home, right?
Rym: Security, even less.
Rym: Even less.
Rym: So that security aside, I got through security, right?
Rym: And then in the airport because it was a flight going to the United States and the United States doesn't trust anyone else's security.
Rym: We all had to go through security again at the terminal where there they had TSA signs up and they had like the three one one rule and all that stuff.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: They actually just did the exact same thing they did before.
Rym: They didn't do anything different.
Rym: They just went through the motions to satisfy the TSA and the paranoid us bullshit.
Rym: But I just have to say it every time I leave the country.
Rym: Fuck you.
Rym: I hate the TSA.
Scott: They'll be gone.
Rym: Will they?
Scott: This is pushing backs.
Rym: So that's why I get to my news.
Rym: because great.
Scott: At least it's going to be more of the same.
Rym: Arguably the problem with the TSA.
Rym: At least they say, all right, they can justify the body scanners that they will catch things that maybe metal detectors wouldn't catch.
Scott: No, they can't.
Rym: But every news story I see talks about how all the things they catch or things that the metal detectors call.
Scott: We've known that they're bullshit for a long time.
Rym: They knew they were bullshit because they didn't catch anything you wouldn't already catch.
Rym: But it turns out they can't even catch the stuff they're supposed to catch.
Rym: The metal detectors can't catch.
Rym: And this guy showed that not only are they useless security theater bullshit, but it is trivial to trick them into not seeing the things that they're supposed to be able to catch.
Rym: All So at this point, I've decided that it's not even political maneuvering.
Rym: It's not even security theater to keep the mouth breathers happy or whatever.
Rym: It is straight up corruption.
Rym: The people who make the scanners had corruption happen to get them in the airports and to suppress.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Are you just discovering this now?
Rym: No, I'm just now.
Rym: I'm confirming it.
Rym: It goes from confirming.
Scott: It's like the 10th.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Now we've got 30 confirmations.
Scott: That's enough confirmations, guys.
Scott: Because now we know for sure, for sure, for sure, this is the first time someone basically completely broke them.
Rym: This is like all the way over the edge.
Scott: I don't know if you saw the German video that was multiple years ago on the show where the guy walked through the scanners and then pulled all this shit out of his pockets.
Rym: Yeah, but this guy did it.
Scott: How is this different?
Rym: This one actually was different.
Rym: You should read the article about specifically the vulnerability he found.
Rym: Yeah, I saw his response, which was interesting.
Rym: They said, don't report on that.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Now, if it's so trivial to break them, I cannot help but think that if there were any matter of QA testing, they would have found these vulnerabilities.
Rym: So either they were suppressed because someone had a vested money interest or everybody in the world isn't confident.
Scott: It's like you're saying like the shock thing.
Scott: It's like, oh my God, Rym.
Scott: Oh my God.
Scott: I didn't say cause cancer.
Scott: It's I know.
Scott: I didn't even say it was news.
Rym: All I'm saying is that the mountain of evidence, there's such a mountain of evidence now.
Scott: It's it's it's concrete.
Scott: There was definitely corruption in the tobacco industry.
Scott: It's set in stone.
Scott: Have you seen this story?
Scott: This dude died of lung cancer.
Scott: He smoked his whole life.
Rym: Every time I leave the country and I come back and I run into this shit, I just have to take my pile of bullshit.
Rym: I left.
Rym: I came back.
Rym: I have a new pile of bullshit.
Rym: I got to dump it.
Scott: So every time I walk down the street, there's a guy smoking.
Scott: I just got to take that pile of bullshit and dump it out again.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Scott, where am I going to put it?
Rym: I mean, my bullshit landfill is full, so I got to dump it on the Internet.
Rym: I got to put it in your cigarette.
Scott: But landfill is full.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So I'm dumping it in all of your brains to get it out of my brain.
Rym: It's an interesting article, though, mostly because we're getting to the point where at least when bullshit like this happens, any average dude can pretty much because, you know, it's easy to verifiably break stuff like this, publicly break it and just wave it in their faces.
Rym: All right.
Scott: So here is some local news.
Rym: Oh.
Scott: New York City news.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That is actually the opposite of corruption.
Scott: Uh huh.
Scott: You may have known previously that, you know, New York City has had various, you know, initiatives were like they wanted people to make New York City apps and they would open various New York City data in, you know, good and maybe not as good, but still open ways to get people to make apps, you know, especially MTA type stuff, things like that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: There is a new law.
Scott: It is a law, not a bill or anything like that.
Scott: Bloomberg signed it.
Scott: It is number twenty nine a blah, blah, blah.
Scott: It basically says, yeah, all public domain data in New York City is has to be open and available on the Internet for free.
Scott: And by twenty eighteen, not only will it be available, it will also be in one place.
Scott: They'll be like one New York City data website that will have all the New York City data that is public in one spot.
Scott: And you can just get at it and make all sorts of crazy apps and shit.
Rym: Interesting.
Scott: I like that.
Scott: And so it won't just be like subway schedule.
Scott: I guess it'll also be like plowing routes.
Scott: And who can imagine all kinds of crazy shit?
Scott: What's in stock at the library schedule of when the sewers are going to get?
Rym: I look forward to like the craziest, most intrusive use of this information to figure out how much traffic goes through the tunnels every day, where the street fair is going to be.
Scott: You know, this weekend, I can't even like I'm trying to imagine all the crazy data that's out there.
Rym: Oh, my God.
Rym: The street fair thing would be great because I could use street fair.
Scott: There is a ghetto static HTML website that tells you where the street fair is going to be.
Rym: I know, but I've decided, you know, I've realized kind of fundamentally on the Internet that in the early days, pull information like that was all I needed, because if I care about X, I will do a pull on X and get X. But now there's so much information available that I could conceivably use.
Rym: It is not worth my time to pull it.
Rym: So I need an aggregated puller.
Rym: The problem is the data isn't all these like difficult to access.
Rym: Every format is different.
Rym: One off cases to where it's not worth my effort.
Scott: Is what I have t t t t t t t t is great.
Rym: Yeah, except it doesn't support G, plus, which is the thing I actually really want.
Rym: Plus doesn't have an API, which is the biggest thing holding me back from really using G plus.
Scott: I just set it up to where.
Scott: now Twitter, Facebook, G plus are all sort of linked up as much as possible.
Scott: So I don't really care which one it is like.
Scott: I'll open up any one of the three and I'm fine, whatever.
Scott: I don't care anymore.
Rym: I really in general, though, cut down on kind of my inbound and outbound data streams.
Scott: I had a huge cutting down of the reading too many websites and I did a little bit up on the, you know, social bits.
Scott: But the reason I up the social bits is because I unfollowed the fuck out of it and unfriended a zillion people.
Scott: So now it's like you go to Twitter and I can go there twice a day and read a bunch of tweets and tweet a bunch.
Scott: But I'm only following like 70 people instead of 170 people.
Rym: So it's like, wow, I'm only following 73 people now.
Rym: And that was before I did an unfollow.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Let me go see how many I'm like.
Scott: I unfollowed like all the people.
Rym: I have long had a policy of never, ever reciprocating follows or friends or anything.
Rym: In fact, on YouTube, I refuse to even engage in the social side because I'm following one hundred and eighteen people.
Scott: That's more than I thought.
Rym: All hundred eighteen of those people have interesting tweets that you want to know.
Scott: Actually, the thing is most of those people don't even don't even like tweet that often.
Scott: So I'll never even see a tweet from them.
Scott: There's only a very small number of them that actually tweet.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway, so one last little bit of news, because a long time ago, you know, Google cars and the Google self-driving thing has been going along for a long time.
Rym: And, you know, we made a big deal about how Nevada was finally going to allow driverless cars and automated cars with restrictions.
Rym: You know, this stuff has to be regulated.
Rym: It's a it's a brand new industry that's slowly going to come on board.
Rym: Big leaps are happening.
Rym: California is now actually has pending legislation that will do the same thing.
Rym: This is actually a huge deal because California is a place where there's enough of a market to where Google could probably start selling these cars to actual rich people who will use them in real life situations.
Scott: I can't wait until the law is, yeah, people can't be trusted to drive the air.
Scott: People get into accidents this rate of the time and the automatic cars get accidents at this rate.
Scott: So you're not allowed to drive, period, unless it's a track.
Scott: And oh, by the way, all the city bus drivers try to work.
Rym: What's amazing to me is that a lot of the comments on this article are people who are saying, but they're not safe.
Rym: I would never trust a computer to drive me around.
Rym: It's like really slash dot.
Rym: This is what you've become.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: The old man.
Scott: They're safer than you driving.
Rym: I well, I don't you know, people make the argument that, you know, they have to be perfectly safe or we can't trust them.
Scott: No, they just have to be safer than human drivers, which is a pretty low bar on average.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Or we can do the thing.
Scott: You know, there are probably human drivers who are safer than the computer driver.
Scott: They probably exist.
Scott: Michael Schumacher is probably going to drive.
Rym: Maybe the rules should be should be if you are a human driver who cannot get above a certain right in the test, the driving you have to use an automated car or you can't drive.
Scott: the driving test will be hard as balls.
Scott: But here's the thing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So let's say you are we already did a show on this sort of.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: You're a low skilled human driver.
Scott: You have an automated car.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It does.
Scott: You're sitting there.
Scott: It does malfunction legitimately.
Rym: All you have to do is slam on the brakes and avoid obstacles.
Rym: Yeah, I think everyone can do that.
Scott: I'm just saying, right.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: you've never.
Scott: even you don't even know how to drive.
Scott: You've never driven because you don't need to.
Scott: You have automatic cars.
Rym: Well, the law is that.
Scott: is that anime?
Scott: What was the anime called?
Scott: Our driver is something.
Rym: it was shitty.
Scott: It was.
Rym: it looked really good.
Rym: I thought it was going to be good.
Rym: It was terrible anyway.
Rym: But the law still states that a driver has to be in the vehicle, capable and ready, capable of and ready to take control of the car.
Rym: So you still can't drive drunk or, you know, talking on your cell phone or whatever.
Rym: But the reason I bring this up, that is noteworthy, is that our government, as slow as it is, is actually for the first time, maybe in the last hundred years, making legislation before we come to a critical like crisis point of technology.
Scott: Well, because it's something that the government can more easily understand.
Rym: I think it's more because this is the one area where Google is putting its money into the political arena that also think about it.
Rym: Google, with its crazy amounts of money, enough money to buy the entire U.S.
Rym: recording industry if they want it, puts a pinky toe into politics and suddenly gets exactly what it wants.
Rym: Interesting.
Rym: But the fact that it's California means that this is the next big step.
Rym: And I really think we're going to see a few rich people buying automated Google cars in the next five years and using them on a day to day basis.
Rym: And I think that is going to be a huge tipping point for the technology.
Rym: I now will argue that within in my lifetime, I know this is an easy argument to make.
Rym: Scott's prediction will come true and we will have a shift toward humans can't drive at all unless they pass some specialized like.
Rym: I'm a car engineer.
Rym: test like car pilot will be a rare thing.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And you'll respect, you know, that's the other thing I understand, right?
Scott: Cars is so much more dangerous, right?
Scott: You know, even today you have this level of respect for the captain of a ship and the captain of a plane, right?
Scott: Because they're transporting you in a vehicle and your life is in their hands.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But there's no respect for the training.
Scott: There's a little respect for the train engineer, but there should be more.
Scott: And I guess there's some respect for the conductor, but he ain't driving right.
Scott: There should be more as much respect as there is for the ship captain and the plane captain, for the bus driver, the train engineer and the car driver.
Scott: And if you do not command that level of respect, right, because of your skills and operating this dangerous transportation thing, you shouldn't be driving.
Rym: Now, the trouble is that pragmatically, you know, I don't know anyone else in the car, but pragmatically, the United States is a place where without a car, you're pretty much fucked unless you live in New York.
Scott: Then let's just I'm the.
Scott: I'm a terror of the bandaid kind of guy.
Scott: You know, no pain, no gain.
Scott: I think we should just suffer greatly all at once.
Scott: And then that suffering will force us to fix the real problem, except probably won't.
Rym: And it would be to, you know, you realize how much we rely on cars.
Rym: shipping in the nation would probably grind to a halt, which means people would fix it real quick.
Rym: No, they wouldn't be like.
Rym: it's not an easy thing to fix.
Rym: It's not.
Scott: a lot of people just don't have the skills to be surprised when people are desperate, how quickly they will fix.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Like the how many students.
Scott: This is how America works.
Scott: This mentality.
Scott: You wait until the last minute.
Scott: The deadline shit's about to hit the fan and then you get it done the last minute.
Scott: The thing is, we've got things set up to where.
Scott: there never is the deadline.
Scott: There never is the last minute.
Scott: So it's just like we got to make it to where like now is the time.
Scott: you're fucked.
Scott: If you don't fix it by the end of the week, you're screwed.
Scott: People will fix it by the end of the week, the same way they would because same way they write the paper one hour before the cut.
Rym: My experience has been that good driving is not something that most people are capable of quickly.
Scott: Oh, I don't think they'll solve it by good driving.
Rym: So what are they going to solve it by trains?
Rym: Scott, it takes years to build a new train network.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, when people need the train to get to work, they'll fucking knock down people's houses real.
Scott: They won't.
Scott: Yes, they will.
Rym: Pragmatically, the Google car is actually a good solution because trains only make sense in very high population density areas and between geographically similar high population density.
Scott: Also, people will fucking move to where trains are now.
Rym: They won't.
Rym: That's it's not.
Rym: moving is not something people can do quickly.
Rym: You greatly overestimate people's ability when they're forced to know they won't because it's actually there are kind of non fungible problems that they can't overcome that quickly.
Scott: Then maybe you'll be they'll stay there and die.
Scott: And then people will only be living where the trains are.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: This is why I take the pragmatic approach.
Scott: Not a bad idea.
Rym: Cars, you know, it's kind of like, you know, trains are more like token ring in certain specialized areas.
Rym: They're much better because they're extremely ring is not better for anything.
Scott: It is in the sense that no one uses token or anything these days, except for an old token that still exists.
Scott: Manufacturing still uses token bus, a brand new token ring, but no one would make.
Rym: a token bus is still used.
Rym: And you don't want to know why in a brand new factory.
Rym: Scott, the reason they use things like token buses is because while they may have high latency and low bandwidth, they have perfectly reliable latency.
Scott: There's no such thing as jitter.
Scott: But there are plenty of other alternatives that also have the same reliability.
Rym: Like what?
Scott: You can use like the CAN bus or various other buses that are not the token bus.
Rym: Scott, token, do you even know what?
Rym: token buses?
Rym: It's not the same as token ring.
Scott: I'm just saying.
Rym: And anyway, that aside, the token ring analogy is that it is a. it is a purpose built like it was a deterministic system as opposed to the early Ethernet, which in a place where population is distributed and work and life and home and all these things are distributed in a semi randomized fashion.
Rym: You can't have a train that goes to those places in an efficient manner, but you can have very small packets, which cars that go.
Rym: The problem with cars is that by and large, people are shitty drive.
Scott: Well, you shouldn't have built the houses like that in the first place, thus requiring the cars.
Scott: You would have built the houses all close to each other to begin with.
Scott: You wouldn't have this problem.
Rym: But even New York, other than certain high traffic times, taking a cab pretty much anywhere in the city is still faster than taking mass transit.
Scott: Yeah, but it's not faster if everyone did that.
Rym: Exactly.
Scott: And if everyone took the train, then it'd be even better because then.
Rym: But the reality is we have this existing infrastructure that even if we make strides to get rid of it over time, we can't just immediately transplant millions of people.
Scott: Free bicycles for everybody.
Rym: Yeah, no cars on the road rather than building trains everywhere, because that's a crazy solution.
Rym: You build trains where trains make sense and you use this sort of packet switch cars driven by computers model, you know, computerized buses that take place every car with a computer car.
Rym: It takes time.
Scott: That's boring.
Rym: Yeah, but it's pragmatic and it works.
Scott: Yeah, but it means that by the time nothing's going to be solved, even when we're dead, because it'll take so long.
Rym: But one big problem will be solved.
Rym: By the time I'm old, I can still get around no matter where I live because I'll have the Google car.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: So Xdriver, there was an OAV that was six episodes.
Rym: The show was terrible.
Scott: There was an XD Danger Zone OAV that was one episode.
Rym: That show tricked us.
Scott: There was a movie that was 62 minutes long.
Scott: That was one movie.
Rym: The Oh my God, this guy did the character designs and it looked beautiful and it was about cars.
Rym: It was just stupid.
Scott: And there was a manga, but I can't figure how many volumes it was.
Rym: Anyway, but anyway, things of the day.
Rym: What do you got for me?
Scott: So, you know, the classic Bugs Bunny cartoon, What's Opera Doc?
Rym: One of my favorites.
Scott: The Spear and Magic Helmet.
Scott: It's everyone's favorite, right?
Rym: I like the the opera singer one a little better.
Scott: Yeah, well, anyway, but there was some guy made a remix of it a while ago from 2005.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And DJ BC made this remix in '05.
Scott: But just now in '12, some guy, I don't know if it's the same guy or a different guy, made remix the video to go along with that remix song.
Scott: And now it is much more presentable and accessible and entertaining on the YouTube than the song and MPV format alone.
Scott: And thus that is now quality enough to become a thing of the day.
Scott: You should watch it.
Scott: It's only got like 302 views and it actually has like four dislikes.
Scott: And I'm like, what?
Rym: I realize, you know, watching YouTube videos and messing around with statistics and everything that it seems like any new video that goes up gets some dislikes, no matter what it is after a certain amount of time.
Scott: I don't you know, the thing is, is like I don't dislike anything like, you know, I just never like.
Scott: sometimes I'll be like, oh, I don't remember this video like, but like I'll never feel like dislike.
Scott: I'll never get that feeling to go and do that.
Scott: Like I don't even know why they even have the thumbs down there.
Scott: I don't know, whatever.
Scott: Who cares?
Rym: Yeah, that's an interesting.
Rym: we could talk about the design of that and what it does.
Rym: There's a game there.
Scott: Yeah, but it's like I never even think to click thumbs down.
Scott: Maybe if I watched a video and it's painful, I might think to click it, but it's never happened.
Rym: So He-Man is horrible.
Rym: You should never watch it if you didn't know better, unless it's the live action movie, which I kind of want to watch again so we can do a show on.
Scott: Or unless it's for research purposes.
Rym: Yeah, but even then, it's rough.
Scott: It is.
Rym: I would suggest if you ever want to research He-Man, have someone do the research of the show who never saw it as a child and thus will not realize that they were, in fact, an idiot when they were five.
Scott: So, you know, the toys are kind of OK.
Scott: The comic books are a lot like the show.
Rym: I've never read the comic books.
Rym: I'm kind of intrigued.
Scott: It was originally a comic book.
Scott: I think it's British.
Rym: If I'm not mistaken, I was reading a Wikipedia article about it a long time ago when I was trying to when I thought, hey, I wonder if He-Man was good.
Rym: I remember trying to figure out what Skeletor's deal was because I realized as a kid I never in my entire childhood of watching He-Man religiously had any idea what Castle of Grayskull actually was or who the fuck Skeletor was.
Scott: I kept trying to understand.
Scott: Like when I was a kid also, I couldn't really understand it.
Rym: I was like, what does He-Man want?
Rym: What is Skeletor after?
Scott: It's like Castle of Grayskull was like the big toy.
Scott: But it's like they spent most of their time in this other castle that was more fancy and futuristic and they hardly ever went to Castle of Grayskull.
Scott: that I could remember.
Scott: And it was just weird.
Scott: And this is why you don't watch He-Man.
Rym: Yeah, but anyway, here's a compilation of a good number of the insults that come out of Skeletor's skeleton mouth.
Scott: And hey, Rym, you have shitty things in your day.
Rym: It's it's pretty great.
Rym: It reminded me both how great He-Man was and how terribly great He-Man was.
Scott: You said was is not the wrong term.
Scott: He-Man still is.
Rym: No, it isn't.
Rym: It's not an is.
Rym: It's a was.
Scott: It doesn't exist anymore.
Rym: The He-Man that I saw as the child is a was because that can never be experienced again, except through the mind of an idiot child.
Scott: I could just bash you over the head a whole bunch of times.
Rym: That might work.
Rym: So in the meta moment, we're going to be at the Penny Arcade Expo.
Rym: Holy shit.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: I didn't see that coming.
Rym: Oh, my God.
Rym: It's coming.
Rym: We're going to be there.
Rym: I picked my book club book, but I'll do a separate show where we talk about why.
Rym: But a little heads up.
Rym: The book club book is going to be The Hunger Games by Suzanne Collins.
Scott: I have not heard the positive things.
Scott: It seems to be.
Rym: I've heard nothing but positive things.
Rym: Everyone's flipping out about this book and the movies come in.
Rym: So I want to see what the deal is.
Scott: Yeah, but this isn't the kind of positive buzz you usually hear about something that's actually good.
Scott: It's like I can sort of tell by the smell.
Scott: It's the same kind of buzz I got from, let's see, Harry Potter and Twilight and those sorts of things that people like that aren't actually good.
Rym: So I'm going to let you in on a secret that I'm not going to say in the real book club book show.
Rym: I read the whole book while I was at the airport.
Rym: And it's actually pretty good.
Rym: Yeah, like I was really I thought I'd read it to then do a book club book show about.
Rym: Yeah, you guys like this book, but it's kind of crap.
Rym: Battle Royale, whatever.
Rym: But you know what?
Scott: That's what I heard.
Scott: I heard it was crappy battle royale above.
Rym: It's more like Running Man crossed with 1984.
Rym: Which are running men of the Arnold, of course.
Scott: Oh, OK.
Rym: Who out there?
Rym: but you knows about your running man?
Rym: All of Korea, South Korea, outside of Korea.
Rym: Who else?
Scott: Conrad.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So Arnold running man, but 1984 style with a little bit of.
Rym: I'd buy that for a dollar.
Rym: It's pretty good.
Rym: More so than I expect is that's going to be the book club book.
Scott: Well, if you read it just at the airport, then it's I could probably read it real fast.
Rym: It's short.
Rym: It's well written.
Rym: I don't know what I can say.
Rym: And you know what?
Scott: Isn't there multiples of them?
Rym: I only read the first one, but it is, in fact, I think, a trilogy.
Scott: Great.
Rym: Well, we're only doing the first book.
Rym: Oh, I just figured out what the third book is going to be about because the title anyway gives it all the way.
Scott: Maybe, maybe.
Scott: May I have to pick a book that you of evil next time?
Scott: Why would you pick a book of evil?
Scott: Well, since you've read this entire book already, maybe I'll read it extra quickly and we'll do this book club right away and then get it out.
Scott: You know, and then I'll come out with something else.
Rym: Well, if you do something I don't like, I got to warn you, the nonfiction is coming out.
Rym: I'll do that.
Rym: The Norman Davies book I'm reading right now.
Scott: I'll have to do, then I'll have to count.
Rym: Four hundred pages of like, Prussian history.
Scott: I'll have to counter with ultimate fiction.
Rym: Uh, Scott, you counter with ultimate fiction.
Rym: I'll counter, counter with the Katamani Cristo.
Scott: I can counter with Ulysses.
Rym: You're seriously going to read Ulysses.
Rym: That's like coming to me with the Davy Crockett nuclear artillery and even trying to make a threat.
Scott: It's basically...
Rym: For you listeners who are not aware, the Davy Crockett...
Scott: Ramble isn't a reason.
Rym: The Davy Crockett artillery.
Scott: Got a nuke in the motorcycle situation.
Rym: Was notable in that it was nuclear artillery whose range was such that the person firing it was inside of the blast.
Scott: That is correct.
Rym: So yeah, Hunger Games is going to be the book club book.
Rym: I cheated because I already read it and it was pretty good.
Scott: Great.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Internet, YouTube channel, all that stuff.
Rym: So we were trying to figure out what to do a Monday show on this morning and I wanted to do the fixed protocol, a single protocol.
Scott: Which nobody cares about.
Rym: Actually, I think people would because I think there's a lot to talk about related to the fixed protocol.
Rym: Why it's the way it is, is a nice study of how to design a protocol for a thing.
Scott: Maybe in general and from that general perspective, maybe someone cares, but no one I think that is not a financial person gives a shit.
Rym: I think they would.
Rym: Anyone who's technological, if you want a job that pays a lot of money, knowing the fixed protocol at all, you'll know it more than the majority of tech people in the financial world and you will be in surprisingly high demand.
Rym: But you have to be OK with writing software to interface between the fixed protocol and arbitrary middleware as in like L.L.M.
Rym: or 59 West or stuff like that, maybe like Active MQ.
Rym: But I digress.
Rym: So then we started talking about other acronyms.
Rym: and oh, should we do a show?
Scott: Yeah, we can do a show on that acronym.
Scott: Let's just do a show on every acronym one by one and that'll fill us with Monday shows forever.
Rym: And it's kind of a good idea, but some acronyms are more equal than others.
Rym: I mean, FTP, there is literally nothing interesting to say about FTP.
Rym: Put other than get passive versus active FTP is something that no one out there actually understands.
Scott: There's also a binary in ASCII mode.
Rym: Yep, except binary by default.
Rym: Duh, duh.
Rym: Who even uses ASCII mode for anything?
Scott: You want to send a text file?
Rym: Yeah, binary mode.
Rym: Jesus.
Rym: Otherwise, you're going to run into the whole Unix versus win anyway.
Scott: Well, that's if it's a Unicode text file, but I'm talking about if you have an ASCII text file for real.
Rym: Who has that and needs to FTP it?
Rym: The real problem is passive versus active.
Rym: You know the difference?
Rym: Because I don't I did.
Scott: I remember it every time that I you have to engage with it, I remember what the deal is and then I forget it again.
Rym: It only matters to the guy who manages the firewall between two people who just want to transfer a file.
Scott: Isn't it one like the ports?
Scott: Oh, is it like one where like the ports open and you're holding it and then it's like you hold the TCP connection open all the time.
Scott: And the other one is a little more complicated.
Scott: You hit you send the packet to when you want to do something and then it opens you up another port where you send your thing and then you close that.
Rym: Kind of it's a little more complex.
Rym: Remember, FTP has two channels.
Rym: It has these file sending channel and the command control channel.
Rym: So it has to do.
Rym: basically the simple way to put it is you pick passive or active depending on who you want the firewall configuration to be a pain in the ass for the guy on the other side or the guy who manages your network.
Scott: The guy with the server has to do the pain in the ass here.
Rym: The real answer is use SCP and or SFT.
Scott: But then you have to share keys and stuff and make a count, something like that, which is annoying.
Rym: Nobody does that in the real world.
Rym: As far as I found, the majority of techies just use password association.
Rym: That's it.
Scott: That's awful.
Rym: But I digress.
Rym: So we were talking about acronyms and we realized we'd never actually done a show on like network mounted storage.
Scott: So we did a show about NASes and why you should get one.
Scott: But we didn't talk about the specifics of the different, you know, technologies, the protocols that are used to actually share the files and mount storage, you know, connect storage devices to other computers across a network.
Scott: You know, like SIFs, Samba, NFS, DRVD, all these guys.
Scott: We didn't talk about those guys.
Rym: In fact, I'm pretty sure we said like, yeah, good NASes unless you share all those arbitrary protocols.
Scott: You can even use there's even like HTTP mounts, SSH mounts, you know, there's all kinds of stuff out there.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So we figured we'd go through some of those and kind of talk.
Rym: You know, it's a nice way to.
Rym: you know, I always try to find tech topics because Scott insists that Monday shows should be about technology itself and not like pseudo technology, like commenting on blogs.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Or, you know, the industries are that's a social that's it's a media topic that is only technological because everything is technological.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I mean, you want to you know, we could take the excuse and do a show about journalism.
Scott: Well, because every industry now in the world and everything is not technological, everything technology has its grip on everything in our entire society.
Scott: But so we could do a show about chemical factories and it could.
Scott: oh, it's a technological show because there's computers in chemical factories.
Rym: Let's do a show about the biological, sole biological processes of pooping.
Scott: Well, that's a science show, which is OK for Monday.
Rym: OK, so science or technology.
Rym: Right.
Scott: But you're talking about if you want to talk about journalism, that's a social topic.
Scott: That's not a technological topic.
Rym: Pooping, journalism.
Rym: I don't think most people out there actually really even technologists know about these things and or use them.
Scott: Well, I think the thing is, a lot of people who do use them, they know like the commands maybe or what you have to do to make them work, but they don't actually know how they work or what's going on down low.
Scott: And I don't really know half as much as I should.
Scott: Yeah, because I tend to just look up the commands, make it work, and that's it.
Rym: I knew a lot more than I do now because I use IT, like that was part of my education was like the lowdown, like SMB, like the protocol itself.
Rym: We learned a lot of core technology that has not actually been applicable in my later life.
Scott: Because no one uses that anymore.
Rym: But even, you know, there's some basic stuff you should know.
Rym: So you want to start with SMB, because I guess that's the one most people know about and use.
Scott: Well, SMB is also known as Samba because there was an open source thing called Samba.
Scott: That was the open source SMB sort of software, client server software.
Rym: You know it as effectively, you'll think of it as Windows file sharing.
Scott: Well, the old Windows file sharing.
Rym: Yeah, well, the new Windows file sharing is pretty much CIFS.
Scott: Right, which is Active Directory as opposed to work groups.
Rym: No, no, no.
Rym: Active Directory is nothing more than a glorified LDAP that it's a directory structure to list stuff.
Rym: It has nothing to do with the sharing itself.
Rym: It's just the authentication for it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But that's what goes, you know, CIFS is basically the SMB that goes with the Active Directory, whereas SMB Active Directory is like old busted.
Rym: That's a conflation that you should not go down that road because you're very close to being wrong.
Rym: Let's just talk about file sharing.
Rym: So Windows file sharing.
Scott: I'm sure we should first mention that SMB and such also does like printer sharing and all sorts of weird shit like that.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Do you know what SMB stands for?
Scott: Is it like symmetric multi something?
Rym: OK.
Rym: CIFS is like common Internet file system.
Rym: And I actually did not even know the acronym SMB ever.
Rym: So I had to look it up.
Scott: I thought it was like symmetric multi, but no.
Rym: Server message block.
Scott: OK.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Nice.
Rym: It's one of those things where you try to guess and you're wrong.
Rym: Like, you're never going to get that one.
Rym: I never would have guessed when I was when I was first learning about hardware that ISA was like industry standard architecture.
Rym: You didn't know that?
Rym: When I first learned about computers, I looked at this bus and I was like, all right, it must the accurate.
Rym: It must have something to do with the bus.
Rym: No, no, no.
Scott: AGP does it anyway.
Rym: So SMB and CIFS are pretty much the windows way of sharing files.
Rym: And Linux actually kind of sucks at it.
Scott: Well, I mean, there is Samba, like we said, which sort of does it.
Scott: And it works.
Scott: like you can make it work.
Scott: And I've made it work in the past.
Scott: And OS X works, but has its weird, quirky differences when it comes to using this.
Scott: But it also just kind of works like you can mount and type in the right the thing.
Scott: The major problem with both Samba, SMB and CIFS is that when you add, you know, the you know, the patterns of the your eyes or your ends or whatever they're called.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Because they're not.
Scott: they don't look like URLs of like double backslashes and all these things very noncompatible.
Rym: Right.
Scott: They tend to change like on your Windows machine.
Scott: You'd be like, oh, how do I connect to this service was backslash backslash DRV-01C2 and then it works.
Scott: But then on your you want to connect to the same thing on the Mac.
Scott: Oh, well, it's on there.
Scott: You actually have to do like SMB colon forward slash forward slash something, something, something.
Scott: And it's totally different, even though it's the same exact thing in the same exact protocol.
Scott: The names of the spots that you're connecting to have different patterns.
Scott: And it's really annoying as all hell.
Scott: And like sometimes like, you know, want you to use a password, but you won't have the password configured, but it'll ask you for one anyway.
Scott: And you won't know what to type in.
Scott: And it's like no one's following, you know, the same steps, even though the actual underlying protocol is the same and the code that handles that is 90 percent identical.
Scott: Really annoying.
Rym: Now, at the same time, though, like if using just Windows, it is actually a pretty great way to share files.
Scott: Yeah, it does.
Scott: Just if you're using just Windows and you set it up properly, everything just works.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: And a lot of people, though, do have trouble with it.
Rym: And it's because they do it wrong, mostly because they don't understand how it works at the low level.
Rym: So they try to like, you know, they go to their network tab and try to browse for something that isn't on the local network.
Rym: And without a wind server or directory or something to tell their computer where the other thing is, then they're not going to find what they're looking for.
Scott: So if you want to set up Windows sharing between two Windows computers or something like that, here's what you do.
Scott: This is the easiest guaranteed way of making it work with no trouble.
Scott: First, you've got to have Windows computers that aren't fucked the fuck up.
Scott: If you fuck them up, then I got no help for you.
Rym: Also, not old Windows computers.
Rym: Right.
Scott: You have to follow the policies of Scott and never installing weird bullshit on your computer or changing settings from the defaults for no reason or any bullshit like that.
Scott: Then find the folder you want to share.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Click on that motherfucker, go to sharing and say, share that bitch.
Scott: Simple sharing.
Scott: Go.
Scott: Right.
Scott: OK, now it's shared.
Scott: But no one can see it, really.
Scott: So what you got to do is you got to go and make a home group or a work group or whatever you want to call it.
Rym: Now, home groups are actually pretty new.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And whatever Windows you got.
Rym: What's interesting is that nobody I know knows how it works or even realizes what it is.
Rym: Windows kind of makes you set it up when you set up a Windows.
Rym: You know, it detects other PCs like, hey, there's a home group here.
Rym: Get the code from the other computer.
Rym: And it's right.
Scott: So the first computer you set up is the one that establishes the home group.
Scott: And the other ones connect to the home group.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And you just have to type in the same name for the home group and the same username and password.
Scott: If you have one on all the computers on your LAN, on the same LAN, and they'll all be in the same home group as each other.
Scott: And they'll be able to see each other's shares and they'll just be there.
Scott: And then you just share the shares and then you go double click on my network and you'll see the shares in there.
Scott: And you can just right click on them and be like mount or connect or open or whatever.
Scott: And all the printers or files that are shared, they'll just be there and you can connect to them and make them work as your local printer or as your local hard drive.
Scott: And your computer won't really know the difference.
Scott: But there are some Windows applications I've noticed that would be like they'll be able to detect the fact that it's a network share and they'd be like, oh, no, I don't use network shares and they won't go on there.
Rym: But never run into that.
Scott: I've run into that or it's like, no, I will not.
Scott: I refuse to save a file to a network share.
Scott: You have to save a file to a local share.
Rym: Usually that has to do with permissions being weird.
Scott: No, like specifically the program popped up a window, a dialog.
Scott: that said, I this program cannot use, you know, you cannot put your like whatever library on a network share.
Scott: It must be on a local disk.
Rym: That's interesting.
Scott: I get new.
Rym: Yeah, you could know from the way the resources anyway.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: But really, Windows sharing, everyone I know has problems with it.
Scott: Try to do too much of this.
Rym: One, Windows, if you set it up by default, will often have trouble when it tries to when you try to connect to a Windows share from the outside with a device that either isn't in the same work group or isn't in the domain, or if the like the usernames, like people will often be in like a domain or something.
Rym: And then they try to log into a share on some other computer that's set up differently.
Rym: And it'll ask for the account, but it'll want to use the same like username between the two.
Rym: So if I have the Rym account on my PC and there's a local Rym account on the other PC and I, you know, it tries to always connect with like a default account and then it'll say, hey, do you want to connect with other credentials?
Rym: The Windows UI for using different credentials, like the other guy's username instead of your username are actually pretty counterintuitive.
Scott: And usually because you don't know if you're supposed you don't know if it's like, is it forwarding by account locally to the other computer?
Scott: or does it want the account from the other computer or what?
Scott: Like what does it want?
Scott: Like mine is if you don't have an active directory with a single sign on for your whole network, you have no idea which account you want to use.
Rym: Like mine is a good example.
Rym: I set it up to do simple like standard Windows file sharing.
Rym: And yet whenever I connect to it, it'll be like, hey, what account do you want to use?
Rym: And if I use Rym and my password, it usually will freak out and say, ah, and then I have to click connect with alternate credentials, type the exact same thing in and then it'll work.
Scott: Right, because the first time is trying to use your local Rym, which is wrong, and the second time it'll actually use the other Rym from the other side.
Rym: But on Emily's computer, where just by hook or crook, the username on the NAS is a different local account name from the local account she uses on her computer, it just wouldn't fucking let her connect.
Rym: And the moral of all this is that NASes tend to not really be configurable enough compared to a Windows box and tend to implement Windows type sharing kind of shittily.
Scott: You know what I do.
Rym: And you're going to run into all these problems and the devices tend to not give you any reasonable logs to tell you how to fix it.
Rym: And your Windows PC doesn't give you any reasonable kind of errors or dialogues to tell you how to fix it.
Rym: And unless you know how SMB works or CIFS works, you're not going to fix it.
Scott: Here's the solution that I have in my house.
Scott: You know what it is?
Scott: I have all the shares.
Scott: It's just completely anonymous, wide open, full access shares.
Rym: Yeah, I don't do that.
Scott: And then I have network level security.
Scott: So if you come into my house and try to use the internets, you'll connect on the Wi-Fi, which is a separate Wi-Fi and a separate subnet.
Scott: And you won't even see that NAS, even though it's right there in front of you.
Rym: See, now, the reason I didn't do that is because I have one NAS where I made three shares.
Rym: Well, I have a private share for me and a private share for Emily.
Rym: And then I have a media share that's public to anyone in my house.
Rym: because, you know, anyone around, I say, like, hey, you know, take any of my movies you want.
Rym: But I want me and Emily to have right access to that and no one else to have right access.
Rym: And then the most important thing I have...
Scott: Now you're getting fancy.
Rym: I have a Dropbox.
Rym: So when someone's over and they're like, hey, I have this movie, I'm like, yeah, dump it on my Dropbox.
Scott: Ah, see, well, actually, you know, I got all kinds of different stuff going on, right?
Scott: So if someone has to dump me the movie, well, the HTPC is on the local network so they can dump it, you know, through there.
Scott: There's also my NAS as a feature where you can put a USB stick in and push a button and it'll just take the whole USB stick and put it on itself.
Scott: So, you know, I got a lot of ways to get files from people who want to dump, you know, and also I don't have multiple people in the house to manage.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's just me.
Scott: So I don't need to have like the separate account for the other people with the separate shares to share different things.
Rym: Also, when we have large gatherings, you know, it tends to be at my place.
Rym: So people are using my shit a lot more than they use your shit directly.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: If they want to come to my house, there's plenty of shit they can use.
Scott: They just can't be accessing my files.
Rym: I let people access my files.
Scott: I don't want to access my files.
Rym: But, you know, aside from NASes, regular Windows file sharing pretty much just works.
Rym: The tricks are when you're using non-Windows devices like a NAS or more importantly, a fucking Mac that can't connect to fucking anonymous shares because it's a fucking Mac.
Rym: Why do Macs handle this so poorly?
Rym: Because Linux handles Samba SMB shares really poorly.
Scott: Well, that's not to do with Linux.
Scott: It has to do with Samba, right?
Scott: Because OSX is Unix.
Scott: It's not Linux.
Rym: Yeah, yeah.
Rym: So Unix and Linux, right?
Rym: Many times the problems with them are not the core.
Rym: You know, GNU/Linux is fine, but Samba is implemented by someone else and they don't do it that well.
Rym: Problem is, because there's no other good alternative.
Rym: It effectively is a Linux problem, even though it's not really a Linux problem.
Scott: It's a Starnix problem.
Scott: Anyone using anything that uses the open source Samba thing has this problem.
Rym: It's yet one other reason why Linux kind of sucks on the desktop unless you're just a developer.
Scott: Well, you know, the thing is, if you're doing the basic stuff of just connecting, it kind of works.
Scott: If you're doing if you have like a standard active directory that's configured properly and you have like SUSE Linux, Susie, whatever it's pronounced, then it kind of just works.
Scott: But if you got anything weird and you have to change configurations, it's possible to make it work.
Scott: It's just a nightmare.
Rym: Yeah, we're not talking about using Samba to run like a Windows domain because that's way out of scope.
Scott: Fuck that shit.
Rym: But you should be able to mount someone else's Samba share or someone else's Windows share on your Linux box if you install Samba and you read a FAQ.
Rym: But really, for most people, it's not worth trying to get your Linux box to share two Windows boxes.
Rym: You're going to run into trouble.
Rym: It's usually not worth the effort.
Scott: Right.
Rym: So let's talk about another really common thing, NFS, it's the network file system, which is basically, sadly, the easiest to use sharing protocol if you're only using Linux boxes.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, if you're only using Unix machines, NFS just works.
Scott: It's really easy.
Scott: Basically, you know, normally you would mount local block devices to spot two places in your file system.
Scott: So you'd be like mount dev SD0 to /mnt.
Scott: Done.
Scott: Network file system is pretty much the same thing.
Scott: It's like, hey, mount this IP address/projects to home projects.
Scott: Ta-da!
Scott: And it just works like that.
Scott: And, you know, the permissions, the Unix file system permissions are kind of preserved and forwarded through.
Rym: Which again, this is why it doesn't work so well with Windows.
Rym: Right.
Scott: Which is good and bad, because on the one hand, if you've got a bunch of machines all connecting to the same NFS and they all have the same user accounts, all good.
Scott: But if like, if on this machine, you know, user ID 1001 is me and on that machine user ID 1001 is Rym, I might save a file to the NFS and then Rym has access to it if he comes through that other computer because his user ID matches the right file system up there.
Rym: The whole fact that user IDs are used the way they are between systems and Linux has actually been a major pain for me for a long time.
Scott: But it just works.
Scott: It's easy.
Scott: You just start it up and you can connect in like two commands and suddenly you have a hard drive that can be mounted on multiple computers simultaneously.
Scott: And it works.
Scott: And it's kind of fast.
Scott: But this is some other problems, right?
Rym: Well, one, if you don't know what you're doing, you know, there's a lot of configuration options when you set this up and you have to do it, you know, auto-mounting, FSTAB, this kind of stuff that most people don't know about.
Scott: Yeah, but it's standard Linux-y stuff, right?
Scott: It's not that weird.
Rym: But to set up NFS, if you're just a kind of not super technical person, you're not even going to know where to start.
Scott: Ubuntu has some good documentations.
Rym: No, I guess Ubuntu.
Rym: I guess I haven't set up NFS on a non like...
Scott: You still have to hit the command line, right?
Scott: It's not going to...
Rym: Yeah, but two, if you set up NFS wrong, you know, synchronous versus asynchronous, the options...
Scott: I was just about to go into that.
Rym: And the other computer goes down, you're fucked.
Rym: You are so fucked.
Rym: Your NFS mount will just hang.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: And there's almost no way to fix that.
Rym: You'll get like a zombie process.
Rym: You got to reboot.
Scott: Yeah, so it's basically it works.
Scott: It's simple, but it's unreliable and can get really shaky, right?
Scott: This synchronous mode and this asynchronous mode.
Scott: The synchronous mode is like, look, whenever I write a file, whenever I do something, wait till that finishes before you do the next thing.
Scott: That way, the hard drive is always in a good way, right?
Scott: We won't like write half a file and fail to write the rest of it.
Scott: If something happens to the network, right?
Scott: I mean, when you have a computer with a hard drive in it, you're pretty much like going to assume, OK, serial ATA bus isn't going to fail.
Scott: It's really reliable.
Scott: It's basically 100 percent reliable for all intents and purposes.
Scott: Maybe your raid card might go down, but it's not going to like flake out.
Scott: Networks will continue to work, but get flaky.
Scott: You might drop a packet.
Scott: Well, what if I drop a packet when I'm sending a file over?
Scott: Well, I hope you were in synchronous mode, right?
Scott: Otherwise, your file is now fucked up on the other end of the line.
Scott: Uh, but if you're in the thing with synchronous mode is that it's mad slow.
Scott: And if a lot of people are using the same NFS, it's even more slow.
Scott: It's ultra slow, mega slow, almost unusably slow if there's a lot going on.
Rym: And if that's also, you know, it's like Scott said, it's easy to set up, but you really have to tweak it if you want to use it in any sort of performing way.
Rym: And to nobody but other Linux boxes are going to connect.
Rym: I mean, at least Linux being open, you know, you can install Samba.
Scott: I'm sure you can buy crazy software that I was about to say Windows.
Rym: There is software that gets NFS to work on Windows.
Rym: But last I used it.
Scott: Fuck that shit.
Rym: It is 10 years behind Samba on Linux.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So and it costs money and I've never seen it for free.
Rym: I've seen some for free.
Rym: I used it at RIT, actually.
Scott: Really?
Rym: It didn't work so well.
Scott: No kidding.
Rym: So if you look at Samba and think, I want to try what Samba was like.
Rym: Like 10 years ago, try getting NFS to work on a Windows PC.
Scott: Now, the asynchronous mode is pretty much the opposite.
Scott: It's like, oh, it's crazy fast and everything just sort of goes.
Scott: And I actually use the asynchronous mode because it's pretty reliable on a small, tiny land.
Scott: You know, you only got one guy mounting using it at a time and I could have trouble.
Scott: But what if some weird stuff happens, like the network flakes out?
Scott: You got mad corrupt files and NFS doesn't even care.
Scott: You might just ruin the whole thing.
Scott: Who knows what can happen?
Scott: because it just doesn't care.
Scott: It just sends the files back and forth as it willy nilly and just trust that everything coming out of the line is right.
Scott: Sometimes you'll save something to be broken.
Scott: You got to save it again.
Scott: You know, that's why I keep copies of stuff on the local hard drive and the NAS and maybe the cloud.
Scott: and you know, because you never know.
Scott: It's not true.
Scott: And you've even seen if you really want NFS to work properly, you have to configure all sorts of weird stuff like, you know, like chunk sizes of how many bits do you send per packet at once and how much do you buffer up on either end?
Scott: You need to actually configure all these crazy numbers to get the optimal performance.
Scott: And it's really not worth it.
Scott: So most people leave the defaults, which work, but you're going to get some slowness if you ever try to do anything remotely serious.
Rym: Now, it is nice that, you know, Windows network file sharing works pretty much as well as you're going to get it to work out of the box without you having to do anything other than set up the permissions.
Rym: And it really only gets complicated when you try to set up like a domain with like security policies and, you know, what's allowed to be shared and what isn't.
Rym: You're trying to do authentication across multiple devices.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I want the accounting department to be able to read and write these Excel files, but I don't want them to see anything else.
Scott: But I want the auditors need to be able to read the Excel files, but can't read them.
Scott: And then I need you know, it's like, oh, my God, kill yourself.
Rym: And all the problems with SMB and CFS really come down to devices that aren't Windows operating systems tend to implement poorly.
Rym: And the logs and documentation around problems are difficult for most people to follow.
Rym: NFS is deeply documented and difficult to follow for the exact opposite reason.
Rym: There's too much low level documentation.
Rym: And I don't know, NFS just kind of sucks in the modern era, but we're forced to use it because there isn't really much better for that exact purpose.
Scott: I want to take a side note here to talk about something called Fuse, right?
Scott: So Fuse is a relatively new thing, a few years old, and it's a. it's a Linux thing primarily, not even just general Unix, just mostly Linux.
Scott: But I have seen it on OS X, so I guess it's Unix in general.
Scott: But what it is, is it's F-U-S-E.
Scott: I think it's like the.
Scott: I forget what the F stands for, but it's basically like user mounted file system, like something like that.
Scott: Is it like full?
Scott: I forget the exact.
Scott: you can look it up.
Scott: I don't remember, but it's basically allowed.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So the main problem is on a Unix machine.
Scott: You know, only root really has permissions to mount file systems.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But sometimes one user, just a regular old user, has legitimate reason to mount a file system, perhaps in their home directory.
Scott: For example, I might SSH to another computer where I have access to files and it'll be really nice and convenient if I could mount that remote computer that I have SSH to as a local folder instead of using SCP and SFTP.
Scott: I could just use CP and MV and all those normal file system commands by mounting that locally.
Scott: Now, there are some permissions issues, right?
Scott: Because if I'm mounting something with SSH locally, then my local user account needs to be the only account that has permissions on that folder.
Scott: But on the remote machine, the permissions are totally different.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Because it's what are the accounts on that machine I'm SSHing to?
Scott: Totally different from the ones I have.
Scott: So the chmod's and the chown's and various file system things on the local machine that I'm on need to be translated and different when they're sent over the wire or received over the wire from the remote file system.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But basically Fuse is this kernel module and sort of user space system that allows you to do to mount almost anything.
Scott: You could mount like, you know, you could turn anything and turn it into a file system.
Scott: You could have like I'm going to turn that website into a file system and you could write some sort of driver that's like, OK, you mount the website.
Scott: And if you can't, if you you know, if you open up the file at home, then it'll you'll get the HTML for the index that HTML.
Scott: And if you you know, it's like you can turn anything.
Scott: It basically turns the file system into a user interface for anything because you can turn you know, you just write a file system driver that maps to any API, any any computerized thing in the world.
Scott: You could make like a video game that was in the form of a file system where like this one file and you open it up and it gives the instructions and then you create a file and that creates an item in your inventory and stuff like that.
Scott: And all the while that's communicating with like a database somewhere with the game data in it.
Scott: It's totally cool.
Scott: And you should try to, you know, see all the crazy, crazy cool things people have been able to mount.
Scott: Like you can mount your friggin scanner and, you know, when you scan something, a JPEG appears in that folder and then you read it out.
Scott: That kind of stuff works weird.
Rym: Now, one thing we didn't really talk about, you know, with NFS versus SMB, we kind of hinted on.
Rym: we were talking about SMB, but with Windows file sharing, you know, home groups and work groups and, you know, I guess Windows servers don't really exist anymore.
Scott: I hope I hope you're not using one of those.
Rym: I've set those up.
Scott: I have pity for you.
Rym: But the I think the biggest, biggest reason why Windows file sharing is so much better than the default in Linux is that it's pretty much self-organizing, like in a typical setup, like in a house, it's one flat network.
Rym: And even with the switch, all the PCs are going to find each other and you'll just kind of see all the other things you can mount on the network.
Scott: It's the same way.
Scott: the OSX file sharing uses Bonjour to find all the other Macs in the local area automatically.
Rym: Right.
Scott: You know, with Linux, you have to type in the IPs of the other guys.
Rym: NFS, you have to type, not a host name.
Rym: No, you don't want to use a host name.
Rym: You don't want DNS look ups for that shit.
Scott: No, you got to type in the IP address of all the other computers.
Scott: It's not just going to look around and find NFS shares on your network.
Rym: Now you could set up some startup scripts that did some stuff.
Rym: There are ways to make automated NFS mounts, but that's complicated and annoying.
Rym: It doesn't self-organize.
Scott: It will often fail.
Scott: And then what do you do?
Rym: So we talked, you know, these are like remote mounted file systems.
Rym: There's files somewhere.
Rym: I want to mount those locally to access them, to read or write.
Rym: And one thing I found is that most people try to set this up, mostly on Linux, more so than Windows, because Windows, they do it to like, literally, I want to give a guy files.
Rym: I want to get some files from some other device.
Rym: I've found people use it on Linux to do dumb shit.
Rym: Like they want it.
Rym: One, they'll use NFS to like mount their home directory remotely in Linux, which doesn't really work nearly as well as the Windows equivalent.
Rym: There are so many problems and things can go wrong.
Rym: Like if you try to log in and your home directory isn't there.
Rym: Linux does not handle that nearly as well as Windows does.
Scott: I know.
Scott: Right.
Rym: But what if we want to, you know, what if I'm like, what if I'm mounting a file system remotely because there's log files written there and I want to like have a thing that grips those log files to generate an alarm?
Scott: Why don't you just have the gripper run on the log file?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Or why don't you use syslog to send the relevant logs to all the places?
Rym: Why not the whole file system?
Scott: That's right.
Rym: When all you need to do is send the individual log lines that matter.
Rym: Syslog, in fact, will send the logs you need to the places you need them and not send all the bullshit.
Scott: That's how I have it set up at work.
Scott: I have one server and that all the other servers have syslog configured to send their logs to that one server.
Scott: So if I want to see logs, I go to that one server and look at the logs and you know what?
Scott: They're all in one big log file.
Scott: So it's like, oh, my God, all the varlog messages are mixed up together.
Scott: But actually, I can just grep and filter that down in one second to just the one machine I care about.
Rym: Or I go one step further.
Rym: The logs are written to their local systems and they're archived to, you know, with syslog to some remote system for archive purposes.
Rym: You know, one of the biggest problems in Linux is that the log files get gigantic because people are stupid.
Scott: Well, I got rotation.
Rym: Yeah, most people don't set that up.
Scott: It's default, at least on a modern distribution.
Rym: Not most people don't because they'll install like some software that logs to like its own place.
Scott: And this is why people say, oh, you got to mount var in a different partition.
Rym: You do need to.
Rym: You should.
Rym: People don't.
Rym: But what I do is one step further.
Rym: The logs are written somewhere else.
Rym: They're syslogged for archival purposes with rotation out of the way, but their agents grepping those logs and they only send to a central location logs, log lines that mean a human has to do something like, hey, error was written because shit went down.
Scott: None of this has to involve any sort of network file system mounting.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: So any time you need to mount a file system from somewhere else, step back and think, what do I need from that file system?
Rym: And if your only answer is this is the fastest way to do what I want to do, you're probably going about this the wrong way.
Scott: Yeah, it's usually, you know, it's a tool that can solve a lot of problems.
Scott: And a very bad and problematic way.
Scott: that will also cause problems like look at when they're usually most of the time there is a better solution besides a file share and a file server.
Rym: And well, not even just let's go once people don't do it.
Rym: The way most people use Samba is they navigate from the network to some share to get some files very different from even though it's the exact same underlying technology going to your computer and being like mount network drive and mounting some remote location as like the you drive.
Rym: Yeah, you usually don't need to do that in Linux is even worse.
Rym: Mounting a file system is the last thing you want to do.
Rym: So one level up from that, you know, let's do it at a higher level.
Rym: Tools like our sync, our sync can probably do what you're trying to do without mounting a stupid file system, especially if everyone has a lot of hard drive space.
Scott: Our sync is a great idea, you know, because you could just, hey, let's synchronize.
Scott: Now we've got plenty of copies of the files all around.
Rym: You can configure our sync to send something and then delete whatever happened on my local machine.
Scott: You can do crazy stuff even better than our sync for a lot of things.
Scott: If they're files that are edited frequently, like our sync is good.
Scott: If let's say you have a folder full of videos, let's say your video editors.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And you have.
Scott: you have someone's dumping in new source material into this big folder.
Scott: You can use our sync and you basically get all the latest source material, you know, synchronized locally to you.
Scott: And that's awesomeness.
Scott: Our sync is also and if someone and if some old source material got updated, you get that update.
Rym: It's also pretty good for the distribution of simple, not often reread configuration files like NTP configuration updates.
Rym: Right.
Scott: But let's say that you've got something that's edited a whole bunch, like, hey, this is the Excel document we're working on, then it's probably not the greatest idea to use our sync, because then, you know, you get all these too many people are syncing too frequently and it gets all broken.
Rym: Or are syncing like rapidly written to log files.
Rym: that again, you're doing something wrong.
Scott: But the thing is, even network mounting will give you problems depending because you get the situations where like, oh, you know, a guy made changes and saved it.
Scott: I loaded before he saved.
Scott: Now I saved on top of his save.
Scott: And I think Windows, if you use Office, has stuff to fight against this problem.
Scott: But other than that, you're going to you're going to have problems where a guy does work, saves it onto the network share and someone else saves on top of him and undoes his work.
Scott: And in that kind of situation, you need Git.
Scott: Git is that problem solver and the network share alone does not solve that.
Rym: Now, at the same time, you can go lower.
Rym: I mean, instead of mounting a remote file system, you can use a shared file system or something like DRBD, which I bring up every now and then because I'm a fan of it.
Scott: It's weird.
Scott: It's mad dangerous, yo.
Rym: It's dangerous if you don't understand it.
Scott: It's hard.
Rym: It's like a lightsaber.
Rym: So basically what this is, it will kill you unless you know how to use it.
Scott: So imagine this.
Scott: Imagine this.
Scott: I've got a bunch of servers and I've got my let's say not even have servers.
Scott: I got like three computers.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And all these computers have one hard drive each.
Scott: Now they could just use that hard drive straight up.
Scott: But, you know, I want all three computers to be identical.
Rym: Now let's back up.
Rym: Let's say I'm on one computer with three hard drives and I want them to be identical.
Rym: Well, I make a sort of like nerd raid.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So DRBD is basically raid where the disks are on multiple computers and it only does mirroring.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: So I have three computers and I DRBD them all and all those computers over the network connect to the DRBD.
Scott: So each computer has and one thinks to itself that it has a real hard drive in it.
Scott: It doesn't even know that it's this network mount situation.
Scott: It only sees a real hard drive.
Scott: It doesn't understand that is networked.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I mean, on the low level, it does, but on the higher level, it just regular hard drive.
Scott: But that hard drive happens to be a magic network hard drive.
Scott: That's actually three hard drives wide on three different computers.
Scott: So sitting down at any one of those computers, you'll see the exact same thing.
Scott: And if I edit the file on one computer on computer number two, suddenly the files edited.
Scott: You're like, what?
Rym: What now?
Rym: What the contention for, you know, who gets to edit a file?
Rym: and all that stuff is handled by the file system, which has nothing to do with DRBD.
Rym: DRBD is just at the block level.
Rym: The hard drive itself is basic.
Rym: Think of it as like a physical replica of the actual block device.
Scott: It's even below the file system.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Like NFS is a networked file system.
Scott: Ext three is a file system.
Scott: Riser FS is a file system.
Scott: What's the Windows one?
Rym: SMB CFS.
Scott: No, at the end and whatever it is.
Rym: Oh, NTFS.
Scott: Yeah, NTFS derp derp.
Rym: Well, CFS common Internet file system.
Scott: NTFS is a file system.
Scott: DRBD is not a file system.
Scott: You could use the RBD and format it with NTFS.
Scott: It would work.
Scott: You could do that.
Scott: You could take a DRBD and then use NFS on that shit.
Scott: It totally work.
Rym: Now, where do I use this sort of solution?
Rym: Well, we talked about log files.
Rym: What if I'm trying to do high availability with a database?
Rym: And the way some databases, most databases work is that when you make a transaction, it is written to a log.
Rym: Some file systems do their own sort of transactional logging.
Rym: You know, journaling, a journalized file system.
Rym: So the transaction is written to this log, which is a file.
Rym: And then that way the database can maintain.
Rym: if I do a select somewhere else before that transaction that's changing.
Rym: the database is completed, I see the database before that transaction.
Rym: But if I'm doing the operations, you know, I've made my own lock, then I personally, where I'm doing the changes, will see the changes I've made.
Rym: And then once I commit those changes, everyone else sees them.
Rym: So if I want to replicate that database, I want to in real time take that transaction log and have it be on my backup server at the same time.
Rym: So I need very low level, perfectly reliable, like block device, DRBD style stuff.
Scott: Now, sometimes it's the wrong answer for a database, right?
Scott: You could just use the database is built in master slave kind of set up, which is like Cassandra or Sloane.
Scott: Cassandra is is a totally is a totally different purpose.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But I mean, MySQL, Postgres, Oracle.
Rym: MySQL has some shitty binary replication.
Scott: Well, but it works, right?
Rym: Yeah, it's shitty, but it works.
Rym: I'm just saying, but Postgres has pretty good binary replication.
Scott: But the point is, you know, everyone's got this master slave replication, which totally works.
Scott: But with DRBD, you could basically get master, master, master, master.
Scott: And it doesn't even matter if you have it configured properly.
Rym: You can still run into problems.
Rym: Don't don't get us wrong.
Scott: Oh, absolutely.
Scott: But if it's a transactional, properly ACID compliant database and the DRBD is configured properly and the network's fast enough and all that stuff, it could totally work.
Rym: The moral of all of this is as such.
Rym: One from a user level, Windows style file sharing for most people is pretty much the best because it just works if you run in any if you do it right.
Scott: But most people don't do it right, which means it's like it's weird, like it just works.
Scott: But for 90 percent of people actually doesn't just work as they fuck it up.
Scott: I don't know what it is.
Scott: I think it's the user interface of it just like encourages people to do the wrong thing because it abstracts it a little too much.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: NFS, you have to understand exactly what you're doing to make it work, which is why it works all the time.
Rym: But you have to understand what you're doing.
Rym: So it's outside of the realm of people who aren't super computer anyway.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And most people, even if you're doing a mount like this, there's a level higher and a level lower.
Rym: And usually the solution to your problem is up or down in the middle.
Scott: Fuse is the higher level.
Scott: And then, you know, actual applications like, you know, the master slave in your database or get or something like that are the higher level.
Scott: And the lower level is DRV or even a SAN or some kind of hardware device or who knows what else.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: You know, there was a way with old SCSI, right?
Rym: You could have a SCSI card, right?
Rym: It has an idea of like one.
Rym: You have a hard drive at like two, a hard drive at three, another fucking computer at four that has access to the same SCSI bus.
Scott: You could do this.
Rym: I don't know if anyone ever did that, but you could.
Scott: I'm sure someone did that back in the day when they bought like a one gigabyte hard drive for like a thousand dollars.
Scott: And then, you know, everyone connected to it like a big scuzzy daisy chain going down the row of computers.
Scott: Sure, someone did that.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Notice we didn't talk about how the protocols work because that's boring shit.
Scott: And you could look it up online and I don't even know it off the top of my head because I would just look it up online.
Rym: I know NFS pretty well because at RIT, you know, talk about IT education.
Rym: We had take a whole class where we learned about the deep down bullshit of X2.
Rym: X3, like exactly how the journal worked, SMB, NFS and that Mac, whatever the old Mac sharing protocol, even for you, what it was.
Rym: Remember Mac had its own like file sharing protocol?
Scott: Well, they still you know, nowadays they still do.
Scott: Mac actually sort of is new, sort of like wanted to compete with Dropbox kind of iCloud thing.
Scott: But they also in the same process updated in the finder, like the thing that shares between Macs and uses Bonjour and whatever.
Scott: And it's kind of weird.
Scott: But if you have Macs, all Macs and you just want to share between those, then use that because it'll totally work the same way as the Windows one.
Scott: It'll actually be even easier.
Rym: And Macs, pretty much my experience with connecting them to Windows shares is I try it.
Rym: It'll either just work immediately or I'll never really get it to work.
Rym: And there's.
Rym: no I can't figure out why.
Scott: Because they hide all the buttons and switches.
Scott: All you can really do is try the default.
Scott: And if the default doesn't work, there's no other buttons to press.
Scott: You don't have to do.
Rym: I don't know if they fixed it.
Rym: But the last problem I had was if I had an anonymous share, I want anyone to be able to connect it.
Scott: No authentication keeps asking for user and password anyway.
Rym: So I'd eventually have to set up a password just for the Mac, even though everyone else and even even trying to use like guest guest doesn't work.
Scott: It has to be a real account.
Scott: I don't know, whatever.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And the thing is, we probably could have figured it out if we, you know, did some research and tried.
Rym: But fuck that noise.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: We're too old for research.
Scott: I'm sort of getting real hungry.
Scott: Let's go.
Rym: OK, we're done.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.