Rym: It's Wednesday, October 24th, 2012.
Scott: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights Tonight, the sixth One Piece movie.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So we were going to watch the first One Piece movie, and I downloaded it.
Rym: In fact, I downloaded a torrent that was every One Piece movie, up to like nine.
Rym: Whoa.
Rym: With Arabic and Italian subtitles only.
Scott: Well, we know it's very popular in Italy.
Scott: They have that great One Piece opener.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: The thing is, the opener that stuck in my head is the American opener, because of that panel I always wrote.
Rym: Did you- One Piece.
Rym: It's the name of the treasure on the grand line.
Scott: Did you not look at the notes on the torrent and see that- Yeah, so you know what?
Rym: Most of these torrents had fuck all for notes.
Scott: Were you on Pirate Bay?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Maybe you should go see for anime, sometimes you gotta go to the other site with like Baka BT or whatever.
Scott: I don't even know what it is.
Rym: I looked around and most of them had all the recent One Piece movies, but not the first one.
Rym: So I had another torrent, so I figured, you know, one of the two would be good.
Rym: Nope.
Rym: Also, only Italian.
Scott: I have a feeling you didn't read something.
Scott: Usually I notice it says on torrents, like, "This has Italian Dutch subtitles, this is Italian
Scott: subtitles.".
Rym: One of them had comments that were only in Italian, and I kind of thought, "Well, this one might not be
Rym: good.".
Rym: Gee.
Scott: But that was my back- I wonder.
Rym: That one was my backup torrent.
Scott: Right.
Rym: So this morning I'm like,
Rym: "Fuck.".
Rym: So I'd search for like every torrent, I'd start them all, because whatever, I got Fios.
Rym: And not only was not a single torrent in English, but one of them was in Hebrew.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: So all the other One Piece movies are really easy to get, so we watched the sixth One Piece movie.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Rym: We'll get to that in a little bit, but first we got some news, because it's Wednesday.
Scott: All right, so check this out.
Rym: I'm checking.
Scott: You know, Katie Cook wrote this pony comic.
Scott: I forgot, who's the guy who drew it?
Scott: Oh my god.
Rym: I don't remember.
Scott: And everyone keeps getting it confused.
Scott: anyway, sorry artist dude, because Katie Cook has been known as an artist, right?
Scott: You know, of many things.
Scott: And she's very, very good.
Scott: So when she suddenly writes a comic, everyone's like thinking she's drawing it without even, you know, noticing.
Scott: But anyway, the pony comic.
Scott: The pre-sales for it, I guess.
Rym: Of course, we're talking about My Little Pony, Friendship is Magic, you know, G4.
Scott: Yeah, issue number one from IDW, right?
Scott: The sales were over 90,000.
Scott: So wait, wait, wait, wait.
Scott: And you might be saying 90,000 copies.
Rym: So correct me if I'm wrong, but is not My Little Pony now, the new comic, before it's even available for real, outselling X-Men?
Scott: Yeah, I mean, it's kind of weird, right?
Scott: Back in the olden days, the number one selling comic book would be millions of copies, like action comics, you know, in the olden days, golden age.
Rym: You know, before everything we talk about on GeekNights.
Scott: Nowadays, if you sell 100,000 copies, you are pretty much the most popular comic there is because the only nerds buy those little, you know, buy floppy comic books in comic book stores and no one else.
Scott: And the number that they quote you is the number that comic book stores buy, not the number that comic book stores sell.
Scott: So a lot of times, you know, the best selling comic doesn't actually sell as well as you think it does.
Scott: Because comic book stores load up on it and then no one buys.
Rym: Or if they don't, maybe every comic book store only buys one.
Rym: That's still a lot of comics.
Scott: Well, no, that's that's a few thousand.
Rym: Yeah, there's more than a few thousand comic book stores.
Scott: There's so few comic book stores, you have no idea.
Scott: It's like a couple thousand.
Rym: Maybe three.
Rym: Well, I'll try to find out how many comic book stores there are in America.
Scott: It is only a few thousand, it is kind of sad.
Scott: It's a really sad number when you find it anyway.
Rym: But yet somehow there's that one in Newberg.
Scott: If that one even counts anyway.
Rym: There's the one in the hippie mall.
Scott: So the thing is, you know, something that, you know, they love to do with comics to make more money is they make multiple covers.
Scott: And the My Little Pony, Friendship is Magic.
Scott: issue number one is no exception.
Scott: There's a there's a like two or three covers to choose from.
Scott: And then there's like limited variant covers and then there's like a box set that has all the covers.
Scott: And then there's an even more limited cover and it's crazy.
Scott: Uh, so I actually did something I never do and bought all the covers, one of everything because I'll read the regular one and flip the rest of them on eBay to crazy pony people who don't know how to order comic books properly.
Rym: Even if they know how to order comic books, maybe they didn't think to preorder like this one.
Rym: They figured whatever.
Rym: No one's going to buy my little pony.
Scott: They're going to go into the comic book store asking for it and they're only going to have the regular cover or it'll be sold out.
Scott: Meanwhile, I'll have a full set.
Rym: So I found one number that said a little over twelve thousand comic book stores in the United States.
Rym: I found another number that said thousands and I found a link to a diamond distributors site that claims to have the answer, but doesn't actually become like if you go to the comic shop locator and you just go to every type in every zip code.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I'm going to get on that right now.
Scott: We have a database.
Scott: one comic shop locator is a database of every comic shop.
Scott: So if you go through it, you could count anyway.
Rym: Now the question is, how many people use that site?
Rym: And if I wrote a W get script that was going to hit it all night, how long before it shuts down?
Scott: So incompetent you could easily get the data anyway.
Scott: No, I'm worried that I'm going to bring it down that many.
Scott: So here's is something interesting, right?
Scott: Is that I got the preorder form that includes my little pony number two.
Scott: And there were three different covers this time.
Scott: Cover number one was the regular cover.
Scott: So I ordered that one.
Rym: Yeah, it is actually selling better than Uncanny X-Men, right?
Scott: Cover number two was a one in, I think, 50 or 25 variant, which means that if you're a comic book store and you order 25 copies of My Little Pony, one of them will have this different cover.
Scott: So if you want two of this different cover, you have to order 50 copies.
Rym: We've talked about why I think the way we distribute comics in this country is ridiculous.
Rym: So we don't need to say anything about.
Scott: there was a third cover on issue number two that was even more rare.
Scott: I think it was like one in 50 or one in 100. get this cover.
Scott: So I was like, oh, might as well buy these and flip them on eBay just like issue number one.
Scott: Crazy pony fan.
Rym: Well, you know, somehow I'm translating you saying that into.
Rym: might as well put them in Lucite and hang them up on my wall.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So they were selling this.
Scott: Keep in mind, this is a discount preorder for smart people who know what's up that extra rare cocoa bean My Little Pony number two cover.
Scott: That was these rare variant.
Scott: They were selling.
Scott: I would have had to pay out of my pocket one hundred dollars.
Rym: What?
Scott: Fuck that up the ass.
Scott: Even though I flipped that on eBay, I wouldn't make shit.
Scott: who's going to pay more than a hundred bucks?
Rym: May how many are being printed?
Scott: Because there's ninety thousand.
Rym: If that comic is a rarity.
Scott: Right.
Scott: If let's say that let's give it a nice because issue two always is a big drop.
Scott: So let's say seventy five.
Rym: Now, some things have a big drop.
Scott: But remember, issue two being my job, conservative estimate ponies goes up.
Scott: Hundred thousand copies is number one.
Scott: Right.
Scott: One in a hundred.
Scott: So there's only a thousand of these in the whole earth.
Scott: There's a lot more than a thousand pony fans.
Scott: I'm not paying a hundred bucks.
Scott: I'm not going to find a thousand pony fans willing to shop more than a hundred bucks.
Rym: I have this feeling that other than people who listen to GeekNights and people who are already fans of My Little Pony and are hardcore enough about it to follow pony news at a time, even at a time like this, when ponies is so far from actually having been on the air with new episodes.
Rym: I have a feeling that the geekery of the world is going to discover that the My Little Pony comic is selling really big and that's going to cause another wave of what the fuck bronies.
Scott: We'll see.
Scott: Anyway, it's the point is, is comics probably going to be worth reading.
Scott: There's some free previews online, a little bit, a few pages or so.
Rym: Pretty excited about it.
Rym: And I'm more excited about this than the last 52 comics.
Scott: Katie Cook is an awesome brony type person.
Scott: So I, you know, I trust her to know what's going on.
Scott: So if you want to read this comic, you should a) someone's going to scan it in on the Internet.
Scott: You know, that's going to happen.
Scott: B) Get the trade, which will come out and you just buy it on Amazon, no problem, super cheap and will not be collectible or expensive in any way.
Rym: I wonder if when that's on Amazon, that'll be about six months from now, the bronies will do what happens with Firefly and everything else where they just keep buying extra copies of it and sits in the number one for a while.
Scott: And it'll be six months from now.
Rym: That would be an interesting measure.
Rym: But I don't even know.
Rym: I do know this is all expected.
Rym: Yeah, but anyway, things of the day, you might remember quite some time ago we interviewed the Oda King on our show.
Rym: He was talking about translation and how fansubbers are dumbasses.
Rym: And it was a great interview.
Rym: He's a great guy.
Rym: He's done cool stuff.
Rym: There are many things he has done and many of you might be familiar with him, but I don't need to get into that.
Rym: He did yet another thing.
Rym: And it's interesting because a lot of the people I know who saw this didn't know it was him who did it.
Scott: Neither did I until someone pointed it out and I said, wait.
Rym: But when they watched it, said something like, hey, this is kind of like what the Oda King did before.
Scott: It looks like his style.
Rym: Yeah, because it is him.
Rym: All I have to say is that if there was a thing that would make me more excited than Ghost in the Shell standalone complex third gig, because it doesn't exist, or My Little Pony, it would be a Star Wars anime that looked like this.
Rym: I just watch it.
Rym: And if you don't think this is one of the greatest things you've ever seen, you're either a terrible person or you're way too young.
Scott: OK, so I saw a link to a funny video on YouTube and it was all about Halloween costumes.
Scott: It was a funny little cute animation.
Scott: And I noticed that it was part of this YouTube channel, Sleeping Ninja Toast.
Scott: So I check out the channel and it has many other hilarious and cute animations in it, mostly about Zelda and tongues.
Scott: Yeah, I highly suggest you watch obviously the Halloween costume animation that brought me into this, but also every video in this channel, especially my summed up experience in Twilight Princess.
Rym: This is the kind of thing where it's really cute, but I feel like we're going to see the girl who's making this stuff like a couple of years from now.
Scott: You can tell watching these videos that whoever is the person doing this is someone with talents who is going to bust out onto the scene.
Rym: I think very similar.
Rym: You know what this reminds me of the kid who did that Lavender Town expose.
Scott: Like very well, I think it's a little better than that equal.
Rym: equal in terms of what I project to be their potential for YouTube.
Scott: This is this is a person who is young and has high talent and is productive.
Scott: And especially if you watch the video, there's a video where they demonstrate how to draw Zelda in flash like, you know, they drew a picture of regular Zelda, just, you know, like a rat, you know, just a pencil, scan it in and then draw vector Zelda on top of it.
Scott: You can tell this person knows what they're doing.
Scott: I expect great things in the future to subscribe to this YouTube channel and you will see things possibly before they explode on the Internet and discover this person before they are super popular and famous.
Scott: I bet they're going to be busting out in artist's alleys and other places soon enough, if not already.
Rym: So in the meta moment, very briefly, before we get into this, this amazing burning, burning con is this this this weekend, also including what you got to get a stutter stutter, stutter looting Sunday.
Rym: I'm running a game in the first slot on Saturday.
Scott: I'm running even the last slot on Sunday.
Scott: So basically, it's a lot mean Scott bookending the convention.
Scott: I'm in the bed slot.
Rym: I think it's a fine.
Scott: So it's a bad slide because everyone's already left and everyone's tired and no one gives a shit.
Rym: I don't leave burning con.
Rym: I usually leave, though.
Scott: I don't leave, but other people do.
Rym: I think you'll be fine.
Rym: We have enough.
Rym: Legend of Krauser.
Rym: I think people will join our games.
Scott: I hope so.
Rym: The thing is, I get to set the bar for every game everyone else plays and who starts with mine.
Scott: I also think, you know, I look through a lot the game schedule and it's like careful.
Rym: A lot of those people listen to gig nights.
Rym: What are you about to say?
Scott: A lot of the games I want to play in are all at the same slots and not I want to play in inheritance.
Scott: I already did inheritance.
Rym: It's changed it.
Rym: It's a larp now.
Scott: And that makes me want to do it less.
Rym: Really?
Scott: Already done that.
Scott: I want to do new stuff.
Rym: You got a lot of opportunities.
Rym: How many slots are there?
Rym: Lots of five.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Five Saturday to Sunday anime Boston a ways out Magfest.
Rym: We're finalizing our schedule for what we're doing at Magfest.
Rym: But rest assured, we're going to be a fucking Magfest.
Scott: Fuck yeah.
Rym: Paxis, the three day badges are sold out, as are all the good hotels.
Rym: We warned you.
Scott: Us badges are on sale now.
Rym: I'm going to buy my badge probably tonight, even in case really in case it's one sells out to somehow we don't get to lecture at it.
Rym: and three, wouldn't it be pretty great to have Australia finally get finally a pax and some American douchebag is one of the omega knots.
Scott: Yeah, that's what you're going for.
Rym: That's what I'm going for.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Maybe I'll buy one by two then by two that I'll have to buy three because Emily's coming to.
Scott: what are we seeing?
Scott: How is there?
Rym: How do we sell them off if I don't know how we're going to manage that?
Rym: I haven't done any planning for this trip yet.
Rym: All I know is it cost about two grand if we fly coach.
Scott: That's cool.
Rym: It's not that bad.
Scott: The thing is, it's like one grand to fly to Seattle.
Scott: So just two Seattle's.
Rym: If you fly a little bit off like we did, I was like 400 bucks to fly to Seattle.
Scott: No, I mean, and back and back.
Rym: No, you bought your ticket after me.
Rym: My flight there was well, my flight back was nothing because we flew back Monday night.
Scott: Yeah, it's like it's, you know, it's a few hundred dollars each way.
Scott: Comes out close, you know, give you between eight hundred and a thousand dollars for the round trip.
Rym: I've never paid more than six hundred dollars round trip to packs because you can get one of the flights for like one hundred and twenty bucks every time.
Scott: JetBlue, the direct flight.
Rym: Yeah, just don't fly.
Rym: You got to fly at the right times.
Scott: We fly in the same flight.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And I always buy the tickets first.
Rym: Then I'm like, Scott, buy this flight.
Rym: Usually the cheap seats are sold out by then.
Rym: Anyway, join the forum.
Rym: Check out our Internet shit.
Rym: We uploaded a radio for Equestria since ponies are coming up again.
Scott: Yeah, I'm going to send out a newsletter probably real soon.
Rym: Yeah, we're going to do more radio for Equestria and we're going to do another show because enough of you said you wanted us to do it.
Rym: We're going to do the RFE treatment on Shoujo Kakumei Utena.
Scott: Gotta watch it first.
Rym: We're going to watch it episode by episode and do a show on the show, dog.
Rym: OK, so.
Rym: We skipped one, two, three, four and five.
Rym: I've only seen, I don't know, seven episodes of the book.
Scott: club book is name of the wind, name of the wind by Patrick Rothfuss.
Scott: So read that shit.
Rym: OK, just the first book.
Rym: I'm about a third of the way through.
Rym: And I just got to the point where the kids like, you know what, I'm going to stop being a dumb ass and I'm going to become a man now.
Scott: That's the good part.
Rym: Also, so far, this plot is very similar to Elminster, The Making of a Mage, which is a fuck out of the realm's book.
Rym: that takes you through the life of Elminster.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: Elminster also became a poor street urchin thief.
Rym: The parallels are astounding.
Scott: Are you saying it's a rip off?
Rym: I'm not sure because Elminster, Making of a Mage is a pretty awful book.
Rym: So tell me this.
Rym: I can ask you one thing.
Rym: Does the main character in our book club book, The Name of the Wind, become a girl and have an elf have sex with him and learn magic better?
Rym: because women are better at magic than men?
Scott: Not yet.
Rym: OK, if that happens, this book is a rip off.
Rym: OK, so we I've seen maybe seven episodes of One Piece.
Rym: I lectured on the anime opener to One Piece.
Rym: Great.
Scott: That's so relevant.
Rym: In different languages.
Scott: I read eleven volumes of the One Piece manga, the first eleven.
Rym: I read one volume of the One Piece manga.
Rym: And I listened to four episodes of Anime Pulse.
Scott: I have seen a handful of the first ever episodes of TV One Piece.
Scott: And that's pretty much it.
Scott: before seeing this movie.
Rym: One Piece six, the sixth movie.
Scott: I told you why you watch this one, because it's the one we could download the English subtitle.
Rym: So we skipped One Piece, Clockwork Island Adventure, Chopper's Kingdom on the Island of Strange Animals, Dead End Adventure, The Cursed Holy Sword.
Rym: And when we watched Baron Omatsuri and the Secret Island.
Scott: So as soon as this starts, within 30 seconds, we're already like Slayer's movie, Ebro's Island.
Rym: Now, you might think that's totally superficial because, all right, we're watching one of those OAV-ish movies from a TV show kind of stand alone.
Scott: Yeah, this is one of those things where it's like, OK, it's the characters you love.
Scott: We came up with this all new story that's unrelated to anything else.
Scott: They literally go to an island separated from the world, go on an adventure, and then there's an end.
Scott: And that's the whole movie.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But it's just like the Slayer's movie, just like a lot of Lupin movies.
Rym: But it was very telling because as we're watching the very beginning, it really felt a lot like Ebro's Island.
Rym: And then I realized about halfway through this thing that it's also a Lupin movie and that all those not the good Lupin movies, no AVs, but the and not the really bad ones, but like the mediocre ones.
Rym: It's not that it's like a movie like that.
Scott: It is.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Literally, if you just took this and replaced all the characters with Lupin characters and changed the proper nouns of their dialogue, it might as well be a Lupin movie.
Scott: It might as well be the Slayer's movie if you change it, right?
Rym: It's like, I've no, no, no, no.
Rym: Well, it might as well be a Slayer's movie in terms of style and theme and story.
Rym: In terms of the interactions between the characters, there's one scene where they're on the boat.
Rym: It's like, yeah, that's Zenigata, not Zenigata, that's Goemon.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: And again, like to the point that they could even say the same lines.
Rym: Yeah, it was so I I almost pictured it as a Lupin movie.
Rym: There's something about these like tier two mediocre anime OAV-ish movies to where they're all the same.
Scott: Well, it seems to me like, you know, this sort of two kinds of anime movies, right?
Scott: There's the real anime movies, which are sort of original.
Scott: They're separate from everything else.
Scott: You know, the girl who lived through time is a Miyazaki movie or, you know, a Satoshi Khan movie or a Mamoruji movie.
Scott: Right.
Scott: These things really stand alone as like these, you know, even like Pat LeBourne movie one.
Scott: Would you think, oh, that's related to like this TV series and stuff?
Scott: No, it stands alone.
Scott: It stands alone.
Scott: It's like this awesome movie.
Scott: It's got its own real plot and everything.
Rym: Now, this does stand alone in the sense that its plot is self-contained.
Rym: And even if you know nothing at all about the characters, it kind of goes out of its way to explain everything about the characters.
Scott: Yeah, at least everything you need to know to understand the movie you're watching.
Scott: I'm sure you can't swim.
Rym: Right.
Scott: It's like, yeah, I knew that before, but, you know, some other people might not have.
Scott: But yeah, it's like, you know, there's this other class of anime movie.
Scott: that's not the compilation movie, but these sort of series movies, the Pokemon.
Scott: You know, it felt a lot like watching that third Pokemon movie or Lupin movie or, you know, any of those where there's movies are in a series.
Rym: But again, not a good anime movie, a mediocre one.
Rym: Yeah, I'm we're talking like Momo.
Scott: Like not worth spending time to watch.
Scott: Now, it has the, you know, the same sort of plot structure.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Here's all the characters you love.
Scott: Let's introduce them.
Scott: Here is a some sort of hook for the thing they're going to do.
Scott: They go there.
Scott: There's something mysterious and there's some sort of silly and lighthearted introductory conflicts with lots of humor because of the beginning of the movie and lots of action.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then the action starts to get a little more serious and some of the characters start to discover the mysterious thing that's going on.
Rym: all of this, even in the lighthearted part in the beginning.
Rym: There's always the the very obvious, sinister undertones, but nothing overt.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And it just feels like in this movie, it zooms in on this flower on the guy's shoulder.
Scott: And, you know, we know immediately.
Scott: anyone who has half a brain knows immediately that guy's a bad guy.
Scott: That flowers the square boss, the end the end.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, everything they show you this volcano.
Scott: You're like the endings.
Scott: I said immediately beginning of the movie, the movie is going to end on top of that volcano.
Scott: Was I right?
Scott: You were right.
Scott: I was right.
Scott: I didn't even two seconds of the movie.
Scott: Didn't even know what the plot was.
Scott: They said they show you a volcano.
Scott: They're approaching this island.
Scott: I'm like, end of the movie is going to be on the volcano.
Rym: So one other warning.
Rym: I read a thing on the One Piece movies.
Rym: It was like, yeah, they're all about 50 to 55 minutes.
Rym: So the first One Piece movie, 51 minutes, second one, 55 minutes, third one, 56 minutes, fourth one, 95 minutes, 95 minutes, 95 minutes.
Rym: They basically escalated.
Rym: One hundred and thirteen minutes.
Scott: But how long is the one we watched?
Rym: The one we watched was 90 something minutes.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: We we went into this thinking it was going to be much shorter than like 50 minutes in.
Scott: We're like, what?
Scott: And we go down to look at the progress bar and it's a little bit over half.
Rym: At one point near the end, there's the scene that's just black and Luffy's just talking to himself and the pirate guys talking to himself.
Rym: And I'm like, and I clicked forward quite a bit.
Rym: Screen was still black.
Scott: Yeah, let's be honest.
Scott: Right.
Scott: We got after we saw that we were only halfway through.
Scott: We sort of checked.
Scott: We sort of click through quickly to look at each scene.
Scott: But we didn't actually watch the rest in the entirety because that would have taken forever.
Scott: And it was sort of unnecessary because we knew exactly what was going to happen.
Scott: The only thing I didn't know, you know, predict that was accurate was the fact that, you know, after the square boss was revealed and, you know, they had the final encounter with the final bad guy.
Scott: and the dire moment, you know, everything gets all trippy, of course, and dark and spooky.
Rym: Of course.
Rym: Usually they don't get this this movie.
Rym: I was but for the end, I would have said this was not worth watching at all.
Rym: But the end is actually pretty odd.
Scott: It's where it is trippier and visually and aesthetically than I expected.
Scott: But it was still.
Scott: I still expected trippiness at the end.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That ending part was much extended.
Rym: Like usually it's like you reveal the square boss and within 10 minutes in Sailor Moon, when the evil flower on the guy's shoulders revealed is the bad guy.
Rym: Wait a minute.
Scott: There's like to feed him then.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like once you see the square boss, it's like and it's the over.
Scott: Right.
Scott: In this, like shit's revealed and that the battle with the revealed ending square boss lasts a long, good percentage of the movie.
Rym: You look at the Mepros Island movie and all these other kind of movies like it.
Rym: One thing I've noticed about the one characteristic is that the movie will have very long scenes where very little happens, very, very atmospheric and very atypical of the show there.
Scott: But I mean, the Cowboy Bebop movie is the worst of those.
Scott: Right.
Scott: In terms of I mean, not that those scenes are bad, but just saying it has lots of long scenes where literally nothing happens.
Scott: Like now.
Scott: another is like a five to 10 minute scene of Ed walking around town while the song plays, even though that's one of the best scenes in the movie.
Scott: It's nothing wrong with.
Scott: I'm just saying is this talk about long scenes where nothing happens.
Rym: There's a scene where Chopper gets waylaid in the typical.
Rym: the sinister thing finally catches him when he's alone.
Rym: These are movies.
Rym: It's like in a bubble gum crisis where I'm going in for a closer look means I'm going to die.
Rym: Tell my kids I love them in a movie like this.
Rym: I'm going to go explore around the island by myself and see if I can figure anything out.
Rym: is also code for an arrow is going to fucking kill me.
Rym: The end.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But so there's a scene where choppers walk in and there's this really sort of surreal someone watching him thing and all these angle cuts.
Rym: It's an interesting scene.
Rym: I actually really liked how the scene was played out, very similar to a scene in Ursa Yatsura to a beautiful dreamer, which also does all these things.
Rym: And what's interesting there is that Ursa Yatsura to a beautiful dreamer was directed by Oshii and was very atypical of even the rest of the other movies.
Rym: This movie, the one we watched, was directed by Mamoru Hosoda.
Rym: I saw it in the credits.
Rym: I was like, can't be the same guy.
Rym: Totally the same guy as in the same guy who did the girl who left her time.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Summer Wars.
Rym: The Yu Yu Hakusho movie.
Scott: I know who it is.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So what was this movie about?
Scott: Just a one piece character adventure.
Scott: You know, they go to an island.
Scott: They think it's going to be a resort, you know, and they're going to have a good time.
Scott: In actuality, it's some guy who presents them with challenges because, I mean, you can't have a tournament in one movie, but you can have challenges.
Scott: I was so waiting for that challenge to be a tournament at, you know, secretly and obviously the island is actually full of evil and they because they're good at the challenges, they get pulled into the evil part.
Scott: And after they all get a bunch of them get captured, of course, you know, Love is the main character.
Scott: He saves the day at the very end after everyone else saves the minor day all throughout the movie.
Scott: He saves the big day in with the help of some of the characters who are just created for this movie, you know, and that's it.
Rym: A lot of trippy stuff happens, though, and I didn't expect that all the characters kind of got eaten by the flower and turned into goop.
Rym: Somehow they became human again.
Rym: And the inside of the square boss is filled with filled with utenna.
Rym: Let's put it that way.
Rym: It is filled.
Rym: I couldn't watch all of utenna and then watch this movie.
Rym: And you'll know exactly what I mean.
Rym: There's no other way to describe that.
Rym: No.
Rym: Movie's pretty bad.
Scott: Yeah, it's not.
Scott: I don't think you should really go out of your way to see this.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I mean, who knows about the other one piece movies?
Scott: I mean, I'm someone who is a fan of part of one piece like when I be pirates.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: When I read one piece or watch the TV series, there's good parts, there's boring parts.
Scott: The boring parts are fights that last too long.
Scott: The good parts are all the other parts.
Scott: It's just fights.
Scott: last too long is the better percentage of it.
Scott: So, you know, it's like 25 percent of one piece is the best and 75 percent is boring.
Scott: And this movie did not have any of the good parts at all.
Scott: Really.
Scott: Very, very few of them.
Scott: You'd have to be like a crazy one piece fan.
Scott: Need to see all the one piece to watch this movie.
Scott: Or maybe you're studying, you know, all of the anime movies that have this identical structure, in which case you need to see this one because it is a perfect example.
Rym: I feel like we could turn this into a panel if we put work into it on showing all these media.
Scott: A whole bunch of movies and show how they're exactly the same goddamn movie and be like we can call the panel like seen one anime movie, seen them all.
Rym: Now, what's interesting is that the the movie internally, it jumps around a lot, like very jarring transitions between scenes, which actually the Mipros Island movie kind of did that.
Scott: Well, I think what early on in the movie, the cameras really in one place, right, because all the characters are together.
Scott: But then the characters sort to start to split up and it's cutting between what all the different characters are doing, supposedly at the same time.
Scott: And that's where things can get a little bit confusing because the timing doesn't make any sense.
Scott: No, but also you look at something like Lupin, there's Lupin, Jigen, Goemon and maybe they'll show you Fujiko, right?
Rym: Or well, Zenigata is there, but every now and then you cut to Zenigata.
Scott: But it's like, you know, hardly ever do they actually, you know, depending on the movie, they might need it to only show Lupin and Fujiko and that's it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I mean, or, you know, Lupin and the bad guy.
Scott: And that's it.
Scott: And this they got to keep going to every different character in Luffy's crew.
Scott: And his crew is like, you know, seven people in it.
Scott: There were people in the crew.
Scott: I didn't know because I never got that far in one piece.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Like, who's that girl with the black?
Rym: I have no idea who that girl.
Scott: I don't know who Robin is.
Scott: I've never seen that red or seen that far in the one piece regular series.
Rym: My problem with her is that she's too cool and confident.
Rym: She doesn't fit in his crew at all.
Scott: No, you know, but Luffy is more like a Captain Taylor situation.
Scott: Tyler, where he's cool and confident.
Scott: But is he?
Scott: But he gets it done.
Scott: But yeah, they keep cutting between the characters until, of course, the secret evil guy removes the characters from the picture one at a time also.
Scott: But that takes a while.
Scott: That's like halfway through the movie.
Scott: They start going out of the picture.
Rym: So, yeah, I mean, you think at first it feels like there's going to be these four challenges.
Rym: They have to pick up the goldfish.
Rym: And then they have a speedboat race where they have to throw hoops at each other.
Scott: That one was weird.
Rym: And that one went on for like a half hour.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And I guess we should have seen that come in a fight that takes forever.
Scott: Right.
Scott: At least there weren't too many direct fights other than the ending fight.
Rym: Wait, spoiler, spoiler.
Rym: And the very end, there's a dude who appears a bit through the movie.
Scott: Good guys win.
Rym: He's an uncle.
Rym: And the uncle is trying to be a badass for his kids, but he's a coward.
Rym: And then finally, he minds up and hardens up and he's going to do the good thing.
Rym: He picks up the bow and arrow and he shoots it at the bad guy, the square boss, and it just fucking kills the square boss.
Rym: The end.
Rym: It just it just works.
Rym: Why didn't anyone do that before?
Rym: Why was it so easy to kill then?
Rym: Suddenly, I don't know.
Rym: Granted, we skipped a bit.
Rym: Maybe there's some baby ate some gum, gum, I don't know.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: This movie is weird.
Rym: And you can kind of see the influence of Hosoda.
Rym: But I feel I think one of the things that drives all these movies to be similar is that you're either directly constrained if you work on one of these, because you can't kill a character.
Rym: You can't alter the relationship between any main character and any other main character.
Rym: You can't change the world's plots.
Rym: You always have to be in a setting that's like separate, like a special island somewhere.
Rym: Right.
Scott: So basically what you do is you write it.
Scott: You take the characters with their personalities.
Scott: You write a self-contained fan fiction story for those characters, and you make sure to reset the status quo and send the main characters on their way again at the end without any permanent change to them.
Scott: And you also, because you need to have permanent change, create some temporary characters that you can have a permanent change for.
Scott: A bad guy who gets defeated, you know, some help, some helpful local characters who improve and, you know, develop as characters and such that will never, ever be seen again.
Scott: And, you know, it's the same thing happens every time.
Rym: Yeah, I feel like that's part of it.
Rym: And I think that's why some of the movies like this that really stand out, like particularly a Lupin or two, is because they took great liberties anyway and they went way out of character and did interesting stuff.
Rym: Maybe this movie.
Rym: It was so.
Rym: the interactions between his crew were almost like someone said, well, this guy likes this girl and this girl is mad.
Rym: Like Nami's character might have been she punches people to show both anger and affection.
Rym: I think that's the only direction they gave for her character in this movie.
Scott: Yeah, quite possibly.
Rym: This movie was not.
Scott: I suppose if you're already like a huge One Piece fan, right?
Rym: It's not.
Rym: it's not a One Piece movie.
Scott: Well, I'm saying I'm saying that if you are a huge One Piece fan, right, because the characters act in character, barely, you might, you know, they're in cardboard cutout character.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: But, you know, when people are huge fans of characters like that, they just get off on seeing those characters.
Rym: Wait a minute, wait a minute, wait a minute.
Rym: So this is American superhero comic syndrome.
Scott: Possibly.
Rym: I care about the events that happen around character with a proper noun A as long as they fit into the cardboard cutout.
Rym: That is proper noun A.
Scott: Hey, people are all about that.
Rym: They are indeed.
Rym: I don't know what I could like.
Rym: I would make fun of this movie, like go through the plot.
Rym: Dave and Joel.
Rym: Let's see.
Rym: All right.
Rym: They land on the island.
Rym: They have a bunch of really stereotypical set up like we talked about.
Rym: This pirate captain surrounded by a bunch of people who all have leaves growing out of their heads in a fake town with Versailles and Moscow kind of inside of it.
Rym: And really bad CG.
Rym: I don't know what was up with the CG.
Rym: It's 2005.
Rym: They couldn't get good CG.
Rym: But they have a contest.
Rym: And the first contest is they've got to pick up a goldfish.
Rym: But the goldfish is gigantic.
Rym: And then they do it anyway.
Rym: And then they have another contest where they have to throw hoops on each other.
Rym: And then arrows come out and bullshit happens.
Rym: Then an hour and fucking forever later, it's over.
Scott: The end.
Rym: There's.
Rym: I defy anyone to enjoy this movie unless you are trying to analyze it.
Rym: And even then, good luck.
Rym: Maybe if you really like memorials and you're trying to see his influence.
Scott: Yeah, I guess he sort of, you know, it seems like he just did this as a job.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Rather than well, the animation was pretty different.
Rym: And especially some of the side characters he added, like look at the uncle who was a coward and those kids that was really hosted a feeling right there.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, that is one thing I noticed.
Scott: Watch the video we downloaded from the Internet.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The encoding was not necessarily the highest.
Rym: The CG was bad, nonetheless.
Rym: Don't think that.
Scott: Well, it's from 2005, right?
Rym: Yeah, it was bad for 2005.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But the what was I saying?
Scott: Right.
Scott: You look and I look even looking at with our batting code that made things kind of blurry because it was a download from the Internet's.
Scott: You know, it looked like things were a little off.
Scott: I'm like, hey, those characters aren't looking like how they look.
Scott: Usually it's a little bit off.
Scott: But according to the Internet's, it was, you know, this movie doesn't look like the other movies because Hosanna did that on purpose.
Scott: He made it look like his stuff.
Rym: Yeah, but he couldn't stray too far from those characters.
Rym: But obviously, so all his own characters like the normal people, Captain Hitler and all those guys, those other characters do not look.
Scott: But, you know, the characters that are new for this movie don't look very one piece ish except for maybe the bad guys, you know, and they only look a little bit one piece ish.
Scott: And, you know, I don't think that the one piece guy actually designed these characters at all.
Rym: Yeah, but that flower, every time it zoomed in on the flower, it was exactly like when it zoomed in on the smiling frog in Mipros Island.
Rym: Oh, so talking about a weird scene, there's a scene where basically Hitler is there.
Rym: Actually, it's a pretty funny scene.
Rym: Hitler's there and he's throwing rocks at Luffy.
Rym: And for some reason, this scene goes on for like a couple of minutes where this guy just keeps throwing rocks at Luffy and Luffy can't see where they're coming from.
Rym: And he keeps throwing bigger and bigger rocks.
Rym: And then he finally finds the guy and tries to confront him.
Rym: And then there's this weird scene where Luffy's like chasing the guy Scooby Doo style, and it just keeps going on and on.
Rym: It is almost identical to a couple of scenes.
Rym: It's really shit like pond movies.
Scott: And then it finally ends.
Rym: And there's the scene where Luffy's like standing there, there's out of a pool.
Rym: And the guy's talking and Luffy's talking and barely anything that either one of them saying really makes much sense.
Rym: And then it just kind of ends.
Rym: And I guess the guy's captain of the mustache crew and he has a Hitler mustache.
Rym: But then there's another pirate crew somewhere else.
Rym: They were the.
Rym: what were they?
Rym: Because there's the mustache family.
Rym: Yeah, there were some other pirate crew, pirate family.
Rym: They were a modest pirate crew.
Rym: And they were the red.
Rym: No, the red tails was the doesn't matter.
Rym: So many pirate crews.
Scott: And it's like, I don't think, you know, it's like, what does it even mean to be a pirate in this world?
Scott: It means you just have a you have friends.
Scott: You have a team.
Scott: You have a team on a boat that makes you pirates.
Scott: It's like a guy.
Rym: What do you pirate?
Rym: I guess maybe that's why they're after the one piece.
Rym: There was only one pirate ever.
Rym: And he plundered and pillaged.
Rym: And he's got pirate booty and they want to get it.
Rym: Maybe.
Rym: And they don't realize how to get it.
Rym: They're going after him to be pirates.
Rym: I don't think anyone but I don't have anything else to say about this movie.
Rym: No, I can't even make fun of it.
Rym: It's just weird.
Rym: So I think this breaks my rule.
Rym: Usually whenever we review an anime movie, I always say there aren't that many anime movies.
Rym: You might as well watch them all.
Scott: Well, no, that really just applies to.
Rym: That applies to anime movies that are not sequels to other anime movies.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.