Rym: It's Thursday, October 4th, 2012.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights tonight in the GeekNights Book Club, The Man Who Was Thursday by G.K.
Rym: Chesterton.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: Do you remember?
Scott: Mr.
Scott: Bubble.
Rym: Mr.
Rym: Bubble?
Rym: I remember Mr.
Rym: Bubble.
Rym: Mr.
Scott: Bubble's the shit.
Scott: That's all I'm saying.
Rym: So you want to have a bubble bath?
Scott: That's what you're saying.
Rym: I have not had a bubble bath since my age was single digits.
Scott: Check it out.
Scott: They still make this shit.
Scott: Of course they do.
Scott: But the thing is I think now it's all non-toxic, ultra safe.
Scott: I don't know what it was in our day if it was a different formulation.
Rym: It's just soap.
Scott: No, it doesn't clean you.
Rym: It doesn't have to clean you to be soap.
Rym: There's no definition of soap that says cleans you.
Scott: But they actually do make Mr.
Scott: Bubble shampoo and body wash, brand stuff.
Rym: You only want the bubble bath.
Rym: I, as a kid, never understood the appeal of bubble baths.
Scott: When I was extremely small it was like, "Oh fuck yeah,
Scott: bubbles.".
Rym: See, I didn't care about the bubbles because I had this little thing that hung over the tub on the side and it was like this play school boathouse.
Scott: I had boats.
Rym: No, it was a boathouse that hung over the side of the tub and had a little landing for the boats to go into and little people could live in it.
Rym: So basically I'd hang out with that.
Rym: If it was bubble bath, then that ruins my fun.
Rym: Because now it's not like happy boat town, it's horrible foam town.
Scott: My trains and boats, they were the kind that stuck to the wall of the tub.
Scott: Oh, mine floated.
Scott: Oh, so I could play on the wall of the tub.
Scott: And then I also had a floaty boat and some other things.
Rym: I also had the Lego cargo ship.
Scott: I had this book that you could read in the tub.
Scott: I had one of those.
Scott: And it was about this penguin and you would take the penguin out of the book and insert him into the waterproof pages.
Rym: The two things related to Lego in my life, three things that I wanted that actually were those kind of unattainable dreams of childhood were one, the monorail.
Rym: Of course.
Scott: No one has it.
Rym: I knew a kid who had it.
Scott: Kid's spoiled.
Rym: He wouldn't let me play with it.
Scott: He's rich.
Scott: He's spoiled.
Scott: And he probably went nowhere in life.
Scott: Probably hipster.
Rym: I wanted the space shuttle.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: I got that one.
Rym: And three, I wanted the motor that went on the back of the cargo ship boat.
Scott: Yeah, we had the boat.
Scott: We did not have the motor.
Rym: I never saw that motor in person.
Scott: I didn't even see the motor in the Lego catalog.
Rym: I only knew it existed because the instruction book had instructions for connecting it to the boat.
Scott: I looked in that Lego catalog for that boat and I didn't fucking see it, but I mostly bought Castle Lego.
Scott: That's what I wanted.
Rym: I was mostly the Space Lego.
Scott: My brother got Space Lego.
Scott: I was all about Castle Lego.
Rym: In fact, when Ice Planet came out, you know what we used to do?
Scott: I had one Ice Planet.
Scott: He had the orange chainsaw.
Rym: I had the base.
Scott: But yeah, no, the best is friggin' Castle.
Scott: I mean, how could you not want Kniggetts and Robin Hoods?
Scott: The Robin Hood forest men were even better than the Castle ones.
Scott: They'd be like, with their bow and arrows.
Rym: Yeah, the bow and arrow's okay.
Rym: That whip that every kid used to make a makeshift gallows.
Scott: I had so many whips and those little leafy green things and drawbridges and trees.
Rym: I didn't have any of the bridges.
Rym: I only had one Castle and it wasn't Lego.
Rym: It was like this knockoff Lego.
Scott: Yeah, the only thing I couldn't get, though, is I wanted the big fucking Castle.
Scott: I didn't get that.
Scott: The $100 Castle.
Scott: Nowadays, the $300 Castle.
Rym: Not a normal show.
Rym: Book club show.
Rym: You might have forgotten about the book club.
Rym: It's been a while.
Rym: It's also a pretty short book.
Rym: I have a feeling many of you didn't read it.
Rym: You should've.
Scott: So I have a funny story also.
Rym: If this story begins with, "So I didn't read the
Rym: book.".
Scott: No, I read the fucking book.
Scott: So on Reddit, some girl, and this is a New York City Reddit, right?
Rym: Some girl posted- Oh wait, so you're doing a thing of the day.
Scott: No.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Scott: She posted this story.
Scott: She's an Asian foreign student.
Scott: She's engaged to a lovely boyfriend who is white.
Scott: Her loving and protective Korean mother does not know any of this and she has been lying to her for over a year.
Scott: She basically made up this elaborate ruse to tell her family- Wait a minute.
Rym: So far, this is the plot of Summer Wars.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So she lives in New York.
Scott: She's engaged to this white dude.
Rym: Does she need a stand-in Asian dude to be a fake boyfriend?
Scott: She has been telling this elaborate ruse for a long time and she basically needs an apartment and people to keep this lie alive when people come to-.
Rym: So, you know, it'd be great.
Rym: If we got someone to respond to this and be all legit and set it all up and when the family arrives, don't reveal the truth.
Rym: Just make everything really weird.
Scott: She was offering $100 or more for help and various people replied on Reddit.
Scott: Her mom found it?
Scott: No, and then the Gothamist posted a story about her post, so it is spreading her ridiculous lie.
Rym: This might be right up there with Captain Buttshugger.
Scott: It's like, why would you even?
Rym: It's like, these are the kind of people- So Scott, remember, remember what ruined the plot of 99% of books and movies anyone could ever write from this point forward in time?
Rym: The existence of the cell phone and the internet.
Rym: These sorts of plots are perfectly viable in a world where there is no way for mom to find out that Reddit exists.
Scott: I doubt mom will find out, but this is still, why don't you just come clean?
Scott: What the fuck?
Scott: It's so much easier than maintaining this incredibly elaborate ruse.
Rym: Yes, Scott, it is so much easier if you are in fact someone like you or me, but for an average person, you would rather die than let that secret be revealed than deal with your mom dealing with that.
Rym: I'm not that way.
Scott: Yeah, then I don't want to have nothing to do with you.
Rym: No, see, here's what we do.
Scott: If you're a crazy person who will create drama, stay away from me.
Rym: We respond, get one of our Asian friends and do the whole thing like super legit.
Rym: And then when the mom shows up, the Asian friend is there, but he acts like he's not the actual boyfriend.
Scott: And we have like, I don't know- Oh, we just tell the truth for them because they can't do it themselves?
Rym: So we get like a black Russian dude to then act like he's the boyfriend and just make everything double weird.
Rym: So now the girl has two options, come clean herself or deal with this doubly ridiculous double trick.
Rym: That is what I would do if I were an enterprising young asshole.
Scott: Luckily for this person- I would have nothing to do with dramatic people.
Scott: I just think it was really- I will laugh at them from afar across the Internet.
Scott: That is what I'm doing right now.
Rym: A younger Rym would engage in elaborate hoax, but I'm old enough now to merely plan the hoax and plant the seed.
Scott: Maybe her mom listened to GeekNights.
Rym: You know, we should try to track down the mom and interview her.
Scott: Well, I'm sure there will be at least one more post about this on the Internet.
Scott: Of course.
Rym: Fark has one of the-.
Rym: you know, this is very important.
Rym: Very few websites on the Internet do this and Fark does it and I feel like it's worth noting because it's related to this.
Rym: Fark has many tags like S9 or boobies or whatever the story is.
Rym: Florida, if it happens in Florida, there's one tag, follow up.
Rym: Follow up is the best tag on Fark.
Rym: That is when you find out what happened to crazy dude who got arrested for chugging wine up his butt.
Scott: But aren't half of those things going to be lame?
Scott: Like, oh, guy just went to jail.
Scott: They don't want long.
Rym: No, they only follow up if it's interesting or if people cared how it turned out.
Rym: But anyway, I digress.
Rym: I think it's time for things of the day.
Rym: So I'm going to cue up that little music there and Mr.
Rym: Bubble or Mr.
Rym: Bucket.
Scott: Mr.
Scott: Bucket sucks.
Scott: Fark Mr.
Scott: Bucket up the ass.
Scott: Mr.
Scott: Bubble versus Mr.
Scott: Bucket.
Scott: You know, Mr.
Scott: Bubble just walk in me like, boom, Mr.
Scott: Bucket's out.
Scott: Mr.
Scott: Bucket will be full of bubbles and then he'll choke to death on the bubbles and balls will come out of his mouth.
Rym: I wonder if people have seen that, actually.
Scott: His balls will come right out of his mouth and that's the end.
Rym: I'm going to do two things today.
Rym: I'm going to cheat here.
Rym: So if you haven't seen it, our good pseudo internet friend, and I talk to him occasionally via email, but we've never talked in person ever.
Rym: The angry video game nerd.
Scott: He doesn't know who we are.
Rym: Did a video that is a dramatic sort of ghost story.
Rym: It's a review.
Rym: Centered around Mr.
Rym: Bucket.
Rym: And it is actually one of the greatest pieces of cinema posted to the internet.
Scott: I'm pretty sure you've mentioned this in the show before.
Rym: But in case we haven't, I make it my thing of the day.
Scott: But my real thing of the day.
Scott: I think I've also told the story of how I got Mr.
Scott: Bucket.
Rym: Yes, you have.
Rym: I remember that.
Scott: Oh, speaking of Angry Video Game Nerd, you know what month it is.
Rym: Oh.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So I've already missed, what, four of them?
Scott: No, he's doing them every other day.
Rym: Ah, come on.
Scott: Thirty one.
Rym: It's all 80s themed.
Scott: They're all 80s themed all month.
Rym: Wait, so that means that means are we going to get Halloween three?
Scott: No.
Scott: Do you remember that movie we watched with Amber about like the ghost, the monster that came out of the TV with the satellite dish in the backyard?
Scott: Oh, oh, I don't know what it's called, but that one was in the trailer.
Scott: So he's going to do it some point during the month.
Rym: Oh, my God.
Rym: That movie is right up there with the stuff.
Rym: Anyway, that was an error.
Rym: We'd watch.
Rym: In fact, you were not there.
Scott: Do your real thing.
Rym: Of all the bad movies that Amber showed us, the worst is the one you were not there to see.
Scott: Do your thing of the day.
Scott: That's the real thing.
Rym: It is called.
Rym: I'm going to put this out here.
Rym: This movie is called Boxing Helena.
Rym: Good God.
Rym: So anyway, my real thing of the day.
Rym: Watch the movie.
Rym: carbonated apple slices.
Rym: This dude made a bunch of videos.
Scott: Basically, he's kind of like those.
Scott: How does that even work?
Rym: Table of videos.
Rym: guys who make like the awesome chemistry videos.
Rym: This guy has a whole bunch of carbon dioxide in various forms and a pressure vessel and just does stuff with carbon dioxide.
Scott: So I guess if you put an apple into a chamber that was sealed and the chamber was full of carbon dioxide and the pressure was high, the carbon dioxide would be forced into the apple where it would go into the apple juice and that is in the apple and fizz it up.
Scott: So now you have a sparkling apple.
Rym: So basically, this guy did a bunch of stuff.
Rym: Like, for example, he makes supercritical CO2 and just shows you how fucking awesome that is.
Rym: It's used in dry cleaning and stuff.
Rym: And anyway, this video, yes, he just carbonate some apple slices and then he eats them.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: Apparently they are goddamn delicious.
Scott: Yeah, they probably just hurt.
Rym: Yeah, I forget.
Rym: You can't deal with carbonation.
Scott: It's one of those.
Scott: It is not a good thing.
Rym: I can't imagine.
Scott: It's also not good for you.
Rym: Cite that.
Rym: Cite a source on that.
Scott: I've read stuff.
Rym: Yeah, I think you read about how cold water hydrates you faster.
Rym: No, that is what you said.
Rym: I have chat logs, Captain Fuckwit.
Rym: I need to pull this out.
Scott: You're the one who is so insistent for many years.
Scott: You didn't even have anything.
Scott: But you were insistent that warm water hydrated you faster.
Scott: But you didn't even have one.
Rym: I had one link.
Scott: What I said, you did say that it is exactly what you said.
Rym: I said that I think warm water hydrates you better, but I don't know.
Scott: No, you are editing history.
Scott: That is a rebase.
Scott: If I check the GetReRef log, we can see what really happened.
Rym: Okay, anyway, what you think of the day, Captain?
Scott: Avoiding.
Scott: Okay, so this is another New York City person, right?
Scott: This girl does a website called TenderNuggets.com and she's got cute.
Scott: She basically writes blog posts and illustrates them with really cute, awesome illustrations.
Scott: So she went on this odyssey across New York, trying to get home late at night on the subway.
Scott: And if you're a New Yorker, you will a hundred times appreciate this entire story with all the pictures that go with it.
Scott: It is super, super true.
Rym: The weird thing, though, is if I had never lived in New York City, you wouldn't get it at all.
Rym: No, I would get it.
Rym: You can understand the odyssey, but you would not grok it.
Rym: Yeah, you and in fact, what's interesting is people who don't live in New York or have never lived in New York read this and go, Oh, my God, what a shitty place to live.
Rym: I read it.
Rym: And while I can relate, all I can think is I fucking love this city.
Scott: Yeah, it's like them feels.
Scott: I have all of them.
Rym: I have bonded more with this girl who made this comic than I have with the majority of human beings I've ever met.
Scott: And we don't even know who this person is.
Rym: That picture we just have a lot up against the window in the hobo car.
Scott: We just have so many shared experiences with this person that we do not know.
Rym: It's interesting how this is like the smell is not of this earth.
Rym: The city has so many more people and so many more things.
Rym: Yet I feel like I have more shared experiences here than I did in like Beacon.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So, yeah, I remember you're up.
Rym: I pushed you on this.
Rym: I was like, give me a citation on your water bullshit.
Rym: And you hemmed and hawed for seven minutes and then finally came back with one link on the Camelback.
Scott: How many links did you have?
Rym: I didn't posit anything.
Rym: You.
Rym: Well, here we go.
Rym: And your link said cold water, psychologically speaking, and had no other evidence other than talking about placebos and psychosomatism.
Scott: Hold on.
Scott: Let me search here.
Rym: And at no point in this chat do I make any claim.
Rym: In fact, all I do is question your claims.
Rym: I have never typed in the history of the FRC.
Scott: You know, OK, so you are in this case lucky and that your claims were not made in a log chat, but were instead made in a verbal and oral fashion for these cannot be cited for the last five or six years.
Rym: I have never, ever typed the phrase type water types into type any email.
Scott: That is correct.
Scott: Chad, you have not typed, but you have over the course of many years since college orally stated.
Rym: It's got the body.
Scott: human body absorbs warm water faster than cold water.
Rym: Prove it.
Scott: I don't have to prove it.
Scott: It's just known to you for now on.
Scott: I'm not chatting with you online ever because apparently, you know, whatever is logged, you know, is what counts.
Scott: But even though you said something one hundred times and everybody knows it.
Rym: Room temperature, water is best.
Scott: Metafilter.
Scott: Yeah, that doesn't count.
Rym: posted by Campbell in Space on December 26.
Rym: So are you now this dude at nine thirty at night?
Scott: Are you saying Metafilter is a better source than the Camelback Web site, which you would presume the Camelback would hire water experts?
Rym: The Camelback Web site said only psychologically placebo effect.
Scott: It said the cold water is.
Scott: it said which absorbs.
Scott: it had a quiz and it said which temperature is absorbed faster and cold was the correct answer.
Scott: And the other answers were not correct.
Rym: So here's why you're.
Scott: my link is as good as your vote.
Rym: What you said seeing the Camelback thing again, it says and then this is a link is a copy paste from the link.
Rym: At which water temperature does your body hydrate most effectively?
Rym: Now, here's the efficiently.
Scott: you didn't even read it properly.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Here is the exact and full text of the response cold.
Rym: Psychologically speaking, people perceive this to be true, making it true, making it true.
Rym: Therefore, it is amazing how our mind works, isn't it?
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So it because you perceive it is true, it becomes true.
Scott: It is true.
Rym: They are saying in that sentence that it is true, that alcohol is good for me.
Rym: Therefore, it is true.
Scott: Camelback says so.
Scott: With water absorption.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So I've got my beer absorption going on here.
Scott: Camelback, I trust more than Metafilter guy.
Rym: I trust Sapper.
Scott: And when we actually looked up scientific studies, I found out the truth.
Scott: The truth is that it doesn't matter.
Scott: And you have still always said orally that you have insisted that warm water is better with no sources for years and years and years.
Rym: Now, while I disagree with that, I have said I'm pretty sure or I think.
Scott: No, you have not.
Scott: You are editing history because you have the luxury of it not being logged, which is what you do often.
Rym: The odds are.
Rym: So I'm just saying that how come in like six years?
Rym: I've never typed that?
Rym: You know, you think that I put that much effort into this ridiculous ruse, this facade?
Scott: No, you didn't put effort into it.
Scott: You just said a thing.
Scott: And then when you found out you were wrong and you just got lucky that there was no evidence of it.
Scott: So you just denied it and rewrote history.
Rym: So, Scott, even were that true?
Scott: You know, ever since I was one, I've always known calculus proved that I got.
Rym: I know you didn't in the end.
Rym: And the reason I can prove that is you failed calculus three twice.
Scott: I knew calculus one since I was zero.
Rym: Prove I didn't.
Scott: Otherwise, it's true.
Scott: No, no, no.
Scott: It's true.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You see how this goes.
Rym: I'm just pointing out that you have no proof.
Rym: I'm all.
Rym: I have a counter evidence and evidence that I'm not a genius.
Rym: Here's my evidence of character.
Scott: You know, evidence of character.
Scott: The biggest lying does this all the time.
Scott: Hundred times.
Scott: Everybody knows.
Rym: So what you have found in many of the times where you've accused me of lying is that upon review or upon discussion with other that you edited history.
Rym: It's not that I ever lie.
Rym: It's that I speak with an extreme precision.
Rym: And when I am vague on points, I am vague to a very precise point to leave ambiguity.
Scott: On this point, you were not vague.
Scott: You are merely saying what you said.
Scott: Now you are post hoc editing what you have said.
Scott: If I could have a time machine, you know that the only way to prove otherwise without any doubt is to go with a time machine, which is not possible.
Scott: Therefore, you are taking full advantage of that fact, as you often do.
Scott: So I implore to make an argument that, you know, I implore all of our listeners.
Scott: I will just prove that you did not say what I say.
Scott: You said you can't because you don't have a time machine either.
Rym: Listeners, I implore you.
Rym: You know me.
Scott: You do know him.
Rym: You've heard me speak many times.
Scott: That's why you know that I'm right.
Scott: And I'm the person who does not lie ever.
Scott: And Rym is the person who lies often.
Scott: Do I not?
Scott: This is well known.
Rym: Do I not, by instinct, by second nature, qualify my statement such that no one can ever actually find specific fault with them?
Rym: Is it not a common thing for me to say things such as, "Well, I believe, I think, I posit, I've heard...".
Scott: In this case, you did not do that.
Rym: But yet, I've done that for almost every assertion I've ever made in my life, except this one.
Scott: Have you?
Scott: Do we have a time machine to prove that as well?
Rym: So listeners, think back upon previous GeekNights episodes.
Rym: Go find arguments we've had.
Scott: And go see who is the person who is always truth-telling and who is the person who is always lying.
Scott: Especially in the board game department, Mr.
Scott: Character.
Rym: Why?
Scott: Readily admitting to lying in the board game department and behaving that way and using the same strategies in everyday parlance.
Rym: Is it, in fact, not the opposite?
Rym: For is it not my shtick, if you will, if I may, in both small world and mafia to never lie ever?
Scott: It is not your shtick, no.
Rym: Have I ever lied in a game of mafia?
Rym: You have.
Rym: When?
Scott: Do we also need the time machine for this one?
Scott: You know what?
Scott: I've always lied in every game of mafia.
Scott: When?
Rym: You didn't play at PAX, so that was the last time we played.
Rym: Right?
Scott: When was it?
Scott: Right?
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: So I'm glad we're clear.
Scott: Do we have any meta moments available?
Rym: That I'm right.
Rym: The GeekNights Book Club, the next book will be announced if Scott's picked this up.
Scott: It'll be announced right now.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: So I gotta tell the story of this book club.
Scott: It'll take a minute.
Scott: So I was reading the Penny Arcade print editions, which I highly recommend because they contain additional commentaries.
Scott: That they do.
Scott: And many other goodies.
Scott: You should buy them for cheap on Amazon.
Scott: And the introduction to one of the later volumes was written by a man named Patrick Rothfuss.
Scott: And I was like, who the hell is this guy?
Scott: And he basically talked all about how he was writing some fantasy novel.
Scott: And I'm like, oh, whatever.
Scott: Some guy wrote fantasy novels right in the forward for some Penny Arcade volume.
Scott: All right.
Scott: And then I look into this guy and apparently he's the hot new fantasy guy on the block, relatively speaking.
Scott: That means, you know, a year or two.
Scott: Right.
Scott: As opposed to 10, 20 years.
Scott: And a lot of people are reading his book all over the place.
Scott: So I bought it, but I didn't read it yet.
Scott: It's just been sitting there on the shelf and my new policy for book club is pick the book that's on the shelf that I haven't read yet.
Scott: So I don't have to buy new books.
Scott: Therefore, the next.
Scott: And also, I heard some people commentate on this book saying that it ends in sort of an air place.
Scott: But the sequel, I believe, is now available.
Scott: So if you were only going to do this first book.
Scott: But, you know, if you feel you're hanging at the end of it, you are no longer stuck waiting for a book to be published.
Scott: You can go buy another one or download another one.
Scott: So the book is.
Scott: I forget the exact title.
Scott: I think is it the name of the wind or in the name of the wind?
Rym: It is Children Who Chase Lost Wind Through Voices Deep Below.
Scott: Yeah, something along those lines.
Scott: It is the name of the wind.
Scott: King Killer Chronicles Day one by Patrick Rothfuss.
Scott: And it is eleven dollars and fifty six cents in paper version.
Scott: And the sequel is The Wise Man's Fear, which is King Killer Chronicles Day two.
Scott: I suppose it's about a guy who kills the king.
Scott: And in fact, the paperback of the second volume is cheaper than the paperback of the first one.
Rym: One, two, three syllabolism of that.
Rym: Just I find it ridiculously hilarious.
Rym: King Killer Chronicles.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So, yeah, the name of the wind, a book that I do not know if is good or bad, but I have it.
Scott: So I don't want to have my money wasted.
Scott: So that's going to be the booklet.
Scott: All right.
Rym: The next one after that will probably be The Great Gatsby because I want to read it before the movie happens.
Scott: Yeah, I'm definitely in favor of the class.
Scott: That's what I'm going to do when I run out of books on my bookshelf that are physical.
Scott: I almost want to make because I'm probably not going to buy too many more of those.
Scott: I'm going to move over to the classics I haven't read.
Rym: The trouble is I every time I would rather do a work of nonfiction, but I know that none of you assholes will read it.
Rym: That's right.
Rym: But I almost for the sake of the fact that it's so important to gaming, I feel like I should almost make the book club book that Richard Garfield book anyway.
Scott: But yeah, I figured, you know, this time I also want to concentrate more on the fact that, you know, it is the book club, but it's the GeekNights' book club.
Scott: We should leans at least slightly more towards the fantasy sci fi.
Scott: Now why is the GeekNights' book club?
Rym: as in we are geeks, not nerds.
Rym: I am just as geeky about rock climbing and mountain biking as I am about video gaming.
Scott: I'm just saying I'm going to, you know, at least my the shelf of unread.
Rym: Besides, you want to go geeky?
Rym: All right, fine.
Rym: That Byzantine bullshit I've been reading is going to be the next book club.
Rym: That's eight hundred pages of the driest history you've ever read.
Scott: If it's your pick, you can pick whatever you want.
Scott: Why don't you pick that Peter the Great book that no one will be able to get a copy of?
Rym: I've read almost that entire book.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: The wars between Sweden and Russia.
Rym: Hilarious.
Scott: Not really.
Rym: They're hilarious from the perspective of if you treat those wars like advanced wars.
Scott: So we have to remember to actually update all the book club section on the website.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So, so the man who was Thursday.
Scott: So this is your selection.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: Explain why it was chosen and what you heard about it.
Rym: So I had chosen literally I was going to choose between the Great Gatsby because the movie's coming.
Rym: That looks actually really good.
Rym: And I've never read the Great Gatsby and the man who was Thursday.
Rym: And I don't recall.
Rym: I might have said when I announced it why I noticed the man who was Thursday.
Rym: But it was called to my attention by something.
Rym: And upon it being called my intention, I remembered in Deus Ex something that sounded similar.
Rym: And sure enough, this book is quoted in Deus Ex.
Rym: So there's a little bit of a nerdy tie.
Rym: And one of our listeners said something to the effect of, my dad says this is a great book and he's always tried to get me to read it.
Rym: And the dad, as I've met him, is pretty nerdy.
Rym: So all these things together, I decided, you know what?
Rym: Maybe I'll check this book out and make it the book club book.
Rym: And when I looked at what it was about, obviously spoilers if you get from this point forward, if you guys haven't read the book, but at the same time, it's fucking book club.
Scott: I mean, what the fuck, guys?
Rym: If you didn't read this book, it'd probably be okay to listen to this episode because it'll spoil everything.
Rym: But you know what?
Rym: This is not about to be spoiled because the premise is the only big spoiler.
Rym: And I read the premise.
Rym: The premise was, as you know, that you've got a bunch of anarchists out there trying to ruin the world.
Rym: And you've got a cop.
Scott: Well, if you believe that anarchy is ruining the world.
Scott: You might like an anarchist world.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And the book gets into that.
Rym: So you've got a cop and the cop infiltrates the anarchists and gets elected to the anarchist council because he's a better proponent of anarchism than the real anarchists.
Scott: How could anarchists have a council?
Scott: Isn't the very mere existence of a council contrary to anarchy?
Rym: So I realized.
Scott: And in fact, they bring that up in the book.
Rym: This book that it is, in fact, a comedy.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: No kidding.
Rym: And that I actually really enjoyed it from that perspective.
Scott: But there were funny parts.
Rym: But yeah, now the funniest part in the entire book is Dr.
Rym: Bull is my favorite character.
Rym: It's pretty good because he is the one whenever everything goes to shit.
Rym: He is always the one who was like, fuck it.
Rym: It's over.
Rym: I don't give a shit.
Rym: You guys suck.
Rym: It's done.
Rym: Or he'll laugh or do something funny.
Rym: And there's one scene that really stuck out in my mind.
Rym: Remember when they think that the anarchists are chasing them down to murder them because the entire world is broken.
Scott: And there's like two or three.
Scott: There's two or three chapters of chase scene.
Rym: Oh, my God.
Rym: There's the longest chase ever.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Well, no, I think the the the the chase after that with the hot air balloon is probably the best.
Scott: It is basically the same chase, as far as I'm concerned, with a slight intermission.
Rym: So the or an intermezzo, the fake anarchists are chasing them and they're trying to get away.
Rym: And then they finally are going to fight and whatever.
Rym: And they run up and he hits the guy with that lantern and he pulls out the sword and all the bullshit.
Rym: Dr.
Rym: Bull's standing there with the sword.
Rym: And then the guy's like, I'm a cop.
Rym: And as soon as he says that, Dr.
Rym: Bull, there's it's just there's a part like there's a break.
Rym: And the next paragraph is one sentence.
Rym: And all it says is Dr.
Rym: Bull threw his sword into the sea.
Rym: And I just picture him being like, oh, fuck, throwing it like everything.
Rym: And that I actually laughed out loud at that scene because Dr.
Rym: Bull reacts to everything like that.
Rym: Just I picture him thinking is that for the love of God.
Scott: Do you remember which day the week he was?
Rym: I do not.
Scott: Not or neither.
Scott: I hardly remember.
Scott: I also don't really remember much of the days of the week, guys, other than Dr.
Rym: Bull.
Scott: Well, this Dr.
Scott: Bull is the first guy.
Rym: I remember more about the colonel, the French guy, Delacroix or whatever.
Scott: All right.
Scott: And that's the guy he duels with, right?
Scott: The French guy, because he has to go doesn't he go to France for the duel?
Rym: But he also has his two French friends who are helping him.
Rym: Yeah, yeah.
Rym: And all that business.
Rym: Anyway, so, yeah, they're all cops.
Rym: Everyone's a cop.
Rym: Everyone in this whole thing's a cop, except Sunday, who I think is God.
Rym: So what do you think of this book?
Scott: I mean, on the one hand, right.
Scott: You know, the premise was actually, you know, considering how long ago this is written and considering that, you know, I was surprised.
Scott: I'm like, huh, I can't think of anything recent that sort of stole this really clever premise.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, this book is written in 1908.
Scott: Right, you would think, you know, something like this would have been stolen and redone a hundred times.
Scott: So the fact that it wasn't sort of made that, you know, that idea that, you know, this guy's undercover, but actually everyone else is also undercover and on his side, but they don't, no one knows it.
Scott: It's like, that's so clever.
Scott: How come nobody's reused that or stolen it?
Scott: And it's like, man, that, you know, just that fact alone sort of is what really makes the book kind of cool.
Scott: But there was also, I kind of liked, you know, a lot of the, you know, symbolic things that were going on in the book, especially the sort of trippy stuff like towards the end, where they've all got the costumes on and the different days of the week.
Rym: So two interesting points.
Rym: One.
Scott: Because I like trippy shit like that.
Rym: I did the sort of like middle school level literary analysis through.
Rym: I didn't really engage too deeply because I didn't care that much.
Rym: But obviously this is a book.
Rym: if like I could picture any like mid, like eighth grader being assigned this book and having to write papers on the symbolism within it.
Rym: But I literally completely did not in any way pick up on the seven days of creation Christian symbolism until the very end when they were like, when one of the characters, like, he's like this costume, how does this match Thursday?
Rym: This is stupid.
Rym: And the guy's like, uh, Thursday's when X and Y were created in the seven days.
Rym: The main characters like, oh, I also.
Scott: I also did not pick up on that.
Scott: I was thinking more during the whole book up until that point.
Scott: I was thinking along the lines of, well, it's Thor's day.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And the origins of the name, you know, the it since it didn't fit.
Scott: I was like, well, I was, you know, where the names of the days come from is the kind of thing I was trying to match.
Rym: Do you know where all the days come from?
Scott: I looked up some of them that I didn't know.
Rym: You know what Tuesday is?
Rym: I won a fucking quiz ball competition with that shit.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Well, what is it, quiz ball man?
Scott: Okay, so Thursday is Thor's day.
Rym: Tuesday is Tyr's day.
Rym: Tyr is a different Norse god.
Rym: So you know how I won this quiz ball?
Rym: This was a...
Scott: Tyr, you kind of mumbled it.
Rym: No, it wasn't the name.
Rym: three elements that begin with H thing.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Helium, hydrogen and...
Scott: Helium.
Rym: So basically it was like, nor it was like Norse mythology.
Rym: It wasn't.
Rym: the topic was something like week, like days and months.
Rym: And it was like the, it was me alone against this other guy, like a one-on-one, like one guy from each team went up and did like these 20 questions.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So it was all like, they would name a month or a day or something.
Rym: And you have to buzz in and say what it like, what the etymological origin of that was.
Rym: And it was like Thursday, I was like Thor.
Rym: And that was like, yes.
Rym: And you know, I'm going through just fine.
Rym: This is Tuesday.
Rym: And I didn't know.
Rym: the other guy didn't know shit.
Rym: So I'm just sitting there and I'm like, ah, and I just figured I'd buzzing because I didn't matter as I buzzed in.
Rym: And I said, Tyr, because Tyr is Norse god.
Rym: Also, you know why I knew Tyr?
Scott: Begins with T?
Rym: No, Tyr is in Forgotten Realms.
Scott: I was going to say D&D.
Rym: He is one of the Norse gods who fled when that pantheon, like pantheon fell apart to live in Forgotten Realms gods.
Scott: That's T-Y-R-E-T.
Scott: No, just T-Y-R.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Rym: So I just said that and it was right.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And I, and everyone was like, how'd you know that?
Rym: And I was like, cause I'm a genius, of course.
Scott: Nerd, anyway.
Scott: I know everything about Norse mythology.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And anyway, the Norse gods did not match up in any meaningful way with the different dudes and their, their personalities or anything.
Scott: So I was just like, oh.
Rym: But what, what's interesting is what this does.
Rym: It really illustrates that the place and time that a work is written can often be very fixed, not just in terms of understanding the story, but in terms of one's interpretation.
Rym: Anyone in 1908 reading this would have been very Bible-y.
Rym: Would have just, even if they weren't religious, they at least knew the Bible and would think about the Bible.
Scott: If you're a literate book reading person at that time.
Rym: So works from that era, you would just assume that seven days, all right, there's probably a Bible metaphor going on.
Rym: But note how in the book, none of the characters picked up on that.
Rym: And they were surprised when it was pointed out to them.
Rym: But it is referenced several times throughout the book that none of them know what's in the Bible.
Rym: None of them are religious.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Even though Syme beats the guy over the head with that religious lantern and talks about how important that cross is.
Rym: But he's never actually read the Bible.
Scott: So, uh, what you read?
Scott: the free edition from the internet project Gutenberg.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: It was okay.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Did that have a, an introduction that was written by, who is the introduction written by?
Rym: No, no introduction.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Did that have footnotes in the back?
Scott: See, I bought, I purchased the Penguin Classics edition for a handful of reasons.
Scott: Reason number one, smells so good.
Scott: Reason number two, the cover is amazing.
Scott: And there's all these police just all over the place beating up on people in this pretty good art style.
Scott: And reason number three, which I didn't know until I got it is as this awesome appendix and footnotes and things like that, which were incredibly helpful because there's things that you wouldn't know.
Scott: Have basically there's no chance.
Scott: even a super educated, well-read person, unless you were kind of like a literary person, you know, with this kind of expertise, you would not know any of this shit.
Scott: that was, you know, only relevant at the time.
Scott: Um, and it, you know, it tells you like what certain words mean and things like that.
Scott: And it was super helpful while reading the book, but some of the things that they were trying to explain were just kind of weird.
Scott: Like, it's like, really?
Scott: It's like Strasburg pie.
Scott: It's a pie.
Scott: It's a pate made with fatty goose livers.
Scott: For example, it was reported the young man in the diplomatic service at Pumpernickel pick crawl used to bring home dispatches consisting of Strasburg pie to the foreign minister of the day.
Scott: And it's like, what?
Scott: What the fuck does that have to do with, you know, I'm sure they mentioned like Strasburg pie in some sentence somewhere.
Scott: And it's like, well, why is Strasburg pie, you know, relevant at all?
Scott: But the one thing that was relevant was the thing about the the the a subs fable about the pig.
Rym: And here that was a good part because that tactic of debate was brought.
Rym: I took an argumentation class at RIT was literally argumentation and debate.
Rym: And we talked about that technique at length.
Scott: So let me let me find this.
Scott: I just want to find the relevant passage in the actual book that it was referencing.
Scott: Page sixty five.
Scott: Footnote number eight.
Scott: I should have done this before the show started.
Scott: But I didn't think of it until just now.
Rym: Come on.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So my other favorite Dr.
Rym: Bull moment is toward the very end when the one guy keeps being like they're all like talking about Sunday.
Rym: Like he's like a god like the world.
Rym: He's like pan.
Rym: And the one guy keeps being like, just like pan.
Rym: And finally, Dr.
Rym: Bull is like, you seem to think pan is everything.
Rym: Shut it.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So here here comes.
Scott: OK, so he's like, what's going on?
Scott: I don't have the context.
Scott: But basically the guy says, I see he sneered.
Scott: You prevail like the false pig in Aesop and you fail.
Scott: I answered, smiling like the hedgehog in Montaigne.
Scott: Need I say there is no hedgehog in Montaigne.
Scott: Or a claptrap comes off, he said.
Scott: So would your beard.
Scott: I had no intelligent answer to this, which is quite true and rather witty, but I laughed heartily.
Scott: Answered like the pantheist boots.
Scott: So in the footnotes, it says the false pig in Aesop.
Scott: Probably a nonsense formulation, though in his edition, Stephen Medcalf, I guess he made an edition of Aesop's Fables, identifies the phrase with the fable of the buffoon and the countryman, actually by Phaedrus.
Scott: But ascribed to him, ascribed by him to Aesop, a buffoon at a theater imitated a pig squeak so perfectly that the audience insisted he must have a pig hidden about his person, but applauded him definitely when he convinced them he had not.
Scott: A countryman claimed he could do better and made a pig, which he had beneath his smock squeak.
Scott: The audience unanimously declared that the buffoons imitation was much more true to life.
Scott: The countryman producing the pig says that shows what sort of judges you are.
Scott: In 1912, Chesterton provided the introduction to V.S.
Scott: Vernon Jones' translation of Aesop's Fables, illustrated by Arthur Rackham.
Scott: There, he insisted.
Scott: in contrast to fairy tales, fables like those through which Aesop was famously was famous are premised on the idea that everything is itself and will in any case speak for itself.
Scott: The wolf will always be wolfish.
Scott: The fox will always be foxy.
Scott: According to this theory, the idea of a false pig is completely incompatible with Aesop, right?
Scott: So in Aesop's Fables, a fox would always be foxy, but in this fable, right, you know, things were not as they seem.
Scott: Therefore, it was not an Aesop's Fable.
Scott: I just thought, you know, that's the kind of crazy and interesting stuff that was going on here, and I don't remember the context of that weird passage, but when I- That's right!
Scott: Oh, that was actually one of my favorite parts.
Rym: Yeah, because the scholar's quoting, like, he's making real witticisms, and the guy's just like, "Well,
Rym: la-di-da!"
Rym: Exactly.
Scott: One of the cops is, you know, impersonates this anarchist scholar, and he impersonates him so well that then what happens is the actual scholar is- gets sort of cast out because they think he's the imposter.
Scott: So he is like the pig in this fable by Phaedrus, right, to where he's the real scholar, but everyone believes the imposter is the real deal because he's better than the- right?
Scott: So, and the fact that Chesterton wrote an introduction to a collection of Aesop's Fables, I think he knew also that it was the false pig of Phaedrus and not of Aesop, and wrote that on purpose, and shows you what's going on there.
Rym: Add some Hamlet level, uh, I'm crazy, check it out.
Scott: Yeah, anyway.
Rym: This book, if nothing, when I read it, I think the reason a lot of people think back to it is, one, the premise is great, even though the book itself, not that entertaining, really, except as a comedy, but it is eminently quotable.
Rym: Like, if you want something somewhat witty and a little bit lengthy with some references to quote that is relevant to a lot of modern society, the characters are just rife with them, and I think that's why it's quoted in a bunch of stuff.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Can you guys- do you see a page of quotes there?
Scott: Do you want to rattle them off of hilarity?
Rym: Well, this isn't really- this is just something a character said.
Rym: He said, "Your offer is far too idiotic to be
Rym: declined.".
Rym: I actually really like that one.
Scott: Yeah, that's the kind of thing that you can use in everyday speaking, if you could be that witty, you know?
Scott: But yeah, my biggest problem with this book is that just the pacing was so crazy, and- The action scenes are unparsable.
Scott: Yeah, it was- everything was moving so rapidly, and yet sometimes so slowly, it's like they would pretty much, like, teleport almost.
Scott: It's like, "Okay, they're talking in London, and they're in France having a
Scott: duel.".
Scott: And it's like, they didn't really just, you know, it's like, they didn't sort of ease into a train trip or anything like that, or the boat, it's just like, BAM!
Scott: And suddenly they're dueling in France, and you didn't even realize they're in France unless you're reading really, really carefully.
Scott: And then, especially those two chase scenes toward the end, it's pretty much like, whoosh, they're in a car, whoosh, they're somewhere, whoosh, there's a million people chasing them, where do they come from so quickly?
Rym: Yeah, like when the anarchists are chasing them, it's like, there's an army now, and again, those guys are stupid too, they're like, "Hey, there's a bunch of guys over there.
Rym: I guess the entire world has risen up in
Rym: anarchy.".
Scott: Yeah, it's like, what?
Rym: Let's go to the police station, they'll help us.
Scott: And it's like, by the time they're at the police station, the town's being overrun, and it's like, two paragraphs ago, you were just chilling at some dude's house, asking him for his car.
Rym: And the weird things that happened, like, when the one guy produces a lantern in the car, and they're like, "Where'd you get that
Rym: lantern?".
Rym: And he's like, "Oh, the guy just ripped it out of the ceiling for me, smashed two of his vases on the
Rym: way.".
Rym: And they're like,
Rym: "What?".
Scott: It's like, why didn't you show that when it happened, instead of, it feels like someone is writing this with ink and didn't have word processor, so they didn't want to go back and write in the smashing scene, so he put it in later.
Rym: They were a little cartoony, like the chase scene in Kung Fu Hustle.
Scott: I think even crazier and harder to follow.
Rym: Well, especially, there's a scene where the guy, early on, that's chasing him, the old man, but always appears right behind him, very Pinkie Pie style.
Rym: But there's also the scene when they're chasing Sunday, and he's like, throwing notes at them, and just sticking around with it.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, that's the kind of stuff that you see in a Babar cartoon, or Babar, right?
Scott: That just shit makes no sense.
Rym: But here's what I really want to say about this book.
Rym: I think it was enjoyable to read, but not super enjoyable.
Rym: But, I'm glad I read it.
Rym: More importantly, this is a story that really, really needs a loose interpretation.
Rym: Like, a movie or a comic that is not very, kind of like how Robocop the movie, was not very true to the original idea.
Rym: And yet it was better because of it.
Scott: There was something before Robocop the movie?
Rym: Well, the original conception for Robocop was very different from what Robocop became.
Scott: But it wasn't a book.
Rym: Fine, Total Recall.
Rym: Total Recall, the story is one thing.
Rym: The movie, the Arnold one, was actually way different.
Rym: But it, on its own, was really good.
Rym: This is that kind of story where, if you just take the events, and the core idea, and interpret it loosely, and do something cool with it, it would make a fantastic and hilarious comedy.
Scott: Yeah, I think the number one thing you have to do, right, is the whole first few chapters where, other than the first one, where he discovers that every single other person is a cop, slowly but surely, one at a time.
Scott: It's like, after the second or third one, when you go up to the fourth guy, you gotta be like, "Alright, we know you're a cop,
Scott: right?".
Scott: You know, it's like, you wouldn't even be, you'd just assume everyone else is one at that point, because it's too crazy.
Scott: The three are, the first three you came across were all cops, and you still assume the rest aren't.
Rym: But the characters!
Scott: All of them.
Scott: but the last one are cops, and you still assume the last one isn't.
Rym: Well, this is my trouble, Syme was brilliant most of the time, but he was stupid in this one regard.
Rym: He would just, he'd find, he's like, "Oh, I guess there were five cops out of
Rym: seven.".
Scott: Right, it's like, no, no, no, after number three or four, it's like, I'm assuming the rest are cops, right, before I assume they're anarchists.
Scott: Because, if it's, even if it was three out of seven, what are the odds that you picked the first three out of seven?
Rym: Also, it's the game of Mafia.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: Kind of.
Scott: You wanna make a Mafia game that is themed on Man Who Was Thursday?
Rym: It would be a Mafia-like, it would not be a Mafia game, it wouldn't be Mafia.
Scott: You draw a card, it says Sunday.
Scott: on it, you're like, "Fuck
Scott: yeah!".
Rym: I don't know how it would work.
Scott: Well, come up with it.
Rym: Well, no, I gotta come up with my 25 shitty games first.
Rym: The one I'm working on right now, it's Bumway Cars.
Rym: It's placing bums on platforms, and then into trains, and then you have your guys trying to avoid the bums.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But anyway, if you did this, if you interpreted this into a movie or something like that, you would have to somehow make it believable that they really, really believe that everyone else was an anarchist.
Rym: Or, you'd have to make it, you'd have to really play it up as a sort of farcical comedy.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Which could still be done, I mean, like I said, I laughed out loud several times at Dr.
Rym: Bull reacting to things.
Rym: Yes, there's also the whole bomb plot at the beginning, which is like- Yeah, the bomb plot was fine until they had the duel, and as readers, we knew the other guy was a cop.
Rym: And yet he, and like, I don't understand what his plan was.
Rym: If he was a cop and didn't want to set off the bomb, why was he trying desperately to win the duel to go set off the bomb?
Scott: Yep.
Scott: And meanwhile, while there's a whole bunch of the people coming out to chase them, why were they running away?
Scott: You know, it's like, that's the point where they got caught up with and the chases began right after the duel.
Scott: So, it's like, you could just let them catch.
Rym: Yeah, I gotta say though, I like Gregory, because he is- I think he's definitely the most- When Greg, that scene in the beginning when he loses the debate, he is the angriest a Gregory has ever been.
Scott: Ever been.
Rym: He is so angry.
Scott: That, I think that was actually probably, you know, that very beginning was like, you know, more well paced and well written than the rest of the book.
Scott: I think it's like, he had this huge idea, he had the perfect set up, and then the rest of it was much looser, but that- I don't think he knew where to go with it either.
Scott: Yeah, but those opening one or two chapters with the whole, the set up, were pretty great.
Scott: If the whole rest of it had been as good as that set up, it would have been awesome.
Rym: So, random aside, but I, every time Sunday was described, I could not help but picture the leader from 1Q84.
Scott: Oh, that's a good- Because they were both described the same way.
Scott: Sort of similar.
Rym: I imagine the leader from- Their bulk and their movement, specifically when they describe the way the leader moves, is the same as the way this guy moves.
Scott: But I imagined, the thing is, I imagined them also very similarly, and I actually did think about the leader from 1Q84, right?
Scott: But I imagine the leader in 1Q84 as being taller and thinner, whereas I imagined Sunday, because he was so, being more square, like the kingpin from Marvel comics.
Scott: True, but- Like a big square guy.
Scott: But in QT84- Which was kind of crazy for the chase scene, because he was running away, but he was immensely fat.
Rym: Oh, that happened all the time.
Rym: Look at the action scenes, made no sense.
Rym: There is no way a thrown piece of paper from a speeding cab lands in the other cab.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Well, maybe they were like horse cabs, but no, they specifically had gas-powered cars.
Rym: Well, later, they both at different times.
Rym: Right, yeah.
Rym: But in 1Q84, the way the leader is described as moving, the way he shakes out his shoulders, there is an identical scene in this book.
Rym: Where Sunday shakes out his shoulders and quivers like in this mask.
Scott: I actually, for a time, because you know, every single one, almost half those guys were like guys in disguise in costume and shit like that, right?
Rym: You thought he was in disguise too?
Scott: I was pretty sure Sunday was like Gregory in an inflatable suit or something.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You know, for a few pages there.
Rym: That would have been great, but I like the fact that Gregory was the only actual anarchist.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: In the whole book.
Scott: Nobody, no one was anarchist.
Rym: So what was the book trying to say?
Scott: What was the book trying to say?
Rym: It made, much like other books we've read like this, it made many small points along the way, but doesn't have an overarching point.
Scott: Well, I think, you know, the one point, I think there are many points to take away, but the biggest one I took away was the thing they say, you know, of course, whatever you say near the end of the book, right, is most likely to be, you know, something that is really very important, or towards the beginning also.
Scott: So the one thing that I really took away was this one part here where it says, uh, pretty sure this is it.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: So I'm spraying to his feet, shaking from head to foot.
Scott: I see everything, everything that there is.
Scott: Why does each thing on earth war against each other thing?
Scott: Why does each small thing in the world have to fight against the world itself?
Scott: Why does a fly have to fight for the whole universe?
Scott: You know, why does a dandelion have to fight the whole universe?
Rym: That could be a metaphor for the ridiculously of the anarchist position.
Scott: Yes, but, you know, for the same reason that I had to be alone in the dreadful council of the days, alone on the councils, he councils a group, but he was alone, so that each thing that obeys law may have the glory and isolation of the anarchist, glory and isolation of the anarchist, so that each man fighting for order may be as brave and good as a man, a man as the dynamiter.
Scott: There is something to be said.
Scott: So that the real lie of Satan may be flung back in the face of the blasphemer, so that by tears and torture, we may earn the right to say to this man, you lie.
Scott: No agonies can be too great to buy the right to say to this accuser, we also have suffered.
Rym: That buys into this idea that the anarchist feels put upon and feels alone and has only one noble way to fight back.
Rym: But if they actually talk to each other.
Scott: Well, I think a whole lot of this is more about, you know, that's why I emphasized isolation, right?
Scott: As you look at this book and it's about, you know, the difference, it shows you, you know, the hypocrisy of your anarchist, but you have a council or, you know, he's a cop.
Scott: He goes, he sneaks into this thing alone, right?
Scott: He thinks he's the only one who's undercover amongst the sea of anarchists.
Scott: He feels as the anarchist feels put upon by, you know, the whole world.
Scott: It's him against this whole council of anarchists.
Scott: But then, you know, because he's not an anarchist, you know, he teams up.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And that is the difference between the anarchist and the not anarchist.
Scott: is that, you know, in a in a place with no rules, you know, and there's no governance and no law.
Scott: There can be no teaming up because you all you can't fully trust anyone with no sort of structure or anything.
Scott: But, you know, the good guys, the non anarchist.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They have the power to team.
Scott: It's not, you know, it doesn't.
Scott: it makes sense for them to have a council, to have a group to all to join up.
Scott: And as they, you know, it's the whole half the book, more than half the book.
Scott: is him going along, teaming up with these guys, getting the band together.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then all chasing together in this team to get, you know, why was he fighting against, you know, to isolate himself.
Rym: And yet the very nature of his struggle drives him to team up.
Scott: Well, but but at the same time, he's the anarchist fights alone.
Scott: Right.
Rym: So here's the thing.
Rym: Look at all the other anarchists from Gregory.
Rym: They form this little council and everything.
Rym: And they were doing the same thing, but legit, at least trying to.
Scott: But but when they went to do their bombing, it was one guy would actually do the bombing, whereas police, they went.
Scott: You know, when it was time to do their thing, they all grouped up together in the chase.
Scott: It wasn't like one guy carrying the weight of everybody, the fatal flaw of anarchism.
Rym: Whenever you see like punk kids today talking about it, which is very common to libertarians or anything, they always sort of go down this road of.
Rym: we don't need these authorities to tell us what to do.
Rym: We can figure it out ourselves.
Rym: We can band together ourselves to provide these services consensually.
Scott: Which is which is all right.
Scott: So it's it's this, you know, conflict between the cooperation and individualism.
Rym: The true anarchist, the Gregory, who actually would go and put the bomb is the one person that debate who, once the government's gone, would actually prevent new government from coming up.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And would bomb any government, even an anarchist government.
Scott: But even Gregory.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Even the Gregory, who would bomb and would prevent government from forming and doesn't want to cooperate, still wants to have friends to walk in the woods with and have witty debates with.
Scott: No, but that is and he's still and he still has the honor of not, you know, of sticking to the word that he said.
Scott: He is he is putting law upon himself.
Rym: Now, there are two ways to interpret that.
Rym: Mm hmm.
Rym: The police were all notably either a religious or straight up atheist.
Rym: None of them knew the Bible.
Rym: It was really outside of what they talk about, archangels and things.
Rym: But they it was made they were.
Scott: they were educated, you know, in true to atheist form.
Scott: They were very well educated in religion.
Rym: But it was made very clear that they did not know the Bible.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Yet they had this code of honor anyway.
Rym: He was.
Rym: Simon was not afraid of damnation keeping his word.
Rym: He kept his word because he keeps his word.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: Gregory may, you could argue, kept his word out of a fear of submission to this higher authority that he cannot strike at.
Scott: Mm hmm.
Scott: So that is you're saying he could believe in anarchy being OK because he also believed in God.
Scott: And so you don't need government because God keeps everything in line or because it was keeping him in line because he was religious or he was also an atheist.
Rym: But in his isolationism, believe that he looked like he still, for whatever reason, had to keep up this honor, had to be an honorable person.
Rym: Yet in the very end, in that scene, in the very end of the book, I point out he tells he basically calls them all cops, effectively breaking his word by revealing that to other cops.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Sime never broke his word.
Scott: Nope.
Scott: There's also the whole thing where the end, you can't even tell how much of that is real and how much that might be Sime tripping on who knows what.
Scott: It's like really quick sentences that are like things went black and then he doesn't remember.
Rym: And, you know, it's like, well, it kind of gets to the point that look at Gregory.
Rym: If the end is to be believed, despite all of his feelings and being a true anarchist can engage in intelligent conversation and debate and in fact seems more fulfilled by that than by bombing.
Rym: So perhaps the true answer is to have all different kinds of people debate all different kinds of things in an intellectual place rather than a physical place.
Rym: Or it was just a thriller book with a bunch of allegory written 100 years ago.
Scott: Yeah, it's also definitely what it was.
Rym: I'm glad I read it, but I could understand why other people wouldn't enjoy it.
Rym: But if I was ever an English teacher, I bet your butt that if you were in eighth grade, you'd be reading this and writing me a five paragraph paper on the symbolism within.
Scott: I will say that, you know, the book had many good parts.
Scott: It had many flaws.
Scott: And if it was any longer, the flaws might have outweighed.
Scott: But it is the correct length for the contents that it is containing.
Scott: It is a box and all the contents of the box are fitting inside of it perfectly with no empty space.
Scott: And also it is not overflowing.
Scott: so you can close the box very neatly.
Rym: All right.
Rym: And I guess to wrap up the box metaphor, let's put a bow on it and stop because I'm kind of hungry.
Scott: Yeah, let's go.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.