Rym: It's Wednesday August 15th.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm posy McPauzer sin, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: It sounded like you were yawning So I was kind of backing off to give you time to finish yawning.
Rym: tonight.
Rym: We're talking about the ranks of the black order and yawning.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So how many of you are yawning right the fuck now?
Rym: Kids.
Rym: if you weren't now you are.
Rym: but uh yeah It's kind of high.
Rym: we want to do the shows quickly now for the next year or two because as of a couple days ago counter-strike go is in open beta and I pretty much play it every day when I get home from work.
Scott: I'm planning once I get home from the show.
Rym: I was playing it when Scott arrived.
Rym: Normally Scott beats me in my own house for GeekNights, but today He comes home, and I've already been playing counter-strike for a while.
Scott: Why wouldn't you be?
Rym: it's you know?
Rym: Too many games.
Rym: I've waited for forever, and they finally come out And they're not what I wanted.
Rym: counter-strike go is exactly what I wanted.
Scott: it's counter-strike Polished to be more modern and shit, and it's still counter-strike.
Rym: Oh my god.
Scott: That's all there is to it But it's Wednesday not Tuesday.
Rym: You don't care about that stuff because clearly you only listen to anime and read comics Possibly manga about listening to anime blind?
Rym: uh Well it depends anyway.
Rym: So well I guess listening to the anime episodes Sure, you know they just listeners here.
Rym: well listener yes But there is actually some big convention news that many of you might not have noticed.
Scott: so every year not actually convention news Specifically, but it does.
Rym: I was gonna make that point.
Rym: But if you ask the average person who knows about comics And this is I think why the thing we're about to talk about happened what mocha is Their response will invariably be that convention with the indie comics not that museum.
Rym: And that's the problem.
Rym: the mocha is the Museum of comic and cartoon arts in New York City.
Rym: I've never actually been to anything that they've ever done or to their actual building other than When I go to the mocha festival every year.
Scott: well I mean I was a member of the museum for like a couple years.
Rym: I was a member twice.
Rym: I never once used any perk.
Rym: I mean in fact when I went to the mocha festival I had already lost my card, so I paid full price for the badge.
Scott: anyway I you could just tell them your name and stuff.
Scott: I was aware that they were a museum and had a museum location, and I was aware of events held at that location.
Scott: But the thing is that location the museum was in because they had so little monies was very hidden.
Scott: It wasn't even any way to tell where it was from the street you had.
Scott: there was no sign.
Scott: There was no nothing.
Scott: you had to know where it was to get in there.
Scott: It was not.
Scott: it was upstairs in a place.
Scott: So it's like hardly anyone went there usually the.
Scott: you know if a museum had like some street presence You'd get foot traffic, and you can get monies But you know not being so hard to find.
Scott: I guarantee that they even probably lost money of people trying to find it and not Finding it and giving up.
Rym: Now meanwhile the mocha festival, which is what most people know mocha as is Actually one of my favorite Conventions slash festival slash events every year it's right up there with packs magfest everything we do.
Scott: But it was also the primary fundraiser for the mocha pretty much the only fundraiser for the museum right.
Scott: so what they would do is They hold this festival.
Scott: the festival would pay for itself and pay for a year of expenses for the museum And because the museum was paying crazy rent on this place that nobody could see.
Scott: They had to keep raising the price not of entrance to the mocha festival But for tables at the festival.
Scott: granted they could probably double the price and still fill maybe But they kept jacking up that price year after year and people did complain because they're poor like SVA college students or whatever and whatnot.
Scott: So the museum had money troubles yep.
Rym: But I think the primary trouble is simply that due to you know the factors you talked about and just in general Nerds know about conventions and people will travel for events like this, but Museums that aren't big sort of like municipal like very well-known museums Generally don't get a lot of traffic.
Scott: I mean if you know some of them do you know like look at museum of sex for example right?
Rym: Yeah?
Rym: Well, that's sex.
Scott: I'm just saying, but you know it had street.
Scott: Maybe if it was the and had money for marketing of comic and cartoon sexual arts It would have had a lot more it this the museum of sex had marketing and it all said street presence Which gets people in the door?
Scott: Yeah?
Rym: I remember seeing ads that were like Museum of Sex.
Scott: right you know the mocha Pretty great.
Scott: Yeah, it didn't have the money or the location to do that.
Scott: so the only people who go to it pretty much are People going to it for like an event.
Scott: who know about it.
Scott: We're already in the know.
Scott: insiders.
Scott: you don't get you know this any spread whatsoever or People might like you know know about it like super comics.
Scott: fans know about it.
Scott: visit, New York And let's spend you know an hour or two going to it.
Scott: But that and you know people in the industry obviously now they had events and all these other things.
Rym: But they just were never really on my radar compared to other stuff I did.
Rym: but the long and short of it is that the museum of comic and cartoon arts ran out of money.
Rym: Yeah, so what?
Scott: they even had to sell a few arts to pay some bills.
Rym: So they have effectively and I'm not going to go through all the gritty details of what happened But they have transferred all of their assets to the society of illustrators.
Scott: Yeah, so on the one hand some people are upset because they're like oh now You're sort of you know in a way saying that comics is a subset of illustrator of the greater art of illness.
Scott: wait wait illustration it is Not really.
Scott: it's also writing.
Scott: illustration doesn't involve writing.
Rym: yeah, but it but part of the an aspect of comics is a subset.
Rym: I mean anime is a subset of animation, but yet.
Rym: There's writers and producers.
Scott: People have a comics is not a subset of illustration.
Scott: I mean there is illustration involved.
Scott: well No, it is the making of comics, but it is not a.
Rym: you know that portion of its set is a subset of illustration But another portion of it is a subset of other things.
Scott: It's like saying anime is a subset of music.
Rym: It's like no it's not what anime is a subset of for example art and aspects of anime.
Scott: Every art is a subset of art.
Scott: so the problem is the inheritance structure of the sets is actually Multi-tiered and complex anyway, but you know the symbolically you know people don't like that, but otherwise this really isn't so bad Right.
Scott: the society of illustrators actually has real space.
Rym: I would say this lots of money.
Rym: if you were choosing Relatively having mocha be owned and be considered a subset of the Society of illustrators or the Society of writers It's pretty much 50/50 Right, but it's like you wouldn't want to have it.
Scott: It's better than like someone privately buying it or who knows what.
Rym: I think it's a silly concern because the side of illustrators is an ancient Nonprofit dedicated soul is basically a lot like the mocha, but it's more of a like outreach group Yep, and they actually have a really good space that the mocha is going to move into.
Scott: Well, I mean the mocha isn't moving into it right.
Scott: basically there is no mocha.
Scott: It's just the society of illustrators owns all the things that belong to mocha.
Rym: well no from what I'm reading Yes, which includes the name.
Rym: so the mocha as a thing is just.
Scott: it's just a trademark.
Scott: That is now the property of the Sun.
Rym: yes And all the collected works and as far as I can tell all the people who work for it The all two people yeah, yeah, and as a result the mocha festival is also going to be a part of it.
Scott: Yeah, so you know they didn't give a lot of details and what's gonna happen with the festival But basically it looks good, and it also looks not too good right?
Scott: the good Is that society illustrators has money from other things?
Scott: It's not like the mocha which is getting all its money from this festival.
Scott: so You know they could just run the mocha festival as a regular fundraiser Since it won't be their only fundraiser for the society of illustrators.
Scott: They don't need to jack up the prices on the tables and stuff And they could just run it and make a regular amount of money off it.
Scott: There'll be no problem.
Scott: on the other hand You know the mocha festival.
Scott: It was not inexpensive to run.
Scott: It is not.
Scott: It's not like this cheap thing like oh It's easy to do.
Scott: so We'll see what exactly they decide to do with it.
Scott: I highly doubt that they will kill it though.
Scott: They may change things.
Rym: Well, we'll see what they would change because if they if it is not primarily a comic like indie sort of underground or you know basically non superhero Standard DC Marvel comic fest I probably wouldn't bother going because but I you know.
Scott: But if you think about it right the mocha festival on its own right was fun was paying for a museum for a whole year and also for itself.
Scott: if They kill it or something happens to it And it dies out a new one will start immediately.
Scott: anyone can just start the festival as its own Organization who has the contacts with all of those people you know and just start a new mocha festival.
Scott: Call it something else, but say hey guys This is the mocha festival.
Scott: It's bait, but it's only got to pay for itself.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: It doesn't have to pay for anything else, so we're these are good.
Scott: the prices are gonna be.
Scott: let's see.
Rym: now It seems like things are gonna be fine because the the society of illustrators said straight up that their goal Is to continue to stage the mocha fest in its current location nice.
Rym: dedicate a gallery in a building to mocha's Perfection.
Scott: making that your goal doesn't mean you're going to do it.
Scott: Just see how my goal is to be to do had did make the Concord fly Scott.
Scott: It's not gonna happen.
Rym: all corporate things are goals because you can't actually promise anything.
Rym: I can promise something and you might not do it.
Scott: I can promise GeekNights' episodes.
Scott: There will be more of them.
Scott: Warranty at least one.
Rym: you want a warranty.
Rym: I'll slap a warranty.
Rym: you can ship your head Bulls ass.
Scott: I promise I will not die before the next week night's episode this episode being the next ones.
Rym: Tell me how the view is from that bull's-ass.
Rym: Anyway, and a bunch of other things and mocha memberships will be honored by the Society of illustrators.
Rym: Whatever that does that mean?
Scott: I'm a Society of illustrators member.
Scott: I guess okay does that bet me Bennett more benefits?
Rym: I have no idea.
Rym: I don't do much with the Society of illustrators either, okay?
Rym: But it'll be interesting to see what happens to the festival because I realized that if I look at every Convention I have ever attended in my entire life.
Rym: I've spent more money in any one mocha fest on Goods from the convention, then I have spent it probably every other convention.
Rym: I've ever attended combined.
Rym: Yeah, yeah And that's not just a factor of me having more money now because I still go back three badges.
Rym: So We'll see what happens with this.
Rym: I don't think it's gonna be a big drama fest because the The amount of internet like freak out about it has been very low and the few like I guess complaints are like the things got raised seem to be raised in a Relatively erudite and sort of.
Rym: let's discuss this.
Rym: What do you think will happen?
Rym: fashion as opposed to the fanboy?
Rym: Outrage that happened when you're a comic-con said they were killing the New York Anime Festival Where the response was they're trying to sabotage Anime or they're trying to like drive us furries out of the convention?
Scott: real answer You don't make them any fucking money.
Scott: So why do they want to pay money to rent a space in the Javits to put you in?
Scott: Separately when that doesn't make that doesn't give them any benefit financially whatsoever.
Rym: Yep I love how the New York Anime Festival like announcement.
Rym: when that happened they basically Did everything possible to not say that they were killing it because it doesn't make money.
Rym: they're like good news everybody.
Rym: We're merging the New York Anime Festival into the comic-con.
Scott: We're not gonna use that name anymore.
Rym: It's gonna be an integral part of the New York Comic-Con.
Rym: Yeah, which is code for yeah, there's no more New York Anime Festival but anyway things Of the day.
Rym: What do you got for me?
Scott: Oh, so You know Alfred Hitchcock, he's pretty awesome.
Rym: He's pretty great.
Rym: I've seen a lot of his movies.
Scott: Yeah, I was actually who are we talking to recently?
Scott: like hadn't seen Rear Window or something?
Scott: Yeah, and I was ready.
Scott: I was gonna like stab myself in the head.
Scott: Whoa anyway, so yeah, if you haven't seen those See them or stab yourself, you know, there's probably a torrent of everything Hitchcock ever did.
Rym: But even if you want to go legit We bought many years ago this DVD box set that was like 20 Alfred Hitchcock movies for like five bucks.
Scott: Yep anyway So if you don't know in most of his movies Alfred Hitchcock himself, you know.
Scott: And the TV show would you know make a cameo like he would.
Scott: he wouldn't make a cameo like, you know have lines speaking lines.
Scott: He would be easily be an extra in his own.
Scott: try to get on a bus answer a phone Walking around in the background standing in a crowd, you know hiding in a window Doing all kinds of stuff, you know, we're big office full of people.
Scott: He's one of the guys in the office stuff like that, you know.
Scott: He just be in the movie on screen somewhere, which is why you know, he is a recognizable person.
Scott: You know now for anyone else because he introed his TV show.
Rym: Yes that Think about how many kids today watch a show.
Scott: the line drawing.
Rym: I'm saying how many kids.
Rym: they will watch a show like Family Guy or the Simpsons and something will parody that Hitchcock presents opening.
Rym: They'll think that that's a joke for the Simpsons as opposed to a reference to something older or even know.
Scott: All right, but it's like, you know, a lot of people who work not, you know Behind the scenes on things even like famous directors.
Scott: people might know their names.
Scott: their names might be incredibly famous But you still won't know what they look like, right?
Scott: But Hitchcock people know he looks like any at least old people.
Scott: Yeah, anyway, well people who know who he is Nobody.
Scott: look.
Rym: now your thing of the day is partly more notable than it would be if it were anyone else Because of the sheer number of works that Hitchcock has done.
Scott: I know you start watching this thing and it's like, you know the very first movies that you see in this thing are from like the 20s and they go all the way up to 60s 70s, right?
Scott: It's kind of crazy.
Scott: Anyway, but yeah, this is every Hitchcock cameo in a movie that his own movie.
Scott: It's pretty epic.
Scott: It's only four minutes long because you know, the cami the cameos are very short But you should.
Scott: You should watch this and all the movies.
Rym: when I was very very young I would pretty much like Alfred Hitchcock presents was like a staple of my extremely young childhood.
Rym: Yeah, so speaking of movies, you know, there's all these sort of mashups or super cuts of movies.
Rym: You know Tom Hanks peeing in movies or whatever his favorite.
Rym: Yeah, specifically that one.
Rym: But this one in particular gets a lot of points my thing of the day because of the sheer breadth of movies from which it drew its sources.
Rym: and it works particularly well because the way the lyrics are Presented in baby got back.
Rym: It's more spoken word than singing.
Rym: So it actually sounds a lot like the original song in many places.
Rym: This is just very well done.
Rym: It is baby got back sung by a couple hundred movies.
Scott: I like how they even sometimes creatively connect the clips like that.
Scott: I saw one part.
Scott: I forget what the lyric was, but it showed John Travolta.
Scott: I think Pulp Fiction and it cut to John Travolta.
Scott: Saturday Night Fever.
Scott: Yeah, right say, you know to combine to say one line.
Rym: It's like a lot of love went into this thing.
Scott: Yeah, that takes hard work to specifically not just find people saying all the words but to go for the.
Scott: you know That element as well Pushes this one above the rest of the pack.
Rym: So in the meta moment, we are going to be at the penny arcade expo prime and the penny arcade expo dev doing three three events short subjects in gaming Academia versus reality and the GeekNights' tabletop workshop.
Scott: now I learned something to probably finish working on the.
Rym: actually I've been working hard on Two-thirds of one of them and on the fullness of another one of them.
Rym: But anyway, the thing you need to know is that if you want to go to the GeekNights' tabletop workshop All of the tabletop content is in the red lion Which is a hotel nearby because packs long ago outgrew pretty much every venue in tiny Seattle.
Scott: Didn't the schedule say like room 302 or something?
Scott: Yeah, that sounds like the room that it was in last year.
Rym: Yeah, but supposedly the red lion has a lot of this content.
Rym: So we're gonna see.
Scott: we're gonna see exactly where it is.
Rym: So but more important ask tabletop people Enforcers now there it is.
Rym: Here's the more important part on.
Rym: you have to sign up for this ahead of time Because the number of seats is limited and if PAX East was any indication this thing is gonna be completely full.
Scott: I have a feeling though people won't actually sign up and that it'll just be first come first serve at the door for the empty People.
Rym: I'm pretty sure people will sign up.
Rym: based on what I've learned from how the signups are gonna work Tabletop stuff does not have a lot of seats.
Rym: This has like 40 less seats than the room.
Rym: We did this in at PAX East and at PAX East We turned a lot of people away.
Scott: Yeah, but at PAX Prime last year, it was like Nova.
Rym: Yeah, because PAX Prime it wasn't even in the goddamn book.
Rym: It was an experiment.
Scott: Is this gonna be in the book?
Rym: Yeah, this is legit like in PAX East.
Rym: He was in the book.
Rym: So it filled up axes.
Scott: I didn't think it was in the book at all.
Rym: It was in the schedule and in the in the.
Rym: whatever.
Rym: I don't know if they.
Rym: I think the description was I don't remember Wasn't but the location was whatever.
Scott: Anyway, anyway, I want to add something.
Scott: We always talk about all the different places on the internet that you can find us and join us and follow us and read us And get our info and all that business, right?
Scott: There's one place that we really haven't mentioned in years and with the release of CSGO I want to mention it.
Scott: There is a official GeekNights steam group.
Scott: It's wicked old but it's still there and if you want to play games on Steam with other listeners It's just a public group.
Scott: You can just fucking join.
Rym: Yeah guys do any times I've played tf2 with.
Rym: yes, like people are we trying to view in the forum?
Scott: Yeah, people always trying to friend me on Steam.
Scott: It's like if I don't know you I'm not Friending you and actually I should go through because I used to just friend everyone on Steam.
Scott: I should go through and delete all the people aren't actually friends from friends But it's like if you're just some listener join the GeekNights steam group and we can play games together.
Scott: Anyway, you don't need to actually be friends You know, so You should join that shit.
Scott: We're just intellectual ha.
Scott: and if you're not on Steam seriously, what?
Scott: Even if you have a Mac you can at least get steam and portal.
Rym: I guess in this day and age Steam is obligatory, right?
Scott: if you don't have steam installed your computer then why listen?
Rym: this book club book is the man who was Thursday and We have a ton of videos.
Rym: I updated I finally uploaded just About six months after PAX East highlights reel from PAX East 2012.
Scott: Yeah I just sent out the newsletter again today and I had to link to like five or six new YouTube videos We've made since the last newsletter.
Rym: Yeah, I got a new pony mashup.
Rym: I got a bunch of a bunch of stuff.
Rym: So in fact, we got a new one of our lectures up from PAX East 2012 a lot more videos going out.
Rym: Yeah, I think that's it.
Rym: We should get into the main bit which is another Timo comic because as you know our dear friend Timo particle physicist many many
Scott: years ago He sent us a box of comics from Finland and Europe and we were gonna read
Rym: him and Give him back and send him a care package in return.
Scott: So but we took many years to do this because we're bums and sir.
Scott: I haven't even read comics I've paid for.
Scott: how am I gonna read comic?
Scott: someone else gave me.
Rym: the thing is some of the comics He gave us are hard to get and pretty damn good.
Scott: Yep
Rym: So what we're reviewing tonight is a comic called the ranks of the Black Order though You may find it under a Ridiculous number of other names ranging from the Black Order Brigade not
Scott: too bad a name But still wrong
Rym: to the Falange de la de noir
Scott: the correct name.
Rym: Oh, what was it was like chaos something chaos theory or something?
Rym: Yeah, I found some weird titles for this comic.
Rym: Yeah but if you don't listen to the rest of this, we're not gonna spoil anything, but the ranks of the Black Order is a Fantastic Comic, it's just one book and an entire story is told within it start to finish.
Rym: It's brutal.
Rym: It's sad depressing Almost inspirational, but it's inspirational in that kind of oppositely inspirational way.
Scott: Well, you really liked it, huh?
Scott: I actually did really like.
Scott: I just thought it was kind of okay.
Rym: I think the reason I really liked it is that it reminded me of Jason and Hemingway.
Scott: Jason as in Jason chainsaw axe-murdering coming out of the lake Jason.
Rym: yeah, of course the scene where the guy comes out of the lake and hockey mask Jason Jason who is known by no other name who makes Comics that Jason comics filled with melancholy that make you go.
Rym: Ah Yeah, I mean, yeah that definitely I think you reacted to any Jason comic ever reading the last panel but for going.
Scott: But that J that aspect of the Jason I think is actually more of a Common aspect of many European comics.
Scott: I think it is so of course this also being a European comic What's it?
Scott: but Bilal did this one right Bilal and Kristen?
Rym: Yeah, I think Bilal did the writing.
Scott: Yes, Bilal is incredibly famous artist you're talking about.
Scott: But yeah Speaking of incredibly famous artists, of course It's Bilal, so, you know why he's incredibly famous?
Scott: because he's incredibly good.
Rym: It's a really sort of gritty washed out almost watercolor looking style with really like thin black lines.
Rym: Yeah, I really like that.
Scott: It's pretty amazing.
Scott: But yeah, I didn't you know, I wasn't that tied up in it?
Scott: I'd also don't?
Scott: I only read this mere weeks ago and I read this like a year ago.
Scott: Yeah, and I remember it starkly.
Scott: Yeah, I remember it kind of.
Scott: It shows how much of an impression it made on me.
Rym: All right, Scott, how many characters from the in call can you name?
Rym: because you just read that - okay The main guy is John DeFool.
Scott: I can't forget that name.
Scott: Yeah, right There's the gray bird thingy, which name is I forget.
Scott: All right, you can't forget meta Baron.
Scott: That's an amazing name total badass, dude.
Scott: There's meta Baron son, which is yellow hair greatest American hero fro kid.
Scott: The in call is sort of a character This animal girl.
Scott: I forget nature girl.
Scott: I forget her name Her sister.
Scott: I forget her name.
Rym: Oh What was it?
Rym: I'll probably remember half her through the show, but I'll say it now.
Scott: I was reading a president guy.
Scott: forget his name.
Rym: I was reading a comic that I read before again not that long ago and I was like Desperately reminded of the in call and I got to find out if the person who wrote this more recent comic was inspired by the The more recent kind.
Rym: I forgot.
Rym: that's why I said I'm gonna remember helping here and I'm gonna go oh shit this.
Rym: but anyway, okay So the ranks of the black or I think the reason I like it so much and why I'm kind of hyping it a little Bit.
Rym: is that any comic that tells a story from start to finish?
Rym: with no sequels no prequels no greater universe and Also simultaneously is serious and good Gets kind of like a plus 20 to the role of will Rym like it over any other comic.
Scott: It's like half the comics I own.
Scott: I know It seems like you haven't read that many comics that fit that category I have and all of them I on the show.
Rym: him like it was great.
Scott: There are many.
Rym: it was so great.
Scott: Okay?
Rym: So wait what this is about to to put it very simply is the Spanish Civil War Sucked.
Scott: no, like it was a war that sucked.
Scott: What is that good for?
Rym: Hey, what about those old like kind of fun sounding Greek wars where they'd kind of fight?
Scott: mercenaries would fight the real ones Or the mythological one the semi-real ones.
Scott: But it was my real completely real.
Rym: or as in like two mercenary armies would fight.
Rym: But the mercenaries were kind of friends with each other and would try not to kill each other and they'd sort of declare a winner.
Rym: It's more like a game.
Scott: You mean fencing?
Rym: No, yeah anyway, right.
Rym: but so yeah the Spanish Civil War was particularly shitty because one it kind of happened with this backdrop of the world between World War one and World War two and during World War two and the aftermath of World War Two and two it was pretty much two groups fighting mostly for the wrong reasons.
Rym: It was to paraphrase history Communists Anarchists and Republicans in a loose alliance fighting against fascists Nationalists and people who just wanted everything to be calm.
Rym: It wasn't a Spanish monarchy still around then Yes, and there was a military coup and Franco.
Rym: and do you know a lot about Spain?
Scott: most of my Spanish history knowledge is of Inquisition days, but pretty much what I know about the Spanish Civil War.
Rym: So the Reconquista?
Scott: Yes, also, I am well aware of issues in the Basque Country.
Rym: So the Spanish Civil War ending Basically meant open warfare stopped but grudges were maintained and villages were destroyed.
Rym: Spain had its own army shelling its own cities at many points.
Rym: It's a shitty war.
Rym: and this story takes place long after the Spanish Civil War is over and A lot of people who fought in it are old men and women.
Rym: So it opens with a bunch of these old men Coming into a small Basque village in the middle of nowhere in the middle of winter Systematically murdering every man woman and child in the town and burning it down.
Scott: whenever there's one of those villages in the middle of nowhere I'm somehow Reminded I don't know why of that Lupin movie where there's the village with all the treasures in the middle of nowhere.
Scott: That's empty.
Rym: Yeah, I am too Huh?
Rym: Can watch that Lupin again, which one was it fuck if I remember?
Rym: but I've got it.
Rym: Yeah, which one, you know, this is totally an aside.
Rym: But now that I've got that torrent of every Lupin ever I was looking through the nail like I think like out of the blue.
Scott: how many Lupin which is the one resented gotta lose this Job, I remember.
Rym: but if I try to think like how many discreet Lupin movies have I seen?
Rym: I'm like, I don't know six or seven, but then I look at this list I'm like most of that.
Rym: seen that seen that seen that yeah.
Rym: But anyway, so the other old men Who find out about this who also, you know fought in this day band together?
Rym: And so it's basically two Blues Brothers situations.
Rym: two groups get the band back together to sort of reenact the Spanish Civil War Long after the Spanish Civil War was done and long after all of them were in any shape to be going about this sort of business Right.
Scott: Well, it's basically, you know, two two different rival groups fought back in the day But then the war ended.
Scott: so they all went home.
Scott: But then one of them got the band back together and started killing people.
Scott: the other group found out about it.
Scott: So they had to get their band back together to counteract the band that already got back together.
Rym: But it has this sort of undertone that the they're not the main characters the you know So-called good guys who were Republican anarchist communist fighters fighting for the Republic during the Spanish Civil War.
Rym: they Don't really say they're fighting to save lives or to stop the plot by the other old men.
Rym: They're really fighting just because that's what you do.
Rym: Yeah, I mean those guys are fighting again.
Rym: So what can we do?
Rym: but stop them.
Scott: who else is gonna stop them?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: it's like, you know It's like who can they go to to tell anyone about them?
Scott: It's you know, it's like they can't just go and say hey military stop those guys.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: well in the modern, you know, you know, they know those guys more than anyone else true But in there's they know who it was, they can't really prove who it was, but they know 100% Yes.
Rym: But in this world, they could they could have been formed the police and there was a much more modern framework of justice.
Scott: Yes, but also there's a scene.
Scott: but also they would themselves be in trouble uncovering their own things.
Rym: Those things are so far in the past that it wouldn't have mattered nearly so much.
Rym: I think they're all respectable people in the modern era.
Scott: Yes while they're respectable though It's one of those typical situations where you had a life of horrible danger Who knows what and then you you know, it ended and you went to a normal life.
Scott: But really that normal life you never really wanted that.
Rym: no Yeah, that's that's what I'm saying that they could have responded to this in a very common story.
Rym: But rather than saying we're the only ones who can do it.
Rym: We got to save these people Their response was basically stop those fuckers.
Scott: Those are our rivals.
Scott: We must beat them.
Scott: and
Rym: it was a story of these people falling back into the roles that they fell into during the first war and it sort of puts the Futility and just absolute pointless waste of human life that the first Spanish Civil War was against this sort of second shadow war of old men fighting against shadows of other old men and It's pretty much just brutal and depressing all the way to the end.
Scott: The thing I like about it the most is how they never you know Forget at all that these are really old people right like.
Rym: they're way old 60 70 I mean, they try to get away on some bikes at one point and they can't.
Rym: Guys die of heart attacks right aneurysms.
Scott: Yep It's like, you know one guy's got like diseased all the time and some of them like the guy who jumps into the water.
Rym: He was doing pretty well.
Scott: Well, I think he was a little younger too, right dude the machine gun I like to yeah, but they were in very.
Scott: they were had varying ranges of physical fitness Just like old people are.
Scott: there's a dude.
Scott: I see freaking almost every morning.
Scott: He must.
Scott: he looks like fucking James Randi.
Scott: He's so old.
Rym: He's just freaking running down second Avenue man, and there I'll see dudes who are easily more than 80 years old skiing faster and better than I am on much harder trails that I could ever even dream of attempting.
Scott: right.
Scott: but I mean isn't more of skiing like skill and muscle memory than it would be say Strength and not that you don't need strength.
Rym: Yeah, but there there is strength involved.
Scott: Practicing would help more but runnings just straight-up running around the city this dude.
Rym: Ah, there is evidence that humans are primed to be able to run for the entirety of their lives.
Scott: That's good Yeah, but I mean a lot of old people can't even fucking walk.
Scott: So that's still badass.
Scott: Anyway, you know it never forgets that these guys are old and they're constantly suffering old people things all the time.
Rym: It's like a scene of action That's kind of sad and oldie on both sides and then a scene of them having to recover from the act.
Scott: Yeah, it's like what would it be like if old geezers are really chasing each other?
Scott: What would it be like if old geezers are really shooting at each other, but it's not chasing each other like get back here Shutty, it's like no, they're actually chasing each other, but both sides are old guys and they both have guns Or motorcycles or whatever they've got but they're all old and not they can't go so fast And there aren't really any young people involved to just come and hose them all down.
Scott: Yeah, so It's uh, it makes you think you know and at the one hand it, you know It's got that side plot of making you, you know, think about seniordom in your future.
Rym: Yep,
Scott: but if you make it that far
Rym: The only complaint I guess I could have about this entire story Is that the moral at the end and the way it's presented and the you know The message trying to get through is a really good message Except that the guys that these guys are trying to stop are Clearly bad guys.
Rym: Yeah, and the guys that tried to stop them while the conflict in the Spanish Civil War You know from a zoomed out perspective was pretty pointless and a waste of life.
Rym: the direct conflict here while it could have been handled better Was straight up a good thing to do if they truly believe that no one would have done it a different way But it was still a good thing to do.
Rym: Yeah, they're straight-up good guys, and it's not a bad if you're an old man.
Rym: It's not a bad way to go dying to save a whole bunch of lives.
Scott: Yeah I mean, it's like, you know, usually you would expect there'd be some sort of ambiguity like, you know Two groups of old guys come up to fight again years later, you know, and you're the story.
Scott: whatever, you know Whether it's a movie or TV show focuses on one of those groups.
Scott: So identify with that group and that group becomes the quote good guys.
Scott: But in reality at the end, you know the message is like oh look both of these sides were the same.
Scott: We just had the camera on one of them.
Scott: So you thought that one was the good one, but really they were identical and just at opposing viewpoints.
Scott: But no the friggin beginning of the book is the first group that got the band back together.
Scott: Frickin murders a town of people.
Scott: They're they're crazy evil terrorists who go around murdering.
Scott: They are bad guys regardless of whether you agree with one political ideology of the other And you probably also agree with the political ideology of the main characters anyway Because it doesn't involve terrorism.
Rym: But you know, for example, there's that scene in the market where they try to stop the assassination and they have a shootout and You know, the police actually show up pretty quick like the tip-off could have worked.
Rym: But through that whole scene all I could think was counter-strike.
Scott: It wasn't in Italy though, that was.
Rym: was it that far was?
Scott: I don't know I Forget.
Scott: they were always.
Scott: basically as far as I could remember in Generic European place is not the market from counter-strike it is.
Rym: But I mean, you know, but no this is a great little comic and I don't know how easy it is to get But I found it on Amazon with one review.
Scott: So all right, it is Theoretically obtainable and we're revving can't obtain it.
Rym: go to Zumba calm where the unattainable is attainable, so There's probably only about a week's more worth of GeekNights episodes before.
Rym: who knows that the fuck's gonna happen between me going back to Turkey and Scott going to DC and all of us going to Seattle?
Rym: Let me look and I might have to go to Munich again and maybe Frankfurt.
Rym: Okay, baby Warsaw.
Scott: Yes That's Rym is about right.
Scott: There's gonna be pretty much next week.
Scott: There will be I guess a Tuesday Thursday episodes.
Scott: now several of you and then after that.
Scott: who knows?
Rym: I've gotten some responses already on people who want to do guest episodes.
Rym: So by this weekend I will get to all of you who have asked a care package of everything you will need to make a Episode of GeekNights, you'll get to our sound clips.
Rym: No, these sound clips will not tell you what the songs are.
Rym: you still have to figure those out except our opening theme Which is booster Tarantino used with permission.
Scott: The other songs aren't used with permission.
Rym: No, they're totally not.
Rym: Fair use is what I will argue to the grave.
Scott: The grave is a really end up.
Scott: You're homeless and they see.
Rym: I Hope I don't look like any of the characters in this comic when I'm that old.
Scott: Oh, yeah also atomic trivia war 9,000 is recording tomorrow with me again.
Scott: Oh shit, but then I guess it's gonna air a week later or a week after that.
Scott: Who knows?
Rym: I don't know when they're.
Rym: I was on one a long time ago, but I forgot about it after I've been on two so this will be number three.
Scott: also somebody put together a nice like stats thing of like who's been the best and On many.
Scott: even only having been on two episodes.
Rym: I am among the greatest Trivia, I wish it was more quiz bully though because I got to say when I was on I knew a lot of the answers to other people's baby questions.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much what it comes down to for me is if it is a topic that's like something I do not know like Star Trek questions.
Scott: Yeah, I'm gonna fail this big time, right?
Scott: Cuz I don't know Star Trek, but if it's something I know Watch out.
Rym: Okay counter-strike time.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music Can't leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.