Rym: Hey, it's Tuesday, October 16th, 2012.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight Genoa the traitors of Let's do this.
Rym: So I found the secret to beating FTL pretty much 90% of the time.
Rym: cheating on easy.
Rym: cheating on easy Just like fucking max out your shield.
Rym: just go for it like you can't lose.
Scott: I've gotten to the boss of max shields four or five times.
Scott: I know what.
Rym: no weapons.
Scott: I had plenty of weapons and I was still unable to beat the boss.
Rym: the saddest thing that ever happened to me.
Rym: Those like I've never won using like the crew teleporter II thing.
Rym: I only really tried to do.
Scott: I've only recently learned how to use that without fucking yourself.
Scott: But the problem with it is is you fuck up once with it and you're done.
Rym: It's how you're like, all right I've got one dude.
Scott: It's like I got really.
Scott: I finally got really good at using it.
Scott: I leveled it up and everything and I was going in and I had I had you know mantises and rock men to attack with.
Scott: So I'm sending them over and beating them up.
Scott: I'm destroying ships without killing, you know with only killing the cruise.
Rym: Yeah, I've been doing that mostly with the oxygen.
Rym: like I'll just I unblast the oxygen until they die.
Scott: That doesn't even work for me because they just keep fucking repairing it.
Scott: I need to actually kill their people so that they can't repair the.
Rym: I have killed many a ship just by letting the oxygen run Out.
Scott: I've tried that.
Scott: just shoot ion at the oxygen and wait with such defense.
Scott: They can't hurt me.
Scott: Thanks a while, but it works and they just repair it as fast as I shoot it.
Rym: If you keep shooting you'll kill the guys in there and not with ion can use like a bomb.
Scott: But if I shoot it with any weapon bombs don't damage the hull.
Scott: I got to get a bomb.
Rym: Yes, I get a bomb again.
Scott: You had to use the missiles.
Rym: Then I gotta get four gameboys and I gotta get four links.
Scott: I can never seem to get the stuff that I you know into.
Scott: it's like for example one game I played and I was the Engi ships.
Scott: you start with the drone, right?
Scott: Oh, yeah, and then at the first Shop there's another anti-ship drone.
Rym: Yeah, I ship drones.
Scott: Fuck.
Scott: Yeah, so I'm like fuck Yeah, and I buy that shit right and I keep going along and I'm keep.
Scott: you know I'm starting to run out of drone parts Even though I tried to get as many as I could and anytime I had an option to like trade missiles for drone parts I did so.
Scott: such like that, right?
Scott: Yeah, and I'm going along with my drone parts and I you know I got a weapon to accompany my own cannon and things are going.
Scott: nice I'm I just I can blow through the regular game up until the boss a hundred percent easily every time on easy no matter what right but Throughout this game for I was like, I really need that thing that you know The drone the drone part collector.
Scott: so I have to so I can stop buying Every time I get that I.
Rym: Somehow that means I'll have like 80 drone parts by the end.
Scott: Yeah But it's better than having to spend Scrap on drone part.
Rym: you only need that if you're doing what I'm doing where you're busting out like three drones every fight.
Scott: Yeah, I was dry.
Scott: I was busting out like two three drones every fight.
Scott: I actually found another anti-ship drone, but I never found the drone collect II thing.
Scott: and then of course You know by the end of the game I had my shields all the way up But I didn't have my engines up as much as I wanted because I had to spend so much scrap on freaking drone parts Right.
Scott: Well, don't use the drones as much But I had to to kill the bad guys.
Rym: No, you gotta have some regular weapons.
Scott: I did have regular weapons, but the other problem was is I had to to power all three drones simultaneously Which I knew I was gonna need to beat the boss.
Scott: I needed to upgrade the drone section to hold six energy random aside.
Scott: We gotta add six energy to the thing.
Rym: I gotta isolate that simultaneously grab and make a.
Scott: so because I had to put so much of my scrap into upgrading the drone section and buying drones I Wasn't able.
Scott: I actually picked up like a crazy awesome weapon, but it required for energy.
Scott: I got the weapon for free and I could did.
Scott: there was impossible to power that weapon.
Rym: What do you saw that screenshot?
Rym: I had like four fucking giant weapons.
Scott: It was not possible to power all that stuff.
Scott: No The way you didn't get it up straight is I lost all that scrap to buying.
Rym: You're like power down those engines and oxygen and then power up the weapons.
Scott: do a big burst if that You know and then of course I can.
Scott: I get to the end of the game.
Scott: I fight the boss, but I can't beat him because they can't power all the things.
Scott: and then right I died the boss.
Rym: Yeah, I've never used crew teleporter against the boss.
Rym: I want to try that.
Scott: cuz I think I did and you know what happened.
Scott: It was actually working really awesome.
Rym: You know what I do.
Rym: what I want to do is send got like a rock man into like the weapon pod.
Scott: Yeah, it was working really awesomely.
Scott: right in the first go I just shredded him up right and in the second go I sent him over there and I was also shredding him up.
Rym: I want like but then boarding drone.
Scott: it only took.
Scott: Drones would be a lot better for boarding drone.
Scott: No, ain't.
Scott: But then I just fucked up a little bit right like one slip up and suddenly your teleporter is broken and you're trying to Repair it.
Scott: but then you got to repair your oxygen because your ship is gonna die.
Scott: So then suddenly you're scrambling to fix your ship.
Scott: Meanwhile, your two guys are suffocating over in the boss.
Rym: She's got you know what and then it's all right now.
Rym: I know how all those other ships felt.
Scott: I basically I can get to the boss almost 100% of the time on easy 99% of the time.
Scott: I Had it all set up.
Scott: I had the drone collecti bit.
Scott: I had three anti-ship drones.
Scott: I had plenty of.
Rym: Get rid of the drone collecti bullshit and put something else there.
Scott: There was nothing for sale there.
Scott: There's no shop.
Rym: There's multiple shops before the fat last zone.
Scott: There was not a shop that was selling a Augmentation of any kind in the last two lines.
Scott: now I was looking for one in the final sector cuz I knew that I didn't need this thing anymore.
Scott: There was not one available.
Scott: All right, and then it was fine.
Scott: I beat the first section of the boss.
Scott: I'd be the second section of the boss easily but then the third section.
Scott: I had so little small amount of hull and no way to repair it because the randomness of the map drawing in the final sector Right put all three repairs next to the base.
Rym: I've never bothered with repairs.
Scott: and then No, but not only that in order to fly to the boss I had to fly through two of the repairs wasting them when I was already fully healed.
Rym: and then after this I just wait.
Rym: there's an option to not jump just wait Hold on.
Scott: I can't just wait.
Scott: you have to go out to fight the boss.
Rym: He'll come to you.
Scott: No, you can't just wait at the base.
Scott: You have to go out at least a little bit go out a little bit and then wait a little bit.
Scott: I had to immediately.
Scott: the only physical star I could go to was the repair star And was because of the random generation.
Scott: I'm telling you this there was no way to go.
Scott: I in or the only way out of the base was through a minimum of Two repair stars got it.
Scott: You know other way to go.
Rym: You're not being trolled if someone flipped like the bullshit bit on your computer.
Scott: I'm telling you because I have not it.
Rym: we need to play this together.
Rym: We need to do a Dave and Joel style stream of like this have Every time there is some like one random bullshit that prevents me from beating the boss.
Rym: Meanwhile I play every time and it's like hey, I'm a rock man.
Rym: I'd like to join your crew.
Rym: Hey.
Scott: I'm a rock man.
Scott: I like yeah, you know what happens to me.
Scott: Hey.
Scott: I'm a rock man like to join your crew awesome.
Scott: Hey, I'm a mantis like to join your crew awesome.
Scott: Hey There's an old man.
Scott: Would you like to try to bring him up to join your crew?
Scott: and I'm like hell.
Scott: You know.
Scott: I know this doesn't work sometimes, but how can I pass up a possibly free crew member yes?
Scott: Yeah, not only does he die he kills one of your crew members who went to get him restart.
Rym: So the saddest thing that ever happened.
Rym: it happened recently.
Rym: I was trying the whole like teleporting crew thing in this game.
Rym: I didn't finish.
Rym: so I teleport most of my crew over to the enemy ship and they're fucking it up And everything's going great, and then out of nowhere.
Rym: It's like they're charging up their FTL.
Scott: So you gotta shoot you gotta shoot the pilot so they can't go.
Rym: so I pause.
Rym: I'm like no biggie.
Rym: No biggie No, I couldn't teleport him back because I'd been ion hit.
Rym: But I put two ion cannons at the pilot And I targeted the engine.
Rym: and just it happened to be chance.
Rym: three full sets of volleys all Missed and then the ship disappeared with my entire crew.
Scott: yeah, there's a video I watched showing final boss strategy and this guy.
Scott: he had stealth He had full shield he had crazy awesome burst lasers right and he had the the hull beam right and his strategy Was this seems pretty good genius strategy?
Scott: He had right he was operating.
Scott: he was using the real-time nature of the game right to his advantage.
Scott: What he would do is he would go up against the boss.
Scott: When the boss is that he would pause all the time like crazy.
Scott: if the boss was about to fire That's when he'd activate the stuff right.
Scott: so all the missiles passed over him when he had all of his way Wasn't auto firing either.
Scott: when all his weapons were charged He would fire all the beams all at once like doo doo doo doo doom And if they all hit the shield would be down to nothing.
Scott: and then you would you have it paused already because he basically be Like fire.
Scott: pause Right.
Scott: if the shields were 100% down you immediately fire the hull beam in this really precise way that did as much damage as humanly possible across like Multiple.
Rym: that's the only reason I use beam weapons because I really like drawing that line right.
Scott: so he draws that line perfectly every time.
Scott: So he does for the maximum effect.
Rym: You know it's weird.
Rym: There's a few things that really get me going in games, and it's basically Maximizing damage with the mechanic literally like one pixel of the line is in one section of the other guy.
Scott: So that an inventory Tetris, so then you know it worked most of the time right.
Scott: and if the if the if the burst weapons Didn't break through the shield he would just sort of keep defending until the next.
Scott: you know Chant when I can tell the weapons were charged again And he just kept doing this and it totally worked.
Scott: and it totally worked, and I was like this is genius.
Scott: How could he lose with this?
Scott: and then of course random bullshit up?
Scott: And all the drones come out of the boss and his stealth wasn't charged yet, and that's the problem.
Scott: Don't use fucking stealth, but he also had max shields.
Rym: It wasn't like fuck stealth Stealth or four crazy weapons and three drones all the same.
Scott: He had all that he had.
Scott: you should see he had everything you need to have.
Scott: it's just random bullshit I don't know.
Rym: I win the majority of the times that play on easy and normal is not that hard either.
Rym: It's bullshit anyway.
Scott: He's already did a show on this.
Scott: so here's that ism gaming news.
Scott: all right Monica what you've been waiting for for yours is mine three or four years.
Rym: Oh my god Shats has been on gig nights before yes two years ago.
Scott: Yeah I can officially announce that Monica was.
Scott: yours is mine my little handmade game You've been waiting for three years to play will be available the way is meant to be played on your couch in your living room.
Scott: It's gonna be on Xbox Live and PC which we sort of knew.
Rym: wait so it's gonna be on PC.
Scott: That's on on the same exact day.
Scott: simultaneous release Unannounced date.
Scott: that is a very soon date.
Rym: finally I've been waiting for this game for a while now.
Rym: What's it?
Rym: It's not interesting, but I've realized I don't use my fucking Xbox for anything except Netflix anymore.
Rym: I Don't use the Xbox for anything else, and I'm not gonna renew my xbox gold.
Rym: no I don't even know when it expires, but I see no Conceivable reason to buy this.
Rym: an Xbox over PC no Xbox.
Scott: if you're one of those dumb people who doesn't have a computer attached to your television Yeah, but then I can't play it on my laptop.
Scott: It's like people don't have this.
Scott: you know.
Scott: realization that like it's like oh, I want to play it on my TV So I'm gonna get an Xbox.
Scott: even the angry video game nerd was like yeah I don't like emulators cuz they can't blame.
Scott: my team will plug a fucking computer in your TV like a normal person.
Rym: how many times You have to say this In my entire life, and I'll be perfectly honest as a hardcore gamer as all these things in my entire life.
Rym: I have maybe two or three regrets in Everything I've ever done in the last 30 years.
Rym: one of them is buying an Xbox 360.
Scott: I don't necessarily regret it, but it's like I regret it.
Scott: I would have been fine not doing so.
Rym: I would rather have owned Super Street Fighter 4 on the computer.
Scott: Yeah, well.
Scott: I don't think it's super on the computer.
Scott: I don't know regular is on the computer.
Rym: I would have been okay with not owning the game as much as I'm really pac-man.
Scott: I just like.
Scott: I wouldn't want to live without that pac-man But I haven't played that pac-man in months.
Scott: that pac-man is not worth the amount of money in Xbox costs even though That pac-man.
Scott: oh my god.
Rym: Seriously though I'm way excited about Monaco because the version of this game that we played at Pax - over two years ago was already enough for me to throw like 40 bucks at him.
Rym: So I can't imagine what it's like now, but I can because at the last packs where I saw it I didn't play it, but every time I walked by that booth the people standing at the booth were screaming while they were playing.
Scott: I've only ever seen that booth crowded and screaming.
Rym: Yeah, it's just people yelling and screaming and curse.
Rym: Oh my god the game looks so good.
Rym: so Xcom.
Rym: as you all know the new xcom is out, but it's 50 bucks.
Scott: fuck that.
Rym: now The thing is the game is probably worth 50 bucks.
Scott: play the demo not worth 50 bucks But it is xcom now a lot easier to play too because the interface is modern It's interesting and it says a lot about the game industry.
Rym: now It's funny because I what I'm about to say is basically the same thing I was saying about anime.
Scott: in the same thing you say about everything not everything, but anime.
Rym: in 2005 you're consistent.
Rym: When in 2005 I was like yeah, X is a really good show X being pot You know.
Rym: and I guess I should say I don't want to talk about X the anime But you know why.
Rym: I guess that's also an anime.
Scott: no East is the east.
Scott: wow is pronounced.
Rym: I see wanderers for me anyway, so I Like a show a lot.
Rym: I would consider a show like the count of money.
Rym: crystal was an excellent example.
Rym: that show was great.
Rym: It was like a b-plus a-minus anime.
Rym: I love the shit out of it and the DVD box that came out and Later, I saw it on sale on Amazon for like six bucks.
Rym: Yeah, and I looked at I'm like holy shit six bucks Didn't even fucking buy it.
Rym: so as xcom is like one of the poster childs of a game made in 1994 that somehow in all these years no one was able to remake correctly until Xcom is one of the formative games of my life.
Scott: It's your jam one of my favorite common bands who ever buy on a commando.
Scott: Those are rims three jams.
Rym: So let's name all the xcom games 1994 xcom enemy unknown.
Rym: the real one one of the best games ever.
Rym: 1995 xcom terror from the deep shit.
Rym: xcom apocalypse.
Rym: Xcom interceptor not even an xcom game.
Rym: xcom first alien in big.
Rym: seriously has bro.
Rym: Xcom enforcer I've never even heard of.
Scott: that's a third-person shooter.
Scott: That's the worst xcom.
Rym: Genesis was cancelled As was xcom Alliance and then xcom enemy unknown.
Scott: in 2012 I think there was actually one that was I think was excellent.
Scott: apocalypse.
Scott: Maybe was the one that was closest the closest.
Scott: it actually played like the original xcom But it was some more modern.
Scott: It just didn't.
Rym: it was not a good.
Scott: It was not as good as it did any.
Scott: it didn't have the base part.
Rym: It was just the base parts the only part I care about right, but anyway, so despite even not you know That's not even counting the like dozen open source like attempts by game people to make the unreal tournament mod laser.
Scott: They were all awful and no one finished working on any of them.
Rym: so thus the conundrum of the gaming industry.
Rym: We gave a lecture at PAX.
Rym: We don't have a video of a long time ago called egregiously unrealized potential where we talked about like how?
Rym: Games like xcom or chrono trigger.
Rym: just nobody fucking remakes and nobody just does it right.
Scott: well They did.
Rym: it's like people don't understand the essence of what made these games good.
Rym: and here It is a perfect example of just doing exactly what I've been saying people should do for a decade And I can't be asked to pay 50 bucks for it's a lot of fucking money.
Scott: buying a commando rearm.
Scott: It was 20 I 50 bucks.
Rym: I'll blow that on dinner and not even think but that's dinner.
Rym: Also, this is my jam.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: a lot of money for xcom.
Scott: I don't think it is what I mean.
Scott: what video game?
Rym: when I got I paid $70 for Zelda 2 $65 for Mario 3.
Scott: xcom is a single-player game.
Scott: if I bought it or someone gave it to me for free I'd play it through and probably stop playing.
Scott: It's a multiplayer component, but it doesn't seem like a good multi-player component one.
Scott: That's worth playing a lot.
Rym: xcom UFO defense.
Rym: I Pirated.
Rym: I didn't pay anything for it.
Rym: in fact It was the first game I ever pirated on purpose, and I played it without an instruction book which was extra awesome, but Like one day I figured out I could duck and I was like oh
Scott: Yeah, but the point is
Rym: but I got maybe I don't know 4,000 hours of entertainment out of that game.
Rym: I played it as much as I played.
Scott: sieve fucking - I'm telling you is a Counter-strike.
Scott: global offensive was 14 and change.
Scott: So xcom does not hold a candle to that shit, so he can't charge me Multiple times the car.
Rym: But you're saying that not worth 50 bucks.
Rym: Here's my problem 50 bucks the price.
Rym: it could be a thousand dollars and have the same discussion.
Rym: the problem is simply Once again, I look at my steam profiler.
Rym: I mean I got steam open right now.
Rym: What games have I never even installed?
Rym: most area Battlefield 2 bad company.
Scott: Why do you even buy battlefield?
Rym: I think I got it like a dollar.
Rym: I uninstalled Bioshock and Borderlands.
Rym: I've never actually played braid on this computer.
Rym: Dave defeat I don't know how I got that all our three ideas is a half-life 1 mod your grandfathered in.
Rym: I have played Europa Universalis 3 a couple of times couple times Let's see Magica.
Rym: I haven't even installed Machinarium Lugaru loom.
Rym: I. I've got enough games to last me a decade right unplayed.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: It's a supply and demand of all Games regardless of what the game is, but this is the problem.
Rym: a game that is both rims Personal direct jam done correctly and done the way he specified well close enough at least won't play it.
Rym: What do we do about this?
Scott: Don't charge 50 fucking dollars.
Rym: if it was free.
Scott: I still wouldn't be playing it right now, but you would have downloaded it.
Scott: Yeah, I wouldn't be playing it If it was a dollar.
Scott: you would have paid the dollar.
Rym: even I wouldn't be playing.
Scott: you still would have paid the dollar And you'd play it eventually.
Rym: what does it take for me to play a game that isn't Counter-Strike?
Rym: I mean it might take a New advanced wars on a computer.
Rym: Oh, yeah, I might do it.
Rym: Anyway, you know.
Rym: sort of brief news that we can go on.
Scott: So another thing it takes to get someone.
Scott: I mean you're gonna you would play it eventually, right?
Scott: The question really is what would it take to get you to play the game now, right?
Scott: To get to play the game now.
Scott: There has to be a reason to play it now as opposed to at some point later in my life Which means there needs to be some sort of?
Scott: multiplayer Community some some component where playing it this instant is actually different like tribes do.
Scott: if you didn't play it when it came out Well, you didn't play now.
Rym: It's interesting is that there was a time Like when Dave's X came out human revolution a lot of the people I talked to and hang out with on the internet.
Rym: We're all playing it right away.
Rym: So I was missing out on that and when I finally played it.
Scott: I don't know why people are so concerned missing out on no.
Scott: No, I'm missing out on the talking The shared Experience and dialogue of like.
Rym: like like the Dave and Joel it hasn't gone anywhere.
Scott: Those people still had that experience and still remember it and you can talk about it with them later when you have it.
Rym: Also, yeah, and then it becomes like our crew where we want it.
Rym: You know someone else starts reading The Prince of Nothing and wants to talk about and everyone else is like fuck.
Scott: Talk about that anytime.
Rym: But anyway, let's talk about it right now, but now Most of the people I talked to online except for the people who don't have jobs or are still in college or Don't have anything else going on.
Rym: They're the only ones who play single-player games Except Dave and Joel, I guess.
Scott: well, you know game reviewer type people and stuff like that.
Rym: We're game reviewer type people.
Scott: We're not paid to do it.
Rym: nor is it our primary Argue that most people are not effectively paid to do it.
Scott: Well, imagine this right Rym.
Scott: if we didn't if we didn't care about anime manga comics technology or anything.
Scott: But video games now board games no role-playing games.
Scott: I Imagine we would be paying 50 bucks for xcom and doing alright.
Scott: And I think there's just a lot of people out there that you know We interact with.
Scott: and you sort of forget that these people, you know They might dabble in some comics and read some webcomics.
Scott: so they might you know, but it's like they're Mostly in video games, right?
Scott: It's like that is you know, if you if you divide made a little percentage chart of like how much of them is each geekery?
Scott: It's like, you know video games would be over 50 60 percent.
Scott: Well, it is.
Scott: It's more even ways.
Scott: it's like 25 25 15 10, right?
Scott: There's nothing.
Scott: there's no hot geekery that I have That's even over 25%.
Rym: so yeah, but I guess case in point look at Otakon the.
Rym: you know, we were guests of Otakon doing lectures for almost a decade and We did a lot of them.
Rym: one year We did like five.
Rym: the biggest and most popular thing we ever did at an Otakon was beyond Dungeons and Dragons.
Rym: Gaming is the most popular thing at the biggest anime convention in America.
Rym: Mmm, it says a lot.
Rym: I think that says more about anime than about gaming now.
Rym: So anyway very briefly, you know, the New York Comic Con happened and as you know, we didn't go for the first time For the second time.
Scott: we didn't go to the very first one.
Rym: Yeah We couldn't though that the guests could go to the first one to go to the first.
Rym: the guests of the convention could not get Into the first New York Comic Con.
Rym: But no I went to everyone after that and I did not go to this one despite having a free badge.
Rym: And it's interesting that when I looked over You know the comic part of it had some interesting stuff going on, but anime is gone.
Rym: There's no anime there and Gaming is also gone.
Rym: Yeah, based on the online coverage right a lot of the kind of show has been replaced by TV.
Rym: It's SDCC light.
Scott: Yeah, so but looking at the online coverage it's.
Scott: they showed a clip of the first episode of ponies Which I got to see on the internet.
Scott: Yep, and to There was.
Scott: There was this.
Scott: I think there's the usual.
Scott: the Gundam booth is always awesome But someone took pictures of every Gundam in it.
Rym: So there was like this e-level mezzanine where all the anime kids and all the people who sit on the floor at cons sat on the floor right.
Scott: and then the only thing that I could tell from the internet that I missed at this
Rym: con
Scott: right is
Rym: the security line because now they were searching bags to let people in that
Scott: and Be if you read bakuman There is a manga within the manga of bakuman no dog called ocelot number an otter number 11 and they had there they were giving away Otter number 11 like the spin-off which is sort of the same.
Scott: It's sort of the same ideas like kuji biki unbalanced.
Rym: You know.
Rym: you could do Scott if you really wanted it because way back when I I could easily get it if I wanted to.
Rym: Yes, yeah, cuz when I really wanted that that pit boy.
Scott: Multiple listeners send me their pit boys if anyone's gonna copy about her number 11 It makes Scott really don't even need to send it to me.
Scott: Just scan it in and send me some JPEGs or send me a link to the JPEGs or whatever.
Scott: I just want to read it.
Scott: I don't need to have it.
Scott: I don't need more shit my house, but I don't know It's just.
Rym: it's interesting because I had some conversations with a lot of different people related to the or comic-con a couple years ago And the sentiment then was very directly Increased.
Rym: the gaming industry and gaming content at the New York comic-con.
Rym: There was a big internal push for that and then all those people one by one Stop talking about it with me and then stop talking to me and then all the gaming content of the New York comic-con disappeared.
Scott: Yeah, and I know those Watson is still there though And I'm pretty sure there's still a few booths that belong to various games like a crane was there.
Rym: but the gaming content at the New York comic-con has diminished substantially and As opposed to increase dramatically, which was what people specifically said they were going to do.
Rym: So I'm curious Who at read pop made the call of you know what?
Rym: Let's just try to be a shit here.
Scott: I guess they don't want to overlap with packs and they want to make money.
Scott: right and you think about it.
Scott: Well, if we have a booth, yeah a booth selling comics makes more dollars Oh foot.
Scott: then a table for tabletop replay does yeah, which makes zero dollars per square foot.
Rym: But then you have the you know, the interesting incentive of you don't want people to stay in the convention for three days.
Rym: You'd rather have three different people come for a few hours on three different day, right?
Scott: Because if three different people come then it's you know, that's that's more customers per booth.
Scott: So all the exhibitors will make more money.
Scott: and if the exhibitors make more money You can charge more money for the tables.
Scott: and you know, so it's like oh that comment that guy just selling his comics You know from kind of came in from New Jersey Makes five hundred dollars.
Scott: You can't sell him a table over five hundred dollars.
Scott: Anyway, that if he makes five thousand you can sell him a table over one thousand.
Rym: We'll talk about that later.
Rym: That's kind of a separate show because it's basically look at packs and Otakon and the New York Comic Con like those three between all three of them show like the three possible directions the convention.
Scott: the one thing about the con is like It's if you want to buy some stuff they have stuff that you know It's.
Scott: I guess it'd be convenient especially because I live here.
Scott: but the cost Getting in Outways the cost of you know, makes it not economical to buy anything.
Scott: It's like yeah, I'm gonna buy a badge just to buy stuff.
Scott: Oh, maybe they just buy this stuff online.
Rym: Maybe this is something really snarky and self-centered to say I kind of forget unless I think about it that conventions cost money.
Scott: It's also think about all these people a lot of people I talked to go to the con.
Scott: I even talked to someone who was thinking about just standing outside the con because it's like all they just wanted to do was sort of like, you know Goggle and gaggle at people in costumes at the you know, and it's like we're just so jaded.
Scott: It's not worth anything to us anymore.
Rym: But to a lot of if it's it's to a lot of years of Otakon that did that to us.
Scott: to a lot of people they just go to it and just being there and seeing all the nerdiness and costumes and craziness is like Whoa, it's that would.
Rym: it's so fun for them.
Scott: But for us that's like you'd have to pay me to do it.
Scott: It's like I've done that so many times.
Rym: that would you could not Know value for me whatsoever.
Rym: the people I know who are the most excited about it Don't go to many cons or don't live in New York City.
Rym: Yeah, and I realized I mean think about it 2002.
Rym: I went to my first anime convention and my mind was blown.
Rym: 2003 jaded.
Rym: Yeah, I'd seen it all.
Scott: Yeah, it's like I walk in.
Scott: it's like people You know like you go in.
Scott: and is that giant inflated Adventure Time?
Scott: Whatever a lot of Adventure Time fans are like, oh my god, so awesome.
Scott: Holy shit.
Scott: Take my picture with it And I'm just like.
Scott: no, I don't even notice that is there unless you point it out to me.
Rym: It's like oh, hey, it's that inflated thing.
Rym: They had at the other the last 11 conventions.
Rym: We attended exactly.
Rym: Yeah, if I even notice it at all, I remember the last New York anime festival that happened.
Rym: We literally showed up Did our lecture and walked out like immediately?
Scott: Someone told me the other I forget who it was maybe a week or two ago and they were like, yeah I was got on this train and these oh it was.
Scott: uh my dad's friend from Connecticut and he talked about how he went to the city for Yankees game and he was on the subway and Some dudes came on the subway and started breakdancing.
Scott: and I'm like, why did you even look at them?
Scott: And he like he actually gave him money.
Scott: and I'm like what?
Scott: I'm like, dude If that he like people come on and they'll be like a mariachi band on the subway and I don't even know that they were There.
Rym: no good thing for those of you don't live in New York.
Rym: That is Scott is not in any way.
Rym: It's not like a I don't know an exaggeration or a silly.
Rym: Literally, it'll be my morning commute and an entire mariachi band of like six people will come from another subway car into my subway car and play an entire song and No one even notices.
Scott: Yep Like if I got my headphones in I might not even know that they I might.
Scott: you know It's like I won't react to it usually but I'll notice it.
Scott: I got mariachi band right and just go back to what I was doing and ignore them.
Scott: But like if I got headphones in There's a good chance that they would come in and leave and I would and like I wouldn't even know that they were there in the first place.
Rym: But anyway things of the day Try not to do like pony mashups because you know I've anyone who cares about.
Rym: those have seen them all by this point and Gangnam style.
Rym: I would Is also something that I would say I don't need to do anymore but This is just such an unexpected and unexpectedly delightful mashup.
Rym: It's Ghostbusters.
Scott: It's flawed slightly, but it's still good enough to be awesome.
Rym: It's pretty great.
Rym: And the thing is you're gonna watch it and all you're gonna want to do is watch Ghostbusters again.
Scott: Yeah So imagine if you know you were watching like a cartoon of like Superman, right and Superman went.
Scott: he like flew away Right and he changed his clothes really fast.
Scott: Imagine if you're walking down the street and you saw someone do that you would be like No, I wouldn't.
Rym: it's New York.
Rym: I see shit like that every day.
Scott: You don't see somebody change their clothes faster than someone could humanly possibly change their clothes and then fly.
Scott: I saw a hobo stripping naked and changing clothes not as fast as Superman nor did he fly afterwards?
Rym: He was lingering a little bit, right?
Scott: So imagine if you're walking on the street, you know.
Scott: And you saw a cartoon and it was Batman with his little grappling hook going whoosh and then jumping across Buildings that were way too far apart now Grappling hook right for any human being to possibly jump, but he did it anyway, right?
Scott: Well, if you saw that happen in real life You'd be and what they weren't using wires or like on a movie set you'd be like, whoa What the fuck even in New York, right?
Scott: Yeah Here's a video of somebody doing something that you would normally consider to be almost superhuman But he actually just does it straight up.
Scott: I'm not really a big fan of playing the game Metal Gear Solid but in Metal Gear Solid I know there was a character and his name is Revolver Ocelot.
Rym: Do you know anything about Revolver Ocelot?
Rym: I
Scott: know that he is a dude who is really fucking good with revolvers and he's also a boss in the game and there are many cutscenes in which he spins his revolvers a great deal like whoosh whoosh whoosh whoosh whoosh whoosh in a way that if you watch, you know in the video game where it's just a You know computer-generated graphics right would appear to be basically impossible for a real person to do.
Scott: They are not impossible for real person to do.
Scott: this guy made a YouTube video of him spinning his revolvers and doing the 100% exact same thing the Revolver Ocelot does in the cutscenes of the video game.
Scott: He is a master of revolver spinning.
Scott: He is so good at it.
Scott: He is as good as a fictionally super powered character at doing this.
Rym: Good God.
Rym: the article on Revolver Ocelot has 33 citations in Wikipedia, right?
Scott: But the point is that this guy is as good as a fictional Theoretically super powered character at a thing.
Scott: Hence my analogies of Superman and Batman.
Rym: So in the meta moment this Friday is the nerd NYC board game night.
Rym: Friday, October 19th 7 p.m To 11 p.m.
Rym: At think coffee at 3rd and Mercer New York City I'll probably be there along with the other Scott and maybe this Scott.
Scott: Oh, really?
Scott: He's gonna be here that early, huh?
Scott: Like Friday afternoon I'm going to work.
Rym: they're taking Friday off.
Rym: They're gonna dinker around in the New York's.
Scott: Smart people move here like smart people.
Rym: Yeah Or dies trying right and the weekend after that Nothing's happening.
Rym: Nope, and then the weekend after that Actually, no the weekend after that is burning kind is Burning on.
Scott: you cannot register for burning con anymore.
Scott: It's closed.
Rym: Wait, it says click here to register.
Scott: I'm pretty sure.
Scott: Luke said two days left in that second day.
Scott: Well, I Appear to still be able to register and he was on his Twitter.
Scott: He said two days left to register for burning come either.
Rym: He forgot to turn it off or something.
Scott: That's possible.
Scott: Anyway, he was at the New York Comic Con.
Rym: burning on October 26th 27th and 28th is A gaming convention that is curated.
Rym: what that means is you can only run games from the people who are hosting it the triad I'm for it.
Rym: Yep, and You have to run a game to play in a game.
Rym: You can't even attend if you're not running, right?
Scott: There's multiple sessions per day and you basically if you go both days You have to you.
Scott: basically you're gonna run one session at some point on day one or day two And then the rest of the sessions you just play.
Rym: So it's gonna be a great time if any of you are going to be there Great time the last two times because we will be there.
Scott: I'm running again as I have run many times at events like this into the mountain the arc of Running a scenario that I'm still polishing, you know minds about and it's still not gonna be fully polished.
Scott: I'm gonna basically finish polishing it when it's being played.
Rym: Mine is about an arc filled with obscenities.
Scott: mine is about a. You're basically a bunch of merchants in a town and this is a knigget and he kills an awesome monster of some kind and has A mad treasure.
Scott: He brings the treasure back to the town and all the merchants fucking want it.
Rym: The last time I ran into the mountain the entire party died, but felt very satisfied.
Rym: The time before that the party destroyed the entire world and the time before that I think they all died screaming Mmm, like I think every one of them was screaming when they died anyway.
Scott: But yeah, I know some burning con.
Scott: a lot of people sort of chicken out because they're afraid to run a game Even if they really know how to play.
Rym: Seriously, I go to a lot of cons man up pussies.
Rym: best majority of people who run games at conventions suck Acid.
Rym: game mastering you will be fine.
Scott: Yeah, no one's gonna hate on you They're just.
Scott: you know, people really suck at this shit.
Rym: You will not stand out.
Scott: even the people you think are really good.
Scott: No, they suck too.
Scott: There's like said Luke Ryan.
Rym: He's really good.
Scott: It's like three people who are any good.
Scott: Yeah, everyone else sucks also And you know what?
Rym: I think I'm pretty shit your shit.
Scott: There's a. I've been told I'm a shit and I thought I was shit.
Scott: But then once I was told I was good only one time or two times.
Rym: I was told at the last Two recesses ago three recess some some recess that I ran the best game The one of the people had ever played in a recess ever.
Rym: Anyway, I was very proud of that.
Scott: There is a beginners track which I guess you may or may not be able to still sign up for Where you actually spend one day learning in one day playing.
Scott: so that's not too bad.
Scott: If you don't know what you do and and you're a pussy, it's gonna be a good time.
Rym: But uh, let's see Saturday and Sunday is gaming and Friday is the party, right?
Scott: I think there might be after an official after party.
Scott: I don't know whatever.
Rym: I think I'm gonna go to all pre and post parties.
Scott: I'm also.
Scott: I did.
Rym: why didn't I do it?
Scott: We did.
Scott: we went to that bar that was upstairs.
Rym: That was the pre party.
Rym: Yeah, I didn't go to any post.
Scott: I don't think there was.
Rym: There was a post party, I know I was invited to it.
Rym: I just didn't go.
Scott: Anyway, I can't imagine me.
Rym: Oh, no the previous one 10-10-10.
Rym: New York comic-con was at the same time right and I went to do some press bullshit.
Scott: Yep Anyway, the book club book is the name of the wind by Patrick Rothfuss.
Scott: I've already finished it.
Scott: How come you haven't finished?
Rym: I just started reading it.
Scott: I'm not talking about you and talking about all the use but also you kids.
Scott: you're slow at reading.
Scott: This is why you need to read and not listen to audiobooks.
Scott: You'll get faster and better at reading.
Rym: I am 10% of the way through this book.
Scott: I started it yesterday Thumbs up or thumbs down.
Rym: I'm liking it so far.
Rym: So Scott.
Rym: I got one question for you who would win in a fight?
Scott: kvot or I think it's kvothe.
Scott: It's how it's supposed to be pronounced.
Rym: Well, he said it's pronounced similarly to quotes.
Scott: Yeah quote.
Scott: I think it's close.
Rym: You know what?
Scott: kvothe reshy sure the guy.
Rym: so There's some things I can say early on.
Rym: Getting some slightly homoerotic vibes from him and his student in the early parts of the book.
Rym: Okay, whatever whatever I'm just saying getting some vibes there.
Rym: Yeah, those vibes to chronicler reminds me a lot of Danilothon from the some frog out in the realms books.
Scott: Well, I don't know that character.
Rym: No, but he's a lot like that guy.
Rym: Okay Three who would win in a fight kvothe or Kellis?
Scott: kvothe or Kellis?
Scott: Yeah Kellis, it depends.
Scott: Yeah, because yeah, it depends because Of course this but these books right all three of them only two of which are out are the story of kvothe from his youth to his older days.
Rym: Yeah, because kvothe could kill like kvothe when he was just one of the enemaru.
Scott: It's like at it's edmera I think but it's like which point in each of their lives, right?
Scott: It's like yeah, who's gonna win in a fight?
Scott: Merlin or Lancelot?
Scott: Well Merlin probably right, but no, it's super old Merlin Who's actually a baby versus super young Merlin who's a knicket with swords and lances?
Scott: I think baby Merlin is gonna lose right.
Scott: so you got it.
Scott: You got to pick a time.
Rym: Well the same time it depends on how.
Scott: we also don't know the full timeline of either character.
Rym: Does kvothe have the mark like?
Rym: well also kvothe.
Rym: there's a lot of names.
Scott: I know you mean coty.
Rym: This book likes to throw.
Rym: I like that this when he starts telling the story and he's like three days and then he's like Some may know me as he starts listing.
Rym: like all these names The bloodless King killer have to do one damage, right?
Scott: Yeah, but book one is day one book Tuesday to book Thursday.
Rym: I'm liking it.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: It's not as artfully put together as the Prince of Nothing.
Rym: Nor is it is deeply philosophical.
Rym: It's given me that good fantasy vibe, which is hard to get going in my blood.
Scott: So anyway, and then the final meta we have an IRC channel.
Scott: You can join.
Scott: there's people in it and You should also join all our other internet things like our forum and Facebook and Twitter and all those things.
Rym: We've also uploaded a bunch of YouTube videos.
Scott: Oh, yeah YouTube also including us discovering the origin of the arrow to the knee thing and Possibly three mini lectures from PAX Prime They're all up and a newsletter you can subscribe to which people seem to really like.
Scott: they like it enough that they were asking for Back issues.
Scott: What the fuck?
Scott: Anyway, yeah.
Rym: Yeah going pretty well.
Scott: So join all our things that can be joined and go to front crew.
Scott: calm.
Rym: Also, if I get more Twitter followers than Scott by the end of the year I will upload a video of my junk to YouTube.
Scott: Yeah your junk meaning your boat.
Rym: I think everyone knows what I mean by my.
Scott: you're not allowed to upload videos of it.
Rym: Oh, I'm allowed.
Scott: I'm just get taken down and your account will be shut down.
Rym: No, I looked into that.
Rym: most likely I'd get a strike.
Scott: Anyway You're better off just posting a photo of your junk to Imgur.
Scott: that'll stay there.
Rym: now I'll upload a YouTube video that has a still of it in the middle.
Rym: take a while for people to notice.
Scott: Mmm, someone might report it.
Rym: Yeah, they.
Scott: probably there's also people who review every YouTube almost every YouTube video that goes up.
Rym: Anyway, anyway anyway, so traders of Genoa is a game that we played.
Scott: But did we do things of the day?
Scott: We did.
Rym: Yeah, we did.
Rym: Okay with you.
Scott: I'm forgetting.
Rym: All right captain All right, then lead us off.
Scott: Okay, so there's a game called traders of Genoa, but now is just called Genoa, right?
Scott: I played.
Scott: there's a. it was an original printing in the u.s.
Scott: Is it traders general on it?
Scott: I played that a long time ago back in Beacon Poughkeepsie actually at Maas and then some reason I didn't go to that Maas meeting.
Scott: Yeah, that guy remember he went to his apartment.
Scott: He was there.
Scott: He played it with us, but it was brought by this red-haired guy with the apartment with the bird.
Rym: Yes Okay, I played shadows over Camelot and then there were like the two cool people in town.
Scott: But there was that there was another cool person who you did not see.
Scott: that was there the red-haired guy.
Rym: Yeah, I never played a game with him.
Scott: He owned traders in Genoa and he played at that time.
Rym: How come the three cool people literally disappeared and we had no context?
Scott: Oh, that's he get for not going every time.
Rym: No, but we they disappeared and somehow we had no way to think.
Scott: I have a business card from one of the guys.
Rym: You should email them.
Rym: be like, hey, you're still in Poughkeepsie anyway.
Scott: So I played the game then and the whole gist of the game Is that it's a game where all the bits in the game are tradable, right?
Scott: So it's like, you know, you play Monopoly and it's like you're not really allowed to just trade money with people, right?
Scott: It's like you can.
Scott: I guess it's in the rules.
Scott: You can trade properties.
Scott: and it's like, you know A lot of games that have trading a really respect even have trading at all have like credibly you can trade Resources for resources in a very constrained.
Scott: Yeah There are very few games that have ultra freeform trading and traders in Genoa also does not have completely freeform trading.
Scott: You can only trade with the person whose turn it is Right and you can only make trades that are binding and immediate.
Scott: The only other kind of trade you can make that's binding is If somebody is going to go into a workshop and this will make no sense If you've never played it.
Scott: you can trade with them for the goods.
Scott: The workshop would produce when they go into it, right?
Scott: So Other than that, you can't really do anything.
Scott: But the interesting thing is all the different pieces in the game.
Scott: You know the cardboard pieces cards tokens money Recent goods, you know all the different kinds of bits and there's a bunch of them.
Scott: There's like four or five six different kinds of bits can all be traded.
Scott: so you can be like I'll give you $3 and a tree for your Contract and a beer, you know you can really go crazy with that.
Scott: And that is the core of the fun and awesomeness of this game.
Scott: So it's had a recent reprinting in the United States and where it's just called Genoa instead of traders in Genoa.
Scott: But it is the exact same goddamn game as far as I can tell only newly printed with new art that kind of thing Going on bigger.
Scott: I think it's like larger In its construction, you know, I have no way to tell bigger board bigger pieces.
Scott: I think I'm not a hundred percent sure But it's the same game and it's just as fun.
Scott: and we own it and we've now both played it many more times.
Rym: Now the the gist of it's pretty simple you basically it's hard to really explain a lot of the bits without looking at a board.
Rym: Basically you move around this board like you have a trail.
Rym: you leave like a slime trail of traders and Every turn you're like trade der not trade toe.
Rym: I could move it here or move it there.
Rym: What do you guys want me to do and Scott will be like?
Rym: I'll give you a beer and five bucks if you move it there.
Scott: and let me do the thing Right, because basically you move this train of discs around the board and they all have to be in a line.
Scott: But you could sort of you know, you follow a path.
Scott: think of it as there is a guy He's walking around town doing errands in one day.
Scott: He can walk five squares, right and in those five squares He's gonna go into certain buildings and do errands in each of those buildings that he walks into Alright one person on is controlling the guy who walks around town and he moves all five spaces.
Scott: Every time he goes into a building one of the players at the table gets to do the errand in that building But only once.
Scott: so you can't normally do two different buildings in the same turn.
Scott: If I do the brewery, that's it for me this turn.
Scott: I can't also do the City Hall in the same turn, right?
Scott: So even though I'm controlling the guy walking around the town Only one of the buildings that I walk into I can keep I can do myself.
Scott: the other buildings I walk into.
Scott: other people at the table are gonna do those buildings Which means I need to get them to pay me to let them do those buildings or I can just end my turn immediately.
Rym: Now if I haven't taken my action yet Like I'm the traitor or doing the thing if I haven't taken my action yet I could always be like, well, I'm gonna use it myself unless someone else gives me another bid.
Rym: But if I come back if I'm gonna go into a place and someone actually does offer me like offers me something I have to take it or in my turn right like if no one at the table wants anything that's adjacent to Rym Right and I say Rym.
Scott: I'll give you $1 for the thing next to you.
Scott: He either has to say yes and let me have it or do it himself or end his turn.
Scott: Those are the only three options available to him.
Rym: now the other cool thing about this game is like Scott said you can trade anything for anything and there's a spatial clue like component of what's close to what and moving around and then there's all these different bits like you can get a contract
Scott: yep,
Rym: which you which has like.
Rym: there's things that have to do with having like a number of contracts adjacent to each other or like deals were like get these particular combinations of goods and then cash them in at this place or Have the trader go between this place and this place in one turn.
Rym: So you have hidden information of.
Rym: here are my goals.
Rym: that will get me a bunch of money and everyone else has their own hidden Goals and you're all trying to negotiate to maximize your own goals and minimize the goals of others.
Scott: But did I mention that the way to win this game?
Scott: The only thing that matters is at the very end.
Scott: How much money do you have, right?
Scott: That's all that matters at the end.
Scott: And of course at the end of the game a lot of some of the things you have like contracts can be converted into Money straight up depending on you know what you have.
Scott: But a lot of the things are worth no money at the end of the game.
Scott: Like if you just have a beer sitting there at the end of the game, it's worth nothing.
Scott: There might be some tiebreakers involving things like that, but I'm not sure what they are.
Scott: I don't have the rules in front of me.
Scott: So really it's all about just getting as much money as possible and all these other bits are just means of getting money.
Scott: Now a lot of them if you get them in the right combinations in time could be worth like a hundred bucks.
Scott: So like if you're get some Rym is like he really wants a beer.
Scott: I see as a large contract.
Scott: I know that with that beer he could potentially get a hundred bucks.
Scott: So I'm gonna be like Rym.
Scott: this beer is basically, you know, it's what's it actually worth in the game.
Scott: overall It may be ten, you know, who knows what but to you at this moment in time it is worth a hundred dollars.
Scott: So if you want it, you're going to have to pay out the nose Right.
Scott: It's like it's worth, you know, at least fifty right?
Scott: Cuz that'll be sort of fair But I want to win so I'll give you give me sixty four Right, and that's the kind of shit that goes on in this game.
Scott: It's like oh if someone else wanted the beer I'd be like oh ten bucks cuz I know that you only have a small Contract which means the most you could get from this beer would be thirty, you know.
Scott: So that all that kind of stuff comes into play where you're looking at what the other guy has To figure out how much the thing is worth to them now as opposed to how much something is worth on a global market.
Rym: Now what's interesting is that this game shares?
Rym: Two very important aspects with another game that we play a lot and I think we've talked about on the show modern art.
Rym: One the one of the mediums you use for bidding and trading is also victory points in both games.
Rym: and two Both games get around.
Rym: the settlers problem of it's not act Like no one actually wants to trade or do business because in both this game and modern art The mechanics basically force you to trade new business.
Scott: I think the other game that does that of course is bizarre Bonanza - right it's people if you're playing out trading right points, right?
Scott: No, that's It forced you to trade right does is that you?
Scott: if you have a game where there is trading People?
Scott: if it's if it's just freeform trading there is no reason to trade with anyone unless you're ripping them off.
Scott: Therefore right if all players playing are smart and it is not possible to rip anyone off because anyone will reject a ripoff trade No one will trade.
Scott: but trading is fun And you that's part of the.
Scott: that's why settlers isn't fun Or very fun when you have good players because no one trades and the whole fun of the game is like brick for wood All right, so in order to have a fun game for smart people with trading that is fun You need something to force people to make it a good idea to trade even if you're not getting ripped off.
Scott: and what?
Scott: Genoa does to make that happen is they give you multiple opportunities when it's your turn to where?
Scott: sure your turn could end right here.
Scott: But if you go and you walk your little guy and you move the tower into other buildings Allowing other people to run errands in those buildings.
Scott: they will pay you and you will get resources this turn You know right now that you could use.
Scott: if you end the turn you're not getting anything for the rest of this turn.
Scott: So even though you're helping other people you will also be helping yourself in this turn versus ending it right now.
Scott: and if everyone just went to one building and ended their turn on every single action if One person didn't do that that person be pretty much guaranteed to win because all the extra stuff they be getting.
Scott: So it's a good idea to let people pay you to do things.
Rym: games like this really put into stark contrast games that involve trading but don't either don't facilitate people actually trading or the trading like the other way around.
Rym: the no one trades and settlers.
Rym: if it turns into the vote who wins game?
Rym: where You know you people trade or don't trade based on who they like or they're the politicals or the heuristics.
Rym: Right you're reading the Richard Garfield book yet Can I start using the terminology from it instead of our own time?
Scott: I'm gonna start reading it soon cuz I just finished the book because what we call vote who wins games?
Rym: He calls the chip taking game.
Scott: I won't describe the chip taking game.
Scott: Is it a sim?
Scott: is one of the simple example game.
Rym: Yeah, so the chip taking game shows how some games Because of the mechanics the.
Rym: now here's another thing.
Rym: Particularly, this is a flaw in games that involve direct fucking.
Rym: Yep, which is what we call he calls it something else.
Rym: But direct fucking is a game like Vinci where I can attack Scott the player directly in the game.
Scott: that is true that is that has a lot of vote.
Scott: who wins aspects?
Rym: so games that have direct fucking tend to have vote.
Rym: who wins ideas?
Scott: right because if you just you can choose.
Scott: if you're playing say three four players you choose who you attack and Whoever you attack your vote.
Scott: You're basically voting for them to lose now.
Scott: They're falling behind.
Rym: So here's the chip taking game.
Rym: every round everyone has an action.
Rym: Well.
Scott: What do you have at the beginning?
Rym: Yeah, so everyone starts with ten chips and on your round you choose one person take a chip away from them and throw it in the garbage.
Rym: Whoever is the last man standing with any chips wins the game, so wouldn't you just always so round one?
Scott: How many people are playing?
Rym: let's say you me and Scott Johnson three, okay?
Scott: So round one I take from Scott Johnson.
Scott: round two you're not gonna take from you know Scott Johnson cuz you already down one.
Scott: Yeah, I'm gonna take from yourselves.
Scott: you take from me, and then Scott Johnson takes from you.
Scott: so basically whoever Went It depend you know depending on the turn order.
Scott: right we're basically so we're all down to one And then it's someone's turn.
Scott: I guess I went first right.
Scott: so now I'm voting either Rym or Scott Johnson will be eliminated and then so I eliminate.
Scott: say Scott Johnson.
Scott: then on your turn you eliminate me Or I eliminate you and then Scott Johnson eliminates me.
Scott: now look you can.
Rym: now here's the problem.
Rym: you iterate through that the game is either set or Who?
Scott: if it's arbitrary what if it's simultaneous voting to which chip to remove?
Scott: yeah But even then right cuz then at round one we both we all reveal our votes And we mean you both mean you both vote Scott Johnson now.
Scott: He's down, too, so then in the second round well You're not gonna vote Scott Johnson again You're gonna vote me and I'm gonna vote you.
Scott: cuz we just both voted Scott John.
Scott: so think about Johnson's gonna pick one of us Again, so think about this one of the game like this now other one of us in a game like this.
Rym: now the person Who's ahead isn't necessarily the person with the most chips cuz that's the person who's going to be fucked the most right.
Scott: you would be Thinking at least one or two rounds ahead of who's someone gonna vote for right?
Scott: cuz you know in round one We both voted for Scott Johnson.
Scott: He's down to eight.
Scott: He voted for me, so I'm down to nine.
Scott: you're still at ten.
Scott: So I'm gonna vote for you, and he's probably also gonna vote for you, and then you're gonna vote for me.
Scott: Right so then we're all dead.
Scott: so, but then I know that you were doing.
Rym: The determining factor of the game is either arbitrary political bullshit or attack Rym.
Scott: He's gonna win right, but it also you get a little bit especially when the chips are getting low like when someone has two chips.
Scott: Suddenly it becomes the stick game of unstable state because if you only have two chips you could theoretically be eliminated that immediately.
Rym: Well, no, then it doesn't become the stick game.
Rym: It becomes the game is already over game Or it becomes the brinksmanship game of Scott.
Rym: if you don't attack him.
Rym: He's gonna win.
Rym: so Which is a problem in many games basically?
Scott: I'm in two and you're both at one the only chance you guys has of winning is if you both vote for me.
Rym: anyway the Terminology that Garfield uses one of you will die because I'm attacking only one is that these Many games just boil down to the like.
Rym: the mechanics don't matter.
Rym: the actual decisions that matter are just which player do I attack?
Rym: Who do I fuck?
Scott: and that's basically deciding which of the other players will lose and your own fate is out of your hands unless?
Scott: You know you would obviously pick the person most likely to vote for you, but that's really all there is to it.
Rym: So once again that you know just to kind of show how cool This book is just because it gives us terminology for all this stuff.
Rym: look at settlers.
Rym: I used to win settlers a lot in our crew before.
Rym: Everyone got really good at settlers and the reason I was able to do it is that the settlers breaks down in that whoever's the?
Rym: Head.
Rym: whenever the seven comes up everyone tries to gangbang on the person who's winning so they don't win to give everyone else a chance to catch up.
Rym: So the key to the game was to lay low and be in second place with a non obvious way To jump ahead of the last second wimpy cards or longest road out of nowhere being close to having longest road and largest army.
Rym: But somehow other people don't notice because and here's the way you don't actually have them in front of you the game has.
Rym: Other players have a poor model in their head of who's actually winning and that is the key.
Scott: and traders of Genoa.
Scott: It is really fucking hard to tell who is actually winning because somebody might be like hundreds of dollars behind you But they might be having a fistful of completed large contracts.
Scott: They just haven't cashed in yet and as soon as you get near via Paletti boom They just lay it out boom boom and they're just you know Cashing them in big time right at the end of the game now And there's nothing you can do about it.
Rym: Here's where the game breaks down and that it's a little not fun.
Rym: The big contracts are worth a hundred dinars ducats whatever the money is.
Rym: yeah now the trouble with that Is that the you know these big contracts?
Rym: There's four places where you can cash them in any time.
Rym: a player Wants to go there and has at least three goods.
Rym: everyone assumes Pretty much correctly that they have a big contract and demands a large portion of the profits.
Rym: So it's a very predictable and unfun element of the game.
Rym: There's no way to really bluff that well.
Scott: But the point is is that that person already paid out a whole bunch Along the way to even get those goods unless they were really lucky and the contract itself.
Scott: So it's like then to pay out a huge portion of the profits.
Scott: on the final end It's like on the large contract how much do you actually make?
Scott: so you know.
Scott: if you have to you know?
Rym: But I'm saying it the more you're going for.
Rym: cashing it in is not fun.
Scott: That's true among smart, and you don't even get a contract What's it called.
Rym: so the only reason people go after those Or the only way people go after them is going after the things that let you teleport somewhere automatically.
Rym: But then people realize that the game determinator Determiner.
Rym: so people now treat that the same way.
Rym: they treat the corners and you can see how the game that the negotiations around that especially among Smart but not necessarily well versed in the game players.
Rym: It's just not super fun.
Rym: It's super fun among really apt players who are also smart.
Rym: It's not fun among Inexperienced players who are smart, but it is fun again If there's a new inexperienced and on the smart players, and you're taking advantage of the nubs exactly.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, it's like you know, but that gets into the the classic example.
Scott: And then there's the whole thing where like they'll be enough doing something dumb And they'll be helping out.
Scott: say Rym and I'll try to educate the nub and say look you're about to give Rym all this.
Rym: Whatever guys advise it.
Scott: What's going on you want to do?
Rym: He's lying and trying to win advice.
Scott: Rym is the person who lies and Scott never lies.
Rym: And you know what the result of that is someone other than me and Scott wins the game like that Possibly, but then I win because that's because you didn't listen to me.
Scott: Yeah If I tell you that the move rims about to make is gonna earn him that much money and that you should ask him for Four victory points and Scott has a fistful of beer and whatever and that's how these games.
Scott: yeah It's only beer.
Scott: you can't do anything with just beer You know what?
Rym: if you're a German style euro board gamer type and you like these kinds of games Jenna was on the you might as well own it list.
Scott: yeah I mean the fact that you can trade anything for anything You know makes this game a whole lot of fun for the vast majority of people who like to play strategic games You know and it can only really be unfun for you.
Scott: if a you don't like trading at all be your it's basically everyone at the table is me and Rym me and Rym or And you do all play like assholes and everyone knows everything.
Scott: now It's actively.
Rym: despite looking like what I see you none of you are smart enough to actually understand the game looks Complex like and Decker if you just look at it.
Scott: No.
Scott: It's.
Scott: it's one of those deceptively simple game.
Rym: Yeah, if you if you have someone else teach you the rules the game is rid dick.
Rym: simple to learn.
Scott: I hate all these.
Scott: that's one.
Rym: now the game sucks to learn if nobody at the table already knows how to play.
Scott: one thing I really hate about a lot of games lately I've noticed is like you know a gregola or this.
Rym: or if someone teaches you how to play It's a unit.
Scott: it's great.
Scott: even if someone teaches you it's like they teach you so many things.
Scott: you can't leave anything out Right.
Scott: so they teach you all these rules And it takes a long time no matter how even if you're super fast learners And they go over all these different bits and cards and all these things and then when you actually play It's like oh, this is really actually fast and simple and most of those rules I had to learn don't come into play very often and When they do I sort of know them now, and it makes sense.
Scott: and this game is way.
Scott: You know it's interesting, but explaining the rules was not easy at all.
Rym: one of the examples Carfield's bug that it I never thought of because like hard to teach easy to play because I don't like.
Rym: I used to play games Like cribbage bridge and whatever and I really don't like games like that anymore.
Rym: I like hearts inexplicably, and I enjoy Euchre, but I only enjoy Euchre if I cheat at it, but anyway, so the the idea of The people who's
Scott: every show about board games actually going to be a review of the stupid book now Until
Rym: you read it and I can just start using the terminology from the book.
Rym: Granted I like our term direct fucking more than his terms.
Rym: I think I'm gonna keep using that one.
Rym: But so if you want people who teach that game who understand that game will usually also teach bidding systems in bridge which are the Systems of bidding to indicate to the other player whether or not you have a good hand and what they should do and all that Bullshit, which is crucial to playing
Scott: bridge without cheating.
Rym: Yeah, but at the same time Really Really confuses new players and really obfuscates what the core mechanics of bridge are.
Scott: and really don't you know?
Scott: I don't even really know the full rules of bridge but like the the scant details I do know they make it seem like wow, that's fucking stupid.
Scott: right.
Scott: what it's like?
Scott: if there's a special signaling system We're like you can't communicate but you can bid.
Scott: So if I bid 10 and that's a signal to my partner to do a certain thing now Don't the other players know what that signal is too?
Scott: because it's a well-known?
Rym: Yes, so then the game.
Rym: so then it's Street Fighter.
Rym: you have this high-level game of Using increasingly complex bidding systems or using a bidding system to bluff So the other team but then wouldn't my partner know?
Scott: not and if I'm trying to bluff and you know You're not allowed to communicate so I try to fool the other players that are on the other team But I end up fooling my own partner and we fuck ourselves.
Rym: You got to trust the other player.
Rym: We mean trust that they understand the bidding systems enough.
Scott: It's it's it's you know, it's like.
Scott: I think it's just nonsense to me.
Rym: I'll be honest games like bridge are taking a deck of cards and doing too much with it.
Scott: I get that I haven't.
Scott: I don't know the rules of bridge and I know a lot I used to play is a lot of advanced bridge out there.
Scott: I heard sort of water is but I just don't know enough about it to really make a you know an informed Judgment.
Rym: I just I don't enjoy games like that anymore.
Rym: I don't enjoy trick-taking games with bidding systems.
Rym: I Like hearts - yeah, but hearts is also.
Rym: we get to be ever done a show on hearts.
Scott: We do a whole show at.
Rym: I could do a whole fucking show on hearts.
Rym: You shut your mouth.
Rym: Microsoft hearts front row crew calm archive Hearts Hearts.
Rym: So we did a special on it on September 11 2007. there you go Huh?
Scott: He knows he's already like two years old.
Rym: I know hearts is a good game now.
Scott: It's Seven years old.
Rym: Anyway, I think we're done.
Rym: You know what Genoa it's.
Rym: it's.
Rym: if you care about German style of art games You should own Genoa.
Scott: Yeah, if you're the entry shelf, this is like there with Puerto Rico.
Scott: This is like the second is the second tier right?
Scott: Like if you are already, you know, if you're hardcore in the European board games, this is the second tier game.
Scott: You got to get it.
Scott: But if you're a dabbler or a newbie or whatever, this is not the first tier.
Scott: So it should not be one of the first games you buy.
Scott: you should but like once you've already covered Like the a-plus games and you're looking for more then Jenna was one of the first games you should go start to look at.
Scott: I mean, it's board game geek rank 172 out of many thousands.
Scott: It's not bad.
Scott: I actually really kind of want to play end decker again now With the huts, the huts are the only good part.
Rym: No, fuck the huts you think is you say the huts is the good part.
Rym: one They're not.
Rym: and two, how come you always fuck up the huts?
Scott: I'm not gonna say I'm good at the huts.
Scott: I just really like that.
Scott: there's little huts and they're hidden and you sort of walk these dudes over to go investigate.
Rym: It's all the games all of our risk management.
Scott: It's physically fun.
Scott: the huts And you know what?
Rym: All the end deckers taught me in my entire life of playing it with smart people.
Rym: is that one Humans fucking suck at pattern recognition and they fucking suck at managing risk.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.