Rym: It's Monday, July 30th, 2012.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, certifications and why they're mostly useless.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: I guess we already kind of spoiled the gist of the main bit there.
Scott: That's fine.
Scott: So check this out.
Scott: I'm checking.
Scott: I was biking on the old west side bike path.
Rym: As usual, like you do.
Scott: And I'm like, "Hey, I'm going to take me a look at that Intrepid when I go past, see if I can see me some space
Scott: shuttle.".
Rym: I think it's covered by something.
Scott: It's covered by an inflatable dome.
Scott: Those pieces of shit.
Rym: You know, now nominally, the reason for that is to protect it from the elements.
Scott: That's horseshit.
Scott: It's so that they make you pay to go in the stupid museum.
Scott: My fucking tax money pays me.
Scott: You let me see the Blackbird for free, right?
Scott: Let me see all these fighter jets for free.
Scott: I'm of New York State citizen, New York City resident.
Rym: To be fair, I did read somewhere that one of the conditions of New York getting it and putting it on the Intrepid was that we protect it from the weather.
Scott: When the weather is bad, we can put a tarp over it.
Rym: Any weather, sunlight, all that stuff.
Rym: Because you realize even when it was at JFK, you could see it.
Rym: Like I saw it from the air.
Scott: I also saw it when it was on the, uh, you know, the giant tank platform thing going rumble, rumble.
Rym: But when it was at JFK, you could see it from the air train, but it was in a giant hangar.
Rym: You'd only see it from the one side of the hangar.
Scott: If they needed it to be protected, they should have put it in a museum.
Scott: that was not an aircraft.
Rym: And there was nowhere but the Intrepid in New York that had facilities to put it.
Scott: How about the flushing with all of the other rockets?
Rym: Nope.
Rym: The only reason
Scott: that a shuttle is a rocket, but you know,
Rym: Scott, the only reason we even had a chance of getting a space shuttle in New York is because it just so happens that the Intrepid, when it was still used, went and picked up the Enterprise when it did its test flight.
Scott: They should have put it over.
Rym: That's the only goddamn tie New York city has to that.
Rym: Other than the fact that we as the city basically funded half the space program.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: So there's Gemini rocket out and flushing.
Scott: We don't have any tie to that.
Scott: We just put it there because it's a science museum.
Scott: That's all this excuse you need.
Rym: And we're in New York.
Scott: We can do anything we want.
Scott: Fuck you.
Scott: We're in New York.
Rym: Yeah, but we have to have at least, we need Cassius belly just like in Europa universalis three.
Scott: No.
Rym: Anyway, that's why.
Rym: Anyway.
Rym: So, uh, there might not be GeekNights kind of meta, but, uh, the rest of the week.
Scott: Well, okay.
Scott: So there's not going to be nice this week.
Scott: So you're going to lose a Wednesday episode.
Rym: Which actually sucks because I read two comics.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The week leading into PAX.
Scott: So the last week in August, we're going to PAX dev.
Rym: So we're going to be gone like Tuesday through Tuesday.
Scott: I don't think we're going to make any podcasts during the week before.
Scott: And the week after packs, not only is their labor day that week, but I'm going to Django con and DC immediately from packs.
Scott: And I won't be back until Friday night.
Rym: Now the reason I bring this up is a Friday morning used to have a tradition every year when we'd go to Otakon of having people do guest shows because after Otakon, we'd go for a week at the beach, our writers retreat.
Rym: So we haven't really done that in a while.
Rym: So if any, uh, fellow podcast friends or people who have skills wants to do a guest episode, there's a decent chance that like four years from now, when I remember to, I'll put it in.
Rym: for when we go to like packs, Boston,
Scott: if you send me an MP3 as an attachment or send a link in an email to an MP3,
Rym: just
Scott: something like if you do something like that, that or Dropbox, whatever you want to use, send me a link to your MP3.
Scott: I can put it in.
Scott: If the MP3 is already ready to be a show and doesn't need any work done to it.
Rym: If anyone's serious and wants to do it, I will provide you with the seed audio files for GeekNights.
Rym: You know, that music at the beginning and the music in the middle and the music at the end.
Rym: Yeah, I can give you that.
Scott: You can say, let's do this yourself.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But uh, yeah.
Rym: So tomorrow night, if all things go well, as in if I get my visa in time, I'm flying to Sao Paulo.
Rym: I'll go to Brazil for the first time.
Scott: All right.
Rym: One listener already said that we might be able to hook up.
Scott: Is he in Sao Paulo or is he elsewhere in Brazil?
Rym: He's in Brasilia.
Rym: I don't know what that is.
Scott: Kind of big.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: There's a lot of States.
Scott: He's in a, you know, the jungle.
Rym: Apparently Sao Paulo is in the state of Sao Paulo or something like that.
Scott: That's fine.
Rym: The state is SP.
Scott: We're in New York in the state of New York.
Scott: That's, he's the same as us.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's not a problem.
Rym: Did you see that thing that was like New York was almost nine boroughs?
Scott: That would have been scary.
Scott: Get the fuck out of the here Yonkers.
Rym: Fuck yourself.
Rym: No, it wouldn't have been Yonkers.
Rym: It just Manhattan would have been three different boroughs and Brooklyn would have been broken in two.
Scott: They should give us all the fricking, uh, cities in Jersey that aren't actually Jersey, like Jersey city and Hoboken and
Rym: those should, that should be the, that
Scott: should all be, that should all be New York city or
Rym: the six borough and Yonkers should be the seventh statue
Scott: of Liberty.
Rym: No, no, you can have a Staten Island Jersey.
Rym: That should be the fifth and sixth borough and someone else can have our land bridge.
Scott: Yeah, you can, whatever.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, anyway, so, uh, you know, uh, usually what I do is I buy a new desktop computer because you know, being a nerd, I have to have a desktop.
Scott: If I wasn't a nerd, I think these days, if you're just a normal person, maybe you don't even need one.
Scott: But in fact you probably don't.
Scott: In fact, a lot of people can get by with an iPad.
Scott: I would suggest they don't, but you know, if they only want to do the things they do, then that's what they can do.
Scott: Uh, I need desktop computer for gaming and for programming and for all sorts of things.
Scott: And that is the thing that I have that I use more than any other thing.
Scott: No matter how many things I buy, the desktop computer is used more than anything.
Rym: Now you've made it a long way with a pretty old desktop computer.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: a core two duo.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: So I usually I, you know, my first one I bought in 99 and it made it to like oh four ish.
Scott: It was like a five year deal even though it had a slight upgrade.
Scott: You know, it always has a slight upgrade to sort of make, to push it to the video card, usually a video card.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So the most recent one I got in oh eight like April, oh eight.
Rym: Now what's interesting is that I got my current computer, the one now that I'm using, not that long after that.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I got it in January of 2010.
Scott: So basically two years is a big difference.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But oh nine because I planned it in oh nine.
Rym: I didn't buy it until January 15th because I was planned it in late.
Scott: Oh no.
Scott: Yeah, exactly.
Scott: That's okay.
Scott: It happened to be December and then you bought it after new year's like, okay, I got a core I seven.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, I seven didn't exist when I ordered the two duo.
Scott: Uh, but it, you know, it's actually the desktop I have now is just fine.
Scott: It totally works.
Scott: It plays all the games and such.
Scott: Well, okay.
Rym: You have a, you'll tolerate lower frame rates than I will.
Scott: Anyway, uh, it's because I upgraded it with a GTX for 70 video card, which is actually pretty awesome.
Scott: Uh, like when I put that video card in, I used to have an 8,800 GT, which was actually kind of awesome, but the new one is just, whoa, just blows everything out.
Scott: It's pretty great.
Scott: Um, but it's a little too slow to do things like any, you know, work of Adobe nature.
Rym: Here's an example.
Rym: Uh, my core I seven with 12 gigs of Ram, a pretty beastly machine is currently still rendering though.
Rym: It's paused.
Rym: And I swear to God, if it doesn't unpause when we're done recording this show, I'm going to cry.
Rym: The elapsed time for, for rendering this video, which is just an hour of a pecs panel, 19 hours, eight minutes, 52 seconds.
Rym: And it's got about another hour to go.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So, you know, I've been collecting all these GoPro videos and stuff like that.
Scott: And I really, even though my computer can do almost anything I need to do just fine and it's not slow or problematic in any way, it's totally great.
Scott: There's things I can't do cause I don't, I don't do them because I can't.
Scott: So I'm like, ah, do I really want to buy a new computer?
Scott: And I'm like, no, I can hold out.
Scott: There's no reason to hurry up and buy it now.
Scott: I don't need to buy it right this minute.
Scott: I can buy it like next year after I hit the five year mark.
Scott: It's not, it's not too far away.
Rym: I mean, my wife's my rush is holding.
Rym: I think I can go to minimum two more years in my current computer if I upgrade the video card and get myself to 18 or so gigs of Ram.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So I'm like, oh, I don't need to buy it right now.
Scott: And then I remembered that fricking secure boot bullshit's coming around the corner and I went a new egg and I'm like, let's see how close the secure boot nonsense is.
Scott: One of the newest motherboards.
Scott: I saw a new egg.
Scott: I don't know if it had secure slash restricted boot, but it was like pumping up the fact that it had UEFI.
Scott: and I was like, uh oh, UEFI is a U F I A. That's right.
Scott: So, I mean, it's so disappointing because the EFI is just better than bios, but every actual implementation of EFI that you can buy in hardware has bullshit attached to it.
Scott: So it's like, you know, max use it.
Scott: It's just better, newer bios.
Scott: It's, you know, a flash firmware kind of situation instead of an old cruddy CMOS thingy, but they always add that secure boot kind of nonsense to it.
Scott: That's why it's a pain in the ass to install, you know, whatever.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: So I'm like, crap, maybe I have to buy one.
Scott: When is windows eight coming out?
Scott: Fucking like a couple months.
Scott: It's around the fucking corner.
Scott: And I'm like shit.
Scott: Cause I kind of wanted to wait until there was, you know, cause Intel does the, they're sort of like Apple where they do the tick tock, tick tock.
Scott: And I think this, this is related to, I think this is related to the way the factories operate because so many companies are doing it.
Rym: I waited until the next gen of I sevens came out.
Rym: Then I got that.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: See what's happening is.
Scott: I noticed a lot of companies doing this.
Scott: I think it must have something to do with factories.
Scott: is they do a release schedule where they do a revolutionary change.
Scott: Like our newest iPhone four, look how different it is in the iPhone three G. It's like, yeah, it's a whole new thing.
Scott: Then like four S it's slightly crooked.
Scott: So you know, same thing with Intel.
Scott: They're like I seven Sandy bridge.
Scott: Whoa, it's completely different from our previous one, whatever it was called.
Scott: Then they're like Ivy bridge, slightly better than Sandy bridge.
Scott: Then they're like, next, you know, next year they're going to come out.
Scott: It's like, boom, something else.
Scott: It's not even bridge is just totally different from whatever.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That's how they work.
Scott: And I think it's, I think it's because they retool their factories like upgrade and it takes, you know, two years to right.
Scott: They have it sort of this rotating schedule of big factory upgrade.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: We can retool the factory once every year to upgrade, you know, the old process a little bit, you know, anyway.
Scott: So I wanted to wait for the talk, the big Intel update, I want to get some Ivy bridge.
Scott: that was just slightly better than Sandy bridge.
Scott: I wanted to get some big improvement, but I can't cause that's going to come with some windows eight nonsense.
Scott: And I'm like, Oh no.
Scott: So I went and I said, well, you know what?
Scott: I have monies, but I should not buy.
Scott: I usually buy $800 computers.
Scott: That's usually what I buy.
Rym: I spent $1,500 on my current computer.
Scott: That's a lot.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: My current computer, when I bought it, remember I had an SSD for my operating system in 2010, like January.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: It was 32 gigs and it cost.
Rym: How much did it cost?
Rym: I'll look up how much it costs.
Scott: So anyway, I went out.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So I'm like, but wait a minute.
Scott: If I'm really worried about the secure boot nonsense, I better buy something stronger than $800.
Scott: I should get like $1,000, maybe $1,200 computers.
Scott: So that way, you know, it's it's full power, right?
Scott: It's you know, that way it can last longer.
Scott: And I won't you know, the dilemma of what do I do?
Scott: I need a new computer, but every computer is bullshit, can be delayed for as long as humanly possible.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So I go on Newegg and I'm just like, I'm feeling real bad and guilty, but I'm just like, fuck it.
Scott: And I spent all the monies.
Scott: I get a $1,600 computer.
Scott: Nice.
Scott: I'm just like, boom.
Scott: I look.
Scott: usually what I do is I look at the scale of things to buy.
Scott: You can see the prices and the prices will be like, you know, 100, 100.
Scott: And you know, like for video cards, for example, it'd be like hundred dollar video card, hundred and five dollar video card, hundred and ten.
Scott: And it just sort of swoops up.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And eventually it's like two hundred dollar video card, two fifty to seventy five, three hundred.
Scott: And you can sort of start to see, aha, there's that big gap there.
Scott: It'll be like three hundred five hundred.
Scott: And I always buy the one at the top of that plateau because it's like you see like three hundred five hundred.
Scott: You like get the three hundred dollar one.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But this time I did different.
Scott: The scale was like three hundred five hundred a thousand.
Scott: So instead of getting the three hundred, like I usually do, I got the five hundred dollar video card.
Scott: I was like, I don't give a shit.
Rym: The last time I spent more than like two hundred and fifty dollars on a video card was when I got my creative.
Rym: Was it the graphics blaster or whatever it was?
Rym: I spent four hundred dollars on a video card, like a decade ago.
Scott: Sixteen gigs of RAM was one hundred dollars.
Rym: Yeah, RAM's way cheap again.
Scott: Thirty two gigs of RAM, which is way more than you could ever possibly need in the present day.
Scott: I'm not going to do a Bill Gates and so you never need that much, but it's way more than you need now.
Scott: It was only two hundred.
Scott: So I'm just like, fuck it to get four thirty two gigs of RAM.
Rym: How many DIMMs you got?
Rym: Because my computer has six.
Scott: It's four by eight.
Rym: My computer is six DIMMs.
Scott: This is maximum for the motherboard.
Scott: Four eight gig sticks.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I just went.
Rym: I could get six eight giggers.
Scott: I'm like, you know what?
Scott: I already have an SSD.
Scott: You know, I have one hundred twenty gig SSD in my computer.
Scott: I don't need another one.
Scott: Oh, but wait.
Scott: They now this motherboard supports the six gigabit per second serial ATA.
Scott: And so I went and I'm like, you know, another SSD, two fifty six gig SSD.
Rym: Because I'm going to buy a couple more hard drives.
Rym: The one thing I'm really lacking and now hard drives are cheap, too.
Scott: It's two hundred fifty dollars for two hundred fifty six gig SATA.
Scott: That's pretty awesome.
Scott: And is six gigs a second.
Rym: Yeah, I'm holding off on that.
Rym: But I think what I'm going to get is a couple of spinning disks, like two terabyte ones.
Rym: So I already have zero.
Scott: So in my computer now, I have the one twenty eight gig SSD.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Which is still good.
Scott: I've got a one terabyte drive.
Scott: that's got my stuffs and I have two five hundred gig drives.
Scott: I'm going to bring all that over.
Scott: I'm going to raid zero those five hundred gig guys.
Scott: Why not?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, what I'm using my rate zero for when I build it is basically when I have video from a con, I dump it in an archive, you know, the stuff I'm going to keep for future use.
Rym: But then when I'm actually editing a video together with all of it, I'll dump it all on this raid so I can edit quickly and then just delete it all when I'm done.
Scott: And then I went even crazy.
Scott: If that could be even possible.
Rym: Good lord, man.
Scott: Because I had already, you know, I had already taken all the guilt of spending all my money upon myself and I had already taken the realization that I was going to be a big jerk and say, look at all the money I'm spending.
Scott: But, you know, it made me feel like I was not a jerk.
Rym: You know, the only thing that would make you be a jerk is if you bought arms to mount your monitors on.
Rym: OK, so so here because those things be expensive.
Scott: Yeah, well, let me get through the whole rest of this.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, you know, it made me feel like not a jerk.
Scott: A few things.
Scott: Number one, this computer is still good.
Scott: And I you know, all these kids in the form are always like, no, my computer is so bad I can't game.
Scott: No, no.
Scott: Well, I'm going to give my perfectly good computer to somebody to make good use of because I don't need it.
Scott: Right.
Rym: So I offered that, too, for my old computer, which is actually my old computer is about as powerful as Scott's old computer, his current one.
Rym: Except anyone who doesn't live in New York, shipping will be expensive.
Scott: You can pay for it.
Scott: Yeah, but it's still a hassle.
Scott: I need I could use I guess I can use the box that my new case is coming in to send away the old case.
Scott: But here's the other thing.
Scott: My monitors are perfectly OK.
Scott: Why should I replace them?
Scott: It's like, well, if I'm going to give this computer to somebody, I should probably give them the monitors, too.
Rym: Wait a minute.
Rym: You who accused me of breaking my D.S.
Rym: Fat as an excuse to buy a D.S.
Rym: Light are now.
Rym: I guess I should get rid of these perfectly good monitors.
Scott: No, unlike you.
Scott: See, you're even worse.
Scott: You destroyed a perfectly good thing as an excuse to replace it.
Scott: I am replacing a thing and making sure damn sure that the thing that I'm replacing is finding a good home.
Rym: I would have killed to have still had my D.S.
Rym: Fat to this day.
Rym: You know how much cultural cachet?
Scott: None.
Scott: Yes, fat has none because you can't see shit when you're playing and you lose a Mario Kart because you can't see what's going on.
Rym: You don't need to see in Mario Kart.
Rym: You just wiggle snake it.
Scott: In fact, because it's you know, you can't see the pieces in Tetris either.
Scott: Anyway, so, yeah, what I did is I went all out.
Scott: I'm like, you know what?
Scott: I'm just going to spend it all my monies and I'm not caring right now.
Scott: I'm going to spend even more monies.
Scott: And I bought two twenty four inch ultra sharps because this one the one I got here is that one.
Rym: That's a really good monitor.
Scott: I bought two of those and I got arm mounts to save desk space.
Scott: And you know what?
Scott: There's an arm mount you can get now that's only like one hundred and twenty five bucks.
Scott: Wait, what?
Rym: That's new.
Scott: It used to be that arm mounts were like a zillion dollars unless you bought like really, really, really crappy ones that are basically a stick with a visa mount on it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So there's TV ones.
Scott: There's still a lot of money.
Scott: Five hundred dollars minimum and they're hard to install.
Scott: And the more articulation they have, the more money they are.
Rym: See, the only reason I'm waiting on that is that someday I will move from this place and I do not want to install like.
Rym: I don't want to assume that this is my desk.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Well, these are mounts attached to the desk, not to the wall.
Scott: So that's a plus.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And they're really awesome.
Scott: And they're only like one hundred and twenty five bucks.
Rym: I laugh when one day they both just like collapse.
Scott: No, I went and read the Ergotron LX.
Scott: So if you're, you know, one of those people, if you're doing like and it's the best thing about them is you do like a standing desk.
Scott: You know, maybe you're.
Scott: and the thing is, you might think even one hundred and twenty five dollars is a lot of money for some people.
Scott: But let's say you're like, you know, poor college student putting your monitor on an arm like that.
Scott: If you're that, you know, you don't have a TV, you're watching all your videos on your monitor.
Rym: That's a really good looking mount.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You can swing that one to the wall.
Scott: You can swing it.
Scott: The cables run through the mount to and it's compatible with my desk.
Rym: So I could put this monitor like here.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: You could like you could swing the monitor around.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I think I'm getting rid of this little monitor here.
Scott: Well, I'm also getting one of those little monitors.
Rym: No, I got it.
Rym: If I'm going to buy another one of these, I got to buy it soon so they don't get out of sync in terms.
Scott: And also that monitor also allows the 90 degree rotation.
Scott: So and the thing is, though, it's like I'm going to buy these.
Scott: These del monitors are going to come with stands that are awesome stands that I won't need.
Rym: Whoa.
Rym: Ergotron for less than twice as much has one that holds two monitors.
Scott: That one is not as flexible.
Scott: But yeah, you know, two daddy two.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: They get they have a lot of choices.
Scott: Ergotron.
Scott: But basically these things only came out like not too long ago.
Scott: And actually this is a newer version.
Scott: The original Ergotron LX, I think, came out in 2010.
Rym: Here's the human scale.
Rym: Hey, even the other brands got cheap lately.
Scott: I guess the relative to they used to it used to be like 250 or 300 for that sort of.
Rym: it's kind of like how I needed more hard drives right when hard drive prices were peaking.
Rym: So I ended up buying like a three after the flood.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I ended up buying a three hundred and twenty gig drive just because that was actually super cheap and everything else was overpriced.
Scott: I just bought two more two terabyte drives to fill my NAS.
Rym: So now I need a bigger NAS.
Scott: There is no.
Scott: Well, my NAS is, you know, has two empty spots.
Rym: I'm saying my NAS only holds two drives.
Scott: Oh, my NAS holds four.
Rym: I'm going to get another NAS and have two for two different purposes.
Rym: No, because I'm going to get it.
Rym: I'm going to get a bigger NAS that has E-SATA in addition to the gigabit ethernet, because then I can use the videos mounted on it in Premiere without a slowdown over my network, because gigabit consumer switches are not that great.
Rym: If I'm downloading video through the switch at a gigabit and someone else is doing something else at a gigabit, the switch does not fully multiplex everything.
Rym: No consumer.
Scott: Gigabit in my house is great.
Rym: Yeah, because there's just one person.
Scott: Hey, sometimes I'm using both multiple computers at the same time.
Scott: I'll be like stream a video from the computer to my HDPC and do something on the computer like a torrent.
Scott: Anyway, say I spent all my monies.
Scott: I'm a bad person.
Scott: Hate me because I'm bad.
Scott: But the reason I feel good about this spending all this money is there are two reasons I feel I am not so bad.
Scott: Justification number one, my coworker just bought a new computer.
Scott: The retina MacBook Pro, the 15 inch, which is the you got.
Scott: the minimum configuration was twenty two hundred dollars.
Scott: This computer was sixteen seventy one, thirty two gigs of RAM.
Scott: Best I7 you can possibly buy.
Scott: I'm making it you got to be a moron to buy that twenty two hundred dollar MacBook when you can get this for seventeen hundred.
Scott: second best video card.
Rym: You can buy X 230 super computer.
Rym: laptop was eighteen hundred, including some accessories I bought.
Scott: So I'm thinking like, you know, before I actually bought this, I'm thinking, man, if some guy you know, I always think those guys who spend way too much money building a computer and the high end parts are stupid.
Scott: But then I'm like, if someone bought a MacBook Pro retina, I wouldn't think they were that stupid.
Scott: The retina is pretty useful, you know, even though, you know, but now seeing the price of that retina MacBook, I'm like, God damn, it's OK for him to buy that.
Scott: It's OK for me to buy this.
Scott: Keeping up with the Jones and two, I see people out there who just like by, you know, who have less money than me.
Scott: Mind you, right.
Scott: They'll just like by car, you know, especially like this midlife crisis, old guys, they're like convertible and like, you know what?
Scott: This is like 20 times cheaper than a car.
Scott: So it's OK.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So I watched every single one of these and you should do.
Rym: some of them are short.
Rym: You could cherry pick and go for the cool ones like sodium is pretty cool, argon is pretty cool.
Rym: But I was actually more fan of the ones like a terbium and hafnium.
Scott: I think I've done.
Scott: I've seen some of these before and I think might be a super rare one.
Scott: There's one that I did.
Scott: I might even been a thing of the day about this one element.
Scott: I forget which one it was that like is.
Scott: you had to handle it very carefully.
Scott: And it was like they went to see a guy who was an expert in that element and he knew how to handle it properly.
Rym: Well, what about Liver?
Rym: Morium is one of the new ones.
Rym: Oh, well, rovium rovium.
Rym: Oh, flour, Russia, mad academia, gazebo.
Rym: This is these people do an amazing set of science videos.
Rym: But the playlist I'm linking to is my thing of the day is a description explanation, commentary and anecdotes video for every single element on the periodic table in order hydrogen, helium, lithium or everything.
Rym: It's some of these are pretty great, especially because the people who do it are funny.
Rym: Every time there's going to be a demonstration, it's pretty much always.
Rym: can we blow it up or set it on fire?
Scott: Elements.
Rym: And I learned a lot about.
Rym: there's one that was really good for how boring it was.
Rym: It was Thulium.
Rym: Anyway, you'll notice that when you think of element names, you think of a certain subset of them.
Rym: There's a ton of elements you probably, like, vaguely know about.
Rym: But if someone said, you know, the name of the element to you randomly, you would not think it was Nellium.
Rym: Like a Holmium.
Scott: Never heard of who remembers Holmium.
Scott: Not me.
Scott: OK, so check this out.
Scott: We're not going to do a Wednesday show, most likely.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So I'm bringing my Wednesday thing of the day over to the Monday.
Rym: Well, Holmium has the highest magnetic moment of any known element.
Scott: That's great.
Rym: Anyway.
Scott: So check out this Wednesday thing of the day.
Scott: Studio Ghibli, supposedly this is their first ever live action.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's pretty good.
Scott: They made this.
Scott: It's not long for a short.
Scott: It's a short.
Scott: They made it for an Evangelion exhibition.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So it's made by Ghibli, but it's for an EVA exhibition.
Scott: And what it is, is it's basically the it's called Giant God Warrior appears in Tokyo.
Scott: And that's exactly what it is.
Scott: It's Nausicaa live action like Godzilla puppetry.
Scott: Right.
Scott: There is miniatures.
Scott: It's not CG or anything.
Scott: And it's the God Warriors of Nausicaa appearing in Tokyo and destroying it in a style that is an Evangelion style.
Scott: And this is an extended trailer that you can watch.
Scott: It's not the whole thing, but it's basically when you see the extended trailer and you know, if you know Nausicaa and you know Evangelion, the extended trailer is enough so that you'll know everything you need to know about this thing.
Rym: Nice.
Scott: It's awesome.
Scott: Of course.
Rym: So in the meta moment, if anyone is in Sao Paulo for the FPL show two days from now, I will be there in Brazil.
Scott: If anyone's going to DjangoCon, which is the week immediately after PAX, I'll be there Tuesday, Wednesday, Thursday.
Rym: If anyone's going to PAX dev, we will be there.
Rym: So will Emily.
Rym: So will our friend Conrad and Avery Alex.
Rym: We will all be in academia versus reality, psychology, game theory and games on Wednesday in the Cascade Ballroom.
Rym: And if you're going to PAX Prime, we'll be doing short subjects and gaming on Friday at three thirty p.m.
Rym: in the Wolfman Theater.
Scott: Yeah, Magfest is January.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And we're talking about Magfest.
Rym: We'll be there.
Rym: We'll be doing some stuff that's already in the works.
Scott: It's a little far away.
Rym: And I was very recently on an episode of Friday Night Party Line.
Rym: Yeah, it was fun.
Scott: Someone in our forum started a Minecraft server.
Rym: It's pretty rockin.
Scott: I built a castle that doesn't look too good, but it works and has a tower.
Rym: Forum, Twitter, Internet.
Scott: On the Internet.
Scott: Come look at us.
Scott: Don't just follow us on iTunes.
Scott: I guess if that's what you want to do, that's what you can do.
Scott: But if you're cool, you'll come to some other place on the Internet besides iTunes to click on things that have our name on it.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So certifications, we had an email actually.
Rym: And while we while we've been asked the question before as well, while we do not respond to most emails directly, we do read them all and we often talk about them.
Rym: We just don't actually really engage them on the show or respond to them in person.
Rym: But we actually responded to this guy in particular.
Rym: The email from Theo was I've.
Rym: I've been thinking of getting my degree in I.T.
Rym: I was just wondering how many certifications you normally get after you get your B.S How many do you two have?
Rym: Thanks.
Rym: Listen to your podcast all the time.
Scott: OK, so here's the thing.
Rym: Well, it's funny.
Rym: Scott and I responded within minutes of each other, not seeing each other's responses.
Scott: Basically the same.
Rym: We both said Scott's first sentence was I have zero certifications.
Rym: My first sentence was I have zero post bachelor certifications.
Rym: So but yeah, basically now we'll address that first.
Rym: So we're not talking about certifications in a general sense because there are specifically the computer industry certification.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: There are other kinds of certifications that are good or not go.
Rym: different industries are different.
Rym: And two, let's just talk about his specific question to start certifications.
Rym: If you already have an I.T.
Rym: or C.S.
Rym: degree or a bachelor's of science in that case, computer certifications are worthless.
Rym: In fact, I would argue they probably hurt you because then it depends where you want to work.
Rym: Well, the thing is, people who are savvy will wonder why did you get a certification from like Cisco?
Rym: If you have a B.S.
Rym: in
Rym: I.T.,
Rym: the B.S.
Rym: in I.T.
Rym: implies that you can deal with any network hardware out there.
Rym: Yeah, so if you got the certification, it's why?
Rym: Like, did your I.T.
Rym: program suck?
Rym: People might not even notice you have a bachelor in science.
Rym: And in fact, they will often gloss over that and focus on the list of certifications instead.
Rym: And it'll be very difficult to dig yourself out of that hole.
Rym: You'll be seen.
Rym: I keep interrupting.
Rym: You'll be seen as you'll be like shoved into the non degree ghetto forever.
Scott: You're assuming, you know, this is the thing.
Scott: It depends on where you're applying, what job you're applying to, which is why you to customize your resume and cover letter if you have a cover letter for where you're applying.
Rym: I've never had a cover letter.
Scott: If you're if you're applying at some sort of stuffy corporate place, right, they might be looking for somebody who knows these three technologies that they use and they need someone to like administer these three systems.
Scott: So if you have certifications in those three systems and that's what they need and you've got it, you're going to get that job pretty much guaranteed.
Rym: But stuffy corporate places I have applied to or talked to or worked with.
Rym: You if you're filling out a form or you're having your resume and they you know, do you have certification for Cisco?
Rym: list your bachelor of science and I.T.
Rym: as the certification?
Rym: Because that's what it is.
Rym: A certification for most stuff like a plus or some Cisco.
Rym: I use Cisco because that's like the gold standard of B.S.
Rym: certification.
Scott: Those A plus things.
Scott: And we're not going to get into the different.
Rym: I said a plus.
Rym: That was the other example I gave.
Scott: And let's not talk about all the different certifications that are out there.
Scott: That's pointless.
Rym: But those things are all implied by a bachelor of science in I.T.
Rym: because actually there aren't that many schools that give B.S.
Rym: is in I.T.
Scott: and a lot of B.A.s.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Watch out for those B.A.s in any computer thing are pretty worthless compared to a B.S..
Scott: Thing is, you might be able to most employers might not know the difference, but the education you will get may not measure up.
Scott: It's mean it's possible for like some school to have a B.A.
Scott: and C.S that's actually good.
Scott: But basically B.A.
Scott: basically means they didn't get it accredited as a B.S..
Rym: So a B.A.
Scott: is B.S There's no guarantee that it's going to be for reals.
Scott: Right.
Scott: An employer might not notice the A versus S. I would if I was looking at your resume, but some people won't.
Rym: Now, the reason I bring that up is that I.T.
Rym: information technology in particular, that's my major.
Rym: I have a bachelor of science in I.T.
Rym: from our I.T.
Rym: and it's actually not a commonly known major except in like high roller computer circles.
Rym: So like IBM knows about that.
Rym: They know what an I.T.
Rym: degree means.
Rym: But I worked at a hot.
Rym: You know, I applied to work at a hospital after I worked at IBM and I got the job and I worked there.
Rym: But I realized after I got there that they didn't really understand how valuable an I.T.
Rym: degree was.
Rym: And the work I was doing was actually very boring and very below my ability level, to put it lightly.
Rym: And when I was like, look, I approached my managers there.
Rym: This was a long goddamn time ago.
Rym: And I was like, look, I could train a monkey to do the job you're paying me.
Rym: Not an insubstantial amount of money to do.
Rym: I could do every other job in this company for and I'll even do it for the same salary you're paying me now.
Rym: I just don't want to do anything boring.
Rym: They didn't understand that I was qualified to do it because of my degree.
Rym: They focused on the fact that I didn't have any certifications.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: If there is a place like that, you are better off not working there, because if you work at a place like that too long, your skills will degrade.
Rym: You'll become one of those people who only like all your industry experiences.
Rym: Like if it's a place that wants like a Cisco cert and they won't accept an I.T.
Rym: degree in its place, you're going to be in the Cisco cert ghetto.
Rym: They will not compare you to other people who have real degrees from universities.
Rym: They will compare you in their minds to other people who did not go to university, but who just have a Cisco cert.
Rym: And your career will be fucked.
Scott: See, I'm not really sure if this is true, but my guess is that these you know, why do these certifications exist?
Scott: It's because in the technology industry, even to this day, though less so than it used to be, most of the people who work real jobs in programming and
Scott: I.T.,
Scott: especially
Scott: oh, my God, did not go to school for that.
Rym: Well, look at it now.
Scott: It's better now.
Scott: There wasn't even school for I.T.
Scott: until recently.
Scott: And even now, there's not that many.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So a lot.
Scott: And for
Scott: C.S.,
Scott: there was always C.S.
Scott: school, but enrollment was never high.
Scott: And in the olden days, that enrollment was like punch card city.
Scott: It wasn't the learning modern stuff.
Rym: So think of this.
Rym: Most people who do what I would consider real I.T.
Rym: for a living do not have I.T.
Rym: degrees.
Rym: They either have a computer science degree or an unrelated degree or no degree.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, I know a guy, he was a CTO, one of the first job I got at a college philosophy degree.
Scott: He just happened to know enough about like managing a Windows network and Windows systems.
Scott: And, you know, could more of what he did was like manage other people.
Scott: Like he would call up the network operating center and they would pay people to do it.
Scott: And he would just, you know, manage all those people and make sure they got the shit working.
Scott: And he knew enough, you know, technology can get it done.
Scott: And the reason these certifications existed really was for two reasons.
Scott: Number one, they're profitable for the people giving them out.
Scott: And I'll explain that in a minute.
Scott: And two, if you in the era when most people didn't go to college, you needed some way to prove to this employer that you knew the thing.
Scott: Like, what if you just learn Cisco stuff because you were on the job somewhere and it's like you go to some other employer and you're like, yeah, manage the network at the last place.
Scott: Let me manage your network at your place instead.
Scott: They'd be like, really?
Scott: Do you really know this?
Scott: You went to school for a friggin history.
Scott: What do you know about Cisco networking networks?
Scott: And it's like, all right, I got I got certified that guarantee that proves there's a certified piece of paper with a seal on it that says that I know this thing and you need someone who knows that thing.
Scott: Therefore, you should hire me.
Rym: Now, computer science used to be the general computer degree because it encompassed basically all of.
Scott: it was the only computer degree you can get a long time ago.
Rym: Now, if you think, you know, the majority, a lot of people who do programming don't have computer science degrees, but more and more do.
Rym: And software engineering degree is now we've got to split out.
Rym: the first accredited degree in information technology in America did not exist until nineteen ninety two.
Rym: And RIT was the first school to have it, of course.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So when I went out into the industry, you know, I graduated RIT in two thousand five technically, even though I actually left before then, but I never met a single person anywhere in my entire career who did not also go to RIT who had an I.T.
Rym: degree.
Scott: I mean, well, think about this.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So you said they invented the degree in what, ninety two and you showed up at RIT two thousand.
Scott: You were the eighth set of people to get I.T.
Scott: degrees in the universe.
Rym: So I entered a job market where most people doing, you know, what is now I.T.
Rym: were.
Rym: it was basically largely untrained labor or Cisco certified people.
Rym: And I was overqualified to a degree that was painful unless I went to the big companies that knew what was up.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So now here's the other thing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like what the money making.
Scott: So these companies, these certification companies and what they do is they they're out, they sort of provide that service to those people who didn't have the degree.
Scott: But really what they want to do is make money.
Scott: And the way they make money is they, A, they sell you books because the way you get certified is by passing an exam.
Scott: It's not like someone comes in, questions you out and figures out what you know.
Scott: They give you a test and you have to look over on the bottom shelf there.
Rym: I have every book for every Cisco certification.
Scott: I don't think that's all of them.
Scott: Well, all the networks, a bunch of them.
Rym: I have the books for all the network ones all the way up to the top.
Scott: So and it basically is they want you to pass this test.
Scott: So how do you pass the test?
Scott: I mean, like if I just took the test, even though I know a whole fucking lot of stuff about computers, I'm not going to know these crazy specific questions using this crazy specific language and words.
Scott: Basically, the only way you could hope to pass the test is to really learn, for example, all the Cisco nonsense, all the Cisco words and show in.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: All these very specific Cisco things, but no shots, no shot, most of which you're never going to use in the real world, which no shot means turn on.
Rym: Like no shot.
Scott: You have to study for them.
Scott: And it's sort of like those S.A.T.
Scott: study things, you know, where you have to buy the books and study the books or maybe even take classes that you pay for and then you pay every time you want to take the exam.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So you pay to take the exam.
Scott: And if you fail, you got to pay to take it again until you pass it.
Scott: So basically, you just give them a ton of money, not quite as much as you would give for college.
Scott: It's just hundreds of dollars.
Scott: But you still pay a lot of money to eventually have them.
Scott: just give you a certificate that says, yes, you passed this test, you know this thing.
Scott: So it's a scam for them.
Scott: And two, you know, like we were saying before, right, it's like an employer that likes certs or understands them and actually wants you to have them is a place you probably don't want to work for to read.
Rym: Now, you were.
Rym: we're talking about people who have a degree.
Rym: I'm assuming you went to a school that has a real I.T.
Rym: degree because it's a B.S.
Rym: meaning you're eminently qualified to do most network stuff there is.
Rym: And while you might not know the specifics of like routing protocol X, it would take you about an hour to learn it if you needed to.
Scott: And another couple hours if you actually, you know, if you're like me, there's a lot of people who have the same degree as Rym people that we know, but they don't know stuff that, you know, Rym might know because they just you know, there are people.
Scott: when I was in
Scott: C.S.,
Scott: there were other people who were just like.
Scott: they didn't code in their spare time.
Scott: They basically just got by barely.
Scott: They just did the work, you know, like, you know, by studying or whatever.
Scott: They don't actually care about programming and they don't program now really when even though they have the same degree, I do.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So just because you have the degree doesn't mean you know the stuff.
Scott: It's possible to get any degree by paying a college enough money and working.
Rym: A lot of these people did know the stuff.
Rym: It was more that if you get into the wrong path early on career wise, you stop being compared to the people who have degrees or stop being considered in the pool of people with real degrees and instead are considered in the pool of people who never went to college.
Rym: And while there are very competent, skilled people who did not go to university, you have to deal with the reality of the way people perceive you.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: By looking at a resume.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Once you get into an interview situation, you can sort of, you know, work yourself up if you're actually good.
Scott: But resumes basically these days, even though there's a, you know, high, you know, high demand for tech labor and low supply, piles of resumes still come in.
Scott: And the thing is, most of those resumes are from people who are completely worthless.
Scott: They're not even tech people.
Scott: They're just sending in resumes to all kinds of jobs.
Scott: And the people at the tech places had to filter these things, you know, which is why you see a lot of recruiters and stuff doing filtering for people, because it's too much, you actual company can't be bothered to waste their time on that.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Like when I look through resumes, I mean, I've actually I realized how old I am for the last like six years.
Rym: I've been involved in hiring decisions for, you know, I've been the guy that makes decisions, interviews people, and I feel really old about that.
Rym: But basically when I see a degree that or not a degree, a resume that focuses on a lot of very low level certifications and there's a ton of them, it's like strike one.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Before I even talk to the person, it depends, though, if the certifications, like if a person did not have a degree and they have certifications that are relevant, that's not a strike.
Rym: But if they have a degree that should have covered this stuff and they have the certifications and they're young, I kind of it's a strike because I assume they didn't understand the industry or they didn't actually learn enough in college or they fucked up at some point along the
Scott: way.
Scott: But it's all about what that employer thinks.
Scott: There's an employer out there somewhere and there's a bunch of them actually who will be like, you know, they're looking through all these resumes and they're looking for this particular cert and they see that on your thing and like, oh, and they do not
Rym: want to work for those people yet.
Scott: Do you really want to work for that guy?
Scott: No, you don't.
Scott: Well, don't waste your money on some cert because you're paying for nothing.
Rym: If you work for that guy, you're really ruining your future career prospects.
Rym: In most cases, you're going because, again, you have a degree that should be the primary part of your resume.
Rym: If it's your first job out of college, I have a bachelors of science and information technology.
Scott: The other things you should brag about in your resume are things you did.
Scott: Don't be like, I got a cert because that means you passed the test, right?
Scott: It's like, OK, you passed a test, but can you really work?
Scott: Just because you passed the test doesn't mean you can work.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So an intelligent person knows that.
Scott: So if you instead of the cert on your resume, you have I did this project and it was successful and this is the project.
Scott: I worked on that.
Scott: I was in fact, maybe I was the leader on that or that was my.
Scott: I did that.
Scott: You could point to a thing.
Scott: you made that and that thing doesn't suck.
Scott: That is worth a billion times any degree or cert like I made that thing.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Like I was the guy who made that awesome website.
Scott: I did the thing.
Scott: I did the I.T.
Scott: for that.
Scott: I program that awesome website.
Scott: Whoa.
Scott: If he can program that awesome website that I know about, then he can definitely is an awesome person to do whatever I need to do.
Scott: Let's hire that guy.
Scott: So in a nutshell, it doesn't matter what degrees he had.
Rym: If you have a degree in I.T.
Rym: specifically, then diluting your resume with certifications will only hurt you.
Rym: Now, if you want to learn Cisco, then buy one of the books for that and just read it used like on Amazon, cheap, pirate it.
Scott: Do not.
Scott: They're expensive.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: No, even if you get your company to pay for it.
Scott: That's how I can blow all this money on a computer and be a bad wasteful money person because I didn't waste money on other stuff like that.
Rym: Now, if you do take the cert, I would actually not put it on my resume.
Rym: But if someone asked me about my skills, I'd mention it in the interview, but I wouldn't focus on it.
Scott: I mean, if someone specifically asked, like, what certs do you have, you know, then, you know.
Rym: But again, I would list my degree of head.
Rym: Like if someone asked for a list of certs, my degree from RIT would be number one on that list.
Scott: I'm also I'm so bleh in interviews.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So normal.
Rym: I'm a dick in interviews now.
Scott: I'm basically like a huge.
Scott: I'm like, so someone's like, what's first?
Scott: You have like sorts of bullshit.
Scott: But I mean, you know, if I had one, I'd like sorts of bullshit.
Scott: But I got this one.
Scott: Or, yeah, I don't have any of those.
Scott: They're bullshit.
Scott: You know, why do you care about certs really?
Scott: Seriously, dude?
Rym: When I was I would literally say that when I applied to my job, I applied to another job, too, at a hospital.
Rym: But as like a director position and in one of the interviews I did, I didn't even like follow up with them.
Rym: I decided I didn't want to work there.
Rym: But basically I was like, yeah, so if I work here, I was basically making demands before they finished interviewing me.
Rym: They were like, do you have any questions?
Rym: And I was like, so what kind of bonus could I expect in my first year?
Rym: Will I get to work with this technology and this technology?
Rym: Will I get to do this?
Rym: I think I asked them more questions than they asked me.
Rym: But that's just us being assholes and bragging because we're old and well, I mean, usually I do that.
Scott: You know, I'm the asshole in the interview when I already have the job and I'm not looking to move.
Scott: But people keep calling me.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I want to make them go away.
Scott: But I'm willing to maybe say yes if they're just everything is awesome.
Scott: Like it's like, yeah, I'll go somewhere else and leave my totally awesome job for the perfect job.
Scott: Oh, you say your office is on a tropical island and you only work 20 hours a week.
Scott: Now, 40 vacation days a year.
Scott: Tell me more.
Scott: Now I'm interested.
Rym: If you do not have not advice to Theo, if you do not have a degree and you want to get into the computer industry, get one ace.
Rym: Well, if you can't get a degree because they are expensive to get from a good school.
Rym: I mean, IT tech doesn't are you?
Scott: are you smart?
Scott: Get a scholarship.
Rym: If you're already out of high school, it's a little too late to get the full ride.
Scott: It is now too late.
Scott: You have already left high school without going to college.
Rym: I mean, you want.
Rym: you want rims advice for success.
Rym: Get a perfect score on the PSAT.
Rym: Use that to get a full ride to any school you want.
Scott: Be smart.
Scott: All right.
Scott: No, be rich when you're born.
Scott: Have rich parent.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Be born in at least a middle class family.
Scott: Be born in a socialist country.
Rym: Yeah, be born in Norway.
Scott: Right now.
Scott: So, you know, if you're most people in the world who are not so lucky as to have all these automatic advantage, if you want to get into computers, you can get like the Cisco cert.
Rym: And if you're smart and you have that cert, the cert will get you in the door to interview at one of the places that we said you shouldn't work if you have a degree.
Rym: If you don't have a degree, being at one of those places will teach you a lot.
Rym: If you're just the Cisco guy, but you're also smart in a few years, you'll learn enough to go past just being Cisco guy.
Rym: But you will need the cert to get in the door past the H.R.
Rym: people.
Rym: The degree is like a magic key to skip the H.R.
Rym: If you don't have that, then you need the certs.
Rym: If you have that magic key, don't waste it by getting the certs.
Rym: Yeah, that's my advice that the certs are great if you don't have a degree because they'll get you in the door.
Scott: One last thing is that, you know, if you got to learn something right and you let's say you want to learn Cisco routing, for example, right, you want to learn how Cisco router works and you don't really you know, you can't afford to go to college.
Scott: You can't even afford to go to like community college that will have a Cisco router for you to mess with.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Number one, you can pirate plenty of stuff.
Scott: You can pirate like Cisco router simulator software.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Pirate it and run it into V.M Yeah.
Scott: Or, you know, if you have a little bit of money, you can like buy an old busted Cisco or whatever equipment you need.
Scott: You know, the computer that you use, if you have.
Scott: if you listen to this show, you probably have a computer.
Scott: So you're good.
Scott: You have what you need.
Scott: But if you know if you need some other kind of hardware, you can probably buy a lot of used junky old stuff.
Scott: Like if you want to learn how to be like a telco person, you can buy like an old busted phone switch.
Scott: Plenty of companies are throwing them out all the time because they upgraded their phone system.
Scott: You get an old busted one for way cheap.
Scott: Get it to your house off eBay and mess with it.
Scott: And then you can become like the master of phone systems.
Scott: Or you can get like Asterisk, which is like open source, PBX mess.
Scott: You know, whatever you need to learn, you can get it either as open source software, pirated software, cheap hardware on eBay and learn it on your own.
Scott: But the key is your house.
Scott: You've got to be using the Internet to get the information.
Rym: You've got to have a project to drive yourself to learn it.
Rym: Trying to learn something in a vacuum to learn it will almost never get you anywhere.
Rym: Like you want to learn to program and you just sit down like I'm going to learn Python no matter how much you study and try.
Rym: You're not going to learn dick.
Rym: But if you think I'm going to learn Python in order to build X and you just build X.
Scott: Well, you have to think I'm going to make I want to make a Tetris, but it's a special Tetris.
Scott: It's like, OK, how do I make a Tetris?
Scott: And you find some tools to make a Tetris.
Scott: Then you will learn those tools in the process of achieving your goal.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Your goal can't be learn the tool.
Scott: So it'd be like if my goal was learn how to use a screwdriver, I would fail.
Scott: But if my goal was hang something on the wall and I need to use a screwdriver in order to achieve this goal, I will learn screw driving in the process of doing this.
Scott: And that's how you learn things.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion, news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.