Rym: It's Monday, October 8th, 2012.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight's sabotage hardware.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So we're catching up on shows.
Rym: I mean it's been a while since we've had like a full couple of weeks of GeekNights in a row with all our travel.
Scott: We're coming up on the seventh anniversary of GeekNights.
Rym: Oh my 31st, 2005.
Rym: It's what 2012 now?
Rym: Jesus.
Scott: I can't believe we've been...
Rym: I can't believe how many years.
Scott: Let's just stop dealing with this shit.
Scott: then we could think about all the free time we'll have.
Rym: I remember those days before we started GeekNights but after we graduated college.
Rym: I would come home from work and you'd come home from work in our giant geek house and we would watch like two movies on Netflix and then play Counter-Strike for like two hours and then cook dinner.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: We'd go to a convention and just fuck around for three days.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Actually we did panels even back then so we didn't really.
Rym: That's true.
Rym: Even then we were not completely free.
Rym: So some time ago I was in India for you know about two weeks and I had my laptop with me and one thing I did every night was you know play FTL and use my laptop for laptopy things and on one night I think was like Wednesday night using my laptop and suddenly while I'm typing in Chrome, Chrome crashes and I'm like okay and I try to start it again and it like starts but it's slow as shit.
Rym: and like if I type in Chrome it's super slow but everything else I can type into just fine.
Rym: and then my internet stops working and I'm like what?
Rym: Oh it's Windows the fuck ever so I just reboot.
Rym: When I reboot my computer starts again and if I start Chrome the same thing happens.
Rym: So I'm like alright.
Rym: whatevs time to investigate this a little bit and I've been working actually on a project a gaming thing I've been working on so I just.
Scott: Sounds like some important file was perhaps corrupted.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So I had this.
Rym: so I figured alright I'll deal with this later and I open up this image to start editing it again.
Rym: but first I double click on it and just to look at it and you know in Windows that just opens it in the windows like image viewer thingy and I get an error that says like memory couldn't be referenced when I double click on that.
Scott: Was your RAM broken?
Rym: So I'm like what?
Rym: So I open it in Photoshop and it's fine.
Scott: Yep definitely the file is broken somewhere.
Rym: So then I realized something weird is going on.
Rym: so I just took my internet and you know in Windows it's not like Linux like if down if up.
Rym: it's trivial to troubleshoot network issues.
Rym: so I right-click on the.
Scott: That works for me fifty percent of the time.
Rym: It actually works a lot better than it used to.
Rym: and I get a. I get a weird ass error.
Rym: I got a screenshot of it but Jesus Christ it was this crazy error.
Rym: So I'm like huh.
Rym: So it appears you know I do some digging.
Rym: it looks like a bunch of Windows system files got corrupted or something.
Scott: Makes sense.
Rym: So I reboot to do a Fisk.
Rym: well a check disk.
Rym: it's not Fisk but anyway and sure enough Fisk finds like 20 gigabytes of orphan files.
Scott: Alright.
Rym: And it's mostly Windows system files.
Scott: See that sounds to me like it wasn't a large portion of the hard drive that was fucked up.
Scott: it was a very small portion of the NTFS you know data.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: That was fucked up.
Rym: Now it's a pretty new laptop with a really good SSD and I you know it's not like I do anything.
Scott: Yeah it's weird.
Scott: I had an SSD for that to happen.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It could just be one spot got the too many writes or who knows.
Rym: Now the thing is an orphan file you can't just recover from.
Rym: it's not like.
Rym: it puts it back it can.
Scott: No.
Rym: So I figure alright I'll just re-image it.
Rym: I'll read you know you run the like Windows repair and it'll be fine.
Rym: So I'm watching this file the scroll by while it finds all the orphans and then I see all this Adobe shit go by and all the Steam shit go by and I'm like oh it's fucked now.
Scott: Fuck.
Scott: It's reinstalled at Windows.
Rym: So it all goes by and then it's done.
Rym: so I get back into Windows and poke around.
Rym: of course nothing's fixed because they couldn't actually fix it.
Rym: So I run the hardware.
Rym: Lenovo like scan my hardware for bullshit.
Rym: No problems with the RAM of course.
Rym: No problems with the hard drive at all either.
Rym: I even ran these deep diagnostics.
Scott: Some software probably just messed up the data on the drive.
Rym: Yeah but I run like.
Scott: Cause it could have been a cosmic ray.
Rym: I know.
Rym: Thing is cosmic.
Rym: You know.
Rym: So in the old days cosmic rays were often a cause of single bit errors in RAM.
Scott: Right well the thing is.
Scott: But they often don't affect hard drives because it's especially not solid state.
Rym: Well no solid state drive is just flash.
Rym: It's actually easier to affect with a cosmic ray than an old spinning disk.
Scott: I thought it was that you would get the one bit errors in RAM because RAM is like a grid of tiny capacitors and the cosmic ray would charge up an empty capacitor.
Scott: You can't empty a charged one right.
Scott: Whereas flash memory is not really capacitors so that a cosmic ray isn't really going to fuck it up.
Rym: No cause it could flip.
Scott: That is based on my really really shitty electronics knowledge.
Scott: It could flip the NAND gate.
Rym: Anyway.
Rym: So I kept.
Rym: So basically I rebooted after doing all this again and then BSOD.
Rym: BSOD.
Rym: Great.
Rym: So I did a system restore and that actually.
Scott: Was that using that sort of extra partition that has the Lenovo shit on it?
Rym: No that partitions already gone.
Scott: Oh you removed it?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I didn't remove mine.
Rym: But I removed mine.
Scott: Because my computer did not come with a disk.
Scott: so I'm like I got to keep that extra partition because that's basically my Windows CD.
Rym: Yeah so when you double click on that partition Lenovo you know what it says?
Scott: You push the blue button on startup and then you do it.
Rym: No you know what it says?
Rym: It says hey you want to recover all this space?
Rym: So if you hit yes you know what it says?
Rym: Give me a flash drive.
Scott: Let's see I got my Lenovo right now.
Rym: Yeah so it'll ask for a flash drive.
Scott: Hold on my computer OK.
Scott: I guess you never did this.
Scott: I double clicked on.
Scott: Oh create recovery media.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Recover drive space.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Welcome to when SSDs first appeared.
Scott: See look I still have mine.
Scott: look.
Scott: It totally did exactly what you said.
Scott: Look right here.
Scott: look there's two buttons create recovery media and recover drive space.
Scott: So I'm just gonna leave it there.
Scott: so that way if I want I can turn on the computer and push the blue button.
Rym: Yeah you know what.
Rym: I got rid of it because I only have 120 gigabyte SSD.
Scott: I also have 120 gigabyte SSD but you know what how much space I have free?
Scott: I have 35 gigs free and there's only 10 gigs on that space.
Scott: so it's not really gonna help me that much.
Rym: Yeah I had 45 gigs free but I do HD video editing on my laptop like at a con and.
Scott: If I was gonna do that I would use my external 500 gig drive.
Rym: Oh I do that too but I still need a lot of scratch space locally for all those renders and shit.
Scott: Well I'm not gonna edit more than.
Rym: That panel a 20 minute panel needs 40 gigabytes of scratch space to render to GoPro camera angles to be able to play them simultaneously.
Scott: Not gonna do that on my laptop.
Rym: Anyway so I gotta reimage my fucking laptop.
Rym: fuck that bullshit.
Rym: but whatever.
Scott: Well you have the USB stick right?
Rym: Yes I do.
Rym: it's sitting right there.
Scott: Oh well that's good.
Rym: My other USB stick is being ready.
Scott: How big did that USB stick need to be?
Rym: Like six gigs it used up.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: It like compresses and stuff.
Scott: Let's see let's go a new egg and check it out.
Rym: Dude I got.
Rym: I bought two 16 gig like super fast flashes for like nothing.
Scott: Flash memory and readers.
Scott: Alright.
Scott: You looking?
Scott: Yeah USB flash drives.
Scott: Oh my god that's out of stock.
Scott: they had a deal.
Scott: I think it was 32 gigs for 25 bucks USB stick.
Rym: Thing is my 16.
Rym: I realized flash drives are too little too late for me because every time one comes out that's ridiculous.
Rym: it's already not big enough for me to even care.
Scott: Alright I'm checking for 8 gig USB 3.0 cause you wanna be fast right?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: 12 bucks.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So check this out.
Scott: Yesterday I went to the Giants were playing Cleveland.
Scott: so that's basically well it's the Giants.
Scott: you can never trust them but Cleveland's the worst team in football and the Giants did win even though they started the game 14 nothing whatever.
Scott: We didn't need to watch the giant game.
Rym: Yeah my fantasy teams didn't do so.
Scott: well.
Scott: It was the one giant game you don't need to watch.
Scott: so we had tickets to go.
Scott: see.
Scott: you know New England and Denver in Massachusetts right?
Rym: Masa Husatz.
Scott: So I go with my dad and my dad's secretary's husband who's totally cool guy.
Scott: he's awesome right?
Scott: Alright.
Scott: So we basically he lives up you know in Hartford.
Scott: so we basically drove up there and then he drove us to Massachusetts and then right there's a little sharing of the driving.
Rym: Masa Husatz?
Scott: Yeah it's Foxborough.
Scott: So you know the game wasn't that exciting but you know we saw a big name whatever.
Scott: this isn't.
Scott: story is not about the game.
Scott: the story is about the town this dude lives in right?
Scott: So we're chatting him up and there was a. it was a little fair in his town you know.
Scott: so he's talking about his daughter's going to the fair.
Scott: he was at the fair the day before right.
Scott: apparently there was something going on at this fair and it was a really a hick kind of affair.
Scott: they had tractor pulls.
Rym: Demolition Derby?
Scott: They had.
Scott: you know pumpkin sized contest.
Rym: Demolition Derby?
Rym: No.
Rym: I'm a huge fan of demolition derbies.
Scott: They did not have it but they had.
Rym: I've been to dozens of them.
Scott: This is not the story.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: The story is about they had rodeo type stuff including bull riding right?
Scott: So you know there's nothing wrong with bull riding you know I guess if you care about animals maybe but you know bull riding is done by professionals right?
Scott: Apparently they had at this fair something called the Ring of Fire.
Scott: Let me show you the picture of the Ring of Fire.
Scott: You can see here it's basically inside of a rodeo fence.
Scott: they have a bunch of dirt like a rodeo and a chalk circle that's maybe 10 feet in diameter maybe 20 feet.
Scott: you know it's not such a big circle of chalk and you basically you're ready.
Scott: this is the stupidest thing in the universe.
Scott: Ready to see how stupid this is?
Scott: If you want to go in the Ring of Fire you pay money right?
Scott: They don't pay you.
Scott: you pay them right?
Scott: So you give this guy 20 bucks and then you are allowed into the Ring of Fire.
Scott: Then it's real simple if you're the last person remaining in the Ring of Fire you get all the 20's from all the people.
Rym: Oh that's great.
Rym: I'll do that.
Scott: Right so but here's the part that you have not heard yet.
Scott: How do you you know?
Scott: you've got to be thinking well if you're the last one remaining right well what's pushing you out of the Ring of Fire?
Scott: the other people?
Rym: A bull?
Rym: A car?
Scott: It is indeed a bull.
Scott: They just let a bull loose on you and the last person who's still in the Ring of Fire after they let the bull loose in the cage gets all the 20's.
Scott: Now you got to be thinking I might do that but not.
Scott: there were only 10 people in the Ring of Fire 200 bucks.
Scott: are you kidding me?
Scott: You would have to pay me 200 bucks to even consider going in the Ring of Fire.
Scott: I think 2,000 might get me to stand in a very large Ring of Fire with hundreds of people in it.
Rym: I have a feeling if the Ring of Fire is hundreds of people in it the bull is the least of your problems.
Scott: Yeah no so the Ring of Fire only likes to want 10 people in it.
Scott: so if you go to I'm linking to this article but at the bottom of the article is a link that says 2C video.
Scott: click here and that will take you to the local news which has the footage.
Rym: Oh my god here's a video of a Ring of Fire.
Scott: That's not the Ring of Fire that's a different one.
Rym: It's the same thing I think.
Scott: That is the same thing but that is not the Ring of Fire from the Berlin Fair in Connecticut.
Rym: Alright they're letting the bull in.
Rym: Oh the bull just fucked that guy up.
Rym: Oh he pushed him back into the ring.
Scott: That doesn't count though he's out.
Rym: 3 guys left.
Scott: This is a more typical Ring of Fire.
Rym: There's no actual fire.
Scott: It looks like these are professional rodeo guys in this Ring of Fire.
Rym: Alright that guy's done.
Rym: I guess the bull's gone.
Scott: They're trying to get his attention to get the other guys out or anyway.
Rym: There's only like 30 seconds left on this video.
Scott: I wonder if the bull's coming back or not.
Rym: Bull's never coming back.
Rym: Bull didn't give a fuck.
Scott: Oh here he comes.
Scott: Nice move.
Rym: That guy doesn't have a good strategy.
Scott: That guy wins.
Scott: Now he's running out.
Scott: after he wins he's leaving.
Scott: Okay so in this particular Ring of Fire in Connecticut a lot of the people who went in this Ring of Fire were not professional rodeo type people.
Scott: They were just like the guy who was running the fair did it and all right.
Scott: You watch this video the bull comes in.
Scott: it wasn't like that.
Scott: It pretty much knocked people over like bowling pins.
Scott: And then when he came back for the second pass that was the end.
Scott: Everyone was trying to boom and half the people were out.
Scott: and then boom everyone else was out.
Scott: The person who was last in technically got stomped by the bull on its way out and she was all fucked up and went to the hospital.
Scott: and this was news.
Rym: So so so so I have something to say about this.
Scott: Why the fuck is this a thing that you're doing at all?
Rym: That's what I was about to ask because.
Scott: Why is this allowed?
Scott: So Scott.
Scott: They stopped doing it.
Rym: We're worried at conventions about getting sued for underage drinking.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Or you know drunk guy getting into the con and hurting himself.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And NerdNYC has to worry about being sued because there's people under 18 in a building in New York City and yet this is legal.
Rym: How can this be legal?
Scott: Yeah so they didn't do it anymore at that particular fair you know this weekend or whatever.
Scott: but I mean are you kidding me?
Rym: What lawyer said?
Rym: you know what that's okay.
Scott: What the fuck.
Scott: What do they do.
Scott: Yeah but yeah how does the bull feel about running over fire.
Scott: They had to helicopter this.
Scott: It's not actually fire but it should be fire.
Scott: They had to helicopter this lady to the hospital.
Scott: She got fucked up.
Scott: She got stomped by the bull.
Scott: It's like oh my god this is horrific you know.
Scott: and the guy that we talked to who had lived in the town he said he just happened to sort of be near it at the time it was happening.
Rym: Wait a minute I got an idea.
Scott: And he's like dude you can't look away but Jesus Christ what the fuck.
Rym: I don't know what's more fucked up that.
Rym: or here comes honey boo boo.
Scott: This is fucked up anyway.
Rym: Did you watch that South Park video?
Scott: I'm gonna do what I usually do and watch them when they come back onto the website.
Rym: Okay all I'm gonna say is I watched that and the whole time I'm thinking I know this is probably actually a real thing but I'm gonna hope to all the gods.
Scott: You didn't know that was a real thing?
Rym: I'd never heard of that.
Scott: I actually knew that it was a real thing.
Rym: I knew too deep down in my heart I knew but I hoped against hope that they made that up for the show or that at least they were somehow making it appear to be worse than it was.
Scott: No they were.
Scott: they're my guess.
Scott: I have not seen the South Park episode.
Scott: I've never seen.
Scott: I've never seen the honey boo boo show either.
Scott: I just know it exists and sort of what it is.
Rym: You're gonna like this episode.
Scott: I just have a feeling that they just directly like just animated clips from honey boo boo show in South Park.
Scott: and cuz it needs no help.
Rym: You're gonna wait at the end of this episode once you realize the premise cuz he's gonna cut to James Cameron a whole bunch.
Scott: Who's that again?
Rym: Famous director.
Scott: Oh the Terminator 2 director.
Scott: So right?
Rym: James Cameron.
Scott: I was right.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So when you realize what his plot is this is gonna be one of your favorite South Park episodes.
Scott: Can it beat my favorite South Park episodes which are lowercase t?
Scott: Time to leave?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I'm mostly a big fan of Scott Tennerman.
Scott: That is also as equal to that lowercase t.
Rym: Time to talk about technology.
Scott: So check this out.
Scott: I'm checking.
Scott: What could be so awesome as to bring together the following companies Adobe, Facebook, the Google, HP, Microsoft, Nokia, Mozilla, Opera and supposedly Apple though their logo's not on the website.
Rym: They agreed to pull their cash and buy the entire recording and music and movie industries?
Scott: No I wish.
Rym: They're gonna buy a senator or ten?
Scott: They made this website called webplatform.org and what it is is basically this website has all the standards for all the webness in a way that's actually readable cuz the w3c is also in on this website cuz they know that their website is basically completely useless for all that kind of shit.
Scott: and whenever you search for something w3 schools end up being like the better result because the w3c site is mostly technical standards that don't actually help anyone with anything.
Scott: so this website webplatform.org right gives you the real information that you actually need in a modern presentation.
Scott: you know that is that is viewable by human beings and has a forum has a blog it has tutorials.
Scott: it has everything.
Scott: so if you want to make the websites right no longer do you have to go to w3.org no longer do you have to go to w3 schools.
Scott: you can go to webplatform.org.
Scott: this is the new website that all of the web companies pretty much have the hands in.
Scott: you know giving it the thumbs up they realize there's something they need to work together on.
Scott: I wish some of the other industries could work together as nicely but they haven't.
Scott: but at least we have this one thing and it is it's gonna be a website that I'm I know I'll be visiting frequently for years probably.
Scott: so get it out while you can don't be one of those people who like finds out about it a year later saying where's this been all my life?
Scott: it's here today.
Scott: so today is the day you start using it.
Scott: and so yet about those other sites.
Rym: so very briefly speaking of the web there was the somewhat famous rumble between Jon Stewart and Bill O'Reilly online and it's Monday.
Scott: do they have a name for it?
Scott: like the rumble 2012 the thriller in vanilla?
Rym: it was the rumble in the air-conditioned auditorium not the rumble in the jungle.
Rym: Jon Stewart had a platform but yeah so you know not to talk about the threats you mean a podium and a lectern.
Rym: he has a podium lectern and platform.
Scott: the platform is what he stands on because he's short.
Rym: well he's on a podium and O'Reilly is taller than him.
Rym: yes and he's a little Jew not to talk about the politics of it but I would vote for either one of them over our current offerings.
Scott: well I mean why can't the current the current offerings are fully capable of debating in that fashion?
Rym: yes we need someone.
Rym: they just refuse to do so with one single metallic testicle or ovary to run the debate and to call their bullshit.
Rym: granted they ignored the fuck out of the moderator in this but it worked out okay.
Rym: oh really they actually debated.
Scott: that's good.
Rym: in fact they debated harder than I think she wanted them to.
Rym: but anyway it's supposed to be streamed online and I thought about streaming it online and Emily actually paid for it to be able to stream it online.
Scott: oh it's not free to stream online.
Scott: no but I thought it was a free stream.
Rym: no but they donate the money to charity.
Scott: I still asked for my money back even though it's charity.
Rym: why would you ask for your money back?
Scott: because it didn't fucking work.
Scott: so chicken dinner.
Scott: so here's what happened stream didn't fucking work.
Scott: no shit.
Scott: so gonna watch on the illegal pirate streaming site.
Rym: so we waited later that day cuz they'd also promised you get like a limited right to remix and you get all these rights if you buy it.
Scott: I can just go in pirate bang.
Scott: get all the rights right.
Rym: well like quotes yeah but anyway they also let you download it with like HD quality from the website as soon as they from pirate bay also so that you so whatever.
Rym: so we don't go to download it.
Rym: the download site doesn't fucking work in Chrome.
Scott: I thought the download site worked.
Scott: no not in Chrome.
Rym: we go to Firefox and we fuck around and get it to work and then we download high quality.
Rym: the video is encoded for fuck and didn't even work.
Rym: so I downloaded like the medium quality.
Rym: friendly medium quality is code for bullshit quality like they encoded the first party.
Scott: you even see.
Scott: here's.
Scott: the thing right is when you try to do something legally as soon as you hit roadblock number one you're supposed to go down the detour points directly at the pirate ship.
Scott: all detour signs point to pirate ship.
Scott: if I pay for something in this one and I hit the detour sign I asked my money back and I get on the pirate ship.
Rym: so I want to talk about something.
Rym: because it failed and from what I can gather they didn't use any normal venue for streaming.
Rym: they hired some company that according to some tweet I saw doesn't even have a Twitter account so no one could add them.
Rym: yeah and uh basically why didn't they use I don't know Amazon video Vimeo you
Scott: YouTube YouTube
Rym: of the dozens of already existing perfectly functional use twitch TV events things that exist and I think I know why
Scott: whoever is in technology is dumb or someone paid them to use something.
Rym: I think there are only two possible answers here.
Scott: they didn't want it to work.
Rym: answer number one the Hulu situation.
Rym: they don't want it to work because of the money cow of the existing infrastructure of distributing television.
Rym: the fact that the Daily Show is watched more by people online than on TV probably worries a lot of people and I know the networks want desperately for Hulu to fail and disappear.
Rym: or to the people who run Viacom and Comedy Central and all that.
Rym: they don't you know.
Rym: maybe they don't want the internet to succeed but simultaneously they're dumb.
Rym: so they thought didn't realize how popular the stream would be and hired this bullshit company because they just didn't know better.
Rym: so it's either incompetence and that on that particular I'm leaning towards incompetence.
Scott: whoever whoever made the decision of what to do here in the technology side was either incompetent or there was someone above you know someone above them who actually made the decision was non-technical and made it based for some other reason like this company paid for the rights to do it but it was incapable and somebody told the tech department this is the people who are gonna do it no matter what because we have a deal with them or it's my buddy who's runs this company or something like that and they forced some decision.
Scott: that was not good but anyway things of the day.
Rym: so there's nothing I like more than industrial accidents really no in particular.
Rym: so there's a certain type of accident that can happen in a certain form of metal smelting and shaping and whatever.
Rym: I'm not really an expert on this stuff no but this is a particular kind of accident that is actually somewhat common.
Rym: so the two things I will say is in both of these videos no one gets hurt.
Scott: mm-hmm that's good they're hilarious and unlike the bull riding video or many people get hurt.
Rym: they're also fascinating to watch and if you want to know why they don't just turn it off the answer is you might as well just let it do its things.
Rym: if you turn it off you got to cut that shit out of the machine and it can take days.
Scott: well it is metal it's hard to cut.
Rym: but when you watch this I mean there's one video they call it lightsaber factory has an accident and you'll see why when you watch the metals probably like it's probably making like a rod of metal and it's probably still hot so it's glowing.
Rym: what's cool is I think this is in Poland and the workers are just laughing.
Rym: if like ah ha ha ha oh my god one guy whose fault was it?
Scott: it's obviously not the laughing guys fault.
Scott: I know whose fault it wasn't.
Rym: now unrelatedly have you ever seen a movie called the machinist?
Scott: I heard of it.
Rym: it's pretty good.
Rym: you should see it okay anyway.
Scott: so check this out checking.
Scott: we sort of know especially from my game theory and stuff like that that human beings seem to have this sense of fairness right like you know there's the old.
Rym: is the ultimatum game the ultimatum game the all right Scott?
Rym: I'm gonna give you ten grand.
Rym: you decide how to split that up between you and Emily and then Emily either says yes or no to the deal.
Scott: if she says yes we split it.
Scott: if we say no if she says no neither of us get any money right now.
Scott: so if I give Emily a dollar and keep the rest she should say yes because if she says no she gets zero.
Scott: she says yes she gets one.
Scott: what does it matter to her how much I get right.
Scott: she's dumb if she ever says anything.
Scott: but yes no matter how much the split is.
Rym: now again this assumes a lot of alternate utility like maybe you getting that extra money over her gives you more leverage.
Scott: okay yeah it's like if I was if I was the competing business.
Scott: we owned grocery stores in the opposite side of the street.
Scott: yeah then she should say no but the principal assuming only that we're getting money.
Scott: she should not care how much money I get.
Rym: the principle sound in the in the ultimatum game.
Rym: if all actors act rationally and then their own pure self-interest then there's an outcome that can be expected.
Scott: but as we know when humans are on this game are fucking stupid because people will say no if you split the money unfairly.
Rym: if people in real or even if they won't people are afraid the other person will say no and spill it equally because they're afraid of not getting any money right.
Scott: it's like they're afraid that the other person is gonna say no if they don't give a flare split.
Scott: or flare split fair split or the other person will say no if the split isn't fair.
Scott: so their fear is is you know is good if you think the other person is dumb and won't say yes.
Rym: now if you think as a human you would say yes in those situations.
Rym: I I simply ask you this if you say remember the days of dig how often did you just vote something down versus burying it?
Rym: hmm anyway yeah anyway.
Scott: so what they did is they said huh well people seem to have this sense of fairness right and they'll.
Scott: they will act irrationally because they believe in some sort of fairness.
Scott: you know where does this fairness come from?
Scott: and the question is do animals that aren't people have this sense of fairness right and that's sort of you know.
Scott: the reason we do these kinds of tests and ask the question about animals is to see if is this a cultural societal thing or is this a genetic thing?
Scott: is it nature or nurture?
Scott: and doing a test on animals to see if they have the same sense of fairness is a good way of determining whether in fairness is nurture or nature.
Scott: it's not absolute but it's you know it's a good way to test it.
Scott: so this guy has done this test with a bunch of different animals dogs birds right parrots but he first did the test with capuchin monkeys which are very good monkeys.
Rym: they're very cute
Scott: and here is the video of him doing this test with monkeys and instead of doing money they basically have the monkeys do work and they reward one monkey for the work with grapes and they reward the other monkey with cucumbers and the cucumber monkey thinks he's getting.
Scott: uh he's not getting a fair deal because the other guy's getting grapes which are way better than cucumbers.
Rym: what scott said to me when he showed this to me was you're not gonna believe how this monkey acts.
Scott: it looks like he's acting like a trained monkey from a movie like you would think.
Scott: the scientific study was fixed and it's some sort of like you know.
Scott: uh one of those scientific scams to you know get published and uh you know fake papers and things like that.
Scott: but uh i mean he is a monkey right.
Scott: so uh just this video is unbelievable.
Scott: the monkey is awesome.
Scott: i mean awesome monkeys.
Scott: that's all i gotta tell.
Scott: i should have just said awesome monkeys watch my video.
Rym: this would have been monkey tuesday.
Scott: is it tuesday?
Scott: no it's monday.
Scott: it is monday but most people are going to be listening to this episode on tuesday.
Scott: the people listen right away at least.
Rym: so now briefly in the meta moment uh if you want to go to pax east buy your fucking badge they're going to sell out any minute.
Scott: in fact if you're listening to this right now probably too late now they actually have not sold out yet and i think they raised the cap.
Scott: that's my guess.
Rym: i am amazed that they have not sold out yet.
Rym: now most of the hotels are sold out already.
Scott: that's the thing.
Scott: is they might have more badges that they.
Scott: it's like they might be able to fit more people in the convention center than there are hotel rooms and and such.
Scott: so we'll see what happens.
Scott: it'll be interesting.
Scott: but i guess that means like if the hotels sell out but they still have badges that means a lot of the people who are local get to go or as other people don't.
Rym: i gotta find out what the deal is because the either the cap was raised or something happened because i cannot believe it did not sell out already.
Scott: maybe just the time.
Rym: however several people in the organization have basically tweeted like guys seriously you should buy them zoom.
Scott: so i think they're close to selling out and their site did not like crash or anything weird like yeah that was.
Rym: one thing with prime is that the site crashed and then it came back later.
Rym: so there's all these problems.
Rym: i guess their technical issues are fixed which is good and also east can hold a lot more people than prime but there is higher total demand.
Rym: but i saw a lot of people who are tweeting things like oh i gotta buy my badge but i don't have any money.
Scott: well that you have a credit card genius and if you can't afford it well then that's.
Scott: uh it's too damn bad.
Rym: but anyway yeah.
Rym: but if they're not sold out yet and you want to go to packs buy your badge.
Rym: as soon as you hear these words pause this show right the fuck now and buy your badge even though it's probably too late anyway.
Scott: uh other meta news.
Scott: you should follow us on the internet.
Scott: what places do you like on the internet?
Scott: think about websites you use all the time when go to that website the next time look for us on there look for GeekNights look for front row crew if it's facebook's twitter's whatever it is look for us and follow us.
Scott: you can also go to gasp.
Scott: uh frontrowcrew.com if you really want to.
Scott: yeah and there might be links to the places you can follow us.
Scott: and other handy.
Scott: more importantly we have related information.
Rym: we uploaded part two of the three-part lecture we did at pecs prime in seattle this year a competitive test of skill.
Rym: uh as soon as i finish editing it i'm uploading the third and final part on the ethics of mind control.
Scott: and just so you know the book club book selection as of now has changed since uh two episodes ago of GeekNights.
Scott: it is now the name of the wind by patrick ruffus and i have begun reading it and it is a fantasy novel that is very excellent and it contains many themes seen in previous fantasy novels uh such as earthsea and many others.
Scott: so uh if you're a fantasy person who likes to play fantasy video games or read fantasy books you should read this book club book.
Scott: in fact uh and i'm basing that on less than 25 of the book.
Rym: so now on pax east.
Rym: apparently it was uh pax east was trending both globally and in the u.s.
Rym: well this doesn't have to compete with much today yeah and is continuing to trend on some more local things.
Rym: so uh we're serious buy them soon good okay.
Scott: so uh check this out right i'm checking.
Scott: people have been worried for a long time.
Scott: it has been sort of a theoretical worry that you know there could be a intentional security vulnerability in hardware.
Scott: right because when you buy a computer you know you can't really modify the hardware itself.
Scott: like you can choose different combinations of parts.
Scott: right.
Scott: but you're not too much worried about the 1989 batman joker like oh use it in video with this chipset.
Scott: oh no that doesn't happen right?
Scott: you're worried about.
Scott: you know that chip was made by nvidia.
Scott: if nvidia was shady they could put something in that chip right that you have no control over.
Scott: that is a threat to you and there's nothing you can do about it except not use nvidia right.
Scott: and the real question is so many of these chips are made in china and other places that those countries and those companies that run those factories could be the ones to to worry about doing something like this.
Scott: so you might not know.
Scott: but like the u.s defense department when they buy computers and other devices for the military they don't put like chinese chips in stealth bombers.
Scott: yeah right they find they make at a much much higher cost uh chips in the united states with companies that they trust.
Rym: in fact i worked in factories that were involved in some of that for uh many years.
Scott: yeah it's like they will not you know.
Scott: it's like we could save a lot of fucking money if we would just buy some chips.
Scott: you know intel chips or whatever but they're made in china.
Scott: so no most of them are anyway.
Scott: so they're not gonna put those like a core 2 duo inside the space shuttle or uh you know an f-22.
Rym: because now there was a pipeline explosion one of the.
Rym: i think it was the biggest non-nuclear explosion russia right in human history in russia which was caused by us the united states providing fake uh sabotage chips to the russians.
Scott: yep but see that was more of a situation of like.
Scott: you know fake chips.
Scott: like you know the.
Scott: there are chips that like would pass the test but wouldn't actually do what they're supposed to do.
Scott: i don't know.
Scott: but anyway we're talking more about like you know normal modern computer chips that sort of.
Scott: they do what they're supposed to do and they appear to work and they're functioning but there's some sort of back door.
Scott: so like you know you could have a computer install clean windows you don't detect any viruses everything works.
Scott: 100 you know there's no problems with your computer.
Scott: but some dude if he wants to can somehow get into your computer and steal your data because you're on the hardware level where your software can't even see shady businesses going on like for example you could make a network card all right with a network card chip that you know looks at all the packets that are being sent out and duplicates those packets and sends them to some ip address.
Scott: and you would not know this was happening.
Scott: unless you use like wireshark to on a separate computer on the network to you know to look at your network traffic that was going out which means most people would have no fucking clue what was happening right except their internet would be half as fast on the upload.
Rym: because uploading your packets is this a legitimate concern or not?
Scott: it's not a big concern.
Scott: it's not something you should should keep you up at night but it is theoretically possible and it is if you're it is kind of possible.
Rym: the reason we're talking about this because the government in the united states straight up banned a specific chinese company.
Scott: u.s government rules hui y a security threat.
Rym: i think it's huawei is it?
Rym: i think so okay whatever whatever they.
Scott: however you i think let's call it hawaii.
Scott: i don't care right who it's h-u-a-w-e-i.
Scott: i'm sorry that i am to not know how to pronounce romanized chinese.
Scott: i think it's huawei.
Scott: i apologize we'll call it huawei because that is less syllables from now on and it sounds more chinese.
Scott: so it's on you sounds more chinese.
Scott: it does right?
Scott: could i mean huawei sounds more japanese?
Scott: right just really huawei.
Scott: right.
Scott: well because i mean think about it's like uh what yotsuba's name is koei y?
Scott: right yotsuba koei y so it's anyway.
Scott: this would be huawei anyway.
Scott: yeah huawei.
Scott: sure huawei sounds more chinese whatever.
Scott: so the u.s congress after a very very long investigation this wasn't like just something they decided.
Scott: right?
Scott: uh the draft of a report by the house intelligence committee said that hui huawei and another chinese telecom zte quote cannot be trusted to be free of influence from beijing and could be used to undermine u.s security.
Scott: so we don't know.
Rym: well there's more to it than that.
Rym: the 59 page report cited a bunch of issues including let's see bribery whatever.
Rym: and there was a second report unpublished because it was classified and only discussed within congress behind closed doors.
Rym: that appears to have specific evidence of malicious implants.
Scott: okay see that's the thing right.
Scott: so in the public view on you know of this draft of a report which is you know pretty close to a final report.
Scott: uh it says that basically these companies are basically doing whatever the chinese government tells them to and the chinese government is telling probably telling them to do shady things.
Scott: so we can't really trust the hardware these companies put out to be.
Scott: you know to not it's like.
Scott: why would the chinese government telling these companies to do anything right?
Scott: so you can't really trust their hardware to be free of influence of the chinese government.
Scott: so you probably shouldn't use it in an application that you don't want the chinese government to influence.
Scott: and the hidden report says yes actually they did something to these chips.
Scott: so don't use them in any machine that you are making.
Scott: that you worry about security.
Rym: at least we're assuming it is.
Rym: a lot of this is speculation.
Scott: well it could also be this point.
Scott: it could be propaganda by the congress attempting to you know get u.s companies to not buy chips from these chinese companies.
Scott: you know conspiracy theories galore.
Scott: oh lordy right.
Scott: um but yeah this is feasible.
Scott: it could very well be true.
Scott: they could do all sorts of stuff and it says it's a telecommunications company.
Scott: so it could be like.
Scott: you know it could be cell phone radio chips it could be all kinds of you know chips that would be very networking chips are much easier to target with this sort of thing.
Rym: well imagine then say cpus.
Rym: the thing is imagine an outright malicious chip that has uh firmware encoded in it somewhere that's hidden or chips even just physical circuits that are primed to when given a certain signal fuck the fuck up right all simultaneously.
Scott: it's like you couldn't really do much to ram right.
Scott: that would be a problem.
Rym: you know i wouldn't be too worried about this in practicality except for the fact that as we pointed out in the beginning not much of this stuff is made in the u.s anymore.
Rym: and two china and russia have basically for all intents and purposes been the bad guys on the world stage lately in terms of uh preventing intervention in serious situations uh vetoing anytime the un wants to do anything good.
Rym: yeah i mean they've been the bad guys as far as the u.s government is concerned yeah but lately they've china's been pretty shitty on the international stage lately in general yeah never mind the free speech issues and all that.
Scott: it's just the way it is man.
Scott: but yeah we only care about the technology part.
Scott: and the technology part says i would probably not want to buy anything that had a huawei or zte chip in it based on this report.
Scott: i mean you know it's it's like you know i can.
Scott: i'm pretty good at maint.
Scott: you know keeping my software secure and you know things like that.
Scott: but if there's something in the hardware there's nothing i can do about it.
Scott: what am i you know?
Scott: and if i find out it's like what am i supposed to do?
Scott: buy a new motherboard?
Rym: now i will consider the uh the current initiatives towards secure boot and the signing and everything to be just as viable in terms of a intrusion mechanism.
Rym: the fact that i don't.
Rym: as soon as i have physical hardware i should have the right to have full control over it.
Scott: yeah because think about it you might have the ability to maybe do a firmware update and fix what everything china did to your chip.
Scott: theoretically maybe.
Scott: but if you have secure boot right uh and that's locked into like one operating system or who knows what or you know other uh secure software mechanisms that that prevent unsigned software from being executed you might not physically be able to execute that firmware update because it is not signed properly and you're not cryptographically capable of signing it and getting it to run on your computer.
Scott: so you can't do the firmware update to fix the security hole.
Scott: so there's a bat.
Scott: not only is there a back door on your computer.
Scott: it's one that cannot be fixed because the people who put it there run the hardware and control what software you can put and then you're in a real bad shape now.
Rym: the reason i bring that up is because you all remember the cbd tpa which you know.
Rym: for everyone who fought sopa and all these things the cbd tpa was pretty much the big bad mother of them all and in terms you know i was just dissing china and russia for being kind of dicks on the international stage.
Rym: the u.s is also pretty bad on this front.
Scott: yeah if you're china are you gonna trust chips made in the u.s?
Rym: or would you imagine in the u.s?
Rym: if the cbd tpa had passed i would have had to get my chips from non-us sources because the u.s chips couldn't be trusted to.
Rym: let me watch my own movies.
Scott: that's true very true.
Rym: so it's a complex issue partly because anyone with knowledge or a willingness to seek out knowledge as long as the bottom of maslow's hierarchy you know they've got food and water and shelter.
Rym: as long as they have those you can learn how to program and you can program anything.
Rym: the limit is really just your own willingness intelligence effort and ability.
Rym: but hardware has a much higher barrier to entry for obvious reasons.
Scott: yeah you can go online and read websites and learn how to design hardware and all things right and you can go to radio shack and put together all sorts of crazy circuits and things but they will be slow.
Scott: you could theoretically build uh theoretically right like a core two duo from pieces if you had enough pieces radio shacks but it would be so slow.
Scott: it would be ridiculously slow because it'd be so big and require so much energy and right.
Scott: so uh you know the you need to do to be able to actually make modern hardware is you need a fab and you need a modern fab right and that is incredibly expensive and difficult and requires a bunch of people.
Scott: and basically you need a factory and you don't have one and you never will and they're all in china mostly.
Scott: uh so good luck.
Scott: you know even you know people like richard stolman who are crazy about free software depend on some factory somewhere fabricating the chips to go in his laptop.
Scott: yeah the hardware and he sees to trust what that you know those people make.
Rym: the hardware of computing is kind of like the medium upon which all of our modern ideas and everything we've built up as nerds in the society is really built on top of this fabric of hardware and electricity.
Scott: now think about this.
Scott: you know he will go and get like a cpu that is completely open and has like its plans published somewhere and has like an open architecture and stuff like that.
Scott: how does he know that the chip that's in his computer is actually matching those that pdf with the documents that you know describe the architecture?
Scott: i mean sure it works.
Scott: you know from his software interacting perspective he sends it assembly instructions and it behaves according to the way that those documents say it should behave.
Scott: but there could be something in here.
Scott: he there he doesn't know.
Scott: and then what?
Scott: even the craziest free software guy i mean you'd have to literally take a scanning electron microscope to the chip to see if it matches the piece of paper that says what's on the chip.
Scott: now you'd have to be and not only that you would have to be able to understand what you're fucking looking at.
Rym: you know that's an interesting point because think about this to a non super technologist the code of their computer is just as obtuse.
Rym: i mean you can go to sourceforge.
Rym: there's a lot of shit dangerous software out there but if you don't know you have to trust someone who tells you oh no it's good
Scott: it's the same as when you go to the doctor and he tells you you need to take this medicine because you have the flu.
Scott: how do you know you don't have pneumonia or meningitis or it's like.
Scott: you can webmd a little bit but you know you're trusting in the doctor and his expert knowledge.
Rym: now when you go there when it comes to open source there's enough eyeballs on it that any moderate to high profile project has enough people watching it to where it's very difficult.
Scott: it's like if you go to 10 doctors and nine of them say flu.
Scott: i think you're pretty sure it's the flu right.
Scott: but when you got open source software there's a hundred people working who are hardcore on this project and a thousand other people who are sort of mid-core on it.
Scott: i mean if a thousand one hundred doctors all say roughly the same thing that that software is trustworthy i think you have the flu.
Rym: but hardware will eventually someday get to be at the same point.
Rym: i mean we will have little fabricators that'll just print chips and then the schematics.
Rym: while they'll be complex the barrier and entry will lower enough to where dedicated people will be able to do the same thing making chips microchips that are fast and up someday up to par with the fastest microchips of the day.
Rym: i'm talking like 40 to 140 years yeah i'm thinking for like 100 years right?
Scott: i mean we'll be able to fab chips that are you know sort of like arduino like kind of slow but they they're chips and they work.
Scott: you know with things like you know maker maker bot of the future
Rym: why does open source pretend pretend we could even if we could just print stuff the the fact remains that the reason open source gets so many eyeballs is that there is no higher authority that can control it.
Rym: so even if you know open source software in china might have the government might you know put bad stuff in software and have control of enough people to where the software is compromised.
Rym: it's very difficult for anyone in china to know or even if they do know well they're saying anything about it right.
Rym: but the thing is if it's same people who use that because it's open source people in the us and people in denmark and people in south africa with all these different governments with different goals can all work from the same base.
Rym: it's highly unlikely that every government in the world is going to want to do the same evil at the same time.
Scott: well there's always the thing with open source right is that there's the source and you can just compile it yourself and then you look at the md5 and you'll do the other guy's md5 and if they're different you know that someone tampered.
Rym: i'm just saying more that even if like if china like strictly controlled software development and controlled the free so that you couldn't do open source in china in china the whole rest of the world exists.
Rym: it would take a concerted effort among all the major industrialized nations of the world.
Rym: that's open software but hardware it's really only made in a few places yeah and you can't really do like.
Scott: i was saying.
Scott: the reason i brought up the md5 to check to make sure no one tampered your software.
Scott: you can't md5 some chip right.
Scott: maybe if it's an fpga you can.
Scott: you could do something right like.
Scott: you can md5 the firmware but you can't md5 the chip itself if there is a physical thing in it there's no checksum on the chip.
Scott: you can perform.
Rym: probably come up with something but maybe
Scott: maybe we have to come up with something right so that you can sort of when you buy hardware you can validate that that hardware is the hardware that you said that you believe it is and has not been tampered with by anyone.
Rym: so here's what i'm getting at the replicators and the printing.
Rym: that is the eventual solution but as we both agree it is a long way out.
Scott: it's farther than google goggles.
Scott: the best case scenario.
Rym: we see the beginnings of that at the end of our lives.
Scott: that's what i'm thinking.
Rym: so the current solution in my opinion is that the united states has to start making goddamn chips again because then in the very least it would take both the chinese government and the u.s government acting together to fuck this up.
Rym: for the rest of us unlikely.
Scott: it's very good you know.
Scott: find something that'll never happen and then set up a situation where the only way we can be fucked is that thing that will never happen happens but that but that's such the obvious solution.
Rym: what all right?
Rym: we need more jobs in the u.s.
Rym: we need more technology in the u.s.
Rym: everything points at this being a solution except the fact that our government is incapable of speaking with themselves.
Scott: well the thing is we do make chips in the u.s but they really only go for military contracts.
Scott: they don't go for consumer products because then the consumer products would be too expensive and no one would buy them right.
Scott: so really the only way in order to make this happen in the u.s specifically we would need to get people in the u.s to be willing to to pay even more for their electronics and to choose more expensive.
Rym: there's a different way to go about it.
Rym: block import of these Chinese now tariffs is one way but i don't think that's the solution either.
Rym: so now maybe some aspect of tariffs maybe incur you know incremental tariffs against countries that also have a history of human rights violations.
Rym: granted we also have a history of human rights violations recently.
Rym: so uh forget that.
Scott: yep so what if we subsidized the production of chips the united states taking taking our oil subsidy and our farm subsidy make it a chip subsidy.
Scott: now here's the crazy same amount of money.
Rym: here's the crazy idea because it balances.
Rym: this came up during the john stewart bill o'reilly thing and i think it's really this specific issue.
Rym: so this same solution but for health care.
Rym: so here's the idea.
Rym: the argument that bill o'reilly made was that our government can run a military because we have a military tradition.
Rym: we can't trust it to run anything else.
Scott: wait because you have a tradition.
Scott: i don't think it's because you have a tradition.
Rym: let me finish.
Rym: his argument was that you know john stewart said so you don't.
Rym: you trust the government to run the greatest most powerful military the world has ever seen but not to run like health care that somehow it's incapable of doing that.
Rym: but yet it can have 16 aircraft carriers and you know floating cities and all this craziness.
Rym: and his argument was simply that the government was doing this for you know couple hundred years we got it down by now.
Rym: now forget all the big questions.
Rym: we could argue against that pretty easily.
Rym: so what came out of that discussion was the idea what if we made a military-esque order of doctors?
Rym: we treated health care like we do the military.
Rym: anyone who wants to enlist in the doctor corps gets doctor education and if they pass doctor i'd be a doctor.
Scott: oh no because i barfed for the guts.
Scott: but if i couldn't bar for the guts i would be a doctor.
Rym: but imagine what if we socialized health care but not in all the traditional ways but by making it a civic duty service.
Scott: someone someone in a debate suggested a new idea must not be a politician.
Rym: now think about that idea and what it does.
Rym: suddenly intelligence and earnestness are the primary factors and one thing that our military for all you might complain about it out there in the world is one of the closest things to a meritocracy we've seen in the modern era.
Scott: yeah it's not perfect.
Rym: don't even pretend i'm saying it's perfect.
Scott: well especially the low levels.
Scott: it's mostly you know depending on who you listen to.
Scott: it's all crazed rambo killers.
Scott: no no you know depending in which what part you're talking about.
Rym: i haven't really heard that from anyone.
Scott: i've heard that from like people who are you know in the inventory on the ground in the wars anyway.
Rym: so imagine if we did that for health care.
Rym: imagine if it was.
Rym: you know you're in you're a doctor and you have almost like a military order of doctors.
Rym: and they even said why don't we take all the you know military doctors who aren't doing anything after we end the two wars and have them build it?
Rym: then why not so anyway if we did something like that with technology surgeon general is a much more important job suddenly.
Rym: so if we subsidized through the government private industry in the u.s.
Rym: or something like that making chips even if they're more expensive now of course we'd be dumping a bunch of tax dollars into it it wouldn't be efficient from a pure no no we'd just be taking the money away from the oil companies on the farm.
Scott: so it even.
Scott: yeah.
Rym: but no that's all again a separate argument.
Rym: i'm trying to keep this focus.
Rym: yeah so if we do that sure it costs a lot more per chip.
Rym: it's a ridiculous waste of money except that now we're building a generation of engineers and factories and all this infrastructure in the u.s.
Rym: in case we need it and all the fringe benefits and all the good things it would do for our society probably more than cancel out the extra cost.
Scott: yeah but the problem is we'd have to actually make chips that people would use and buy which is the difficult part.
Rym: yeah i'm talking like intel core i7s.
Rym: fuck it.
Scott: yeah they're not gonna make i7s.
Scott: intel's not because no one's gonna buy an i7 if it costs more.
Scott: when you buy a chinese i7 you subsidize the production.
Scott: uh well you'd have to keep.
Scott: you'd have to increase the subsidy until the price was the same as the chinese price.
Rym: yeah you basically make the price identical and you have.
Scott: that would how the.
Scott: it really depend mathematically on how big the subsidy would have to be.
Scott: that might have to be a you know.
Scott: basically think about the difference in pay between all of the workers.
Scott: imagine if you had to pay all the workers at the foxconn factory like u.s wages.
Rym: uh scott so that level of work i remember i worked i supported the production fab at ibm the 200 millimeter and 300 millimeter fabs across multiple sites for many years.
Rym: the work at that level doesn't pay that much and isn't that skilled anyway?
Scott: but you multiply it by the number of workers in like you know the chinese factory and the increase right.
Scott: that's going to be a huge subsidy.
Rym: possibly pay a living wage?
Rym: not really i'm not.
Rym: you pay a living wage.
Rym: so imagine this instead of the model of paying someone like us to do it you pay a living wage.
Rym: not a great wage but enough wage for someone to take care of their family.
Rym: it's not even that much money and you put it in some town where anyway.
Rym: but by subsidizing it basically those people are learning at least a pretty good trade.
Scott: you're also the other problems.
Scott: there's all kinds of other issues that come into play there.
Rym: oh yeah there's.
Rym: there's international rules against.
Scott: well it's like we have a lot more environmental regulations so that we couldn't even build the same kind of factory here and it would cost even more.
Scott: yeah you know what it's not it's not like this factory's next door you know providing the other parts.
Scott: we had to ship all these other parts.
Rym: yeah so we slowly build up.
Rym: you build all the factories to build those pieces one by one subsidizing this huge ship fabrication industry.
Scott: yeah the only i mean i'm you know it's a good idea.
Scott: i'm just saying that on paper the number the amount of money it might take me so tremendous.
Rym: uh considering the scale of our current budgets in the us i don't think the scale is even close to what it would be compared to say i don't know the current oil subsidies.
Scott: well i mean well you know it depends right i mean you know.
Scott: uh obama went to steve jobs and he was still alive supposedly and said hey how can we get those jobs you know back in the us?
Scott: and steve jobs said those jobs aren't coming back right.
Rym: yeah because jobs is this visionary on?
Scott: no but i mean but he knows about.
Scott: you know what cost to build things in factories?
Rym: no i think he was being more pragmatic that the cost to build things in factories is the only factor anyone would look at and not any of these other you know possibly worthwhile results of investing this ridiculous sum of money.
Scott: maybe it might it depending on the math.
Scott: it may just be too ridiculous.
Rym: i don't think it is.
Rym: and if it is then we're completely fucked as humans because it means that that all manufacturing will basically go to the shittiest place on earth and there will be a bunch of rich people of invested interest in keeping those places shitty forever.
Scott: it just may be the case.
Rym: i highly doubt that.
Rym: or fine we make a military order of technologists.
Scott: i know that's real social.
Scott: that's in fact communism.
Scott: you know what we're not.
Scott: we're not going.
Scott: that's god.
Rym: if there was a knight's templar of technology that i could join and work in a monastery promoting well you go you can do that this freedom religion.
Scott: i thought you were talking about a government order.
Rym: oh yeah funded by the government like the old military orders.
Scott: now you've got even three.
Scott: you got even more problems.
Rym: yeah knight's templar of knights technology are.
Scott: i think this show is going on too far is it maybe?
Scott: but yeah it is a concern that you know there could be back doors in ships.
Scott: so it is something to you know.
Scott: be concerned about when next time you're on new egg.
Scott: just you know.
Scott: here's what you should do right.
Scott: don't actually worry about this don't lose sleep over it don't do anything about it.
Scott: but next time you look at a motherboard on new egg or something like that zoom in.
Scott: and or next time you buy a motherboard or look at the one inside your computer read who makes it says on every microchip that will be the name of the people who made it and the model numbers and all those things and you can go online and look up each of those chips and see where it came from and what it does by typing in the numbers right.
Scott: so do that and take a look and see.
Scott: you know if you trust all of those or what you think about them.
Scott: it's kind of interesting.
Scott: and if even if you're not worried about security you will learn something anyway about the various chips that are on various pieces of hardware even open up like a clock radio and search for all the chips and see what they are and it will be uh quite uh quite education.
Rym: this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to dj pretzel for the opening music cat lee for web design and brand ok for the logos.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech mondays gaming tuesdays anime comic wednesdays and indiscriminate thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.