Rym: It's Tuesday, August 21st, 2012.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: Counter-Strike go go go go Start going around back.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: you know suddenly my life got really exciting like just in the last few weeks.
Rym: packs became a few weeks away and Counter-Strike go I can play it.
Rym: Yeah, and I haven't done much else except wait for packs and play counter-strike.
Scott: So I got this awesome gaming opening.
Scott: be ready for this.
Scott: On Sunday, I met up with some people in the Prospect Park And we played this game that I got once as part of a kickstarter Called Johan Sebastian joust.
Scott: have you heard of this game?
Scott: I have not.
Scott: it was sort of this indie thing.
Scott: people wait.
Rym: that explains because I was in Prospect Park on Sunday and I was.
Rym: I was on my way home and I pulled up Google Maps to find a better route because I wanted to take fillin Chieh up Bedford Avenue to show them the gradient of Conservative Jews to less conservative to hipster to full hipster
Scott: yep,
Rym: and I was like oh Scott's like right there I wasn't.
Scott: I was like why is he down here anyway, so It's not a game.
Scott: It's one of those games that's hard to play because you need people and you need the equipment and you need stuff, but these people had it.
Scott: so I went down there and Basically what they did is they ran the software on the Macbook and they had a bluetooth speaker.
Scott: actually they plugged a wire into Eventually because the save a Bluetooth channel, and they used ps1 motion plus and that motion plus.
Scott: What are they called?
Rym: move the lollipops?
Scott: Yeah the lollipops?
Scott: Did you know that the ball in the end of those is squishy?
Scott: Yes, I've never used one so I didn't know that anyway.
Scott: so the way the game works is pretty simple.
Scott: everyone grabs a lollipop and you push any button on it to connect to the blue computer and the computer runs it not the.
Scott: you know PlayStation right and Everyone joins and everyone gets a color.
Scott: or you can do team mode, but we did every man for himself And you get a color so you push it and it goes green and it makes a lightsaber noise like But all the noise comes out of the central speaker anyway, then it'll go ready Go and that the game begins and music starts playing and the music is Bach.
Scott: now You can't just load in any music which is disappointing because the data file that goes with the music and the data file sort of You know no tells the game which when the music is getting fast and when the music is getting slow.
Scott: So when the music is slow you have to go slow and the music is fast.
Scott: You can go fast and the all there is in the game is this it's last person alive wins If your lollipop PlayStation thing or or you can use remotes, but you won't have the handy light on top.
Scott: It's better with the PlayStation ones.
Scott: if it is disturbed too much It will explode and turn red and then go out completely and you'll be dead which means you're out.
Rym: So I'm trying to without disturbing mine disturb yours Exactly now at the same time and I kick you in the shin and grab it.
Scott: Uh, listen, I'm gonna get to that.
Rym: So that seems like the basic strategy.
Scott: if it's disturbed a little bit It'll start to blink and warn you and vibrate a little bit.
Scott: that you are, you know on the edge.
Scott: Okay So, of course I'm like, how do I win this game?
Scott: and everyone else is just sort of playing casual for fun?
Scott: And I'm like none and I played a win.
Rym: Did you kick everybody in the shins?
Scott: Well, okay, so I try it.
Scott: first of all, I you know, I was.
Scott: I asked them I'm like, can I just fucking kick you?
Scott: Can I?
Scott: what can I do?
Scott: So I tried many things I tried putting.
Scott: first I came up with the idea and this idea worked Putting instead of holding on to the thing I put it under my armpit giving me one arm free and a half an arm free whereas other people were holding it in a hand Right, which was meaning giving them one half an arm less than I had, you know for for doing things.
Scott: Also putting it on my body was more stable than your shaky hand.
Scott: Well, because the radio hand is at the end of a lever which is a very bad place to put it.
Scott: then I came with Even better idea and I held it like a running back holds a football or like holding a baby As opposed to holding it just close to the body so that you know It's not at the end of a lever where it's gonna move a lot.
Scott: Okay, so then the next thing I did is I just started far away from everyone else the maximum Bluetooth range.
Scott: Everyone else sort of started near each other and I'm like before the match started.
Scott: I'm fucking far away.
Scott: Everyone else kills each other and then I go in there's only one person left.
Scott: So I come in at least second place right no matter what.
Rym: not a bad strategy.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't work so well when the last person alive was of course the strongest of the her.
Scott: It's not like that.
Scott: It's not like a game where there was health like they were weakened like Smash Brothers or something, right?
Scott: It's they're at full health when you go in there and you're at the same level as they are.
Scott: so good luck.
Scott: one time I Was able to get a kill by pretending to kick someone and he flinched.
Scott: that was a good move, but it didn't work.
Rym: You're not allowed to actually kick people in the shin.
Scott: Well, you don't want to do anything that's illegal or will cause a real fight, you know, cuz you're in a public park, right?
Scott: So I don't think you can punch people in the face cuz that's illegal our fight.
Rym: What about what do you fight?
Rym: Club it?
Scott: I don't know, but it's up to you.
Scott: We were in a park with strangers.
Rym: So, you know, so fight club.
Scott: One thing people did to me a lot was they would you know, I would be like all you know I was.
Scott: I was tucked in right and sort of trying to dodge and defend.
Scott: I was all defense early on and I wasn't very good at offense.
Scott: They would just put their hand on my shoulder and shove and then you know Even though I'm facing them sideways to.
Scott: you know I tried to dodge it but they would shove and then my whole body just goes backwards and it's like at you.
Rym: so shoving's.
Scott: They shoved pushing.
Scott: I think pushing and shoving or body checking.
Scott: I You wouldn't want to do that because you're guaranteed to lose if you body check.
Rym: What about what if I?
Rym: what?
Rym: if I shoulder check and as I jump forward I keep my hand in the same position Like ah, it's you.
Scott: Bruce Lee could do that.
Scott: Bruce Lee would be the king of this game.
Rym: I can work on that fencing the big.
Scott: I think the best attack was sneak up behind someone who doesn't realize you're there.
Scott: No, you just whack their controller.
Scott: I was just I smacked like three controllers just down to the ground just like bam Right.
Scott: That's the best move is hit the controller directly just like smack and they're guaranteed to be out.
Scott: There's no defense against that bad.
Scott: But yeah, this game is pretty fun.
Scott: It's a little bit flawed if everyone is like us playing to win or if you don't draw the line clearly as to What's legitimate moves.
Scott: it also crashed a lot and had lots of technical difficulties.
Rym: So you got a. play was like running man.
Scott: It was difficult in the park to always sort of hear this the music coming from the one sort of crappy little speaker They had if you played it and say an enclosed space with a stereo that everyone could hear very well.
Rym: Here's my question for you.
Rym: Would it be worth it at a convention?
Rym: That's not full of jackasses To bring it and play it If you have enough money that you can buy.
Scott: I think it supports seven or eight of the controllers.
Scott: So how much is a PlayStation?
Rym: So here's a better idea.
Rym: Pax is coming.
Rym: Yeah Put out the call be like yo dogs bring your PlayStation controllers to Pax alright, and We'll do this You need.
Scott: you also need a space large enough that is sort of a safe space where people can fall down or push or You know Outside of packs somewhere nearby.
Rym: Yeah, maybe in that cool park That's gonna end with someone falling five stories to their death, I think that's the cool part.
Scott: Yeah, but anyway You know, this is a. it is worth checking out if you can.
Scott: I mean, I got a copy of like this alpha version because I kick-started who knows what back in the day.
Scott: I'm not sure exactly how you get it.
Scott: Someone else took care of all those logistics.
Scott: I did not, you know inquire enough.
Scott: Nah But yeah Johan Sebastian jazz sounds pretty cool.
Rym: I did not know about this and I didn't know you did that I just thought you were biking in Brooklyn.
Rym: I also biked there.
Rym: Yeah so if you didn't hear the I guess news that was predicted however long ago this thing day one
Scott: when I heard about
Rym: it so on live which purported to sell a system of playing games on your computer Remotely meaning all the processing and video card and stuff happens at some remote data center and your key presses.
Rym: It was bullshit.
Rym: It was basically it was listen.
Scott: We did an episode.
Scott: We did this as a news the day it was announced.
Rym: I'll try to find that.
Rym: basically The deal was it was for people who don't have a computer strong enough to do this on their own or can't afford a real Computer or whatever.
Rym: It was stupid.
Rym: We said it was stupid.
Scott: They gave up free consoles at some packs.
Scott: which one was?
Rym: it was stupid in case you forgot was that sure?
Rym: Maybe if they got it to actually work which back then we weren't even sure.
Scott: if it were they sort of got it to work.
Rym: they did but video cards and home computers are still progressing at such a rate that these things would rapidly become obsolete because they wouldn't be able to play the Newest newest game anyway.
Scott: Well, I mean all it needs to do is stream 1080p, right?
Scott: It's not gonna get any more streamy than that.
Rym: Well, they'd also had to deal with the input back and forth and do like prediction and lag Lag correction and all that to make the game smooth and play a lot of games.
Scott: That doesn't matter.
Rym: even yeah but for a lot of games it does and the game has to be available on their platform.
Rym: and Basically, it was silly and it's finally going out of business.
Rym: Yeah, but it went out of business in a complicated way.
Rym: So on Friday online last Friday on lives assets were acquired by a newly created company on live.
Rym: No They made a new company called the same name as the old company.
Scott: Well if you owe if the new company acquires the old company and acquires the trademark and can then rename itself to that trademark it just Acquired.
Scott: like if I bought McDonald's I could name my and I was.
Scott: I was Scott Co.
Scott: I could rename Scott Co to McDonald's and start using the McDonald's trademark because that's not my property I just bought it.
Rym: So the way they did this is that they did not go into bankruptcy.
Rym: instead They did something complicated.
Rym: I actually had to read up a little bit called assignment for the benefit of creditors, which basically said they took the company gave it to another company in validating all the stock options and any Investments from any outsiders.
Rym: so all the people who invested in this and all the employees who by the way pretty much were all laid Off at least half were laid off immediately.
Rym: as far as I can tell.
Rym: I think they're all going away.
Scott: I thought it said half were getting hired by the new company half were offered new jobs at the new company.
Rym: Okay, so we'll see what happens with that.
Scott: Whatever But why are you working on live?
Rym: This thing was a disaster from day one and I feel kind of indicated in the fact that I said Okay, so this is what the thing is.
Scott: I want to you know who cares about online.
Scott: right here's is something I do care about.
Scott: It seems like in the gaming industry You can only really succeed if your scale is enormous Like you need to sell a zillion consoles or a zillion right.
Scott: and we sort of know this because you know.
Scott: The reason is if you're a platform of game development You know, we're only talking about platforms.
Rym: Games don't need to scare.
Scott: you need to be very huge in order to attract developers of good games right such that you know people want the console because this games of it platform because this games available on it and So people will make you there won't.
Scott: there'll be games for it period Cuz it.
Scott: no one's developing for you because your audience is too small.
Scott: so it's like you can only really have a successful gaming platform if you're really big.
Scott: and it's kind of said because I sort of Wish like wouldn't it be cool?
Scott: Like if there wasn't just like these mega gaming platforms like Steam Xbox PlayStation We DS PSP if there were say a bunch of medium-sized gaming platforms that weren't necessarily You know super successful.
Scott: They don't really need to be.
Scott: they just need to be profitable and they keep going.
Scott: It would be kind of cool.
Scott: I don't know how impossible well the thing but it would be neat for me.
Rym: I have a PC.
Rym: it can run any arbitrary code.
Scott: I know that.
Rym: so I don't need a platform right.
Rym: but I mean team just does all these niceties for me.
Scott: But I just wish that there were just sort of like, you know These medium-sized it was possible for there be a medium-sized player in the gaming really want in in the in the console or platform world.
Rym: What is a medium-sized player really provide other than now?
Rym: I gotta log into this other stupid thing.
Scott: What I imagine a medium-sized player to be would be something specialized.
Rym: because alright so like blizzards crap.
Rym: No, no, no all like somebody makes a platform.
Rym: that bullshit.
Rym: I have to log into for Starcraft.
Scott: No, somebody would make like a console and the console it specializes in one kind of game, right?
Scott: It's like this is the sports game Console thing and it just fucking kicks so much ass at sports games Station.
Rym: both kick-ass just fine.
Scott: I mean, I'm just coming up with any exact way.
Scott: There's a Frickin.
Rym: I guess.
Rym: what is it?
Rym: What are these I have to offer that a PC doesn't because the more niche you get the more likely it is that the people Who play and make those games are all on the PC anyway?
Scott: Yeah, some you would need to be something, you know inventive that had like a specialized harder maybe like a bimani specialized platform.
Scott: it's like that's.
Rym: you don't need a platform for that because the Good part about bimani games is that everyone has a completely unique interface.
Scott: Yeah, that's true.
Rym: And the old the closest thing to a platform that we had like that was in the groove which is gone.
Rym: I'm just you know, just I just did a bunch of research on this.
Scott: for packs Yeah, I just wish it was possible for there to be something that was sort of unique.
Rym: There is what about direct-to-drive?
Rym: I Okay, that was great wasn't it?
Scott: No, I just mean, you know, there would be something unique that appealed to a medium-sized audience didn't need you know and even though it never grew to be super huge and everywhere and even though it you know succeeded about as well as on live succeeded could be profitable and stick around and have its fans and do its thing.
Rym: but why would anyone be a fan of a Platform?
Rym: the put the important parts the games remember I look at it from my perspective.
Rym: I'm a gamer and you know design or whatever aside.
Rym: I just want to play my games want to play my games in the easiest way possible.
Scott: What if there was some cool thing?
Rym: is it better than steam?
Scott: It's not competing with steam.
Scott: How not steam Some sort of device or maybe it's a mobile thing.
Scott: Who knows?
Rym: It's okay.
Rym: So a device.
Scott: There is some gaming platform that offers something that other gaming platforms do not but it's not something that everyone really cares about Something that only certain.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: So, let's see.
Rym: What do I care about?
Rym: Keyboard and mouse awesome first-person shooters.
Rym: I have a console for that.
Rym: Well, that's you a computer.
Rym: All right, RTS keyboard and mouse Dancing games.
Rym: Well, they all need a unique Piece.
Rym: DDR is DDR.
Rym: There's a you know, there's dozens of DDR games.
Rym: They all have.
Rym: I guess that's a platform.
Scott: I'm just saying it's That's just a controller.
Rym: So you're saying you want a controller?
Scott: No, I'm just saying it's.
Scott: Can there be a medium-sized player?
Scott: It's all got to be go big or go home.
Rym: I think for all the reasons I just illustrated there's no benefit to a medium-sized player.
Rym: but Steve look at steam.
Rym: If you're if you are a PC gamer of any kind steam is pretty much got you back.
Scott: I'm just saying I recognize the reality of why there is no medium-sized player, but I'm saying if the reality were different It would be nice.
Scott: Imagine if there were just a bunch of medium-sized players.
Rym: Higgs bosons were made of chocolate.
Rym: I don't see any utility in this.
Rym: I don't see any.
Rym: I don't see another platform.
Scott: I'd Scott the ooh, yeah Guys, no, that's not going anywhere.
Rym: But it's a platform.
Rym: It's too small size player Specialized for crappy droid-style angry games.
Scott: Yeah bad idea.
Rym: This is exactly what you asked for Scott.
Rym: Yeah, no you wanted I'm mask.
Scott: Imagine if instead of like, you know, the like three like we Xbox PlayStation there were like ten consoles that were all sort of even.
Rym: That would be a disaster.
Rym: is there any game that's exclusive to one and not another?
Rym: Don't you bitch?
Scott: You're a game developer, right?
Scott: Which one of the ten consoles do you make your game for whichever one's most popular?
Rym: Cuz it's stupid to serve.
Scott: They're all sort of equal.
Rym: Then you all collude and pick one.
Rym: that cuz that's to everyone's benefit.
Rym: what makes one of those different from another one?
Rym: What makes an Xbox really different from a ps3?
Rym: Crook slightly, so yeah, so there's no effective real difference other than fake exclusivity.
Rym: Yeah, it's artificial.
Rym: You you don't want anything.
Rym: you want a thing that can't be a thing.
Rym: I want to be omnipotent.
Rym: I just went on mission, but I want to be surprised.
Scott: I'm just saying is it there was you know competition?
Rym: All right, so what should steam do that they're not doing, you know Competition.
Scott: it'd be cool If some guy could set up a gaming company in his garage and be successful even though he didn't Sell you because he sells games not consoles or platform.
Rym: That's that's where the magic is.
Rym: Anyway, anyway, the oh, yeah stupid.
Rym: You shouldn't buy one.
Rym: You shouldn't buy anything.
Rym: That's not a big player because middle and small and the online was silly and you shouldn't have bought one.
Rym: Yeah, but here's the funny thing.
Rym: and then let's move on.
Rym: so From one article I read today.
Rym: The company says it has more than 1.5 million active users.
Rym: I found two other articles that say here's a quote from one of these Some of the news coming out of the whole event says that on live averaged about 1,800 users.
Scott: Yeah, how many of those?
Scott: one and a half million?
Scott: where you gave away a free console and counted that is one Yeah, but it's the same way as Facebook.
Scott: It's like well, there are this many accounts.
Scott: They just did a count star on the users table.
Scott: It's like guys.
Scott: that doesn't count.
Scott: how many people logged in today?
Scott: - spammers, okay 1,800 users, let's see.
Rym: right now on Steam If you go to 1,800 users, you are slightly more popular than just cause - okay and slightly less popular Than Batman Arkham City and you're an order of magnitude below Counter-Strike source.
Rym: Counter-Strike 1 6 and Counter-Strike go Individually, okay, so you got any news.
Rym: then we can bust into the best game ever.
Scott: I have a sad news.
Scott: Well sort of I guess something you sort of realize.
Scott: you just didn't think about it specifically, right?
Scott: It's like, you know Magazines be dead But you didn't think specifically.
Scott: Oh shit Nintendo power is done because it is.
Scott: Huh You know what?
Rym: I Stopped subscribing to Nintendo power right after the 200th episode.
Rym: I almost said episode the 200th one.
Rym: I think that was a Legend of Zelda special or something.
Rym: Let me look it up.
Scott: They have They have something special planned for the final issue.
Scott: There you know, they're gonna put that in 10 of our 200.
Rym: Uh, no, no wrong ring.
Rym: Never mind.
Scott: Yeah, anyway, didn't you?
Scott: But yeah, Nintendo power back in the day super important.
Scott: now not important at all.
Rym: I would argue that Nintendo power was only actually important back in the day because there was no internet.
Rym: No, and I thought we did a show on Nintendo power.
Scott: I think I think we might have and Really?
Rym: The only purpose that served for me was to vicariously live the games.
Rym: My parents wouldn't buy me.
Scott: Yep But yeah, this is if you really want to get the idea of what it was like back in those magazine days You should play Game Center CX for the.
Scott: You know the DS.
Rym: Because oh, yeah, that's a good game that does pretty well replicate the experience.
Scott: It just said I just want to bring it up.
Scott: What else do we like to say?
Scott: It's not needed anymore.
Scott: But I do think see you at the crossroads Nintendo power I hope someone I'm sure there's somewhere we can download like a scan of every Nintendo.
Rym: I should get a bunch of people to go out and pour a bottle of whiskey into the river or something.
Scott: You can pay for that.
Scott: Yeah, I'll pour some $5 hobo one.
Scott: That's that's about the right price I have.
Rym: you know, I have fine memories of Nintendo power.
Scott: I also have some fond memories even though mostly I had game pro.
Scott: In fact, I'm pro sucked You know game bro, they all sucked right every video game.
Rym: No, Nintendo power was great because it didn't even pretend it wasn't just an ad right.
Scott: but game pro At least when I started getting it was actually just as good as Nintendo power.
Rym: only it didn't cover just Nintendo But just Nintendo was all I wanted at that point from about Nintendo power one through about 90.
Rym: Nintendo was all I gave one fuck about.
Scott: yes, I don't even have any magazine in those days.
Rym: I subscribe to Nintendo power from one.
Rym: Yeah, we got every single one of those bitches.
Scott: But yeah video game.
Rym: But anyway things of the day.
Rym: So monkey magic is a band that many of you have probably never heard of.
Rym: there are Japanese Canadian like pop band And that's unique.
Rym: at least yeah and For various reasons I've been a fan of them for a while and All I want to say is this is a music video from them.
Rym: That's about Lupin the third and it's to the melody of the Lupin the third theme But with lyrics and it's animated with Lupin.
Rym: It's pretty good.
Scott: Okay, so check this video out.
Scott: Since I got my new powerful computer I've been doing what I can do with.
Scott: it is something I couldn't do before which is play a game with full settings Obviously, but more so than that I can use fraps to record the game at full settings without losing any frames Which is pretty amazing.
Scott: So I've been trying to think of awesome things to make besides boring as let's play videos and bullshit like that.
Rym: random aside Let's play has run its course guys.
Rym: You can stop now.
Scott: Yeah, I think I think we have let's play of every game But they're terrible.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So anyway, someone here gave something.
Scott: gave did something that sort of gave me a good idea and is a good thing of the day.
Scott: It is Half-Life 2 crossbow endurance.
Scott: And basically what he did is he killed 538 things with the crossbow and Half-Life 2 which is the most satisfying weapon in gaming history.
Rym: It's amazing fucking gun other than the plasma gun or the double shot.
Rym: You go to gun.
Scott: It's not really it's a crossbow It's not a gun.
Scott: Um shoots a pot rebar.
Scott: It has a scope on.
Scott: But yeah he took video of 538 crossbow shots and he used them as the bass drum for the song cotton-eyed Joe.
Scott: This video is pretty awesome.
Scott: Check it out.
Rym: So should we do a super cut of like every time you kill a dude in a game?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I'm just gonna start recording a lot of gameplay Scott.
Rym: Here's a super cut we could do beat mario 1 and super cut together every time a bad guy dies on screen.
Rym: Just Anyway, so Well, there might not be in the meta moment a lot of GeekNights for the next month or so It's a long time without a GeekNights So we're gonna try to get some guest episodes up.
Rym: But basically what's happening is PAX is this weekend next weekend.
Rym: Yeah, oh my god, if it was this weekend, I'd be in trouble.
Rym: Yeah and Independent of PAX Scott is not going home from PAX.
Rym: He's going to DC for Jenga Khan.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: And right after Scott gets back I'm probably going to Istanbul for like a week and then I'm either gonna be in Hong Kong or Singapore or possibly Germany or maybe Poland and All of the above.
Rym: Yeah, so between all this there's gonna be a dearth of GeekNights but This happens every few years when the stars align and we get busy with our real.
Scott: this is good because when we when GeekNights Returns the fuel tank will be fully stocked of fuel.
Rym: Oh also, we're going to PAX dev - so we're flying out like Tuesday next week.
Rym: Yeah, there probably won't be any shows either after today or after Thursday for a while.
Scott: Let us give you a new normal show.
Scott: If you find yourself in need of podcast and GeekNights is not available.
Scott: fast karate for the gentleman May I suggest fast karate for the gentleman.
Rym: that is in fact my favorite podcast.
Scott: I haven't.
Rym: Dave Riley is one of my favorite people.
Scott: I mean, I will honest I have not listened in years.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: It hasn't changed.
Rym: I know the one thing I will say Dave Riley stopped listening.
Scott: in the 24 era.
Rym: Dave Riley finally took me up on the offer to like for real do panels Need a panel at Connecticut for us and it was great.
Rym: and he did the same panel at Otakon and he's stepping up his game.
Rym: So you should reward Dave Riley for stepping up his game.
Rym: I'll Joe white - I keeps.
Rym: I talked to Dave more.
Rym: That's the only reason I'm saying Dave more than Joel.
Rym: Well, also Joel didn't come to Connecticut.
Scott: We can support Dave bomb is smart and move to New York.
Scott: Therefore.
Scott: He gets more Joel.
Rym: You should move to New York.
Rym: In fact, I know someone who's a roommate.
Rym: But anyway, no, I talked to Dave more but usually indirectly via Twitter.
Rym: If you want some horror fiction check out pseudopod, it's actually really good.
Scott: If you care about sports, there's this TV show on ESPN called PTI.
Scott: It's pretty much the only show on ESPN worth paying attention to because ESPN is the worst And they have a podcast.
Scott: it's pretty much just audio of the show So you don't have to watch it on cable television Especially if you don't have cable television and it's totally free and I listen to it every day.
Scott: But it's actually on hiatus for this week because of Little League World Series.
Scott: It'll be back next week when GeekNights disappears.
Scott: What a coincidence.
Rym: We will likely have guest episodes and such.
Rym: I'll try to upload a One maybe a radio free equestria of some fashion before I disappear.
Scott: and lastly, you know If you're not going to PAX and you really would need some GeekNights, even though there won't be new podcast episodes There will still be plenty of GeekNights content in the form of say videos Photos
Rym: Tweets the last thousand All of which are
Scott: online.
Scott: So make sure to go to our website.
Scott: go to Twitter's Facebook Google+ The email newsletter which you can subscribe on the website.
Rym: Who can't go to pecs, you know a lot of our pecs lectures are on our website.
Scott: Join our steam group and play kind of straight go and other games with other listeners.
Scott: There is a lot of GeekNights you can do for the next few weeks.
Rym: I wonder if they all realize that this is all just a lie to cover for the fact that we're gonna play counter-strike go constantly For the next three months.
Scott: We're all take we're.
Scott: actually it's a secret.
Scott: We're taking a week off month off of work to play counter-strike, you know If I took a month off to play I would not play counter-strike.
Scott: if I had a month off I mean I played some.
Scott: No, that would not be my activity for a month.
Rym: I took a month off to train in counter-strike.
Rym: I think I could step up to my previous former glory.
Scott: thing is I'm gonna be honest, right?
Scott: Too old?
Scott: no, if I actually had time to train at a game I would probably train at a game that needed more training like dota or something.
Rym: I Don't know if you'd enjoy dota Scott playing dota 2 at the level of the people who play dota 2 or Being that guy who single-handedly kills 14 people on the enemy team with a pistol.
Scott: Nobody is that guy?
Scott: I just you know who that guy is the cheater.
Rym: That's that guy I played on source and actually I got.
Scott: I mean, I'm already.
Scott: I mean, I'm not the greatest I'm certain.
Scott: my main problem is I'm inconsistent, you know, like one match I'll suck and one match will be awesome.
Scott: But it's like sometimes about half the time.
Scott: I'm the guy who kills two guys with the deagle like boom.
Scott: Boom.
Scott: That's it You know and it's I can.
Scott: definitely it's like it's a. it's not a luck thing because it's like.
Scott: I was trying to do it And I did it, you know.
Scott: In one then other times I'm the guy where I go around the corner and I die and I didn't even to see anybody.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Well, I think we should just talk about the show.
Scott: I was trying to segue into it.
Rym: Okay, though Last thing we are doing three events between PAX Prime and past dev.
Rym: We are doing academia versus reality psychology game theory and games.
Rym: Wednesday August 29th at 2 30 and grand.
Scott: to think people really need to know this.
Scott: if they're going they'll see us on the schedule.
Rym: Short subjects in gaming Friday, August 31st 3 30 in the wolf man and the GeekNights board game workshop.
Rym: Saturday September 1st at 8 p.m.
Rym: In room 302.
Scott: if you're going to PAX you look in the guidebook you search for us.
Scott: You'll find it Yeah, so yeah counter-strike.
Rym: So right now Global offensive doesn't appear to be beta anymore.
Scott: I thought it launched it.
Scott: When does it launch?
Rym: Well apparently right now because here are the.
Rym: here's why we're talking about counter-strike Right now the top game on steam as in total over people playing right this second at 643 p.m On Friday or Friday.
Rym: on Tuesday August 21st 68,000 people are playing Team Fortress 2.
Rym: Okay, 49,000 people are playing Dota 2.
Rym: Okay 39,000 people are playing counter-strike global offense.
Scott: So this 10. so if you take all the people who are playing Counter-strike go and add 10,000. that's when you people are playing Dota 2 and you add like few fat tens of thousands more.
Rym: now It says counter-strike global offensive not beta.
Rym: beta disappeared.
Rym: Football manager 38,000 Counter-strike at 32,000. that's counter-strike 1.6.
Scott: elder scrolls at 26,000 Civ 5 at 22,000 Counter-strike source at 21,000.
Scott: So if you add up the three counter-strikes together Now they're more than the Team Fortress 2 by a lot by tens of thousands.
Scott: So at first glance is like Oh counter-strike not as popular as tf2 or Dota 2.
Rym: meanwhile Actually for a game that is as old as shit counter-strike came out in what 1999 or 2000.
Scott: I first played it At RIT.
Scott: I played it at RIT and let me tell you I think we did a counter-strike show.
Rym: So I don't want to reiterate too much.
Rym: but basically Scott I don't know if Scott told me or I told him or what.
Scott: I just remember no CS lab guy talked about counter-strike and he said yeah when you die you don't respond and I was like wants to play that?
Rym: See I remember I started playing.
Rym: then I played it.
Rym: this looks like action quake - this is gonna be fuck and I was dead And then I'd start a new round is dead.
Scott: I think we're recapping the original counter-strike show materials.
Scott: Let's talk about CS go.
Rym: The point is counter-strike go is the game.
Rym: So I Have waited for ever For I don't know.
Rym: Team Fortress 2 tribes 2 - Civilization 5 these are games that like we're on the horizon of my life for as long as they could possibly be Duke Nukem forever.
Rym: Counter-strike go is the first game in a long time that I was personally excited about To an undue degree and when it came out the dunas was not un undeserved.
Rym: Counter-strike go is great.
Rym: It is literally just the next step from counter-strike source, right?
Scott: So, let's see What is counter-strike go?
Scott: It's counter-strike.
Scott: It is a hundred percent counter-strike, but what has changed?
Scott: Well, the first thing that has changed.
Scott: I'm gonna start with the most significant change at least in my opinion and then you can do yours, right?
Scott: All right I think the most significant change in counter-strike source is The change in the interface that puts a lot more focus on which team has won and the fact that when you play Say like a map rotation.
Scott: It's actually like you're playing to 10 or you're playing to 16 or whatever it is and I've noticed that because of that emphasis in the interface The biggest numbers are CT wins versus T wins and it you know It really gives you that terrorists win is a lot more emphasized.
Scott: I see a lot more bomb planting and hostage rescuing than in source or Original on public servers than I have ever seen.
Rym: I am going to make a minor counter-argument That we've been playing the counter-strike go beta.
Rym: it's mostly people who already know the deal with counter-strike Clanny scrimmy type people who are playing this game now to get an edge when competitive play starts for real.
Rym: But when you go to counter-strike if you and you've been playing the mode I've been playing Real mode competitive mode, right?
Rym: Which again is a self-selected sample of the people who want all of that stuff.
Scott: Well, here's the thing they change my fight.
Rym: my final minor counter-argument The all the things you're describing Like, you know, the the number of matches and switching teams and all that.
Rym: That's how scrims have worked in counter-strike source forever, right?
Scott: But here's the thing because it is encoded in the software, right?
Scott: And it's sort of the default mode.
Scott: if you go in to open up counter-strike old counter-strike Right any either of the old ones and you want to play online?
Scott: It brings up old-school server browser.
Scott: find a server and play right.
Scott: or I think this is like a quick Connect button which randomly finds a server low.
Rym: You know, I agree with you here because in that in that model I went to my like clan server and played with the same people all the sudden new counter-strike.
Scott: This is for.
Scott: it is actually four different ways to get into a game.
Scott: There's like start a server.
Scott: There's Go bring up the old-school server list.
Scott: There's all these modes but the mode I actually use is the baby mode or you would think is the baby mode which is Find game and you could find game and there's four choices.
Scott: The four choices are I want to play gun game, which is called arms race.
Scott: now I want to play demolition which is sort of a combination of gun game and regular counter-strike.
Scott: I Want to play, you know real counter-strike, but sort of casual mode, right?
Scott: No friendly fire and such and such or I want to play counter-strike for serious friendly fire on.
Scott: let's play real counter-strike And if you click either of those last two options, it's gonna put you on a server right that is running Default counter-strike five on five where bots replace missing players and You actually will you know set a number of rounds say 20 rounds first to 11, you know, 10 wins
Rym: It's best whoever is best of 30.
Rym: So as soon as you get that 16th win as a team a lot of the servers I've done our best of 20 Really?
Rym: I've never seen that.
Scott: Anyway, I've also seen the servers that are get the 16th win.
Rym: But the great part is it you play as one team and then your team's swap and you play the other side.
Scott: So if you're doing best of 30 in the fit You'll play 15 rounds as counter-terrorists and in the 16th round you'll switch to being terrorists.
Scott: Now you might.
Scott: you're gonna play a lot less terrorist rounds, right because the game is gonna end sometime there.
Scott: So you're not really playing an even number of rounds on both sides.
Scott: But it you know, if you won half the rounds the first half you then you are gonna play a full number.
Rym: So you only don't play an even number.
Rym: if you just kick the shit out of the other team.
Scott: Oh the other team kicks the shit out of you.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: But now this is the point Scott's getting at by making all these things the default for just dudes Who've never played counter-strike before.
Rym: Remember we did that panel.
Rym: the game makes the community.
Rym: What's counter-strike known for?
Rym: Pretty bad before the Xbox appeared.
Rym: before, you know, halo with voice chat.
Rym: Counter-strike was like the benchmark for shitty online community play.
Scott: now It's not even close.
Scott: every other game is way worse.
Scott: The counter-strikes community is great compared to the communities of almost every game except NS.
Rym: by making all this the default There's this sort of top-down culture of taking the game seriously playing competitively.
Scott: Yeah It's like it used to be Counter.
Scott: people play counter-strike and they just be trying to get the most kills or whatever.
Scott: Now if you are playing on one of those servers that you found not, you know Sure, if you go click community server and find some modded up server who knows what's gonna happen there?
Scott: But if you click find game counter-strike competitive the odds are you're gonna not have griefers.
Scott: It's gonna be.
Rym: people are gonna be trying to run into such Horrid griefing problems.
Scott: I have not run into any griefing personally and you know people I've played with.
Scott: Everyone tries to win the game.
Scott: They don't necessarily always try to win by bomb but or by rescue.
Scott: But there's a lot of bombing and a lot of rescuing.
Scott: whereas before people just wouldn't even give a shit who had the bomb I just be let's kill each other.
Rym: Yeah Now the thing is I never had those problems in source and one six because I played on very heavily modded You know heavily like admin queue at like awesome servers with clan people running them.
Rym: So I had people like managing all this stuff.
Rym: That's kind of the default experience for everyone's like everyone gets to experience what clan play is like to a big degree Yep, and that I think is gonna really push counter-strike culture in a different direction.
Scott: something else I really like about the new counter-strike if someone well, yeah music we can talk about I want to talk about the.
Scott: When someone drops out there's a bot.
Scott: that is you know There's bots to take over the bot.
Scott: take over the bot.
Scott: as the first time that happened to me I was like, oh my god, what a great idea, right?
Scott: It's like, of course, I'm dead But we have a bot on our team.
Scott: Obviously I want I can take over for the bot and I can be him.
Rym: Oh my god I was on a server where we was a really close match and it was like four good people on my team and then one No, which is fine.
Rym: He was like we're all voice chatting and he was like what I do.
Rym: We're like you follow this guy, but follow the bomb guy.
Rym: and he was trying.
Rym: So we're sitting there and there's one guy left and it's the bot and the bot is guarding the planted bomb.
Rym: So the noob out of nowhere says over the bus says and I quote press e to take over and everyone in the team was like no And he hits e and then he's just standing there and then he dies and then they diffuse the bomb, right?
Rym: I almost cried.
Scott: I want to tell you about the time though.
Scott: The first time I took over a bot was really uneventful Like nothing happened because the match just sort of ended and I didn't see anybody.
Scott: but the second time I took over a bot I can't basically think no one.
Scott: I was like I took over and this bot was like in the middle of nowhere.
Scott: But like the hostages needed rescuing and I had no idea was go, you know where the other team was or anything.
Scott: So I'm just like, alright, let's go.
Scott: the bot had a deagle.
Scott: I went over.
Scott: it was in Italy.
Scott: I go into the house, right and I'm looking around the house and there's you know, there's nothing going on.
Scott: I grabbed the hot some hostages and I walk out of the house.
Scott: when I walk out of the house I realized the guy was climbing up the crates to go in the top window.
Scott: as I was leaving through the bottom door.
Scott: I just turned to the right and a boom one shot.
Scott: as the bot took him out turned to left Right to start running with the hostages and there's a dude.
Scott: that dude is just at the end of the tunnel.
Scott: He comes around.
Scott: I just appeared at the end of the tunnel as soon as I started running down the tunnel.
Scott: Boom one shot Taking over.
Scott: thing is I'm like pissed because those kills don't count for me.
Scott: They count for the bot.
Scott: Yeah, I'm like no I did it but I died that round.
Rym: so I don't really deserve my most glorious moment so far in Counter-Strike.
Rym: go is So.
Rym: it was demolition not demolition.
Rym: it was a gun game and I was golden knife and there was one other guy who's never.
Scott: so I gotta tell you I suck so bad a gun game.
Scott: I'm never golden knife.
Rym: I'm golden knife 90%.
Scott: I have not golden knife, but I don't.
Rym: I've only let alone one.
Scott: I've only won one gun game so far one zero gun games and I've never even golden knife.
Rym: It is so rare that I am NOT golden knife when someone else wins and usually I'm knifed to death by one of the other Golden knives.
Scott: I'm I've never golden knife.
Rym: So my most glorious moment yet I was in that a baggage handling map and I jumped onto that ledge and I see the golden knife guy run by.
Rym: I Jumped down on top of him and golden knifed him to death from the air.
Scott: There's something about that map I just suck so bad at because even though I've never won gun game or you know arms race When I'm on the sort of jungle map, right?
Scott: I'm doing pretty well.
Scott: I'm like, you know getting to pistols and stuff.
Rym: I spawn camp the back I just hide and then I kill everyone.
Scott: I spawn as soon on that stupid baggage handling map.
Scott: I can't even get past the stupid fucking shotguns half the time run.
Rym: Just run down the ramp and up the other ramp and shoot anyone.
Rym: you see the shotguns are just.
Scott: I can't hit anybody.
Rym: You got to run down the ramp or they can't dodge you.
Scott: I'm so bad.
Scott: That's a stupid man.
Rym: No, I'm seriously golden gun like every round Golden knife anyway.
Rym: Yeah, all the other weird mods of counter-strike do not exist yet.
Rym: Yeah, which is problem?
Scott: I think there's a zombie mod that someone's already poured it over.
Scott: whatever.
Rym: We should do a separate show on how come there's this culture in PC games of these people who want to play zombies.
Scott: this dude I got this game for you called left for dead - no, here's the part of it.
Rym: It's not just zombies.
Rym: people make these god-awful like the world.
Rym: the Warcraft 3 mod for counter-strike 1 6 these god-awful garbage unbalanced like non analogous mods.
Rym: and there's like Maps the worst tech like who plays these games.
Scott: I actually kind of really like bad maps.
Scott: I want counter-strike.
Scott: go icy world real bad the icy world.
Rym: I could make a great argument that it is actually a great map I'm talking about like crack house or pool.
Rym: those maps in stock Actually played a lot of gun game in that man.
Scott: I hate that.
Scott: I actually kind of like the gun game Lego II map with the upstairs and downstairs.
Scott: That one's okay, but their mods of it is like it comes into all different very always like scouts and knives.
Scott: No gravity I actually like the crazy orange Gun game map from counters like source.
Rym: No, you know what?
Rym: Here's the only problem with counter-strike go.
Rym: the only bad thing I have to say about it right now There's a. there's only a small set of maps.
Rym: So there's no militia yet.
Scott: I also don't like how you have to choose Demolition or hostage mission.
Scott: It's like I want to sort of mix it up.
Rym: guys You know that.
Rym: you see if you want to choose for real you join a server that has a rotation you like.
Scott: Then I gotta find.
Scott: I gotta like search for like SV pure and stuff like that.
Rym: No, you've just got to know a good clan.
Scott: I gotta start a service.
Scott: I'm gonna do.
Rym: that's what we're gonna do.
Rym: Yeah The thing is I like my anarchy death clan dudes and I feel like I want to play with them more than I want to play with you guys.
Scott: anyway, I'm gonna go and Let's go down the list of the other things that are new and kind of okay.
Rym: So the crosshair is somewhat contentious but I found a pretty big survey and a counter-strike forum and it seems like about it's about 60/40 like hate of the new crosshair the default one.
Rym: I Think it's great.
Rym: And I think anyone who says otherwise doesn't understand it and is stupid.
Scott: Yeah, I mean it had you know, the old counter-strike crosshair would spread out showing you that your you know Weapon spread is you know getting wider.
Rym: and this one does too.
Rym: But you realize guys it has two different spreads and it shows a ton of information If you pay attention to it, right it shows you.
Scott: basically the spreads at different ranges is what it's telling you.
Scott: It's also.
Scott: it's a lot like the grenade launcher in NS one.
Rym: It's also showing you the difference between running walking and what the difference will be if you stop running to start walking And it turns into that X if you're aiming at a friend.
Scott: that is the best part.
Scott: is the X aiming at a friend especially when you're aiming at something because when you have a high-resolution screen and Basically a black dot through some smoke and you you're aiming through the smoke.
Scott: You'll get the X like hey don't shoot That's your friend which is important on the competitive friendly fire server.
Rym: now along those lines That crosshair is very important because the biggest most important change is that you don't pick You know Arctic or whatever.
Rym: You just get a model and the models for the characters are thematically set to match the map.
Rym: Yep, so when you're on he forgers to style banter and everything.
Rym: This is how we will get our freedom.
Scott: Yep, so it's like the revolutionaries on this map.
Scott: or you know the the sort of urban terrorists on that man.
Rym: This remove the GI GN.
Scott: Have you noticed that on the Italy map?
Scott: It's the GI GN which makes no sense.
Rym: It depends.
Rym: it could be a foreign force.
Scott: The GI GN do not belong in Italy.
Scott: They should have some Italian.
Scott: It's a foreign force.
Scott: I think there'd be an international incident if the GI GN went to Italy.
Rym: Uh, probably We're already remember counter-strike.
Rym: I read this interview a long time ago.
Rym: I'm paraphrasing based on my memory of 2001. ish Someone's saying that counter-strike or it was designed to begin the game the moment when negotiations broke down.
Rym: The game is literally between.
Rym: when negotiations break down and either all the terrorists are dead or the terrorists or the hostages are rescued.
Scott: Other realize that the problem is in the real world.
Scott: if counter-terrorists lose More counter-terrorists show up and the terrorists are still.
Rym: well because the terrorists got their objective which was Blow up the arms depot, right?
Scott: But then the terrorists are escaping and now you're chasing them.
Scott: That's a different game.
Scott: What if it's a rescue the hostage mission though?
Rym: So maybe if you don't rescue the hostages then the diplomatic instant happens Because you realize it's like the Iran affair or that Russian thing where if you send the Counter-terrorists to actually rescue the hostages and you fuck up Sending the next round is usually not what happens instead.
Rym: There's political involvement and internationally terrorists are still there with their hostages.
Scott: They got to do something.
Rym: Yeah, but that's a different game.
Rym: Okay, this game is just when the president says send them in All right.
Scott: What else has changed in this new version?
Rym: So the models changing removes one minor element that I used to like which was using Arctic guy in the desert.
Rym: I used Arctic in every map because when I killed a motherfucker I wanted him to remember it was me and that I didn't even need the camouflage.
Rym: I'm this standout white ass dude in the middle of the desert with the deagle and I still killed you.
Scott: I picked whichever guy I felt like on counter-terrorists.
Scott: I always pick GIGN no matter what I was Arctic all the time.
Scott: On terrorist I chose either Phoenix Connection or nerdy glasses guy.
Scott: I only chose Arctic if it was snowing and that was even sometimes.
Scott: I didn't do that.
Scott: and the fourth terrorist guy I never picked ever but the the bandana guy never.
Rym: now there is no meta advantage of choosing one over the other because they're set to the map.
Rym: but - By having it themed like this coupled with the music which I think is very artfully done It'd be very very easy to ruin counter-strike by adding music and making it more Call of Duty ish or some other.
Scott: I think the music is very NS ish, right?
Rym: Yes, because it tells you what's going on in a very subtle way like bomb gets planted suddenly.
Scott: There's the music of uh-oh Yeah, it's not like it's a song playing while you're playing the game.
Rym: It's like that Hans Zimmer style.
Rym: Yeah, it's.
Scott: the music is action movie music letting you know what's going on.
Scott: It brings more of that old action quake natural selection into the counter-strike sort.
Scott: of.
Scott: you know It's if you think it would be unpure because it wasn't in the ever in counter-strike, but actually it's bring it's coming it's it's a it's sort of a What's it called the genetic thing where suddenly your kid has red hair?
Scott: The recessive gene of the action quake has reemerged and the counter-strike go but this is expressing itself.
Rym: So the immersion the banter the themed character models and the music together Basically make counter-strike go.
Rym: a perfect fusion of 1/6 in source in that Plus an upgrade of modern technology.
Rym: It was not immersive.
Rym: 1/6 was a sport.
Rym: It was it was not immersive.
Rym: It is, it exists, it still is.
Rym: Yes, I did not in any way think of it as an immersive.
Rym: like I am this counter-terrorist.
Rym: I was not involved.
Scott: I still don't think that.
Rym: but but playing the game I am much more immersed in the in the game world.
Rym: because of all these elements which source did better?
Rym: because it was Technologically better, but source was less of a sport.
Rym: for reasons I don't want to get into because we're not talking about that if you disagree with me.
Rym: I'll simply say that right now Counter-strike go because it just went live is the number one game.
Rym: Counter-strike 1/6 has been consistently more popular than counter-strike source Forever yeah, and counter-strikes basically once go came out.
Rym: source lost a ton of players.
Rym: 1/6 didn't lose any.
Scott: yep The let's talk about the fire right the molotovs and the incendio grenades.
Rym: I use those as area denial highly effectively.
Scott: That's pretty much all they do is area denial But they are awesome.
Scott: because what I tend to do is you know It's that one thing you really need in counter-strike is you go down a hallway and you can go right or you can go left.
Scott: But you're so worried.
Scott: What if I go left?
Scott: I'm Turning my back to the right.
Scott: a bad guy could appear it.
Rym: I still will appears.
Rym: Run through fire.
Rym: I ignore he grenades because Grenades you can ignore in a clan match.
Rym: that doesn't work, but against puppies.
Rym: Yeah They don't expect me to come through the flame.
Scott: But now right when I turn left I can throw the flame to the right and feel a little bit safer About doing that.
Scott: whereas before it was you just had to sort of Slowly turn back and forth real quick until you got around the corner to make sure nobody was good.
Rym: You know where I use it the most on Aztec.
Rym: rather than sniping the the bridge I'll just wait at the bridge for like 20 seconds, and then I'll just flame the edge of the bridge.
Scott: You know what I remember I still do.
Scott: I still play on Aztec my old strategy secret staircase secret staircase down.
Scott: Throw the grenade from below the bridge up into the other side Distracting those guys so that my snipers win the bridge.
Scott: then go up the other secret staircase.
Scott: a first time Aztec loaded when I played CSGO I did my secret staircase cuz I'm like.
Scott: is it still there.
Scott: It's still there.
Rym: bitches not like one Kuwait for you get there, and it's not there anymore.
Scott: I popped up on the other end of the secret staircase.
Scott: The whole other team was there not even looking at the secret staircase.
Scott: They were all looking down the hallway or into the room.
Scott: I shot one dude in the back started shooting another guy, and then I died, but that's how it goes.
Rym: really You should have headshot it because it doesn't much better.
Scott: How was I supposed to headshot for dudes?
Rym: Before click.
Scott: after I killed the first dude they started looking at me.
Scott: I'm lucky.
Scott: I managed to even hurt a second dude.
Scott: Scott.
Rym: It would take two seconds to click on forehead.
Scott: They weren't all together in one lump.
Scott: They were all you know.
Rym: yeah Yeah, this is why we're not a team players.
Rym: We're not top tier counter-strike, and I had a p90.
Scott: it wasn't like.
Scott: I was right on top.
Scott: You know I wasn't that close they were.
Rym: so the guns.
Scott: right now the shotguns are Slightly opie, and I you think the shotguns are opie, so yes, I think the shotguns suck Are you kidding?
Scott: I can't hit shit with Unless you're really close, which I guess was shotgun supposed to do, but I think especially that stupid sawed-off one.
Scott: Oh fuck that are you kidding?
Rym: that thing is the one of the best gun.
Scott: it can only hit the broadside of a barn.
Rym: Yeah, you know how much damage that does from a surprising distance.
Scott: I can't hit anybody with.
Rym: maybe you just suck.
Rym: I have not played on the same server as you yet.
Rym: I think we need to do some versus gun game.
Scott: I did not hit anybody with the soup and when I play gun game it used to be when I played gun game in the original old gun game.
Scott: You know I would.
Scott: it would start off with the AWP and I'd be like fuck.
Scott: And I would basically until I as soon as I got past the AWP then I'd be on a roll.
Scott: I start killing everybody right, but it took me like one or two rounds.
Scott: I always be behind and those one or two times when I got a kill with the sniper rifle right away I'd be set cuz then I'd buy my way past the stupid scout And I'd you know I'd get right through to the end unless you get knifed.
Scott: unless I got knifed which happens sometimes in The new gun game you don't start off with a sniper rifle you start off with like what this Like the mp5 or something right, so I'm like hey, and I get right into it You know, but then when I get to the shotguns I'm just like oh, I can't fucking kill anyone.
Rym: with the way this is I can't get close enough to anyone.
Rym: I am the best in any game in terms of just my kill ratios with submachine guns and shotties Rather than the rest with submachine guns and assault rifles because the SMGs have a very low spread even when running.
Rym: Yeah, and there's that new SMG that doesn't slow you down at all.
Scott: Yeah, it doesn't do a lot of damage.
Scott: That doesn't matter.
Scott: headshots, baby Yeah, I mean the thing yeah usually a headshot with it, but it's still.
Scott: I prefer p90 and mp5.
Scott: Those are my guns and AK and m4.
Scott: I mean m4.
Scott: I mean the game even sort of tells you that the m4 is the best gun.
Scott: There's these little hints when you're waiting for stuff to load and one of the hints are is like yeah The m4 is great at medium range and with practice It's great at long and short range too, and it's like so.
Scott: basically the m4 is the best which I already knew.
Rym: They ruined counter-strike though.
Rym: There's no silencer on the m4.
Scott: Yeah, I Are you kidding?
Scott: I know I got the m4 and I pushed secondary attack and nothing happened.
Rym: So I got the m4 and I pushed secondary attack and when it didn't happen I thought oh this must not be the m4.
Rym: It must be some other gun.
Rym: and I just didn't notice.
Scott: Models did change a little bit.
Scott: So like the mp5 looks different.
Rym: Is it just me?
Rym: or the models actually look kind of shitty and like low res.
Scott: they don't look shitty and low res.
Scott: It's just that the low polygon count.
Scott: like they look cheap not for me But what they?
Scott: the thing that bothers me about them is they don't look the same.
Scott: So it's like I can't tell I have the mp5 because it doesn't look the way.
Scott: the mp5 looked in old counter-strike Because you see less of the gun.
Rym: I yeah You don't.
Scott: you don't see.
Scott: you see like the top of it more than the side Because it's you don't get that.
Scott: it's more like it's closer to doom than the sort of.
Rym: so you haven't talked about the decoy grenade.
Rym: But I think it's because based on our conversation earlier.
Rym: You didn't know what it did.
Scott: I didn't know what it did.
Scott: I didn't really experiment.
Rym: So here's what it does.
Rym: if you throw it it makes sounds like whatever gun you have For a while.
Scott: So now here's the thing.
Scott: It's uh, oh it sounds like whatever gun you have.
Scott: yes, I thought it always sounded like assault rifle.
Scott: No Because I was like, you know this shows how much I didn't know.
Scott: I was like.
Scott: if someone throws one in round one It sounds like a star rifle in train.
Rym: when I'm CT when we're not terrorists, right?
Rym: I'll run way past the dumpster that long haul where there's the big ambush that always happens.
Rym: Yeah by myself the whole rest of the team rushes some other way.
Rym: I don't care which way they go.
Rym: I throw smoke fire decoy and then I throw all the grenades smoke fire decoy And I also shoot.
Rym: so if the counter-terrorists went that way they think we rush that way and they come back to fight.
Rym: You'd think they'd figure it out.
Rym: They've never figured it out.
Scott: You can have one person completely fake a rush using all the grenades.
Rym: now the trouble with the decoy is that Prince of Nothing style the numb finger doesn't feel the barbs.
Rym: a Decoy doesn't do anything against a nub.
Rym: I Throw a decoy around like I threw a decoy and I'm running away and to see a nub just kind of walk around the corner.
Rym: It's like right toward it.
Scott: It's like dude.
Scott: Didn't you hear this gunfire?
Scott: Why would you go there granted?
Rym: I just turned around and shot him anyway, cuz he's a nub.
Rym: He didn't know.
Rym: but yeah, oh My god, I love counter-strike the other thing in this game right?
Rym: other other other thing.
Scott: Yeah, I mean well, there's a million other things.
Scott: the thing is suffice it to say because it's a new counter-strike I really want to shoot people and practice shooting people.
Scott: So I will often against my best interests Go to somewhere.
Scott: I'm gonna get shot and die.
Rym: I will also just because it's more boy It's more exciting than hanging around with the hostages Because they're hanging around with the bomb because there's so many nubs I rush Because I don't get to do that when I normally play counters, right?
Scott: So I've been doing a lot of stupid shit.
Scott: just because I want to get into a gunfight Even when the gunfight is not the place.
Rym: I got any dust.
Rym: like regular dust.
Rym: I'll just fucking run out into the middle with like a pea 90.
Scott: I'm right I played dust.
Scott: I played regular dust twice right both times.
Scott: I just rushed bombsite a 100% and no one was ever there.
Scott: Everyone was like messing around with the tunnel.
Rym: I'll run into the apartments and then I'll like hang back or like duck into the sniper room and like set up an ambush.
Rym: I'll wait maybe five seconds for I give up and just keep rushing because no one's gonna come no one goes.
Scott: bombsite a. You could just go there put the bomb away.
Scott: And it's like we went a like ten times in a row.
Scott: Nobody came there until after he planted the bomb and then as soon as they came through those wooden doors I dig it dig it dig it again.
Scott: It does.
Scott: I'm like guys.
Scott: When are they gonna go to a here and meet us there?
Scott: and they never met us at a until after we planted the thing.
Rym: After this rush of noobs, I think I'll do most of my play on either our own servers or The clan servers that I used to plan.
Rym: I got to figure out when the clans will have their servers.
Scott: I think I just want to set up our own server.
Scott: That is the way to go.
Rym: Is it gonna run gun game or what?
Scott: Well, no I think what will run?
Scott: normal counter-strike Reels and then since it's our server if we want to do a gun game we can do that.
Scott: But I think most I think by default I mean I even kind of want to leave it public.
Scott: so I'm thinking like by default We'll leave it as like public.
Rym: We'll make it private when we do scheduled events.
Scott: Yeah I think I'm thinking like public regular counter-strike when I'm like at work and shit.
Scott: and then when we're playing we can take it Over you can make a private we can make a gun.
Rym: Yeah, cuz what I want to do is I cuz I'm not I'm good at counter-strike.
Rym: This is my game.
Rym: I've been playing this game from almost day one.
Scott: You know, that's the thing that really upsets me is like, okay I'm better than nubs, but I'm not great as you can, you know tell by not winning game.
Rym: I'm a really good skier.
Rym: I do double black diamonds.
Rym: I'm really crazy all over the mountain and some 80 year old dude or some ten-year-old kid will just fly by me Thousand times better.
Scott: No, but what upsets me is that I've been doing this shit since 12 years and some guy Who's been playing it for like a month will come and kick my ass like because that guy's been playing it for a month Straight.
Scott: I've been playing.
Scott: if you add Ten years Twelve years if you all my counter-strike playing together.
Scott: It's at least six months.
Rym: How much of a gap was there between when we kind of stopped playing source and recently?
Scott: does it really matter?
Scott: I mean, yes, it does think about DDR.
Rym: I didn't play DDR a lot for like a year and a half.
Rym: I started playing again.
Rym: You know what I couldn't do the nine footers anymore without some practice When I started playing.
Scott: go again, well, I better go home and play counter-strike to get those skills back.
Scott: Yeah, maybe I'll get the golden knife someday.
Rym: I might at mag fest if they have the PC area set up go play some counter-strike I.
Scott: that is one thing I am curious about.
Scott: right and I've always been curious about this is I know that there are people Who are better than me right there.
Scott: is that as a fact?
Rym: you want to know why they're better.
Scott: They're just better.
Rym: I'm Scott.
Rym: No, I Plan a lot of like curated passwordy clan servers, you know what.
Rym: the people who are better, you know We talk about geeks versus nerds.
Rym: They are all Counter-strike nerds.
Rym: right that is their thing one, but there are also people who cheat.
Scott: there are cheating people not that many.
Scott: There are still some.
Rym: it's hard to cheat in the modern era of counters.
Scott: You'd be surprised.
Scott: They're there.
Rym: What do you base that on?
Scott: I'm just saying they're they're cheaters out there.
Scott: Alright, I really want to because I never have play counter-strike in a closed environment.
Scott: This is the thing if I play counter-strike in a public ever.
Rym: I had that experience, you know land parties We don't go to that much.
Rym: I used to when I was right for so Many years ago me and Scott Johnson.
Rym: We're running some anime content for some con somewhere in Rochester.
Rym: I think it was No, no, it was some other bigger better con.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Well astronomical was the sci-fi con.
Rym: This was like an anime and gaming con.
Rym: So it was like 11 o'clock at night midnight and we went over to the land and there was counter-strike.
Rym: So we're like, alright, so we sit down and the two of us Were just neo.
Rym: We were accused of cheating.
Rym: we killed Everyone.
Rym: right we are our team.
Rym: just literally our entire team would die except Austin.
Rym: We would single-handedly kill everyone plant the bomb to the point that people were getting pissed off and looking around the room looking figure Who we were right?
Scott: So this is what I'm saying is I have only ever played counter-strike.
Scott: 99% of my counter-strike play has been on a public server where there's someone who's way better than me or In a private server with only people I know in which case I'm sort of the best
Rym: I've played on clan servers where it's everyone I know at least in the context of the game and I can spectate them They're not cheating.
Rym: They're just that good.
Scott: There are people I you know, they could be cheating.
Rym: I know but I'm saying they're.
Scott: they're generic sort of direct X level.
Scott: I want to play at a LAN with people.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I've had your experience with people.
Rym: I know are not cheating.
Rym: There are people who are that good.
Scott: What do they do that?
Scott: I haven't learned in 12 years.
Scott: What do I do now?
Rym: What we could have been that good and in fact We were close to being that good at RIT when we played counter-strike every day for multiple hours.
Rym: Yeah We don't do that anymore.
Scott: Also, we're older now, how am I supposed to win gun?
Rym: he's got our bodies physically slow down.
Rym: I have beaten max 300 and you know what?
Rym: I think within a few more years I will not be physically capable of doing so again.
Rym: I'm serious.
Rym: I have slowed down as a human being.
Scott: I did turn down my mouse sensitivity for this counter-strike and that helped a lot.
Rym: Oh Scott also steel series my like fancy mouse raw mode.
Rym: It's it's it's great.
Scott: Yeah, my mouse is also a gaming mouse.
Scott: it's a logitech g5 whatever something something.
Rym: this thing's got a screen on it.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Yeah, whatever.
Rym: It's pretty good.
Scott: Mine is also pretty good.
Rym: I'm also wearing it out.
Scott: Let's say this show is too long, ah, it's not too long.
Rym: Well, yeah, it is too long because I'm gonna go play counter-strike.
Rym: This is Suffice it to say counter-strike.
Rym: go is the next evolution.
Scott: It is the same.
Scott: It is counter-strike.
Scott: It's just modern for modern machines and modern Sensibility as I predicted and modern polish.
Rym: It did not affect the numbers of cs16, but it is decimating source.
Rym: I predict that as time goes on No one's gonna play counter-strike source except nut jobs and The majority of counter-strike players will be playing.
Scott: there will be a few thousand.
Scott: There'll be a few thousand people playing.
Rym: Yes, not jobs.
Rym: I think counter-strike one six is going to maintain its thirty to fifty thousand players until those people until those people die.
Rym: so a Lot of new people are continuing to join that counter-strike community.
Rym: Yeah, that's I was playing some one six the other day and you know what a lot of the people on the voice chat way young.
Rym: It's kind of like Starcraft these.
Rym: they join this community because they feel like it's a more pure competition kind of like how to this day.
Rym: I think that lithium to deathmatch is is to me a better like Competition of certain kinds of skills in the deathmatch.
Rym: quake style then quake three.
Scott: Well, the thing is lithium deathmatch.
Scott: while it is very great It has many weird things like the grappling hook the grappling hook.
Rym: You hold a button and a grapple shoots out.
Scott: Yes, but I mean it has a lot of weird crazy things like grappling hooks.
Scott: That's the only weird crazy thing I think it is.
Scott: I remember having a couple other crazy.
Rym: Yeah, the runes which are identical to dolar and quite three.
Rym: Don't You guys realize Doubler the doubler in quake three.
Rym: It was only in the last year that Scott and I realized that they were saying doubler.
Scott: No, I learned I knew that they were saying doubler a long time ago.
Scott: But the thing is it was so rare that a map actually had the dough.
Scott: Most maps just have a quad damage and that's it.
Scott: Very few maps have the dolar.
Rym: Scott.
Rym: lithium deathmatch has the same runes.
Rym: It's not different.
Rym: The only difference is that you know quake two weapons quake two maps, which are actually much more three-dimensional.
Rym: I like quake two maps a lot better than quake three maps are no good Yeah, but it also had that that one change the grappling hook which made everything more three-dimensional.
Scott: Yes, but it's sort of it's has a little bit of that ridiculousness to it that no Scott you are ridiculousness.
Rym: So there's a mod where instead of the laser grappling hook, which is pretty straightforward It's a grappling hook.
Scott: you swing and throw it with physics.
Rym: So you had to bind four buttons to use this grappling hook.
Rym: grapple ungrapple draw in reel out And let me tell you that was crazy bullshit that I really enjoyed.
Rym: but I understand that most people would not enjoy that.
Scott: Yeah Counter-strike grappling hook at it.
Rym: Oh counter strike.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.