Rym: It's Tuesday November 12th 2013.
Rym: I'm Rym and this is GeekNights tonight games of the yard.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: So yeah finally got Google Glass.
Scott: It's uh join the club.
Rym: it is Exactly what I expected because unlike a lot of people out there I had perfectly reasonable expectations based on my own research, okay I knew what it would be like.
Rym: it's about what I expected and the only interesting thing I can really say about it is that I'm finding I Don't know I feel like I got used to it really quickly and as a result whenever.
Rym: I'm not wearing it.
Rym: I periodically already kind of every now and then look up and then nothing happens.
Scott: Well I mean for you right you're already a glasses.
Scott: That's the thing.
Rym: I already wear glasses so wearing Google Glass has no physical disruption in my life.
Rym: wearing them and not wearing them is the same.
Rym: So I don't notice a physical presence, so I don't.
Rym: unless I think or pay attention I won't really know if I'm wearing glass or not.
Rym: I just kind of always assume that screen is there and then occasionally it's not there because I'm not wearing the glass of wearing my other glasses.
Rym: But I did a lot of research and while I can get the prescription Semi, maybe or maybe not official Setup sometime next year.
Rym: I ain't waiting.
Rym: so I found an optician who is willing to make me custom Prescription lenses that will clip in the same way.
Scott: that I'm so rich.
Scott: look at me I'm so rich, so here's the deal.
Scott: it money money.
Rym: You know Scott I were talking about this.
Rym: all the things that aren't made by Google that are related to glass Seem to be things that are aimed at people with a lot of disposable income perhaps due to the overlap of demographics.
Scott: Well, I mean when you have a luxury item the accessories market for it is gonna be other luxury targeted things, right?
Scott: It's like if you're selling Ferrari accessories, you're not selling cup holders.
Scott: Okay Right.
Scott: so for glass is the same thing.
Scott: because glass is a high ticket luxury item all the accessories and apps for it are also a high ticket Targeted tour.
Rym: Here's the thing Are several hundred dollars anyway at minimum.
Rym: so getting custom Lenses with a custom mount bespoke lenses Yeah, you know well You know.
Rym: as an aside I used the word bespoke at work in reference to some.
Rym: I was making a joke and I was always Say here's an artisanal character sheet.
Rym: I was like here's a bespoke alert rule template for one of our products.
Scott: What about a?
Scott: Is it hot?
Scott: go to her?
Scott: How do you pronounce it?
Rym: So every everyone involved in this conversation with one exception was like bespoke What?
Rym: But then the one person who knew that term was left.
Rym: He laughed and then explained it to everybody and then he was like really only a hair.
Rym: it used in reference to designer custom clothing Not other things.
Rym: but then he pointed something out interesting that He's noticed that tech people have been using the term a lot in reference to technology over the last few years And that's a recent trend in his mind and his experience.
Rym: and I will admit that my first encounter with that word was a glove.
Scott: My first encounter with that word was some hipster place and then yeah for me.
Rym: It was bespoke Fox.
Scott: No, right Yeah, I knew what the word meant when I read that comment.
Rym: Well, I was able to assume from context what the word meant.
Rym: So I hint all you kids out there, especially your younger kids, you know how to read.
Rym: Yeah, really you can.
Scott: you are your literate.
Rym: I don't know I've.
Rym: I've run into a problem lately in my interactions with younger listeners.
Scott: They're young.
Rym: They're not literate, but though You can figure out the gist of what a word means not.
Rym: if you're not literate guys Guys, it's not that hard.
Scott: You're illiterate then you can't.
Rym: that's I mean.
Rym: Maybe I say that my has too much spleen.
Rym: then maybe maybe there's some trouble with that context.
Rym: But yeah, I like Google Glass.
Rym: I rigged up a sort of custom prescription lens in the meantime that It works fine Except it looks like the kind of glasses that an unfashionable dad from the early 80s would wear Like these insert.
Rym: these lenses are not designed for humans to see.
Rym: they're supposed to be inside of my ski goggles.
Scott: They're not for humans to see they're for dolphins Doll.
Rym: why would a dolphin see them skiing goggles?
Scott: you'd imagine if you're a fucking near-sighted dolphin you think like Oh, man, that shark is way far away.
Scott: I'm sure I'm cool.
Scott: That's all the ones that are get caught in all the nets of the fishermen.
Scott: Maybe that.
Rym: but near-sightedness doesn't mean things look further away than they are.
Scott: In fact, things are more means you can't see shit.
Scott: That's far away.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: It means the further what you're.
Scott: I'm safe here.
Scott: There's no sharks around.
Rym: Your focal point is actually close so you can focus on things that are.
Scott: you can see Google Glass itself.
Scott: You just can't see them.
Rym: So here's how bad my vision is also because of the way they project the glass image.
Rym: Because though it's interesting the first thing everyone asked me was not the dumb questions you get but the question was always the same question.
Rym: So where is the screen?
Scott: who's asking you this?
Scott: people on the street or people that you already knew?
Rym: one person in the subway?
Scott: No one ever asked me that question ever.
Rym: one person who I was playing ingress and then the guy was also playing ingress and he Was like yo dog got Google Glass.
Rym: Where's the screen that you show?
Rym: Where's the screen?
Rym: show up?
Scott: that should give you some I don't know.
Rym: It's hard That's right there.
Scott: That's also sort of a dumb question because it's like Where else it's?
Scott: on my left where?
Rym: Like people don't know like most people still think it's a heads-up display and Google is not Disavowed normal people of that notion.
Scott: Yeah, it's like you have a little rectangle TV in the corner.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: It's about like a hand like put your hand out as Far as your arm will reach in front of you and then twist your palms.
Rym: So your palm is facing you.
Rym: it's about there and about that bit.
Scott: It's like there's a see-through TV just sort of floating around.
Rym: Yep in the top right corner but if I don't have the prescription glass in I Can't see the Google Glass screen.
Rym: It's out of focus.
Scott: if I ever had to compete at you with anything and the stakes are not low as they usually are You're gonna knock my glasses.
Rym: Yeah, you know what if I'm ever competing you and with you and something where the stakes are Sufficiently not low?
Rym: one of the growing in the ball - because you won't see it coming - I'm not wearing Google Glass.
Rym: I'm wearing like my ski goggles.
Rym: If we're having some sort of Locke Lamora contest then all bets are off.
Scott: I was stabbing.
Scott: I guess You don't have any stab armor.
Rym: I could.
Rym: I just saw an ad Randomly for a stab and bulletproof suit.
Rym: Spoke.
Scott: Maybe I'll do the.
Scott: who is the guy from Australia Kelly?
Scott: Ned Kelly, that's my new strategy.
Scott: Ned Kelly aka the world's first weeaboo Armor plus guns can't lose.
Scott: Well did lose Six year dudes.
Rym: So the only other thing I'll say about glass now and we'll talk about it later once You know write apps and play with it and we've talked about it before is this It is worth the price of admission as is if they never add anything to it just for the turn-by-turn GPS enabled bike navigation,
Scott: but I don't have that.
Rym: Yeah, I cannot like.
Rym: I expected it to be okay.
Rym: So what I did?
Rym: the first thing I did I took glass.
Rym: I walked out of Chelsea market.
Rym: after I was all done in there I got on a city bike and I said Google glass navigate whatever and I told it to navigate me somewhere specific and far away In a neighborhood.
Rym: I didn't know and then I just biked there and the directions were so perfect and so easy to use.
Rym: I Cannot express to you how much I love having that there and I can't wait to drive with those navigations in my eye Mmm, and the battery runs out in the middle of the drive.
Rym: Yeah, so I already experimented with that.
Rym: the using the navigation does not seem to diminish the battery life at all.
Scott: Well, that's because the phone is doing most of the work.
Scott: Yes, and your phone battery dies already driving.
Rym: So so the phone the the screen only turns on when it turns coming.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I know I have it.
Rym: Yeah But you haven't used the navigation.
Scott: No, but I know that the screen old turns on hardly ever.
Rym: yeah, but the screen turns on every time there's a turn coming up or there's anything weird coming up and It also plays a little tone and tells you through that awesome transducer speaker that works perfectly.
Scott: Mine doesn't work.
Scott: Perfect.
Rym: I know mine does.
Rym: I don't know if there's anybody upgraded it mine.
Scott: Basically if it beeps and if someone calls me on the phone it tries to use it to be like for the phone call.
Rym: But then it just sounds like see I got the cool little earbud you can stick in.
Scott: now They're gonna make stereo earbuds.
Scott: Yeah, they are is gonna be good because then it's like oh, I finally have Bluetooth headphones.
Scott: Okay, I was one of those no wires.
Rym: Yep But yeah, we'll see.
Rym: I like Google s a lot and I'm gonna try to write an app for it at some point in the Next month.
Scott: you will not succeed.
Rym: The mirror API is so easy to use.
Scott: That's the web API.
Scott: You can't really do much with it.
Rym: I know I'm not going to try to write anything real yet because I don't want to go down the road of Android development.
Rym: I'm gonna use the mirror API and make something dumb and useful and assume that I'll have internet when I would use that thing.
Scott: Mm-hmm Yeah, my computer just all messed up like anyway What you do.
Scott: it is Tuesday, I guess Explorer crashed or some shit.
Scott: Anyway, I know my news is so.
Scott: It's gaming day.
Scott: It's Tuesday.
Scott: Maybe we should actually talk about that.
Rym: All right game time, right?
Scott: One of the games that we don't really like is pandemic.
Rym: In fact, we have lectured in multiple unrelated lectures in a section about how much we hate pandemic and how we think it's a bad game from Almost every bad game.
Scott: So they're coming out with pandemic the dice game and this seems to be happening a lot lately where you have a game and then They come out with like the same game again.
Scott: So like Tigris and Euphrates the card game or What are?
Scott: there's a lot of them that have card games and one Right.
Scott: There's like you have a big game and you make some other version of us to make pen.
Scott: They're coming out.
Rym: I think next year with pandemic There's that there is the dice monopoly that came out way back in the day, right?
Scott: They're coming out with pandemic the dice game and I predict it's gonna be bad.
Scott: I read the description of it and Basically, it sounds nearly identical to pandemic.
Scott: So every problem that pandemic has this game also has.
Scott: the only difference is All right.
Scott: that from what I can tell based on a description and not reading the rulebook.
Scott: So this isn't final.
Rym: Well, I'm basing my opinion based on literally nothing.
Rym: So go on.
Scott: right is that it's identical to pandemic but Instead of that deck that reveals like where shit appears right your old ice and Each player right the different rolls has different dice and on your turn you roll your dice and whatever they come up.
Scott: Those are the actions that you can take.
Scott: instead of being able to take, you know, any combinations of actions.
Scott: You're more limited by luck.
Scott: right because you roll these dice.
Rym: I assume you can yah see the dice.
Scott: I don't know it didn't?
Rym: You can't yah see the dice.
Rym: fucked up guys who knows.
Scott: but it's the point is is that it's a You know, it's a it.
Scott: otherwise it seems clearly identical to pandemic based on the rules that were described.
Rym: I was burned by this a lot of like I remember.
Rym: so why it's like this new Frades card game?
Rym: just It shared these superficial similarities, but was just kind of bad Right.
Scott: So the reason this is weird to me is because usually when they make these You know other versions of games like something something the card game or something something the dice game.
Scott: right that new version of it Bears some mechanical similarity But is usually highly simplified and shortened and more portable and has these other features that you know.
Scott: It's like yeah, you can't bust out T&E right now, but you can bust out this card game, right?
Scott: this seems Like it's not less than pandemic.
Scott: It doesn't seem to take less time or play faster at least based on the description.
Scott: So why it's like they're just trying to.
Scott: it's like why would you play this instead?
Rym: Well, you know what it does do.
Rym: it removes the need for a big board and abstracts it Completely sure.
Rym: You just have a little circle disc.
Rym: It looks like for each continent and then you put dice that you've expanded or used or whatever on those Continents.
Rym: Yeah, and there's a little circle track that looks like a cribbage bridge score track.
Rym: Yep Yeah, I'm gonna assume this is bad.
Scott: Also the picture the dice look like it doesn't seem like it actually solves any of the problems of pandemic.
Rym: I would argue that for the people who like pandemic and for the people who make pandemic None of those things are problems because they like the game.
Scott: I really wish there was some data collection on board game playing because I get the feeling right.
Scott: you look at something like Pandemic and it's hugely popular.
Scott: It sells really well Like
Rym: I go to a convention and
Scott: and there
Rym: are fourth at the tables are playing some very much Right,
Scott: there are people clearly they exist who are into it right like they are, you know they're playing a lot of munchkin or They are playing a whole lot of pandemic and that's their thing and they're into it.
Scott: But I get the feeling that maybe a lot of people like they play it a few times and they're right Some sort of churn right and then they're not into it, but maybe they'll play a few games sometime later, right?
Scott: But they they're into it then they're not into it.
Scott: and then another wave and it's like a wave that passes over The community and at any time at any given moment.
Scott: the hump of the wave is large Which is why the game is popular.
Scott: because you know, it can it can it spreads almost like a you know A fractal kind of.
Scott: however, the hump is big like a pebble falling into the water.
Scott: It spreads.
Rym: the hump is big enough that it would imply a but the middle of the ingress of people getting into board games.
Scott: Well, you know, even if it's not people getting into board gaming It's you play the game and then you play the game with new friends and then you play the game with right?
Scott: Ah, and I think that's what if you think about.
Scott: if you think about a circle, right the radius keeps increasing But the only players are the people who are around the edge of the circle and the middle of the circle isn't really playing The game very much at all.
Scott: So I wonder that's what I think it might be.
Rym: I think there's there's a two-step going on.
Rym: I think you're right.
Rym: I never considered that angle.
Rym: So I think there is a huge churn through games like pandemic.
Rym: But - I think there's a there's one other factor because there are other games that people churn through that you don't see Around like you see pandemic.
Scott: Well, there's less vibe.
Rym: I think the less popular is actually just a. I think they're.
Rym: you know, there's some kinds of people who play a game Eventually figure it out enough to where it's not fun anymore and other than teaching or occasionally Like I'll play settlers once they come every few years.
Rym: They don't play it anymore.
Rym: But there's some people and I think they're a good like quarter or third of board gamers Who I don't think they have the capacity to get bored with a game that they like.
Rym: No, like they but they never get good at the game.
Rym: They're like the scrubs in the fighting Culture like fighting game culture the people who never really get good enough to be good But never are bad enough to not have fun and they enjoy playing the game and constantly play it and never improve themselves.
Scott: There are people who come to play netrunner Every single tournament, right?
Scott: They just they're at the bottom.
Scott: They've been playing as long as I have.
Scott: they keep showing up They keep playing they keep buying cards and they still at the bottom of the tournament every time I don't win.
Scott: I came in second once but I you know, I started like middle-ish and now I'm sort of higher middle-ish and I'm moving up slowly very slowly You know, so that sure, you know, it's like I'm getting better at it.
Rym: There are gods I can't assail and so so my other thing is I think there's a pretty high overlap between the kinds of people who like pandemic and the kinds of people who like all those house on Haunted Hill Arkham whatever kinds of games obviously.
Rym: and I think those core people who never get tired of these games or Don't play them enough on a regular basis to get to the point where they'd be tired of them are the ones maintaining this core That draws the churn in.
Rym: they're the guys who are at the gaming club and they're there every week playing pandemic.
Rym: So every week one of the new people who shows up plays pandemic once with them.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So speaking of another game you guys might remember candy box Candy box - is that?
Scott: yep.
Scott: I played candy box - I only play candy bags - a tiny bit.
Rym: it had some more Game mechanic mechanics in it a whole lot more.
Rym: Yeah, there's a lot to do and it was pretty fun.
Rym: But then I cheated.
Scott: cheating was slightly more difficult to do than in candy box.
Rym: Yeah I tried to give myself just a infinite candy and that worked.
Rym: but then spending that candy didn't actually work because I messed something up.
Rym: But I digress candy box one.
Rym: I didn't cheat.
Rym: I just beat it by waiting a few days and then playing the game.
Rym: But there's another form of candy box known as all those games on the 3ds that just make you wait for people and then Turn those people through.
Rym: nothing games.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Well, the one the one game is not a nothing.
Rym: What game is a not a nothing game?
Scott: The shmup is not a nothing game thought.
Rym: All right, that is Exactly one planks hair width above a nothing game.
Scott: It's a shmup.
Scott: It's a legit shmup.
Rym: It's not terribly legit not fucking Ikaruga.
Rym: So is there any reason to play that shmup over say an emulated copy of Galaga on your phone?
Rym: Other than for the candy box purposes?
Rym: Captain candy pants.
Scott: It's more of a great I'd say it's more of a gradius than a Galaga.
Rym: I picture Scott saying this from inside of a candy box more of a great stomach exposed and gorged on candies.
Rym: So there is another candy box game that many of you are not playing and I played it a whole bunch.
Rym: So I'd be able to talk about it.
Rym: ingress.
Scott: Oh not cookie clicker.
Scott: Fuck cookie clicker the ultimate in candy box.
Scott: In fact, the guy who made cookie clicker specifically said he was inspired by candy box.
Rym: Ah, I guess it is in the same class.
Scott: It is getting by.
Rym: so ingress I would say is it by Niantic Labs, which is really Google.
Rym: It's like through Google.
Scott: I was surprised this thing took off because usually when Google makes shit like this it just bombs.
Rym: So from what I've read Google gave them unprecedented latitude to do whatever the fuck when they made this game and as a result, they made the game kind of however they wanted let them stick with it.
Scott: even after failing.
Scott: they just kept trying.
Rym: so I Got into the early early beta and proceeded to not play the game at all Because my old Samsung Nexus s was not fast enough to render the effects and I couldn't fucking play.
Rym: Like if I wasn't way out in furthest Queens the game would work, but there's like one portal out there.
Rym: great But then it was when I was in Manhattan.
Rym: portal density is subject to population density.
Rym: So there's like a hundred portals that I can see at any one time and my phone just couldn't deal with it.
Rym: So I didn't play until I got my new Nexus 4 and then suddenly I could play.
Rym: so I played.
Rym: I leveled up It's candy box, of course, and it's surprisingly popular.
Rym: It seems to be most popular among College kids like people who are in college.
Scott: Yeah, cuz that's where you have a density of people savvy enough to play the game.
Scott: also cities.
Scott: You can't play this game in the burbs?
Rym: Well, you can but then you know, it's funny cuz in the burbs.
Scott: But if you're if you're a kid in the burbs and you've got a Android phone and you're playing this game Okay, so you can make portals at school and portals.
Scott: at your house.
Scott: It may be a portal like at the place you get piano lessons.
Rym: And so here's the way the game works if you played it at all.
Rym: Do you have any idea how it works?
Scott: I don't have an Android phone.
Rym: All right I have a bunch of invites to.
Rym: if any of you guys want them.
Rym: I just keep getting them and ever use them because everyone I know who wants to play the game has an iPhone.
Rym: So the way the game works is there's an overlay of the world.
Rym: Magic dust is falling from the sky Landing all over golden compass style.
Rym: so you can join either the resistance or you can join the enlightened.
Scott: I would definitely just based on the names.
Scott: Enlightened.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: Also enlightened is green.
Scott: Oh Definitely enlightened.
Scott: Oh, here's the deal.
Rym: The enlightened believe that wow power's come out of this dust.
Rym: Let's use it to Transhuman.
Scott: Yeah, okay.
Scott: so I'm still on the enlightened side.
Rym: the resistance is worried about their powerful ramifications of this space bullshit and wants to fight against it and Wall humanity off from this awesome power.
Scott: so Republicans.
Rym: Yeah, pretty much Okay, so you can either play as an awesome green person or a shit bird blue person.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: No red.
Scott: It's not red.
Rym: There's only two factions green and blue green and blue.
Scott: Well fuck blue.
Rym: So the way it works is there's portals that are out there.
Rym: There's a separate mechanism where you can submit Places and pictures of things to to them and they slowly like new portals appear in places.
Rym: But just you submitting a portal has nothing to do with the gameplay of the portal.
Rym: If you find a portal you can deploy resonators around it.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Rym: And when you apply those then the portal starts building power and building power and you can hack it and get shit out of it Like guns and stuff.
Scott: Mmm guns what?
Rym: what weapons?
Scott: Okay Bursters XMP bursters is what they're called, but their guns use the magic dust falling from the sky to make guns.
Rym: Well, that's one thing we do because we're not the people who are being trans human Like the being trans human does not what we're?
Scott: wouldn't only the resistance make guns.
Rym: We both make guns.
Rym: We're the people who are trying to use these portals to gather the dust and accelerate humanity toward this trans human Awesome.
Rym: So what do you do?
Rym: is you hack the portals and then you can link multiple portals together and the distance You can link is based on the level and power and energy built up in the portal.
Rym: So if you make a field by enclosing an entire area with links between your colors portals Then that area is in your zone of control.
Rym: the population of humans under that is now points for your side Mmm, so it's a fairly straightforward game.
Rym: You're trying to cover the globe in your color and block the other guys.
Rym: So you might make a. you might coordinate with.
Scott: how's New York looking?
Rym: New York is all over the place but right now there's a big Huge fight going on downtown around City Hall and the entire area around City Hall Park is flipping from green and blue on a daily Basis.
Rym: and you're going on my way home.
Rym: yesterday I blew up like eight portals claim them for my team and captured like four or five hundred thousand human points All right, and then the next day Queens looking some eighth level asshole.
Rym: So Queens is kind of a weird battleground right now.
Rym: There's this huge green area.
Rym: That's very heavily controlled.
Rym: It looks like there's three or four high-level dudes.
Rym: We've just got that shit locked down Mmm, but there's a bunch of blue creeping its way in.
Rym: so I shoot at it every day on my way to work Like the seven passes this one set of portals.
Rym: It's every damn like pew pew pew pew pew pew.
Rym: as many shots as I can Get in while I pass.
Scott: Oh, that's you're using the guns to shoot at the portals.
Scott: So you can get guns out of the portals to shoot the portal.
Rym: you get guns and resonators and items out of the portals.
Rym: You can upgrade portals with different things like turrets and whatever and if you hack a portal and it's your own team's portal You get a lot of stuff out of it.
Rym: If you hack an enemy portal a lot of time it just starts attacking you.
Rym: hmm and That's pretty much a high-level dude.
Scott: You can take the enemy portal down.
Rym: Yeah, and I can.
Rym: There's max level right now is eight.
Scott: So how come you with all this playing?
Scott: You're still not level eight.
Rym: Uh, no, cuz I've only been playing for a few weeks and also more candy bun Refused to coordinate with people or power level or anything because the community is fucking intense.
Rym: Like people are really into this get in on it.
Scott: So Take City Hall.
Scott: That's so.
Rym: I'm an opportunist.
Rym: All I do is I watch and whenever there's trouble I'm there and I help out.
Rym: Although three separate people have messaged me because they saw my me doing stuff like this.
Rym: all in our resonators.
Rym: They're like, are you the GeekNights Rym?
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: I'm such a fan.
Rym: Hey Hey, hey That's part of the reason why I'm not engaging too much in the community.
Scott: Oh you get so people see when you do stuff Like.
Rym: if you go like if you set up a portal like you captured it your name is on it Basically forever unless you lose it.
Scott: Where's the Rym portals?
Rym: Uh, all the Rym portals have been destroyed except for one right now But I have resonators with my name on them on tons of portals.
Rym: Mmm, cuz I leave I upgrade people's things.
Rym: I do like ng work.
Rym: The game is fun, but it has the problem that all Augmented reality games have.
Rym: they're just candy box.
Rym: if you're willing to do more things than the other team and Coordinate slightly more you just start winning.
Scott: Candy box is not doing more things.
Scott: It's waiting.
Scott: just patience.
Rym: Ah, but this one's also patience.
Rym: You can just.
Rym: you can wait to accumulate enough stuff and then go do a thing when you have enough stuff to where it would.
Rym: Okay, okay, but the difference is that.
Rym: imagine if candy box and cookie clicker were combined.
Rym: So candy box is just going.
Rym: you can just play or you can click to get extra candies.
Rym: So it's more like the candy box of the 3ds games where if you're willing to go through the bullshit You'll level up way fast and be way powerful.
Rym: And if you're just willing to go all the puzzle pieces if you're willing to do this shit every day Everywhere you go, you'll get powerful really quickly and have a big impact for your size.
Rym: So it's fun, but I'm not going to get any more involved in it than I am now.
Rym: I will play it idly like I do all other candy box style games.
Rym: if you care a lot about this game And you're one of those life stylers like.
Rym: I see all these pictures of people who got legit tattoos.
Scott: Yeah What?
Rym: because Google's got.
Rym: there's some contests going on where they're good.
Rym: they're trying to track down like the five coolest agents and give them shit and Sometimes you'll get like media and missions and stuff out of these portals like specific missions You got to get done.
Rym: I saw the New York team for the enlightened Coordinating this big thing where they had to.
Rym: there's a portal on governor's island The ferries not running there anymore right now not now.
Rym: Yeah, so The the enlightened still hold the portal.
Scott: It's got like one resonator on it But no one can go there to put anything else on it.
Rym: So a few people have portal keys to it like sometimes you can get a portal key for a portal and then you can do stuff with that portal remotely.
Rym: So they're trying to coordinate getting a huge link like many miles between that Particular portal and some other portal way off in Jersey Because that'll it'll basically cut the blue territory in half.
Rym: So there's this big operation going on.
Scott: I Don't know.
Rym: It's moderately fun, but it's Nintendo 3ds candy box in the end.
Rym: So I got five forty five and it's five forty five.
Rym: well, I got five forty five and it's five forty five.
Scott: Gotta get a whopper and a 40.
Rym: Fuckin feel me.
Rym: Actually, it's more like six fifty two, I'm glad it is.
Rym: So I would rather be five forty five right now, but I'm glad that I have more than five forty five.
Rym: So you might remember a charming a little video about the true history of Sodom and Gomorrah, I Think we made it things out.
Rym: I'm named after Gomorrah named after an even worse thing.
Rym: So the real Brad Neely has a YouTube channel and that is where that is.
Rym: The real Brad Neely is still making stuff and I stumbled upon this video that the song has just been stuck in my head.
Rym: I have nothing but good things to say about it because it is exactly what it needs to be.
Rym: This is kweeblow episode one Whopper and a 40. just watch it.
Scott: Two things that I will not eat or drink.
Scott: Speaking of eating and drinking.
Scott: Some of my favorite people in the world have made a return to the internets.
Scott: Oh, no the internet celebrities.
Scott: Yeah Here they come.
Scott: they have come back and they have brought us a new series.
Rym: The series is such a good idea.
Scott: the food warriors.
Scott: What they are doing is they're gonna ride the a-train and at every stop on the a-train They are gonna find what people are eating.
Scott: episode 1 168 Street an area.
Scott: I know I have been there quite a few times.
Rym: I biked through a lot in the summer Yep, and now I know the names of four restaurants that seem good.
Scott: Let's go there and eat at el president.
Scott: We should make our own YouTube series following the food warriors and Malecon And all of these good restaurants that are up there and then Let us see the next stop on the a-train and eat at those locations as well.
Rym: These guys do everything that I like on the internet.
Scott: This is like the highlight of my day nay week nay month the fact that they are back.
Scott: They have been away for a while.
Rym: We're going all the way all the way back.
Rym: Oh, there you go.
Rym: Yeah Alright, you're not good at saying to you cuz it's up to you it's not my culture but black dynamite like that.
Rym: so in the meta moment the book club book is I do by William Gibson, I've already read it but I'm gonna read it again because I one liked it and two I want to be able to intelligent conversation about it.
Rym: I just finished the Lac Lamora book the sixth book that I heard one while waiting for Scott to finish Stasi land.
Rym: And it's okay.
Rym: No, we don't need to do a book club book on it.
Scott: It's okay You're a lock lever up and you probably want to read it.
Rym: Yeah, it's not great.
Rym: It is the weakest of his books By far, but it's okay.
Rym: We got a bunch of videos on the internet.
Scott: We do.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: We're gonna be at magfest Probably doing a 90-minute version of bad games what we did at PAX Probably also being on one or two of the Mages panels renamed from the gaming intellectuals with a lot more people.
Rym: We will be moderating and/or speaking on these panels And there'll be other people on them too.
Rym: So unlike our usual lectures, you'll see us arguing with and being Somewhat adversarial toward other people in this industry dum-dums And also non-dum-dums.
Rym: Yep, you know who you are.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: Paxis is sold out.
Rym: So yeah, too late.
Scott: Paxos almost.
Rym: Paxos almost sold out.
Scott: So I'm gonna get ready for PAX Prime tickets.
Scott: Watch your Twitter every day.
Rym: I'm seriously considering just Reserving a hotel room now for PAX Prime outside of the con rate at a considerable expense.
Rym: All you Because I'm well actually Seattle's not so bad because the furthest hotel away is like a five-minute walk to PAX Red line unlike Boston.
Rym: I mean, yeah.
Rym: Anyway, this stuff's all sold out.
Rym: We're gonna be at all these things.
Rym: probably not us, but maybe us.
Scott: Someone else pays for it.
Scott: Ah, there's any benefactors out there who want to buy me a plane ticket to Australia.
Scott: That's all it takes.
Scott: I will pay for the hotels and other things while I'm there.
Scott: if you would like a bespoke panel Yeah, I mean if you buy me a plane ticket, I will do something for you in return.
Scott: That is within my power and is a fair Exchange.
Rym: we have considered seriously at some point launching a Kickstarter for us to return to PAX Australia Do the panel do the video do a bunch of specific shows.
Rym: I ran it by some Kickstarter people.
Rym: They said that as long as the deliverable is shows and content and not us just going to PAX Then it's fine.
Rym: But I don't know if I'll do it because it's a pain in the ass pull out together.
Rym: I might go without Scott.
Rym: We'll see we'll play it by ear.
Scott: so if I don't go there I'm going somewhere else.
Scott: if you
Rym: really want to see us at another PAX Australia either Email us and convince us to do a Kickstarter give us a pile of money or Somehow convince packs that were worth flying out and considering that they didn't fly out a lot of people who are cooler than us Probably not likely they're gonna fly us out.
Scott: No, but you can.
Scott: only thing is like, you know It's like if they fly us out, they're gonna fly us right the fuck back.
Scott: They're not gonna like.
Scott: let us, you know pay for us to hang out there a long time.
Rym: Oh, no But the way that works like when I fly for work right because I'm going and I have to come back.
Rym: Anyway, they buy my plane tickets, but if I want to come back a week later, they still pay for the plane ticket But I'm on my own when I'm not on their time, of course.
Rym: So I don't think we I think we're getting ahead of ourselves with the let's get packs to fly us out.
Scott: That's never gonna happen ever.
Rym: Um, so yeah also our forum is super upgraded.
Rym: So if you and super expensive if you recently or at some point in the past used to go to our awesome forum and stop You might want to come back.
Scott: It's uh, it's never like tried to register and failed or Anything like that.
Rym: you quit because there was a feature that you wanted.
Rym: that wasn't there.
Rym: It's the forum is so much better joined for some weird reason.
Rym: Our forum is an ivory tower set on to the withering masses.
Scott: Looks.
Scott: everyone can see what's in the tower.
Scott: It's totally transparent and not ivory.
Rym: It's the transparent tower, but it is nonetheless a tower.
Scott: Also, if you had a tower made of ivory you would totally go to jail.
Rym: Did you see that government's destroying?
Scott: That's why I thought of that that multiple tons of ivory.
Scott: I still I'm not sure like why I don't get it.
Scott: It's like how does that?
Scott: Make them not want to kill elephant.
Rym: So if they resell the ivory you don't want to do that either.
Rym: So what put it all in a museum?
Rym: Yeah They already filled and that part of the article said that they have already given all the ivory that every museum and outreach group wants.
Rym: Okay, like they don't have any more Non-selling uses for it.
Rym: They've already pulled out all the actual historic artifacts all the.
Scott: does it have any practical uses?
Rym: Uh No, you know someone on FARC said something like really someone should work on an ivory substitute.
Rym: and the second post was Yes, it's called plastic It's true.
Rym: Yeah One guy was like my piano that has ivory sounds and feels so much better.
Rym: and then the rest of the thread was everyone calling bullshit On that guy, of course the rationale I read for them destroying the ivory was that by destroying it?
Rym: They won't prove a point to reduce.
Scott: the point that he proved is we will catch you.
Scott: Look how much ivory we caught.
Rym: but also they reduce the supply of ivory which while on one hand you would argue would increase the That's what you would think.
Scott: Yeah on the other hand and increase the demand as well the less ivory Wasn't on the market.
Scott: Anyway, the harder it effectively was already destroyed.
Rym: in those regards It's not the less legitimate ivory There is out there.
Rym: that remains.
Rym: the harder it is for you to explain yourself if you've got some ivory.
Rym: So it's easier for them to get people who they find with ivory on them.
Scott: But who's gonna get that ivory?
Rym: Well, no one now.
Scott: Well, I mean even before it was destroyed who was gonna get it?
Scott: Well, it was in a vault somewhere.
Scott: right vault.
Rym: try just unlock government warehouse.
Scott: I mean, yeah, that's yeah Probably more expensive to put it somewhere safe.
Scott: That's just sending money for nothing.
Rym: So when I was a kid, one of my favorite lawn games was bocce ball.
Scott: Well, I only played bocce like maybe a handful of times.
Rym: I kind of want to get a bocce set.
Rym: It's a good game to play.
Rym: I like bocce a lot.
Scott: You don't need a set.
Scott: if you come up to Astoria and Steinway and there's some courts there Play with the old guys.
Rym: One of the apartment buildings that we're looking at to maybe move into in a year or two has a bocce Arena on the roof.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: So yeah old people must live there.
Rym: bocce ball I don't know.
Rym: It's this.
Rym: it's the same game as horseshoes effectively for all intents and purposes sort of same gist.
Rym: You're trying to get something close to something else closer than other people.
Scott: You know, there are subtle differences.
Rym: You can't disrupt another person's horseshoe the way that you can disrupt another person's bocce ball.
Scott: Oh, they got a leaner.
Scott: you can mess it up.
Rym: I see you're deep in the terminology lingo.
Rym: I'm gonna throw the jack ball.
Rym: so far.
Rym: You can't even get it out there.
Scott: Yeah, so one time I was Speaking of bocce, right?
Scott: I have less experience with bocce, but I have experience with something else.
Scott: I was going to Whitney Museum, I think and I heard something happening a few blocks away.
Scott: So I went to this a few blocks away and there was this street that was closed off in Manhattan All right and they were playing this game.
Scott: that looked a lot like bocce, but it wasn't bocce.
Scott: and I was like What is this game?
Scott: and they were everyone is speaking French and there was like a French sponsorship and everything was French.
Scott: Oh, and I was like, whoa, is this like the street where French people live?
Scott: What is going on here?
Scott: And I couldn't figure out what it was because everyone was speaking in French II and I was like what the hell couldn't even pick out any cognates.
Scott: and you know, it's it's easier for me to do Spanish than France II.
Scott: so Eventually, I figured out the game they were playing was petunk Petunka which is very similar to bocce and it's actually really interesting petunk.
Scott: Yeah, PETA and QUE.
Scott: and it's a really interesting game.
Scott: and here's how it works.
Scott: You throw out first this sort of Object, I guess it's a jack of some kind, right?
Rym: It looks like it's the same as the jack ball in bocce, but it's like a metal thing I think.
Rym: well in bocce It's just a smaller ball.
Scott: Yeah, I think in this one.
Scott: I think it's like a metal ball.
Rym: Anyway, small wooden ball ball called a caution nets Yeah.
Scott: And then you throw out the basically the bocce balls and you're just trying to get close to the first one right just like similar to bocce, but here's the way it scores is Whoever has the closest ball Gets that balls gets points, right?
Scott: So let's say I have the closest ball and you have the second closest and then all the other balls don't matter Because I I have the closest one.
Scott: That's the only one that matters All right, so I get a point and you get nothing because mine was closer.
Scott: Let's say I have three balls that are close and your ball your closest ball is the fourth closest.
Scott: Then all three of mine score.
Scott: so I get three points because your closest was the fourth closest.
Scott: if my closest is like the fifth Closest then you get four points or I'm right.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Nice diagram.
Rym: Okay, so the big balls are metal.
Rym: The jack ball is a little lime looking thing.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: But yeah, it's it's right.
Scott: so bocce They're sort of like wooden or stonish kind of weird material.
Rym: Wow, there's a. there is a Pretty intense standards organization around this game.
Rym: Yeah The jack they were playing must be made of wood or of a specific synthetic material must carry the maker's mark and have secured confirmation by the Fi.
Rym: PJ P. Yep The tolerance is there is one millimeter for a 30 millimeter ball.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Yep Oh glossary or special terms.
Scott: All right telling these people are really serious.
Rym: Lob is not a special term guys Lob is a generic word.
Rym: Oh You can.
Rym: you can get a metro fanny.
Rym: to win the game without the opposing team scoring any points is a To fanny the opponents.
Scott: Yeah, right if all of your balls are closer than all of their balls then you Say he made fanny.
Scott: That's the best possible Fanny.
Scott: that's like in shuffleboard when all your guys are on scoring points and all their guys are in like the - and must kiss The bottom of a girl named what?
Rym: Wikipedia.
Rym: Okay, something about fannies anyway.
Rym: I Learned about bocce when I was a kid because it was a popular sport among old people who lived in Detroit in the Midwest And whenever there were garden parties or lawn parties or block parties The old people would all go play bocce in this one backyard.
Rym: when I was a kid Yeah, so I would always go over there because I kind of didn't like all the normal little kids in my neighborhood.
Rym: So I'd go over with those old people and be super polite until they'd eventually let me watch and/or play bocce with them.
Scott: Hmm for us it the kids are the people who wanted to play lawn type games.
Rym: The adults didn't want to do anything In the Midwest they had like lawn games were the thing to do as an adult at a party.
Scott: Yeah, adults didn't play lawn games really except kids would like maybe try to force them.
Scott: And of course our number one lawn game was wiffle ball.
Scott: Yeah, not forget any of these others.
Scott: I mean, you know, there was an occasional badminton Big up on badminton or this ghetto soccer Or capture the flag.
Rym: I don't know if capture the flag is really a long game.
Scott: It was for us.
Scott: use the whole lawn, but you can see everybody.
Rym: is it just tackle like how do you do it?
Scott: the way we would do it back in the day is You would basically one half of the lawn in front of the house is one side and the other half of the lawn the other Half of the house is the other side, right?
Scott: All right, and You would basically just grab someone.
Scott: if you could just grab someone and just drag them to the jail Then they were in the jail until someone rescued them, right?
Scott: And you rescued people in the jail by going in and getting them out you see to get to the jail which is in the enemy territory and then The flag would just be fucking hidden somewhere and the other half of the lawn see to get over there.
Scott: You know, you could sneak over there possibly by doing trickery like, you know, you'd play in the dark, right?
Scott: So you sneak like into the neighbor's lawns sneak up and then hop into the other backyard Where no one saw you hop in.
Scott: then you have a few minutes to look around for the flag.
Scott: Maybe you could run fast grab it and get away from everyone, you know, so it's a combination of speed One person running and making a sacrifice as someone else can make a move Pushing someone down and going past them, you know all kinds of maneuvers were available.
Scott: You know some woods areas bordering some of the people's houses you could take advantage of.
Rym: so I guess one thing I'm noticing is that the lawn games that kids tended to enjoy Tended to be pretty super serious for the kids involved.
Rym: like their full focus and I remember I was the same way Was on the game, of course Even if the rules were kind of loose the kids would focus on the game a hundred percent and all Socialization was based around the game.
Rym: Mm-hmm I've seen some adults do that like the old people playing bocce 100% focused on the bocce.
Scott: Is it?
Scott: kids and old people and nerds all of the same mind and then everyone else not?
Rym: Yeah, the everyone else.
Scott: it seems like it's like you go to an old.
Scott: you go to an old play old folks place in Florida, right and it's like I'm playing shuffleboard.
Scott: kids are playing shuffleboard.
Scott: Grandpa's playing shuffleboard Everyone's trying to win at shuffleboard.
Scott: And what's the conversation?
Scott: Hit is hit is 10.
Scott: You can bump them into the - you can bump them in.
Scott: they'll go for it Right or no?
Scott: play it safe.
Scott: Don't?
Scott: we already got a lot of points.
Scott: Just don't knock our points out.
Scott: Just just you know, don't even try to score.
Scott: just push it real easy.
Scott: It's the last.
Scott: it's the last buck, you know.
Scott: But everyone else of any other age group or non nerd Leaning would just like sit by the pool talking.
Rym: or well I think what it comes down to is that the the ideal lawn games are games that can serve both purposes.
Rym: They can serve the purpose of a serious focused competition, which is easier for kids because kids seem to be able to make Games that don't have rules somehow very competitive and serious in a way that no one Smarter or older will ever be able to do.
Scott: I think what it is right is you look and you know Board games and stuff and there's the serious games right that we play right like the ogre that just showed up.
Rym: Oh my god, that ogre box is so big, right?
Scott: but then you have the apples to apples and the cards against humanity and the party games in Basically long games are the party games of sports, right?
Scott: It's like you're not gonna play fucking NFL football you're gonna play Croquette you're not gonna play PGA golf You know or anything like that you play badminton.
Scott: It's like it's Apples-to-apples is to.
Scott: you know, Puerto Rico as I don't know Horseshoes is to like for example.
Rym: Tokyo is a simple example.
Rym: You can play that game super serious and have the social interaction center around the game while you're playing it.
Rym: Sure, but you can also play it casually where you're putting most of your attention into the game.
Rym: But you're socializing in equal parts.
Rym: And I think the the optimal lawn games are the ones that allow for both.
Rym: They have some Reasonable real ortho game component.
Rym: There's a real competition there.
Scott: Well, it's usually it's usually sport and that it's some sort of actual dexterity skill.
Rym: Yes, right something physical you have to do but so it is an ortho game sport in some capacity.
Rym: the closer to like You know jungle speed and it is serious or difficult enough Requires enough skill to where you can have meaningful social interaction Centered solely on the game like you can't have meaningful social interaction around a game of tic-tac-toe Even though tic-tac-toe is an ortho game.
Rym: Sure, but there's no.
Rym: how many Sentences can you say related to a game of tic-tac-toe?
Rym: while you play it with someone you win.
Scott: It's time.
Scott: It's time It's time.
Rym: So as a result these games are perfect when they are both an ortho game But to do not require the full attention of the players such that you can choose to socialize Solely in the context of the game which is good for kids who may not you know know each other that will or anything else to talk about and is good for Old people because they want the game to be the focus.
Rym: They're tired of talking to all their old friends.
Rym: They want to just play this game and the game provides a social context.
Rym: but they also allow the in-between where you're kind of half socializing about the game, but using that as a Also.
Scott: the thing about them is that while it is possible to have a high level of skill right at games Of this nature right like you can be Olympic badminton gold medal.
Scott: Oh my god, right, but Badminton's not like tennis.
Scott: or if you suck you can't do anything like yeah, you can hit it.
Scott: It's kind of slow ish, especially when the other people hitting it aren't Olympic badminton people So it's it's like a sport that's accessible.
Scott: Anyone can actually play this and have a meaningful contribution.
Scott: horseshoes It's like yeah, you if you got professional horseshoe persons getting a ringer every fucking time almost just like a bowler get you know Professional bowler gets mostly strikes and spares with a few nines and eights and not really anything less than that.
Scott: But you know if you throw horseshoes and you've never done it before You'll score some points.
Scott: You're not gonna get zero.
Scott: get something.
Rym: I feel really bad newborn baby.
Rym: I feel really bad for the guy.
Rym: listen to the show who's never scored a point in horseshoes.
Scott: It's like yeah, listen you stand there and throw enough horseshoes.
Scott: you measure is unceasing you're gonna hit it.
Scott: it's gonna happen Right, you know what?
Scott: I noticed it's really popular lately Even though I never played it.
Scott: the game where you have the slanted wooden board with a hole in it and you throw bean bags Trying to get in the hole.
Scott: Oh Cornhole, I don't know.
Scott: I guess that what it's called I see bringing that to the beach.
Scott: I seen people playing that in football stadium parking lots while tailgating.
Scott: I see that game everywhere and it's like oh, yeah, it's something everyone can play.
Scott: It's got a skill to it, right?
Scott: You know and it's it's actually can actually be pretty intense because you throw that thing and it's like slides up the board after it Hits.
Scott: so it has a little bit of that golf action where it's like Yeah, that's cornhole.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Yeah cornhole.
Scott: It's that is the popularity of that has been increasing wonder I know way that did not become popular on its own either.
Rym: It was in some TV show.
Rym: that's popular or Someone like made a version of it like a Hasbro and then marketed it.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: There's no way it became.
Scott: it has become popular.
Rym: Maybe it has some hipster kish.
Scott: I have been seeing hipster cache.
Scott: It's not hipsters.
Scott: I see playing it I see normal people doing it, but it's I see more and more of that game every year in various places.
Scott: I did not expect to see it.
Scott: It used to be like a thing that you would see and like Summer camp maybe and that was about it.
Scott: And now I'm seeing it and all sorts of other places.
Scott: So It's not too bad, you know.
Rym: I remember we were at Scott Johnson.
Rym: Our friend had a huge party at his new house and he did long games.
Rym: Or there's such a good idea for large gatherings of people who might not all know each other because he left his badminton set just set up in the backyard and People were rotating in and out and basically playing badminton For the entire day like 14 hours.
Rym: at any given time.
Rym: at least two or four people were playing badminton Constantly and it sort of it focused people who weren't immediately interacting socially on a on an ortho game and gave them a context for their further interactions and Caused like the conversation pieces to shuffle in and out.
Rym: and it caused it was like a stirring rod inside of the party As and I say that because the people there was a set of people who it was hot so they stayed inside.
Rym: there was one part of the house that was air-conditioned and a chunk of people were in that place and never left it.
Rym: and Every time I peeked my head in there with the same people and the conversation was shall we say?
Rym: stagnant This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brand ok for the logos.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.
Rym: So tonight there's a party at this girl's house.
Scott: I think we're cool because with stamps I always help her out.
Scott: She is fine, but her friends are kind of this and thatness, but with me I better help her find her in a Katniss.
Scott: So I dance with my manage Vance asking if I could just get a friendly payment advance.
Scott: He blows me off so I scoffed on my smock.
Scott: check the clock take it off check my wad feeling soft.
Scott: all I got is five forty five and it's Gotta get a whopper and a 40.
Rym: Well I got five forty five and it's five forty five.
Rym: Gotta get a whopper.