Rym: It's Wednesday January 30th 2013.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott and this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight we're talking about saga and Star Wars the comics.
Rym: Let's do this warm today.
Scott: Yeah, kinda relatively speaking.
Rym: I would have biked to work.
Scott: I would not have why not?
Rym: it's super warm out.
Rym: I would wear shorts and a t-shirt in weather like this.
Scott: I needed about five more degrees and a hundred percent less of water Raining right now.
Scott: it is mad wet and even if there's not raining right now if you bike in the wetness I've had the problem many times the strip of filth down the middle of the back.
Rym: Yeah, you gotta wear something dude.
Rym: It's over 50 degrees with a 100 percent chance of severe rainstorms.
Rym: Oh Wow Showers and thunderstorms.
Rym: What's the weather tomorrow?
Rym: Breezy and showers.
Scott: What's the weather the next day?
Scott: No, what's the temperature on that day?
Rym: 36 degrees?
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Guess what?
Rym: It's not gonna get cold again, but it's not biking season.
Scott: It's gonna be 50 degrees again tomorrow.
Scott: It's not biking season It's biking season.
Scott: No Biking in the fall when it's 50 degrees.
Scott: I'm stopped by.
Rym: really I bike until it's like well below freezing like 20 degrees.
Rym: This is when I won't bike anymore.
Rym: No Anyway, remember last show we did.
Rym: we're like, yeah all this stuff happened.
Rym: Let's be sure not to forget about all the cool things we did for like the two weeks.
Rym: We're doing gig nights.
Scott: It's the last show he did wasn't it two shows ago?
Rym: Well the last show we didn't do a show on Monday.
Rym: I remember.
Rym: I don't remember we didn't do one on Monday.
Scott: This is what probably.
Rym: how can you?
Scott: So you want to talk about something else that happened over the New Year's break?
Rym: We had like a hundred awesome things that happen that we didn't talk about.
Scott: All right, so you remember one of them?
Rym: Nope, not one.
Rym: Oh, I went skiing a whole shit ton of times and I had some awesome ski times But I remember what they did.
Rym: In fact, I went to Hunter Mountain this previous weekend which is actually after at the show where we said there's a bunch of stuff and It had snowed a whole bunch and there were like snow Valleys on trails that are normally flat.
Rym: It was awesome.
Scott: I Got one.
Scott: You got one.
Scott: I got one.
Scott: got one when we were getting on the bolt bus to go to magfest.
Rym: Oh, right the crazy yelling star was a crazy.
Scott: You're basically I don't know what happened.
Scott: I think it was just a situation of narrow bus aisle guy was trying to push past a guy, right?
Rym: Well, we are.
Rym: There was a prelude to this because apparently outside the bus the same guy had an altercation with an unrelated person for an unrelated reason Really?
Rym: I didn't know that with this guy as far as I can get my guess my gut feeling.
Scott: He's just an angry guy.
Rym: he's one of those guys who is both angry has poor impulse control is Prone to feeling like other people disrespect him and feels like he needs to assert his manliness and get respect From people around.
Scott: or maybe he's just a nut with a problem.
Scott: Anyway, so apparently this guy, you know, we're just sitting on the bus waiting to take off.
Scott: people are loading their shit on.
Rym: We're doing our thing like me and Scott and chase was talking about, you know, we're having the same conversation.
Scott: Everyone in the bus hears this guy saying like oh you lucky, you know I'll fuck you up.
Scott: Fuck you up kick your ass.
Rym: I'll fuck anyone else.
Rym: I'm looking at me.
Scott: Yeah, he's basically like really threatening this dude.
Scott: Like, you know, you're lucky whatever.
Scott: I didn't beat the shit out of you.
Rym: I'm pretty sure.
Scott: what happened in this case was the dude was Standing there and slightly bumped into him a little bit on a bus or maybe walked past him because he was in the aisle And he needed to get to a seat or who knows what.
Rym: it's one of those kinds of guys.
Rym: So the guy's causing all this just being really like yeah, and the whole bus just sitting there looking at him.
Rym: I got my camera out videoing.
Rym: cuz I'm waiting for you to YouTube.
Rym: good heaven Stop looking at me.
Rym: I'll fuck anyone up.
Rym: So then bunch of people go out and they're like, yeah, this guy's causing trouble.
Scott: So I so I go to fill and I'm like if that guy starts anything We're all jumping up at the same time, right?
Rym: Let me and chase and fill are all like just count to three and everyone's like yes The bus driver comes back on the bus pretty much right away and he's like their problem.
Rym: Because if there's a problem on this bus I will stop it and I will call the police and they will take to whoever is causing the problem Random ass jail in the middle of nowhere.
Rym: He's like, I don't care where we are on the freeway.
Rym: We will stop this bus and the police will come and they will deal with it.
Rym: So is there a problem?
Rym: Does anyone have a problem?
Rym: so?
Rym: Problem.
Scott: they reconfirm that no one had a problem like a bunch of times and that shut the guy up real fast.
Scott: Cuz he must have really wanted to go to DC.
Rym: now one point.
Rym: that guy was like I wasn't causing any problem and the bus driver plays.
Rym: It's so cool.
Rym: The bus driver knew who the problem was.
Rym: The bus drivers like.
Rym: I ain't talking to anyone specific.
Rym: I don't know why you think I'm talking to you many pauses and he's like I'm just saying if there's trouble do would anyone like to tell me if there is trouble on the bus?
Rym: He gave us all a chance.
Rym: if any one of us have been like that guy I think he would have been arrested or at least kicked off the bus maybe.
Rym: and then someone else who was outside later was like Yeah, the guy like got to a fight with someone else because he say cut in front of him in line, whatever.
Scott: But the in the end all that happened was you know The threat of being arrested in the middle of the fuck.
Scott: know where wherever the bus that guy was silent the whole Troopers was I guess enough to get that guy to shut up and go to DC quietly and then on the bus ride back.
Scott: It was normal.
Rym: I didn't get to ride on the bus ride back because I was waiting to fly to Istanbul like five hours after the bus I'd paid for was gonna leave and then actually it was even better than normal because instead of having to pay Oh, that's another story, right?
Scott: Oh It's coming back now.
Scott: Yeah, so we go outside the train station once we get to.
Rym: Oh, I wasn't in for this.
Rym: No, no on the way on the way in.
Scott: Oh the black cab the black cab.
Scott: So this guy, you know, there's the real cabs and there's the limo service that wants to charge you a fortune, right?
Rym: It's like no man.
Rym: Come with me.
Rym: I'm a cab.
Rym: I'll take you where you're going 70 bucks.
Scott: Yeah, like no that guy's gonna charge me like 30.
Scott: I'm not paying your 70 you charge me 30.
Scott: I'll get in your car.
Rym: No, usually if you're a New Yorker or you're from a New York, we know the score and the guy got him.
Rym: He starts arguing with us.
Rym: Like what are you saying?
Rym: I'm not a real cabbie.
Rym: Look at this guy starts looking at like the guy whose job it is to get real cabs for people.
Rym: He's like these guys said I'm not a real cabbie.
Rym: What do you think of that?
Rym: And that guy just kind of looks at him like hey, please stop talking to me And the guy gets super mad though.
Rym: I think No, I've never met anyone outside of New York who calls them black cabs.
Scott: Why would you call it?
Rym: I just call it fake cabs fake.
Rym: I call it a fake cab.
Scott: I called the black cab because it's always black or I call it What was the color of his SUV or a shady cab a car service?
Rym: I will call it that sometimes.
Rym: But I think when you said black cab, I think he thought you were racist.
Scott: But that guy wasn't black.
Rym: I know but he was dark-skinned and I think he thought you were being racist.
Scott: No, I was referring to the color of his car, but he tried to argue with us too.
Rym: We were like, all right All right, how much to take us to magfest to where we are going?
Rym: He's like 75 bucks and I've taken cabs to magfest a bunch of times already.
Scott: $75 is more than the combined cost of getting all of us to DC on the bus.
Rym: I was like, it's 35 in a yellow cab.
Rym: go away Wouldn't go away.
Rym: and eventually we got we all crammed into a real cab and that cabbie thought this whole thing was hilarious.
Scott: That's pretty much it.
Rym: Yeah so moral.
Rym: if you don't live in a big city and you're not used to this you ever get out of an Airport and a plane.
Scott: but this only applies to major cities in the US.
Rym: I said real city Not us world.
Scott: You mean other places.
Scott: I see the thing is in the rest of the world it's the same situation.
Scott: they have regulated cab.
Scott: Yes, I mean London has regulated Scott in India.
Rym: There are four levels of regulated care, but they're regulated.
Rym: Yes Okay, in fact, they're regulated to a surprising and comforting degree.
Scott: the price The thing is wherever you are don't get into an unregulated cab.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: now in more importantly if you're going to a I don't want to say normal but like a kind of Standard place like a major global city you're going to like Berlin or Istanbul or New York or Chicago or LA or DC if you get out of any form of mass transit and are getting out of getting transportation There is a taxi stand somewhere.
Rym: find it stand in line and a cop or some sort of uniform person will Get you ask where you're going a legitimate cab.
Rym: turn to a cab and he'll basically say take this guy where he's going.
Rym: Don't rip him off.
Rym: We're keeping track of the shit.
Scott: Yeah, cuz basically the unlegitimate cabs.
Scott: what they are is their car services.
Scott: Like, you know If you if you're fancy rich You can call an airport and the guy will wait for you with the sign with your name on it.
Scott: when I business travel I do That and then take you ever you want and that's a car traveling for work.
Rym: Yeah, a car service picks me up wherever I am exactly.
Scott: But the thing with the car service is that guy who usually holds your name in the airport, right?
Scott: What does he do?
Scott: and no one calls him on the phone?
Rym: Well, he tries to rip off tourists.
Scott: He's not allowed legally to pick people up off the street.
Scott: in most places like in New York City They're not allowed to pick people up off the street except in special cases like during the hurricane.
Scott: They said okay temporarily you can pick people up off the street, right?
Scott: But now you can't.
Scott: normally They've tried to pick people up off the street.
Scott: Anyway tourists you don't know better mostly right and if they pick you up off the street, they don't have like a meter.
Scott: They just charge you whatever the fuck they want.
Scott: Right and you're a stupid tourist.
Scott: What do you know?
Scott: So they'll be like, yes 75 bucks to go to the airport.
Scott: You didn't know that any yellow cab is required to take you to JFK for a flat rate from anywhere in the five boroughs.
Scott: Even fucking Staten Island is what like 35 40 bucks.
Rym: It's not much.
Scott: It doesn't even count for Staten Island.
Scott: They have to take you on the ferry.
Rym: I don't think so.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: there they take you on the Verrazano.
Rym: I don't know if you know what.
Rym: who cares doesn't matter.
Scott: Okay, I'll never get in a cab.
Scott: This doesn't?
Scott: that's not yellow.
Scott: that has a stamp on it.
Rym: Well, it depends.
Rym: I've been in cities where the regulated cabs are blue.
Rym: Okay, black.
Rym: there's some other color.
Rym: the regulated yellow cabs are real cabs.
Rym: any other color is not a cab.
Rym: it is a scammer.
Scott: That's right Unless you called for it on the phone in advance.
Rym: And even then unless your business traveling probably don't want to do that because they're gonna charge you a lot of money.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So in the big anime news, so for the last I don't know three years Whenever we talk about anime, I'll pretty much always list old GeekNights.
Rym: You can probably verify this.
Rym: We'll say something like man.
Rym: There's all this new anime.
Rym: But I really just want more Ghost in the Shell which has been true ever since the last episode of standalone complex to second gig.
Rym: Well, you might mean Society which I didn't like nearly as much as second game.
Scott: No, it seemed like a repeat of the original Ghost in the Shell mostly.
Rym: Yeah, anyway, it wasn't the repeat of the original Ghost in the Shell.
Rym: It was just a kind of pedestrian.
Rym: I don't it was.
Rym: it wasn't as good as standalone complex.
Rym: But I want procedural cyberpunk drama with yokocato music and Makoto Kusanagi more than I want pretty much anything else in anime that's feasible.
Rym: and yet for a long time in fact a person I will not name Four goddamn years ago gave me these rumors about Ghost in the Shell stuff that he claimed were super legit and because of his connections I trusted him and none of that ever panned out.
Rym: So he must have been lying.
Scott: Mmm.
Rym: But anyway new Ghost in the Shell is coming.
Rym: We know almost nothing about it.
Rym: So the theory of the things we know.
Rym: one it is called Ghost in the Shell Arise.
Rym: Two no yokocato music.
Rym: I've been told.
Rym: three Kenji Kameyama has nothing to do with it.
Rym: four it is not a Straight sequel to standalone complex.
Rym: It'll have a different aesthetic or style.
Rym: that has been said, but that is not verified by anyone official.
Rym: But it is production IG and the character design Looks like a slight departure.
Rym: It looks like the the younger body that Makoto used at the end of first gig Mm-hmm.
Rym: Remember in the airport and everything which was in that like younger body?
Rym: It looks a lot like that with like cropped hair, but she's got that same vaguely pissed off Kusanagi look that I know and love and surprisingly small breasts.
Rym: Okay, so the only other thing we can say is that the first episode is streaming worldwide live on February 12th at 9 p.m.
Rym: In Japan.
Rym: Okay Or it is the production presentation.
Rym: We're not sure exactly what that will entail.
Rym: Then there is a commemoration special night in Rapunzel's I. it's sold out apparently so you can't go.
Scott: Well, that's good.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I'm pretty excited about this, but I wonder Yoko Kanno and Kenji Kamiyama kind of defined the kind of ghost in the shell TV show that I like.
Rym: It's the only one but I really liked it.
Rym: So I'm curious.
Rym: How different will it be?
Rym: Will it be at least Ponderous and oshi Tacular, will it be shirotastic?
Rym: I don't think so.
Scott: No, it doesn't really matter right because it's not a moe.
Rym: I am so excited.
Scott: Thing you would see it on the anime chart and think it was a fake anime chart.
Rym: therefore Oh my god, so a guy Kazuchika Kisei is directing it.
Rym: I actually did not recognize his name at all.
Rym: So I went in and I got the high hopes.
Rym: now, you know, I He had a part in a lot of things that most of them are animation director and key animation.
Rym: So that is the kind of person who usually does really well when they direct a sort of stand by never directed anything.
Rym: I'm looking through I'm trying to stall for time.
Rym: Look he mostly did key animation for a ton of stuff including the heroic Legend of Arslan your favorite Yeah, and the Escaflowne movie.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So, I don't know what key animators who then have a bigger role in production seem to always do pretty well.
Rym: Animation director key animation.
Scott: Finally an anime to watch the end.
Rym: Well, so there is anime to watch because I'm actually watching space brothers and so is Emily and it's super good Super super good.
Rym: You should all watch it if you're even close to a fan of anime and or space space space.
Rym: So what do you got got news?
Rym: So
Scott: you may know if you are a listener of this show or you know a nerd of the internets There is a person who is named Casey Green and that person is the creator of such funny webcomics as gun show Also the sub comic of gun show the anime club.
Scott: Oh shit the funniest Right.
Scott: This person is now doing a comic for money at boom studios That is based on the Cartoon Network show known as regular show.
Scott: I have watched one episode of regular show.
Rym: I do not terribly enjoy the regular show But again, I have not seen much of it.
Scott: I've seen one episode and I also did not terribly enjoy it.
Rym: I know I have to give it a decent benefit of the doubt.
Rym: I gotta watch a bunch of some point because I had a similar opinion of Adventure Time when I saw a couple random episodes early.
Rym: But Adventure Time is now literally my second favorite current ongoing show.
Rym: second only to my little pony.
Rym: friendship is magic.
Scott: But anyway, uh, he's making this comic now.
Scott: So I'll probably buy at least one issue and I can say my sister really likes his show.
Scott: I was like, eh, I watched the whole episode But I really liked the character design of the high-five ghost because I mean hell it's a ghost and has a giant hand on top of its head and high fives and What's better than that except for an actual boo?
Rym: All right, so I've thoroughly examined this.
Rym: Kazuchika Kisei has basically done nothing but Animation in some capacity for a ridiculous number of different anime all over the place from the weathering continent to angelic lair and Xxx this person I think he's pretty old.
Rym: I don't know much about him says he's born in 65 in Osaka.
Scott: Yeah, so actually he was incredibly young When he was making some of those animes in the 80s dude, he worked on black magic m66.
Scott: Yeah, what year I?
Scott: so what year did black black jack, right?
Scott: So what year was black magic m66 from?
Scott: my god?
Rym: I watched that.
Rym: I rented it from a blockbuster.
Rym: I think 87.
Rym: It's from 87.
Scott: So he was 22 when he was working on that.
Rym: dudes been working on anime for a while Yeah, and I don't think he has any straight-up director credit to his name.
Rym: Well, it says he was the animation director of a lot of these animation director a mechanical animation director chief animation director at character Design and key animator in the vast majority of things he has done.
Rym: All right I will learn more about him well before it goes in the shell happen so I can talk about him.
Rym: This also reminded me that the weathering continent exists.
Rym: I kind of want to watch it again.
Rym: all you have you ever seen it?
Scott: I've heard of it.
Rym: Every anime fan has heard of it.
Rym: I've never.
Scott: I know it's.
Scott: I know it's like a stereotypical fantasy thing.
Rym: I've never met anyone.
Scott: I guess it goes.
Scott: it hangs out on Fridays with Legend of Lemnier.
Rym: Oh my god, I guess I've never met anyone who I was friends with who had watched it But everyone had heard of it.
Rym: Anyway, oh and I should mention it because while we often don't go to Otakon anymore or don't often Yeah, we broke our basically decade-long streak nine year streak Yeah, almost I said basically a decade not actually a decade round seven maybe seven eight years and whatever.
Rym: 2002 was the first one We went to.
Rym: so two three four five six seven eight.
Rym: Okay, anyway This first Otakon we went to the concert was what the para para thing?
Scott: Yep, which I didn't actually go to.
Rym: I went to the dance thing for it later.
Rym: The next one we went to I think it was TM revolution.
Rym: Mm-hmm, and it was a pretty boss fucking concert.
Rym: So not too long later, actually, I think it's actually quite a bit long later.
Rym: we had the opportunity in 2008 okay, so it was a long time later to interview TM revolution the frontman.
Scott: there's a GeekNights episode about it.
Rym: I think yes, I'm gonna link to it.
Rym: We're really small.
Rym: We reviewed.
Scott: did I say that enough the first time?
Rym: I think I. not only did you say that a lot?
Rym: But I commented it.
Scott: how you said is probably smaller than Jon Stewart.
Rym: We did a bunch of things like there was a cop like the six-month span where we did a bunch of things with Tokyo FM and Kinokuniya and all there's this whole like thing we were doing.
Rym: that kind of faded away.
Rym: I wonder if we should do that again.
Rym: Anyway, so we reviewed Maurice the chojo On April 23rd 2008 and we talked about how we got to perform an interview with TM revolution.
Rym: mr.
Rym: Takanori Nishikawa, and He's a super cool dude, like he's actually he answered our questions The way normal people would answer questions.
Rym: He didn't do the kind of expected Japanese dodges.
Scott: No, he was totally just a chill guy like whatever.
Rym: Yeah, also motherfuckers pretty mother.
Scott: Well, he had so much makeup.
Rym: He was covered in makeup.
Rym: You know what he was pretty.
Scott: if I covered makeup I'll be pretty too and I shook his hand so would anybody.
Rym: and then on the way out there's all the because they're a bunch of Fangirls from Japan who won a contest who came to the US with him for his tour.
Rym: So they were there watching the whole interview in Kinokuniya and I high-fived one of them and they went And it was hilarious.
Rym: So I'm gonna link to all that stuff because that was a surprising blast from the past.
Rym: But yes, Otakon is bringing him back for another concert this year now.
Scott: Well, that's kind of awesome.
Scott: at the same time kind of repeats to quote.
Rym: Who cares if it's a repeat.
Rym: how long?
Scott: I mean, yeah, it's been a while right so it's not too bad.
Scott: Let's see 2000. has he done any songs for new anime newer than Gundam seed?
Rym: Let's see TM Revolution has since performed a string of anime hits for bleach Helver Sengoku Basara the gray man.
Rym: Okay, Ken should solely it Solely it.
Scott: Hey, dude, so this guy's actually been in the game.
Scott: Oh wait gonna see think about this team revolution.
Scott: How long has he been a rock star?
Rym: For a fucking long ass time, that's how long He said and I quote this is from the anime news network article in some other context I never imagined when I made my debut that I would be doing this when I was over 40.
Rym: That is not bad at all.
Scott: So I just you know, I just think that you know.
Scott: on the one hand it's like yeah, okay It's okay to bring him back But if you bring him back like every six seven years, okay Have a question for you because we talked about this at length when we wanted.
Scott: you want to compare it to packs.
Scott: When
Rym: we were staff at Otakon, I had many conversations with other staff about this and It is my impression and correct me if you believe that I'm wrong that in a six-year span the vast majority of people who went to the Otakon at the beginning of that are not the ones who are there at the end of
Scott: that.
Scott: that is true.
Rym: So it's pretty much a brand new concert to 90% yeah of the people at Otakon at least 90%.
Rym: So I will say this if you go to one anime convention a year It should be anime Boston cuz I know Boston super fun.
Scott: If you go to two Boston also usually gets amazing musical guests.
Rym: If you go to two go to anime Boston and Otakon, but if you go to Otakon Definitely go to the TM revolution concert because it is this High energy music that you might have forgotten exists well, and when we saw it we were in that.
Scott: you know main events.
Scott: now This is gonna be in.
Scott: you know I guess the arena right I hope does that still exist?
Rym: well When we hurt back when we were on the staff the city was saying they're gonna tear the arena down to rebuild.
Scott: knows What's going on there?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I have.
Scott: no I haven't been to be more.
Rym: I'm gladly oh Yeah, and kids if you want us to be at Otakon and perform will happily perform if they let us.
Rym: but I have it on good authority from an Otakon staffer as a Three months ago who said we're still on a sort of unofficial blacklist, and they won't let us come and do performances, okay,
Scott: so Maybe get TMR can tell them hey We should
Rym: start headlining with that anime boss if you should always come out and be like banded Otakon.
Rym: It's Rym and Scott.
Rym: Also anime Boston panel submissions end tomorrow The 31st at midnight.
Rym: so if you want to submit a panel to anime Boston to make Luerata very happy You've got very little time to do so you can also submit a panel to kinetic.
Scott: Oh, he was going right.
Scott: we skipping over the way for the meta moment, okay?
Rym: We're waiting wait wait.
Rym: I got things.
Rym: the day are coming.
Rym: they come here.
Rym: They come Things of the day.
Rym: what do you got for me?
Rym: You saw it already.
Scott: some guy or girl?
Scott: I don't even know.
Scott: Made a to get their bachelor's degree in animation from I guess the animations something school in Denmark somewhere Right here.
Scott: click on the link.
Scott: It's in the first tab there.
Scott: Let me see what it says.
Rym: You need me to pull up your research.
Rym: Yeah Award from animation workshop.
Rym: Emily can talk at length about animation.
Scott: animation workshop I guess is a college of animation in Denmark.
Scott: in the board.
Rym: the board.
Scott: what a great name.
Scott: So this guy who is?
Scott: who's the name of the person?
Scott: It doesn't say.
Scott: anyway this person made this animation to get their bachelor's degree.
Scott: I guess they had a lot of help.
Rym: film by the directed by Mikkel mains Echoljere, okay, I'm really sorry for my.
Scott: they have a whole bunch of other credits of people who helped them.
Scott: So I guess it must have been a project of multiple students together.
Rym: Scott if one person made this on their own either it took a decade or they are insane.
Scott: Come on daikon animation.
Rym: right daikon.
Rym: How long is the daikon animation?
Scott: It's this is a lot less frames.
Rym: How many people made the daikon animation about the same number?
Rym: Yeah?
Scott: So anyway, this is you know a pretty awesome video of just two guys going on a fantasy adventure.
Scott: It's pretty fantastic Totally worth the handful of minutes.
Scott: It takes you to watch it.
Scott: So definitely watch this short video.
Scott: You know, I wish that these people would make something that was long and for serious especially with their Monster designs and and setting designs because that would be I really like really cool.
Rym: The montage like bit really reminded me of the montage and brave.
Scott: The whole thing is a montage except for the scene of the exam the scene in the city and the scene at the end.
Rym: It reminds me of a story them because they see busy opener montage middle part montage ending.
Rym: The end is pretty good to like you can see it coming from the beginning But it's a good it.
Rym: This is a work that has a pretty good moral.
Rym: Yep Also the main character, I guess the first guy Kind of a monkey wizard or wizard kind of boy half warrior Kind of reminds me of our friend Conrad.
Rym: but a lot of things remind me of our friend Conrad.
Scott: I actually would you know, I prefer the Cowboy warrior guide.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well that guy to the drunk wizard guy, but at the end they're both awesome.
Rym: Yeah, well because the drunk wizard guy once he has his his full beard like his full potential.
Rym: That is some shit.
Rym: That's the kind of guy who helps you get to La Patena Ghibli movie.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: So my thing is that I bring this up surprisingly often in casual conversation And I realized that most people don't actually know what I'm talking about.
Rym: The City of London is actually tiny.
Rym: It's smaller than the City of Beacon.
Rym: Okay London is separate from the City of London and surrounds the City of London.
Rym: Okay this is a video that explains the fullness of what the deal is.
Rym: and the thing is The.
Rym: the same people did a video that explains the difference between Albion Britain Great Britain the United Kingdom and that.
Rym: So you can watch that.
Scott: Why don't they just reshuffle their names to not be stupid?
Rym: Uh, so the history of why London is the way it is and why you can say oh the City of London is tiny It's only like a square mile is actually pretty goddamn Badass and this video does a very good job of explaining it and the people who make these videos do a really good job of Explaining stuff to a pretty good degree of accuracy and I just I recommend watching.
Scott: I made up a bunch of bullshit and you totally eat it ate it fell for it.
Rym: No, this is legit.
Rym: Okay This is straight legit possible.
Rym: It's pretty cool.
Rym: the secret history of London.
Scott: All right, so metamoment.
Scott: so metamoment number one was send panels to animate Boston.
Rym: Yes, you've got not much time.
Scott: metamoment number two send panels to Connecticut.
Rym: Yes, who approves panels for Connecticut?
Rym: We do me And a third person.
Scott: Also, we're gonna need some even more staff at Connecticut.
Scott: So if you want to go to Connecticut for zero dollars at least on the badge price And you want to get a reference for staff?
Rym: There is a whole process for people joining the staff normally But we can fast-track you.
Rym: if one you are actually a competent.
Scott: We are going to make you do work.
Scott: It's not gonna be just hey, we snuck you in for free because you listen to us or you like us It's you come to Connecticut you spend quite a few hours a day Doing our bidding and then maybe you can play some board games with the other hours.
Scott: But more importantly Connecticut is a pretty awesome con and it's in everything con like but it is officially geekery you're into be it anime or board games or sci-fi TV shows or book reading or Fucking cosplay of course and anything it is at Connecticut.
Scott: I don't care if you're one of those nerds.
Scott: We're like.
Scott: all you do is play magic.
Scott: Guess what?
Scott: There's a ton of magic playing at Connecticut.
Scott: If you're one of those people all you do is read manga.
Scott: Guess what tons of manga at Connecticut.
Rym: here I'm gonna read for you some of the panel submissions.
Rym: We got to give you all you read is silver age spider-man.
Scott: There's a little bit of silver.
Rym: a spider-man Sewing clip-on cat ears a workshop.
Rym: What's the scenario?
Rym: writing tips for serial authors?
Rym: advanced skills for RPG game masters.
Rym: gone to the sled dogs.
Rym: That is a panel on mushing like through the Arctic and the Yukon with the sled and dogs.
Rym: Well, that is the car the happiest homestuck panel.
Rym: We will review it fairly and honestly, well, we do not.
Scott: we just you know, we had to you know.
Scott: at the one hand We have to always judge to based on the highest quality presenters.
Scott: if there is multiple Homestuck submitters, right?
Scott: We can't accept all of them because we need to balance the content, you know in equal parts web comics and Animes and video games and such and such.
Scott: now here's the biggest reason cream of the crop Why you should submit panels to Connecticut one?
Rym: We have a lot of big rooms But we have a lot of small rooms too.
Rym: So if you want to get into the running panels at cons game We can put you in a relatively small room.
Rym: You'll get a pretty big crowd and you can kind of get the feel for all this.
Scott: Yeah, last year we had this one tiny room.
Scott: We put all these newbie panel people in there and half of them were awesome and two of them didn't even show up.
Scott: Yeah, so if you show up, you're already doing really well.
Rym: more importantly magfest as we learned recently does not get Nearly.
Rym: magfest gets so few panel submissions relative to what they should.
Rym: that is kind of sad.
Rym: So if you submit a panel that's related to gaming to Connecticut and we accept it and you do a good job I will totally straight up recommend you to magfest and other conventions like it Because I don't know if you guys realize this the people who run the panels departments that all the cons on the East Coast We all know each other like we literally share information about all of you.
Scott: other meta moments The book club book is the Great Gatsby by F Scott Fitzgerald.
Rym: It'll take you like an hour to read it.
Scott: if it takes you longer than an hour You're not reading enough books.
Scott: You got to get your reading skills up.
Rym: And if you hate it, that's fine.
Scott: If you know famous and whatnot, it's important to have read it like it or not.
Rym: If you don't respect it cuz I just read it.
Rym: I'm done with it.
Rym: We're you are very miss.
Rym: Yeah, it is a. it is a well-written book And if you like the Kingkiller Chronicles more than you like the Great Gatsby, that's a problem.
Rym: I really feel sorry.
Rym: Okay, well we got a bunch of videos up from magfest.
Rym: I did an unofficial Twitter poll last-metamoment thing.
Rym: We have limited resources.
Rym: So one if you want more videos to come out spread the word on our videos to places To someone linked from reddit to our beyond dungeons and dragons.
Rym: I can't figure out where on reddit.
Rym: So if you know where that link is, let me know.
Rym: I'm curious.
Rym: three I'm either gonna upload our third panel from magfest a new radio free equestria or a new GeekNights presents utenna.
Rym: You guys need to tell me which one you want us to do next.
Rym: The votes are actually completely equal right now based on emails and tweets.
Rym: I got Mmm, so you alone might push me over the edge.
Rym: That's all You should.
Scott: I sent out another newsletter.
Scott: People seem to like it, but the newsletter needs number one Q&A because it has a Q&A section.
Scott: So we need cues to a and number two.
Scott: it has a fan art section Which doesn't necessarily have to be drawings.
Scott: It could be art of any kind of any medium that is digitally Form of a cornucopia.
Scott: Yeah cornucopia is there are good.
Scott: Yeah, anything like that?
Scott: Even though it's out of season, you know, but any sort of GeekNights fan created work You know can go in that section.
Scott: that section has been mostly empty for a while.
Scott: So if you submit pretty much anything You'll have no competition and we'll probably get straight into the newsletter now also hit.
Rym: if it's a YouTube video I might do something with that.
Rym: If it's audio, I might also do something with that.
Rym: Just saying just saying
Scott: anyway
Rym: saying So we're talking about two comics because I've actually been reading a bunch of comics lately
Scott: Because I've you know Everyone knows I get a box of comics in the mail every month and pretty much what's been happening for the past Year or so is I would get it and I would read Bakuman immediately I would read 20th Century Boys immediately I would read ponies immediately You know there are certain ones that I read immediately and everything else sort of go on the shelf and wait right and Only in the past month or two.
Scott: I started to try to dig through the shelf and burn through.
Rym: It's been gaming season for a while here on GeekNights But I'm starting to feel I think an anime comic season is gonna like suddenly come up.
Scott: Well, I think what I've done is I don't think gaming season is over.
Scott: I think what I've done with gaming season they've concentrated.
Scott: I'm only playing two games that begin with N, natural selection 2 and Android netrunner.
Rym: right now I'm pretty much only playing counter-strike and XCOM.
Scott: So by focusing on only two games and not playing any other games that leaves a whole lot of room for all these other geekeries to to step in.
Rym: But also I'm watched I think adventure times.
Rym: what did it?
Rym: because I burned through adventure time and you know when you're watching a show that goes on For a while and like you're catching up and then you hit like the most recent episode you have this wall of oh now I gotta wait Like watching Escaflowne episode by episode or VHS tape by VHS tape.
Rym: I think that forced me to start consuming other media and I started watching all these anime again.
Rym: All right, so let's talk about the short one first.
Rym: We only read one issue of this.
Rym: Scott just came over.
Scott: Okay, so the deal with this is you know Dark Horse?
Scott: if you don't know this right Dark Horse Comics has the licenses to a lot of things including Star Wars.
Scott: So they whenever you see Star Wars stuff in your comic book store There is a very good chance that Dark Horse made that thing be it a statue or a comic or or anything, right?
Scott: So I guess not.
Scott: the game Star Wars games are by someone else but Star Wars everything else is by Dark Horse.
Scott: So There's a ton of fucking Star Wars comics covering everything you can imagine.
Scott: there are ones that just retell the original trilogy.
Scott: There's you know Old Republic Shadows of the Empire and these things have been going on for at least a decade forever.
Scott: They've been making these things.
Scott: they cover every corner of the expanded universe and the regular universe and every kind of art style and every kind of creator and It's where do you fucking start right and the way you start where you start episode four or five six, then you stop, right?
Rym: So I mean some of them are better and TIE fighter.
Scott: the game and the quality variation is so great.
Scott: How would you even even if you knew what you liked right?
Scott: It's like well, I like, you know x-wings.
Scott: So there's a whole bunch of rogue squadron comics.
Rym: I mean an income t65, right?
Scott: So let me read those.
Scott: maybe you know I like that already.
Scott: maybe those are good and you know what.
Scott: some of them are good and some of them are bad and it's just sort of get To do a lot of research to figure it out or waste a lot of money.
Scott: So a New Star Wars comic is coming out.
Scott: So I ignore it as usual But this one had two factors that made me buy it.
Scott: fact.
Scott: Well a few factors.
Scott: factor number one is written by Brian wood Who is the guy who does DMZ and many other comics of interest now side point?
Rym: And we'll get it.
Scott: talks about him in the past.
Rym: If you look at the cover of this.
Scott: It's a Ross cover.
Rym: Yeah, if you don't know who that Some comics you read and it's like Brian K Vaughn.
Rym: blah the name and everything together the author Artist.
Rym: basically the credits are three last names hidden in the bottom left like the top left under all the other logos.
Rym: They're basically invisible right?
Scott: But anyway, this comic is called Star Wars number one.
Scott: That's what it's called.
Scott: It's not any other sort of subcategory.
Scott: It's not shadows of the dark republic empire the third, right?
Scott: It's just Star Wars number one.
Scott: And also this first issue was extremely Discounted through my mail-order service.
Scott: I paid almost nothing for it.
Rym: So Star Wars in the shadow of Yavin basically what it does.
Rym: it picks up right after episode 4.
Scott: Yep Well Star Wars, so it's in between Star Wars before the Empire Strikes Back.
Scott: So it's all of your favorite characters doing what they do.
Rym: You got Han Solo Chewbacca droids Luke pretty true to character too, but despite So, well, how could you mess them which ended with the destruction of the Galactic Empire's fearsome space station the deaths?
Rym: The fledgling rebel alliance is still struggling to find new allies new sources of supplies and most importantly a new location for its permanent base.
Scott: Well, you know where that base is gonna be.
Scott: I Got bets.
Scott: What do you think my bets gonna be?
Rym: watch they're gonna have some other base.
Rym: first.
Rym: I have a feeling wait wait, it'll be hot.
Scott: I have a feeling the base that they're gonna find is very cold.
Rym: My psychic powers are telling me It's gonna be on Dantooine first and then there's this whole plot where it gets blown up and then they move on who knows.
Scott: But anyway, it takes place in episodes four and five and it's pretty much there's two plots going.
Scott: There's a few plots, but the big ones are.
Scott: we need to find a new base.
Scott: We're just a fleet flying around.
Scott: the Empire is still strong Even though we blew up the death star political thing around that.
Scott: and then two there are some spies within the Rebel Alliance.
Scott: Oh shit, we need some Both ends to die to find supplies.
Rym: There's a sort of side plan Darth Vader trying to Redeem himself in the eyes of the Emperor because he basically fucked up, right?
Scott: And there's also the side plot of Han Solo.
Scott: got the money at the end of episode four.
Scott: So what do you do?
Scott: What's he gonna do?
Scott: Is he gonna stick with the rebels?
Scott: Is he gonna pay Jabba the Hutt?
Scott: is you know, what happens there?
Scott: And I'm sure you know this comic can't go on forever because at some point it has to become Empire Strikes Back.
Scott: So, I mean how much time really was there between those two movies?
Rym: So I'm gonna say this reading this I Actually enjoyed it a lot.
Rym: Like I was like, alright, whatever this is gonna be garbage.
Rym: and then I read like five pages.
Rym: I'm like, huh, and I'm really liking.
Rym: I'm trying to figure out why I keep stopping like.
Rym: why am I so into this?
Rym: And there's a line that made me realize Exactly why I'm into the one about the income factory.
Rym: the one about the income factory I guess because that I realized then that this is aimed at the kind of person who watched Star Wars and played TIE fighter either.
Rym: that person Was in my wheelhouse.
Rym: also Leia Fucking murders a guy like right away just shoots him right in the heart covered in blood and she's like no biggie.
Scott: Well, did you see episode four?
Rym: Yeah They didn't cover her in blood in episode four though.
Rym: Also Darth Vader in this looks like he's looks pretty badass in Star Wars the movie, right?
Rym: He looks scary.
Scott: They made him a little exaggerated scary.
Scott: He's huge.
Rym: He's like bigger than everyone else by a degree that does not make sense.
Scott: It sort of looks like his mask sort of like flexes to make faces as opposed to you know in the movies It was a static
Rym: Ever since someone made that mashup where it replaced all of the harmonica
Scott: don't
Rym: know When they replaced all of Darth Vader's dialogue with Arnold Schwarzenegger
Scott: line.
Rym: That's a great one also and I realized that if you turn the sound off and watch Star Wars Darth Vader's just kind of like shuffling on his feet and kind of like just being like He's only menacing with his voice.
Rym: of course without the voice he looks actually kind of derpy yeah But this comic is super fun, I don't want to say a lot more about it because it's gonna spoil it.
Scott: Well, I mean, I don't think it's.
Scott: you know it's not amazing.
Scott: I think it's it's good.
Scott: You know.
Scott: I'm not like oh my god I got to buy more of this.
Scott: oh my god I'm rushing out to buy more, but it's like it's okay And it's got some of that.
Scott: you know like Rym said the extreme Star Wars nerdiness where R2D R2T4 Give me the position on that missile.
Rym: Yeah, do you know the difference between an R2T and an R2D?
Rym: I'm sure you do.
Rym: actually I Barely know.
Scott: the point is is that if you are one of those extreme Star Wars nerds You will enjoy this and if you're one of just a regular Star Wars enjoyer of the good episodes movies You also enjoy this right so it's it's really in that exact right spot.
Scott: The only thing I wonder is like how canon is this?
Scott: and really I don't give a shit You know what?
Rym: as far as I'm concerned there is no expanded universe.
Rym: There is the first three movies, so this is a fanfiction, and then there is this fanfic.
Rym: We'll see we'll see how this goes, but it's sticking true to the characters And I'm enjoying it to a degree.
Rym: that surprised me considering how much I tend to shit on comics that I'm handed by Scott.
Scott: All right, well, let's talk about the other comic that I handed to you.
Scott: so Saga.
Scott: here's the deal with saga.
Scott: This is a comic from image comics.
Scott: It came out or some months ago six to twelve months ago March 2012. so well That's when issue one came out.
Scott: There's one trade paperback currently available that I believe has the first six issues.
Scott: if I'm not mistaken and the writer of this is Brian K Vaughn of such amazing comics as why the last man X Machina Runaways, I gotta catch up Like the first chunk of X Machina that I didn't finish right.
Scott: X Machina has been completely over I know.
Rym: I just never finished.
Scott: I own every volume, and I've never finished it great.
Rym: Okay feel that bad.
Scott: Anyway, so his new comic is saga, and you just knew right away.
Scott: It's called saga.
Scott: It's by Brian K Vaughn.
Scott: Who's the artist?
Rym: cuz the arts really good the artist is Fiona staples.
Scott: Oh, yeah, I know that name.
Scott: Oh, it's a me I've never I think like.
Scott: it's a name where if you said Fiona staples I would have told you that's the name of a comic artist But I could not have told you like what you know she drew at all 40 dv8 gods and monsters Thunder Agents and saga.
Scott: never heard of any of those except saga, but I've heard of Fiona staples for some reason.
Scott: anyway art is amazing.
Scott: That's all you got to know.
Scott: So this comic was much hyped.
Scott: I pre-ordered that first issue just to see the first issue.
Scott: was it was good?
Scott: I was like.
Scott: no That's what I expected.
Scott: kind of awesome comic in that first issue.
Scott: really interesting premise right you know?
Scott: I'll read the rest.
Scott: so then first issue.
Scott: I bought the first trade.
Scott: I got the first trade, and I said oh, this is hot.
Scott: people who aren't huge comics people are even reading and talking about this.
Scott: I'm gonna read it and find out what's up.
Scott: You know I already read the first trade.
Scott: So I reread.
Scott: obviously that I mean first issue, so I reread the first issue in the trade and then kept going Once you get past that issue one.
Scott: it was like whoa.
Scott: this is way better than the first issue.
Scott: It just goes off the chain.
Rym: it reminds me a lot of the in call.
Scott: it reminds The fifth element.
Rym: well the end call reminded me of the fifth element.
Rym: So I think there's a circle of things that are all similar, but the end call.
Rym: I liked it, but it was kind of One further step crazy and one further step comicky.
Scott: Yeah, then cause a little hard to follow.
Scott: Maybe some things are lost in translation.
Scott: It didn't really fill in all the blanks.
Scott: for you the pace is really rapid Yeah, but meanwhile saga.
Rym: It's like it's one step closer to a movie much more Like.
Rym: this could be a movie like that.
Rym: Many TV miniseries easily the dialogue is is like TV dialogue straight up.
Scott: Yeah, so here's the.
Scott: here's the general summary of what's going on in saga.
Scott: right.
Scott: so in this universe There was a race of people that lived on a moon and a race of people lived on a planet that the moon Orbited and they didn't like each other's.
Scott: they were fighting, but the fighting got so severe.
Scott: They realized oh shit if we keep shooting at the moon and fuck it up We're gonna fuck ourselves because our moon will get fucked up.
Scott: Realize well if you look at the planet we're fucking up ourselves on the moon, so they wanted to keep fighting.
Scott: So they basically came up with this thing where we're gonna keep fighting each other because we still hate each other's guts Just not in our home world and home moon.
Scott: We're gonna take our battle to every else in the universe.
Scott: They go to someone else's planet Force them to take sides and then make them fight and they basically go around fucking up the rest of the world by staging their Battles on other people's planets with the people know
Rym: it's interesting the the war is kind of at this point This is a one of those worlds where there's kind of like two sides.
Rym: neither of one is good or evil and they're both sort of doing their job like the both sides kind of respect each other and have rules about when and how to fight.
Rym: and As far as I can tell these two main characters and the peasantry are like the only people who see any problem with this Right.
Scott: so of course you know the.
Scott: what's the story?
Scott: the story is Romeo and Juliet.
Scott: you have one person from one side.
Scott: if Juliet Was a consummate badass who's also really horny all the time and Romeo was a pussy you happen to have a sword But that's all he had.
Rym: Oh, no.
Rym: She's also really foul-mouthed, and I don't know their dialogue is really funny, right?
Scott: But anyway one person from the moon and one person from the earth part sort of sneak away decide They don't want to fight in this horrible war.
Scott: they were forced to fight in and fall in love and they go on an adventure trying to run away from danger.
Scott: and You know at the same time there are people out to get them and the saga of them running away and traveling across Galaxies universes wherever they the distance is I don't know.
Scott: and that's what saga is all about.
Rym: yeah I don't want to say anymore.
Rym: seriously if you're gonna read a comic like this right now saga is pretty great.
Scott: This is pretty much the hot comic on the shelves right now.
Rym: They are along with ponies is great and the thing is it throws you in media res and doesn't explain shit.
Scott: That explanation I just gave you comes like later than the first issue At the very beginning.
Rym: the very beginning is the two characters in that style of it reveals stuff like really quickly and all over the.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't spoil it right.
Scott: I mean there's also some.
Rym: I think my favorite character is the will.
Scott: Which one's that again?
Rym: the the freelancer with the cat?
Scott: Oh, okay?
Scott: Well, okay, so my favorite character That's the thing this thing is all about and that's why I compared it to Fifth Element.
Scott: the thing is all about Awesome characters.
Scott: the main characters are awesome, but there's all these side characters I actually really like Prince robot - well, okay.
Scott: Yeah, Prince robot the bad guy totally reminds me He's not a bad guy.
Scott: No, but I mean he's he's.
Scott: you know quote the bad, right?
Scott: He's the adversary.
Rym: they make a point in this comic.
Rym: It's like they call the war good versus good.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah anyway He real his design of.
Scott: you know the TV head kind of person really reminds me of the guy in.
Scott: You know the one.
Scott: what Galaxy Express In rice and rice boy.
Rym: Oh, he reminds me of Count Mecca.
Scott: anyway Yeah, he's he's that kind of guy.
Scott: and then you've got.
Scott: you got this.
Scott: basically the guy the will is basically Bruce Willis.
Scott: Yeah from Fifth Element, right?
Rym: You've got there's one page.
Rym: He makes this face.
Rym: He's basically Corbin Dallas where he is twitching.
Scott: It's so great He has a pet cat.
Scott: That's the lying cat which is also incredibly awesome.
Scott: where the cat makes the best faces to anyone is near it talking and you lie It'll say lying and it's always right.
Scott: So it's just a cat that can tell with 100% accuracy when someone is lying.
Rym: The cat also has a personality and while he or she doesn't talk all it says is the word lying.
Rym: here She funny looks gives the will some looks and his name is the will.
Scott: Yeah So there's another bounty hunter along with the will Scott really likes.
Rym: that was an amazing cat.
Scott: The stock was amazing because they foreshadowed the stock where the will is like, oh the stocks on it.
Scott: I'm not even gonna bother I'm just gonna go get.
Rym: I'm gonna go to the sex play.
Scott: I'm gonna go to the sex planet because the stock is taking care of it.
Scott: Oh my god, though that like when he's walking through the sex planet and you just see like the back It's like, you know All you know is there's another bounty hunter called the stock and the stock is so badass that the will is just like.
Scott: well If the stock is on the job, I don't have nothing to do.
Scott: fuck this shit.
Scott: And then later you see the stock and the stock is amazing.
Scott: Then what other you know, you've got a ghost girl with no legs and oh, she's great.
Scott: That's spilling out amazing character who seems to write.
Scott: It's just every single character that shows up is amazing.
Scott: It's not even one of those situations like you're reading urasawa like 20th century boys, right?
Scott: And they'll introduce a character and immediately you don't care about them.
Scott: But then within three pages you care This is character appears and immediately the first frame they're in.
Scott: you care about them because the design is amazing and you like Their existence was foreshadowed leaves a little bit to you.
Scott: It's not like a surprise character.
Scott: Like what's this person about?
Scott: It's like oh Snap, they've just filled in a blank that was already set.
Scott: they have you know, there's a half full glass.
Scott: now It's a full glass and that water looks so good, you know, so every character is awesome.
Scott: I mean usually when you get into some sort of you know fictional story world material There's like the awesome character right like Star Wars Darth Vader.
Rym: Here's a good example Game of Thrones.
Scott: Darth Vader is just better than everybody.
Rym: most people agree like they like Game of Thrones Pretty much because of Sean Bean.
Scott: is that the midget guy?
Rym: No Tyrion the midget guy, right?
Rym: Tyrion's the midget guy.
Rym: Whenever Sean Bean's in a movie, I just call him Sean Bean instead of calling him his character's name.
Rym: But pretty much I really only want to see Tyrion in Game of Thrones.
Rym: Whenever Tyrion's not on screen Right.
Scott: So I was right.
Scott: is that midget guy is the reason to watch right?
Scott: So in saga, it's amazing because Everyone is the reason to read every single character is the reason to keep reading.
Scott: and of course The first trade has an awesome cliffhanger.
Scott: Of course.
Scott: Yeah, I'll just get the second trade when it comes.
Scott: I did not expect like I turn that page and I didn't expect it, but then it made perfect sense.
Scott: once it happened It's like oh, of course and and then you can see that totally sets up that ending.
Scott: you know the structure of the story is gonna be for like the next whole trade at least right.
Rym: and There's the dialogue and there's a certain level of sarcasm that pretty much everyone talks like normal people Just like in ponies and such.
Rym: well No, they talk like normal people are in a movie where everyone is sarcastic.
Scott: Everyone in real life is okay.
Rym: No, that's just cuz we live in New York and watch Seinfeld.
Scott: Anyway, this is this is a must read comic SOG I mean the Star Wars.
Rym: we're gonna talk about this again one.
Rym: Yeah things done.
Scott: if you're a huge Star Wars fan You should get the Star Wars comic.
Scott: or if you just really like Star Wars and are looking for more and you're disappointed With you know or not having high hopes for the movie that's coming or who knows what right then, you know If you really need some Star Wars your Star Wars bucket is low.
Scott: You can fill it with the Star Wars comic.
Scott: It's not necessary.
Scott: saga is mandatory reading for all people.
Scott: Period end of story.
Rym: So apparently there's nerds.
Scott: read saga.
Rym: Brian cave on made a big deal about why he chose image over anyone else and I have a whole quote.
Scott: the way that image Gives people money.
Rym: It's a little more than that.
Scott: It's also Chris Oh quotes and doesn't really tell you what to write.
Rym: or yeah quote Brian Cave-on.
Rym: I love all the other companies.
Rym: I've worked with but I think image might be the only Publisher left that can still offer a contract.
Rym: I would consider fully create around.
Rym: Saga is a really important story to me and I wanted to guarantee of no content restrictions or other creative interference And I needed to maintain 100% control and ownership of all non publishing rights with the artist Including the right to never have our comic turned into a movie or television show or whatever.
Rym: And basically he's like image is the only publisher left.
Scott: Yeah, if you if you're interested in this sort of thing I'm not gonna go into it now also because I forget a lot of the details.
Scott: but basically the different Comic companies the way they make deals with the like Marvel will I you know DC they'll either give people a job Right as in like you are, you know exclusive to Marvel artists.
Scott: You're on the salary, you know, we pay you whatever.
Scott: I don't know if it's a page rate or what it right to draw what we tell you to draw, right?
Scott: And there are some people with like freelancers.
Scott: They'll be like, hey, we'll pay you to draw the cover for this this month or something like that, right?
Scott: But every the other the independent comic companies, right and you know the big ones like, you know image and IDW, right?
Scott: They all they they.
Scott: basically though the the way they make deals with the creators is Completely different and there's the way the image does is different from the way everyone else does it?
Rym: Here's something great Total aside.
Rym: in case the comic had not been successful He had a plan where at the end of issue 5 they would have died and that was the end of it.
Rym: No, nice The rocket ship would have just explained there would die.
Rym: that would have been the end.
Scott: like great for telling about the rocket ship.
Rym: The rocket ship is foreshadowed in the beginning.
Scott: The rocket ship is made of a tree.
Rym: It's so awesome some Hyperion going on in there.
Scott: Oh shit I didn't even think of that.
Rym: But sad news to.
Rym: Vaughn basically said I never want this to be on TV or in a movie theater.
Rym: ever ever ever.
Rym: it won't Happen.
Scott: that's kind of actually good in a way in that maybe people who really want to read it want to read the comic True, but at the same time it would make a great movie.
Scott: But on the other hand the production cost would be so high It would have to.
Rym: it would be.
Scott: it costs a lot of money to make this.
Rym: I know it would to make it right.
Scott: Yeah, all the costumes and special effects, you know, I had to be off the chain.
Rym: But I would I would put a lot of money out of that chain to have that chain come off.
Scott: Oh, I'm fine with the green.
Scott: the comic is also about the comics.
Scott: great What do I need it to be, you know, it's like Oh bakkemon turned into an anime.
Scott: That's the same thing.
Rym: I like how the world mostly doesn't say much just walks around smoking that joint.
Rym: Yeah Yeah.
Rym: Also the will Bruce Willis, I think that's intention is intentional.
Scott: Oh my god, that's true.
Rym: When they introduced him as the will and then they show him sit that one page where he's sitting and he just got the call.
Scott: You know, we've been talking about the will.
Scott: more than any other character.
Rym: the will is not the main character he's a side character because he is the best character except the cat and I Can't even say the other character.
Rym: all awesome Everyone's awesome.
Rym: Even this stock is even the secret agent guy in the beginning who goes to the robot prince and is like Here's your mission.
Scott: No the pussy.
Rym: Okay, this is it's a good comic.
Rym: Yeah, this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: Heat nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.