Rym:
Scott: Yeah That's not very good at all.
Scott: Yeah, that's awful.
Rym: It's Thursday, October 35th, that's also 2013.
Scott: Rym Rym has skills in many things, but not acting.
Rym: this is Voices.
Rym: tonight, we're gonna be doing a show on politics And then we will also be doing a show on the book club book which involves politics.
Rym: Also, it's the what year anniversary of gig nights.
Scott: I think we just finished year.
Rym: We started we started October first 2005.
Scott: we just finished year eight.
Scott: We are now entering year nine.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So six seven eight nine ten eleven twelve.
Rym: good God, we've done a lot of gig nights.
Scott: It's how it is.
Rym: gig nights just keeps coming out.
Scott: Well, look how much you know, like Letterman Look something like that.
Rym: I know and it gives me heart because every time I feel like today I watched a video.
Scott: Peewee Herman appearance on Letterman in 83 one one.
Rym: whoa I am actually been zero.
Rym: I randomly saw a clip from The Daily Show Back when Craig Kilbourn was on it.
Rym: Yep, man.
Rym: That show looks way chintzy and way shit tears.
Scott: Yeah, remember TV wasn't even HD.
Rym: I know watching it's even watching daily shows from like five years ago.
Rym: It's like really.
Rym: I watched this.
Scott: Yes, like.
Rym: it's not just that the production values have gone up.
Rym: It's that like Kinds of humor have gotten better and more polished and like humor writing has gotten everyone gets better at everything.
Rym: I know I mean watch stand-up comedy from the early 90s.
Rym: not much of it holds up guys Not much.
Rym: some I some of everything Steven Wright, I still find funny even though other people have done his kind of humor better in since him.
Rym: But I think he's still anyway, I digress.
Rym: So it's Thursday.
Rym: It's the anniversary of GeekNights.
Rym: It's the lounge.
Rym: No, it's not and I figured we could talk about actual politics.
Scott: Well, you know you want to talk about it.
Scott: all listeners want to hear it.
Scott: I'm not interested but I guess It's our anniversary, so we'll give gifts of people what they want.
Rym: Well more.
Scott: no, you should give us gifts of what we want.
Rym: you people always want us to do politics.
Rym: shows Like what about the NSA?
Scott: and Obama and foreign government talked about that like a hundred times.
Rym: And as much as I like to talk about that stuff shit is not changed.
Rym: the thing the insights there is nothing new to say.
Rym: Well, there's new things to say.
Rym: Scott is gonna doesn't give a shit.
Rym: The insights that I would give you are Should not be revelatory if you hear me talking about politics and start thinking oh, oh Then you really need to pay more attention.
Rym: You need to read more Internet Even though my knowledge is starting to diminish since it's been a while since the last.
Rym: it's all politics.
Scott: I mean this was an issue Right that they dealt with in the 1700s.
Rym: Which issue I mean?
Scott: privacy of people.
Scott: Well, we have a whole Quartering troops and sort of came up with the answer already and the right answer hasn't changed much.
Scott: and Yet people are still discussing it like it's new like they just discovered this.
Scott: there's nothing new to say That was not figured out like a century ago.
Rym: Well, no, actually most people aren't talking about it at all and don't care I just saying anyone who is talking about it.
Scott: There's nothing just like copyright.
Scott: We've been having the same goddamn copyright argument since they invented the Internet.
Rym: Ah, but in the early days of the Internet We had the big argument and came to a bunch of conclusions.
Rym: and it's just government and society have not caught up to Internet Right, but there's nothing new to say they just up to.
Rym: but again if you listen to GeekNights and you have some Revelation some in like moments of you did not.
Scott: you should read more internets.
Scott: All he does is read internets to you.
Rym: It's like Internet's the audiobook Yeah, but the point I'm getting at is that what you're gonna get is what we're gonna talk about right now.
Rym: is politics that actually Matters but it only matters only thing.
Rym: if you live in New York City State, maybe New York State, New York State Yeah, but it affects the city more.
Rym: These are all state.
Scott: they are things by one in the state.
Scott: The state is.
Rym: the majority of the state is the city at this point.
Scott: That is true But these are all state level things.
Scott: Yeah, you know usually getting all disillusioned with politics cuz your vote don't mean shit.
Rym: Yeah we know it don't mean shit and it's all corrupt.
Scott: and unless you're mad rich and can like bribe some senators or whatever you basically just vote and that's it.
Scott: and Basically, there's one thing you can actually do.
Scott: you can do it a lot if you live in Oregon, but in New York California - mostly Oregon is almost all freaking like freaking, you know What's it called referendums and Oregon has what like one congressional district?
Scott: I don't know, but they have a ton of referendums and like you send this whole booklet out to everyone.
Scott: Anyway in New York, you know, we get these ballot proposals which are effectively referendums.
Scott: You go in and you vote yes, or you vote no on these questions Not people actual issues.
Rym: Oregon has one two three or it is like five congressional districts.
Rym: good on you There's more than like five people living right.
Scott: so on these things you can only vote yes or no, you can't give sort of a detailed response.
Scott: and The thing is they're not like delineated by party lines.
Scott: It's not like yes Democrat.
Scott: No Republican, right?
Scott: It's you actually are getting sort of, you know real Democracy happening here on these issues.
Rym: But at the same time you're getting democracy from the least in foreign people who vote usually based on a bumper sticker.
Rym: They saw telling them Proposition 5 is good.
Scott: But have you seen in New York anywhere in the past month or two anything that says like yes on 3 or no on 5?
Rym: I did in grocery stores.
Scott: Oh, what did it say?
Scott: What did the grocery store want?
Rym: I saw a thing in a grocery store that was talking about the first proposition.
Rym: the casino won the casino one.
Scott: It was just like dude is a grocery store care about casinos?
Scott: They can put slot machines in the grocery.
Rym: I don't know if it was there officially.
Rym: Okay, but it was like vote.
Rym: Yes proposition one.
Scott: Okay price.
Scott: someone loves gambling.
Scott: Maybe the guy who owns a grocery store is a gambling addict I don't know and he's tired of going to Jersey.
Rym: but anyway I guess what the point we're making.
Rym: the high-level point here is that we're gonna have a real conversation about politics as in The stuff that matters that we have a statistical effect over that we care about and that depending on how the vote goes Something real changes for us as real people.
Scott: and if you don't live in New York, it's probably meaningless to you Maybe entertaining to you and also you wanted it.
Rym: You should find out the things you can vote for.
Rym: that might matter.
Scott: Yeah, you live somewhere else in the United States.
Scott: most of you anyway, except you foreign folk I'm foreign folk don't have a government that has the kind of problems ours has most of you northern European types, especially.
Scott: So you don't have to worry about this shit, but I'm sure you have other shit to worry about.
Scott: So what have?
Scott: so?
Rym: Proposite proposal one Authorizing casino gambling basically if you tough one for me already.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know if I'm gonna go yes or no because it's sort of even right.
Scott: if you vote Yes That means they're going to allow real casinos with table games and everything in New York State up to seven of them But they won't allow any in the New York City for seven years.
Scott: So that means the first one will open up in New York City in 2020.
Rym: now already the thing.
Rym: I Ideologically, I believe in freedom over most other things, but I agree because I'm not a uppercase L libertarian I prefer to not have the freedom to murder people or dump raw sewage in the river, right?
Scott: I agree.
Scott: You should be free to gamble your money away if you wish.
Scott: I know
Rym: I should be able to gamble on a game of Puerto Rico with Scott if I want to and Absolutely,
Scott: but but you are stupid if you do so in most cases Yeah, especially in a casino which there are no games you can win unless you are the house.
Rym: and thus Here's the reality.
Rym: in my opinion Lotteries and casino gambling are just a tax on the poorest and least able people in our society.
Scott: exactly.
Scott: people say Oh the lottery is okay because the money goes to schools, which it does And in fact this thing also says it goes to schools thereby Replacing the property taxes that normally fund schools.
Rym: thus no net benefit to schools And then when gambling income dries up schools are fucked.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: It's going to say look Regulate to seven casinos increasing aid to schools permitting local governments to lower property tax.
Rym: Oh, yeah It says right there, right.
Scott: So basically what they're gonna do is they're gonna tax rich people less and instead to tax the casino.
Scott: You think well tax on a casino is a tax on the rich person who owns the casino?
Scott: No The money the casino gets comes from the poor people and the stupid people who go to that noise I would.
Scott: are there high rollers in the casino?
Scott: Yes, very few.
Scott: most of the money comes from old ladies putting coins.
Rym: I would only vote yes for a casino in New York like this.
Rym: if one it wasn't Obviously a corrupt law and I'll talk about why it's a car.
Scott: I would vote.
Scott: I would vote whoo.
Rym: Yes, because if they did not lower any other taxes and this was just additional money going into school Even if they don't lower any other taxes, it's still a regressive tax.
Scott: I would vote yes, if it was a casino only with high rollers No One could argue that people who are that sad are gonna.
Rym: they're kind of making their way to Atlantic City Occasionally on those buses.
Scott: obviously put their money in there And you're saving them some money because they have to travel less and to the bus to Atlantic City isn't if enough already?
Rym: all Of the money as in like some ridiculously high.
Scott: Oh, the casino is a non-profit casino 100% of its profits.
Rym: either It has like an 80% tax or it's a government-run casino and all the profits.
Scott: Yeah, the same way those liquor stores and those other states.
Scott: exactly.
Rym: if all the profits went into schools and Property taxes and other school revenues were not decreased in any way then I'd be okay with it because you'd be taking money from dumb and poor people now and Funding the next generation to be less dumb now.
Scott: Here's what I would do if I was this.
Scott: if I ran a state I would say look we're not gonna open up any casinos Except this online casino that only people in our state can use Which means less.
Scott: poor people are gonna use that because it's an online casino.
Scott: It's harder for them to use it.
Rym: They would have a wink and a nod to that.
Scott: only people in our state part obviously But it would mostly be People who have credit cards which eliminates a lot of those lower-income people's and it's mostly gonna be not as regressive attacks Also, it would cost less.
Scott: We didn't have to open physical casinos and a hundred percent of the money that casino makes would go to the state.
Scott: But I'm This proposition, yeah, this is gonna be a no because this specific one.
Rym: There's two problems with it.
Rym: one the fact that it forces the first casinos to all be out of New York City.
Rym: I'm done with this New York State bullshit.
Rym: I'm done with New York State continuously Holding.
Rym: it's so much cheaper.
Scott: I'm actually keeping the casino outside of New York City Actually makes it less regressive because if you put the casino in the city all those poor people in the city You'll be able to go to it real easy.
Scott: If you keep it out of the city It might end up being more like a Mohegan Sun, which is the kind of casino that you know The sort of middle, you know class Connecticut people go to.
Rym: but obviously the moratorium on having it in New York City is purely Because upstate interests want to have the so-called economic benefit in their local area.
Rym: first There's a bunch of pork going on with this.
Rym: You know that a bunch of people paid a lot of money to ensure the state Actually be in like these specific place a state senator somewhere whose buddies with a guy who wants to open the casino and he's pushing this.
Scott: Anyway, all the reason the other one of philosophically opposed to this particular law.
Rym: I forgot why I was opposed to it.
Scott: It's a casino.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway casinos are no on casinos, even though I think gambling should be is dumb to wait.
Rym: Wait, what just happened here?
Rym: Look at this ribbon Scott have an ideological position on something It's mostly yet also have a practical position on a reality of that thing.
Scott: Most people who didn't real news can.
Scott: we're basically more advanced than the real news already, which is why I ignore the real news.
Scott: alright, so Number two this one.
Rym: All right Here's the other reason why I was mad about this law.
Rym: all the literature that is for it is really pushing the idea that it Lets us lower taxes.
Rym: I'm I don't want to lower taxes.
Rym: I want to raise tax.
Scott: Right anyway.
Scott: Number two this one I sort of don't care about and I can see good and bad and I'd not Passionate or I might even just not even vote on it.
Scott: So it's what it is additional civil service credit for veterans with disabilities certified post appointment.
Scott: so what this means is that if you are a veteran right and You have been wounded in some way or have disability of some kinds.
Scott: You're in the military and now you have a disability and you want to get a state job in New York State.
Scott: Right you work for the state some kind of working for the state job, whatever it is.
Scott: It could just be like janitor in the town in the city hall in the capital of Albany or you know Who knows what it could be, but some sort of state job.
Scott: It could be state trooper.
Scott: All right, you have to take a civil service exam.
Scott: There are all kinds of these things.
Scott: I know some people have taken them and it's just a lot like bureaucracy.
Scott: You take some crazy test and you get a score and that score determines whether you can get these state jobs or not.
Rym: I took one to be a part of the census and the federal government.
Rym: First job, right.
Scott: so you take the civil service exam you just get a score and the higher score increases the likelihood or in fact guarantees the Likelihood or that you will or will not able to get a job working for the state.
Rym: Well, so the sad thing.
Rym: when I took the federal one for the US Census in the year 2000 I got a perfect score and So pretty much of any educated person takes these things they will get a perfect score.
Rym: So few people got more than 50% In my area that they called me daily begging me to work and I got offered every position.
Scott: A lot of times people get a too good a score and won't get the job They want like they want to go work for the police station.
Scott: It's like you can't be a cop.
Scott: you score too high Stuff like that.
Scott: Anyway, you hear those stories once in a while.
Scott: So then I think I'm Might sound harsh.
Rym: I think I'm gonna vote no on this one, too.
Scott: Okay, well you convinced me because I'm basically abstain right now.
Scott: So my rationale is if you say yes Basically, what you're saying is that if someone's a disabled veteran they get bonus points.
Scott: So they score middle of the pack.
Scott: They're gonna get bonus points because they're disabled veteran and they might get a job that they were under quality.
Scott: You know, they'll basically get preference over someone else.
Scott: You scored the same as them which is sort of unfair if you think in a meritocracy kind of fashion, right?
Rym: But it's also because we know our veterans get shit on right.
Scott: just because you're a disabled veteran You should get bonus points or you're a disabled veteran.
Scott: You deserve bonus points.
Scott: Both of those in my mind are a hundred percent equally credible.
Rym: I think we need better social safety nets for veterans So they don't need to do this kind of safety net.
Scott: Well look at in New York City for example if you're a veteran you can get a street vending permit way easier and the street vending permit that you get as a veteran puts you Lets you set up your table to sell stuff in way better locations like the touristy areas Whereas if you're not a veteran, it's almost impossible to get that street vending permit.
Scott: And even if you do get one It's gonna let you set up in a place where there's not a lot of people like you set up your hotdog cart in Astoria And not in you know right the corner of Central Park.
Scott: And if you see a lot of those people who are street vending in New York City who have the really good spots and aren't breaking the law By getting illegal permits They're mostly veterans because those the people who can get the permits because of the way the system works
Rym: But I guess because of the combination of our economy being not so great right now and the fact that a lot of people need These jobs anyway and veterans already get some level of preference.
Rym: I really don't want to prod the bureaucracy further hmm, but think of the veterans.
Rym: I do think I'm better in children.
Rym: We need to think about the veterans at a much more systemic level than this band-aid law.
Scott: That's true, but you still didn't convince me to not abstain.
Rym: Yeah, I'm not 100%.
Rym: I think I'm gonna vote now But I'm probably gonna make a snap decision in the little voting booth.
Scott: abstain.
Rym: proposal 3 exclusion of indebtedness Contracted for sewage facility.
Scott: you might say who gives a fuck about this.
Rym: I give a lot of fucks about this right.
Scott: So what this is is you let's say you have a town.
Scott: you're a mayor in New York somewhere like Elmira piece of shit.
Scott: town right and You want to set up.
Rym: you live in Elmira.
Rym: you take issue with what Scott just said.
Rym: you know why fuck you.
Scott: You know what.
Scott: you're not even all right.
Scott: Let's say you live in a good city in New York.
Scott: New York like Corning.
Scott: You're the mayor of Corning right Corning setting up some sewers.
Scott: well They've already got sewers there of course But maybe they need to improve the sewers or add new sewers for the new neighborhood or who knows what.
Scott: maybe the sewers get a Little broken they need to fix it.
Scott: well They need some fucking money for that right?
Scott: so where does the town get money if they don't have the you know enough tax money?
Scott: Because they already budgeted all bonds get taken debt right you borrow fucking money.
Scott: That's how it works.
Rym: this extends the limit of the debt that these that your city can have to have paid for Sewage infrastructure improvements.
Scott: your sewer breaks.
Scott: you need to get some debt to fix the sewer or you need to expand your sewer because people have septic Tanks and they suck, but oh there's dead limits.
Scott: There's a limit on the amount of debt you are legally allowed to take and you've already taken it all.
Scott: so you can't fix the Sewer and others poop everywhere, so if you say yes on this you're basically saying yes.
Scott: Allow towns to get more monies by borrow more monies than they beyond their limit Sewer so that they can fix the sewers and not have shit all over their town.
Scott: now They and why would the fuck would you say no to this?
Rym: well because the argument against let shit get everywhere.
Scott: Everyone have septic tanks which are bad.
Rym: more revenues, so we don't have to go into debt to do basic infrastructure.
Scott: That's a good idea too, but but also you need to fix your shitter right now.
Scott: You can't your shitters over phone.
Scott: You don't wait on that.
Rym: this exclusion has been in place since 1962. it just happens to be expiring next year right so that's the only reason we're voting on this.
Rym: is we extended another decade?
Scott: Well if it's worked from 62 to 2013?
Rym: now I don't know.
Scott: poop all over the place.
Scott: I mean look when we should say yes to keep the poop underground.
Rym: look what happened right.
Rym: it is possible that there are Townships or cities or municipal entities and even counties in New York State that are accruing debt that eventually will force them into bankruptcy.
Rym: Mm-hmm, and I don't know what to do about that.
Scott: But just because you go bankrupt doesn't mean the people who live there should have poop everywhere.
Rym: I feel like poop.
Rym: poop prevention on a mass scale is one of the most important things.
Rym: go ahead.
Scott: Yeah, I mean if you're talking about things government does it's like take the poop away bring the water in.
Scott: Okay Everything get set on fire.
Scott: Not let everyone kill everyone.
Scott: those are the right the fundamental parts before research.
Scott: You know we're lucky that the things you have to worry about in government are like these high-level things like you know not They aren't important, but like abortion and stuff and all these kinds of you know social.
Rym: Do we get sewage right?
Scott: yeah, no, it's you know.
Scott: it's like yeah, we need gay marriage.
Scott: That's important, but we're lucky that we can even think about that and not have to spend our time thinking about keep the poop underground Scott how do you know he's a king?
Scott: That's right, so let's keep the shit off the king and the regular people.
Scott: That's why we're better than those medieval folks.
Rym: so four and five are kind of part of the same the same thing.
Scott: It's.
Scott: I don't know why it's split up like this.
Scott: What would happen if you didn't vote the same way on both of these?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I didn't read the full text of.
Rym: like what would happen?
Scott: free right.
Scott: so what?
Scott: the first one?
Scott: We'll just do both together.
Scott: the first one is basically let this little.
Scott: the Constitution of New York State says that the Adirondack Foresty land has to remain public property forever period say so that's a constitutional thing.
Scott: so they want to make an amendment that says settle this land dispute and Let this part of the forest become private property.
Scott: and the second one says let him frack all over that forest.
Scott: That's now private property, so it's like well.
Scott: What if we vote no you can't have the land.
Scott: yes You can frack on it, or what if we say yeah, you can have the land can't frack it what happens?
Scott: I don't get it.
Scott: It makes no sense.
Scott: I think obviously you vote.
Scott: No you can't have the land.
Scott: It's a fucking my land.
Scott: It's state land.
Scott: and no you're not gonna.
Rym: Because if you vote for four what it does is the state gives up its claim on certain parcels of land But then gets an unlimited doesn't make other doesn't it?
Scott: make a constitutional amendment such that all Future land is now longer protected by the Constitution because the amendment opened the can of worms.
Scott: so even though immediately only that land would Go it opens up all the other land.
Rym: because the Constitution is now changed I can't I got to read the full text of it to figure out the nuanced detail of it.
Rym: Yeah, it seems to be specific to the town of Long Lake in Hamilton County.
Scott: Yeah, and it doesn't even say what the dispute is.
Scott: it just says there is a dispute and they can't resolve it.
Scott: and in order To resolve it without amending the Constitution.
Rym: Why don't they just resolve it with eminent domain?
Scott: Oh, that's a good point.
Scott: But basically in order to resolve it even if they use eminent domain it's set.
Scott: one of the arguments here is they're gonna have a lengthy Court battle will be the Constitution is complicated.
Rym: the Constitution actually forbids the lease sale exchange or taking any Forest Preserve lands.
Rym: they can't hear reserves either.
Rym: yep, so if we vote yes We could actually Theoretically also take lands, but I don't really want to let Nyko minerals incorporated Fuck around with the forest just because I don't trust anyone in our government.
Scott: because you use that forest.
Rym: I just don't trust anyone anymore, and I kind of want to wait on.
Scott: these things work so well in North Dakota.
Rym: Let's let.
Scott: let's look at other places that say you know it's like whether you think you know whether there is an Environmental danger for the mining or not.
Scott: it's like that almost doesn't matter.
Scott: It does matter, but it almost doesn't matter that out It's not us.
Scott: it almost doesn't matter for this decision because we can simply just look at The human effects of what has happened in North Dakota where they said yes and look at what is happening there.
Scott: We're basically you have like all these horrible social things happening because of the mining community that has sprung up and We don't want that in New York at least.
Scott: I don't want that in New York.
Scott: keep that in your shitty state non-existent, North Dakota All right, I'm gonna figure.
Rym: I'm gonna read a little bit of the details this one.
Rym: so go over the last proposal.
Rym: Okay, I'm not sure I'm voting on the forest stuff yet other than no fracking.
Scott: I'm pretty sure I'm gonna vote.
Scott: No, you can't have the forest.
Scott: But no you can't practice.
Rym: yes, you can have the forest.
Rym: also gets forest more forest back does it gets to pick.
Scott: which forest are We picking?
Scott: I'm trying to get maps and figure out which forest you like better over the last one about the old people.
Scott: the last One's pretty obvious.
Scott: it basically right now Judges in the Supreme Court which in New York State is actually the lowest court and the Court of Appeals Which is I guess the one above.
Scott: that I don't know.
Scott: But basically state courts state court judges are forced to retire when they're 70 just like get out your job is done.
Scott: We're getting new judges.
Scott: You know and I don't know if those are appointed judges or elected judges But whether you are appointed or elected you're kicked out at 70. your judging days are over and basically this says well look People are living longer.
Scott: Why don't we let him keep judging till they're 80?
Scott: They're so experienced.
Scott: Why would he kick out the experienced judge to bring in some young?
Rym: Experienced on one end ideologically.
Rym: I don't like the idea of a mandated forced retirement.
Scott: Yeah, I guess not practically the old people People in government.
Rym: yes You know that I'm sure there are good old people in.
Rym: out of
Scott: pure self-interest a young judge is more Likely to judge in a way that meets my sense of social justice less likely to say you know Not want to get do gay marriages or you know be racist when judging against or you know Person of color or etc.
Scott: Etc.
Scott: No, I'm not saying it all the old judges are like that.
Scott: I'm just saying more likely that an old judge not knowing any individual judge is more likely To not do judge in the way.
Scott: I want to judge.
Scott: So I want to kick out the old judges and bring in the young judges.
Rym: All right, I found some text that I got to go through in more detail on that forest one.
Rym: Okay But the amendment seems to indicate that it adds an exception that allows the state to do this Settlement and trade the land for the other land, but they don't do anything else ever only in Relation to title disputes in Township 40 Totten and Crossfield.
Scott: So basically they're amending the constitute the whole Hamilton County to resolve this specific.
Scott: There's a whole constitutional amendment That's gonna name this really fucking specific exception.
Rym: You know what this tells me?
Rym: our state Constitution is fucked the fuck up.
Scott: probably yeah, most of them are yeah, they're pretty old.
Scott: It's not like, you know the state constitution of Hawaii, which is pretty new.
Rym: I will read it in more detail.
Rym: I think I'm gonna vote yes on the first part and No on the second part.
Scott: Well, you figure out if voting.
Scott: Yes on the first part is Means that they're gonna do some mineral whatever is or whatnot.
Rym: I'll figure it out.
Scott: Yeah, who's take it doesn't even say who's taking the land.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I gotta read it in more detail.
Rym: It's like just tons of pain now imagine right?
Scott: So we're gonna read this and figure it out.
Scott: Almost everyone who's going to vote it's gonna have no fucking clue and it's gonna vote randomly Again the kinds of decisions that I'd rather experts that we trust in government be making.
Scott: well How come the state, you know legislature just couldn't figure this shit out?
Scott: Why did?
Scott: why did it become a proposition on the ballot because the way our Constitution set up here?
Scott: Let's move on all right.
Rym: so spooky things of the day Not-so-spooky.
Rym: So I have there's a tradition for me.
Rym: I'm a Farker.
Rym: if you guys didn't pick up on that I read far.
Rym: have any total farks right now I I do not have total.
Rym: I don't post to Fark much.
Scott: When's the last time you total Fark?
Rym: Oh god, like four years ago.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: I only ever total farks if someone gifted it to me and I don't post that often anymore.
Rym: I just read because I don't have time to post.
Rym: I've kind of I don't think many people on Fark know who I am anymore But I thought Fark.
Rym: I'm sorry.
Scott: You were a name on fire.
Rym: There's some people like my little pony killer and three-horn like there's people right.
Rym: so anyway or That titty bopper.
Scott: Sure.
Rym: So there is a tradition on Fark every year in Halloween to have the Halloween spooky story thread.
Scott: Doesn't it just get repetitive?
Rym: No, because everyone has new stories.
Rym: There's new people on Fark of.
Rym: people find.
Rym: basically people post either their creepypasta or like the scary ghost stories that happen to them As kids that may or may not, you know, they're like, I don't believe in ghosts But when I was a kid.
Rym: this freaky shit happened and here's my story Filtered through the memory of a child.
Scott: That's why it has ghosts in it And this is.
Rym: this thread is a delight on Halloween And if you enjoy to read ghost stories, even if you do not believe in ghosts This is the kind of thread where you will find a bunch of kind of normal mundane.
Rym: it's the kinds of stories that all your friends would collectively tell around campfires on Halloween and you can just read them collected in this Fark thread and I defy you to not be creeped out by fishy.
Scott: all right, so You know people like to wear costumes in Halloween.
Scott: We're in New York City.
Scott: We've seen a lot of costumes going around But this one here at San Diego State University their college baseball team had their annual Halloween Contest.
Scott: basically, they played real game of baseball Wearing funny costumes and it's pretty great because you know, it's one thing to wear costumes.
Scott: It's like I go to so many conventions now.
Scott: costumes basically mean nothing to me.
Scott: I don't even see them.
Scott: two guys at work both cos both dressed up as Doctor Who and it was the same Doctor Who and they Didn't know.
Scott: and they you know One guy was keeping it all secret and I'm like you have any idea how?
Scott: not original any Doctor Who?
Scott: Costume is ever there's 10 bazillion people dressing up as Doctor Who.
Rym: you would Ask him is which doctor?
Scott: it was the one with the fez.
Scott: I don't know which one that is, you know, you know, okay I just know it's the one with the fez anyway.
Scott: So yeah These guys played baseball in their costumes which increases the awesomeness and brick freshens up the whole thing again.
Scott: Cuz not only are you wearing the costume you're doing something in the costume and some of their costumes are pretty clever and hilarious.
Scott: Watching Obama at first base.
Scott: That's pretty good.
Scott: Yeah Obama getting the double play.
Scott: Thanks Obama.
Rym: Yeah Actually speaking of Obama my Healthcare provider is getting rid of my plan and they're blaming Obamacare for it.
Rym: Okay, so now I got a change.
Rym: I'm gonna get worse health care actually.
Rym: Okay, I have to change health care and is the worst The Obamacare then because I have to do it through my company.
Scott: Okay, I thought it's if you don't get it through your company then it caused way more to get it through an exchange.
Scott: Oh, I thought the whole point of the exchange was that you can get good Less than buying it from like just directly from a health care company.
Rym: Yes But that's still way more expensive than getting it through your employer the old-fashioned way.
Rym: if you can get a job The problem really is that you need a job to have health care.
Rym: Mmm Obamacare is like the first baby is Backwards blind step toward a possibly almost better solution.
Rym: It's not the answer Mmm, and it's so sad that we had to fight that hard to get that like.
Rym: that's what we want.
Scott: Let's vote out these old judges and none of them will say Obamacare is unconstitutional.
Scott: Yeah So Stasi land well things of the day.
Scott: Oh, we did things.
Scott: today met a moment.
Rym: Oh, yeah new forum.
Rym: It's awesome.
Scott: Yeah, we got a new forum.
Scott: The only people who don't like it are people who don't like change.
Scott: There's always people who don't like change.
Scott: I ignore them and give them the finger as I has always done things change deal with it.
Scott: You got used to that second form and you can combine.
Scott: so whatevs What else?
Rym: I made my 15,000th post in our forum great today.
Scott: I don't know how many I've.
Rym: I said, I'm game.
Rym: I wish I knew if I could put prescription lenses frames together.
Rym: Where's that?
Scott: Where are post counts?
Scott: I thought there are no post on your profile comments.
Scott: Yeah, oh, but it's only for you.
Scott: It's not for anyone else.
Rym: That's what it appears to be.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know I don't know.
Scott: What are the meta moments?
Scott: go to magfest.
Rym: go to magfest?
Rym: We're gonna be at like Zank icon and anime Boston and fact.
Scott: We have YouTube channels on.
Scott: my youtube channel is a lot of netrunner videos.
Scott: on rims YouTube channel is a lot of with ten of videos.
Rym: Yep, we uploaded a new episode of geek guys present shoujo kakame, utenna.
Scott: It's 35 minutes long longer than the episode of utenna.
Rym: it talks way longer than the episode But that's because it was a complicated episode.
Scott: it was but all episodes from here on out are complicated.
Rym: No, the next episode is really straightforward.
Rym: Nanami murdered that cat the end because she was jealous of it.
Scott: Yeah, that's it.
Rym: Oh, yeah, and Nanami has issues.
Rym: Oh, yeah, and Nanami tricked her into dueling.
Rym: our toga tricked her into dueling.
Rym: Oh That's it.
Scott: That's what happens the next time you watch that episode 100 years.
Rym: I remember that was it pretty well, so Any other meta things at all?
Scott: No, I sent out the newsletter again.
Scott: If you want to I'm doing that.
Scott: if you want to start a newsletter, it didn't work.
Rym: I didn't get one.
Scott: Oh, did anyone get it?
Rym: I Definitely did not get a newsletter Scott.
Scott: Oh, I got a check to me.
Scott: What'd you do?
Scott: I pushed the send button.
Rym: Let me look at my spam folder.
Rym: the fuck do I even get to my spam folder?
Scott: I'm gonna log in and try to send it now.
Rym: spam more Spam.
Rym: It's not my spam.
Rym: Oh wow sent 18.
Scott: All right Oh, sorry, but our anti Sam flagged this message for some reason so we can't send it right now.
Scott: It'll be sent after a member of our abuse team has reviewed it.
Scott: Huh?
Scott: There is nothing spammy about this email.
Rym: Maybe you link to something that is on one of their lists.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: tumblr YouTube.
Scott: No, we'll see it'll.
Scott: it'll be sent out soon.
Rym: I guess or they're gonna like cut down our account.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: It doesn't look like spam to me.
Rym: Looks like I swear to God if I get this newsletter and it's like Viagra for your Cialis Sure Or just a bunch of Japanese that basically says bye Versace yep.
Rym: All right, so Stasi land.
Rym: So Rym chose this book because Emily read it and it seemed interesting.
Scott: Well often picks it as the book club book, I'm probably.
Rym: Well, if you're a good boy Scott, I'll probably pick water ship down to the next boat.
Rym: Emily's choice if you're a bad boy, I'm going to pick something that you're not gonna like.
Scott: Oh, so basically the good boy choice is always Emily's choice.
Scott: Why don't we just have Emily?
Scott: do book club get Rym out of here?
Rym: You have a three-way cycle, but it's got if you're bad no Rym or if your choice is not It's got an Emily book club.
Rym: You realize if you've if you've stepped falsely the next book is going to be the satanic versus which I've always wanted an excuse.
Scott: What the hell is wrong with you?
Rym: Do you know what the satanic versus is?
Scott: Yeah, it's what's-his-face?
Scott: the rush D.
Rym: No But the other guy The other guy Not salmon rush D.
Scott: Is it?
Scott: I thought yes.
Scott: Oh, I thought it was the book by.
Scott: No, no What's that book then?
Rym: you don't know about this book.
Rym: it's crazily controversial history all the people who have died because of this book.
Rym: Okay, you don't know anything about this book.
Scott: I know someone rushed.
Scott: He is.
Rym: Do you know why he's famous currently still?
Scott: isn't he like?
Rym: Okay, that'll be my book club book Like.
Scott: he's like a Muslim guy that like Muslim Muslim people hate.
Scott: now, you see secular right?
Scott: I think it's something like that.
Rym: Okay, this is gonna be the next book then anyway.
Scott: Oh So Anton LaVey wrote the satanic Bible.
Scott: Yeah satanic.
Rym: I've read the satanic Bible I don't really want.
Scott: I was like, why are you making that the book club?
Rym: If I was gonna make something like that the book club, I would pick.
Rym: What would I pick?
Rym: I was going all Satanist in economic.
Rym: Uh, that's there's not it's not that interesting.
Scott: Okay anyway The next book club book is decided.
Scott: I did decide cuz I used my it's.
Scott: actually it's all.
Scott: it's too easy for you Which made me reluctant to choose it, but that the reason of it being easy for him Was not enough to dissuade all the other good reasons for choosing it which are a it is on Scott's shelf hasn't been read yet, which is always the first factor, right?
Scott: Yeah and factor number two cyberpunk so relevant to netrunner playing and right, so next book club book is Idoru by William Gibson, which Rym is already read.
Scott: Yep, so he doesn't do anything.
Rym: I will read it again because I remember you can actually talk about it.
Rym: Well, I I can talk about it.
Rym: The problem is I will talk in some generalities.
Scott: I guess I guess maybe the critic for the season title is Idoru.
Rym: It's it's like You've seen Macross Plus.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, it's Macross Plus the book kinda Only without as many badass fighter jets and with a lot more existential drama.
Scott: Oh, oh, I just want to throw in one anime tangent here, even though it's Thursday something related to Kill la Kill.
Scott: No crunchy ball crunchy.
Scott: Kill la Kill is on a crunchy roll.
Scott: If you go to the crunchy roll store, they have a store where they sell stuff like physical goods.
Scott: Right right now they are selling mystery box.
Scott: It's not the first time they've done this Mystery box of 30 anime DVDs version 2.0.
Scott: It's the second time they've done this for $20 $20 30 mystery anime DVDs.
Rym: you only have Two more days, I think to even yes because I really need 29 Akane's high kick DVDs.
Scott: you sell them individually afterwards
Rym: for a dollar each
Scott: and get your money back And there's some good ones in there or you rip them all and then whatever and it's super fun to get a box of random Anime,
Rym: I might do it anyway, but I gotta tell you
Scott: there's a discount if you're a crunchy roll member.
Scott: I got a discount on top of the discount.
Rym: I have a lot of anime DVDs that are still in shrink-wrap.
Scott: I just want to get it to make an unboxing video and laugh at whatever is in there.
Scott: It's like a surprise.
Rym: We should do it.
Scott: We should.
Scott: all you people hate spoilers so much.
Scott: You must fucking love surprises, right?
Scott: So buy this.
Scott: it's a surprise in a box or $20.
Scott: You love surprises more than anything.
Rym: All right, why don't we?
Rym: Buy it and review every DVD that comes.
Scott: I already bought it.
Rym: Well, we should.
Rym: I need anything.
Rym: we have not already reviewed that.
Rym: we see so nothing we should watch.
Scott: We're not gonna see anything in there.
Rym: We have.
Rym: we have not reviewed Akane's high kick.
Rym: So if we get 29 DVDs of Akane's high kick, I guess we're gonna have to watch it.
Scott: I think they'll all be different.
Scott: They're not gonna be 30 of the same DVD.
Rym: It'll be the sanctuary.
Rym: Oh, I don't think that ever made it to DVD.
Scott: No, it's VHS only.
Scott: All right, let's talk about Stasi land the actual book club book.
Rym: so my Here are my criticisms of it.
Rym: I liked it a lot.
Scott: I like it.
Rym: Okay, the stories were good but the author Focused way too much on the parts.
Rym: I didn't care that much about and totally left the threads.
Rym: I was really interested in just hanging like when she met with the basically the Super propaganda guy.
Rym: Oh, that was the most interesting guy yeah, and she like barely talked about him and just like never done didn't finish the interview and Raised him a whole bunch.
Scott: It's like oh that should have been.
Rym: I want to book just about him.
Scott: I mean the guy was so crazy.
Scott: I can sort of understand why.
Scott: you know, she more talked about, you know His personality and him and her being mad at him, right?
Scott: And you know, which is understandable because you could totally.
Scott: she did a really good job of letting you picture what that guy is Like.
Rym: my god him in my old man, right?
Scott: It's like she did a really good job of that in this book, but Really bad job of talking about anything.
Scott: He actually did historically or whatever Right.
Scott: Like I want to actually know about.
Scott: you know things he did and whatnot.
Rym: and I'll know historical Documentation almost and thus my primary problem with the book.
Rym: while I enjoyed it Anna Funder put herself into the story in this sort of Journalistic way.
Rym: that is a style.
Rym: I almost always hate right?
Scott: Well, it's there are ways to do that right and I want the actually, you know thought Thompson does that very well.
Scott: Michael Moore in his movies does that?
Scott: Yeah, right He does his documentary where he self inserts.
Scott: and the thing is even you look at him Sometimes it works like his like the first movie he did.
Scott: what about Ford Motor Company?
Scott: He did a good job of putting himself in there Yeah, but like in some of the other ones he didn't do a good job.
Scott: and you can actually see like in Fahrenheit 9/11 He only insert himself in so much as like narrating and didn't really go in the movie himself so much as the other ones.
Scott: Maybe because he you know saw and recognized that putting himself in that movie didn't really work.
Scott: Right, and that's sort of the case you get.
Rym: I think it's weird conspiracy theory in the second half.
Scott: Well, obviously the crazy conspiracy theory notwithstanding.
Scott: We're just talking about the filmmaking aspect Right.
Scott: So here in the book making aspect of this.
Scott: It's like the self insertion I think in some parts was good and in some parts was bad.
Scott: right in terms of the good.
Scott: it was like.
Scott: You know noticing those drunken guys who always hung out in the park and then going to hang with them.
Scott: you know showing you.
Rym: you know that sort of thing that goes on by having those very mundane experiences like with her landlord who Lived through a lot of this shit, right?
Rym: It's like being the outsider.
Scott: those people seem to open up to her more than they would a German right but in other parts It's like, you know she would just interview someone and you would end up learning less about that person's story because of the way the you know, the She was.
Rym: the perspective was you know Camera looking at both of them her and Telling me about her feelings Listening to this person and from her experience as an Australian who doesn't speak German that well, she spoke enough German You know Yeah But there's.
Rym: there were points where she kind of noted that she like she would lose nuance and subtlety and I think it showed in The fact that some of her interviews she would put direct quotes But in a lot of them like you could see like to be direct quotes and then there'd be a long paraphrased paragraph.
Rym: I don't want to say she was lying or that she was filling But I think she was reading way too much into some of the things people said and I think she was.
Rym: she was adding to the story more than was necessarily implied by what these people said and Implying a lot based on her own experiences.
Rym: So I didn't a hundred percent trust her retellings of some of the stories.
Scott: Yeah, I could see that for sure.
Rym: She said a lot of things about.
Rym: the other person was angry The other person was sad and I didn't really trust that those emotions were being captured.
Rym: But some of the stories were the kinds of stories that you wouldn't get in the more traditional Histories of this because she was a journalist there getting these stories not too long after the wall fell down.
Rym: Yeah When the German media was it still wanted too long after the wall fell down But the German media didn't want to touch this with a hundred-foot pole.
Scott: No, and the thing is some of these some of these individual people like crazy propaganda guy, right?
Scott: It's like, you know milky was still alive.
Scott: I didn't know that.
Scott: I mean, I know who he was.
Scott: I didn't know he was alive at this that late in the game and wasn't even in jail or anything.
Rym: Like some of these stories we wouldn't have gotten any other way.
Rym: and my guy the guy who painted the line It's like those stories were great, especially the guy who stole that fucking plan.
Scott: That's the best one That isn't that the same guy who painted the line.
Scott: I think it was ya know or that's a different guy.
Scott: It was a different guy.
Scott: I think yeah the guy who stole or was it?
Scott: It was the same guy could have been the same guy.
Scott: that guy was an interesting, dude.
Scott: He reminded me a lot of like that guy who thinks he's like the fifth Beatle or whatever where it's like, yeah, right anyway, but
Rym: I guess my main problem with the book is that much of the history and everything else could have been gotten from better more direct sources.
Rym: and If you removed all the stuff about the author herself, then there wouldn't be much book left.
Rym: That's true Especially Toward the end.
Rym: like she goes on and on about these sort of Trivial details of her trying to get it like she gets into the archive to watch some of those old propaganda videos
Scott: I
Rym: want to read a book just about those Propaganda videos
Scott: you're telling me and she
Rym: only was there for what like a day watching them and then she wrote her whole thing Just like
Scott: and the one she focused most on was like this lady who apparently you know She had.
Scott: really.
Scott: it's like, you know who had a normal story, right?
Scott: You know of living in a horrible place and it's like, you know She you know, that was the main focus is relating to these normal people and I think you know That was the person she could relate to most and it wasn't something that's you know worthless It was.
Scott: it was very valuable, but it it's not what I wanted.
Rym: her Her relation with her let that lady Had weird undertones at times that I couldn't tell if it was just the way she writes But I got.
Scott: yeah she kept putting in like she kept trying to call her and leave voicemails and When they finally met again, they were super friendly after X years.
Rym: Yep Like a lot of the a lot of those scenes were just written with such detail that there's no way that was all recalled from memory.
Rym: And then shin and they read the way I would write the early parts of a romance Like a lesbian romance.
Rym: I don't think that's what was going on, but they like it.
Scott: No that you could.
Scott: you can't disagree with that.
Rym: Yeah, that undercurrent was there and it was really distracting.
Scott: Yep So the thing that I you know, the thing that the book, you know If you know about East Germany and you know, this isn't gonna teach you that much more.
Scott: You didn't already know.
Scott: All right You know in terms of you know What happened there historically speaking and if you want to know that and you don't there's better places to learn it.
Scott: But the thing that I didn't know or that this book pointed out to me of the many points it made This wasn't the main point.
Scott: But the thing that I thought was most interesting was how When when the East German people sort of Felt like, you know, uh, those Nazis are gone good, right?
Scott: Like they weren't the night's like.
Scott: no you were the time But those people are you.
Rym: it shows how powerful propaganda is.
Rym: if propaganda says something you really wish was true, right?
Scott: And also but also now they basically feel like oh those communists are gone.
Scott: It's like no the ones of you who are old or you are like, you know what it's like a fucked-up Dumbo.
Rym: It wasn't the magic feather.
Rym: It was you all along.
Rym: That's right.
Rym: You were the Nazi.
Rym: You were the communists That's right.
Scott: And it's like I don't.
Scott: that's not something that I was really thinking about but it's like oh You know because a thing that comes up often, you know is how the you know Young people of Germany people who are maybe even born, you know the same age as us.
Scott: They were young when the wall fell or maybe they were born after the wall fell, right?
Scott: You're born after the wall fell.
Scott: you could be like freaking like 20 something years old.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, I remember the wall falling.
Scott: Yeah, me too It's like, you know They still get like, you know guilt on them for the things that have happened in the past.
Scott: and it's like we always say well That's bullshit because you didn't do any of that shit But your parents did you know, but meanwhile if you read this book it makes you think those people who were you know, the senior citizens of Germany don't feel or maybe some of them don't feel like they were.
Scott: Yes, you were.
Scott: and then maybe the middle-aged people of Germany don't feel like they were.
Scott: you know Germany at least don't feel like they were communist.
Scott: What's like?
Scott: yes you are.
Rym: Well, this book brings up all this idea that I've read
Scott: For the things that you
Rym: actually did that in general Germany as it came back together at least with the the East German stuff in the Stasi
Scott: Really
Rym: tried to kind of pretend nothing happened until it was too late to do anything with the information.
Rym: Yeah, like They're just trying to wait until enough people are dead to where when all the secrets start really coming out There's no one left to be personally affected enough to care.
Rym: Yep, so that then it could just go into a museum without drama.
Rym: When I mean you get like when the model look look at the puzzle thing, right?
Scott: It's like yeah We could just get some computers and just put these all together without doing this.
Scott: instead We're doing it this way partially because the computers are too expensive but partially for that reason.
Rym: you just said yeah Germany is a very prosperous country now and that stuff they have the technology.
Rym: It could be done and it's not moving quickly because there's too many people alive or in those files.
Scott: Which means you know, look how many Stasi bad people are alive and living about their everyday lives.
Rym: Well, because look at the sheer percentage of people in East Germany who were part of that.
Scott: Yeah, they weren't as evil as Nazis.
Scott: I mean, you know they were evil so they didn't get like Nuremberg.
Rym: if the US bad We if the US were like East Germany today, then we could assume that an arc in the front row crew forum Probably a third to half of you are in farmers.
Rym: Yeah, I mean there's that note that I never I never realized this and it was brought up in two separate stories in this book that There were the opposition.
Rym: organizations like the student groups had more Infiltrators in them than they had members But as a result the infiltrators actually made these groups look bigger than they were and how the Stasi had to deal with that as a problem.
Scott: Well think about this.
Scott: how this might relate to other places on earth.
Scott: We don't realize.
Scott: like, you know when my grandma was young in the US A lot of the people in the US were people who actually were Confederates.
Scott: They were alive.
Scott: There were Confederate people alive.
Rym: Still people whose parents fought in the Civil War saw the moon landing.
Scott: exactly, right?
Scott: So It's like oh the the bad, you know There were slaveholders walking around on the streets in the United States.
Scott: not anymore Right now.
Scott: their children are there but their parents aren't.
Scott: but it's like, you know There are still these cases right where it's like, you know Some people feel like you know No longer guilty for crimes because some revolution happened and sort of washed everything away.
Rym: But at the same time look at the sort of pragmatic reality of as much as I would viscerally have wanted revenge.
Rym: I mean, it's hard to not want revenge if you lived under something like that.
Rym: Mm-hmm, but at the same time Germany Reassembled itself relatively quickly both after this and after just World War two in general and Japan also did the same thing By having that sort of period of just wait and wait until it's not as Japan
Scott: hasn't gone over that because it wasn't It wasn't even that long ago.
Scott: also and those old Japan old people are way old.
Scott: So plenty of those people are still around.
Rym: Yep, but there's got again.
Rym: They're kind of just waiting and waiting and waiting and just waiting for this again at worse because what's his face is in there?
Rym: Well, yeah, they got a few right-wing people and there's right-wing people in Germany, too.
Scott: Yeah, sure, but you know, at least you got the pirate party in Germany evening it out.
Rym: Yeah, but the pirate party increasingly has to seem to ally with bad people to get anywhere, you know I'm not saying it's perfect or I'm just saying it's crazy.
Scott: things are going on there.
Rym: But yeah, it was an okay book, but I wouldn't necessarily.
Rym: unless you're into this history I think there are better books to read.
Scott: Yeah Like I'm sure there's a book out there like history of East Germany or history of that crazy Propaganda guy or YouTube videos of his show.
Rym: Yeah So yeah, that's it.
Rym: We got the next book.
Rym: It's Halloween It's 2013.
Rym: We started this GeekNights' shit in 2005 and we're still doing it.
Scott: How long will we still do it?
Rym: Uh, I think we got another 10 or 20 years.
Scott: Okay I'll have to kill you.
Rym: Yeah, if I kill you first watch GeekNights ends one day with us killing each other.
Rym: live on the Show.
Scott: Yeah, I will live.
Rym: Ah All right Jefferson Adams.
Rym: Yeah This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and make comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.
Scott: It's October 31st, 2005.
Scott: This is GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: Leroy.
Scott: We should probably put leeroy in there whatever.
Scott: Doo doo doo doo.
Scott: Oh, I got you start the news like doo doo doo doo doo doo doo, but not the noise.
Scott: Doo doo me going.
Rym: doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo doo.
Rym: you want to do that originally?
Rym: We're gonna have the So, uh, I guess we could do that or I could make that sound.
Scott: I think this copyrighted or patented by whatever news.
Rym: No, we'll just make it something else.
Rym: It's just Morse code.
Rym: We'll make it say something geeky.
Scott: Let's do this in Morse code.
Rym: That's real slick.
Rym: I like it.
Scott: All right, we're good.
Scott: Okay, so Scolito Scolito.
Scott: so, um Personal lawyer didn't cut it to no surprise.
Scott: So he picks the most conservative judge he could find in all of the appeals course Samuel Alito.
Rym: Yeah He's a little conservative a little bit.
Rym: Yeah, cuz this I mean.
Rym: the Senate's main gripe at least the Republicans main gripe with Myers wasn't that they didn't know about her.
Rym: It was that she wasn't proven to be conservative and not.
Scott: well, this guy's real conservative.
Scott: But you know, you look at not real real conservative.
Rym: He's I don't think he's yeah states rights.
Rym: I think he's more.
Rym: Yeah, yeah Rovers his way.
Scott: they pretty much call him Scolito and his name is Alito because he's scalia, too.
Scott: But if you look at there's a Scalia, however, you want to pronounce.
Scott: I don't know how the correct pronunciation.
Scott: I've heard both but Scalia.
Scott: I look at his voting record and like and a lot of things he votes the way.