Rym: Hey, it's Tuesday, September 17th, 2013.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: We're back from everything, we're not going anywhere in a while, and we're feeling salty.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So is it Darude or Darude?
Rym: To paraphrase what Scott just asked me- I'm looking it up.
Rym: And I realized in my entire life I've been saying it alternatingly.
Scott: I think it's Darude.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I'm gonna say Darude because I still say Macanized Supremacy off and on, even though that is also incorrect.
Rym: Or at least is incorrect.
Scott: I don't know if it's- How to pronounce Darude in Finnish.
Rym: In Finnish.
Rym: That helps.
Scott: Hold on.
Rym: Is it really- should we pronounce it in Finnish or in American?
Rym: Darude.
Scott: Darude.
Scott: It is Darude.
Scott: Is he a Finnish guy?
Scott: Yeah, he's a Finnish guy.
Rym: Alright, yeah, we'll say it like that from now on.
Rym: But yeah, that's that song.
Rym: So, because Emily didn't go to PAX, I got back from PAX and she was like, "I kinda wanna go to a con because I missed a
Rym: con.".
Scott: If you wanna go to a con, pretty much any weekend, there's a con to go to somewhere.
Scott: It might be a tiny shitty con, there's a con.
Rym: So for many years, all of our cool friends would go to SPX and there's always some other shit going on and we just never went to it.
Scott: I never went to SPX because they basically assumed it was Mocha 2.0 just in DC and I was like, "Why go to DC for the same con I've already been to this
Scott: year?".
Rym: Yup, so we decided to go, I'm not gonna review the con, save that for another time, but we went to SPX, just me and Emily, we brought along Loldwell, which made for some lols in the car on the way down.
Rym: You can't have a non-lol time with someone with lols in their hand.
Rym: It was also weird because I realized, you know, people kept, like other CollegeHumor people and just all these people kept coming up to us at the party we were in and they were like, "Oh yes, how do you two know each
Rym: other?".
Rym: We looked at each other and we never really had a good answer for that.
Scott: No we don't.
Rym: Like, we both know Conrad, we follow each other on Twitter, that's pretty much it.
Rym: And then at the party, I didn't even know, like there were people who showed up, but anyway I digress.
Rym: So SPX was pretty cool and we hung out and did the thing and I can see why the tweets that come out of it every year are the way they are.
Rym: I learned about its innermost traditions like, "Imagine if PAX had a chocolate
Rym: fountain.".
Scott: It does.
Rym: No, like an official chocolate fountain that happened at like 11 o'clock on Saturday in the con.
Rym: Where?
Rym: Eland.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: That's not, that's special.
Rym: Also there is no chocolate fountain there.
Scott: Oh is there?
Rym: Also I do not trust chocolate fountains.
Scott: No.
Rym: Because I've decided that the SPX chocolate fountain is in fact the same chocolate every year.
Scott: Whoa.
Rym: But yeah, there's a lot of cool stuff I can say about SPX.
Rym: but my opening bit, the reason I bring this up now instead of on a Wednesday show or a Thursday show, is that we drove there and that was fine.
Rym: We got to this place and it has been a long time since I've been to a convention that was not in a city.
Rym: It was in a convention center in Bethesda by itself.
Rym: You had to drive to it and we were like, "Hey, let's walk outside, look at our phone and see what food we can
Rym: get.".
Scott: Nothing.
Rym: There were two pizza places, neither of which was open because it was a weekend, and they were both like half a mile away.
Scott: Might as well be Hartford, Connecticut.
Rym: Hartford is a cornucopia of dinner compared to Bethesda.
Scott: And you know I like cornucopias.
Rym: I know you do.
Rym: So we see this Chinese place and Emily's like, "Let's just go,".
Rym: and I'm like, "I'm super dubious.
Rym: I'm the most dubious that a room has ever
Rym: been.".
Rym: And she's like, "Oh come on, you're always down on
Rym: me.".
Scott: And we're always right, Emily.
Rym: So she's like, "Yeah, we should eat at this place,".
Rym: and I'm like, "Eh, not super feelin'
Rym: it.".
Rym: And then we go in.
Scott: Meanwhile, every time we're not feeling something, it turns out that we're right.
Scott: You know, I see where she's coming from every time this kind of thing happens, but let's talk about the story of eating the weird vegetables at the diner, or the story about getting the salad at the Fudd Ruckus.
Rym: No, it wasn't a salad, it was like a chicken sandwich.
Scott: We're always sadly correct on these issues.
Rym: Well, I think in general in my life, the times I've been burned by being optimistic were way worse than the times I was burned by being pessimistic.
Rym: But we walk in, and then I see her go *sniff sniff* like take a little sniff, and then she's like, "Ehhhhh,".
Rym: and I was like, "Eh, let's walk back out the
Rym: door.".
Rym: And then we walked back out the door, went back to the hotel.
Scott: What smelled in that restaurant?
Rym: Smelled just like shitty Chinese restaurant.
Rym: Like shit-tier Chinese.
Rym: Remember when we couldn't get the good Chinese food planned D&D at RIT because it was too late?
Rym: So we'd get like the worst Chinese food, the one that would deliver, and it'd always be like vaguely room temperature instead of hot.
Rym: So yeah, we went back to the hotel and ate there.
Rym: If you live in that area, and there was tons of huge apartment buildings right there, there is fucking nothing.
Rym: Nothing.
Rym: So the other reason I bring all this up is that I go to check in, and they gave me the presidential suite.
Rym: I don't know why.
Rym: The room was a palace.
Rym: My entire apartment could fit in it a couple times over.
Rym: So we did what any good person would do, and we threw the cool kids party.
Rym: And a lot of people who were cool showed up, and I wanted to give a shout out to everyone who was cool who showed up at our party.
Rym: You all know who you were, and thank you for helping me rearrange some of that artwork.
Rym: I wonder if the hotel will notice.
Scott: So, here's the funny news.
Scott: Recently, people were complaining, or I don't know if they were complaining, but they were discussing like, "Hey, how come no one's brought back
Scott: HeroQuest?".
Scott: And my post was, if you've listened to the show, you know, HeroQuest is the He-Man of board games.
Rym: Yeah, I think we did a show on replaying HeroQuest.
Rym: I'm going to try to find that show and see if we in fact did, because if you summarize- It sucks balls.
Scott: It is a piece of shit.
Scott: Even if you want to play that genre of game, of, you know, basically NetHack with a board, just play Descent.
Scott: And I don't even like Descent, but it's, or, you know, there's a whole bunch of these games that are basically just dungeon crawl games.
Scott: Help!
Scott: Play fucking Dungeons and Dragons!
Rym: HeroQuest is not the worst of that genre.
Rym: I will say that.
Rym: It had some cool things going for it, and really, the problem was just that if you follow the game by the book, the game becomes trivial because the players kick in every door and kill everything in the room in one hit.
Rym: It's like when you're leveled up too far in Fire Emblem.
Scott: So here's the details, right?
Scott: A Spanish company named GameZone is going to create this anniversary edition.
Scott: They have distribution rights to Spain, but nowhere else, so I guess in Spain they really love HeroQuest.
Rym: Didn't they say they're going to release it in a bunch of other languages as well, because fuck you?
Scott: They will do so, which means you can buy it, even if you're not in Spain, you just got to get it shipped over, you know?
Scott: There may be some sort of Kickstarter crowdfunding, but they don't know.
Scott: There's going to be four heroes, male and female.
Scott: They're still going to have the 3D plastic furniture.
Scott: It's going to have a reversible board, so two different maps, and there won't be Fimirs, but there will be equivalent reptilian creatures.
Scott: I guess there's some licensing issue or something?
Rym: How can there be a licensing issue on Fimir?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: And it won't be expensive.
Scott: It'll be about the same price as Descent version two, in which case, just buy fucking Descent version two.
Scott: I don't like Descent.
Rym: All right, there's a whole Wikipedia article.
Scott: Way, way, way better.
Rym: Fimir are a fantasy race created by Graham Davis and Jess Goodwin at the end of the 1980s Warhammer fantasy roleplay.
Scott: This is why.
Rym: Oh, they were, Walt, okay.
Rym: In the Wikipedia article, they created, they wanted a race to be as distinctive of Warhammer as the Bruar of RuneQuest, however, the Fimir did not prove popular.
Rym: They made a guest appearance in Milton Bradley's HeroQuest.
Rym: Very few official sources remain published on Fimirs.
Scott: I thought it's a Fimir.
Rym: I always said Fimir as a kid.
Scott: Fimir would start with F-E, like the bone of Fimir.
Rym: Yeah, because I is always pronounced I and E and not E.
Scott: It could be a Fimir.
Rym: It could be a Fimer.
Scott: Is there a pronunciation there?
Rym: Uh, no, there is not.
Scott: I'm sticking with Fimir.
Rym: I'm going to say Fimir.
Scott: Fimir is a bone.
Scott: Fimir is F-E-M-U-R.
Rym: Fimir society is divided into a case system consisting of the Merg, the Dirac, the Warriors, and the Sheerl.
Scott: All right, listen.
Rym: The Merg is also known as the Witch Hag.
Scott: If the word Fimir, F-E-M-U-R, for the bone, the large leg bone, did not already exist, I would pronounce that as Fimir.
Rym: Okay, I will grant you that.
Scott: Because that word already exists, a different spelling must have a different pronunciation.
Rym: Okay, there's a lot of information on Fimir society here.
Scott: Yeah, if you pick any Warhammer race, how much fucking information do you think there's going to be?
Rym: Well, I guess it's a dead race now.
Scott: What are those, like, zombie robot guys?
Rym: Now, I'm convinced.
Rym: to this day, when I was a kid, I used to play Hero Quest.
Rym: Me, my little brother, and my dad was the game master.
Scott: And you were too dumb to realize the things we know today?
Scott: Uh, no.
Scott: Rolling the dice doesn't matter.
Rym: My dad cheated by accident in that, one, we thought Fimers could cast fucking spells just because we were dumb.
Scott: Okay, where did you figure that out?
Rym: I don't know, we just did.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Fimers cast spells.
Rym: Everything Fimir and up could cast spells.
Scott: Sure.
Rym: And they could cast any goddamn spell.
Rym: Sure.
Rym: So that actually made the game slightly challenging.
Scott: Sure, okay.
Rym: But, uh, I'm convinced to this day that my little brother went and got the book, looked up where that fucking, what Borin's armor was.
Rym: Because when we got to that map, you know, we're doing our normal thing, and my brother just makes a beeline as the elf toward this part of the map that I'm like, "Don't go over there yet.
Rym: It's dangerous.
Rym: Finish up over
Rym: here.".
Rym: And just searches this one fucking room and finds this chest with this magic goddamn armor in it.
Rym: Even though I was the barbarian, I needed it way more than he did.
Rym: Ah, good times.
Rym: But no, that game is great if you're eight years old or you're a patient father.
Rym: Otherwise...
Scott: It's like He-Man is great.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: It is the worst game.
Scott: It is not good.
Rym: You know, it's funny because there's another property that's getting a similar sort of...
Scott: Everything's getting remaked.
Scott: No one has an original bone in their... No one has an original Fimir in their body.
Rym: It's similar in that it's a foreign country pulling up a license with blessing from the original creator.
Rym: Some Canadians are remaking River City Ransom with official licensing.
Scott: River City Ransom was remade.
Scott: There was a River City Ransom on the GBA DS.
Scott: There was even the Super Dodge Ball, which we had.
Rym: You know what I want?
Rym: I just want to play all the other games in that series, but I digress.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: River City Ransom Underground is a modern remake of River City Ransom.
Rym: The video for the Kickstarter is kind of annoying because the guy's not that funny.
Scott: Yeah, he's definitely trying hard to be funny and failing.
Rym: But then they showed gameplay and it's like, wow, that is in fact the gameplay I want.
Rym: Because while the Scott Pilgrim game is fun, it doesn't quite feel like River City Ransom.
Scott: No, it feels like Scott Pilgrim.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Also, the characters look a lot older, so we'll see.
Rym: Ryan looks like he's got stubble now.
Scott: Ryan looks... Oh, those are the old pictures.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Ryan looks like Ryan.
Scott: What are you talking about?
Scott: How about Alex?
Scott: How's Alex doing?
Rym: He also has stubble.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: They both have stubble.
Scott: So, I guess it's more, I don't know.
Scott: Is someone ransomed?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I didn't watch the whole video, but I Kickstarted it because whatever.
Scott: Anyway, we should make River City Ransom where the girls save the dudes and it's all girl fights.
Rym: Oh, that would be a good game.
Scott: I know, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: As long as it didn't devolve into... It would have to be the exact same kind of game.
Rym: Another idea?
Rym: It can't be like the Princess Peach game where she uses the power of emotion to save the day.
Scott: Another idea?
Scott: We should make a fighting game.
Scott: All the characters are characters from beat 'em up games, so it's everyone from Final Fight, everyone from Streets of Rage, everyone from River City Ransom, Ninja Turtles, right?
Scott: Or we should, a lot of these characters are, I think, might be missing from, I know Hagar's on there, but there are some characters missing from Salty Bet.
Rym: You know what we need to make in Salty Bet?
Rym: You know what the number one thing we need to make in Salty Bet now is?
Rym: The femur.
Scott: The femur.
Scott: Sure.
Rym: Do it.
Rym: So, the auction houses in Diablo, Pay to Win, we didn't talk about them a lot because they're the kind of thing that just angered me and saddened me to the point that this, they're shit.
Rym: If you like it, if you used it, you're a terrible person.
Rym: We talked at length about why they were a bad idea, right alongside that Always On DRM, and yeah, they're gone.
Scott: That's, what?
Rym: They are gone as of March 18th, 2014.
Scott: Oh, so next year?
Scott: Yes, they are- That's still, that's crazy, right?
Scott: That this is a real story, not a joke?
Scott: Yeah, a game- What game ever has had microtransaction bullshit and then removed it?
Scott: None.
Scott: None ever.
Scott: This is the first one I've ever heard about removing microtransaction nonsense, and Blizzard no less, which is coming out with Hearthstone, the most microtransaction bullshit Pay to Win I've ever splayed in my life.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And they're removing that bullshit from Diablo 3, holy crap.
Rym: Now, it's interesting because they gave a statement talking about why, and they basically said that it wasn't, like it didn't fit with what they wanted the game to be.
Scott: You notice, this comes after they bought themselves back from Vivendi.
Rym: Alright, Vivendi, it's easy to forget.
Rym: It's easy to forget.
Rym: There was a time when Penny Arcade and the like would often point to Vivendi as being the source of all evil.
Scott: Vivendi owned Activision, which owned Blizzard, and Blizzard has sort of been this company where in some ways it's a good guy like Valve, in some ways not a good guy, but now ever since and Activision was more bad guy, only a little bit good guy.
Scott: You know, Activision, Pitfall good, modern stuff not as good, but Activision- Also, most of their old games also not that good.
Scott: Buying itself away from Vivendi, so now it's just Activision Blizzard, suddenly a good guy thing happens, it's like,
Scott: "Ohh.".
Rym: Well, keep an eye out because Dell- Hope increasing.
Rym: Notice how Michael Dell is just buying Dell back.
Rym: He's like, "Fuck you guys, I'm going private and I'm going to fix
Rym: Dell.".
Scott: I wonder if he can do that.
Rym: I might be able to.
Scott: So to quote them- If I was him, I would just concentrate on selling the servers, the 1Us and the 2Us because nobody's making those anymore but him.
Rym: The official statement from them on the Diablo update is, and I quote, "When we initially designed and implemented the auction houses, the drive-in goal was to provide a convenient and secure system for
Rym: trades.".
Scott: That's horse shit.
Scott: They could have made secure trades without fucking real money.
Rym: Yep, but as we've mentioned on different occasions, it became increasingly clear that despite the benefits of the auction house system and the fact that many players around the world use it, it ultimately undermines Diablo's core game play, colon, kill monsters, and get cool loot.
Scott: Of course it undermines that.
Rym: Uh, yeah, but it didn't really undermine it.
Rym: It undermined the grind part of it.
Scott: That's what Diablo's core- You could pay to skip grind.
Scott: That's what that is.
Scott: Kill monsters, get loot, equals grinding.
Scott: Diablo's core game play is grinding.
Rym: But who likes grinding?
Rym: Well, we know who likes grinding.
Scott: People who play Diablo more than once.
Scott: See, when I play Diablo, I play it and I just go from the beginning to the end and I just try to get to the end.
Rym: One, one, one, one.
Rym: Two, two, one.
Rym: One, one, one.
Rym: Yes, get to the end, beat Diablo.
Scott: Good, I'm done, right?
Scott: If you're the kind of person who plays Diablo where you go into hell and you sit there killing hellions and things in hell for a long time hoping they drop mad loots, yeah.
Rym: I did that once in one game in recent history.
Scott: Which is?
Rym: The first Castlevania on the DS.
Rym: Because I had the second best- I had basically the third best axe in the game.
Rym: The first best axe you can only get if you take the second best axe and kill, I think, death drops it and then you can have this crazy fucking axe.
Rym: So the only way to get the second best axe in the game, it dropped from this one monster.
Rym: So I was walking around and I found a screen that had that monster on it and I thought for a second and I was like I have to do it and I just walked back and forth for like a half hour until he finally dropped it.
Scott: You know, I was playing Super Metroid, which I streamed.
Scott: By the way, I have this Elgato streaming device.
Rym: Oh, where Geeknight streaming shit is coming to you guys.
Scott: So I'm just streaming like random games I'm playing, whatever.
Rym: Thing is, I want to do the same thing, but it'd be a pain in the ass to borrow scots.
Rym: I feel like I might just have to buy my own.
Scott: Anyway, so I was just playing Super Metroid and it's like I'd find a secret and sometimes I'd be like fuck that secret.
Scott: I don't need that.
Scott: It's probably just missiles.
Scott: And sometimes it'd be like I'm getting that secret.
Scott: Look how secret that is.
Scott: You know that's something good.
Scott: You know that's like super missiles.
Scott: So at least super missiles.
Scott: So I would go for it and some of them would be hard to get and basically I was trying to get it's like I could.
Scott: just sometimes I was like I'll just go get the space jump and come back.
Scott: It'll be way easy.
Scott: But sometimes I was like I want it now.
Scott: I'm using the wall jump, but I want it now and I basically got these crazy hard to get secrets.
Scott: that would have been a piece of cake if I had the space jump screw attack.
Scott: But because I only had wall jump, I basically had.
Scott: it was like sitting there for like at least 15 minutes failing at wall jumping with the shitty Wii classic controller.
Rym: What's funny is that actually of all games it was the Zelda Minish Cap game that sort of killed my desire to get secrets in most games because that game had all these cool secrets to get, but what you actually got was nothing.
Scott: See in Super Metroid you get something.
Rym: Yeah, Super Metroid you get something.
Scott: Well, there's that one secret where you have to run really fast and do the duck, the crouch, you know, dash super jump thing into this very narrow spot to go up into a missile and it's like hell.
Scott: no.
Rym: I can do with five fewer missiles.
Scott: Yeah, I'm not going for 100%.
Scott: I'm going for defeat the mother brain.
Rym: But you know, we have a lot to say about this, but I've slashed shot of all places.
Rym: The top comment, the first comment, as far as I can tell, quote, I always thought auction house is what may have Diablo three relevant and rewarding since the gameplay focuses on being grindy.
Rym: Now that you can no longer exchange gear for actual money, what's the point?
Rym: The game itself isn't fun enough to play.
Rym: And then people basically say everything that we were going to say, but we'll say it anyway.
Rym: So one, are they going to get rid of the DRM?
Scott: That's a good point.
Scott: The only reason they had this sort of always online, which is the bigger complaint than the auction house by most people, but not us.
Scott: Well, I mean, not that we didn't complain about that, but it was sort of the second worst thing about Diablo three was because of the money auction house.
Scott: If you don't have the money auction house, why do you need the always online bullshit?
Rym: Well we know why.
Scott: The console version, which isn't always online.
Rym: Because their ulterior motive was they didn't want people cheating because if some asshole out there cheats at his effectively single player game and gets loot that he doesn't quote deserve, that ruins my gameplay experience somehow.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: Also, too many people watch kawaii bebop, it's not a good show anymore.
Rym: Yeah, as that guy at Anime Boston so eloquently tried to describe to his friend and didn't realize my camera was just next to him recording.
Rym: But there's a statement here also on slash shot.
Rym: that is choice.
Rym: This is my second favorite comment of the year.
Rym: And this guy does not appear to be joking.
Scott: What's your first favorite comment of the year?
Rym: I'll have to go look it up again.
Rym: It was, I'll find it.
Rym: It was something great.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: I tweeted.
Rym: I just have to go find it again because I have to say it exactly or it loses its impact.
Rym: The lack of an auction house is what made D2 and Borderlands such a success.
Rym: Precisely that you had to grind endlessly to perhaps get good stuff gave people a sense of achievement.
Rym: When all anyone needed to do was flip out the credit card, that disappeared.
Rym: Plus five insightful.
Rym: What the fuck, dude?
Rym: Really?
Scott: Yes.
Scott: You achieve something by wasting your goddamn time.
Scott: Well, I mean, it is true, right?
Scott: It's a, it is completely correct.
Scott: People do get this sense of achievement, right?
Scott: It's these games reward people for spending time, right?
Scott: Look at like net runner or counter strike the games that we like.
Scott: these games, it doesn't matter how much time you spend.
Scott: They punish you if you're not any good.
Scott: And if you continue to not be good, there's people who've been playing net runner as long as me.
Scott: There's a guy I know.
Scott: Nice guy.
Scott: Great guy.
Scott: He was at the first tournament I was at.
Scott: Susan playing as long as me and he shows up the tournaments.
Scott: He still places even worse than me.
Scott: Like I'm usually middle of the pack, even though I just came in second for the first time.
Scott: Go me.
Scott: I could have won, but yeah.
Scott: Um, but he's always like dead last.
Scott: He just, he's just not good.
Scott: And he's just punished for sucking over and over again.
Scott: He doesn't get any sense of achievement.
Scott: Why?
Scott: Because he hasn't achieved anything.
Scott: A game like Borderlands or an RPG or Diablo or a border, you know, whatever these games, you don't have to be good.
Scott: You just have to spend time.
Scott: The more time you spend and they will reward you, you automatically will succeed and get rewards and make it feel like you've achieved something simply because you spent time.
Scott: Farmville doesn't matter if you've actually achieved anything.
Scott: And this is why these games, if you want to make money, that's the kind of game you should make because people of any skill level will enjoy that shit because they'll feel like they've achieved something when they haven't.
Scott: If you make a game that only achievers, real achievers, can feel like they've achieved something at, only hardcore people who are good at shit are gonna like that game.
Scott: Now it's a little more subtle than that.
Scott: You know how many people stop playing Netrunner because like, fuck, I just got my ass handed to me constantly.
Scott: Fuck this shit.
Scott: Or damn, Counter-Strike sucks.
Scott: I just die instantly all the time.
Scott: What the fuck?
Rym: It's a little more nuanced than that.
Rym: Because one, you know, I'm playing through Fire Emblem just to beat it so I can review it fully, liking it less and less the longer I play it.
Rym: But it is hard as a human to not feel that sense of achievement when you level your fucking dude up in a thing.
Rym: That is, that is, there is a psychological, there is a powerful desire.
Scott: It works on me.
Rym: I mean, Fire Emblem, like I found myself, I was like, well, I haven't really used that character yet.
Rym: Maybe I should power level her.
Rym: Oh no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Rym: But, dude, games like Counter-Strike and Netrunner, they don't reward time directly, but they reward it as a secondary effect.
Scott: Yes, practice, obviously.
Rym: They reward practice, which means you're spending time.
Scott: But anything, you know, if you want skills, even if you're a genius, even if you are a fitness.
Scott: in all of these, you know, fundamental skills, if you play a new game, you still need practice.
Scott: You could take a great athlete, and if they've never played this new sport called suckball, right, they need to practice these specific skills of that sport, which takes time, but the time in and of itself is not enough.
Scott: The time has to be well spent on practicing specific things.
Rym: They might just have natural talent and a knack.
Scott: You have to be, and you have, that practice has to be successful practice.
Scott: You actually have to, you know, do the right things the right way, and then when you go to play the actual game, you have to carry those things over.
Scott: It's not easy to do.
Scott: It's not guaranteed.
Scott: The games I'm talking about, like, you know, Borderlands, it's if you spend time, unless you are really, really, really dumb, time spent guarantees success, regardless of practicing or skill or anything like that.
Rym: Okay, so I found my best internet comment of 2013.
Rym: It's hard to really get it across, because everything's spelled wrong.
Rym: So you're, and this was in response to some political thing where the south as a unit was brought up.
Rym: You're spelled wrong, right.
Rym: sad to say comma, Yankee empire in caps is 10 root of all evil period caps secede.
Rym: Okay, that comment is my favorite comment of the entire year.
Rym: I have not seen anything that gave me as much joy as reading that comment.
Scott: Okay, whatever.
Rym: But with this auction house thing, there are a lot of people who do feel slighted or wrong somehow.
Scott: If I was a dumb ass and spend money on it, no one's complaining about that.
Rym: The people who get mad, if someone else cheats, I make finger quotes here by not grinding to get an item in a single player game.
Rym: They feel like because that person didn't put forth their effort, if he just, Oh, he just downloaded that Evie train Pokemon.
Rym: He just hacked it.
Rym: It is not worth the value of mine.
Rym: And in fact, he is invalidated my work and I feel bad about wasting my time now.
Scott: Well, I mean, if there was a competition, right where I had to fight some guy and it wasn't a level playing field, right.
Scott: And some other guy has a thing I don't have, regardless of how he got it.
Scott: I'm fucking this.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: But again, Diablo isn't directly competing at the penny arcade comic.
Scott: The penny arcade has already commented on this.
Scott: Who's cheating?
Rym: Who's who is the cheated party here?
Scott: Satan?
Scott: Fuck him.
Scott: Right?
Scott: Just linked to that penny arcade.
Scott: That says everything we have to say in so few words and pictures, which are a million words.
Rym: But that slash shot comment is that guy, the people who actually believe this are real and get voted plus five insightful on slash shot.
Scott: Of course.
Rym: So we'll see what happens.
Rym: I still haven't even bothered.
Scott: People who think how we give up sucks when it gets popular or plus five insightful.
Rym: I haven't even bothered playing Diablo three.
Scott: But I'm you know what, when it gets cheap, you know, I like I buy like a torch lighter at Diablo just to play through and kill Satan just once.
Scott: If it's if it's not 50 bucks, you know, why not?
Scott: Ten bucks if I got nothing else to do and all the other games are done now.
Scott: They said they gave this resident and beat torchlight to you publicly.
Rym: They basically said they want to.
Rym: you know, they're changing the experience for a reason.
Rym: They gave a reason and they have a secondary reason of.
Rym: we feel that this move, along with the loot 2.0 system being developed with Reaper of Souls will result in a more rewarding experience for those.
Scott: give me an expansion.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Oh, 2.0.
Scott: So then I think I will get a game of year edition that includes all expansions and play through once and kill Satan.
Rym: But I say I somehow don't think that they removed the auction house system to make a better experience for the players.
Rym: I think they removed it because it wasn't making the money they hoped it would make.
Rym: Maybe that is my guess.
Rym: That is the the unstated reason because it seems it seems odd to me that they would actually remove it for any reason other than it wasn't making money.
Rym: unless it is the we are free of a Vendi.
Rym: Let's actually do good.
Scott: It could be.
Rym: I give it a fifty fifty shot either way.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So I might have to stop fucking playing Counter-Strike.
Rym: go now because there's issues like, you know, the draws his draw distance issue, which Scott and I were talking about.
Rym: I learned some more.
Rym: There's two factors going on.
Rym: And I found a widget.
Rym: I can twiddle.
Rym: Oh, I'm going to play around with some widgets.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And that sounds like bullshit to me, though.
Rym: I'm going to.
Rym: I'm going to play around with some with both.
Rym: There's two pieces of bullshit.
Rym: One, I couldn't see into those fucking windows.
Scott: Right.
Rym: And now that I have a video card, that's good.
Rym: I can.
Rym: But two, if if there's a barrel on a map and you get far enough away from it and your draw distance recedes, the barrel disappears.
Rym: But player objects don't.
Rym: So you can see through the barrel.
Scott: Well, only if you're zoomed way in.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: And the thing is, this also wouldn't have been noticeable except they brought back a lot of those gigantic goddamn maps or at least there are.
Scott: at least there are certain spots on the map where you can see really far.
Rym: I think it's really the the those rush maps, the small maps that they do for, you know, they all the different modes there.
Rym: You don't play that much.
Rym: They have a rapid fire mode of gameplay where imagine a normal Counter-Strike match twice as fast on a smaller map like you start closer.
Rym: You fight right away.
Rym: There's a very simple objective.
Scott: And those matches hold down the button at spawn.
Rym: Those maps.
Rym: Not quite an F.Y.
Rym: Icy world.
Rym: OK.
Rym: Those maps are actually, for whatever reason, huge world.
Rym: Icy world.
Rym: I could play some Icy World.
Scott: I'm going to play Icy World now.
Rym: Oh my God.
Rym: I just want to play some Counter-Strike.
Rym: But yeah, this scandal proves that Valve has no idea what they're doing and they're ruining the competitive community for Counter-Strike.
Rym: You got a thing of the day.
Scott: I do.
Scott: So the most.
Rym: Top comment on YouTube.
Rym: I quit CSGO because of this.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: The most remixed, listened and loved video game music of all time is, of course, Mega Man 2.
Scott: Everyone knows that there's been a zillion Mega Man 2 remixes.
Scott: To use one as the thing of day would be a sin to, you know, put it above all the other ones that are also great.
Rym: I've got like 60 on my hard drive.
Scott: I know, right?
Scott: Here's one, though, that is unique.
Scott: I won't say it's the better of all Mega Man remixes, but the Mega Man 2 Lullaby album.
Scott: Lullaby renditions of all Mega Man 2 musics.
Rym: That's kind of cool.
Scott: Track one, opening theme.
Scott: Two, Air Man, Bubble Man, Quick Man, Flash Man, Crash Man, Wood Man, Heat Man, Wily Stage, end theme.
Rym: In the meta moment, we are going to be at MAGFest.
Rym: Be there.
Rym: Machine supremacy.
Rym: We did a panel at PAXOS and another one at PAX Prime at Shits on YouTube.
Rym: Our book club book is still Stazzyland.
Rym: Scott has not read it.
Scott: I have not read even one word.
Rym: You should read it.
Rym: It's kind of relevant to the NSA stuff going on.
Rym: I've already picked my next two book club books.
Rym: So, uh...
Scott: I get to pick next, so you have to wait.
Rym: Yeah, yeah.
Rym: I'll read my book so quick, just so I can get back to the next book I'm picking.
Rym: Alright.
Rym: You're not going to like one of the next books.
Rym: I'm picking.
Scott: The Cup Count of Monte Cristo long edition?
Rym: Nah, because I don't need to read that again yet.
Scott: War and Peace long edition?
Rym: I'm not going to read that shit.
Rym: It's no great expectations.
Scott: And yeah.
Scott: Complete works of some poet long edition.
Rym: I do have the complete works of Poe, but don't really need to read all those.
Rym: A lot of her just...
Scott: Well, you know if you go to the library, they always have those like, the old books are always like, complete works of like, I don't know.
Rym: Shakespeare.
Scott: Someone.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway.
Rym: So, yeah.
Rym: Salty bet.
Scott: Salty bet?
Scott: So, salty bet, we're a little bit late to the party on salty bet.
Scott: It's been around for a little bit.
Rym: Yet we seem to be ahead of the party because no one I talk to has ever heard of this thing.
Rym: Right.
Scott: Well, it's weird.
Scott: I didn't know about it.
Scott: At all.
Scott: Suddenly, I see like a news story about it and I'm like, what is this?
Scott: So I discover it because I read a lot of internets.
Rym: But apparently... Oh shit, Queen Beryl versus the most ghetto Gohan I've ever seen.
Scott: Never bet DBZ.
Rym: Oh, look at this Gohan, oh my god.
Scott: Do not bet that.
Rym: Gohan Zeta.
Rym: Yeah, Queen Beryl's winning the fuck out of this.
Scott: Yeah, it's Sailor Moon, your favorite, right?
Rym: Yeah, always bet SM.
Scott: Actually, Sailor Uranus is freaking the craziest powerful.
Scott: I'm glad I learned about Sailor Moon from you so I know to bet on outer-senshi and not inner-senshi.
Rym: Yeah, well Sailor Uranus is, Sailor Saturn is technically more powerful.
Scott: I haven't seen Sailor Saturn fight yet, but Sailor Uranus also almost won a tournament.
Rym: You know what Sailor Saturn's power is in the show?
Rym: End all life in the universe.
Scott: Nice.
Scott: Bam.
Rym: That's her power.
Scott: Queen Beryl, why aren't you doing anything against that DBZ?
Rym: Uh oh, potato, potato.
Scott: Okay, so the deal with salty bet.
Scott: There's a fighting game engine out there called Mugen and what Mugen is, it's sort of an open source free fighting game engine thing where just anyone can make characters for it.
Scott: So it's like the open fighting game.
Scott: You want to make a fighting game character?
Scott: Make it and they'll fight and pretty much characters can do anything.
Scott: You can make any kind of character.
Scott: Any mechanic that's ever been in a fighting game is in there, is possible to do.
Scott: There's a lot.
Scott: Like power up meters.
Rym: How many buttons does your character have?
Rym: Do they have beams?
Scott: Fatalities, fatalities, you know, everything.
Scott: So what this guy did, Salty, is he took Mugen, he set it up and he installed and downloaded from the internet every character he could find, thousands, literally thousands of characters from every property, licensed property you can imagine, right?
Scott: Some of them, you don't even know what the fuck they're from, but a lot of them are from animes.
Scott: Like here we got a Sailor Moon fighting a DBZ is a lot of anime characters, fighting game characters, video game characters, you know, cartoon characters.
Scott: I saw some Finn and Jake, I saw some Bender, I saw all kinds of stuff, right?
Scott: And he set it up to stream, right?
Scott: These characters, this game playing.
Scott: And what does it stream?
Scott: It streams the AI fighting itself, random versus random.
Scott: It picks two characters and they fight on shitty AI versus shitty AI and he streams it on Twitch.
Rym: So case in point right now, it's Gohan Zeta versus Queen Beryl from Sailor Moon.
Scott: Gohan Zeta won, fuck that shit.
Rym: Well Beryl was pretty potato.
Scott: Even though her animation was so good, whoever drew that one.
Rym: All the comments are WTF, WTF, WTF.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So you watch this and if you sign in, they give you like 300 something salty bucks that you can bet.
Scott: So you bet on which side you think is gonna win at the beginning of the match, then they fight.
Scott: If you win, you get money.
Scott: And the way they do the money is they take all of the losing players' bets.
Scott: So anyone who bet, is that Rorschach versus Mega Vegeta?
Rym: The Vegeta's doing that Mexibeam Twitch.
Scott: I wonder what Rorschach's gonna do from Watchmen.
Scott: I'm gonna bet on... Look at this, Watchmen versus DBZ.
Scott: Have you ever heard of something so crazy?
Rym: I'm betting on Mega Vegeta.
Scott: Whoever put that combination together in their wildest dreams?
Rym: Always bet flickering DBZ.
Scott: I know, right?
Scott: Yeah, Rorschach probably sucks.
Scott: So let's say that all the people who... Let's say Rorschach wins this fight and all the people combined who bet on Mega Vegeta bet a million dollars combined.
Scott: And let's say I bet 1,000 on Rorschach and the total bet on Rorschach was 500,000.
Rym: Rorschach's turtle.
Rym: I got beat like a girl.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So 500,000 divided by my 1,000 is one 500th.
Scott: So if Rorschach...
Rym: You win proportionally.
Rym: It's like an old school bookie in a movie.
Scott: Yes, you would divide the DBZ losing money into 500 pieces and I would get one of those pieces.
Scott: Everyone gets a sized piece in proportion to how much they bet on the winner.
Scott: So the more you bet, the more you win.
Scott: If you lose, you just lose what you bet.
Scott: And if you lose all your money, you go into the mines and you basically get like 10 bucks?
Scott: I've never been in the mines.
Rym: I have also never been in the mines.
Scott: Rorschach won.
Rym: Yeah, he did.
Scott: And he took...
Rym: Oh, and the owl came and picked him up.
Scott: I know, that was pretty cool.
Scott: I like that.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Come on, MexiBeam.
Scott: Never bet DBZ.
Rym: I need that beam.
Scott: The thing about Saltybed that makes it great is not really just the betting part.
Scott: It's the community part, right?
Scott: On the right side of this thing, there is a chat room, a Twitch chat room where everyone's chatting.
Rym: And it's just flying by.
Scott: It's a ton of crazy chat, even when the popular... Right now there's 557 Saltybedders, but usually there's more or less.
Scott: During the tournaments, they have... Sometimes they'll have tournaments, Shaker Classic.
Scott: And then there's tons of people then.
Scott: But during the non-tournament time, it goes up and down with time of day.
Scott: Chats are crazy.
Scott: And there's a bunch of basically in-jokes and culture of this particular chat room.
Scott: that is so internet, I like it a lot.
Rym: Here's the deal.
Rym: Think about what we've just told you.
Rym: What this is, in a nutshell, is a place for a community of people to gather and watch AIs fight each other with random properties, and it's just off the wall.
Rym: Simultaneously, the community support is limited too.
Rym: The only interaction you get, other than betting, is this little scrolling chat to the right of the screen.
Rym: This thing, because of all the things it combined, became a cool kids on the internet thing right away.
Rym: And as a result, it proves everything we've said about the internet and culture for the last seven or eight years of GeekNights.
Rym: It formed its own culture in a matter of weeks, distinct from all other internet cultures, with its own references, its own self-references, its own community, its own celebrities, its own lexicon.
Rym: It took weeks for that shit to come together.
Rym: And it's continuing to evolve rapidly.
Scott: Let's talk about some of the cool things that happen in Salty Vet.
Scott: So number one, they're always playing music, right?
Scott: You can hear the sound effects in the game, but there's basically a soundtrack.
Rym: It's sort of like background nerdy music.
Scott: The guy has really good taste in music, you hear a lot of Samurai Champloo soundtrack going on in there.
Rym: A lot of Sandstorm, I heard.
Scott: Yeah, one of the jokes is, anytime someone asks, "What song is
Scott: this?"
Scott: Everyone just says, "Daru De
Scott: Sandstorm.".
Scott: "Daru De
Rym: From what I can gather, at one point, already the lore of this thing is lost.
Rym: I can't seem to find a reference to where it started, but I think Sandstorm played once.
Scott: Yeah, whenever a Shaker classic starts, he actually does play Daru De Sandstorm.
Scott: And you know, in fighting games, there's always the map, like the screen, like the arena of where they're playing.
Scott: So it's random.
Scott: during the regular times, during the Shaker classic, they actually have a Shaker classic.
Rym: You know, shitty Eris or waifu with a, ugh.
Scott: Probably waifu.
Rym: Ah, I'm gonna dream on Eris.
Scott: Ikisan, I'll take Ikisan.
Rym: I'm dreaming on Eris.
Scott: Yeah, the dream.
Scott: If you bet on the character who no one's betting on, that's called the dream.
Scott: And it's like, "Dreams,
Scott: dreams!".
Scott: 'Cause if you win, you're gonna get mad rich, 'cause you bet on the high odds, like betting on the shitty horse and the Kentucky Derby.
Rym: Okay, wow, so someone's explaining to someone else in the chat right now, what people keep saying
Rym: "Mexi.".
Rym: They're like, "What's
Rym: that?".
Rym: And they're actually explaining it legit.
Rym: So here's the deal.
Rym: With Mugen, as we said, anyone can make any character.
Scott: So apparently, people, particularly in Brazil.
Rym: And Mexico.
Scott: Mostly Brazil, made a bunch of characters, and those characters speak in Portuguese.
Scott: You'll have like a Gohan show up, and he'll speak Portuguese, like, for his taunts and whatever.
Scott: So people are like, "Mexi, Mexi,".
Scott: you know, it's not Mexican, but they call it Mexican.
Scott: Even though it's not.
Scott: And then, these characters tend to have like these beams.
Scott: they shoot a lot, you know?
Rym: Well these characters are usually made, but you know, look, in Central and South America, things like Dragon Ball and robot shows are ridiculously popular.
Rym: So the kids down there are also really into video games and fighting games.
Rym: So there's a lot of communities that will make characters for Mugen, and they make their favorite characters, and they make them ridiculously overpowered, because that's what you do when you're 14.
Rym: So you'll have this like glitched out fucking Gohan that doesn't even animate right, and he'll sit there kind of spazzing out for a while, and then out of nowhere, this one-shot beam just shoots out of his mouth and kills the other guy.
Scott: You'll also have guys with like HP, where like they take tons and tons of damage constantly, but they hardly lose any health because they have Mexi HP, yeah.
Rym: The fact that this culture has grown so quickly, and it's such a unique part of the internet, I enjoy it thoroughly, and I can't really tell you why.
Scott: It's like if I really just don't feel like doing anything, you know, I just put on some salty bit.
Scott: And especially if I see a tweet that says there's a Shaker classic going on, I am so in on that.
Scott: Because the fights in the Shaker classic are so real, they go down to the wire usually.
Scott: It's crazy good.
Rym: Oh yeah, Eris winning handily.
Rym: The waifu is pretty, uh, it's not doing so hot.
Scott: Aww, that's sad.
Rym: Yeah, it wasn't a dream though.
Scott: I think people know that he sounds bad.
Scott: I always bit waifus.
Rym: I learned waifus burn me too many times.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: I always bit Toho though.
Rym: So I don't know what else we can say, I mean I'm watching salty bit and I keep getting distracted because I got salty bucks riding on this shit.
Scott: Right, but who would think about it, right?
Scott: It's like, it's already, when you're sitting there watching your friends play a video game, most of the time it's like boring, I want to play, I want to watch.
Rym: Sometimes it's not.
Rym: Like when we hang out, like two people are playing, I don't know, Street Fighter IV and the rest of us are on the couch, we'll kind of watch it while we're hanging out.
Scott: Yeah, but this is like, I'll intently watch salty bit and it's AI's fighting each other.
Scott: It's crazy.
Rym: It would not be as interesting if it was always real people, if it was always real characters.
Scott: I think originally they built this system so you could bet the fake money on some like real fighting tournaments, like pros fighting.
Rym: But I like it way more.
Scott: But then they took that system and put the salty bit into it when there weren't any real tournaments happening.
Rym: Because the moments will be like, one time this tiny little Kenshiro came up against a gigantic colossus and I bet on Kenshiro.
Scott: X-Men colossus versus Hokuto.
Scott: no Ken.
Scott: Think about that.
Scott: That's amazing.
Rym: Kenshiro on screen was like 15 pixels tall.
Scott: Always bet hitbox.
Rym: So I bet him and then the match starts and just WOOTAAH and he hits colossus, one shots him.
Rym: WOOTAAH.
Scott: It was a beauty to behold.
Scott: Omae wa mou shindeiru.
Rym: But this other time there was this glitched out fucking Servbot versus someone else and they were fighting.
Rym: and then the Servbot just like starts spazzing out and floating up higher and higher and higher and just flew off the screen and never came back.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: And then the chat people were like, his people needed him.
Scott: I think, you know ever see a movie and there's some kind of fight and people are betting on it, right?
Scott: Like think about, for example, in Street Fighter 2, the background on Vegas.
Rym: There's always the guy standing there like shouting odds and taking money from people and handing them tickets.
Scott: There's people with a fist full of money and they're just pumping their fist.
Scott: that's full of money, right?
Scott: Or there'll be people surrounding a cage where people are fighting, banging on the cage with money in their fist and money falling down, right?
Rym: Huron Barter Town.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's like, if you think about that stereotypical scene of people betting on something, you know, some sort of gambling fight.
Scott: When you're watching Salty Bet and you're betting and reading the chat and you're into it, it's like you feel like you're in one of those situations where you're the guy standing next to the cage with a fist full of money, shaking it, watching the fight, going, yeah, go whoever you are.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Kick his ass.
Scott: Yeah, dude.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And it's like, it just puts you in that mood.
Rym: It is what horse racing.
Scott: It feels like what horse racing looks like in the movies without the horrible illegal parts or the real money or just the sad parts or the sad homeless guy betting his last dollar or the poorly treated.
Rym: But this has that moment where you buy the ticket for the long shot and it almost wins and then it loses and you tear the ticket up and throw it on the ground, except I tear up my virtual ticket and throw it on the ground.
Rym: I only got like seven hundred salty bucks right now.
Scott: Yeah, I actually pay.
Scott: So you can pay real money for Salty Bet, which I did, not because I care about how much salt.
Rym: Now do you realize half our listeners are laughing hysterically now at that admission, What?
Rym: That you paid money for Salty Bucks.
Scott: OK, so I didn't pay money.
Rym: I also paid money.
Scott: Right, because I don't really care about winning Salty Bet.
Scott: It's like I'll just go all in every time.
Rym: Poison is definitely going to beat that glitched fucking SpongeBob.
Scott: I don't know about that.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: I'm betting on poison.
Scott: SpongeBob is hit bucks.
Rym: He is definitely going to win.
Rym: Anyway, look at that sad bender in the background.
Scott: Yeah, I know.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Um, I bet I paid money to Salty Bet as basically I just wanted to reward the people for coming up with this like, holy crap, this is amazing.
Scott: Take my money.
Scott: And, you know, so I gave him 30 bucks.
Scott: It's like whatevs.
Scott: It's no deal for me.
Scott: I have money, but Salty Bet.
Scott: It's like I do not want this to disappear.
Scott: It's incredible.
Scott: And the fact that the benefits I get, hell, SpongeBob, I don't even use the benefits I get from it.
Scott: So the benefits you get by giving them money is that number one, you can't go below 600 salty bucks.
Scott: So basically I could, if I wanted to, I can go all in every time and just feed the economy.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And eventually a dream will come true and I'll be mega rich, but a big deal.
Scott: I can't use this money for anything else.
Scott: So what does it matter?
Scott: how much I have?
Scott: All that matters is that the more I bet on an individual fight, the more I end up like sort of caring about the result.
Scott: So it's like going all in every time actually gives you the greatest enjoyment.
Rym: Oh, this fight is real.
Scott: I know, right?
Scott: You get the greatest enjoyment of Salty... No, yes!
Rym: Look, it came down to one goddamn bar, poison one badly.
Scott: Real, so real.
Rym: Oh, my God.
Scott: Yeah, you get the most enjoyment by betting more.
Scott: And it's like if you lose, so what?
Scott: Even if you didn't pay money or in the salt mines, you have 10 bucks.
Scott: Fine.
Scott: You bet all your 10 bucks for the dream, right, and hope you win and you'll get out of the mines.
Scott: And you see plenty of people in the chat are like, yes, out of the mines.
Scott: So it happens.
Scott: It happens pretty often.
Scott: The other benefit you get is that if you're in like the Illuminati, you can actually look up the stats and see basically in real time, you know, how many wins and losses each character has.
Scott: So you can sort of know who to bet on, like buying a magazine that tells you which horse is better and the horse races.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: I never even use it, because if I look at that, basically, all I'm basically seeing is either A, this side is one fight, one sided.
Scott: And now there's no reason to even watch that fight, because now I'm just going to bet.
Scott: And if I bet on the loser, it's like, oh, oh, well, this does, you know, you got to watch out, too, because, OK, Gohan wins a lot.
Rym: But there's like 100 GoHans.
Scott: Well, you can figure out which one it is by looking carefully.
Rym: Usually.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Other people will be like, fake Gohan, fake Gohan, they'll let you know.
Rym: The thing is, people lie just as all.
Rym: yeah, poison crush, trust.
Scott: because of the way the betting works.
Scott: You cannot trust the chat.
Scott: The people who know which character is going to win want everyone else to bet on the character that is going to lose.
Scott: That way they get more money.
Scott: Most times everyone bets on the one who's going to win.
Scott: No one bets on the one that's going to lose.
Scott: Ninety nine percent of the time, the dream does not happen.
Scott: The winner who is expected to win wins.
Scott: The stronger horse wins the race.
Scott: Everyone who bet on the strong horse gets holla holla yada, one dollar, just one dollar and everyone, the losers lose everything.
Rym: Oh, it's the magic girl.
Rym: OK, but Gohan Grande, Normale, Grande, Normale.
Scott: Be magical from as Yu-Gi-Oh!
Scott: Right.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I think I bet on her once and I was sad for doing so.
Scott: If I remember correctly.
Scott: I got two grand.
Rym: I'm putting it all on Gohan, Grande, Normale.
Scott: I think that might be a good idea because I remember Be Magic Girl did not come through for me once when I bet on her.
Rym: El Grande go home.
Rym: All in on penguin?
Rym: Oh, there's penguins in the background.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But they're like real penguins.
Rym: They're not.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Salty Bet is super fun.
Rym: You guys should play it.
Rym: We might do some GeekNights stuff related to streaming ourselves playing Salty Bet.
Scott: We're definitely having Salty Bet fun times.
Scott: I haven't gotten tired of it yet.
Scott: I don't know when I will.
Rym: OK.
Rym: Everyone bet on Gohan, Grande, Normale.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: There you go.
Rym: My $2,000 bet is going to get me 35 bucks.
Scott: Hey, not bet.
Scott: See, that's another reason to go.
Scott: all in is that when you do win, you're not going to get holla holla a dollar.
Scott: You're going to get like $35, something like that, because you bet enough that you're getting more than a dollar's worth.
Scott: It's just funny how the Salty Bet economy keeps growing because just the way it's built is so many people just get like automatic dollars.
Rym: And so the top bet for this match, someone bet one hundred and twenty five.
Scott: The green number is how much they bet to three.
Rym: All right.
Scott: They bet one million salty bucks because they know that he's going to win.
Scott: Click on toggle.
Scott: See what people bet on player two.
Rym: Ah, yep.
Scott: There it is.
Rym: Fifteen thousand.
Rym: They're going to be really about fifteen thousand on that dream.
Scott: Listen, if they win, that is the biggest dream.
Scott: What are the odds right now?
Rym: The odds were fifty eight to one.
Scott: that if he won that.
Scott: Are you kidding me?
Scott: He would have been the richest and salty bet immediately.
Rym: Every time I bet on a DBZ character, I lose all my money.
Scott: That's I don't know.
Scott: It's Salty Bet.
Scott: The Salty's Dreamcast casino has nothing to do with Dreamcast.
Scott: Do not bet on the thing with the blue stick.
Rym: Why?
Scott: It never wins.
Rym: But look at that thing.
Scott: No, I've bet on that before.
Scott: It's a mistake.
Rym: Look, Emma Frost's boobs are moving, but most of the rest of her body is not.
Scott: Mistakes were made.
Scott: Bet Emma Frost.
Scott: I'm telling you.
Rym: I'm betting ten dollars on that stick.
Scott: It's dreams.
Rym: It's a ten dollar dream.
Rym: Ten dollar dream.
Rym: Con Me Chon.
Rym: What is that blue stick?
Rym: I don't even know what Con Me Chon is from.
Rym: What's this up?
Scott: It's an ice hockey stick.
Rym: Con Me Chon.
Rym: Mugen database.
Rym: All right.
Rym: That's the only plus the top link.
Scott: There are some characters just in there.
Rym: Is a fighter with a big wrench.
Rym: But she's the mascot of an online board game and possibly a character of the Mugen game Nijikaku.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Creator.
Rym: She was created by a woman.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: And you can't download her.
Rym: Oh.
Rym: Uh, people bet evenly and she's kicking Emma Frost's ass.
Scott: I guess Emma Frost is sucking because I don't know how I've ever seen Emma Frost fight in Mugen this before.
Rym: This is a fake Emma Frost.
Rym: Look at her busted glitchy hair.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Because Con Me Chon is pretty, pretty potato.
Scott: She's not super potato, but she's potato.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Uh, we're gonna stop now so we can display some more salt in bed.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.