Rym: It's Wednesday, August 28th, 2013.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights Tonight, Attack on Titan.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: The other day, uh, Emily was kind enough to buy some tickets and we went with some friends to go see Potted Potter, which was supposedly- They've been advertising the fuck out of that everywhere.
Rym: Yep, but I read some reviews and people seemed to have good things to say about it.
Rym: And I'm not a big fan of the Harry Potter books But I'm a big fan of reduced Shakespeare and those kinds of things.
Rym: So I figured, all right, this appears to be a 70-minute summary of all of Harry Potter.
Rym: That could be pretty good and it's selling out and people seem to really like it.
Scott: It's possibly good.
Scott: Well, it's advertised everywhere.
Scott: It could be contributing any of the fact that it's Harry Potter.
Scott: Yeah, but- I'm surprised it's not like, is it actually like legal?
Scott: Like, did Harry Potter endorse this shit?
Rym: Well, parodies are pretty heavily covered by the First Amendment.
Scott: Yeah, but they're calling it Potter, right?
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: And charging money.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Yeah, but regardless, uh, so we went to see it and I'm not gonna say it's the worst thing I've ever seen in my life because I did in fact see a man die once.
Scott: Great digital target?
Rym: This was What a- this is an- It was bad.
Rym: I'll tell you what.
Rym: It is bad.
Rym: It is so bad.
Rym: It is hard to express how bad it is.
Rym: What I will say is that in the 74 minutes of this event, maybe 5% of that was actually Harry Potter jokes and the rest was the performers mugging for the audience and making meta jokes about how they don't know anything about Harry Potter.
Scott: Really?
Scott: Really.
Scott: You think the whole thing would be Harry Potter jokes, even if they were bad ones?
Rym: It was- it was the most superficial you could be and still even be close to being Harry Potter.
Rym: It was literally like every joke was a one-note joke and then the same meta joke, "If you haven't read the books, have
Rym: you?".
Scott: "Ha ha
Scott: ha.".
Scott: Mmm.
Rym: The acting was bad.
Rym: The interaction was bad.
Rym: The stage setup was bad.
Scott: How did they get enough money to advertise all the fuck over town?
Rym: So it keeps selling out, right?
Rym: And the audience, it- you know what it played like?
Rym: Imagine bad children's theater.
Rym: Like, you know, imagine cosplay chess.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Or, I don't know, any cosplay event at a convention other than- That shit's popular.
Rym: Other than the judging of costumes.
Scott: So any cosplay skit, any cosplay related event- How were the costumes and sets and things?
Rym: Uh, non-existent.
Rym: Awful.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Rym: The worst.
Rym: It was a terrible, terrible thing.
Rym: It's going to Boston now, so I encourage all of you out there, if you even think or know anyone who might think that they might want to go see Potted Potter, just slap the tickets out of their hands and tear their credit card up.
Rym: If they like cosplay chess- Yeah, if you like cosplay chess, you will love the fuck out of this Potted Potter.
Scott: But- Or the cosplot at the Masquerade?
Rym: It was not as good as the cosplot at the Masquerade.
Scott: Whoa, that is seriously bad.
Rym: I'm actually gonna say that.
Scott: Cosplot is unintelligible.
Rym: Yes, but the cosplot at least had a pretty well-acted Skeletor.
Scott: That guy Skeletor was pro MVP Skeletor.
Rym: That Skeletor was better than anything that happens.
Rym: They should have just made a short Skeletor show and that- I would watch a periodic five-minute webinar, webisode show.
Rym: that was just that Skeletor.
Scott: That might exist.
Rym: It might.
Rym: Potted Potter is an abortion.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Or it should be.
Scott: The sad part is the audience- It's a baby that's not doing too well and needs an abortion.
Rym: The audience was about three quarters adults about my age without children, who seemed equally unimpressed.
Scott: Oh, really?
Scott: There wasn't a large applause?
Rym: There was a large applause, but the people in the- like, basically the other quarter of the audience was families with little kids.
Rym: And all the adults, almost without exception, were people who obviously do not commonly go to the theater.
Rym: They were taking the playbills and going like, "Oh my god, a playbill, ooh," and just listening to their conversations.
Rym: Yeah, Potted Potter is great if you've never seen a mediocre cosplay chess before.
Rym: So yeah, that's what I think your cosplay chess.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: Okay, so I don't really have a news right now.
Scott: So what I'm gonna do is I did, however, find some time recently to read some of the comics that have been piling the fuck up in my apartment.
Rym: Oh my god, I'm barely working my way through the adventure time.
Scott: I get a whole box of comics fucking every month at my doorstep, and I can barely read any of them because I'm too busy with other geekeries, but I read through all basically the single-issue floppy comics and a couple trades.
Scott: So among those single-issue floppy comics, of course, most written, or right, or not as bad as Potted Potter, but you know, not good.
Scott: And there were, of course, some gems, and I want to talk to you today about The Gemist, right?
Scott: Written by none other than the most heralded comic creator, perhaps, of GeekNights.
Rym: You know, it would be fitting if this were Gem, the comic, but I know it's not.
Scott: Yeah, no, Jeff Lemire, who's the person where we, you know, the must-read of all GeekNights.
Rym: Jeff Lemire's one of those people, you know, he's one of those people that we love everything they do without question, and it would take a lot of bad works coming out of them for us to stop loving them.
Scott: Anyway, so yeah, so Jeff Lemire's latest comic, A Sweet Tooth Ended, so his new vertical comic is Trillium, right?
Scott: So I pick up Trillium, and I just start reading it, and I get to the title page, which is page two, and I notice that there's two sets of credits, and they're sort of upside down each other, and I'm like, "What the
Scott: fuck?".
Scott: And I sort of flip to the back, and I realize there's like an upside-down, it's a flip book, which is, they do a lot of that on free comic book day, where you put one cover on one side and one cover on the other side, and you flip the book over, and basically there's one comic that reads and ends in the middle, and another comic that reads and ends in the middle, that we get two comics and one book, right?
Scott: And I'm kind of glad I didn't buy this in trade so that I could get the flip experience, because when I got to the middle, this is not really a spoiler, it's actually the same goddamn comic book, it wasn't two in one, and it's called Trillium, so I wonder what the fuck the third thing is.
Scott: This might be the best, I mean, just based on this one issue, right, this may be the best comic Jeff Lemire's done ever.
Rym: I was gonna say, Jeff Lemire, so how would you rate it on the scale of Silver Surfer to Saga?
Scott: It's not as good as Saga.
Rym: I thought you were gonna say it's not as good as Silver Surfer.
Scott: And I like Silver Surfer a lot, but it's better than that, so, you know.
Scott: Alright.
Scott: But yeah, if you're reading comics, and you're already reading Saga, you gotta read fucking Trillium.
Scott: I mean, seriously, come on, this is probably, it's probably the second best comic made right now.
Scott: that's coming out in stores today.
Rym: Alright.
Scott: So, there you go.
Scott: And it's, yeah, the one half was sci-fi, and the other half was like Indiana Jones type shit.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day!
Rym: I'm gonna cop out, we're finally doing the Attack on Titan, I'm gonna get a bunch of the best Attack on Titan mashups out of my system and never talk about it again.
Scott: Alright, Muffy, or Miffy, is that still the best one?
Rym: I don't know, I mean, I made one with Emmanuel Yarbrough, so I'm linking to that one.
Rym: Great.
Rym: And I guess the ones I like the most are the Adventure Time one, not the one you're thinking of.
Scott: I like the one that uses children's programming.
Rym: Yeah, I like the Adventure Time one, I like the Pingu one a lot.
Scott: Pingu one is like number two.
Rym: Yeah, and the one that I'm making privately, this, I'm gonna find out if our friend Scott Johnson listens to the show, because I have this video of him playing DDR with other Scott in our apartment, and none of us had shirts on, and I'm gonna mash that up with the Attack on Titan opening.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: So, my thing of the day, in Japan, at the offices of, I believe, Shogakukan, which is probably the biggest manga company publisher after Shueisha, which is the jump company, Shogakukan is number two.
Scott: They got friggin, you know, 20th Century Boys and all these other, you know, Urasawa works there, all kinds of great comics come out of there.
Scott: And they have an office.
Scott: that is mega old office.
Scott: The office is like, I think it's in Osaka, like near where, you know, Tezuka and all those people, like, you know, originally did comics way back in the day.
Scott: So, this is like the historic manga office, but it was just too small.
Scott: So, they had to get a newer, better, more modern office, and the old office is getting knocked the fuck down.
Scott: So, what they did, after they cleared it out, they got all the manga people to come to the office, and they all came, and they drew mangas all over the walls, and then they sold tickets to let people come and look at it, and then they knocked it down, and then they moved to their new office.
Scott: So, here is all the pictures and video and whatnot of all the awesome stuff, all the best mangas in Japan drew on the walls, in their office, before losing it.
Scott: Oh my God.
Scott: If you care anything about manga, this is super awesome and important.
Rym: So, the Book Club book is Stazzyland.
Rym: We are on our way to PAX, or at PAX, by the time you listen to this.
Rym: We're presenting bad games in the Wolfman Theater at noon on Monday.
Rym: Might not be a show or two.
Rym: We'll see if we could do shows after PAX, because we might be tired from four days of PAX, and the PAX charity event that's not PAX sanctioned.
Scott: Yeah, the pre, and also there's a pre-Pax day and a post-Pax day.
Rym: The pre-Pax sky-high tabletop play benefiting Food Lifeline, where we will be VIPs running games with people, playing games with people, eating food with people.
Rym: Good times.
Rym: We got a fuck-ton of videos from conventions up on the internet.
Rym: Scott just put out a new episode of the newsletter.
Rym: I was waiting for you to say something about the episode.
Rym: Our newsletter is pretty boss, and people seem to really like it, so if you're not subscribed to it, better get subscribed, and maybe you can trade people to get them to forward you previous newsletters.
Scott: Something like that.
Rym: 'Cause if we get a lot of requests from people who subscribe, and they're like, "Hey, how can I get the old
Rym: ones?".
Rym: It's like, "Yeah, you should subscribe
Rym: sooner.".
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: We're not gonna make an RSS feed of this shit, otherwise you won't subscribe.
Scott: That's a shame.
Scott: Gotta remind people once in a while, we exist in their email box, where they actually look.
Scott: A place they actually look if they don't check our forums or don't use Twitter and don't use Facebook.
Scott: People check their email at least once a day, hopefully, if they're not that disconnected.
Scott: So we can get into their new email box once every once in a while to remind them that we exist.
Scott: That should help, right?
Rym: Also, gonna give you guys a heads up on MAGFest.
Rym: It's a ways out, you know, New Year's, but the hotel at the con, I hear, is already like 80% sold out.
Scott: Which is much better than other conventions that fill up instantly.
Rym: Yup, like PAX.
Scott: But that doesn't mean you shouldn't go and get a hotel room right the fuck now.
Scott: Why don't you have one already?
Rym: You should be at MAGFest.
Scott: Why aren't you already at MAGFest being like, if you're sitting there going like, "Yeah, I already got my room and ticket for MAGFest, and the transportation,
Scott: uhh."
Scott: Then, you're the smart person.
Scott: If that's not you, what the fuck is wrong with you?
Rym: Yeah, MAGFest, look, we like PAX a lot, if you couldn't tell.
Rym: We like MAGFest almost as much.
Rym: For very different reasons.
Scott: Uhh, not yet.
Rym: It's too soon, too soon.
Rym: MAGFest is the one con, if you want to just hang out with us and play games at four in the morning, we're actually just hanging out playing games at four in the morning.
Scott: That's all you do at MAGFest, it's always four in the morning.
Scott: You're always hanging out, you're always playing games, except for the Machine Supremacy concert.
Scott: Yes, Machine Supremacy's first appearance.
Scott: First time in US ever.
Scott: I've waited over a decade, and now I am rewarded.
Rym: This is one of those things where every year I tell everyone I know who works for the Penny Arcade Expo, I'm like, "Yeah, get Machine Supremacy.
Scott: Come on, just get him, please, get him, just get him, get
Scott: him.".
Rym: But MAGFest did it.
Rym: MAGFest got him.
Scott: That's how badass MAGFest is, they got what PAX could not or would not get.
Rym: [laughs].
Rym: So, I feel like this is the hot show that we should talk about, and for all of you who complain that we don't talk about anime that's on right now, one, we're actually watching a shit ton of anime, didn't we just review Shinseki Yori not that long ago?
Scott: - I didn't watch that.
Rym: - Two, I did, and we reviewed it.
Rym: Well, I reviewed it with Emily.
Rym: But Attack on Titan, Shingeki no Kyojin.
Scott: Just as with Ponies, and with Madoka, people talked about it so goddamn much, they talked about it way more than everything else.
Rym: Emily and I started watching it before you did.
Scott: Yeah, but people talked about it so the fuck much, that it's like, "Well, I guess I have to at least take a look at that, 'cause no one will shut up about
Scott: it.".
Scott: They're not shuttin' up about it ten times more than usual.
Rym: Shut up, shuttin' up.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: So, after I got, you know, I had some free time, enough free time to read comics, so I had free time enough to watch anime, so I went out and I watched the Attack on Titans.
Scott: Actually, I got five volumes of the manga, and then watched the anime.
Scott: Yup, now Scott started reading the manga.
Scott: I've seen 20 anime episodes, which I think is all of them.
Scott: Yeah, 'cause once in my life.
Scott: And I've read five volume mangas, which is all of them that are in English, that you can buy, but you can read more if you scan.
Rym: Now, Scott started reading the manga, and I was like, "Just watch the show, the show is way
Rym: better.".
Rym: 'Cause I'd flipped through the manga and it was kinda meh.
Rym: The show, it's kinda like Death Note.
Rym: Death Note, as a comic, is great, but the anime is just the comic plus music, so you might as well just read the comic.
Scott: Uh, okay.
Rym: But, No Dame Cantabile is a comic about music.
Rym: Reading the comic is not as good as watching the anime, 'cause in the anime you actually get to hear it.
Scott: Yeah, same thing with, like, Beck, or Digital D.
Rym: There are often anime and manga pairs where they are the exact same plot.
Rym: Sometimes you wanna watch or read one of them over the other one, because there's a reason to.
Scott: Sometimes you wanna mix it up.
Scott: I watched Hajime no Ippo, and then when there was no more anime left, even though more is coming out this season, I switched over to the manga.
Rym: Yep, Monster, just because of who made it, and because of what it is, I prefer the comic, and I read the comic.
Rym: The show seems okay, but the comic, I burned through it so fast, because I really needed to know what it was about.
Scott: Yeah, well, I mean, it's a weird thing, 'cause usually when you talk about adaptations, it's like, "Man, they really fucked up that Hobbit movie," right?
Scott: And certain characters change, right?
Scott: But with the manga anime, usually the adaptations, they're not always 100% faithful, but they're super faithful, so the question is, like, "Well, what do you do?
Scott: One, both?
Scott: The other?
Scott: I don't
Scott: know.".
Rym: Well, look at the Fullmetal Alchemist situation.
Rym: We have a show following a manga, but then the show diverges from the manga, because it's coming out faster than the manga.
Scott: Anyway, so, that's a done manga, but I have all the volumes.
Scott: I haven't read that.
Rym: But I bring up Fullmetal Alchemist for one reason.
Rym: We're gonna talk a lot about Attack on Titan, we'll avoid spoilers, we might spoil some stuff in the very end of the show, we'll warn you, no spoilers yet, but it's really good, I really, really like it, but I'm gonna warn you right now.
Rym: This is the Fullmetal Alchemist of this season.
Scott: It is.
Scott: I've been thinking the same thing.
Rym: The Fushigi Yugi of this season.
Rym: It is great.
Rym: I love every goddamn second of it.
Rym: Every episode ends with me going, "Fuck," and waiting seven days to see the next episode, only to go, "Fuck," again.
Scott: Even though it's kind of predictable, I know what's gonna happen.
Scott: Yeah, but even then, I predict things, but-- Everything I predicted isn't right so far.
Rym: Yeah, but they're always crook slightly so.
Rym: Like, I expected the plan for most of these episode to not work out.
Scott: I don't know how the actual, how things are gonna play out.
Scott: I just know what the facts are of certain things.
Rym: Well, I knew this plan was gonna fail, because the preview of the previous episode.
Rym: You can tell when a show is like this when I watch the previews built into the show, 'cause usually, I have a policy of not watching them.
Rym: All my whole anime life, I have not watched the previews.
Scott: I watch them sometimes.
Rym: You know when I watch previews?
Rym: The second time I watch a show.
Scott: Initial D. Don't miss it.
Rym: But seriously, the reason this show is a Fullmetal Alchemist is because Fullmetal Alchemist, Fushigi Yugi, Attack on Titan have a very common set of traits.
Rym: One, the plot is really interesting, to the point that I have a strong desire to find out all the proper nouns and verbs.
Rym: I wanna know what the fucking titans are.
Rym: I wanna know what alchemy is.
Rym: I wanna know if Mikasa will ever shut the fuck up.
Rym: Time of hope.
Rym: But, Miyaka.
Rym: But two, I don't have any desire to re-watch the show.
Scott: No, it's like Attack on Titan.
Scott: It's like, I read the volume, it's like, done, right?
Scott: And that's how I can sorta get a tell feeling that, yeah, Attack on Titan, once it's over, and there's no more new animes and no more new mangas, I think it might fade away.
Rym: - It will.
Scott: - Not to say that it's bad.
Scott: Fullmetal Alchemist isn't bad.
Scott: - And you still see Fullmetal Alchemist cosplays.
Scott: - Okay, yeah.
Scott: Just not nearly as many.
Rym: - Yes, Fushigi Yugi is pretty much gone at this point.
Scott: - Not like Monika, which, it's like, I watched it, and then I just watched it fucking again.
Scott: Watched it again, again.
Rym: - And not even that, while we were still watching it, or right after we'd just watched it, we'd meet someone and we're like, oh, you haven't seen Madoka yet?
Scott: Here.
Scott: - Let's watch it the hell again.
Rym: - Let's watch the first three episodes right now.
Rym: I do that with Giant Robo.
Rym: I'll do that with Escaflowne.
Rym: I have not done that with Attack on Titan.
Rym: When I meet someone who hasn't seen it, who should.
Scott: - Just like, yeah, go see it.
Rym: - You know what, yeah, I say, oh, go watch it and tell me when you've caught up, and then we'll talk about it.
Rym: I have no desire to watch any episode of it again.
Rym: I might watch an individual scene again, because the scenes are really well animated and really well done, but.
Scott: - I watched the opener, 'cause that music, the first opener.
Rym: - Yeah, you know what that song is?
Rym: - Second opener's.
Scott: not bad, but first opener.
Rym: - Most people, because that opener.
Scott: - There's a reason everyone's remixing that shit.
Rym: - Yes, that's the song you listen to on a loop while you're taking the test, or driving to the con.
Rym: (humming) Yeah, most people know that song in their head as mumble a mumble, a mumble a yagger.
Scott: - That's pretty much it.
Rym: ♪ Ah, ah, ah, ah ♪.
Rym: - I do like the second opener a lot.
Scott: - It's good, I like the second opener.
Scott: - But notice again.
Scott: - It's not, it doesn't live up to the second opener, first opener.
Rym: - It's just the same with Full Metal Alchemist.
Rym: The opener kept changing as the show progressed.
Scott: - Yeah, but the second one was better.
Rym: - Gundam C, the opener kept changing as the show progressed.
Scott: - The first one was the best.
Scott: - But-- - Utenna?
Rym: - Yeah, well, Utenna only changes twice, once.
Scott: - Oh, that's the closer.
Rym: - Yeah, the closer and opener change.
Rym: Sailor Moon changes every season, but with this one, when the opener changes, it's because the show goes to a very different place, and different characters matter a lot.
Scott: - I do wanna say the only other openers that I can think of that have the same power, not in terms of just raw quality, right?
Scott: But in terms of-- - All right, power.
Rym: We're just talking power.
Scott: - In terms of powerful openings, right?
Scott: It's like, Big O.
Rym: - Not Initial D.
Rym: 'Cause Initial D is only powerful for us.
Scott: - No, Initial D is not powerful.
Rym: - It's powerful for us, not for normal people.
Scott: - Obviously Attack on Titan, Big O, Evangelion.
Rym: - Yup.
Rym: Fadin' fast.
Rym: - Yeah.
Rym: - Madoka, no.
Rym: - No, not powerful at all.
Rym: - Madoka's the on purpose, not powerful.
Scott: - Talking about openers that punch you in the face, like, mm, I'm opening this anime.
Scott: Here comes anime.
Rym: - Doom, the game.
Scott: - Yeah.
Rym: - The opening music to the first level.
Rym: Oh, man.
Scott: - Anyway, there's not that many, and this is up there.
Rym: - If you have not watched Attack on Titan, here's how I'll sell it to you.
Rym: Attack on Titan is about a world where there are humans, and they recuse themselves behind gigantic walls that they would be hard pressed to build these walls again today.
Scott: - Right, like someone just, you know, I knew that there was behind this thing with walls and giants and whatnot, but I didn't realize until I watched the show just how big the walls are, right?
Scott: It's like, you think the walls are Gundam size?
Scott: It's like, no, they're Eva-sized walls.
Rym: - Yeah, Avas would have a hard time knocking these walls down.
Scott: - I think an Eva could step over the wall.
Rym: - It would have to vault over the wall.
Scott: - It could do it.
Scott: - It could vault over the wall.
Scott: - The Avas are bigger than Colossal Titan.
Scott: We need to, actually, I think we need to make a JPEG showing Eva versus Colossal Titan size.
Rym: - Without weapons, just an Eva, an Eva would be hard pressed to knock the wall down.
Scott: - An Eva would just punch it down.
Rym: - It would take it a while to punch it down.
Scott: - Maybe.
Rym: - The wall is pretty fucking big.
Scott: - It is, it's made of rock, though.
Scott: Anyway, but yeah, the walls are gigantic, and the thing about the walls that's not gigantic is the height, it's really the length, right?
Scott: It's the circumference of the Wall.
Scott: Maria, the outer wall, is so gigantic that there's multiple towns and cities.
Scott: It's basically almost the size of a country, a small country.
Scott: I don't know, it's not as big as, say, Luxembourg inside of it, but it's big.
Rym: - Well, here's the thing.
Scott: - There's a lot of land in there.
Rym: - There are these concentric sets of walls that are huge that have been around for as long as humanity has historical records available to the general public.
Scott: - Which is really only a few hundred years.
Scott: - Yes.
Scott: - It's not long, they have a short memory.
Rym: - As far back as history goes, these walls have been there, and outside of these walls are gigantic, naked fanboys that eat people.
Rym: - Yep.
Rym: - That's the world, that's the plot.
Scott: - Most of the world, you don't even know if this is like an Earth, I mean, it looks like an Earth, it's got forests and trees.
Rym: - I am done comparing shit to Earth.
Rym: People always ask, oh, is it set in a post-apocalyptic Earth or pre-Earth, it doesn't matter.
Rym: The reason stories are set on things like Earth is because that's where we're set.
Scott: - Right, it's some kind of, it's an Earth-like--.
Scott: - It is clearly our Earth or not.
Scott: - No, it doesn't, but it's an Earth-like planet, right, in terms of it has forests and trees and whatnot.
Rym: - Which, again, like Fullmetal Alchemist, it's an Earth-like planet, and that's it.
Scott: - Yeah, grass, right, but humans supposedly don't know what's far away outside the walls.
Scott: They've only been outside the walls like 50 times ever.
Scott: - Yes.
Rym: In fact, the people that--.
Scott: - And usually, most of the people who go out come back dead or always.
Rym: - Now, that's the world of the show.
Rym: There are these gigantic, horrifyingly disturbing giants that eat people.
Scott: - And they're super, you basically can't beat them.
Scott: They're super dangerous.
Rym: - They're mindless and scary.
Rym: Like when humans tangle with Titans.
Scott: - It's like fast zombies.
Scott: - Yes.
Scott: - You can't, you know what you can do.
Rym: - But it's not just fast zombies.
Rym: Imagine fast zombies--.
Rym: - Fast giant zombies.
Rym: - That are 30, 40 meters tall.
Scott: - Well, there's some that are only five meters tall, which is still gigantic, right?
Scott: That's like, you know--.
Rym: - You realize my new joke, to this day, my new joke, at every con when a fanboy is approaching us at a table is going to be two-meter Titan incoming.
Scott: - Yeah, right?
Rym: - Two-meter class.
Scott: - Now, think about this, right?
Scott: Shaq is huge, right?
Scott: If you see Shaq coming, you're like, "Oh, fuck me," right?
Scott: That guy's huge.
Scott: The smallest Titan is like two Shaqs tall.
Scott: It's like, just kill yourself, right?
Scott: You're not gonna beat him, especially at basketball.
Rym: - Yep, but the Titans are huge and unbeatable, and the plot of the show begins right away.
Rym: You've got a bunch of characters doing their stuff.
Scott: - They're not unbeatable individually, but they're unbeatable collectively.
Scott: - There's a military-- - There's so many of them, they can't beat him.
Rym: - And there's a military, and they do the expeditions, people die, but basically the world is pretty stable.
Rym: Titans have not been a serious threat inside of the walls for over a hundred years.
Scott: - Yep, basically the wall is big enough that even the biggest Titans can't get through it, so the humans live happily inside the walls, and just defend just in case, looking out over the walls to make sure Titans don't get in.
Rym: - And then one day, a gigantic fucking Titan bigger than anyone has ever seen just appears and fucking kicks one of the walls down.
Scott: - What the fuck?
Rym: - Oh, shit.
Scott: - Oh, shit, it's on.
Rym: - And I can't spoil anything else, because this is a show like Fullmetal Alchemist where a lot of the enjoyment of watching the show is the, "Oh, fuck, did that just
Rym: happen?".
Rym: - So don't read ahead in spoilers and crap.
Scott: - It doesn't matter, because the thing is, a lot of the stuff is just so plainly obvious that even if you don't, for example, right, there's a, in addition to the colossal Titan, there's another Titan called the armored Titan, and you look at him and he has this hair.
Scott: - And then later-- - And then there's another character who has the same exact goddamn hair.
Scott: Now it's like, have I actually seen anything in the manga or anime that 100% verifies that that character and that Titan are related?
Scott: No, but you know what?
Scott: I will bet my entire wallet, which actually has a lot of money in it right now, that that guy is that Titan.
Scott: They have the same goddamn hair.
Scott: They're just giving it away.
Scott: It's a freebie, right?
Scott: And there's another one just like that, two characters that look exact.
Scott: It's like there's so many things just given away, but there are also things that are not given away, like the colossal Titan itself.
Scott: There isn't a character that looks like that.
Scott: I'm guessing.
Rym: - It's King Bradley.
Scott: - It's gotta be King Bradley.
Scott: It's like the Akio, right?
Scott: A character revealed later, or it could be, it can't be, I thought it was Pyxis.
Scott: 'cause he was bald, and the colossal Titan is also bald, but there's a scene where the colossal--.
Rym: - Ah, forget that.
Rym: Pyxis is just too cool.
Scott: - Pyxis is too cool, but they showed the colossal Titan attacking while Pyxis is simultaneously playing chess with some noble.
Rym: - Pyxis is one of my favorite minor characters.
Rym: He's that badass in the background that we love so much.
Scott: Another thing about this show is it sorta has these arcs in a sense, right?
Scott: That's why the opener changed, and the manga's the same way, where the beginning of the show is sorta like the intro, and then there's a whole sequence of the training, and it's sorta like the main characters are in the military, training, and then eventually joining the actual military.
Scott: So the whole first part of the show, while things go down, is the training.
Scott: Then once they join the military, the opener changes, the characters change, all the characters that are in the town are left behind, and now we're focusing on the outside.
Scott: The only characters that stick with you are the few central ones that were in the training that are now trained, and all these secondary characters swap out, and they're not dead, most of them anyway, right?
Scott: Well, some of them.
Scott: People dying all over the place, and there's giants eating everybody, right?
Scott: But the main characters basically move from one group of friends to another.
Scott: It's sorta like graduating from high school to college.
Rym: - But that's the interesting thing about the show.
Rym: It moves quickly like this, and the characters we're focusing on, it jumps around a lot, and it's perfectly willing to leave major characters by the wayside for a long time.
Scott: - Right, and also kill people.
Scott: - Yes.
Scott: - It makes, though, they achieve the goal of making the world super dangerous by fuckin' killin' people off, L-O-G-H style, give 'em a name, now they're dead.
Scott: - Yep, but the thing is, they won't kill everybody.
Scott: - And at the same time, it also achieves the Urasawa thing of introduce a new character, make you care about them right away, as opposed to, "Oh, these new characters, "I don't care about
Scott: them.".
Scott: Yes, you do.
Rym: - The show just does a really good job of driving home the point that a lot of people are dying, and that every one of these people is just as cool as the main characters, and it's--.
Scott: - And even the most badass people are all fuckin' scared to shit of titans.
Rym: - And a lot of the badass people also just fuckin' die.
Rym: - Yep.
Rym: - Out of nowhere.
Scott: - Super badasses who seemed invincible.
Rym: - Characters that you would be like if you were watching "Utena," and Mickey just dies in a duel.
Scott: - Yep, well, the thing about it, there's that guy who's got the gray hair, who has such a high titan kill count, but he's super annoying.
Scott: I'm so sure that guy's gonna die.
Rym: - No, I don't think he's gonna die.
Scott: - He's gonna get killed, so--.
Rym: - I think characters I care more about are gonna die.
Scott: - That guy is the perfect guy to get killed.
Rym: - Nah.
Scott: - Also the girl he's always arguing with.
Rym: - My favorite character in the show is the scientist girl who studies the titans.
Scott: - I don't know if she'll die.
Rym: - No, I'm saying she's my favorite character.
Rym: 'Cause she's just kinda like the Fluttershy-looking girl in "Little Witch
Rym: Academia.".
Rym: She's creepy, and there's a great scene where she's like, you wanna hear about my experiments on titans?
Rym: Let me tell you about them.
Rym: And then all these badasses who have seen bloodshed and death for much of their lives are like, I'm gonna be ill, I'm gonna leave the room.
Scott: - I think my, I don't know what my favorite character is, but Levi is basically, he is the King Cosma of "Attack on
Scott: Titan.".
Rym: - Well, there's a scene where he beats the main character up, and it's one of those scenes where it's not necessarily particularly especially violent, especially in a show where people are getting crushed and eaten and bitten left and right.
Rym: But then this one scene where a human just physically punches up another human is so brutal to watch.
Scott: - Yep.
Rym: - It's almost hard to watch.
Scott: - I think my favorite character, as usual, are like the secret characters, right?
Scott: There was a trial in the show, and the guy who comes to basically be the judge of the trial 'cause it was a military trial, was the head of the entire military, all three branches.
Rym: - That's either gonna be a super--.
Scott: - That guy's one step away from the king, and he was super just and awesome, so that guy is like-- -.
Rym: That either means-- - That's the kinda guy like-- - He's a King Bradley, or he's a good guy.
Scott: - He could be a good guy, but basically he's one step away from the king.
Scott: He's the head of the whole military, the five-star general, the chief of the joint chief, the secretary of defense.
Scott: He's the number one guy.
Rym: - I really like Erwin, but I'm pretty sure he's gonna die at some point.
Scott: - I don't know, Erwin's cool, but Erwin's also got a lot of mystery.
Rym: - The show also gets points when you learn about character backstories that the backstories are not what you would expect.
Scott: - Nope.
Rym: - Characters have pretty rough paths, and a lot of this is really just shown to you along the way like, oh, that guy, yeah, his family was sent off to die outside the walls because there wasn't enough food.
Rym: We get that in a flashback.
Scott: - I also like how the focus moves around a lot.
Scott: Like Mikasa is a major character overall, but in the more recent episodes, basically you hardly see her at all.
Scott: - Yeah, it's all about Erwin and Eren.
Scott: - Yeah, there's almost no focus on her right now 'cause she's not important right now, but I'm sure she's gonna get back into it in the next episode.
Scott: because they showed, she got like one scene of like, oh, Eren must be that way, I'm going.
Scott: So she's heading into the fray.
Rym: - She's also the last Asian.
Scott: - That's true.
Scott: All right, but yeah, there's a reason, you know, everyone's talking about this show because of the hot show right now.
Scott: Will it have long staying power?
Rym: - Definitely not.
Scott: - Probably not, most likely, but, you know, Fullmetal Alchemist, if you haven't seen it, is still worth watching now, but it's just, you know, it's just not as great as, you know, anything else.
Scott: So Attack on Titan's the kind of thing you watch once and that's it.
Rym: - Perennially, there are these blockbuster anime that everyone watches together in the anime world.
Rym: They're super good, but they're just not particularly memorable beyond that.
Scott: - This is not gonna be an all time great anime, it's just a good anime that's hot right now.
Rym: - I feel like these shows string you along because you really, really need to know all the proper nouns.
Rym: You really wanna know what the Titans are and where they come from.
Rym: And the show does a good job of teaching you about the Titans as they're--.
Scott: - But like 10 years from now when someone says, "What great anime should I
Scott: watch?"
Scott: No one's gonna say Attack on Titan.
Rym: Unless they're getting into the list of, "Oh, you should watch a
Rym: blog.".
Rym: You know how we do panels, we're like, "Yeah, you should all watch Fushigi Yugi "to know what blockbuster anime were like "in the late 90s, early 2000s in the
Rym: US.".
Scott: - I should just go home and watch Madoka again.
Rym: - Ah, yeah.
Rym: Madoka, Utena, Eva, Escapada.
Scott: - Oh, right, I should watch Utena, we're doing that thing.
Rym: - Yeah, we should do that thing.
Scott: - And I kinda want to real bad.
Rym: - Yeah, but all, you know, with the deaths of characters, like to kind of give you an example of how well the show does the kind of arbitrary and capricious nature of the Titans and death.
Rym: There's one character who's pretty cool and he just kind of disappears at one point in this big sort of action scene going on.
Scott: - Yeah, there's so many characters that when they don't get scenes--.
Scott: - Like you don't notice.
Scott: - You don't notice that they're not, oh, that guy has, I've been paying close attention like who shows up on screen and who doesn't and it's sort of like, I don't want to say this, but it's like a MOBA, like middle is missing, right?
Scott: It's like, oh, I haven't seen so, 'cause everyone's got this, you know, maneuver gear and they're flying all over town and fighting Titans all over the place.
Scott: So people are moving real fast, going everywhere.
Scott: It's like everyone's Spider-Man basically.
Rym: And the animation of the Spider-Manning is great.
Scott: - And people are splitting up and grouping together all the time.
Scott: Splitting up and grouping together like D&D parties.
Scott: So that are all sort of together.
Scott: So it's like, oh, someone, you know, went off.
Scott: I haven't seen that person in like 10 minutes and they're not with the people they were with.
Scott: Where are they?
Scott: - So one super badass character-- - Oh, nope, they just showed up again.
Scott: You know, so it's like, sometimes they're dead.
Scott: Sometimes they show up again and do something awesome.
Rym: - Or, oh, they tried to save somebody and got squished.
Rym: But there's one super badass character who you don't notice for a while.
Rym: And then later you kind of forget about him.
Rym: And then after this battle, they just find his body.
Rym: They don't even know how he died.
Rym: He died alone and anonymous.
Scott: - He wasn't that badass, he was just really nice.
Rym: - He died alone and anonymous and they just found his body.
Rym: No heroic moment, no last words.
Rym: They found his rotting corpse and that's it.
Scott: - Yup.
Rym: And the physiology and the mystery of the titans and how they work and why they eat people and what happens to people they eat is all just--.
Scott: - Terrible Secret of Space.
Scott: - Really interesting.
Scott: - The greatest thing in all of anime, the Terrible Secret of Space.
Rym: - But there's two kinds of Terrible Secret of Space shows.
Rym: This is the show where the Terrible Secret of Space is 80% of why you're watching the show.
Rym: You'll wanna know.
Scott: - Any show that has a Terrible Secret of Space, that's gonna be the reason I'm watching.
Rym: - And the other 20% is just.
Rym: the characters are really good.
Rym: They usually act really smartly or sometimes they fuck up.
Scott: - There's never a case where it's like, oh man, why is someone so stupid?
Scott: Because if they need to make someone do something dumb, they don't have to make the person dumb 'cause the titans are just so dangerous and the people are freaking out.
Scott: 'cause yeah, giant titans just bit your friend's legs off and they're crawling at you.
Scott: So they never have to make someone dumb as an excuse for them to do something.
Scott: that is not the best thing.
Scott: They just make the person emotionally freaking out.
Scott: or yeah, the person was really good and did the smart thing, but it's just not good enough.
Scott: 'cause the titans are that dangerous.
Scott: You never hate on characters for anything like that.
Rym: - Now, it's obvious based on the progression of the manga and the fact that there's a one 26 episode season of this, that season one is going to be like the end of season one of Gundam Sea.
Scott: - And if they don't continue.
Rym: - Or Full Metal Alchemist.
Scott: - Yeah, if they don't continue.
Rym: - I think they will.
Rym: I think the show is really popular.
Scott: - The anime, you're just gonna have to read the manga and the thing with the manga is it will get you all your answers, right?
Scott: And they're gonna actually, in the US, they're gonna start putting out one volume per month and catch the fuck up right away 'cause they realized they're striking the iron while it's hot, but it's just not as good as the anime.
Scott: It's the same story, but the craftsmanship of the manga is flawed.
Scott: There's some bad art and I don't mean bad art like.
Scott: it's a style I don't like 'cause I actually do like the style that is different, but it's like, oh, the anatomy is all fucked in that panel.
Scott: Oh, that person had totally the wrong facial expression in that panel.
Scott: that didn't really make it look like the feeling that they were supposed to be having.
Rym: - Yep, now the anime does a good job.
Scott: - Oh, these panels are in the wrong order.
Rym: Oh, I can't--.
Rym: - The anime does a good job of taking that sort of sunken eye socket, like there's all these weird faces that the characters have.
Rym: The anime does a good job of using that to great effect.
Scott: - But it uses it lightly.
Scott: It's like the anime has more of an, I don't wanna say normal anime style, but a style that has more in common with, say, Full Metal Alchemist kind of style, right?
Scott: But it sort of still applies a light veneer of the manga style instead of going heavy on it.
Scott: And it makes it more, I guess, intelligible to figure out what the hell's going on.
Scott: And also the action sequences are the exact opposite of Akira, which is the best action sequences of any manga ever.
Scott: It's like you can't even tell what the person's doing with the Titan until it's over and you're like, oh, he beat it, oh, he died.
Rym: - I think you were the one who was like, it's kinda like Naito.
Scott: - Yeah, it's a little bit like the Trigun manga.
Scott: It was like you flip through a Trigun manga action scene.
Rym: - It's like you're on one page.
Scott: - You don't know who's shooting who, and at the end it's like, okay, Wolfwood won.
Rym: - Yeah, like you're on a page and something's happening.
Rym: You flip to the next page and you're like, oh, I must have skipped a bunch of pages 'cause the pages were stuck together.
Rym: And you flip back and nope, you didn't skip any pages.
Scott: - Nope.
Rym: - That's just what was on the next page.
Scott: - Yep.
Rym: - The backgrounds in the show and the skies are just ridiculous.
Rym: They remind me of Makoto Shinkai skies.
Rym: I love everything about this show, but I love it in the same way I love Fullmetal Alchemist.
Rym: It was my number one priority in life while FMA was coming out to see new episodes.
Rym: And I have not watched it again and I have no plans to ever watch it again.
Rym: But yeah, we'll do a final thoughts-y show once it's done.
Rym: done because the plot might be dumb.
Rym: We don't know.
Scott: - Yeah, I mean, the terrible secret of space could be a dumb secret of space.
Scott: As soon as a dumb thing is revealed, you're really anxious to learn this horrible secret.
Scott: There's a whole thing about, there's a basement the main character has a key to, and it's like, what's in the basement?
Scott: And I'm sure we'll eventually find out what's in the basement.
Scott: But if something dumb is in the basement-- - It's just his dad's porn collection.
Rym: - Yeah, if there's something-- - Like in Staring Up at the Half Moon.
Scott: - Yeah, if there's something dumb in the basement, that could actually sort of flop the whole show.
Scott: It'd be like, yeah, it's worth watching up until the basement to just stop 'cause then that'll sort of ruin everything else that happened before it.
Scott: It's like, oh, I'm anticipating this present.
Scott: Oh, my anticipation feels so good.
Scott: It feels so good.
Scott: I wanna open the present.
Scott: I'm feeling real good with all this anticipation.
Scott: I'm opening the present.
Scott: I'm feeling really good opening this present 'cause it's so fun, and I'm finally letting my anticipation go.
Scott: I've gotten some hype, and then I open it, and it's like some fucking underwear.
Scott: And now all that was ruined.
Scott: I had good feelings, but now I have shit feelings, and that sort of ruins those good feelings even though I already had them.
Scott: So you should not open the present.
Rym: - At the same time, the show could escalate into Ava territory.
Rym: if the Secret of Space is so transcendently good.
Scott: - It's not gonna happen.
Rym: - No, but there's a chance.
Scott: It's not possible.
Rym: - There's a chance.
Scott: - Impossible.
Scott: - There's always a chance.
Rym: - So yeah, watch your Attack on Titan.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: - Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: - Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: - GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.