Rym: It's Thursday, October 3rd, 2013.
Rym: I'm Riff, I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights.
Scott: No it's not.
Scott: Tonight we're shut down.
Scott: Shut down the GeekNights.
Scott: Going to get dinner.
Rym: I'm just surprised that Scott actually wants to talk about something even remotely related to politics.
Scott: I don't.
Scott: I'm just indulging you and then I expect next week, well two weeks from now, to be indulged.
Rym: No, uh oh.
Rym: What could you possibly want me to talk about?
Scott: I don't know, I'm thinking about it.
Rym: That I wouldn't want to talk about.
Scott: If I had something, we would already be doing that as the episode.
Rym: See, that's the trouble with this tit for tat.
Rym: If you help me out first, I am under no obligation.
Rym: Unless you shut GeekNights down.
Scott: I can shut it down.
Rym: Anyway, so as you guys know I was in Istanbul again and I noticed something about traveling to a place like that and working multiple times in a row.
Rym: is that there's sort of, like the first time I went everything was new and strange and I spent a lot of my time learning and going to a neighborhood and trying to explore it.
Rym: Like the first time I rode the subway, I walked down into the subway and I looked at the map and then I looked at the token machine and then I tried to figure everything out and like really understand what I was doing.
Rym: And the second time I went to Istanbul, I had a sort of false sense of knowledge.
Rym: That oh, I've been here before, I know how shit goes down and I stayed in the same neighborhood.
Rym: so I knew that neighborhood really well.
Rym: and as a result, I got lost every time I left that neighborhood because I thought I knew where I was going better than I did.
Rym: But then now that I've been there several times, I actually got my way around Istanbul.
Rym: Like I rode the subway every day to work commuting.
Rym: I lived in like a little neighborhood more downtown near normal people.
Rym: Like I lived in the Long Island City instead of the last few times when I lived in the equivalent of like Forest Hills.
Scott: Why don't you just live in the Ritz-Carlton?
Rym: I'm not going to waste that much of my company's money just yet.
Scott: The company who gives a shit?
Rym: Because I kind of have a vested interest in the company and that money.
Rym: That money is kind of my money too.
Scott: Yeah, I want to set a good impression.
Scott: Make it look like, you know, that's why, you know, financial people always drive fancy cars.
Rym: Yeah, yeah.
Rym: So you know what?
Rym: Here's an aside.
Rym: I realized, one, one of the meetings I got, the people there knew GeekNights.
Scott: What?
Rym: They saw it on my LinkedIn profile and they brought it up because they listened to it.
Rym: And these guys were super cool and super nerdy and everything about them was awesome.
Rym: But basically, the impression I'm getting, the more I do the work that I do, is that every other company that does financially stock market stuff, they have salespeople who only do sales.
Rym: Their job is I am sales guy.
Rym: I sell you thing.
Scott: That's, yep.
Scott: You mean every company ever?
Rym: Yeah, so that doesn't work in a technical field so much.
Rym: Or when it does work, it doesn't actually end well.
Scott: Well, it doesn't work if you're trying to sell to nerdy people.
Scott: The thing is usually, you know, take for example, you know, a normal work, right?
Scott: People who are not technical often get an opportunity to make a technical purchasing decision.
Scott: For example, who decides whether to use Salesforce or some open source.
Rym: Ah, now in both companies I've worked at, me.
Scott: Yeah, but at most companies it would be the head of sales guy.
Scott: So, right?
Scott: It wouldn't be the CTO deciding which thing to use.
Scott: It would be the guy who's actually going to end up using that software.
Scott: Who decides what to use for the HR management thing that everyone logs into to, you know, log their time off hours.
Scott: The HR person would decide that and that salesperson has to sell the HR person.
Scott: The salespeople, their job, what they do works on those sorts of people.
Scott: It doesn't work on CTOs.
Scott: So, if you need to sell somebody, say, I don't know, like Barracuda network sells their stupid, you know, useless routers spam filter things that suck ass.
Scott: That you need a person who can sell something to a CTO unless you're trying to sell to a company that doesn't even have a CTO, which is a lot of companies.
Scott: They don't have any tech people in house whatsoever and they just buy things that do stuff automatically and will like outsource and like the vendor will set it up.
Scott: Sort of like when you pay someone to set up the copy machine in the office.
Scott: You don't have anyone in the office who can service it.
Rym: So what I'm noticing is that in the circles I'm in, the financials, there's a lot of younger people who are getting into these positions and they're all technical but ended up doing less technical jobs.
Rym: Or the tech people are getting to make the decisions because the tech people are increasingly invaluable.
Rym: I've seen companies where the one guy who knows about like the kind of fixed stuff that I know leaves and then the company's fucked because literally no one else knows how it works.
Rym: So increasingly I'm succeeding at sales because I show up with like a sales guy, like me and the chairman or something.
Rym: show up to a company and we talk to them and we're both also technical.
Rym: So when the guy asks the question like, yeah, so could we just like integrate that to our JMS whatever?
Rym: We're like, yeah.
Rym: And we start talking about the APIs.
Rym: No one else does that.
Scott: Of course not.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So it's kind of cool that I get to do that and it's all working out.
Rym: But anyway, I digress.
Rym: Istanbul was awesome, but long flights.
Rym: I flew Turkish Air, which has...
Scott: Is that all luxury?
Scott: First class?
Rym: No, coach.
Rym: So I'm going to tell you all a secret.
Rym: If you eat food on an airplane and it's shitty, which is all the time...
Scott: You know, that flight, food on the Qantas was better than I expected.
Scott: It was okay, but it was good.
Scott: I looked forward to it because I was hungry.
Rym: Oh my God.
Rym: I was so hungry.
Rym: We got to fucking L.A.
Rym: and we didn't have enough time to do anything before we got to the next flight.
Rym: I was so hungry.
Rym: But like I was waiting, like when I saw the food trucks coming out, I was like, ah, ah, ah.
Rym: I just walked over like taking one.
Rym: But Turkish Airlines in coach has better food than I buy for lunch on an average day in New York.
Scott: There you go.
Scott: Is it Turkish food?
Rym: Sort of.
Rym: Some of it.
Scott: What did you eat?
Rym: A bunch of different meals.
Scott: What were they?
Rym: So one of them was just this pasta thing that I got.
Rym: One of them was...
Scott: I'm hungry right now.
Scott: This is not good.
Rym: This isn't a good conversation you had.
Rym: One of them was this sort of like artichoke thing as one dish.
Rym: And that like artichoke marinated in olive oil.
Rym: Oh my God, it was so good.
Rym: And then this other piece was like a salad.
Rym: It was a good salad with feta cheese and stuff on it.
Rym: The main dish was like this chicken thing and this beef thing.
Scott: Who's the chef for Turkish Air?
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: You can look that shit up.
Rym: But what I'm saying is that the coach food, the cheapest seat food on Turkish Airlines is better than the business class food on any U.S.
Rym: domestic airline.
Rym: And the comfort class and business class food on Turkish Air...
Scott: Must have been like...
Rym: We're talking salt and fat level of quality.
Rym: Like, good God.
Rym: So seriously, United,
Rym: U.S.,
Rym: what the fuck?
Rym: How can you fuck up pasta so bad if Turkish Airlines in coach...
Scott: Because good pasta costs more money and they're already not profitable.
Rym: Maybe we should stop subsidizing these assholes anyway.
Scott: Yeah, that's a good question, right?
Scott: It's like we subsidize all our stupid airlines and they suck, right?
Scott: Does Turkey subsidize Turkish Air?
Scott: Because the U.S.
Scott: doesn't subsidize Turkish Air, does it?
Scott: Right?
Scott: I'm pretty sure it doesn't.
Scott: So is it profitable, Turkish Air?
Scott: You know, how about Lufthansa?
Scott: Do they subsidize Lufthansa?
Rym: So another thing I learned, just kind of bear in mind, if you ever think that you're going to do a transfer at Heathrow, don't fucking do it.
Rym: Don't do it.
Rym: I landed at Terminal 5 and was transferring to a flight leaving from Terminal 5.
Rym: You have to go through security for that to happen.
Scott: Of course.
Rym: There were two international flights.
Scott: Lufthansa is about as worse at security than the
Scott: U.S.,
Scott: pretty much.
Rym: The security was pretty bad in Heathrow.
Rym: And then later, this really nice British lady came down and sat next to me and she was like, "Can I interview you about your experiences in our
Rym: airport?".
Rym: And I was like, "Are you sure?
Rym: Are you sure you want to sit down next to me?
Rym: How long will this
Rym: take?".
Rym: And she was like, "I don't know, about a half
Rym: hour.".
Rym: And I was like, "All
Rym: right.".
Rym: And she seemed kind of taken aback that I said yes.
Rym: And yeah, I...
Scott: Where was she from?
Rym: She worked there.
Rym: She lives in Albion, I guess.
Scott: Oh, but she worked for the airport?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Oh, she didn't work for the Guardian or something?
Rym: No, she worked for the airport.
Scott: Yeah, and you were like, "Your airport is
Scott: awful.".
Rym: No, I was like, "Everything about your airport is great, except your security is ridiculous
Rym: theater.".
Rym: Also, I missed my flight and I was stuck here for seven fucking hours.
Rym: And all you gave me was a 20-pound voucher.
Rym: But let me tell you, I drank a whole lot of beer.
Scott: For 20 pounds?
Rym: I drank 20 pounds worth of beer and then got on another flight.
Scott: Couldn't one beer in an airport be like five pounds at least?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Oh, pounds are worth a lot, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: They don't suck.
Rym: Also, it's Britain, beer is kind of cheap and it was pretty good beer.
Scott: Even in the airport, it's not overpriced?
Scott: No, it really wasn't.
Scott: Why didn't you take the 20 pounds to the duty-free?
Rym: I really just didn't want to.
Rym: I think dirty-free is a ridiculous scam/joke.
Scott: Sure, but it's, you know, you just got free money and pounds are worth a lot, so you could have gotten something good.
Rym: Yeah, I spent that free money drinking beer and hanging out for an entire day.
Scott: You could have gotten something better, like free electronics.
Rym: And playing FTL on my laptop.
Scott: Just FTL?
Rym: And SIP-5, because I happened to have a charger with me that worked because I was on my way to Turkey.
Rym: All right.
Rym: But I watched three movies on the way back.
Scott: Daddy three movies.
Rym: Because the screens on Turkish air are HD.
Scott: Beautiful, okay.
Rym: It was great.
Rym: It was amazing, not like those JetBlue things.
Scott: What kind of airplane was this, 787?
Rym: I don't remember.
Rym: Every time I've flown, it's been a different type of plane.
Rym: Anyway, the three movies I watch.
Scott: I always know what kind of plane I'm on.
Rym: That I would like to Geek Bite for you are No Country for Old Men.
Scott: Seen it.
Rym: The Last Castle.
Scott: Never even heard of it.
Scott: And Phone Booth.
Scott: That sounds something like we would find a video barn.
Rym: So, No Country for Old Men, a ridiculously good movie that I hadn't watched for no goddamn good reason, was a ridiculously good movie.
Scott: I wouldn't say it's ridiculously good.
Scott: I think it's one of those movies where I didn't win a bunch of Oscars and everyone thinks it's the greatest thing ever.
Rym: When I say ridiculously good, compare it to the average movie.
Scott: It's a really good movie, but it's one of those ones where people act like it's fucking the best movie when it's only a really good movie.
Rym: I put it on the level of Fight Club.
Scott: Yeah, it's about the same level as that.
Scott: I think this is happening more.
Rym: If you like this movie, you might also like Fight Club, Chinatown, Memento.
Scott: About the same.
Rym: L.A.
Rym: Confidential.
Scott: Memento's another one I think is even more overrated.
Rym: I think L.A.
Rym: Confidential might be a little bit better, just because it came out earlier.
Scott: It's very hush-hush.
Rym: I should read that book.
Rym: Oh, Seven?
Rym: I guess.
Scott: Yeah, about the same level as that.
Scott: But I think these movies are getting... When someone makes a really good, decent movie on the level of those movies you just mentioned, nowadays, people act like it's the greatest thing ever because there's even more shit now.
Scott: There's more shit now, so relatively speaking...
Rym: I'm not going to say there's more shit.
Scott: There's not more shit on an absolute scale.
Rym: It's that the percentage of movies are more shit.
Rym: Because...
Scott: Just go to Google, do this, and type in a year and type in, like, 1994 movies, 1995 movies, and Google, in the search results, will just show you posters across the top and keep increasing the year.
Scott: And when you get to about 2001, 2002, 2003, you can see, like, Lord of the Rings, it's, like, up, still good, and then there's, like, a cliff.
Scott: Except for Lord of the Rings, pretty much.
Rym: And there are still good movies every year.
Scott: There's just hardly any.
Scott: You go to, like, the early '90s, and it's just like, wow.
Scott: There are, like, four or five all-time classics in that list.
Scott: Well, like, look at this.
Rym: Look at what other movies came out the same year as Forrest Gump.
Scott: All right, so hold on.
Scott: 1994 movies.
Scott: Forrest Gump.
Scott: Pulp Fiction.
Scott: Lion King.
Scott: Shawshank Redemption.
Scott: All right, all right.
Scott: The Professional.
Scott: Already.
Scott: So, one, two, three, four, five.
Scott: True Lies.
Scott: I don't know if you're going to count that.
Rym: True Lies.
Rym: Have you seen True Lies again recently?
Scott: I'm just saying.
Rym: Because it is a great movie.
Rym: It really is a great movie.
Scott: All right, let me continue, right?
Scott: So, Dumb and Dumber, Speed, The Mask.
Scott: Okay, those aren't the greats, but those are still, you know, movies that have lasting power, right?
Rym: I wonder if The Mask holds up.
Rym: I'm going to guess.
Scott: The Crow is significant, at least.
Scott: Natural Born Killer is important.
Rym: Do you think The Crow is significant just because he died?
Rym: Or do you have another reason why you think it's significant?
Scott: No, it's significant not just because he died, but because people make a thing about him dying.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: So it's like a historical item.
Rym: I wouldn't count that, though.
Scott: Just the fact that it's existence, right?
Rym: Because it's not like stuff like that happens that often.
Scott: The first Ace Ventura.
Scott: Stargate.
Scott: Clerks.
Scott: Okay, so those are all the same year.
Scott: Look how much there was in that year.
Scott: All right, go check out the year 2007, because that's when No Country for Old Men came out.
Scott: All right, so 2007 movies.
Scott: Transformers, nope.
Scott: Juno, nope.
Scott: Spider-Man 3, nope.
Scott: No Country for Old Men, Ratatouille.
Rym: All right, two greats.
Scott: Two.
Scott: I Am Legend, super bad.
Scott: There Will Be Blood.
Scott: Knocked Up, Bourne Ultimatum.
Scott: Hot Fuzz.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Okay, not bad.
Scott: You know, one of the Harry Potters.
Rym: Super bad was kind of shit.
Rym: I'm sorry, guys.
Scott: I'm saying it was shit.
Scott: Yeah, I don't like, you know, it's like.
Scott: everything here is just like, um.
Scott: Yeah, so we've got, what, three?
Scott: Two?
Scott: Two or three, right?
Scott: We went from how many?
Scott: Like, seven to two or three.
Scott: And if you look, it's like, all right, we'll go to 2006.
Scott: Here we go.
Scott: The Departed.
Scott: There we go.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Prestige, slightly overrated, but still good.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Casino Royale.
Rym: I will never blame a movie for being overrated.
Rym: I will not rate a movie based on how other people are overrating it.
Scott: No, I'm just saying it's not as good as, like, a lot of people out there think, you know, if I say Prestige, some people out there might be thinking, great movie.
Scott: Oh my god, so good.
Scott: I'm like, oh, good.
Rym: If you haven't seen a lot of movies, it is.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: Um, X-Men Last Stand, Superman Return, right?
Scott: So again, two, two movies in this year.
Scott: Pan's Labyrinth.
Scott: Okay, three.
Rym: Pan's Labyrinth was super good.
Scott: Pretty good.
Rym: Um.
Rym: Kind of brutal.
Rym: You know, so No Country for Old Men is a good movie for the acting and for the deconstruction, and it's a Coen brothers movie, which I kind of like all of them.
Rym: And they're all kind of the same.
Rym: Not that they're the same plot, but that they have the same kind of attention to atmosphere that I like in movies.
Rym: But of all the people who played characters in this movie, the reason I like this movie a lot is not, I'm not going to spoil anything, the bad guy is one of my favorite quote bad guys in movies in a long time.
Scott: Real good bad guy.
Rym: Because he's a fucking psychopath and he's crazy, but he's not crazy in the way that people who are crazy in movies usually are.
Scott: Yeah, he's not like Joker crazy.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: He's not like, you know, uh, who else is crazy?
Rym: And all the other characters know he's crazy and act like he's crazy.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: And the way that he's crazy is just really fun.
Rym: I don't know, I like that movie a lot.
Rym: Also, Woody Harrelson plays a really good role and his resolution was great because I didn't see that coming at all, but it's a good movie.
Rym: So, uh, there was a movie called The Last Castle in 2001.
Scott: I like castles.
Rym: And Robert Redford stars in it.
Scott: All right.
Rym: And all I could think when I saw that was Robert Redford is alive.
Scott: Sure.
Rym: Robert Redford was in a movie, in a movie that's relatively recent, like within the last two decades.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: So yeah, this movie, I just didn't know what to expect, but I read the description and this sounded pretty good.
Rym: A court-martialed U.S.
Scott: general rallies together the inmates in his prison in an uprising.
Scott: So it's a military prison.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: So what I expected was famous court-martialed general uprising.
Rym: I thought this was going to be some awesome shit going down.
Scott: You court-martialed the wrong guy.
Rym: And he's guilty.
Rym: Apparently, like he disobeyed orders or whatever.
Scott: His leadership skills helped him, you know, free all the guys in the prison.
Rym: So the movie starts with him being taken to prison and the commandant of the prison is like, they shouldn't be putting him in prison.
Rym: They should be giving him a goddamn medal.
Rym: So I thought there's going to be some crazy political drama.
Rym: You know what this movie is?
Rym: It is Cool Hand Luke plus Dead Poet Society crossed with The Shawshank Redemption.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: It is those three movies mashed together and it is fucking awful.
Rym: It is the main character.
Rym: The bad guy is basically George Costanza and Robert Redford.
Scott: Is that the warden?
Rym: Yes.
Rym: The commandant.
Rym: He's the warden is Cool Hand Luke straight up, except he's also Robin Williams in the Dead Poet Society.
Rym: This movie.
Rym: Good fucking God.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: So false.
Scott: So what's the third movie?
Rym: So the third movie is phone booth from 2002 is about Superman.
Rym: So, uh, the beginning of this movie was weird because it makes a big deal about, Oh my God, cell phones.
Rym: Oh my God.
Rym: But then you think back to 2002.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Like cell phones were not that much of a thing yet.
Scott: In 2002 only certain people had them.
Rym: So I remember when this movie came out, I remember thinking it was dumb and I ignored it.
Rym: The plot of this movie.
Rym: Oh, it was written by Larry Cohen.
Rym: I didn't know that.
Rym: Anyway, the plot of this movie is that some douchebag goes to the last phone booth in Manhattan, which was a real phone booth and makes a call.
Rym: And then as he, after he hangs it up, the phone rings and he picks it up and the guy's like, I have a rifle trained on you.
Rym: If you hang up, I'll fucking kill you.
Rym: And then he shoots something nearby to prove that he could do it.
Rym: And then the movies, one of those dramas that plays out in real speed, which I just mentioned earlier, except it plays out in real time.
Rym: More like what was the name of that movie?
Rym: where the guy has to assassinate this like Senator in this mall or else they'll kill his daughter.
Rym: And that movie was filmed in real time.
Rym: Like it doesn't skip forward or fall back.
Rym: And it just follows time like second for second, the whole thing.
Scott: I don't know when you said a guy has to assassinate.
Scott: I might, my brain was just like, uh, what's it called?
Rym: Um, so I didn't remember the name of a movie and you don't even remember the name of the movie that you're referencing from the name of the movie that I remember.
Scott: The one where they, they like mess with the guy's memory and they brainwash him and it's got the crazy Chinese conspiracy.
Rym: Oh, the Manchurian candidate.
Scott: That's when you said they forced the guy to assassinate someone.
Scott: That's what I thought of.
Scott: Or the remake called the Manchurian candidate.
Scott: If someone says Manchurian candidate, I've seen both of them, but my brain just always thinks of the old one with the scene where, you know, the Chinese crazy, you know, room, whatever with those guys.
Rym: The movie with the Chinese crazy room.
Rym: So the movie follows that drama and I got to say it was better than I expected and I didn't know Kiefer Sutherland was in it.
Scott: I don't know who that is.
Rym: Uh, he did the voice acting in Armitage, the third poly matrix.
Scott: I don't remember that voice.
Rym: The second worst dub ever.
Scott: Pretty bad dub though.
Rym: Ever.
Rym: It has that scene where Armitage is like getting like taken away or shot or whatever and he just goes, no.
Scott: That's just one of those animes.
Scott: that's all action and art and there's no story.
Scott: It's just, all right, we have some robot girl and she runs around shooting stuff at the end.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: But it's so deep.
Scott: No, it's not.
Scott: You just run around shooting stuff at the end.
Rym: This movie was better than I thought and here's why.
Rym: The movie is so fucking stupid.
Rym: The main character is such a douchebag and such a stereotypical Hollywood douchebag.
Scott: Maybe you just hope he gets shot.
Rym: But then there's this scene where he's in the phone booth and he can't hang up or the guy will shoot him and this hooker comes over.
Rym: Cause this is back when, you know, the end of the era of hookers, it like just out in the daylight in New York city and she bangs on the phone booth like I want to make a call and she sounds like a Ruby rod and he's like, no, I can't hang up the phone.
Rym: and he closes the door on her and he bumps into her hand and she's like, Oh, you hurt my dick hand.
Rym: You didn't.
Rym: Oh no, you didn't.
Rym: You just hurt my dick hand.
Rym: And this dick hand thing just keeps coming back.
Rym: And it is telling that as dumb as this movie was, I had to know how it ended after having watched just a little bit.
Scott: He had to know.
Scott: He had to see the dick hand.
Rym: I had to know what happened to the dick hand.
Rym: And I watched to the end and I was not disappointed.
Scott: You got dick hand?
Rym: And it's funny cause I explained the plot to Emily in more detail.
Rym: She was like the same as you.
Rym: Why did you watch this movie?
Rym: And I was like, all right, so here's the plot.
Rym: And then she's like, all right, whatever.
Rym: And then later in the night she's like, so does he get away?
Rym: And I was like, Oh, maybe you should watch the movie and find out.
Scott: If someone did that shit to me, I'd be like, okay bro, just, just don't do anything.
Scott: I proved to me that you can shoot some does.
Scott: And that's right.
Scott: And then as soon as I say that, it'd be like, okay, I hang up and I run into an alley.
Rym: Uh, so he had a, he might've had a semi-automatic rifle.
Scott: Oh no, no.
Scott: You hear it.
Scott: You hear it later.
Rym: It is definitely a bolt action rifle.
Scott: But can he re-aim it at me so quickly?
Rym: Probably.
Scott: Even like he's aiming at some light bulb or something.
Rym: So here's part of the part of why the movie was actually kind of fun.
Rym: So he's in the phone booth and he's scared cause the guy already proved he's super accurate.
Rym: And then this pimp comes out and he is really funny.
Rym: And eventually the pimp's like, hang up the phone.
Rym: I'm going to fucking beat the shit out of you.
Rym: So then the pimp comes back with a baseball bat and just basically going to kill the guy.
Rym: And then the guy on the phone is like, I can make this stop.
Rym: And he's like, fine.
Rym: And then the sniper shoots the pimp and then all the police come now.
Rym: And the guy in the phone booth is surrounded and everyone thinks he shot the pimp and he has a gun.
Rym: And the guy on the phone's like, if you do anything now, the cops will shoot you.
Rym: I don't have to do anything.
Scott: And the movie for a shitty movie, a little bit of attack on a gas station there.
Rym: The movie was better than I thought.
Rym: And the reason I bring this movie up is that even Emily was like, so how's it end?
Rym: Like how's he get away?
Rym: It was better than The Last Castle.
Scott: I'm sure it was.
Rym: The moral of all of this, you all need to watch the Dead Poets Society, Shawshank Redemption, and Cool Hand Luke.
Scott: But not The Last Castle.
Rym: Not The Last Castle.
Rym: In fact, pretend that all those movies were the same movie and that is The Last Castle.
Rym: Also Robert Redford keeps taking his shirt off.
Scott: How old is he?
Rym: Like a hundred?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: So you got anything?
Rym: On Thursday?
Scott: The lounge?
Scott: Yeah, I was in the lounge with your mom.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Everything that I have is anime, video game, or technology related.
Scott: There's pretty much nothing going on that is not related to one of those things.
Scott: And you already spent a whole bunch of time talking about three whole movies.
Scott: So why waste any of those things?
Scott: We can just move on.
Rym: So moving on to things of the day.
Rym: Wanted to see if I could clip the new mixer and I did not.
Scott: Okay, so check this out.
Scott: This is a video from 2011 showing some research done at Stanford.
Scott: So it's two years old, a little late to the party.
Scott: But what it is is it's dual photography.
Scott: So the way this works is they have a camera and they have a projector, right?
Scott: Like the kind you would use to project a movie onto your wall.
Scott: And they aim the camera and the projector at the same scene from two different angles, right?
Scott: Then they basically take a picture with the camera of the scene, right?
Scott: And they are able to, with math, take a pic with the data from the camera, show you what the projector sees.
Scott: So the picture that develops after processing is this is what the projector is seeing, right?
Scott: And it can go so far in the demonstration as to they have a playing card.
Scott: And you look at the photograph that the camera took.
Scott: And the photograph is the back of the playing card.
Scott: But the projector, of course, is at a different angle and it can see the face of the card.
Scott: And, of course, with the data that comes out of the camera, plus their processing, you can see the face of the card super clearly.
Scott: Based on the light that reflected off the card and bounced off and back into the camera.
Rym: I've talked about stuff like that for a long time.
Rym: Having a functional example is amazing.
Scott: And they had this two years ago.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So imagine if...
Rym: That's in Google Glass.
Scott: Well, it doesn't have to be Google Glass.
Scott: Just like any camera.
Scott: You take a picture of something with your camera.
Scott: And then you just like go into Lightroom or Photoshop and you're like, "Okay, here's the scene.
Scott: There's a thing...".
Rym: What's around that corner?
Scott: Yeah, there's like a light bulb over there and the light bulb is at this position.
Scott: Show me what it looks like from the light bulb looking that way.
Rym: I'm convinced that cameras as we know them will someday disappear and will be replaced by a button that you carry around on you or you activate it.
Rym: You go,
Rym: "Bam!"
Rym: And it just takes a sort of metadata moment of...
Scott: It just captures a bunch of photons from all over.
Rym: No, it doesn't even do that.
Rym: It just captures the exact timestamp and GPS location of you.
Rym: And then embedded sensors from everything else in the world combined all dump their data into a blob associated with that.
Rym: And then you can explore that blob at your leisure later.
Scott: I'm sure.
Rym: That's all gonna come.
Rym: That's culture shit that's coming down the road.
Scott: But I can't wait for this shit to... Like if someone could use this in sports, right?
Scott: You could have a lot less cameras at the sporting event.
Scott: But still get the angle to see what happens.
Rym: Wait, wait.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Take that soccer.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Soccer will never use this.
Scott: Soccer isn't even using regular cameras.
Rym: I know.
Rym: Speed walking.
Scott: But football might use this.
Rym: I look forward to the day when they zoom into the hockey player's brain to figure out if he started the fight or the other guy did.
Rym: So Scott apparently had no idea that this "What does the fox
Rym: say?"
Rym: meme happened.
Scott: Oh yeah, I didn't see that at all.
Rym: Yeah, that was all over the internet.
Rym: 81 million views already.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: So, yeah.
Rym: What does the fox say?
Rym: If you didn't see this, culturally in the US at least, and a lot of other countries, you know, what does the dog say?
Rym: Woof.
Rym: What does the cat say?
Rym: Meow.
Scott: Well, in different countries it says different things.
Rym: Yeah, but everyone has a thing for that.
Rym: But culturally, if you ask the average American, "What does the fox
Rym: say?"
Rym: They blank.
Scott: It's like a dog, but it sort of yaps.
Rym: Yeah, smart people know foxes make noises.
Rym: But if you ask an average person, if you go to a speak and say, there's no goddamn fox on that thing.
Scott: Dude, let's make a speak and say that only has animals that are normally not on a speak and say.
Scott: That would be a pretty good speak and say.
Scott: That would just be like, we'll make it like an Arduino and we'll just sort of, you know, we'll print out a sticker for it.
Scott: We'll just take a speak and say and mod it.
Scott: And that'll be like a special speak and say.
Scott: You just plant it somewhere or bring it to the Maker Faire.
Rym: That would be a cool thing to do.
Rym: That's actually the first time I've had a project with an Arduino.
Rym: That'd be fun.
Rym: That I could just do anyway.
Scott: We need to come up with all the animals though.
Rym: Someone said in some country in Eastern Europe, I think, they were on Fark.
Rym: They were like, "Yip,
Rym: yap."
Rym: And they linked.
Rym: I forget.
Rym: I can't even find it again.
Rym: But there's this little...
Scott: A children's book?
Rym: A children's comic book, cartoon, whatever.
Rym: And the fox says, "Yip,
Rym: yap.".
Rym: That's just what foxes say.
Scott: Yeah, that's about right.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But yeah, this video just kind of makes fun of that.
Rym: It's very, very well done.
Rym: But that's not my thing of the day.
Rym: I'm just pointing out that Scott didn't know what it was.
Rym: So many of you might not either.
Rym: My thing of the day is someone else.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Who made the origin story of What Does the Fox Say?
Rym: And this is so good.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: That's it.
Rym: That's what I got.
Rym: Metamoment?
Scott: Metamoment indeed.
Scott: Wow, there's a lot of meta going on.
Scott: Let's check the calendar.
Scott: My calendar is pretty empty except for Thanksgiving.
Scott: Thanksgiving in November is coming.
Scott: It's going to be probably the only time for the next many millennia that Thanksgiving and Hanukkah overlap.
Rym: Want to do something special?
Scott: You got to have freaking so much combo that can happen.
Scott: Potato latkes with cranberry applesauce is only the beginning of the miracle of Thanksgiving.
Rym: We always go home to our families for Thanksgiving.
Rym: You want to throw a big feast of Thanksgiving in the city?
Scott: I'm just saying we need a thanksgivica something.
Scott: Anyway, also this Saturday, no, this Saturday is netrunner tournament in Albany at the zombie store that I'm go to.
Scott: But there's going to be one in Sunday, 1230 at the 20 sided store in Brooklyn, which I will go to.
Scott: But the Albany one is the special magical fantasy flight official one.
Scott: The fantasy flight official ones in New York are on the 19th and the 20th, which is going to be the 19th is at the strat and the 20th is in Brooklyn somewhere.
Scott: But that is also the weekend of Burning Con 2013, the penteclagon, which I think you can still register for.
Rym: I guess the schedule is being made.
Rym: Like the deadline for submitting my shit was long past.
Scott: Next weekend is New York Comic Con and we're not going to.
Scott: This weekend is big bad con in California somewhere, which is an indie RPG con.
Rym: I got to finish my new scenario.
Scott: But the only con that really matters is next year, the beginning of next year, which is magfest.
Rym: It's coming.
Scott: That's the only thing to be excited for right now.
Scott: Everything else is sort of like hibernate for the winter and play games, guys.
Rym: We are resuming production of.
Rym: GeekNights presents utenna.
Rym: Have no fear.
Rym: We have a new mixer.
Rym: We have videos on the internet.
Rym: We're streaming stuff.
Rym: There's a tumbler that every day is tumbling an old episode of GeekNights, an artisanal tumble.
Rym: The book club book is Stazzyland, a book about what will happen in the US if we let the NSA go away with all this shit.
Scott: Right now they're shut down.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Nope.
Rym: The NSA is not shut down.
Rym: In fact, you want to know some bullshit?
Rym: You know what?
Rym: One thing that is shut down, the part of the IRS that helps you defend yourself if you mess up on taxes.
Rym: OK.
Rym: You know what's not shut down?
Scott: The part of the IRS that collects taxes.
Rym: That takes your shit away if you mess up.
Rym: So basically the due process part is shut down, but the take your shit part is still running.
Scott: How is that not an essential service?
Scott: They realize the head of the IRS decided that, right?
Scott: That's what they've been telling us.
Scott: is that the people who decide what's essential and what's not essential are like the heads of the departments, like the upper management.
Scott: So that means the head of the IRS just decided that they have complete power to just make that decision.
Scott: And they decided that, which means whoever is the head of the IRS right now, let's look them up.
Scott: That's not head of IRC.
Scott: Who is the head of the IRS?
Scott: Commissioner of Internal Revenue is.
Scott: That's from 1862.
Scott: Currently, Daniel Werfel.
Scott: He is the acting head of Internal Revenue.
Scott: Daniel Werfel, you're a jerk.
Scott: You're a bad person.
Scott: Legitimately, you're just a bad guy, but you're appointed.
Scott: So we can't vote you out.
Scott: You're just an appointed person.
Rym: So yeah, the government shut down.
Scott: You did.
Rym: I'm kind of amazed that it actually happened.
Scott: Start menu, but when you go to the start menu, you actually are stopping.
Rym: Did you see that tweet?
Rym: Someone was like, it appears your government has shut down improperly.
Scott: You realize there are like four tweets that keep going around and everyone just keeps retweeting them.
Scott: I saw them like three days in a row, the same tweets over and over again.
Rym: Because they're just going to make the same jokes about this stuff.
Rym: The thing is, many of the people who are tweeting.
Scott: I wish there was a way to like tell Twitter like high duplicate retweets.
Scott: Like if I've seen that tweet from someone else and someone tweets it again, I don't see it again.
Rym: It depends sometimes because years ago I tweeted something and it just like really went viral.
Rym: And I remember that it kept getting retweeted, but then it kept getting retweeted back at me via old clients with the RT and things in front of it.
Rym: So I kept getting my own tweet retweeted back at me by people that I follow like months after the fact.
Scott: Yeah, I don't like that.
Rym: But I think a lot of the people who listen to GeekNights were not really old enough to remember the last time that this happened.
Rym: Like back when we were in high school.
Rym: Because that happened when we were in high school.
Rym: It was shut down for like a month right around the same time of year.
Scott: Also, many states have had shutdowns.
Rym: I grew up in the state of Michigan where government shutdowns were plentiful.
Scott: There have also been a lot of town shutdowns I've known about because the town, it was usually involving the school budget.
Scott: There would be like an argument where between people who, usually old people who wanted to not have a school tax.
Scott: And you know, and then the people who had families or were in school and were like we need a school tax so we want to make the school budget more.
Scott: And they couldn't decide and the town would shut down.
Rym: So to talk about this a little bit, in case you guys really don't understand what happened.
Rym: Because I went back when Obama got elected.
Scott: I know there's a lot of countries and other places where this cannot happen.
Rym: Oh my god, like Australia, if this happens, everyone just gets fucked in these new elections.
Scott: Right, there are other places where it can't happen.
Scott: So for people to understand why it happens here, we need to explain to you.
Rym: Well I was just in Istanbul, right?
Rym: And the people I talked to, because I have a lot of friends there.
Rym: They were like, so what's this about your government shutting down?
Rym: Like how the fuck can that happen?
Rym: And the funny part is that when I explained it, a lot of people outside of the US.
Scott: Don't know how the US works.
Rym: No, they think that the Republican party is like some wacko right wing fringe and isn't a mainstream party.
Scott: It is Iraqi mainstream, it's a mainstream wacko fringe.
Rym: It's a mainstream party, they don't realize that.
Rym: They're like, what do you mean?
Rym: they're half the country?
Scott: Their country didn't have a south.
Scott: Like Germany had a south, it's called East Germany.
Rym: Well you saw Greece just arrested the leaders of their far right party.
Scott: And they were only able to do that because the guys friggin murdered somebody.
Scott: Right, because I guess they have mostly freedom of speech in Greece, right?
Rym: Yeah, kinda.
Scott: I mean they couldn't just arrest them for being Nazis that they are.
Rym: And I'm fine with those not being allowed to arrest Nazis.
Scott: The thing is, while I'm 100% anti-Golden Dawn nut jobs, if they arrested them simply for being Nazis, I would be not okay with that.
Scott: But those guys have done plenty of other things besides simply say antisemitic things and express their evil speech.
Scott: So it's perfectly okay to arrest them, which they finally did.
Scott: It took too long.
Scott: You realize those Golden Dawn crazies, like in the US, there are plenty of places where you can vote for the Nazis, right?
Scott: In Greece, those Golden Dawn guys have like 18 seats.
Scott: That's how racist Greece is.
Rym: Far right country.
Rym: Dude, in Sweden, the Nazi extremists are a significant political force.
Rym: Yeah, free speech is the best thing ever, but I digress.
Rym: So I'm gonna explain what's happening to you by quoting Abraham Lincoln.
Scott: Ram, you gotta stop doing the tweets.
Scott: If you can't fit it in one tweet, you shouldn't be tweeting it.
Rym: Do you know how many people retweeted that stream of tweets?
Scott: Except for every single person that says,
Scott: "Rims."
Scott: And you realize, I have more followers than you.
Rym: I'm gaining on you.
Scott: I just want to point out this thing.
Scott: I don't care how many followers I have.
Scott: It's just relevant to the other point I'm making.
Scott: The number doesn't... I don't have an ego or whatever, right?
Scott: So I have like 100 more than you.
Scott: You have almost twice the number of tweets that I have and you've been tweeting for less time.
Rym: Yeah, I tweet a lot because I poop a lot.
Scott: I tweet too much.
Scott: Too much tweeting.
Rym: The thing is, most of those tweets are just me having conversations with people.
Scott: I'm just saying, too many tweets.
Rym: Not enough tweets.
Scott: Twitter is all about less... The reason it's small is so that you shut the fuck up.
Rym: Nah, nah, nah, nah, nah.
Rym: How many tweets does Daryl Surratt have?
Scott: Probably more than either of us.
Rym: Alright, Daryl.
Rym: Let's see, Daryl Surratt.
Rym: You follow each other.
Rym: 40,000 tweets, 3,000 followers.
Scott: You have like 12,000 and I have less than 10,000.
Rym: I've noticed something because I was keeping track of it with the graph.
Rym: The more I tweet, the more followers I get.
Rym: Straight up.
Scott: Besides you just have an auto-tweet tweet constantly?
Scott: Bother everyone who follows me, the stream is flooded and they unfollow me.
Rym: The thing is, you do want to do it like Conrad has his regular Twitter and then all my developer shit is in his other Twitter.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: Anyway, I'm going to quote Abraham Lincoln in a letter he wrote in 1861.
Scott: Republican Abraham Lincoln.
Scott: Noted Republican.
Rym: So one thing to keep clear, guys, outside of the US.
Rym: The Democratic Party today is effectively the Republican Party from the 1860s.
Scott: The Whigs.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: The Republican Party today is basically the Democratic Party from the 1860s.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: The quote is as such, and as a side note, people could write fucking speeches and letters back in the 1860s.
Rym: This is just a letter Abraham Lincoln wrote to a guy.
Rym: What is our present condition?
Rym: We have just carried an election on principles fairly stated to the people.
Rym: Now we are told in advance that government shall be broken up unless we surrender to those we have beaten before we take the offices.
Scott: Right.
Rym: In this, they are either attempting to play upon us, or they are in dead earnest.
Rym: Either way, if we surrender, is the end of us and of the government.
Rym: They will repeat the experiment upon us, ad libitum.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So here's the issue, right?
Scott: So you have a system in place, which we do, that is kind of a crappy system.
Scott: It has problems.
Rym: Notice our system is not the system we gave to Iraq and Afghanistan after we invaded them.
Scott: Yeah, whatever.
Rym: We gave them a parliamentary system instead.
Scott: Yeah, so, in the
Scott: U.S.,
Scott: you have a majority rule, right?
Scott: So you need a majority to rule, of course.
Scott: But, if you have, say, the numbers not working out, right?
Scott: We have, you know, the two, right?
Scott: So right now, the House, you've got Republicans sort of, right, in charge.
Rym: Well, the Republican Party controls the House of Representatives because they took over, many years ago, the state legislatures ahead of the U.S.
Rym: 2010 census.
Rym: that determines where district boundaries are drawn.
Rym: So they gerrymandered, or gerrymandered, if you're a pedant, like me, the districts to ensure that they would control the House and hold on to that one piece of the government they can still control.
Rym: Right, and the Senate- Even though they lost the popular election.
Scott: Right, so most of the people in the country voted Democrat.
Scott: Most of the Senate is Democrats.
Scott: The President is Democrat.
Scott: Most of the states, right, where those Democrats live, have Democrat people.
Scott: But, the Republicans won certain things, so they control this one part of the government, right?
Rym: One half of one third of the federal government.
Scott: So it's like, they don't have enough people to where, let's say they wanted to write a law and pass it, they don't have enough people to do that.
Scott: They can't do anything they want to do.
Scott: But, they have enough people, mathematically, to where they can stop someone else doing what they want to do.
Scott: Now, it's slightly more complicated than that, because I don't want to get into the details of the Senate- You need to at least get a few of these crazy people to agree with something if you want to make it happen.
Rym: Actually, you don't.
Rym: Here's the trouble.
Rym: So, the Senate, for once, is actually working fine.
Scott: Of course.
Rym: But the House, the problem, and to get back to Lincoln's thing, isn't just that this tiny part of the government can shut things down and fuck things up.
Rym: The reason they can do this, in this case, and shut the government down, is that Republicans pushed forth all this stuff back in the day, to where we have to keep passing these bills, periodically, to keep the government going.
Rym: For no good reason.
Scott: Yeah, basically when they write the law, in the law they say, "This law expires
Scott: X."
Scott: Right?
Scott: And it's like, we don't have to write the law.
Scott: that way, we can write whatever law we please.
Scott: Why don't they write the law to say, "This law lasts
Scott: forever!"?
Rym: Well, because- Every time this comes up, they have the option of saying, "Fuck you!
Rym: Do X, or we won't pass a
Rym: bill.".
Scott: Right.
Scott: They can hold the government hostage- If you want this law, you need some of us to say yes on this bill to make it happen, therefore, if you don't do what we say, and we say, "Put in an expiration date," and if you don't do that, it won't happen, but if you do what we say and put the expiration date, then maybe we'll vote yes on there.
Rym: So let's go back to the election of 1860.
Rym: Lincoln won, the majority of Americans were against slavery, and the Republicans, now the Democrats, effectively won the election.
Scott: The people who lost the election, they lost because- So most of the people in the country, though not all, wanted slavery gone, they voted against it, and they won- But the entire South basically voted for it-.
Scott: There were enough people who still like slavery, though.
Rym: The South voted entirely for it, but simultaneously split their vote between a really crazy and a moderate crazy.
Rym: Kind of like what's going on now.
Rym: So when they lost the election, they said, "Well, fuck it.
Rym: We're shutting it all down.
Rym: We're seceding.
Rym: Fuck you
Rym: guys.".
Rym: They basically said, "We lost the election, so we're going to not use the government
Rym: anymore.".
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, that's all there is to it.
Scott: And that's what they're doing now.
Scott: It's supposed to be that we all vote, and it's like, imagine if you're with your friends, and you vote on where to go to dinner, right?
Scott: And six people vote to get pizza, and four people vote hamburgers.
Scott: And the four hamburger people are like, "Well, I didn't get my way.
Scott: I'm going to hamburgers anyway.
Scott: Fuck you
Scott: guys.".
Scott: That's what's going on.
Scott: That's exactly what's happening.
Scott: Now, in the past- Ignore the people who won and are in charge of their own little world.
Rym: Now, in the past, when things like this would happen, the Democrats can't really muster one combined testicle or ovary between a lot of them.
Rym: So they would always compromise on any issue like this, and kind of move toward the Republicans.
Rym: But the Republicans just back right the fuck up every time, because it always works.
Rym: So now, for the first time ever, the Democratic Party said no.
Rym: If, like Lincoln said here, what's Lincoln saying if you can't interpret that paragraph I read?
Scott: If you can't understand 1800 Es?
Rym: He's saying, if you let them hold the government hostage to overturn the electorate, then they will do that every time.
Rym: they don't get their way forever.
Scott: Right, you're basically saying as long as any number of crazies, if they have a signi- you know, it doesn't even have to be a majority, right?
Scott: Suddenly, a minority can rule, basically, as long as they have enough.
Scott: It doesn't have to be the majority.
Scott: So even though most of the people in the country want one thing, what's gonna happen is something that a minority of the crazies want, simply because they're using a crazy strategy of, "We'll just burn the house down if you don't do what we
Scott: say.".
Scott: Like a, you know, like a little child who's like, "Oh, if you won't buy me that toy, then I'm gonna cry and make a mess in the house and break
Scott: everything.".
Scott: So you had to buy me that toy, even though there are four people in this family besides you, you know, the little kid just gets his way just by screaming and crying.
Scott: And if you give the kid what he wants, you know, to make him shut up, guess what happens next time you're in the toy store?
Rym: I don't know why, but all I can think of- Screaming and crying again.
Rym: All I can think of while you were saying that is the baby in dinosaurs.
Scott: Yeah, so the only option is to let the baby scream and cry and mess up everything in the house.
Scott: Or beat it up.
Rym: Here's what happened this time.
Scott: Or throw it out the window.
Rym: For all of you non-US listeners.
Scott: Or like my mom down the incinerator till her friend Debbie saved me.
Rym: For now.
Scott: I don't think I fit down the incinerator anymore.
Rym: The incinerator of Damocles is waiting under you.
Scott: She literally saved me from the incinerator.
Rym: So, the Republican Party is the moron party.
Scott: Of course.
Rym: Don't get us wrong.
Rym: It is their fault 100%.
Rym: But within that party, there are two factions.
Rym: The moderate Republicans.
Scott: Who are like- They're crazy.
Rym: They're morons.
Rym: They're bad.
Rym: But at least they're like your old enemy.
Rym: Like in the Prince of Nothing.
Scott: Like Bill O'Reilly?
Rym: It's like the Prince of Nothing.
Rym: The old enemy, where you at least, you and your old enemy understand each other and know when to fight and when to kinda just go through the motions.
Scott: It's like they disagree with you, but they're not totally fucked the fuck up.
Rym: They're like, "Look, backdoor deal.
Rym: We gotta do something to make this work.
Rym: Alright, well I'll give you this, you give me that.
Rym: Let's do
Rym: it.".
Rym: Right.
Scott: It's like you've got Superman and the old enemy is Lex Luthor.
Rym: Like Lex Luthor's not gonna destroy the entire planet to get Superman because his shit's there.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Maybe.
Scott: Well, I know.
Scott: I haven't read enough stupid DC Comics.
Rym: Yeah, it depends on which era of Lex Luthor.
Rym: Right?
Scott: But, you know, the crazy enemy is like Doomsday.
Scott: Right?
Scott: He shows up, he kills Superman because he's just so crazy powerful.
Rym: So, the Tea Party side of the Republicans will say they're gonna burn it all down if they don't get what they want, but unlike the moderate Republicans, they'll actually do it.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: And my guess is that eventually John Boehner and the moderate Republicans were like, "You know what?
Rym: Fine.
Rym: Fuck it.
Rym: Go for it.
Rym: This is what you want?
Rym: Let's do
Rym: it.".
Rym: And the Democrats were like, "Yeah, fuck you.
Rym: Have fun.
Rym: We'll wait.
Rym: Clock is
Rym: ticking.".
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And here we are.
Rym: Government shutdown.
Scott: So, you know, government shutdown, you know, the problem with the government shutdown, of course, is in and of itself doesn't cause enough pain to anybody to, you know, in particular, or enough people, or enough pain to actually bring about change.
Scott: Right?
Scott: It's like there's very few people who are, you know, up in arms enough, deprived of enough bread and circuses such that, you know, there's gonna be any sort of uprising or push to actually fix anything.
Scott: And basically, so these people in Washington know how to do anything.
Scott: And also these crazies, right?
Scott: The only people the crazies have to answer to are the people who voted for them.
Scott: And in the place they live, in their gerrymandered district, right?
Scott: It's all crazies.
Scott: So even though the whole rest of the country is like, "You guys are crazy.
Scott: What the fuck is wrong with
Scott: you?".
Scott: Those people don't vote for that crazy.
Scott: That crazy only represents this, you know, place in the desert or in the south where a bunch of hicks live.
Scott: So they're all crazy.
Scott: And those hicks are very happy with this.
Scott: And the government shutdown doesn't hurt those hicks one bit.
Rym: So thus explaining why these so-called moderate Republicans are letting the crazy people get what they want because of challenges from the right.
Rym: If you're a Republican, even if you're really conservative, and you vote with the Democrats to just get the government working again, they'll brand you as a traitor, a rhino, a Republican in any name only.
Scott: Because remember, the people who are voting for these crazies are dumb people.
Scott: So you have to appeal to dumbness, which is really easy.
Scott: That's how they got in power in the first place.
Scott: It's easy to brainwash and propaganda.
Scott: dumb people.
Rym: You think Americans don't vote in elections?
Rym: Americans fucking don't vote in primaries.
Rym: The only people who vote in primaries are super politically motivated people and horrible old conservative busybodies.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So basically you you that's what you did.
Scott: That was your strategy.
Scott: to get elected was to brainwash and appeal to crazies and stupids to get them to vote for you.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So now you are basically beholden to stupids and crazies.
Scott: So if you do intelligent things, somebody else who's crazier than you can now basically tell the crazies, oh, this guy who said he was on your side, you know, compromised a little bit.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So the same weapons that you were using against your enemies are now used on you if you don't actually do the crazy things that you said you would do.
Scott: Just to get in office.
Rym: So the moderate Republicans have basically a gun to their head.
Rym: If they do business as usual and fix this or do any sort of compromise, some ridiculous far right guy will come in to the right of them, no matter how far right they are.
Rym: Right means conservative and stupid in the US.
Rym: Left means liberal and usually also stupid.
Rym: But I guess so.
Rym: People will come in to the right of you more conservative.
Rym: And the only people who decide who gets to run for the Republican office are the people who vote in the primaries.
Scott: The most crazy people in the people who have nothing better to do.
Rym: The craziest of the crazies are the only people who vote in those things.
Rym: So, yeah, my prediction of what's going to happen in the end of all this.
Rym: And then I want to talk.
Scott: I want to let Scott explain his idea for how maybe the only way I think we can fix anything in this country in a short amount of time.
Rym: So my prediction of what's going to happen is that the moderate Republicans, if they do anything, there's going to be this problem.
Rym: I think nothing is going to happen and the government is going to stay shut down until we get to that other deadline that's coming up, the debt ceiling, which that is actually for real a big deal if we don't.
Scott: If they don't do what they need to do then and they keep holding out and keep just holding everyone hostage, basically all the economy will collapse.
Rym: This is the equivalent of pissing in my own bed to prove a point.
Scott: It's like the country isn't doing what I want to do.
Scott: So I'm just going to burn the whole country.
Rym: You feel like a king of the world when you first piss in your bed.
Scott: Well, they managed to get past the last debt ceiling situation.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And they pushed it off until.
Rym: Well, here's what I predict.
Rym: Democrats don't budge.
Rym: We get to the debt ceiling debate.
Rym: Eventually enough moderate Republicans defect and vote with the Democrats just to get things going again with minimal compromises from the Democrats.
Rym: Then the Republican crazies go apeshit.
Scott: I'd rather see.
Rym: They're going to burn down.
Rym: They're going to go apeshit to a degree that will define the term apeshit.
Rym: Imagine someone going apeshit.
Rym: That is what you will see on the floor of the house.
Rym: And then there's going to be crazy, crazy crazies coming in from the right in the Republican primaries.
Rym: And I don't think they're going to win general elections.
Rym: I think Democrats are going to replace them because the people that the crazies are going to target the most are the ones that are going to win general elections.
Rym: The Republicans that are near sane places in the US, like suburbs of the big cities.
Rym: So I think the Republicans are going to destroy themselves over the course of the next 18 months.
Scott: I think I hope they burn it down and the debt ceiling doesn't work, because even though that would suck for everybody, I think that, you know, the government shutdown doesn't cause enough, you know, bread and circuses.
Scott: Right.
Scott: We still have bread and circuses, even though the government is shut down.
Rym: Oh, I'm not saying what I want to have.
Rym: If they
Scott: fuck up the debt ceiling, then there will actually be a lack of bread and circuses in a significant way to where every even people just ignore fucking politics and don't even give a shit and don't pay attention and just living out their lives will be like, oh, shit, my shit is fucked up.
Scott: I can't.
Scott: Oh, my God.
Scott: My life is basically ruined because of these crazies.
Scott: And then they'll be forced to do something and have a more drastic and rapid fixing after a short term pain, as opposed to putting in, you know, stitching up their wound and holding it together even longer.
Scott: Right.
Rym: I think part of this, too, is that this fight is all over Obamacare, the Affordable Care Act.
Rym: I think the Republicans are desperately afraid that it'll work or at least won't make things worse.
Rym: And then suddenly everything they've been saying for the last four years sounds really stupid.
Scott: You know, that's that's how it is.
Scott: You know, when you when you when you're it's it's a battle of an ideologue versus a pragmatist.
Scott: Right.
Scott: If you have an ideology, basically, you believe in it on faith.
Scott: And so it's like people who believe in God.
Scott: They don't want to hear the arguments that show that.
Scott: No, they're probably most likely almost zero percent chance of there being a God.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They just don't want to hear it.
Scott: And if you actually had some evidence, say, to disprove somebody's I don't know, fake medicine.
Scott: They don't want to hear that either.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Because if you could actually prove them wrong, that just ruins their entire worldview.
Scott: So they just believe this thing on faith.
Scott: No evidence whatsoever, even though it's wrong.
Scott: And basically the they're happy.
Scott: They're lucky that they have the power to prevent you from doing the thing that goes against their ideology, because then that would be evidence in their face.
Scott: You know, basically bringing their world to a halt.
Scott: Everything I believed is wrong.
Scott: No.
Scott: So as long as they can prevent you from doing it, they never have to see that they're wrong and they can continue believing their lies and, you know, faith or and not have to have a crisis of faith of any kind.
Scott: So keep living in their fantasy land.
Rym: We live in New York in a sane place where there are no crazies.
Rym: There are very few crazy where as a result, we have zero ability to in any way impact the situation.
Scott: No, not by voting.
Rym: So, Scott, suppose we are type of person needed to change things in the government.
Scott: Well, so, you know, in throughout history, there have been many ways to change things in government.
Scott: when voting doesn't work.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So way number one, violent revolution.
Scott: Not going to work, guys.
Scott: Not only, A, the people who are good have less guns than the people who are crazy, but B, even if we went and got guns, the government has better guns.
Scott: And C, because of all the terrorism nonsense, which we would like to fix, the government and even the police have way too many guns.
Scott: They're basically just armies everywhere.
Scott: You can't.
Scott: There's nothing.
Scott: Also, violence is bad.
Scott: I don't want to kill cops.
Scott: It's not their fault.
Scott: They didn't do it.
Scott: They agree with me.
Scott: They're just doing a job.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Except for the Nazis were just doing their job.
Scott: Except for the bad cops.
Scott: You know, the bad cops.
Scott: Those are the ones, you know, right?
Scott: So speaking of bad cops, beating up protesters, right?
Scott: We can go protest like dirty hippies.
Rym: Yeah, that doesn't do anything.
Scott: It doesn't do anything.
Scott: Because who has to listen to a bunch of...
Rym: Remember your rally for sanity?
Scott: Remember your Occupy?
Scott: Nothing?
Scott: Right?
Scott: You know who shows up?
Scott: People with no jobs and hippies and crazies.
Scott: And even people who agree with them are just like, there's no, we don't have to listen to anything you say.
Rym: Speaking of people with no jobs, speaking of people with no jobs, I biked to work at like 10 this morning because I was doing some stuff first.
Rym: So after normal people go to normal jobs, it was all fixies.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: It's all the people without jobs are riding fixies at 10 o'clock.
Rym: All the people with normal jobs are riding normal bikes at like nine.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Anyway.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So if you go out and protest, people just ignore you.
Scott: You're a crazy hippie.
Scott: That's completely pointless.
Scott: Doesn't do anything.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So what else can we do?
Scott: Write letters to our representatives.
Scott: My representative already is on my side.
Scott: You know, they're not perfect, but they're on the right side of this issue.
Rym: I just initiated a gas attack in this room, but I don't think it's gonna have much effect outside of this room.
Scott: Trail of tears.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So really, like, what can we do?
Scott: Right.
Scott: So we have to look through history.
Scott: And we look back and we try to find people who are able to do this.
Scott: Any instance in all of history, someone was able to have a change in their government from the bottom up, you know, who didn't have political power, maybe with a, you know, group of people, whatever.
Scott: So let's go back.
Scott: Martin Luther King, civil disobedience.
Scott: Right.
Scott: We can do that.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: That won't really work today either, because we'll just end our asses up in jail.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And this issue.
Scott: So Martin Luther King.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The issue he was fighting.
Scott: He broke the laws that he was trying to get rid of.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So it's like we pirate music.
Scott: We'd like to get rid of those laws.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But what law can we break here?
Scott: That would be the law that we're trying.
Scott: Can we go and just give people health care?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: What are we supposed to do?
Scott: Are we supposed to?
Scott: I don't know what.
Scott: There is no law to be disobedient to because we're not the ones who have to obey this law.
Scott: The government, the Treasury, I guess, has to obey this law.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So even if we were civil disobedient, there's no civil to disobedient in this case, and we'd all just end up in jail and it wouldn't matter.
Scott: There's only one thing I could think of that we could do.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So I looked even further back to Gandhi.
Scott: And what Gandhi did is he would do stuff like, yeah, we're just going to take all this salt and dump it in the ocean.
Scott: And it's like, well, dumping salt in the ocean.
Scott: It's like they dumped tea in the ocean, you know, in the US.
Scott: Right.
Scott: What does that matter?
Scott: It's like that mattered because salt was fucking expensive and it's protesting salt taxes.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That was what it was.
Scott: Pretty sure it was protesting salt taxes.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It was relevant and it actually caused damage.
Scott: He caused damage in a nonviolent way such that people were harmed.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's not harmed physically, violently, but he was able to damage people.
Scott: Such that they had to do something about it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So they couldn't just let him do this.
Scott: You know, he would also do like hunger strikes.
Scott: And it's like, well, if he died, it's now your fault.
Scott: So now, you know, right.
Scott: And it's sort of like, well, shit, they can't have that.
Scott: And the British were forced to, you know, basically let India be its own country eventually.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So what can we do like that that we could maybe possibly no one's going to do it doesn't matter is we could just not work.
Scott: A general strike.
Scott: Nobody.
Scott: Period.
Scott: Even essential.
Scott: Well, I don't know if essential people really have to like do the you know, just nobody goes to work.
Scott: But what does nobody mean?
Scott: Like, would it work if the firemen still went to work?
Scott: or maybe even the firemen don't go to work?
Scott: Even the doctors don't go to work.
Scott: Even the military doesn't go to work.
Rym: Our demographic, if all of us stop going to work, a lot of things stop working really quick.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: And it's like you look and it's like not going to work.
Scott: All the rich people suddenly have no money.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, oh, you want to take money away from a rich guy and you can't pass a law to tax him?
Scott: Just no one shows up to work.
Scott: Suddenly, his company is losing billions of dollars a day.
Scott: It's like, what now, rich guy?
Rym: So you're advocating a sort of Atlas Shrugged general strike, right?
Scott: Is it basically?
Scott: if none of that, you know, Atlas Shrugged was like, yeah, the smart people don't go to work in this fantasy libertarian land.
Scott: I'm saying nobody go to work.
Scott: Janitor doesn't go to work.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Draw taxi driver doesn't drive his taxi like nobody goes to work.
Scott: And we do that.
Scott: And it's like, all right, government, nobody is working or at least enough people, you know, or certain people in enough quantity and enough important positions are not working such that it is causing, you know, people distress.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Such that they are upset.
Scott: And they like we we can't not fix this.
Scott: We had these people need to go back to work, but they refused to do so until, you know, you fix the health care and you do these things that we want.
Scott: Otherwise, it's going to actually be painful for a lot of people.
Scott: And they're going to be really upset.
Scott: And it's your fault.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: It's like Gandhi's hunger strike.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like it's your fault if Gandhi dies because you're not.
Scott: he's not eating because you're not doing what he said.
Scott: So it's like it's your fault if, you know, these people in the hospital die because the doctors aren't working because you didn't fix the health care.
Scott: bullshit.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And those.
Scott: So now not only the doctors, they were originally upset, but now the people who are dying are upset and the families who are dying upset.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like one person not going to work.
Scott: They don't pick up the garbage for a few weeks.
Scott: That's thousands of people because like two or three people didn't work.
Scott: So we just had to reach a critical mass of people not working and refusing to work until shit is fixed.
Scott: And that will force them to fix shit.
Rym: Now, that is almost where a real rally is.
Rym: Imagine those people not only don't go to work, but they all just go to D.C Yeah, it doesn't matter if they go to
Rym: D.C.,
Rym: they can just stay home and drink, you know, one thing that the general strike does not give you for a while.
Rym: And that's the media frenzy.
Scott: You can have a media frenzy without, you know, everyone going in.
Rym: Enough people would go.
Rym: You just got to fill that mall and then you're good.
Scott: I mean, I would just instead of I would not go to the rally.
Rym: Don't get me wrong.
Rym: I know better.
Rym: But I would convince all of you to go to the rally.
Scott: If I ran the rally, what I would try to do is have it not look like a hippie protest where everyone's got the signs and the chanting, whatever.
Rym: Well, Martin Luther King, they would march in their Sunday best.
Scott: I wouldn't march either.
Scott: Marching is also pointless.
Scott: What I would do is I would party.
Scott: I would be like, all right, everyone, you're not going to work.
Scott: Let's all go to the National Mall and party.
Scott: Drunken.
Scott: It'd be like drunken Central Park party day.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: Like everyone's we're not working.
Scott: We're having a grand old time.
Scott: Everyone's just picnicking and you know, it's all good here.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So what?
Rym: what issue would it take for us to try to make this happen?
Rym: Is that I'm not I knew it over what's going on.
Scott: I saw him.
Scott: Someone has to be the first guy.
Scott: Are you not going to go to work tomorrow?
Scott: If it would work, would you be the guy to start it, not go to work tomorrow?
Rym: Over what?
Rym: Over this stuff?
Scott: Hell no.
Scott: All right.
Scott: And also not go to work the next day.
Rym: Over what's going on now now.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: OK, so there you go.
Scott: I asked my co-workers, I said, would anyone here not go to work?
Scott: They said, no, we're going to work.
Rym: For me, it would take it would have to be First Amendment losses.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But no.
Scott: What if there was you want to do a positive change?
Scott: Like you could demand something and get your demand.
Scott: The thing is, I would need like imagine if we could like demand single payer real health care for reals, not just Obamacare.
Scott: We would get it if you just, you know, went on strike.
Scott: You know, you need.
Rym: you need almost a Kickstarter for this.
Rym: You need the week.
Rym: We should we call it first follower.
Rym: Here's how it works.
Rym: You make a cause.
Rym: But and you all sort of sign a contract like I will strike if we reach the threshold.
Scott: But nobody will.
Scott: People sign it and they won't do it.
Rym: Well, you may you make the site kind of set up as a contract with real verified contact info, a contract that you physically sign.
Scott: And what if they don't show up?
Scott: What happens to?
Scott: what's the penalty for not showing up?
Rym: I know a breach of contract.
Scott: So I'm going to go around and sue all these individual people who said that they would stop working, went to work.
Rym: That'd be a pretty good business model.
Rym: Sue them for damages to my cause.
Scott: I don't know if you'd get away with that.
Rym: You might be able to.
Scott: Unlikely.
Rym: Or in the very least, a site like that.
Rym: It's just that you need enough people to do it at once.
Rym: So it's not just the one lone wacko who loses his job and then no one cares because he can't afford to still be on the Internet talking about it.
Rym: You need enough people to go at once and you need some modicum of assurance that if you do it, all these people do it together.
Rym: Like the first 10,000 people have to all do it together and make a big media shitstorm like the first 10,000 all go to D.C.
Rym: and go and say none of us are working.
Rym: We all left our jobs, drove here and are staying here.
Scott: It's sort of a catch-22, right?
Scott: It's like nobody will go to those lengths as long as they still have bread and circuses.
Scott: Because for all the shit that goes down in this country, it's like life is really great.
Scott: Everyday life for most of the people is pretty terrific.
Rym: Also, the people where life isn't so great.
Scott: What you risk, if your life's not so great, what you risk by doing something like this is losing the last that you have and having nothing.
Scott: Yep, exactly.
Rym: It's hard to ask someone to risk.
Scott: Unless there is already that harm to you, you're not going to get up and do something that's going to cause harm to you on purpose.
Scott: But at the same time, it feeds into itself.
Scott: The strike itself is the thing that would cause harm to people such that they would get upset and strike.
Scott: The spark itself is the thing that can be caused by and result in the thing that needs to be done to bring about the change.
Scott: So you have a chicken and egg, there's no way to make a chicken or an egg.
Rym: I'm hereby striking on GeekNights until I get some food.
Scott: Sounds good.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.