Rym: It's Wednesday, July 3rd, 2013, I'm Rym, I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, those quiet badasses.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Well, I guess they're not all quiet, but they're all badasses.
Rym: But I got another biking story.
Rym: I guess GeekNights has the, we don't have the opening bit anymore, we just have the "So I was biking home from work" bit.
Scott: Hey, you know what my bit is?
Scott: I said I wasn't able to bike pretty much fucking all week with this rain.
Rym: I biked to work almost every day because I'm not a pansy.
Scott: I had, you know, the different nights I had stuff to do, every night.
Scott: it was just, the rain was not on my schedule.
Rym: Yeah, well I got to admit, I biked to work this morning, but it just started to rain like right as I got to the office, and then it was fine when I left.
Scott: I used an umbrella to walk to the subway.
Rym: Yeah, I'm biking over to the Pulaski, coming home, doing my thing, and there's this big dude who's kind of chubby and kind of angry looking, just kind of walking forward, blocking the whole bike path, the whole pedestrian way, so I can't get around him.
Rym: He's walking super slow right in the middle.
Rym: So I'm like, "Excuse
Rym: me?".
Rym: You know, I'm real polite and he doesn't respond, so I ding my bell.
Rym: He turns around, he's like, "Slow the fuck down, fucking
Rym: biker!".
Rym: He's just really mad at me.
Rym: So I scoot around him and I start to bike away, and he starts chasing, like, "Come back here
Rym: you!".
Rym: And I flipped him off, and then I heard him yell even more, and he got so mad, and I just biked away, because chubby, angry guy's not going to do much.
Scott: What's he going to do?
Rym: I guess he would try to hit me if he got close enough to me.
Scott: Listen, if he can chase me down while I'm riding my bike, my hat is off to you, good sir.
Scott: On foot?
Scott: In a friggin' all race, fucking Usain Bolt on my bike.
Rym: I did, as a kid, someone stole my bike.
Rym: I was in, like, middle school.
Scott: Usain Bolt's on foot, by the way.
Rym: I was in middle school, and I parked my bike, and I walked over to fuck around with this tree ford, and this bully kid, I hear a noise, and I look, and he's standing next to my bike, and he's getting on it and going to ride off with it.
Rym: I don't think he realized I was right there, up in the tree, watching him.
Rym: So I jump down, and I start chasing, and he sees me and tries to bike away.
Rym: Doesn't know how gears work.
Rym: So I ran up behind him, and I grabbed his shirt, and I pulled on it, and it didn't pull him over, but it ripped his shirt basically off and ruined it.
Rym: And then he turns around like he's gonna fight with me, and he gets off the bike, and bully kids tend to be big and slow.
Rym: So I ran around him, got on the bike, and then I just biked away, and I left him there with his broken shirt.
Rym: There's nothing else happened there.
Rym: That was the story.
Scott: If someone's on a bike, running away, what you want to do is run up and give them a good ol' check.
Scott: They play shoulder ram right in the side.
Rym: Boom!
Rym: I'm pretty sure I could chase down most people who weren't good bikers if they tried to get away from me on a bike.
Rym: My bike or someone else's bike.
Scott: It's like if they pick up the bike and it's in high gear, they don't know how to shift down.
Scott: That's actually when I...
Rym: 'Cause sometimes I'll leave my bike outside the store, 'cause I'm gonna go in, get some ice cream, and then come right back out.
Rym: I can see it in the window.
Rym: I just put it in the highest gear, because the majority of bike thieves would not be able to get away in time.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, unless they toss it in the back of a truck, they're gonna get on and go, "Nyeh," and I'm gonna see them and easily be able to catch up and slam right into the street.
Scott: Yeah, whatever.
Rym: So, I was gonna link to this on the Anime News Network, but their DNS stopped working literally as we started to do GeekNights, so I can't actually visit their link.
Scott: Well, their loss is their loss.
Rym: However, the site I found is pretty cool.
Rym: It's all Sailor Moon-y.
Rym: So, the person who created Sailor Moon, Naoko Takeuchi, hasn't done an interview in over a decade.
Scott: Have they done anything besides?
Scott: make Sailor Moon?
Rym: I don't actually know.
Rym: Sailor Moon is the only thing of hers that I know about.
Scott: It's the manga creator, right?
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I'll be honest, I don't really know anything about her other than Sailor Moon.
Scott: Are you the Sailor Moon fucking expert?
Rym: No, I just happen to have seen all of Sailor Moon.
Rym: If you have seen all of anything, you can speak to it.
Rym: You can probably say things that make you sound like an expert about Hokkaido Ken to someone who's never seen it.
Rym: But regardless, I learned from Wikipedia that she's a licensed pharmacist, and her senior thesis had the title "Heightened Effects of Thrombolytic Actions Due to
Rym: Ultrasound.".
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Anyway, she has not done an interview in 11 years.
Scott: But she's still been making manga?
Rym: She's made some stuff, doesn't look like much of it's that recent.
Rym: There's something called Tokimeka from 2006.
Scott: Is she just raking in Sailor Moon money and pharmacy money and not working?
Rym: In 2002 she did Love Witch, story of a girl receives a perfume bottle and becomes a witch, but it carries a heavy price.
Scott: Sounds fancy-lala-ish to me.
Rym: Discontinued after three chapters with no explanation.
Scott: Oh, because it wasn't because it was bad?
Rym: It was just- Has yet to be reprinted in any form.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Let's find it on the internet.
Rym: Yeah, I kind of want to read that now.
Rym: But one, you should check this interview out because Sailor Moon, like it or not, seen it or not, is a pretty important anime in terms of the history of anime.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: And two, if you've seen the anime, especially if you've just seen what was on American TV, you've never read the manga, go find some of the Sailor Moon manga and just read a little bit of it.
Rym: Just check that out.
Rym: It's more like Green Lantern than you would expect.
Rym: And it mostly involves space drama.
Rym: But yeah, that's all I got here.
Rym: I would say more, but again, the Anime News Network's DNS stopped working.
Rym: Oh, but the news is that she gave an interview for the first- The news that she gave and interview, the first one in supposedly 11 years.
Scott: What does it say in that interview?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I can't read the whole thing.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: I gotta search around for another site that has the interview.
Scott: Okay, so in real news, it's more important.
Scott: You know, I buy a lot of comic books every month and it's pretty great because I get a huge discount because pre-ordering, but it's pretty sucky because my house fills up with comic books.
Scott: I would much rather have digital comic books.
Scott: However, there are problems with digital comic books, unlike other forms of art and mediums such as anime or JPEGs or whatnot.
Scott: Comics do not translate perfectly to digitalness.
Rym: No they don't.
Scott: They do not.
Rym: Someday we'll have that technology.
Scott: A lot of these comic readers get like zoom in on a panel.
Scott: It's like, nope.
Scott: Or the ones it's like, oh, one page at a time.
Scott: It's like two page spread.
Rym: I know what the perfect interface is.
Rym: It's trivial.
Rym: Magic paper.
Rym: Hologram.
Rym: No, no magic paper.
Rym: No.
Rym: Overlay glasses and it just holds a perfect comic book in front of your face.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: But anyway, the main reason I don't buy digital comics is because, you know, the only ones that are really like pirated.
Scott: You can go online and there's torrents fucking every week, like every DC comment that came out this week, every Marvel comment that came out this week.
Scott: But I don't want to read that shit.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I want to read all this other weird stuff that doesn't really get torrented, pirated as much.
Scott: It's not as easy to find because, you know, no one's really buying it.
Scott: Like who's buying and scanning, for example, you know, complete Prince Valiant hardcovers that are dragging nobody.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So I had to buy it.
Rym: But so you would you only buy stuff because you can't pirate it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: OK.
Scott: Anyway, if it was digital and a reasonable price, I would pay for it like steam anyway.
Scott: So there are digital comics and most of them run comiXology and such.
Scott: But I don't like that shit because DRM.
Scott: Same reason I don't buy no Kindle books.
Scott: Right.
Scott: DRM's.
Scott: Don't tell me steam has DRM's.
Scott: Steam is a dollar.
Scott: ComiXology.
Scott: They're charging you the same price as the physical comics.
Scott: Go fuck your mother.
Scott: Even if there's no DRM, I'm not paying that price for a digital comic.
Scott: Go to hell.
Rym: Oh, wow.
Rym: Seventy bucks is the cheapest I can find.
Rym: One of the Prince Valiant's.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: This is why preorder comics at a discount.
Scott: I bought it at thirty five percent off retail and I have all of them so far.
Scott: So take that.
Rym: Oh, here's a someone some guys selling for one hundred and twenty eight that hasn't been opened or read yet.
Scott: Mine's been opened in red anyway, anyway, anyway.
Scott: So there are sites that do DRM free digital comics.
Scott: We just get PDFs and such.
Scott: I think it's like my digital comics dot.
Scott: com.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But nobody really goes to those sites because they really only have, you know, sort of more obscure indie comics from publishers.
Scott: No one really cares about like, you know, you know, there's indie comics that are the ones that are like, you know, they're hot indie comics, like maybe from a publisher, like Top Shelf or Fanta Graphics.
Scott: And then there's those indie comics that's like, oh, it's just that generic stuff that fills the shelves of the comic book store, like vampire something or zombie and girl with boobs and guns or shit like that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That's the kind of stuff you're going to find on my digital comics dot.
Scott: com.
Scott: Well, big news.
Scott: Image comics redid their website to be less sucky because, you know, comic publishers usually don't have good websites.
Scott: And part of that is they put DRM free comics for sale directly on their website in PDF, EPUB, CBR or CBZ.
Scott: So any format you want.
Scott: Not bad problem pricing.
Scott: Still not so good.
Scott: Oh, how bad?
Scott: Well, it's not as bad, really.
Scott: It's pretty much like old comics are like a dollar each and brand new ones are the same price as the print.
Scott: So still not buying it.
Scott: But that's a major publisher.
Scott: Images number three.
Scott: And in fact, I see myself on my order forms ordering more image comics.
Scott: I mean, fucking saga, right?
Scott: That's fucking image.
Rym: Oh, my God.
Rym: I need to read the next trade of saga.
Scott: I read it.
Scott: I have not yet.
Scott: I own it.
Scott: I need to borrow.
Scott: that lives up to the hype.
Rym: Of course it does.
Scott: It's no joke.
Rym: I can see in my Twitter feed as the issues come out, because it's good enough to where a lot of people I know who otherwise are trades only end up getting issues anyway.
Scott: You can pay for these digital issues every freaking month.
Rym: No, I'm just going to read the trades that you buy.
Rym: See, I don't pirate anything.
Rym: I just borrow your comics.
Scott: That's a good deal.
Rym: Scott's library is open for business, but yeah, that Sailor Moon interview did not happen yet.
Rym: Oh, it will be available on August 1st.
Scott: Mm.
Scott: Interesting.
Scott: Did the interview happen?
Scott: Is it not published or the interview didn't happen?
Rym: It's going to be published in a women's fashion magazine, Rolla.
Scott: Interesting.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Maybe she's working on some Sailor Moon fashions.
Scott: Uh, so yeah, image is now making DRM free comics.
Scott: So if you're into the digital comics like, uh, I'm not, and you're willing to pay the cover price or slightly less than government price for old stuff, then you don't want to pirate you because image comics are probably easily parable.
Scott: You can go to image comics is official website and buy DRM free comics.
Scott: This is a big deal.
Scott: Uh, hopefully like the whole comics industry can sort of do stuff like this and really put the pressure on Marvel and DC to get one.
Rym: Because if the, even if, if the prices don't change just as long as it's all available digital for at least no more than the physical copy, I think that'll cause a big seismic shift culturally.
Scott: I think really what they need to do is it's good to sell it on their website.
Scott: Obviously that's good for them because they get all the money from sales, right?
Scott: But what they should also do is if it's DRM free, it's like also sell it on Amazon.
Scott: Also sell it on Apple.
Rym: All here's the trouble for the business model where they have, instead of having 4,000 people reading a comic, they have 1000 people who buy each of the four alternate covers.
Rym: Hmm.
Scott: So it'll actually cut down on their, I mean, if there's digital copies, the nerds, but they save money, I'm not paying to print the paper, even though that isn't a good, the significant cost, the significant cost is paying artists to make the comics, right?
Rym: So what they should do is sell it digitally for price X and then only print like 500 copies or a hundred copies of each alternate cover and sell those for like 40 bucks.
Scott: Here's what they should do.
Rym: So double down on that.
Scott: Image comics should just be like, look, you pay us 25 bucks a month or a hundred a year, some price like that.
Scott: The kind of prices that make you go, Ooh, right with the small annual fee like flicker or the small monthly fee like Spotify or something.
Scott: And you just fricking get every image comic, no matter what.
Scott: And as they just had to, then they just had to make enough image comics that are good enough to get you to do that.
Rym: There is a trouble with that model that from everything I've read, Spotify basically pays out rounding down to zero to pretty much everyone.
Scott: Let's talk about that a little bit before we get off, you know, even though it's a tangent.
Rym: I mean, they were getting back into an issue that has not had new discussions since 1994.
Rym: Right.
Scott: It is true.
Scott: But there was one point someone made recently that I did not think of.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And they were talking about how Pandora basically pays.
Scott: almost some guy, I think he's a songwriter was like, I get basically get nothing when my song is played on Pandora, but it's a huge hit.
Scott: It's been played millions of times and I got almost nothing.
Scott: I'm curious if you're going to say what I was about to say probably, but basically number one is that Pandora actually paid out a lot more than what he got.
Scott: All these other people took a cut, right?
Scott: The record company, the other people who played the music, the et cetera, et cetera.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But the real reason, uh, is that he didn't get as much money as say a play on the radio is that he was, these people were comparing the one radio play to the one Spotify play or the one Pandora play.
Scott: It's like one Pandora play is heard by one person.
Scott: One radio play is heard by more than one person.
Rym: One radio play is heard by one old person.
Scott: I know.
Scott: I'm just saying theoretically.
Scott: more than one person hears the one radio play.
Scott: So a one radio play is worth multiple times as much money as a Spotify play, which is one person playing the song one time, which really has almost no value.
Scott: If you consider that paying a dollar to iTunes for a song is infinite plays of a song, what is?
Scott: one play of the song costs almost nothing, right?
Scott: Even at the $1 overpriced iTunes price.
Scott: So they're actually getting pretty good money from a Spotify iTunes.
Scott: So what is one read of a comic worth to what?
Scott: Right.
Scott: Not much, you know, definitely not $4 that they charge at the comic book store.
Scott: That's for sure.
Scott: Dollar at most.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But at the same time, it depends that the more niche your comic is, the fewer people are interested in it, but it doesn't really get cheaper to make it.
Scott: Hey, listen.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's the world we live in.
Rym: Deal with it.
Rym: This is the hand we're given.
Scott: I think, you know, Image could also companies, these comic companies could also do much better to drop a lot of the shitty fucking comics.
Scott: Like what good comics does Image have?
Scott: Walking Dead and Chew and Saga.
Scott: What else they got?
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, why are you even publishing all that garbage?
Scott: It's like, yeah, give new stuff a shot.
Scott: But if it doesn't work, it's like, yeah, you got five issues.
Scott: Then you're out of here.
Scott: If it's not as big as Mouse Guard, fuck it.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So Collectivet is a, appears to be a Norwegian comedy group, and they do funny songs and other things.
Rym: And Emily found this for me.
Rym: They have this funny song, it's in English, where they go through the idea that bigger is better and size matters.
Scott: So the United States- Making fun of the big fat US.
Rym: So the United States wins at everything.
Rym: We have the biggest amusement parks, the biggest people, aka they're fat.
Scott: They're like- Biggest cars.
Rym: You're so fat, you're so big, you're dying of it.
Rym: We can't compete with that.
Scott: Biggest hats.
Rym: But they point out the one area where Norway wins.
Rym: They have a bigger alphabet than we do because they've got the I-O-O.
Rym: The A-E that are stuck together, the O with the line through it, and the A with a funny little circle on top.
Scott: They don't have anything with two dots on it?
Rym: Well, those are accents as opposed to letters.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: There's a difference between a letter that has an accent like an E with an accente gear, or accent circumflex, or accent grave, or a C-C-D, and an actually different letter, even though that is an entirely arbitrary distinction.
Rym: Their alphabet has I-O-O in it.
Scott: Where do they put the I-O-O?
Scott: Is it A-I-O-O?
Rym: I'm going to find out right now.
Rym: Google Images.
Scott: How do they sing the alphabet song?
Rym: I'm going to find out, Norway.
Scott: While you do that, I'm going to do my thing of the day.
Scott: So, when I was a baby, as in zero, in the womb of my mom.
Rym: In Queens.
Scott: In, yeah.
Scott: She would be sitting around, all pregnant and shit, and what would she do?
Rym: Play the Atari 2600.
Scott: With?
Scott: What game?
Scott: What was my mom's favorite game?
Scott: Super Breakout.
Scott: Super Breakout was my mom's game.
Scott: She still loves that fucking game.
Rym: You know, it's funny because my mom has the same story.
Rym: Maybe that's why- But your mom didn't play Super Breakout.
Scott: She played other games.
Rym: She played regular Breakout, she liked it more, and a bunch of other games, but did your mom do the same thing?
Rym: When my mom was super pregnant, it was hard to lean over and hit the reset button, so she liked the 2600 because she'd reach over with her toe and tap the reset button.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Ask her.
Scott: Anyway, she played on a tiny black and white TV.
Scott: But anyway, yeah, Super Breakout.
Scott: So, I played Super Breakout since before I was born.
Scott: That's how good I am.
Scott: So, you think, I've seen pretty much every Breakout.
Scott: there's been for as long as Breakouts existed.
Scott: There has not been a Breakout that has escaped me.
Scott: Here is one that was totally new and amazing.
Scott: This is Brick Smash, Brick Smash, Brick, Brick Smash, Brick, whatever, by Alan Hazelden, the creator of this.
Scott: My hat is off to you.
Scott: It's a tiny flash game, and basically you play Breakout, and in each of the bricks and the Breakout, there is another game of Breakout.
Scott: It is Brickception.
Scott: It's incredible.
Scott: Yo, dawg, Breakout.
Scott: You have to play this.
Scott: I won on my first try.
Scott: Rym did, and I'm better than Rym.
Rym: Okay, so if you look for the Norwegian alphabet song, you just keep finding this comedy video that I'm linking to.
Rym: But their alphabet, a, u, o, are in order at the end.
Scott: Oh, so it's just z, a, u, o. Okay.
Rym: So, they just added them at the end there.
Rym: They also have accents.
Rym: They have an accent, a, u, the up line, the down line, the hat.
Rym: That's it.
Scott: Do they have the two dots?
Rym: No.
Rym: They do not have the two dots.
Scott: You gotta have the two dots.
Rym: Why?
Rym: What are the good of the two dots?
Rym: Do you even know what the two dots do?
Rym: So, in the meta moment, the book club book is Stasi-land, true narrative stories of the bullshit people went through living in East Germany under the Stasi during the Cold War.
Rym: It's kind of relevant with all the NSA stuff going on.
Scott: The next book club book is going to be Gideon's Bible.
Rym: Then the next book club book is going to be Ulysses or Norwich's history of the Byzantine empire.
Scott: And the one after that will be Dead Sea Scrolls, the real edition.
Rym: I'm going with Webster's.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: No, the OED because it's longer.
Scott: The complete works of Dostoevsky in Russian.
Rym: The first story, once it gets past kind of the intro, is pretty good.
Rym: And it's about this 16 year old girl who actually tried to go over the wall because she got arrested and held in solitary confinement and was tortured.
Scott: How was that barbed wire?
Rym: She got over the barbed wire okay.
Scott: Nice.
Rym: She got past the dogs too.
Rym: And the Stasi, it's interesting because people have this impression in the West that the Stasi were this like almost Nazi-esque level of control.
Rym: And that's kind of true.
Rym: But at the same time, a lot of what they would do was so utterly and patently ridiculous, but yet they would do it seriously and with a straight face.
Rym: It's a weird part of world history that I don't think enough people know about.
Rym: And the more I'm reading this book, the weirder it is.
Scott: Yet another group that had really great fashion sense that you can't use anymore.
Rym: The Nazis.
Scott: And the Stasi.
Scott: The Stasi too.
Scott: They had those awesome leather coats with the...
Rym: There's something about that sharp look.
Rym: Why can't we have scientific fascism?
Scott: What do you mean?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: All the trappings of fascism, but with the goal of making awesome science, making everything great for everyone.
Scott: So we can wear evil looking coats, but they have no swastikas or anything on them.
Scott: People know that we're good.
Scott: We just really like, we just respect good fashion.
Scott: We should call it.
Scott: And then we're going to call ourselves the grand dragons and be like, look, we fucking hate the KKK, those assholes, but they took all the good names.
Scott: We're going to be there.
Scott: No, it doesn't work.
Scott: We can't take it back.
Scott: The fashion and the names, I've let them go long ago.
Scott: I just like to complain about it every once in a while, but I've given up.
Scott: There is no way to take those awesome fashions or awesome names back without bringing also the evil.
Rym: I mean, even the Charlie Chaplin mustache has been destroyed by all this.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: Other metas.
Rym: ConnectiCon.
Scott: It's like fucking tomorrow.
Scott: Next.
Rym: God damn.
Rym: Well, the schedule of the panels that we are running ourselves, I don't even know what those are.
Rym: I got to go look them up because I forget.
Scott: Great.
Rym: Uh, yeah.
Rym: ConnectiCon is going to be awesome.
Rym: And then Scott and I are immediately flying to Australia to present beyond judges and dragons in the Wombat theater.
Rym: 1 p.m.
Rym: on Friday in Melbourne, Melbourne, Melbourne, Australia.
Scott: Just if you want to pronounce Melbourne correctly, Melbourne, imagine it's M E L B I N. Melbourne.
Rym: Forget that R. Forget the O U. Melbourne.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Melbourne.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Um, we got to plan the rest of this trip.
Scott: Yeah, it's fine.
Rym: So far.
Rym: I've not planned beyond, beyond dungeons and dragons.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: You know, if we just get there and ask natives, like what's the awesomest thing, you know, we'll end up doing the good stuff.
Rym: What a plan ahead a little bit.
Rym: I kind of want to do those go-karts.
Rym: I got to trick someone in Melbourne.
Scott: Uh, organizing it.
Rym: To organize it.
Scott: So we needed to show other people to do it.
Scott: We can't just make it happen on our own.
Rym: We can do it Sunday after packs.
Rym: I think we could get enough people from packs.
Rym: Maybe our first packs in the U S. we trivially formed what can only be described as a mob by snapping our fingers and saying, moonblazing, burning whale, signed up in advance and shit.
Rym: Anyway, I'll figure it out.
Scott: Um, any other meta moments you should, while we're away and we're not going to be making a lot of stuff for you, pretty much the rest of July after next week or so is going to be like nothing, uh, in terms of GeekNights.
Scott: So you're going to want to go to our YouTubes and other such and follow us on the internet and the Twitters and all those places, because that's the only place is going to be content because that's the only place we can post things while we're on the go, like Lord of the rings on the go.
Scott: So you're going to watch our flicker, see some photos from Australia and kinetic con and all that kind of stuff.
Scott: So make sure you follow GeekNights and me and Rym at all the internet places, the Google pluses, the Facebooks, not only that.
Rym: you want us to do GeekNights, presents you 10 faster.
Rym: You want us to ever make another radio for Equestria.
Rym: You want the four other, well, I guess five other lectures, man in Boston, rerecorded.
Rym: Uh, I'm taking my sweet ass time.
Rym: unless you guys do what you did with our, uh, judge anime by its cover and get the views up.
Scott: If you get like three or four videos up, so now you have to do another one.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Get more views up the more views up, look, they put the views up and what happened?
Rym: I almost immediately released on other GeekNights presents.
Rym: In fact, I ordered new lights that we're going to use right after packs.
Rym: Awesome.
Rym: Ooh.
Scott: Ooh.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So meta moments over.
Scott: It is time for the episode.
Rym: So I realized we realized we were talking about anime and we, we kind of, there's that, there's a certain kind of character that everybody loves and whenever there's a show that has a character like that, it's always the like unstated, obviously the best character.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: But in this particular way, it's the Hughes in the full metal alchemist.
Scott: Usually this character is usually a dude, but not always usually old, but not always.
Rym: I think already there's a distinct separation of two kinds of the anime bad-ass kind.
Rym: Number one, the old master, the old invincible sensei, right?
Scott: It's like the main character, you know, is leveling up in an anime, getting more powerful.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But how can the main character learn anything?
Scott: If they're the most powerful, there is someone who is so ridiculously powerful, but doesn't use it.
Scott: Just like in the Simpsons episode, the guy in the white suit who stands still and doesn't do anything when he does something, holy crap, it's going to be the best, right?
Scott: For example, in Kill Bill 2, Pi Mei is the bad-ass, right?
Scott: You know, he's so much stronger than everyone else, but he just started chills out and doesn't use his full power.
Scott: That's the guy, you know, in Initial D, crazy Bunta, right?
Scott: He's not in the races.
Scott: You just know he could win every race with like his eyes closed because he's that much better, but he stays in the sidelines and watches.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: Now these guys, we were trying to think of all the examples of that kind of guy and they're all really, really similar, at least in a superficial two minute conversation.
Rym: because the first people we thought of, let's see if there's Bunta, there's Aramaki in Ghost in the Shell.
Rym: Who's, especially now we're going to see him younger with brown hair, like it's not fully clowned out yet, not Wilead all the way.
Rym: There's Fujisawa Sensei in El Hazard and notice how they all will often have sort of a smoking or drinking or some sort of like thing.
Rym: that's up with them.
Rym: Like they're not 100% the best people or they have some sort of flaw or past.
Rym: that's dark, but that's not the story.
Scott: Who's the guy in Naruto who's always reading, the teacher who's reading the porn magazines all the time.
Scott: I always forget his name.
Rym: Forget his name too because Naruto stopped being good after 3.5 episodes.
Scott: Let me look at list of Naruto characters on the Internet.
Rym: Plus I don't think he is the invincible sensei anymore, but he did serve that purpose in that part of the show, though he was too young to hold it off in the long run.
Scott: I think it's Kakashi.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: That's definitely him.
Rym: Wow, all the young anime fans listening to GeekNights are like, "How do you not
Rym: know?"
Rym: Right?
Scott: In one piece, it's Red Shanks, right?
Scott: Red Shanks, the guy you hardly ever see.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: Because he's in the beginning, he's the badass, loses his arm.
Rym: Spoilers.
Rym: But then there's the other kind of badass, the young, not invincible guy, who is the badass and seems to often get killed in a pivotal plot point because they're not the main character, they're not a villain, but they're the badass that makes the impossible possible.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: The Moolaflaga, the Hughes, the Fokker, in fact, I think all three of them serve basically the same purpose in their three respective shows.
Scott: But even those guys are sort of like incredibly powerful, older than main character, sensei-ish mentor figures, right?
Scott: They just sort of are more active than, say, a bunta on the sidelines.
Rym: Well, I think with them, it's really that they're the characters that the show starts and they're already way leveled up and almost no one else around them is.
Rym: They're the only ones who can pull shit off, they're the only competent ones, they're the only cool ones, and they're not on screen that often.
Rym: I think that's the key.
Rym: It's the same thing with King Cosma in Summer Wars.
Rym: It's the character where people watch a show and they think back and it's like, "Who's your favorite
Rym: character?"
Rym: With 90% of people like King Cosma.
Scott: Yeah, duh.
Rym: Mula Flaga, Hughes.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, it's someone that is showing you what the future can be like, right?
Scott: Like, you play Mega Man X and at the beginning of Mega Man X, it's just like this equalitis video.
Scott: Mega Man X is kind of weak ass, he just woke up from his friggin' stasis, whatever, but you know what?
Scott: Zero's out there.
Scott: Total badass, already leveled up, and then it's eventually you get the main guy, Mega Man X, eventually is better than Zero, but not right away.
Scott: It's showing you the future, right?
Scott: It's like, "Oh yeah, Mula Flaga at the beginning is, yeah, the competent pilot, and you know what?
Scott: These kids are just some fucking kids at the beginning of Gundam Seed.
Scott: You know at the end of Gundam Seed?
Scott: Those kids are now the really powerful people, and Mula Flaga's still pretty good, but basically they leveled up to his level, but he was so high level, he really only gained one level over the show because he needs so much XP to get one
Scott: more.".
Rym: I don't think anyone ever gets better than Punta.
Scott: I don't think ever, no.
Scott: I haven't read enough Initial D, but I don't think so.
Scott: I think Punta pretty much stays at the most powerful.
Rym: So why do we like these characters?
Rym: Why do they stand out so much to us in particular?
Rym: I don't know if it's universal that other people think about this or are obsessed with these characters.
Rym: It might just be us.
Rym: I mean, when normal people talk about Ghost in the Shell, they're like, "Oh, the major, the best," or "Bato, hey," but we're just always Aromaki.
Rym: Is it because we're getting old?
Scott: Well, you know, I don't dislike those other characters.
Scott: In fact, I think I like Togusa the most in Ghost in the Shell, but Aromaki is still the baddest ass.
Scott: You know, Togus is not exactly a bad ass, he's just sort of, you know, cool, whatever.
Scott: But yeah, why do we like these bad ass characters?
Scott: Well, I think it's because number one, right?
Scott: These characters are super powerful, but they're not super powerful in like an evil boss kind of way.
Scott: or we're just going to make the show boring and use my superpowers to end the conflicts kind of way, right?
Scott: Is they're super powerful in sort of a funny way and it sort of creates this contrast of, you know, like you want to see them in action so bad, like this hidden mystery power.
Rym: Well, like Fujisawa, when he learns his kick and his punch and he's just, he's such a bad ass, but he's also such a moron at times, but he's not a complete moron.
Rym: But yet, this is distinct from Captain Tyler, let's say, where he is the plot, he is the main character.
Rym: It always feels like cheating where your favorite character is the main character.
Rym: I mean, if your favorite character in Hooka Nona Ken is Ken Shiro, that feels really obvious or cheap.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: It's okay.
Rym: And I think there's a lot of anime fans, because I know a bunch of people we knew at RIT would do this.
Rym: They kind of like to like the obscure character that no one else likes.
Scott: Well, I think the thing is in animes in particular, and a lot of stories, main characters have to be appealing to everybody, to a wide audience.
Scott: So they're very generic, they're not, you know, the kind of thing that would appeal to only one person.
Scott: So like in a harem show, right, let's say it's a girl harem, there's one girl and a whole bunch of dudes in this harem, it's a dude harem, whatever you want to call it.
Scott: But a lot of dudes, one girl.
Scott: That girl isn't going to have a lot of character to her usually, it's going to be someone that every girl can identify with in some way.
Scott: And then all it's sort of like a harem combined and merged into one person.
Scott: Whereas the harem itself is a bunch of separate individuals that are all really specific and everyone's going to like one of them or maybe two of them, right, that are going to be sort of the ones, you know, and then there might be one in the harem that has a wider appeal than that's the one that you're actually going to get together with in the story at some point, right?
Rym: I think there's some characters that sort of fall between, like they're not like they serve that purpose in the beginning, but don't later.
Rym: Like Toga in Utena actually, in the beginning of the show, he seems like the only one who's got it together and he knows more, he's secret, he's mysterious, he's badass, but then you learn about other people who know way more.
Scott: Yeah, well, I mean, that's an interesting, that's what makes Utena really good, but it's also something that, you know, where they made a use out of that character instead of just having them there to be a character that people like to set a contrast, to help the main character by giving them advice and stuff like that.
Scott: They actually brought them into the plot and made a use out of them without them overpowering everything.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And in Toga's case, it's like, yeah, he wasn't as bad as you thought, right?
Scott: Bunta, if they would have brought Bunta into things, you know, and made him race or something, it's like, well, that sort of ruins everything, right?
Scott: Because he can't lose, you know, there's not going to be any drama there if that happens, right?
Scott: They would have had to bring Bunta down to give you doubt about Bunta's power.
Scott: And you can't do that, that every, every race, it's the key, he's not going to win this time.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The other ability, the other possibility to bring everyone else up to Bunta's level, which is like, hell no, that's not going to happen.
Scott: That's Dragon Ball.
Scott: Maybe you can have Bunta versus Michael Schumacher.
Rym: That might work.
Scott: But otherwise, no, you know, but it's like some animes.
Scott: it's or mangas.
Scott: It's hard to figure out.
Scott: Is there such a character?
Rym: or most shows do not have these characters.
Rym: I've realized as an aside, I was looking for just like a giant list of anime that were popular like top hundred list to scroll through just to kind of remind myself of, oh yeah.
Rym: And that show, there was that guy.
Rym: So my only point is this pretty much every top X anime list on the internet is ridiculously bullshit.
Scott: No credit.
Rym: Here's, here's one that's actually pretty popular.
Rym: Fullmetal Alchemist is number two of all time.
Rym: Alpha leaves.
Rym: Number six.
Rym: Whoa.
Rym: What?
Rym: Cowboy Bebop's number five.
Scott: Why is it not number one?
Rym: I was 37, but Naruto's at 35.
Scott: So copy of up and I was among the two great shows that do not have such a character.
Rym: Most shows don't have these characters.
Rym: Escaflowne almost had one, Alan Chazar, but he's basically a toga.
Scott: He's not yet.
Scott: He's not strong enough to be that guy.
Scott: The main character is actually the most powerful in that show and doesn't really have mentor action going on.
Rym: You don't have the awesome side character except for you have the old instructor in the beginning, but he dies.
Scott: He's not, he's not an awesome, whatever.
Scott: And even jelly and you can have someone, what's his name?
Scott: Kaji.
Rym: He's sort of the, well, Kaji is the Hughes.
Scott: Yeah, exactly.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Again, look at the pattern.
Rym: The characters that are the younger stereotype of the bad-ass or at least the favorite side character or all the certain way.
Rym: And then the old ones are another certain way that, but there isn't an old one in Evangelion.
Rym: There's just the Hughes.
Scott: Well, like in star Wars, it's Yoda or Boba Fett or both of us.
Scott: The bad one.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But at the same time, you know, we said it had to be on the good guy side.
Rym: Is that really true?
Rym: Because star Wars, maybe this explains this thing we're talking about why Boba Fett appears briefly in star Wars.
Rym: He is barely part of star Wars at all.
Rym: And yet when I was a kid and I saw star Wars for the first time, my friends all saw star Wars.
Rym: Boba Fett was all.
Rym: anyone could fucking talk about Boba Fett, but everyone was obsessed with Boba Fett.
Rym: No matter how sure I am, I never risked the Fett.
Scott: Boba Fett never risked the Fett man.
Rym: So I think it's the same thing.
Rym: There's something about that secondary badass character.
Rym: And if I had to guess psychologically, I think it really just comes down to the mystery that you don't know their full deal.
Rym: So you can kind of fill in way more than you can with even a main character.
Rym: Cause even in a harem show, a main character has some kind of plot and there's some sort of framework, but Boba Fett, you look at both and you're like, what's that guy's deal?
Rym: I don't know, but he's a bad ass and you don't see him lose until you see him lose.
Scott: I think, Oh, you know who has another perfect example of this character in Hajime no Ippo, right?
Scott: There's a what's his name?
Rym: Oh, the fricking, uh, I have not seen a lot of that show.
Scott: Takamura who's basically like the, the world champion guy.
Scott: He's just incredibly, ridiculously powerful.
Scott: He punches the bear.
Rym: Oh, the bear punching guy.
Rym: I know who that is.
Scott: He's basically, that is like the perfect example of ridiculously powerful, you know, best character guy.
Scott: You know, he's sort of a mix between Bunta and, um, from sanctuary, Mr.
Scott: Um, Tokai, yes.
Scott: Sort of a combination of those two.
Rym: Sanctuary is a problem because everyone is that guy.
Rym: If you ignore the main characters, everyone is that guy.
Rym: And the main characters are just better than them.
Rym: The end, the good guys are that way.
Rym: The bad guys are that way.
Rym: Every character is that way.
Rym: Every side character is that way, except for background, normal people, maybe that's why I like sanctuary so much.
Rym: sanctuary is just nothing but Boba Fett.
Scott: It's written by the same.
Rym: It's Boba Fett and Boba Fett fighting against Boba Fett.
Rym: That's what that manga is.
Scott: I mean, it's written by the same guys who wrote Fist of the North Star, right?
Scott: Which has the same situation where everyone is a total badass.
Rym: It's all about Bronson.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Anyway, uh, do you have anything else to say about this?
Rym: Well, I'm going through anime that I have watched and they're not that common either.
Rym: The more I really think about it, I mean, like Cowboy Bebop does not have a character like that.
Rym: Really?
Scott: Nope.
Scott: What the native American guy?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But he's not bad.
Scott: You don't see him doing it.
Scott: He has the sensei part, but not the badass part.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: There's a lot of characters that have an aspect of this, but these two kinds of badasses, there's the young badass who makes the impossible possible and probably dies and you feel really bad because they're young and invincible.
Rym: And then there's the old invincible.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Madoka doesn't really have such a character at all.
Rym: You could argue almost that a Homer follows that purpose of the consummate badass, but the show is partially, the show is too good.
Rym: And also does notice how the best shows don't have characters that fall perfectly into all these stereotypes.
Rym: Madoka has the trappings.
Scott: This is a character that you see in the formulaic, you know, the, the anime formulas, the quality stand out.
Rym: anime is a formulaic show.
Rym: And in El Hazzard, there is Fujisawa, who is that kind of character that we're talking about.
Rym: Madoka is too complex.
Rym: It has all the trappings of a formulaic show, but doesn't actually follow any of those formulas.
Rym: And every character is a mold breaker in one way or another.
Rym: Every single one of them.
Scott: How about slayers?
Rym: Slayers.
Scott: Not really.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, you can go with the rock face dude, but not really lean is more powerful than he is.
Scott: And he's not really a mentor or anything.
Rym: Plus that's a show about a team of people.
Rym: They're all basically the main characters and the enemies are way more badass than them until the end.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: What a rezo.
Rym: Well, rezo is my favorite villain ever.
Scott: You know, and Trigun doesn't have such a character though.
Rym: Though I think Wolfwood almost fits into the stereotype of the Hughes type.
Scott: But he's not.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But he's not as strong.
Scott: He doesn't have that aspect of being so super powerful more than everyone else.
Rym: He has the aspect that notice how fans seem way more invested in Wolfwood and talk about him more than they talk about Vash.
Scott: Quite possibly.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: That's purely anecdotal.
Rym: But that's, that's what I've seen.
Rym: I mean, Monster doesn't really have anything like this.
Scott: Monster is not that kind of formula, but 20th century boys does have a, what's his face, the Shogun, Ocho the Shogun.
Scott: He's basically the badass guy.
Rym: So whenever you're watching anime, just think about the characters that fit into that particular stereotype.
Rym: The side character, the King Cosmo, that's not super important to the plot.
Rym: They're not the main movers and shakers, but they're there.
Rym: They affect things and everyone just seems to always be like, yeah, that's the best character.
Rym: That's my favorite character.
Rym: Everyone's always obsessed with the side character, even more so than the main character.
Rym: And if they think that way, pretty much always Bunta, or Boba Fett.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando Kay for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.