Rym: It's Tuesday, June 11th, 2013.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, the E3 news, the console news, gaming news.
Rym: Lots of news.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: This morning was way weird.
Rym: Really?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: How?
Rym: I mean, I got up, was tired because I stayed up late, and I just biked to work and work was normal.
Scott: I woke up at like two or three.
Rym: What?
Rym: Like
Rym: a.m.?
Scott: Not p.m Yeah, a.m I don't know why.
Scott: I went to bed at like 10, like normal.
Scott: For some reason, I woke up way early, and I didn't really go back to bed that much.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Scott: It was very strange because that doesn't usually happen.
Scott: I mean, sometimes there'll be stretches where I'm waking up like an hour early, like six.
Rym: Did something wake you up?
Scott: Not unless.
Rym: Like when Brian and Family Guy wakes himself up with a fart?
Scott: Not unless that thing is nothing.
Rym: All right.
Scott: And I felt refreshed, so.
Rym: You just didn't go back to bed?
Rym: You just.
Scott: I just sort of laid in bed a lot and played some mobile games.
Rym: You know, a lot of people we know have experienced insomnia.
Scott: Yeah, but for them, that's a consistent problem.
Scott: For me, this is like once in ever.
Scott: So that's why it's strange, right?
Rym: So you just stayed up until eventually work?
Scott: No, I sort of got up early, and then I took a shower early.
Scott: I'd eat breakfast early.
Scott: I computed, and then I walked around outside.
Scott: Ah.
Scott: And then I went to work.
Rym: That's weird.
Rym: At least you had a nice walk outside.
Scott: Took some pictures of the neighborhood in the early morning.
Rym: I think you're getting old.
Rym: Those are the kind of things that old men do.
Rym: They wake up super early, and they putter around.
Scott: Maybe I just turned into an old man.
Scott: Suddenly.
Rym: I think that was the moment.
Scott: Yesterday I was 31, and today, 90.
Rym: So yeah, the only thing I really got going on is jury duty.
Rym: I completed it by, again, not being selected to serve on a jury.
Scott: Did you make it to voir dire?
Rym: I made it to stand outside of the courtroom for voir dire to begin.
Scott: Oh, I never made it that far.
Rym: And then the judge basically was like, "Yeah, we pretty much just called the jury, so you'd be standing out here to force these two schmucks to actually just come to a
Rym: settlement.".
Rym: And it worked, because once we were standing out there, I guess inside the judge was like, "Look, I'm gonna call that jury in here right the fuck
Rym: now.".
Scott: But you were at the Kew Gardens one, right?
Rym: No.
Rym: I ended up having to go to the state supreme court and civil court way out in Jamaica.
Rym: Oh, okay.
Rym: Let me tell you, Jamaica, there is nothing to eat.
Scott: Nope.
Rym: There are three awful looking fried chicken places.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Kennedy.
Scott: I saw Lincoln Fried Chicken.
Rym: No, there wasn't even Kennedy.
Rym: It was all these super-off friends.
Scott: I actually saw Lincoln Fried Chicken.
Rym: Wow.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And there were a couple of really crappy diners, a couple of restaurants where I walked in and nobody spoke English and there was no menu.
Scott: Awesome.
Rym: There was just a sort of buffet of- A washing machine full of money?
Rym: There was like a generic buffet of really kind of sad looking food, but no really obvious way I could see to pay for it.
Rym: Never mind.
Rym: There was no cash register that I could see.
Scott: I'm sure it wasn't expensive.
Scott: Maybe it was a soup kitchen?
Rym: And that would have been the most boring day of my life, except I read all of Player of Games.
Rym: That's good.
Scott: That helps us out.
Scott: Did they make you watch that video about doing jury?
Rym: So they turned it on, right?
Rym: And before they turned it on, the woman stood up front and she said, "You all have to give this your full wink and total wink
Rym: attention.".
Rym: And she turns it on and then after like a minute, this judge who was there walks out of the room and she stands up and just mutes it.
Rym: And it just played for the next like 20 minutes.
Rym: It was like these peasants murdering a dude in the water.
Scott: I saw that exact same video.
Scott: Now the thing with that video, right, is one thing it says in that video because they didn't mute it for us, right?
Rym: It had closed captions.
Rym: I could have watched it.
Rym: I watched up until.
Scott: There was one thing in that video that was relevant to your story about standing outside the courtroom for the settlement.
Scott: In the video it says, "The people in the court feel the pressure of you sitting in this
Scott: room.".
Scott: Right?
Scott: It's like just by sitting here, the people in the court, the lawyers, the defendants, the plaintiffs, the judges, they know that you're waiting in this room to come in and juror, right?
Rym: Yeah, to basically cast judgment.
Scott: Yeah, and because of that, even if you don't go in and do anything, right, that has an effect.
Scott: And you saw that effect even worse.
Scott: In fact, the judge was wielding it.
Rym: And the bailiff was pretty cool.
Rym: He was like, "Well, you know what?
Rym: I guess this
Rym: counts.".
Rym: And he gave us all the form that says we never have to do jury duty again.
Scott: Mine counted.
Scott: I didn't even make it out of the room with the TVs.
Rym: They only went for one day?
Scott: They said, "Anyone who's left in this room, come up to the
Scott: front."
Scott: And they gave us all the piece of paper and we went home.
Rym: I got to leave early, basically.
Scott: We also did early, as soon as they had all of our dears taken out.
Rym: But this video was great.
Rym: There's this one moment where basically they're like, "In the old days, justice was
Rym: bullshit.".
Rym: That's right.
Scott: There's like murdering people.
Rym: And they do it like, "If he floats, he is guilty, but if he sinks, he is
Rym: innocent.".
Scott: And in the modern days, justice is still bullshit, but we're going to act like.
Scott: it's not because you're in the court right now.
Scott: But at least it's not that bullshit.
Rym: Whatever actor it was who played, I guess, the magistrate of that town, because they throw the guy in the water.
Scott: I'm sure we can find that video on YouTube.
Rym: I'm going to.
Rym: I'm going to add it.
Rym: I'm just going to link to it because it's pretty great.
Rym: But basically, they throw the guy in the water and everyone's all super serious.
Rym: And then the guy doesn't come back up.
Scott: Because he's a witch.
Rym: The magistrate just looks and then makes this kind of offhand gesture like, "All right, I guess he's
Rym: innocent.".
Rym: And then everyone celebrates.
Rym: Maybe we should go back to that.
Scott: They should just take that video and put the Monty Python thing in there and be better.
Rym: If that video is on YouTube, I'm going to mash it up with something.
Scott: All right, since our whole show is news, let's not do news.
Scott: You got any other openings?
Rym: Not really.
Rym: I've been playing Mario Tennis on the 3DS.
Rym: It's a new Mario.
Scott: I got a very tiny one.
Rym: It's not as good as at the end of 64 Mario Tennis.
Scott: We'll talk about that later.
Scott: I bought on Amazon the sequel to the Nine Doors, Nine Persons, Nine Hours, Nine Whatevers for the 3DS.
Scott: And I thought I'd save some money buying a used copy for 10 bucks less.
Rym: Uh-oh.
Scott: I opened up the package at work today.
Rym: Game wasn't in there?
Scott: No, they gave me a PS Vita copy.
Scott: What?
Scott: So I went and I immediately returned it.
Scott: I went on Amazon and I was like, "Give me a return slip.
Scott: Print, tape, go to UPS
Scott: store.".
Scott: Immediately.
Scott: So take that.
Scott: But I guess I have to buy a new copy to guarantee that I get a DS one.
Rym: We could buy another used copy.
Scott: I'll get another PS Vita one.
Scott: Whatever.
Rym: So anyway, things of the day.
Rym: I thought this was just cute.
Rym: It's a video about Magikarp and his trials and tribulations trying to find an owner.
Scott: I choose you, Magikarp.
Rym: Use your splash attack.
Rym: It's that kind of video that's well done and makes the same joke consistently from beginning to end in increasingly absurd situations.
Rym: It's adorable.
Rym: And it's Magikarp.
Scott: You should also link, you know, I choose you.
Scott: Ditto.
Rym: Oh, shit.
Rym: I'm sure I could find that.
Scott: I love that one.
Scott: Anyway, so check this out.
Scott: There's a city in Spain, España.
Scott: I guess it's near Madrid.
Scott: It's called Brunete.
Scott: And in Brunete, they had a problem.
Scott: The people, they know scuba to poopa, even though I use an Italian accent in Spain.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They don't scoop the poop in this city.
Scott: This nice old city in Spain.
Rym: I think New York also has that problem.
Scott: This place had it much worse.
Scott: No, New York has it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So what they did is they first tried to, uh, they made a remote control poop car.
Scott: They had a flag in it that said, you know, hey, scoop poop asshole.
Scott: Right.
Rym: It looks like they'd actually drive it into your foot.
Rym: If you didn't pick up the, that didn't really work.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So what they did is they, they, you know, we're doing clever with their marketing to get people to scoop the poop from the dogs.
Scott: And what they did is whenever anyone let their dog poop without scooping, they would go and scoop it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And they would talk to the person and say, Hey, that is a nice dog.
Scott: What does your dog?
Scott: He's a name.
Rym: My dog's the name is Mario.
Scott: He's Italian dog living in a Spain.
Scott: I'm Italian living here.
Scott: That's why I do not scoop the poop.
Rym: He's a German shot.
Rym: I had a point.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So then, but just based on the name of the dog, they knew a town the person lived in.
Scott: And the breed of the dog, they could look up in the dog license database and figure out who the fuck it was that didn't scoop the poop.
Scott: So they took the poop and they put it in a box and they would hand deliver it to that person's house.
Scott: lost property as lost and found.
Scott: And they made them sign a thing.
Scott: And inside the lost and found with the poop was a notice like, Hey, if you do this again, big fine, hundreds of dollars.
Rym: That is the kind of thing.
Scott: Poop scooping was decreased by like think 70%.
Scott: They say that's the kind of thing.
Rym: I mean, increase that just because of the way America is, we can never do stuff like that, but that's the kind of stuff you need to do.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: So funny video with the poop.
Rym: So in the meta moment, the book club book is Ian M. Banks is player of games, which we will do on Thursday.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: We finally read it at the jury duty.
Rym: Super good book.
Rym: Sadly, in a banks just recently actually did pass away.
Scott: I feel guilty because I chose the book right before we knew he was sick.
Scott: Then he got sick right after I chose it.
Scott: And then right before we do the episode, it's like, what the fuck?
Scott: More than one.
Scott: I feel like I shouldn't have chosen it.
Rym: More than one author of a GeekNights book club book was dead by the time we reviewed the book, but the timing, my psychic powers is the reason I'm so sad about it is partly that the book was awesome.
Rym: And now I already know that all the books he wrote are already out and there will never be any more.
Scott: There's one more.
Rym: And I wish I'd paid attention to him.
Scott: finished.
Scott: It's just not published a long time ago.
Scott: Oh, well, the books are still there.
Scott: The money will go to his family.
Rym: So we have uploaded one of our five lectures from anime Boston, 2013 Joe anime by their cover night, which has a ton of likes and one dislike, I assume from some dude who likes tit anime and is mad at our valuation of tits in tit anime.
Rym: I can't imagine any other reason.
Scott: It could be just one of our haters are two haters.
Rym: It could be.
Rym: It's what's weird is the kinds of comments because we don't really upload anime lectures or shows just for logistical reasons.
Rym: Like we have a lot more sort of facilities and convention support from gaming cons like packs.
Rym: So we have a lot more video.
Scott: It only has like less than 200 views here.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Cause I just uploaded.
Rym: I'm not saying a lot of views.
Scott: What I'm saying is I could listen to you guys talk forever.
Rym: If you look at the comments of this anime video, it's basically people sucking our collective dicks.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But if you go to like, you guys make the best panels ever.
Rym: If you go to our entertaining panel, it's always people who are like, well, really don't you just drag and just that bad.
Rym: I don't know why you're being bad day, right?
Rym: It's a very different caliber of discussion.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Maybe we should just do more anime panels.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I think anime people are just easier to please.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: And yeah.
Rym: Pax OS is coming up.
Rym: Connecticut is coming up.
Scott: Oh, uh, this Saturday, which is Saturday, June 15th thing is the New York city net runner regional tournament at the complete strategists.
Scott: If you want to participate, I don't know if there's open slots left.
Scott: There probably are.
Scott: You have to call the complete strategist and registrate, right?
Scott: You have to also know how to play net runner and have cards, right?
Scott: This is a tournament.
Scott: This isn't beginner's net runner.
Rym: My deck is 45 agendas.
Scott: No, is that legal?
Scott: No, there aren't enough agendas to do that.
Rym: I wonder, are there not enough with all the expansions?
Scott: because you can only use neutral.
Rym: You can't bring them from three of every neutral and then you've got to have all of your factions agenda.
Scott: It's not enough.
Rym: All the rest of the cards are the weakest possible ice.
Scott: How are you going to raise them?
Rym: That's the point of the deck.
Scott: Anyway, uh, actually lots of week guys works pretty well, but anyway, uh, it's going to be pretty awesome.
Scott: It's going to be six rounds.
Scott: Usually we do three or four rounds, six rounds.
Scott: People.
Scott: This is going to lose.
Rym: This
Scott: is, this is effectively, I mean, I don't want to like toot New York's horn anymore than I already toot it, but from everything we can surmise, like, you know, how do you feel the story of the go master who, who's like the king of go, but he plays in the village and
Rym: then he
Scott: goes to the capital and he gets his ass handed to him because
Rym: they have far surpassed him.
Scott: Right.
Scott: New York is the capital of net runner.
Scott: Like I'm really good at games.
Scott: I'm not the best here at net runner.
Scott: I'm like straight down the middle of the road.
Scott: The people here are super dangerous.
Scott: I think that whichever people from New York go to the world, you know, championships, which I'm not going to because they're in like bumblefuck middle of the country at a bad time.
Scott: Uh, and I wouldn't go there even if it was a good time are probably going to win or come close to it because they're super dangerous.
Scott: So this regional is sort of like, you know, world championships, you know, guess one level under that.
Rym: Well, do you think, how do you think you're going to do?
Scott: I predict I will get 10 prestige points because that's what I always get.
Scott: But that's in four rounds.
Scott: I think with six rounds, right, I get an average of 10 prestige points for four rounds.
Scott: in six rounds.
Scott: I can get at least 14 or 16 prestige points.
Scott: It's hard to get an odd number 15.
Scott: So 14 or 16 points to win this tournament.
Scott: You're going to need to get a lot of sixes.
Scott: So the maximum score you can get is 36 prestige points.
Scott: I'm thinking the top people are going to have between like 32 and 36 points, right?
Scott: If you don't at least get to 30, you're not winning this thing.
Scott: But the top eight people get some sort of goody prize of swag.
Rym: That's how all those things seem to work, because a lot of people seem to only go to card based events at game stores or events in general at game stores and comic shops.
Scott: If there's swag of some kind, there are people I know who are in it for the swag.
Scott: I can't imagine being like that because basically NAC flight sells these game kit game night kits to stores.
Scott: You can't buy one unless you are a store.
Scott: But for example, one guy works at a store in Westchester.
Scott: He just bought one because he worked it right.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: He bought the whole kit for himself.
Scott: But and then the store uses those things in that kit as game night prizes or tournament prizes or whatever they want to do, and it includes a regionals trophy.
Scott: that fantasy flight makes them and everything.
Scott: So, you know, they don't sell those on the shelf.
Scott: They give them away at an event and that's the only way to get them.
Scott: So people go to events just to win these things.
Scott: I know people who went to like New Jersey and Long Island to try to win tournaments to get more swag because there'll be less competition.
Rym: Granted, there's a PAX medal hanging in your apartment.
Scott: I didn't go in that tournament to get that medal.
Rym: Did you went into that tournament specifically to get that medal?
Rym: Because someone reminded you that it turns out if you play in the early Sunday morning tournaments, there aren't many people.
Rym: And you thought you could just snag a free medal.
Scott: Meanwhile, I ran the early Sunday morning tournaments at PAX East.
Scott: There was a ton of people.
Rym: I think PAX East gets more of the early morning people.
Rym: I don't know the tournament at PAX East.
Scott: It's so many people.
Rym: Anyway, the is actually really popular.
Scott: The thing is, in Netrunner, I'd actually want to win that trophy.
Scott: It's basically just a glass thing with like a laser etching on it.
Scott: This is like, you know, Netrunner championship, whatever.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, regionals champion.
Scott: I would want that.
Scott: I wouldn't want any of the other stuff like play mats, cards, you know, credit tokens.
Scott: I don't want any of that bullshit.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Or like there's like a Netrunner box.
Scott: You can put your cards in.
Scott: I want none of that.
Scott: All I want is the trophy because then I can gloat for like five minutes before people think you're going to like put that on a chain and wear it around your neck at PAX.
Scott: Listen, it's possible that every game I sit down like Maker's Eye seven points, I win.
Scott: And just every time it is possible, it could happen.
Scott: It could happen.
Scott: I could.
Scott: it could also act.
Scott: some nub could show up and they all they know is how to do that.
Scott: It could happen.
Scott: So I've never played before.
Scott: it could happen.
Rym: So Xbox, PlayStation, Wii U, what are you talking about?
Scott: So many E3 news is let's try to cover the biggest one.
Rym: We are not going to bother with the blow by blow, play by plays fact sheets.
Rym: If you want to know the individual announcements, there are a lot of people who actually cover that way better than we would ever even bother doing.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Go read what we read on the Internet and you can know all the things.
Scott: we're going to commentate on the thing.
Scott: So let's commentate on the used game thing because that's the biggest.
Rym: So I am conflicted on the used game thing in a lot of ways.
Scott: All right.
Rym: On one hand, I feel that first sale rights are a crucial aspect of the modern economy and consumer world.
Rym: I agree.
Rym: I feel like that is a strong right that needs to be not just upheld, but extended by the courts.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: If I buy a thing, it is now my thing to then do with as I please.
Scott: Imagine people didn't have first sale rights for like a car.
Scott: So you bought a Ford.
Rym: You had to sell it back to the company shop.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: It's like all you could do with it when you were done with it is, you know, whatever Ford let you do with it.
Scott: That's bullshit.
Scott: I'm not renting.
Scott: If I'm renting it, I understand.
Scott: But I'm not renting or leasing.
Rym: I am buying now at the same time.
Rym: First sale rights have been actually very recently upheld by even recent Supreme Court guy reselling his autocads.
Rym: Remember, he I think he won that court case selling textbooks that they bought overseas, then moved to the United States, also another win for us.
Rym: But at the same time, it has not been applied directly to all manner of things yet for a number of reasons.
Rym: And it was difficult to apply to digital things because someone who has, say, let's go back to ancient technology, a CD, some music on it, if they rip it and then sell it, that basically also constitutes duplication and dilutes the market.
Rym: And it has secondary effects if you call it piracy.
Rym: And regardless of how you feel about that, it does have an effect on that industry with games.
Rym: A lot of people tried to call me a hypocrite because I'm so for this first sale rights.
Rym: But yeah, I'm so against DRM, but yet I keep buying games on steam.
Rym: My answer to you is that I buy games on steam for a dollar.
Rym: That's right.
Scott: See, here's the thing.
Scott: When you pay 50 bucks for a fucking game on a disk, right, you own that shit.
Scott: You paid 50 goddamn dollars.
Scott: I know there's contracts and legal agreements and you lose.
Scott: Forget all that bullshit for right now.
Scott: Right.
Scott: If you pay 50 dollars for a fucking video game, you own that goddamn game.
Scott: It's yours to do with as you please.
Scott: Right.
Scott: If I pay one dollar, I mean, technically, steam says, you know, I own it kind of.
Scott: But it's like you could call that a rental.
Rym: I can't 100 percent trust steam.
Rym: I like steam, but I don't 100 percent trust steam.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like for a dollar or for like a hand for almost no money, you know.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: OK.
Scott: I'm willing to accept that this is, you know, just like if I go to Blockbuster and I pay five bucks and they let me take home an NES cartridge like I did back in the day, I didn't feel like I owned it, even though I gave a person money and took a physical good from them.
Scott: I didn't feel like I owned it because I paid so little.
Rym: Now, I understand why a lot of people are really OK with this because they're looking at it from the perspective of a game gets sold for 50 bucks.
Rym: Someone sells it back to GameStop for like five bucks and then GameStop sells it again for 40 bucks.
Scott: So basically GameStop is is ripping people off.
Rym: GameStop is getting a ton of money from this churn, but none of that money goes to the original producers of the games.
Rym: Well, the same thing happened in the music industry before.
Rym: piracy was even cars.
Scott: If I sell my car for doesn't get shit, but cars wear out.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: Video games don't, but video games get old.
Rym: So it's a complicated situation.
Rym: But what I would say is that every industry where this has come up has tried to wash it.
Rym: The media companies did not want Blockbuster Video and its ilk to exist at all.
Rym: They didn't want DVDs to even be able to be in libraries.
Scott: Use bookstores, people.
Scott: Just deal with it, right?
Scott: The thing is, used bookstores are not ripping used music stores at many junctures in the early days, but used bookstores aren't ripping you off the way.
Scott: GameStop is ripping you off just because GameStop, but is GameStop really ripping you off?
Rym: They're just charging what the market will bear and the market will easily bear that price.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But the thing is, what the market will bear is too damn high.
Scott: They pay you too little for the game when they buy it from you and they charge too much and they resell it.
Rym: But they're not charging too much because people gladly pay it.
Scott: You could just see.
Scott: the thing is more people need to sell their games directly to each other.
Scott: Amazon to get the full price.
Scott: If I, you know, GameStop is if I, let's say, have a copy of I see Mario.
Rym: You're right.
Rym: But here's why that doesn't happen.
Rym: The only people who sell games back to GameStop are like 14 years old.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: And can't use the Internet and Amazon to do this effect.
Scott: They could if their parents are fucking cool.
Rym: Well, yeah, I mean, I could have, but most kids can't.
Rym: I'm not going to pretend that there's a magic universe where parents are going to let their kids do that.
Rym: Not everyone had a credit card at 16.
Scott: You don't need a credit card to sell things.
Scott: And you just need a box and some tape and a printer.
Rym: I'm pretty sure you have to be a teen or an account.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But, you know, you log in your parents account.
Scott: You know, you say I'm selling this, you get whatever.
Scott: It's not hard, but it's definitely something a teen could do if they were smart enough enterprising and their parents were cooperative.
Rym: But what's interesting is that the majority of gamers don't even know this is an issue or care.
Scott: No, they they're the most of these people, the same as the anime fans, you don't even know an anime con is a thing that exists.
Rym: They don't even realize that the Xbox and PlayStation four were actually 100 percent announced.
Scott: Like they don't realize they only get that news is that they'll only get their game news from like the mainstream media, like the door, maybe the really game magazine or go to a game store.
Rym: The impression they get it from hearsay and rumors from their slightly more connected friends.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Only Internet people.
Scott: And it seems like there's a lot of Internet people know Internet people is still the minority.
Rym: It's just you're on the Internet right now hanging out with Internet people.
Scott: Yes, you are Internet people.
Scott: Most of the world is not doesn't get us.
Scott: They're not connected to us.
Scott: I know I meet a lot of people on the street.
Scott: They have no idea what the fuck's going on in the world the way we do.
Rym: Here's what really bothers me.
Rym: The whole argument for consoles, because consoles have a place and had a place, was that it's the thing that just works.
Rym: You bring it to grandma's house, you turn it on.
Rym: You put something in the thing and the game just works.
Scott: No, here's the reason the video game consoles.
Scott: Right.
Scott: We're super big back in the day.
Rym: Well, back in the day, there was no alternative.
Rym: Well, right.
Scott: Well, there was.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, OK, you get any S or you can get a computer, but what's a computer?
Scott: It's an Apple to four thousands of dollars for just one hundred dollars.
Rym: You can get an NES and use more than one hundred bucks.
Scott: NES is one hundred bucks after like a year or two.
Rym: Yeah, after a year or two.
Scott: And that was with a gun and with the cartridge.
Scott: Anyway, they were cheap, way cheaper than like an actual computer.
Scott: And also because they were only doing games, not doing anything else like at the time the NES was out, it could play games way better than the best computer that you could buy in your house.
Rym: The NES launch price was two hundred bucks.
Rym: OK, so that's two hundred and fifty with the bullshit.
Scott: How much in that?
Scott: what year was that of eighty four, eighty four, eighty five.
Scott: And how much did an Apple to cost in eighty four, eighty five?
Rym: I'm not saying your core point is wrong.
Rym: I'm saying what was better.
Rym: Mario Brothers, Oregon Trail, Oregon Trail is actually kind of a shit game.
Scott: I didn't say it's a good game.
Scott: I'm talking like graphically audio wise, everything wise.
Rym: I think I implied all that.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: NES had superior software to far more expensive machines at the same time now.
Scott: And the thing is, right, those computers, they didn't do all the things that a modern computer does.
Scott: If you got an Apple to what were you going to do with it?
Scott: Play games and make games.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That is what you're going to do with it.
Scott: You couldn't really type up a paper.
Rym: Oh, you might break it.
Scott: Maybe.
Rym: Yeah, that was a lot of kids bought it to break.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: You know, even later when they were like black and white, like Mac plus and stuff, it's like, yeah, OK.
Scott: Carmen Sandiego on there.
Rym: Not as good as any of all these traditional arguments about the places and of consoles and in the world, everything aren't as relevant to the modern era.
Rym: And in the modern era, the primary use of a console is that you don't need to know shit about computers.
Rym: You don't need to buy a gaming computer, which is more expensive than a console.
Rym: I mean, if I buy the new Nvidia 770 video card, that costs about as much as an Xbox one is going to cost just for the video card.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But the thing is, you supposedly you already have a PC because you need one to live these days.
Scott: It wasn't like in the 80s or the 90s where you didn't need a PC to live.
Scott: Right now, everyone's got one.
Rym: Well, no, everyone who's in the middle class and up has one.
Scott: Well, yeah, but you could, for example, now get some Macs which don't really play games or just live off iPads for your PC-ing.
Scott: if you're not really computery and you don't need to, you know, get Adobe tools or programming or anything serious.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then get a video console for your video games.
Scott: You could do that and not have a PC at all.
Scott: But if you're going to have a PC and you're going to spend more than like a couple hundred dollars on it, right, buy a fucking gaming PC, kill two birds with one stone.
Rym: What I'm saying is that the consoles, the way they're going, especially with this resale thing, they're killing a lot of the big part of what does make consoles great compared to PCs for a lot of people.
Rym: I'm going to remember right now all of the reasons I could see myself using a console instead of a PC.
Rym: One, it does just work.
Scott: I never really have a problem with the PC not just working.
Rym: Yeah, well, this is where magic Uber race.
Scott: I open up steam.
Scott: I double click on a game.
Scott: It runs.
Rym: We're normal people.
Rym: It does just work.
Rym: Give it to grandma.
Rym: As long as you help her plug in the HDMI cable, it will just work.
Scott: No.
Rym: Two, the games are physical things that you just keep track of and trade around your friends and sell and whatever, which now they're killing that.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Three doesn't need to be connected to the network.
Rym: So you bring it to grandma's house when your parents foist you on her or the vacation, the beach house.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Bring it into the beach for you.
Rym: Bring it to the convention and you play it in the room.
Rym: A lot of people will play video games in their hotel video game.
Scott: Hotel room is big.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: They're killing that with the twenty four hour check in and I have to pay for Internet to use my console in the hotel room at Otakon.
Rym: That's rough.
Rym: It's real rough.
Rym: Even further beyond that.
Rym: So now the game, the video game room itself.
Rym: at a con, they don't wire the console gaming rooms up with Internet.
Rym: No, that'd be a giant pain in the ass and really expensive.
Scott: Well, conventions are a concern to a very small number of people.
Scott: It's just something we're very familiar with.
Rym: It's a big deal.
Scott: It is a big deal for a small number of people.
Rym: Yes, but there will be ramifications of that.
Rym: A lot of small gaming cons will not be able to have Xbox ones with working games on them at the convention.
Scott: That is true.
Rym: That's not going to bode well for the Xbox one.
Scott: I don't think conventions are going to be a big seller for Xboxes, nor were they ever.
Rym: No, but what it means is that part of the culture around the console that allows, for example, the fighting game community in one particular game to keep itself going long multiple years into that console's lifespan is because they play in tournaments at conventions.
Rym: That's true.
Scott: If you go to a local fighting game tournament, the kind that doesn't have all arcade machines or stuff like that, they're going to be using PS fours for the foreseeable future for those tournaments and not Xbox one simply because it'll be a pain in the ass to set up the Xbox ones for those sorts of things.
Rym: Yeah, but believe me, it is not easy to get Internet set up at these convention centers, let alone in all your little console gaming rooms if you've got more than one.
Scott: And because of that, I wouldn't be surprised if already a lot of the fighting game community is all across different systems, wherever their games are.
Scott: That's where they go.
Scott: I could see all sorts of competitive game communities, you know, people who are going to want to use the same system as they're going to be competing on in a local tournament are going to be not using Xboxes because the local tournaments won't be using Xboxes because they can't.
Scott: And that is a little bit larger than the convention community, but still a small percentage.
Rym: Also, the library.
Rym: A lot of the ways the libraries of these small conventions work is people donate their old discs.
Rym: That's not going to work anymore.
Scott: Also, here's the more significant the local library.
Scott: The real libraries often check out games to people.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I can go to the local library and like get some Xbox games if I want, but not Xbox one games.
Scott: No, no.
Scott: Now, imagine if.
Scott: imagine if there were like books like published by a certain publisher and they didn't have them at the library.
Scott: You could only get them at Amazon.
Scott: You couldn't get them at Barnes and Noble and like you couldn't give and lend them to people.
Scott: And they were just like Kindle books only.
Rym: So meanwhile, Sony won a big press coup by announcing that they're not going to have that kind of D.R.A That was definitely like a slide they added in.
Rym: And the Internet was ecstatic about that.
Rym: But that's not actually what they said.
Scott: They said, well, the thing is, right, is if you watch the video of their presentation, right, that is what they said.
Scott: Very clearly and loudly while smiling.
Rym: Yeah, because what they said is technically true.
Rym: But there's a follow up interview here with Tretton and he says, and I quote, we create the platform.
Rym: We've certainly stated that our first party games, we're not going to be doing that in regards to restricting used game sales.
Rym: But we welcome publishers and their business models to our platforms.
Rym: There's going to be free to play.
Rym: There's going to be every potential business model on there.
Rym: And again, that's up to their relationship with the consumer and what they think is going to put them in the best stead.
Rym: So we're not going to dictate that.
Rym: We're going to give them a platform to publish on and to translate that all the third party people can do whatever the fuck they want.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Which is good and bad, right?
Scott: If you're a developer, you want to be able to do whatever the fuck you want.
Rym: And also a gamer, average gamer out there, gamer dude name first party Sony games.
Scott: Little big planet.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Name another one gamer out there.
Scott: Not Metal Gear.
Scott: That's Konami, right?
Scott: Also, they said the same thing about DRS PlayStation All Stars, which is the Smash Brothers of PlayStation on DRM.
Rym: The DRM decision is going to have to be in the hands of the third parties.
Rym: That's not something you're going to dictate, mandate or control or implement.
Scott: Well, that is sort of nice in one way.
Scott: And I was saying developers can now do what they want on the PlayStation that they're less restricted, sort of, you know, it's not P.C.
Scott: unrestricted.
Scott: Right.
Scott: We can do whatever the fuck you want.
Scott: But it seems like there's going to be less limitations for developers because Nintendo is the polar opposite.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Where you have to do the what the fuck Nintendo says, you know, if you want to put a game out on their system, whereas Sony is going to be like they're even letting indies self-publish on PlayStation four.
Scott: Like, go for it.
Scott: Bring the games to the PlayStation.
Rym: But I guess the moral is that everyone who's saying, oh, I'll be able to sell my used games and there'll be no DRM in the PlayStation four.
Rym: That's not probably actually true.
Scott: I wonder how if you wanted to, let's say EA, evil EA wanted to make a no use sale game for the PS4.
Scott: How would they do it without the with if there's nothing in the PlayStation four platform to support that?
Rym: Technological.
Rym: Yeah, we don't know.
Scott: They would have to.
Rym: But they went out.
Rym: I mean, this interview went out of his way to say basically they can do it if they want to.
Scott: I think the only thing they could really do is when you open up the game from the disk, you know, you have to log into your EA account or something and then, you know, the disable that disk, it won't work again.
Scott: I don't think they could disable the disk because all the disks would be identical.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They would have to just basically you would have to pay and have an account and your account would have to have that game rumblings like on Xbox.
Rym: The disks won't actually be identical.
Rym: There's a way to identify disk.
Scott: Whoa, crazy.
Rym: I don't know if that's if that's legit or not, but I read that and it's from a semi legitimate source.
Rym: Yeah, whatever.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So the used thing has been beaten to death.
Scott: Let's move on to the other things.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Backward compatibility.
Scott: No one.
Scott: No one's doing any of it.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: No one ever does.
Rym: It's funny because people have such short memories.
Rym: A lot of people on the Internet were like, well, we shouldn't really expect backward compatibility, but Nintendo actually has been doing a good job with that.
Scott: Yeah, remember the original DS, the DS fat could play GBA, right, and DS games.
Scott: The 3DS can still play DS games.
Scott: The Game Boy SP could play Game Boy Advance, Game Boy Color and original gray cartridge Game Boy games.
Scott: All right.
Scott: The Game Cube had a thing that you could put under it to play GBA games on it.
Scott: The Super Nintendo had the Super Game Boy.
Scott: You could play Game Boy games on that.
Rym: And there's older precedent.
Rym: The Atari seventy eight hundred could play any Atari twenty six hundred game.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Only fifty eight hundred couldn't was incompatible.
Rym: It's not the fifty eight.
Scott: fifty two hundred.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The five one.
Scott: That was the one that couldn't play.
Rym: And nobody owned.
Scott: I had a friend who owned it.
Rym: I know everyone.
Rym: Everyone had a friend who owned it, just like everyone knew some kid who had an EOG.
Scott: I had twenty six hundred fifty two hundred.
Rym: I always wanted a fifty two hundred because then that little book of all the different games, the fifty two hundred had all the cool, weird games with keyboards and shit.
Scott: It did.
Scott: But you could just get like an Atari eight hundred Excel if you want to do that shit.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But that wasn't in my stars.
Rym: My first computer was a forty six six two.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, but yeah, backwards compatibility is a thing that's existed.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And I've noticed the pattern is pretty much is the thing, you know, Nintendo to Super Nintendo.
Scott: Nobody really complained about not having backwards compatibility.
Scott: Why?
Scott: Number one, the cartridges are completely different.
Scott: It was sort of a common sense thing.
Scott: Like, of course, Super Nintendo can't play NES games.
Scott: They don't fit.
Rym: I mean, the Genesis and the Master System and all the other systems didn't do it well either.
Rym: Right.
Scott: And it's also on top of that, there were only those the second system ever effectively for a lot of people.
Scott: Right.
Scott: For most people, the Atari twenty seven hundred didn't even exist.
Scott: It was NES was the first video game, maybe second.
Scott: It will bring Atari into it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And SNES was the second.
Scott: So people didn't see this future of boxes piling up under the TV.
Rym: Now, also there I mean, back then, what other devices did you have hooked up to a TV?
Rym: You had your VC fucking arm and a cable box, maybe if you had if you had cable.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Or you might have had that little box that lets you rotate the antenna on your room.
Scott: There was no plague of boxes under the TV.
Rym: I had one of those boxes.
Rym: I could physically rotate the antenna on my right.
Scott: But basically the precedent up to this point was if the cartridges are the same as the seventy eight hundred and twenty six hundred were, they all work.
Rym: And so I was wrong.
Rym: The the Sega Genesis had backward can full backward compatibility with what the master system.
Scott: I did not know you could put Master System games in a Genesis.
Scott: Didn't you need some sort of adapter thing to do that?
Rym: I'm reading right now, say release the power.
Rym: There's a big article, so keep going.
Rym: I was I was a smart kid, so I didn't tend to.
Rym: I got to read this article.
Scott: Now, I didn't know you could play Master System games in agenda.
Rym: Anyway, continue your thought.
Rym: I'm going to figure out what the deal is.
Scott: So and notice.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So what happened is that was the last system that had the same exact cartridge.
Scott: They kept having different cartridges until the CD was invented.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And as soon as the CD was invented, backwards compatibility and made an immediate comeback.
Scott: The PlayStation one and the PlayStation two both had CDs or DVDs.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And guess what?
Scott: PS2 backwards compatible.
Scott: As soon as the media format stop changing, backwards compatibility immediately reappeared.
Scott: The expectation is if it has the same physical media, it should fucking run the games from the previous system.
Scott: And this and also around that time, a weird as adapter that I told you.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: By that when the PS2 came out, that is when the plague of too many boxes under.
Scott: the TV was just getting started.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And the PS2 actually saved you because that was when the PS2 came out.
Scott: Most people didn't have DVD players.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: You realize the only reason we had a brand new when we lived in an apartment at RIT is because I found for Scott Johnson's DVD player.
Rym: Well, we took his for a while, but then I got for ninety dollars.
Rym: I bought a stand piece of shit, super bootleg piece of shit.
Rym: We had to take the case off because it would overheat.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And we had flashed its bios to make it region free.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Even though we never once watched a region disc on it.
Scott: Well, you know, some of those ones from video bar may or may not have been.
Scott: Yeah, we don't know.
Rym: It's hard to say.
Rym: We had no way to know anyway.
Rym: The there's another factor here that I think is actually a big deal when it comes to the backward compatibility.
Scott: Well, I want to say the Dreamcast is not back as compatible with the Saturn.
Scott: So that doesn't entirely hold right.
Rym: in the old days.
Rym: You it was typical in a lot of middle class households to have many TVs around the house.
Scott: Well, even today, people who have houses and families have TVs around the house.
Scott: I have noticed having visited living room, kitchen, every bedroom has a TV.
Rym: So I've noticed just from visiting people's houses, especially like, you know, years ago going to co-workers houses for dinners and whatever there, I think there are fewer televisions than there used to be.
Rym: A lot of people now have the big flat screen TV in the living room.
Rym: They have the previous older TV in one other room and the bedroom TV is slowly being replaced by iPads.
Scott: That could be true.
Scott: But even my parents house where there's only two people living.
Scott: Right.
Scott: There's still a TV in like every fucking bedroom and in the kitchen.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But I think I feel like I don't know if the kitchen TV is still there.
Rym: Younger parents do not have as many TVs as older parents.
Scott: That could be very well the case.
Scott: It's also interesting to see.
Scott: maybe the Wii U is sort of realizing that.
Scott: And that's why they're like, hey, if someone's using the TV, you play on the Wii U. But that's more of a Japanese thing, right?
Scott: You think a Japanese house definitely only has like one or two TV.
Rym: Now, what I would also see is that a lot of people in the old days, like in the 80s, 90s, not only would they have a TV in every room, but they'd have a one game console plugged into each TV.
Rym: The newest console was on the newest TV in the living room.
Rym: And then like the Atari was in the basement hooked up to the old TV.
Rym: And the Nintendo was in like the little brother's room and the Super Nintendo was in the older brother.
Scott: A lot of people's houses I went to who had more money than we did.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, yeah, the main home theater TV, the big one that had no console, no consoles, just VCRs and stuff.
Scott: And then the kids had like the busted had the second best TV was in the basement with all the kids shit.
Scott: And it had all the consoles on it with switches.
Scott: Or maybe they had the best console was there and some other console was like in the kids bedroom.
Rym: Yeah, it was another TV for a long time.
Rym: My brother and I, I kept the NES, he had the SNES.
Rym: And if we wanted to play one, we just had to go to the other kids room.
Scott: But I do see I think a lot of also bedroom TVs, like for teens, are replaced with bedroom computer.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: Or just or just tablet.
Rym: They don't even have a computer.
Scott: But the point is, you have a you have a screen is just not a television screen.
Scott: that's in your room.
Rym: So all this means that backward compatibility would be much more useful to the average person, especially because they want to resell the old console and not keep all their consoles forever and have a pile of boxes under the TV.
Rym: People would do in the old days when they only own two or three, but they have a game that they bought.
Scott: They want to be able to play that game forever.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And people like us know that in like five to 10 years, we'll just be able to emulate that game on our PCs.
Scott: But most people still don't even have to emulate fucking NES games and they buy virtual console games.
Scott: They don't know better.
Rym: Dude, when I was in middle school, there was a kid whose family was rich at a laptop, like a four eighty six laptop.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And he had an NES emulator on it.
Scott: There you go.
Scott: But yeah, people who don't know how to do that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They have a game.
Scott: They want to be able to play that game.
Scott: If they don't have backwards compatibility, they effectively lose that game.
Rym: When they buy a new console, unless they have a pile of boxes under their TV, which also because kids the longer memory of the Internet and the fact that people use apps on their computers, they expect things to stick around forever once they pay for them.
Rym: I mean, steam does that.
Rym: Steam is just up.
Rym: Those are all my games forever.
Rym: It doesn't matter what changes on my computer.
Scott: I can go and find the first game I ever got on steam, which is Half Life one and play it today.
Scott: And it works.
Rym: But it's all moot.
Rym: I'm going to argue that having or not having backward compatibility in the modern era has zero effect on sales.
Scott: I agree.
Rym: Zero, not even point one percent zero.
Rym: Nobody will not buy a console because it's not backward compatible with the previous version.
Scott: They might have other reasons for not buying and that might be one of them, but that's not going to be the straw that breaks any camel's backs.
Rym: So there's this article here about Nintendo's stuff.
Rym: It's a Totillo and the headline says everything.
Rym: Nintendo's new games are fun, but they're playing it ridiculously safe.
Rym: That is the truest true bog standard Nintendo.
Rym: So I was not impressed with a link between worlds.
Scott: Yeah, that was the one.
Scott: that was one of the reasons that I was going to get a 3DS because and I did get a 3DS because I said I also have a 3DS now sequel to link to the past.
Scott: And I'm like, well, fuck, yeah, I got to have that.
Scott: And apparently I look at it and it's like, hey, this looks like a not really a sequel, but mostly just a slightly remixed link to the past.
Scott: You sort of fooled me there, asshole.
Scott: I was expecting an all new game in the same world with the same mechanics.
Scott: And this is looking like mostly the same game with a few things changed here and there.
Scott: I can play that game anytime I want.
Scott: I don't need to buy a new copy of it.
Rym: I have a much more direct complaint and I swear this isn't just nostalgia.
Rym: I think this kind of 3D graphic looks like butt.
Rym: I think it looks terrible.
Scott: I agree.
Scott: The graphic looks like butt, but I don't buy or not buy games based on graphics.
Rym: But it also just looks kind of fiddly like you don't have as much control because it's not obvious where things overlap like it was in the old 16 bit era for a game like this.
Scott: I agree with that as well.
Rym: Just don't look that precise.
Scott: I agree.
Scott: It looks more like what was that one for the DS?
Rym: Oh, I feel very vindicated.
Rym: The top several comments are about how ugly the game is.
Scott: OK, I mean, I'm not saying it's not ugly.
Scott: It is, but that's not what's going to make me buy or not buy the game if it was actually a true sequel to Link to the Past and it played like a Zelda game.
Scott: That's all I need.
Scott: You can make it look like all the butt you want.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Remember when Wind Waker came out, everyone complained and now only stupid people.
Scott: And now everyone's like Zomgy Wind Waker.
Rym: Thing is, people, the people who complained about that style, I hated them because they were complaining about the wrong thing for the wrong reason.
Rym: OK, they was.
Scott: the point is look at Nintendo's lineup, right?
Scott: And they again, as we all have been complaining on GeekNights since GeekNights has existed since 05, they are not taking advantage of their hardware.
Scott: Their software is not fulfilling the potential that they could be making.
Scott: Of course, there's no Pokemon MMO.
Scott: Right.
Rym: But wait, they're making Wii party.
Scott: What?
Scott: Next, what else they got?
Rym: Eighty brand new party game.
Scott: I mean, there are some games in there that I kind of want to play.
Scott: For example, they got the Smash Brothers coming for the Wii U and the 3DS.
Scott: Good move.
Scott: But that means now I don't have to buy a Wii U. I can just play it on 3DS.
Rym: Now, I have a big worry about it being on the 3DS.
Rym: kind of an aside.
Scott: My worry is going to be the hit in every packs.
Rym: My worry is that it's actually not going to be as good and complex as the previous Smash Brothers and they're going to slightly dumb it down.
Scott: Well, here's the thing, right?
Scott: If the pro Smash Brothers people already complain that was it Melee or which one was second, Melee or Brawl?
Rym: Brawl is the newest one.
Scott: So, so they basically say Melee was the real deal and Brawl basically already dumbed it down.
Rym: too much for them.
Rym: I can see their points.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, you know.
Rym: And having played the new Mario, even on the console, you're already.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: The thing is, Brawl was OK for me because I'm not hardcore about it.
Rym: I also like Melee and I like playing both of them.
Scott: I like playing the original.
Rym: I never really liked the original.
Scott: Same fucking game.
Rym: I didn't like it.
Rym: I never liked it.
Scott: All of them are good.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But having played the Mario Tennis, it just doesn't feel too slow and too sort of dumbed down and easy and timing doesn't matter anymore.
Scott: Nintendo's making all their games easier.
Scott: That's what they've been doing ever since Mario Kart Super Circuit.
Rym: Mario Kart is still not doing much interesting with this separate console, with a separate screen.
Rym: They're doing this kind of basic, lame stuff like, oh, you can keep playing the game when you go take a poop because you only have one TV, but they're not doing the kind of crazy.
Rym: I still think Crystal Chronicles did more with this stuff than almost any game they're releasing.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You know, I was hanging with the Netrunner people.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And we were talking about it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And all of those people also.
Scott: Crystal Chronicles four swords.
Rym: Oh, my God.
Rym: We should just play four swords.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Right now, we were all together in our club of having GameCube GBA hookups and really Deus Ex on the Wii U.
Scott: We already played that on PC a long time ago.
Rym: Now, I can see it working on the Wii U, but they didn't.
Rym: They showed like they zoom in on the person holding the handheld thing.
Rym: And oh, my God, he's got his inventory down there instead of on a separate screen.
Scott: Oh, my God.
Scott: Welcome to the GameCube era.
Rym: Maybe, maybe they'll do something cool where you do the hacking game there while your guy's just still on the screen.
Scott: But getting shot at.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Which happens in the real game.
Scott: OK.
Rym: You try to hack and someone comes around the corner, you're fucked.
Rym: You just start taking damage.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Any other games in there?
Scott: I think the new Yoshi's Island, which is kind of interesting.
Scott: And Yoshi's Island is really good, but I actually never even beat the first Yoshi's Island for Super Nintendo.
Scott: So I got to start working on that.
Rym: This new Mario Kart.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Mario Kart eight.
Scott: See, I actually was wrong on this.
Scott: I thought that, you know, there was strong evidence to suggest that Nintendo considered the 3DS to be the primary platform and the Wii U to be secondary because, for example, right on the on the 3DS, they had new Super Mario Brothers, new Super Mario Brothers, too.
Scott: And on the Wii, they had new Super Mario Brothers, you or Wii U. Right.
Scott: And it's usually, you know, Mario Kart DS.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You'll call Mario Kart and they have Mario Kart DS.
Scott: And when you put the name of the system in the title of the game, you're sort of implying this isn't the mainline version.
Scott: This is sort of the side version.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So when you call Mario new Mario Brothers, the 3DS one, you don't put 3DS in the title.
Scott: You're implying that that's the main one.
Scott: And the one on the Wii U that has Wii U in the title is sort of a second track, you know, the second tier.
Scott: But Mario Kart sevens on the 3DS and Mario Kart eight is on the Wii U. So what the fuck does that tell you?
Rym: Tells me I won't be playing Mario Kart eight anytime soon.
Scott: Well, yeah, but I mean, I think it means that Nintendo doesn't really consider either platform to be primary or secondary.
Rym: Maybe we're Gandalf Gerthing and they're just inconsistent in their naming.
Scott: Now, I don't think they have any logic behind their naming, really.
Rym: Yeah, but there's nothing particularly interesting or innovative from Nintendo.
Rym: It's all kind of just hardcore ports.
Rym: Like, look, we've got big boy games, too, coupled with their basic smash hits.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: The remakes I'm not interested in because I can play the originals, right?
Scott: Most of the baby games and interested in the third party games are all crap.
Scott: There's just a few Nintendo exclusives that I want and pretty much all of them are on 3DS.
Scott: And there isn't even one for Wii U that I can think of.
Scott: that I need to get a Wii U for.
Scott: You know, it's like they got that Wind Waker HD.
Scott: That's a remake.
Scott: Don't need it.
Scott: I have Wind Waker.
Scott: I could play it anytime I want.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: So, I mean, they added some new stuff, but whatever.
Scott: I don't give a shit.
Scott: So the Xbox price, I just want to say, I just want to say you can get a badass gaming PC for $800 that can play pretty much everything on Steam.
Rym: So I just want to say to all you kids out there, because I said it was going to cost $500 a long time ago, and I was ridiculed by certain listeners.
Rym: You told me that I'm old and out of touch and I don't know anything about the market.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: You can all eat a big old dick.
Scott: Bag of dicks.
Scott: EABOD.
Rym: You know, I, while EABOD, the original use was eat a bag of dicks, I like big old dick because it implies...
Scott: I like bag of dicks.
Scott: That is mine.
Scott: Imagine a bag, like a bag of holding with just dicks coming out of it all over the place.
Rym: But what about a guy, just a big old dick, eat a big old dick, like eat a big old crow.
Scott: No, eat a bag of dicks.
Scott: It's better.
Rym: Regardless, I was right.
Rym: You guys are stupid.
Scott: Yeah, and the PlayStation 4 is going to be $400.
Scott: But I assume that extra $100 is the $100 you're not spending on all that TV tuner.
Scott: You know, it's not a cable box like the Xbox.
Rym: Well, adjusted for inflation, the Atari 5200 cost $680.
Rym: That's true.
Rym: In 2006.
Scott: How about that $200 NES in modern dollars?
Scott: Wow.
Scott: The 3DO.
Scott: So all the inflation happened between the $7800 and the NES.
Rym: Remember the 3DO?
Rym: $700.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Interesting.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Oh, well.
Rym: Yeah, well.
Rym: Neo Geo, almost $1000.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, I'm going to say the same thing I say every time...
Rym: Oh no, 3DO adjusted $967.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Scott: I'm going to say the same thing I say every time new consoles comes out, right?
Scott: Pretty much the reason you buy a console is for the games.
Scott: We're already assuming you're not a PC gamer, you're not going to play games on a PC.
Scott: Maybe you just have iPads and Macs, right?
Scott: So you're going to buy a console to play games on.
Scott: Most of the games are on both consoles, right?
Scott: But those are still games you want.
Scott: So you need one of the two consoles to play those games.
Rym: And even if you are a PC gamer, you might want to play the game, the console games online with your gaming people.
Rym: If you're super gamer, I could see someone owning both, especially if like your friends playing Steam while you're on the Xbox.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Like if you, you know, we still don't have cross platform online play.
Scott: So if your friends are playing a game online and they they're all PS3 people, PS4 people, you need a PS4 to play online with them because they're not using Steam, right?
Scott: Anyway, so, you know, you're going to choose one of these things to play the games on.
Scott: So what is the difference really between these two things?
Scott: Well, I guess if you don't have an HDBC and you don't want one, the Xbox is probably going to give you all that stuff you don't have and maybe not mean you don't have to have a cable box, which is kind of good.
Rym: But you've got to have Internet in your living room and all the restrictions we've talked about.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: If you're willing to deal with that, you're willing to deal with it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: To, you know, maybe you don't want to put up with that annoying Internet bullshit.
Scott: And the PlayStation exclusive games are the ones you want.
Scott: As I go with that, it doesn't really matter.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's whichever one has.
Scott: if you want Halo, get Xbox.
Scott: If you want some JRPGs, get a PS4.
Scott: And just if you want and all the games that are not exclusive, get them for whichever one you pick.
Rym: If you want Nintendo games, get a Wii U, get a 3DS.
Scott: I'll get a 3DS.
Scott: No games on a Wii U that you want to use.
Scott: Second, there's not one game for Wii U that I saw that I need.
Rym: Yeah, that is not.
Rym: I don't know if there'll ever be a time I need a Wii U, but I didn't.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Name one Wii U game that you got to have.
Rym: Now, someday there might be one.
Scott: Maybe one is not enough.
Rym: So I have a posit, an idea as to why Microsoft is making the Xbox check in every 24 hours and have online.
Scott: Well, there's a lot of reasons we can guess.
Rym: Yeah, I don't think the Internet part of it has anything to do with DRM or piracy.
Scott: I think it doesn't either, because if they they already basically have as much DRM as they can have on a console, if someone's going to hack the console, they'll just make it play offline.
Scott: So that doesn't protect them from mod chips or anything of the sort.
Rym: It is to be able to drive advertising.
Scott: Of course, they already do drive advertising, but this will make it better.
Rym: It makes sure everyone with one is getting the advertising driven to them.
Scott: Absolutely.
Rym: So it'll force you to at least get some Xbox silver account for free or whatever, and then they'll keep pressuring you to get the more expensive one.
Rym: It'll let them integrate all of their sort of achievement social stuff to to pressure you into buying the games your friends are playing.
Scott: They'll also track everything you do on there, including your TV, watching habits and everything you do, any part of the console.
Scott: And they'll make sure that that data gets sent to them by giving you a strong incentive of your games won't fucking work unless you send us our tracking data.
Rym: And I think they're going to really have a lot more free to play microtransaction games that need that, because otherwise not to be able to pay the real money to get the microtransaction bullshit.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: If you don't have Internet connection, basically free to play is not possible on that platform, right?
Scott: Therefore, they want to make sure that a free to play game is possible for everyone.
Scott: Otherwise, what might happen if someone goes to the store and buys a game that's a free to play game or picks up a free copy of it, right?
Scott: And brings it home to play.
Scott: And they didn't have Internet on.
Scott: their Xbox is like, you know, there hasn't been a game on a disk that is said Internet required to play.
Scott: I don't think there's been one.
Rym: Well, if we go all the way back again to the PC game cube, when you would buy a not not fantasy star that was older.
Scott: No, it was a fan.
Scott: It was a fantasy star online.
Scott: I don't know if it was on GameCube.
Scott: I think there was a GameCube MMO that was a fantasy star online, too.
Scott: It might have been fantasy star online, too.
Rym: You ever played a fantasy star game?
Rym: No, no.
Rym: windows, PlayStation, Vita, iOS.
Scott: What was the GameCube GameCube MMO fantasy star online?
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: Regular PSO was on the GameCube.
Scott: OK, yeah, there you go.
Rym: OK, there we go.
Scott: So I guess you needed Internet for that to work.
Scott: I remember Scott Johnson.
Rym: Well, there was that.
Rym: there was that single player.
Rym: There was that adapter to the dream cast into your broadband back in the day.
Scott: So the GameCube had the modem.
Rym: Yeah, which I guess was only ever.
Scott: PlayStation two had a modem.
Rym: I guess those things are only ever used for fantasy star online.
Rym: But I worry that this is going to go one step further.
Rym: The really I feel like whenever people have these kinds of DRM systems nowadays, they're doing it also to prevent you from fucking around and cheating in your local single player games so that they can then have the microtransactions and have the sort of progression of achievements between you and all your friends and make it still feel cool.
Scott: But they're not preventing anyone from cheating, because look how many people cheat at Xbox games anyway.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And stuff that's online.
Rym: Pac-Man, CEDX is leaderboard.
Rym: Yeah, seriously.
Scott: Speaking of which, new maps for Pac-Man, CEDX.
Scott: Now, I really want to get rid of my Xbox 360 to write, but Pac-Man, CEDX and a few other games that I have on there, that many right that I paid for, that I feel bad because I paid for them.
Rym: I got Pac-Man.
Rym: I got a half minute hero.
Scott: Yeah, stuff like that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's like, damn it, I made the mistake of getting an Xbox.
Scott: And if I get rid of it, I lose those games, basically.
Scott: But Pac-Man, CEDX is the only one I really care about.
Scott: And it's on Windows eight only.
Scott: It's like, damn it.
Scott: I'm going to buy Windows eight just so I can get Pac-Man, CEDX on my HDPC.
Rym: Really?
Scott: Really?
Scott: Just let me get rid of this Xbox out from under my TV.
Scott: I think I'll just let it sit down there and collect dust and play Pac-Man when I want to.
Scott: Yeah, I already paid for it.
Rym: But basically, I took the list of every game that's been announced from E3 and just in the last several weeks.
Rym: And 90 percent of the ones I want to buy.
Rym: I've already been announced that they'll be on PC.
Rym: Yeah, so or 3DS probably just going to upgrade my video card because it'll cost less than an Xbox to upgrade.
Rym: Mm hmm.
Scott: Anything else really to say about all these events that have happened at the E3?
Rym: Not really.
Rym: It's interesting watching the Internet go crazy about Sony's announcement and already start declaring Sony the winner.
Rym: And while they won the PR coup, never forget that normal console gamers have no idea what happened.
Scott: No, they have no fucking clue.
Scott: Let me tell you, these people, the vast majority of the people who buy these consoles and these games do not Internet.
Scott: They do not even know there is a PlayStation four announced.
Scott: They do not know there is an Xbox one announced.
Scott: They don't know anything about them.
Scott: They will tell you they don't know what DRM is around the water cooler.
Rym: Like, yeah, I heard there's a new Zelda game coming out for the Wii U. It's totally brand new and it's in 3D.
Rym: And they won't realize it's that remake of Link to the Past.
Scott: They don't know.
Scott: Well, that's for 3DS.
Scott: Well, yeah, they have no idea anything that's going on.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Right.
Rym: For 3DS was the point of my anecdote.
Rym: Oh, OK.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They are clueless.
Scott: And those people are just going to buy based on brand, most likely the same way they vote for president.
Scott: And if they're Halo Call of Duty people, they're going to buy Xbox ones.
Scott: And if they're the other kind, if they're Gran Turismo people, they're going to buy PlayStations.
Scott: And that's how it's going to be.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: All that other stuff that nerds care about will not matter.
Rym: Yeah, especially the things about DRM and the things about used games.
Scott: Remember how in the PlayStation three came out, all the nerds were down on it?
Scott: Well, it did OK.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion, news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.