Rym: It's Monday September 9th, 2013.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight's Motherboards, I can't believe we haven't talked about motherboards or have we?
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: Well, we're back legit from packs.
Rym: Yep, and now we got pretty much nothing until magfest.
Rym: Oh Not yet, I'm not.
Rym: I'm not gonna do the Second half of that until it's within a month.
Rym: It's mag fest.
Rym: season is kind of like the lead-up to Christmas.
Rym: You can't bring out that Christmas tree at least until after Meg.
Scott: This is effectively replaced Christmas Hanukkah, whatever You know, you don't celebrate that shit.
Scott: It's just fucking new year's.
Scott: miss New Year's mag fest.
Scott: That is what is coming.
Scott: Fuck everything else.
Rym: I almost regret not going to one of those New Year's mag fest But at the same time I kind of like my own New Year's.
Rym: so I like the fact that now we're gonna go to mag fest After having New Year's in the same town as mag fest, but not at mag fest.
Scott: Well, there are a few things people should know.
Scott: Next weekend the 21st and 22nd is the Maker Faire, New York City.
Rym: That's the following weekend.
Rym: Oh, no.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: I said the 21st in the 22nd.
Rym: Yeah Not this weekend next.
Rym: you did it right for once.
Rym: Usually I jump all on you for doing that wrong.
Rym: I apologize.
Rym: Anyway, I was incorrect.
Scott: October 18 1920 Burning con.
Scott: 2013 the pentec logon.
Rym: you still buy tickets.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I still got to submit my game.
Scott: Yep, I might miss Saturday.
Rym: What?
Scott: there is a netrunner tournament?
Scott: Really?
Scott: No, okay, so Normally I would be like netrunner tournament.
Scott: There's like two netrunner tournaments and one and there's one burning con a year.
Rym: So Saturday is the heavy-hitting day.
Scott: Why why would I skip the heavy-hitting day of burning con?
Scott: For a netrunner tournament of which there are two a month when there is only one burning con a year?
Scott: that is just fucking stupid.
Scott: right and Normally, I would but this isn't just any netrunner tournament.
Rym: Okay?
Scott: This is the netrunner plugged in tour.
Scott: They're basically the fantasy flight.
Scott: peoples are traveling around the country to only a handful of places to run basically super netrunner tournaments between October 4th, so November 3rd netrunner tournament from a regular one.
Scott: Basically, the official dudes are gonna be there and it's all super serious business and they're giving away.
Scott: I don't care about the sweat rare cards.
Scott: No, it's just swag like play mats and stuff.
Scott: I don't care about that shit.
Scott: okay, but if you go to one of these you can vote.
Scott: there's two runners and You vote on which one you want to be real and then whichever one wins all the voting and it's only voting by people at These tournaments will become an actual runner card and the other one will be forever.
Rym: D rezzed great So rainbow - is gonna be the next row.
Scott: No, it's this.
Scott: the two choices are right.
Scott: here There's the collective and there's Laramie Fisk.
Rym: I vote for Laramie Fisk.
Scott: I also vote for Laramie Fisk simply because he's not only better in every way.
Rym: He's better in one way his name.
Scott: Yeah He's a criminal and we got the other ones a shaper and we have plenty of shapers.
Scott: So the collective what that one does is this the first time you perform the same action three times in a row each turn Gain a click which is pretty powerful because like if you're running a magnum opus with those guys You could just be like magnum
Rym: magnum
Scott: magnum
Rym: Magnum
Scott: exactly,
Rym: but
Scott: their minimum deck size is 55.
Rym: well 50 I thought you were gonna say 50.
Scott: No, it's big 50.
Scott: They have to have a big deck and their influence is 5.
Scott: So it's pretty much shape for cards and more shape for cards and not gonna play with ya Laramie Fisk.
Scott: He's normal He's a criminal 4515 normal numbers and it says the first time you make a successful run on a central server each turn You may force the corp to draw one card When their hand is full.
Scott: with five cards you run HQ.
Scott: you take a look.
Scott: see maybe with a nerve agent or an HQ interface.
Scott: Then if they still have five cards, you know now they've got six and then their turn starts and they draw another one.
Scott: now they got seven and They're gonna have to throw something out or use it all or something.
Scott: and so run HQ again with your HQ interface.
Rym: Scott Point.
Rym: the first it's not Tuesday It's Monday.
Scott: All right point.
Rym: the second you always give me shit for talking about this shit in the non meta moment section of the show.
Rym: That's true.
Rym: So what gives?
Scott: it's an intentional Back attack up.
Rym: So you realize all you have done is given me carte blanche.
Rym: No You legitimize me Scott.
Rym: Not at all.
Rym: And if you and Emily have learned anything about me, it's that legitimizing Me is the last thing you want to do.
Scott: Did you right?
Scott: did not try to shut me down.
Rym: I let you talk for almost five minutes about netrunner.
Rym: Yeah Monday show But you're.
Rym: you have noted that it was not good.
Rym: Have you not so are you so therefore or not?
Scott: If my netrunner talk was no good Then also all your talks are no good.
Rym: only meta talks.
Scott: in the pre meta all your talks are belong to crap.
Rym: So Up on new video card.
Rym: about time.
Rym: I've been rocking a GTX 260.
Scott: That's not a bad card that can play a lot of games.
Scott: What game what game out today.
Scott: counter-strike go needs a better card than counter-strike go.
Scott: How does counter-strike go not run at full frames of the 260 Scott?
Rym: It doesn't really.
Rym: yeah No, so actually it will run at full frames.
Scott: It's not full quality.
Rym: by cutting your draw distance big deal.
Rym: I don't think you understand how narrow My draw distance is between my body and what I can hit in pretty much any map.
Rym: if there's a window And I want to snipe in that window.
Rym: I cannot see beyond the window.
Rym: Sometimes I can't even see the window.
Scott: that sounds more like reflections than draw distance.
Scott: No window in behind the window either.
Scott: So just shoot.
Scott: It's a window.
Rym: There might not be someone there.
Scott: So you wasted some bullets?
Rym: Also the windows big and I can't see where to shoot it is.
Rym: having a 260 has Significantly impacted my ability to win.
Scott: you get a gun that fucking zooms.
Rym: Oh, yeah, it zooms into nothing.
Rym: You can't see player models that far away if there's no window.
Rym: I can't see if there's a person.
Scott: So so if there is a person there he kills you and you can't even see him.
Scott: Yes, that sucks.
Rym: Yes, the GTX 260 is too old.
Scott: What do you just turn down like the texture qualities and increase the other?
Rym: you can't control the draw distance.
Rym: as far as I can Tell it's all dynamic.
Rym: Anyway, also details Disappear to a surprising degree and they do it so well that you don't notice it.
Rym: But if you're paying attention at all, like you're running and suddenly a tree like all these leaves appear on it Oh my my 680.
Scott: don't know what that's like.
Rym: Yeah, you know what.
Rym: my 770 didn't cost that much.
Scott: No, it didn't fry for the my 680 by a lot, but Adobe will just recognize Adobe.
Rym: You'll have recognized 770 now.
Scott: Good yeah, in fact, I got their fucking shit together asshole.
Rym: I got Adobe to recognize my 260.
Scott: nice doesn't work.
Rym: So well, no with some hacks.
Rym: No, you can basically tell it in Creative Commons.
Rym: You can be like yo dog Creative Commons.
Rym: Yeah Creative Cloud you can be like yo dog.
Rym: use my video card and if it's not and if it's not on the list.
Rym: It'll be like yo dog.
Rym: I won't guarantee.
Rym: I'm not gonna crash.
Scott: but okay Speaking of creative cloud.
Scott: I didn't actually have a news But you just reminded me of a news the Photoshop news.
Scott: Yeah, but there's a second news.
Scott: All right, those two Photoshop related news is lay down the news.
Scott: one Photoshop related news.
Scott: They now have creative cloud Photographer Edition.
Scott: you pay ten bucks a month.
Scott: I think there's a limited time deal.
Scott: So if you want it get it right away.
Rym: You said they have no plans to raise the price in the foreseeable future.
Scott: That's good.
Rym: granted We know that Adobe can finish saying what the hell this is about exactly one year.
Scott: Ten bucks a month.
Scott: you get the full Photoshop the real deal and The full Lightroom the real deal with perfect upgrades forever.
Scott: Just like all the other creative cloud stuff Yep, and you get some other stuff like a Behance account and all that stuff You don't gonna use and it's only ten bucks a month now.
Scott: That's a hundred and twenty dollars a year.
Scott: This is for the real Photoshop.
Scott: This finally a reasonable price for a big expensive software.
Scott: This has never happened before.
Rym: it's huge for another reason to the biggest complaint That was semi legitimate against creative cloud because most people complaining are morons.
Rym: They don't realize that paying that monthly fee is actually way less than buying the full editions all the time.
Scott: Well, it's only cheaper if you upgrade all the time.
Scott: If you never if you buy the full creative suite and never up ever then you're better off doing that.
Scott: No I'm the creator only.
Rym: you were only better off if you bought one of those limited subsets because you didn't use the rest of it To buy everything everything the master suite.
Rym: Yeah, it was expensive.
Rym: Yep, but like a production premium Yeah, I could have gotten away.
Rym: I was just keeping my cs4 anyway, but anyway, the biggest legitimate complaint was that Photoshop is special in that there's a huge huge number of people whose profession is photography or who are Serious photography hobbyist.
Scott: There's a lot of people the only goddamn thing they need is photo.
Scott: Need all that That Photoshop is used more than all those other things combined.
Rym: I'm gonna use more than one Adobe thing.
Rym: You probably use like five or ten Adobe things or you just use Photoshop and Lightroom.
Scott: Yeah, even most people use Photoshop not even Lightroom I know.
Rym: but now just like how with creative cloud suddenly people started using Adobe They normally didn't use like I started using in design and illustrator because before I didn't have it.
Scott: But now what I learned, you know typekit where all the fonts come from.
Scott: Yeah Creative cloud the one we pay for actually includes a very high class typekit account.
Scott: I thought I had to pay for those fonts and it was just an integrated thing.
Scott: I already paid for those fonts without even knowing Yeah I can just go get fonts and use them all I want and if I use them on a website I can do That too.
Scott: as long as I don't the website doesn't get a fuck ton of traffic.
Scott: and then I had to pay a little bit of money.
Scott: But as long as the website just doesn't get crazy traffic I can use those fonts on a website Or anything I want.
Rym: so you you implied that there was another piece to your news.
Scott: Alright, so the second piece Photoshop added a feature today.
Scott: That is incredibly interesting.
Scott: There's a lot of people out there, you know Photoshop is.
Scott: it is a tool of many uses.
Scott: many uses not intended, right?
Scott: It was originally intended for photo editing Yep.
Scott: And now people use it for three like in every raster image any any imaging thing period.
Scott: they use Photoshop, right?
Scott: One thing people use Photoshop for is to draw websites and they basically draw a picture of a website and then cut it up into Pieces and make a website.
Rym: I'm gonna flash back to the year 2000.
Rym: Yeah I was at RIT and we're going to.
Rym: I'm taking my Intro to new media class and they're like make a website.
Rym: and they told us and they gave us the software to draw it But not in Photoshop.
Rym: They were like the noobs would use Photoshop for this but your pros we got to use fireworks Which is dead now fireworks 3.0 right alongside Macromedia director, right?
Scott: So anyway, the new feature they added to Photoshop was basically sort of what Microsoft is an Excel move, right?
Scott: Excel people like Microsoft is like you're gonna use Excel for that fine.
Scott: We'll help you out and make that better.
Scott: So Adobe is basically fine.
Scott: You want to use Photoshop to draw websites and not use all this edge and stuff that we made for you.
Scott: fine.
Scott: Here's this feature.
Scott: So what the feature is this you draw a website you keep all the pieces of the website in different layers, right?
Scott: And you tell it hey Photoshop.
Scott: I'm drawing a website.
Scott: Yo, it says alright, bro I got you.
Scott: every layer is then turned into a JPEG GIF or ping and put into a folder and It's constantly updated.
Scott: So as you edit the layer It'll update the JPEG the GIF or the ping in that folder so that you can just go reload.
Scott: You can edit the Photoshop reload your website edit the Photoshop reload the website.
Scott: That's on your local machine until it looks right.
Rym: that is actually, you know, I'm not gonna make fun of it.
Rym: It's an excellent example of use case driven design philosophy.
Scott: That is a crazy good feature.
Scott: if you're making websites and photo Yeah That efficiency gain you get from that feature.
Rym: zoom out a little bit off the hook when people make software.
Rym: in general Way too many people for websites for software design for everything.
Rym: They have a vision of what their things should be used Yeah, and they strive toward that.
Rym: no look at what people actually try to do and make that easier.
Scott: Yeah, it's like think about what the workflow was before it was going to Photoshop.
Scott: Yeah Edit a bunch of stuff Cut a piece out save it in a separate folder and every time you wanted to cut a piece out save it in a separate Folder.
Scott: now, it's just always.
Scott: maybe you were checking.
Scott: There's no cutting.
Scott: There's no cutting none.
Scott: No cutting other than the layers which you should be just automatic is it's automatically a full a folder full of files.
Scott: automatic not bad It's gonna save people like hours a day who do this stuff.
Rym: if Except some of the people who should use that kind of feature the ones who won't or they don't know about it yet because it's Only in the newest newest Photoshop people have 3 and refused to upgrade.
Scott: Yeah, it's only in the creative cloud Photoshop if you pay for the you know $10 or the more dollars.
Rym: so in all this talk about the NSA and encryption.
Scott: and Have we not talked about this enough?
Scott: We've been talking about this since forever.
Rym: Oh, well one we haven't talked about it that much.
Scott: on GeekNights did a whole episode Multiple episodes on privacy and encryption and security.
Rym: Yeah, we didn't talk about the NSA stuff.
Rym: but in all of that it seems like people talk about bitcoins a lot too and My news is to remind you that they're not that related.
Rym: no bitcoins are not anonymous.
Rym: No guys, they're not.
Rym: They're pseudo anonymous.
Rym: They're Intrinsic is the word you should use.
Rym: but they are not anonymous because there's the thing called a blockchain Which is how the whole goddamn thing works.
Rym: So this researcher took a Bitcoin Analyzed his blockchain and it was like right there.
Rym: That's where the guy bought drugs on Silk Road and figured out how you can basically track what people have done with bitcoins And there's a good chance you could track the actual person that did the transaction if you really wanted to.
Rym: Okay now People could take steps to a doubly triply anonymize and use services and everything.
Rym: But the fact remains that Bitcoins primary use is not that it's anonymous It's that it's intrinsic and you can use it without trusting the other person you're doing business with.
Rym: Mmm It's almost like a cash escrow except the cash is all virtual.
Rym: So if you think you can use bitcoins to do anonymous shady stuff, I recommend you read this article.
Rym: I got one more little news.
Rym: That one was little.
Rym: so, uh There I heard there's a lot of sexism in the universe.
Rym: In the tech industry in particular.
Scott: there's a high concentration of it in that particular place.
Scott: That's sort of where it comes from these days.
Rym: Yeah, it pretty much comes from the MRA subreddit and from the tech industry, but So those aren't the same thing.
Rym: And I don't think a lot of people who post to MRA actually made it to the tech industry.
Rym: I think they're wishing they could be in the tech industry, but haven't actually quite gotten there.
Scott: They get closer to their to their Mecca but Some people, two dudes.
Rym: Oh, I think I have their names here from Sydney.
Scott: Uh, JethroBots Great name.
Rym: David Bolton.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: At a TechCrunch event.
Scott: Oh Great.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Already this is looking worse and worse every second.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: Disrupt, which is a hackathon It's it's pretty much the worst thing ever.
Rym: They presented their joke app and it was supposed to be a joke and their joke app was TitStare.
Scott: Wow great job guys, that's gonna win them over.
Rym: Yeah It was pretty bad and I see a lot of the internet starting to try to defend them like look guys What?
Rym: No.
Rym: What?
Rym: Just stop it.
Scott: WAT what?
Rym: Yes Anytime you forget how egregious this shit is.
Rym: This is just to remind you that shit like this happens at these conferences Pretty much all the time.
Scott: Do you even internet?
Rym: For every one scandal that happens that a PAX are related to a PAX There's like a hundred related to tech conferences and they're way worse and it's like how clueless are these people?
Rym: They did apologize, but it looks like it's because they were forced to by TechCrunch.
Scott: Yeah, TechCrunch is also not the greatest.
Rym: Yeah, but at least they put the token effort forth.
Rym: Sure The thing is the app itself what it does were it not a Joke and were it not presented in this way could actually be cool.
Rym: because the idea is let's say I buy a new video card Right.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So here's what I was the app I would make.
Rym: I'd call it unboxing and use some clever web 3.0 spelling of boxing.
Rym: Yeah So I take my video card and I hold my phone up.
Rym: one camera is pointed at the package The other one's pointed at my face.
Rym: I Unbox it live and it videos the unboxing and my reaction to the unboxing at the same time.
Scott: Why don't we just make a app called double cam that videos both cameras at the same time?
Rym: But I would call it unboxing and really sell it as and in.
Rym: have the site be all about.
Rym: you set you tag What you unboxed so you can go to the site and be like video cards GTX 770 and you'll get all the unboxing videos of people who just got that or their own people would like Photoshop.
Scott: people would end Up using it just for the double cam part and oh, you know what?
Rym: That's great.
Rym: But having that conceit like vine or like Instagram gets it that initial cachet among morons.
Rym: Yeah So yeah guys make this app.
Rym: just don't make it hit stare.
Rym: but anyway things of the day Ever wonder why we can't use our phones on planes.
Rym: Bullshit, this video is not what you expect and it is.
Rym: it is great Cuz.
Scott: it would annoy the fuck out of everyone else on the play.
Rym: the conceit of this videos.
Rym: The stewardess is like make sure you turn off your cell phones and this guy's like why?
Rym: Like really why?
Rym: I just want to know I'll turn it off.
Rym: just explain to me why.
Rym: and she explained so like, okay But okay, how come?
Rym: I've turned off my Kindle and it just escalates.
Rym: this one woman's like wait a minute So can I hold the plane hostage with my 3ds?
Rym: And it just goes off from there.
Rym: This is an excellent video and I just want to point out that part of this video is kind of true.
Rym: I have flown Around the world With work blackberries that I always forget to turn off.
Rym: They're just on in my carry-on the whole time when I was on the flight to Australia.
Scott: There were some other packs people on that plane and and they played Wireless Mario Kart in flight and didn't give a fuck with each other.
Rym: I on our flight home from fax as soon as the Stewardess walked past me after telling everyone to turn everything off.
Rym: I just turned my Kindle back on and kept reading and the plane didn't crash.
Scott: Yeah, you know what?
Scott: Most people I see on planes.
Scott: It's like you're supposed to turn your shit off off.
Rym: Oh, I've never ever turned my.
Rym: no I've never seen anyone on the plane actually put the phone in autistic mode and that's it.
Scott: Yeah, they just freaking you know, they don't even really do airplane.
Scott: But sometimes they do airplane mode most of the time, but most people just friggin just put the phone away.
Scott: They like click it.
Scott: It's the screen goes blank.
Scott: They think that's off And sometimes just cuz they're dumb and not you know, so yeah, that's what I got.
Rym: It's pretty funny.
Scott: Okay I got so when I was a kid, I watched a lot of kids shows Eman and One of them is one that I did not watch but I know about that Rym watch.
Rym: Oh m dot a dot s dot K.
Scott: No, Oh Thomas the te.
Scott: Oh You saw this video.
Rym: Oh my god.
Scott: This is a super cut doo-doo-doo-doo-doo-doo of Thomas the tank engine.
Rym: Do train crashes and not some of that shining time station bullshit.
Rym: We're talking about the actual Thomas the Tank Engine show.
Rym: Yeah, you know who mr.
Rym: Conductor was on shining time station.
Scott: Well, there were two.
Scott: Yeah, there's Ringo Starr.
Scott: No and George Carlin.
Scott: Yeah I did not Appreciate who either of them was when I was very small.
Rym: you want to know something that really says a lot about my childhood.
Rym: I didn't know who Ringo Starr what like.
Rym: I didn't know that was Ringo Starr.
Rym: Not when I didn't understand that for a while, but I knew that was George Carlin from the beginning.
Rym: I think that says more about my parents than about me.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't watch either one.
Rym: this is actually a pretty good video in the meta moment.
Rym: wait Scott already ruined the meta moment.
Rym: It's over.
Rym: Oh What do we do now?
Scott: book club book.
Rym: the book club book is Stasi land.
Rym: I keep forgetting to update the website.
Rym: I'm gonna update the website ten nights.
Scott: I keep forgetting to read it.
Rym: It's pretty good.
Rym: And again, I can't stress this enough The reason I want you to read this book is because you're not nearly mad enough about the NSA.
Scott: Why would I read a book when I could just watch salty bit?
Scott: Okay, I guess other metas You might have discovered us because you saw us at PAX.
Scott: Yeah, you can go and check us out everywhere on the internet that there are things You know how many of our videos of other packs panels are on YouTube?
Scott: how many videos of things in general are on YouTube?
Scott: I just got I bought an elgato cap game capture HD, and I was just to test it it out.
Scott: I'm just streaming me playing games real soon.
Rym: You're gonna seem to like it for some reason I think you're gonna get Scott and mines are regular outlaw matches.
Scott: Maybe I don't know how we're gonna plug the Atari into the elgato.
Rym: It's got our CA out.
Scott: I don't know it needs component out.
Scott: It's a game capture HD.
Rym: God damn it.
Rym: Is there an elgato SD?
Scott: There is.
Scott: I don't have it.
Rym: Use the Atari emulator, maybe What other.
Scott: yeah, but check us out on the Twitter's the Facebook's the Google pluses Google the forum on our own website our forums pretty awesome.
Scott: and Rym has a tumble.
Rym: I do have a tumble.
Scott: I have some blogs.
Scott: I never update once a year.
Scott: Yeah I don't know all the places on the internet that you go.
Scott: We're there follow us and shit.
Rym: Yes, and we'll be at magfest and Emily, and I and Caldwell will be at SPX this coming weekend If you live it, then you were in your DC.
Rym: You should go to SPX.
Scott: I'm too busy for that shit.
Rym: Yeah, what are you gonna?
Rym: Play netrunner salty bet salty bet and netrunner.
Rym: someone's gonna make the salty bet app Just on your phone.
Scott: I would just salty bet all day, but in your Google glass just oh my god It just anytime there's a new person to bet on.
Scott: it's like all right.
Scott: Who is it reverse you know?
Scott: Waifu.
Scott: I always bet waifu ten bucks on waifu.
Scott: I just say ten bucks.
Scott: I got ten bucks on waifu and then he just takes the bet and then it shows me the result and then shows me the Next contenders.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: I just watched this match where it said Goku Goku.
Scott: I think our next Tuesday show was salty bets.
Scott: I think it is so no show no talking.
Rym: right now I'm gonna spoil just so you guys know to listen to that show I watched a match.
Rym: this character's name was Goku Goku And there was nothing there.
Scott: Nothing why I watched a fight yesterday.
Scott: It was I forget who against Mike Tyson as in punch-out Mike Tyson all in on Tyson.
Scott: I was all in on Tyson, and that was not a bad idea.
Scott: No one fucks at the champ.
Scott: Iron Mike was made of iron.
Rym: So I can't believe we never did a show on motherboards.
Scott: I hope we didn't.
Rym: I searched our website and maybe Interesting to see if our opinions on motherboards have changed since the last time we did a show.
Rym: if we have in fact talked about mother I hope we haven't.
Scott: but yeah, I searched our archives didn't find an episode.
Scott: I think I searched on Newegg And I said what part of a computer haven't we done a show on?
Rym: and I know when we got to the point of like.
Scott: See optical drives CD R double you dig in the bottom of the barrel.
Scott: But again the motherboard is the most important part of the computer.
Scott: Have we not done a show on it Now?
Rym: I'm sure we've talked about them in a secondary sense in our like how to build a PC.
Rym: I'm sure we have yeah, but Motherboard actually kind of matters less than it used to.
Scott: in some ways it matters more and in some ways it matters less.
Scott: It matters more.
Scott: and that it's called the motherboard for a reason right.
Scott: like the mothership It is the core it is the computer.
Scott: most of it right it is like the important part that connects everything together.
Rym: But at the same time the processor does know what the processor does.
Scott: the work, but all everything goes through the motherboard.
Rym: Right, but it's interesting if you grab made a graph of like how important the decision of your motherboard is.
Rym: You basically didn't have a choice until I mean the era of people building their own computers who weren't Mid to late 90s.
Rym: Yeah, like you people didn't build their own 46. is that commonly?
Scott: Yeah, it happened much more.
Scott: when the Pentium lines came out is when computer building started to appear and not really until the Pentium Pro 2 did it really start to have.
Rym: yeah that in the when the AMD k6 chips came.
Scott: That's when modern PC building really started to happen.
Rym: Yeah That is when you'd go to egghead.com and you'd spend an entire week doing research on This motherboard computer.
Rym: when you computer shopper magazine was around in the late 90s You know, but the modern sensibility of picking all your components and building a computer Widespread.
Scott: no computer shopper magazine was the only way to do it before Internet's really took over before Egghead.com.
Rym: that was not something I did.
Rym: the first computer I built it was a k7.
Scott: Yeah, the k7 was when first one I built was a Pentium 3.
Rym: Yeah, I did not build a Pentium.
Rym: I never built a Pentium back at first.
Scott: so speaking of motherboards, right?
Scott: So the most important part of the motherboard is basically the North Bridge South Bridge and that's basically been the way motherboards have been made For a long ass time.
Scott: It used to matter a lot what you picked yeah, but basically there's these chips on the motherboard that are the North Bridge in the South Bridge and those do all the work of.
Scott: You know getting the memory to talk to the you know processor to talk to the video ports right to do all this sort of other stuff to talk to the the IO ports with the SATAs and all that kind of stuff is all in the North Bridge in the South Bridge.
Scott: It's split between these two chips.
Scott: all right and When I first bought a computer it was a for Intel 440 BX The most reliable chip set on earth.
Rym: that PC ran forever.
Scott: that Pentium 3450 never died when I thought it was dead.
Scott: It was actually the power supply, and I didn't realize it.
Scott: when I got a new power supply It just worked again.
Rym: It wasn't so much that it the hardware didn't die It was also that it was just really stable, but I think that was partly due to the fact that Younger kids might not remember.
Rym: home-built computers used to be mad unstable.
Rym: If you didn't know what you were doing you had to actually do a lot of research like all right setting up all these timings And the bio and voltages this via chipset.
Rym: But if I buy this video card it might not work unless I change the clock on this.
Rym: or well I bought this one kind of RAM.
Rym: I gotta up the voltage a tiny bit to make it work.
Rym: But if I up it too much, it'll burn out modern BIOS's.
Scott: and now EFI which is in most motherboards Just automatically does all that shit correctly almost all the time.
Rym: I remember the first time I overclocked with my a bit motherboard So excited no one in there And I up the multiplier and it wouldn't fucking post because that was a mistake.
Rym: and then instead I increase the FSB Yeah from a hundred megahertz to a hundred and thirty three megahertz.
Rym: oh That was a huge Huge performance gain and It also crashed about once a week.
Rym: playing Counter-Strike More frames right.
Scott: so when you're shopping for motherboards You're gonna see they're gonna tell you sort of like what the what kind of chipset is on there right in terms of North and South Bridge and in turn I don't know all of them these days But I know the Intel ones is sort of split between the ones that have the letter Z and the ones that don't and the ones Z. those tend to have like these integrated video cards and stuff like that going on and the ones without the Z. Those don't have that.
Scott: those are more like just motherboards.
Rym: Yep You know now if we're talking about advice on buying motherboards what it really comes down to nowadays is the more expensive ones usually aren't Better.
Rym: they just have more features that you probably don't need.
Scott: right and time.
Scott: I'm practically speaking right.
Scott: when you buy a motherboard today It's all about how many connectors does it have of which kinds?
Scott: right?
Scott: so you know it's like how many USB ports Can I get on this thing?
Scott: how many do you need?
Rym: I need a lot of fucking USB ports?
Rym: I don't want to buy USB hub Scott said connectors for the longest time.
Rym: I would look at a spec on a motherboard.
Rym: I'd be like all right.
Rym: I need at least two ISAs and I need like six PC eyes because what I'd have sound card MIDI card Separate game controller card video card they used to not be like AGP or all these.
Rym: we have like those things in My SCSI card another hard drive control.
Scott: Mike and my old my Pentium 3 had so many cards.
Scott: my computer now has a video card.
Rym: I know.
Rym: I don't.
Rym: I don't think I've put our card.
Rym: that wasn't a video card in any computer.
Rym: I've built since 2000 and 2000. yeah, nope I put the sound card the the PCI sound card Into the computer I built around 2004. okay, it had one PCI legacy slot for that sound card.
Scott: cool But yeah, it's all about how many connectors slots are still sort of important if you're gonna put stuff in them But there's just less stuff to put in them these days.
Scott: How many RAM slots are there?
Scott: right?
Scott: how many Really important?
Scott: how many s ATA connectors are there?
Scott: So how many drives can you connect?
Scott: does it even have a floppy connector?
Scott: if you have an old floppy drive does it even have?
Scott: Old IDE connectors?
Scott: if you have really old hard drives You know or maybe your CD ROM isn't s ATA and it needs an old.
Scott: You know ID ribbon table You know what.
Rym: seriously don't bother with ID.
Rym: if you if you have any device that needs ID Get an external thing.
Scott: we get all the data at it.
Rym: No, just buy a new one of that device.
Rym: a CD RW is like 12 bucks.
Scott: That's true You know.
Scott: does the motherboard have connectors for like you know all the audio inputs.
Scott: on the front of your case I?
Rym: Would argue you don't want to use the onboard sound anyway.
Scott: Yeah, well does it have?
Scott: well most people?
Rym: Motherboard supports that.
Scott: sure you know they have every month.
Rym: No.
Rym: There's two standards would be deprecating.
Scott: It could be in a different spot on the motherboard.
Scott: It's annoying to connect to.
Scott: you know.
Scott: the arrangement of the things on the motherboard also matters a lot because if you pair up a Motherboard with a case it's like it's ATX ATX.
Scott: Yeah, it'll fit, but will the wiring be nice?
Scott: I know.
Rym: I would argue that the case matters way more than the motherboard in the modern era because there's very little variation in motherboards.
Scott: There's still some variation.
Scott: like if you use this motherboard with a case that has a bottom power supply instead of a top power supply Suddenly the wirings janky because the power connector on the motherboards in a weird spot Except the power connectors are almost always in the same spot almost always.
Scott: But there's other connectors on the back of the computer that are important like if you've got the onboard video card Is there an HDMI or just a VGA or a DVI?
Rym: I have not yet looked.
Rym: I've been clicking on like 10 motherboards here.
Rym: I've not yet found one that didn't have HDMI.
Scott: if it had integrated video does it still have ps2 mouse and keyboard if you need?
Rym: I know I have not seen one yet.
Rym: That does not have that does the?
Scott: how many USB threes are there versus USB twos?
Scott: How many fire wires are that doesn't even have fire wires?
Scott: is the onboard sound card?
Scott: It just stereo sound or is it surround sound?
Scott: does it have optical out or just the analog audio out?
Rym: But I guess the point we're getting at and then Scott's really getting at here.
Rym: The feature set is what matters now not the back end Performancy stuff that used to matter or the compatibility stuff that used to matter.
Rym: Yeah You can just pick a motherboard that has the features you want and if there's two that are pretty much equal and one cost more Money look at them side by side.
Rym: most likely the more expensive one just has extra stuff more USB more SATA a Dedicated say to controller with rage.
Scott: Well more expensive one could also be smaller.
Scott: smaller is usually more money Except for when it's just not as good, right?
Rym: You know like thing is again that's more limited by case and whether or not you want a game or video card.
Rym: Yep, there's also a factor ATX AT micro.
Scott: of course There's also some other boards that is made with better components like more better capacitors that are all solid-state might raise the price.
Scott: Name brand raises the price.
Rym: Yep, but what is the name brand?
Rym: Cuz when I the last time I was buying motherboards It was pretty much you bought a bit if you overclocked and wanted features.
Rym: you bought aces if you never wanted it to crash.
Rym: Pretty much.
Scott: It doesn't matter what.
Scott: as far as I can tell, you know, there's no name brand.
Scott: That is just better than the others.
Scott: It's pretty much.
Scott: is it name brand or not name brand?
Rym: Is it anything other than aces a bit gigabyte MSI?
Scott: Right.
Scott: Is it not?
Scott: is it one of the known motherboard brands or is it not one of those brands?
Scott: Is it like some ghetto brand right?
Scott: Like I have an ASRock.
Scott: That's a pretty much.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: That's a pretty well-known brand.
Rym: It's actually really popular for HTTPS.
Scott: Yeah, there's a lot of ones out there that are the big brands.
Scott: But there are other brands out there like I'm pretty you know, I know star Biostar, but then you get into the second tier.
Rym: I think all right new egg only lists six Alrighty, then aces ASRock gigabyte MSI ECS biostar.
Scott: ECS is the only one that I've never heard of.
Rym: Let me look at these ECS motherboards.
Rym: Let's see there They look like motherboards.
Rym: They're as expensive as the other brands.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Wait a minute.
Rym: This was only 50 bucks.
Rym: Let's see what's going on here.
Scott: Yeah every motherboard manufacturer seems to have a full lineup from the cheapest to the most expensive with lots of Variations and it's like I really wonder like how many people are buying each of these slight variations.
Scott: I know that it matters shouldn't?
Scott: they have like fewer motherboards of like just like.
Scott: here's the crazy gamer one with a million slots.
Scott: Here's the sort of normal one with a regular number of slots.
Scott: Here's an 8 micro ATX that has like one video card hole.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: What else?
Scott: what else do you need guys?
Scott: Really?
Rym: Yeah, and the differences are always really Subtle crap.
Rym: It's never like.
Scott: well This one only has one SATA controller with six connectors and this one has a second SAT controller with ten SAT connectors, but those four extra ones are on a separate, you know Controller.
Rym: Yep, that has its own separate like raid thing.
Scott: Yeah that launches after the first one launches Post.
Scott: it's like what?
Rym: But I really I just there's.
Rym: I need so little from my motherboard that I pick a name brand and I just picked the cheapest One that has all the holes I want in my mother.
Scott: Yeah, the other of course most important thing about the motherboard is the socket.
Scott: right the socket is the thing.
Scott: That's where the CPU goes and you need it to be the right shape.
Scott: You need it to be the right shape to match the CPU.
Scott: You're gonna put in it.
Scott: the motherboard determines which kind of CPU it can hold and which kind of RAM it can hold.
Scott: and if you want a CPU that is Newer than or too far older than that motherboard or not the right shape for its socket or RAM That's faster than or slower than and not the right kind for that motherboard Need a motherboard now.
Rym: at the same time a lot of motherboards that list all the speeds of RAM They'll take but a lot of those speeds are non-standard and don't mean anything unless you're overclocking.
Rym: And in fact a lot of RAM will say it supports X speeds But yet you're never gonna actually put that in the stock of it.
Scott: It's so weird how the motherboard companies encourage overclocking and the CPU companies encourage overclocking in the video card companies.
Rym: In the old days they used to try to actively lock you out of overclock?
Scott: No, the CPUs would be the ones to over to lock you out.
Scott: The motherboards didn't want to lock you.
Rym: Well, but I remember there was a time when a bit seemed to be the motherboard that didn't stop you But all their motherboards didn't really give you any way to overclock without really fucking around.
Scott: Oh But yeah It's it's motherboards.
Scott: don't even give a shit about overclocking the CPUs of the companies that don't want you to.
Scott: But even they don't seem to be stopping anyone anymore.
Scott: They're just like go for it.
Scott: What else?
Rym: Yeah, well partly because I think manufacturing technology is improved and Binning is probably more common because it they're not making as many bad chips It's a guess.
Rym: so things are eminently overclockable and you're paying for the guarantee.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: so another thing to watch out for with motherboards is flash and Flare.
Scott: right the motherboards that have like crazy colored metal coloring covering things Like you can't avoid it.
Rym: gamery shit, you can't avoid it.
Scott: and look how look at all the orange garbage all over that one.
Rym: Yeah you know what.
Rym: you can't avoid it because that's the heat pipe and all the stuff and The pea kinds of people who drive the motherboard consumer market now are gamer guys.
Scott: Anyway, it's like you buy some ram even ram chips.
Scott: you buy some ram chips and it's got like these blue spikes all over it.
Scott: It looks all crazy.
Rym: Well, because all ram chips now in the old days you'd buy ram.
Rym: They all look the same.
Rym: and then you could buy ram coolers that you never needed.
Rym: You could stick onto your RAM.
Rym: now pretty much all the RAM comes with these crazy heat sinks sticking off the top.
Scott: Yeah, but it's like the this.
Scott: the design of them is so ridiculous.
Rym: Yeah, but you can't avoid it.
Scott: So the more expensive motherboards always have more ridiculous stuff on them.
Rym: Well, you can get the fatality editions of things.
Scott: I guess still yeah, those are the more expensive ones.
Scott: Yeah And the more gamer you get the more ridiculous the motherboard looks to try to convince you to buy it When it's actually not any bet.
Scott: it's like they'll have another motherboard that's exact just as good maybe has a few less connectors on it and It's like really really They just need to somehow psychologically convince you to buy that motherboard.
Scott: That's $100 more.
Rym: I just I really am fascinated that for the longest time for most of the pcs I'd built in the course of my life motherboard decision mattered so much for so many reasons and now it's Fairly a generic choice that comes down to a very limited set of features I require and most of the things I used to care about I don't care about anymore.
Scott: Yeah, my decision-making process for buying motherboard is pretty much this I have this many hard drives and other CD ROM drives and such.
Scott: does it have enough s ATA connectors for all of those?
Scott: if it doesn't it's ruled out - does it have a PCI Express slot that will handle the video card that I'm putting into it?
Scott: the maximum speed?
Scott: Okay, good it has that it's not ruled out.
Scott: Does it have a CPU socket matching the CPU that I'm going to purchase?
Scott: Does it have enough RAM slots to hold the RAM that I'm going to put into it?
Rym: My trouble is the computer I built has six dim slots.
Scott: Yeah, as long as it has that a lot as long as it has yes to all of those questions Then it's an okay motherboard and I'll get it and any you know Whichever one the cheapest that meets all of the requirements.
Rym: that is from a name-brand Yep, like when I think about what I look at because I'm not gonna build a new computer yet I bought between buying the video card and buying some more hard drives.
Rym: I've staved off having to upgrade this computer that I built in 2009 mind you for at least another year Maybe longer, but if I were to buy a new computer now because I did the research, you know It's worth seeing should I just buy a new computer rather than upgrading the one I had
Scott: on the?
Scott: you need new computer.
Rym: I thought the research concluded that I don't because buying a few hard drives cost almost nothing compared to buying a new computer.
Rym: but When I when I was doing my research the things that I was doing the most research on I found were the CPU.
Rym: again Like what is the exact price point to make a computer that I will not upgrade again anytime soon?
Rym: Like do I really need the i7 nowadays as opposed to in the old days?
Rym: well, the i5 be good enough like those kinds of questions and Beyond that it was just how much RAM do I really need?
Rym: 12 or 24?
Rym: I have 32.
Rym: It's crazy.
Rym: I don't even need that much yep, and That's it.
Rym: Like I think the case is what I'm gonna agonize over the most.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much So motherboards.
Scott: do we have anything else to say about that?
Rym: I know I mean unless we get into anecdotes.
Rym: I mean remember When I had that motherboard at RIT and it started flipping out and eventually stopped working.
Scott: the capacitors exploded.
Rym: We opened it up and all the capacitors that exploded all over it because it was that Janky stolen formula of the.
Rym: it was the sabotage formula for capacitor fluid.
Rym: Yep Those are good days.
Rym: Now I just have all these extra motherboards laying around nothing to do with them.
Scott: How many times people tried to push a CPU?
Scott: Heatsink onto a motherboard pushed too hard and broke the CPU and/or cracked the motherboard because they didn't have the motherboard seated properly.
Rym: I have never done that.
Rym: I've never done but I always think I did it every time I install the CPU.
Scott: cuz when you put that heatsink down it Goes click click click and you can't tell between that noise and the motherboard breaking.
Rym: I know because the motherboard breaking just makes a really loud single crack and so does the heatsink actually linking in.
Rym: Yeah, so does the CPU actually linking in.
Scott: not as much.
Rym: it used to used to make a mush louder cracking noise.
Scott: Well, now they've moved the pins from the CPU onto the motherboards.
Scott: The sockets have changed.
Scott: used to be the pins were on the bottom of the CPU and when the pin was bent the CPU was Ruined.
Scott: now when the pin is bent the motherboard is ruined.
Rym: One thing you can say is there was a time when they when they went to the socket from the socket to the slot The nice thing about the slot was that that was not a problem.
Rym: You just slid your CPU in like you did a video card.
Scott: Yeah, there are other problems with that like performance.
Rym: Well, it's funny how cooling.
Rym: for actually for the short term cooling and Some kinds of performance were easier.
Rym: They did that because they could fit a fuck ton more cash on the thing.
Scott: That was Something for its time.
Rym: Yes, and then we admit it me it's so quickly we got from Cooling and cash mattering more to.
Rym: oh the physical distance actually matters a lot.
Rym: We got to actually physically get the CPU closer to the motherboard again.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Oh, wow Yeah, motherboards are not as interesting as they used to be.
Scott: Oh your motherboard these days I guess we didn't mention also includes your network card.
Scott: Yeah used to be a to buy Ethernet cards.
Rym: In fact at my first computer that had a network card at an ISA network card And I also had an ISA sound card.
Rym: I had a Sound Blaster all 32 plugged in to my one ISA slot and on the same ISA bus I had an ISA network card connected via 10 base Ethernet to my cable modem.
Rym: up until like Anytime I started a big download.
Rym: my audio would stutter I think.
Scott: up until like when we lived in Beacon my computers had Ethernet cards that weren't the motherboard.
Rym: Right my computer at RIT the one I built at RIT while we were living there.
Rym: I bought a dedicated network card.
Scott: Yep, and it's interesting now how it's like.
Scott: even when I went to college I had to buy a network card on the internet and bring it with me to college because I had just a modem a USB Modem attached to my computer not an Ethernet card USB modem.
Scott: I had an ISA modem.
Scott: Yeah, home computers just had friggin modems.
Scott: They didn't have network cards.
Scott: You didn't have a LAN in your house right.
Scott: hardly anyone had that.
Scott: Routers were not home equipment now.
Scott: They're routers at home equipment.
Scott: people have ethernet cards just built into the good.
Scott: But now people are using wireless cards.
Scott: some motherboards even have wireless built-in.
Rym: It's crazy But the fact that the moral of this whole show is that motherboards are a lot less interesting than they used to be.
Scott: It's a weird, but becoming more interesting by include just having more.
Scott: you know commodity stuff just built into the motherboard That doesn't matter.
Scott: like sound cards network cards The they matter less.
Scott: you know it used to matter more when the motherboard did less stuff because then you know those different.
Scott: You know, but now that motherboard does so many things.
Scott: It's all commoditized.
Scott: So your choice is kind of meaningless, and we're seeing this across all aspects of home computing.
Rym: I mean when I built computers back in the day to talk about RAM for a second I'd have to research the RAM timings and the RAM brands yup of my motherboard and figure out the compatibility.
Rym: And then I actually would have to look at what?
Rym: Cast latency cycle do I want?
Rym: am I willing to pay more for cast?
Rym: who RAM?
Rym: is that a cast three?
Rym: Nowadays if you look at RAM it gives you all these ridiculous statistics about cast.
Rym: you know like twelve Six four four four two two two one and all these numbers that from a performance standpoint mean nothing.
Rym: Benchmarks, there's no way to tell it does not matter in 99.9 repeating percent of the.
Scott: it only matters if over clocking is your hobby and over clocking is a Stupid hobby.
Rym: well even that if it is even if it is your hobby most of those numbers don't matter anymore.
Scott: Yep, all the things what there aren't.
Scott: at least in those days.
Scott: There were some games that no one could get full frames on with any equipment right like the software was outpacing the hardware you could Have at your house.
Scott: You got like crisis the day it came out.
Scott: or I forget what the other game big deal game was before that.
Scott: It's like you couldn't full settings full frames it no matter what you bought, and you really needed that.
Scott: a super expensive shit.
Scott: now You can full frames full settings with like you know last generation.
Rym: well I mean, I think part of that is the advance of video cards.
Scott: That's also.
Scott: the video card does more than anything.
Scott: my previous computer was a core to duo.
Scott: I upgraded the video card in it from an 8800 GT to a 460 or a 470.
Scott: I forget and Just.
Scott: it just went crazy fast.
Scott: all the all the games are suddenly crazy crazy performance huge boost even though nothing else change.
Rym: Yep, and that's the video card does all the work, and that's why when Scott said you know rib You don't need to build a new computer now I built my computer in 2009.
Scott: the only thing that I think should be good for two more years at least things that are obsolete Are video cards and spinning discs.
Scott: that thing should be good for two if not three more years and by then who even knows?
Rym: Because there is actually a problem it does not support PCI Express 3 fully the new the new high speed so I will actually not get full Theoretical performance out of my GTX.
Scott: when you do upgrade in two years You'll probably be able to bring that video cart over with.
Rym: yeah when I say upgrade my computer You know what that would entail in the modern era a new CPU a new motherboard RAM to put in it if it doesn't use the same RAM I already have and new hard drives maybe Maybe?
Scott: hard drives tend to be the thing that lasts the longest like my drives.
Scott: I think I usually carry drives around for like 15 years before.
Rym: the only reason I need to upgrade drives Is that this computer was built before?
Rym: SSDs were really available.
Rym: I mean I bought a 32 gig SSD at considerable expense And I ran my games off of that 32 gigs.
Rym: Now I can just buy a bunch of hybrid drives and whatever and actually I'm thinking about sticking these two new drives into doing A RAID 0 just for video editing performance.
Scott: You do whatever you can do.
Rym: yeah, but the point is the computer upgrade cycle is so drastically different from what it used to be that my CPU is a limit on rendering video.
Rym: if I render a video and I had a faster processor It might take four less hours out of the 18 hours it takes.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: Heat nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.