Rym: It's Tuesday, August 6th, 2013.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: We're back from PAX Australia to talk about gaming and PAX in Australia.
Scott: Good day.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Yeah, it's been a while since we've done this.
Scott: Well, let's save our, hopefully we've, you know, filled up the bins of material for us to use to get us through the next month.
Scott: Oh, but then there's real packs.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: And then we're going to have even more material and then it'll be the quiet times.
Scott: We have to use all the material and then New Year's.
Rym: So I was biking to work today.
Scott: Yeah, let's not.
Scott: Let's do that.
Scott: Let's talk about biking to work because the Australian material we have to save for the Thursday episode.
Rym: No, I got no bike into work.
Scott: My bit is I got no bike into work either because my arm is fucked up.
Rym: I bike to work.
Rym: Same as always.
Scott: Now, as soon as I can bike to work.
Scott: Yeah, my arms fucked up.
Scott: Fuck this.
Rym: It's kind of weird being back in the States.
Rym: I will just say one thing, because I drove long distance in Australia and I biked around a whole bunch.
Rym: I and, you know, jaywalking constantly.
Rym: I almost rode on the left side of the road when I went to work.
Scott: I did not make that mistake ever.
Rym: I literally like came out and I started to go to the left side of the road.
Rym: Then my brain's like, Ram, seriously?
Scott: I did not make that mistake.
Scott: Really?
Scott: I think you're just making it up.
Rym: No, I actually almost did right at under the seven train and the end.
Rym: Anyway, anyway.
Rym: But yeah, we're back.
Rym: We're bad.
Rym: We missed our crazy ton of news, like the steam sale, which luckily I was able to buy games using my mobile app.
Rym: Well, the steam cell got us doubly because we had Connecticut.
Rym: So we're running everything there and then like checking our steam apps and buying things like.
Rym: I remember Civ five went on flash sale while I was doing Connecticut and stuff.
Rym: And I had to like get the app working to buy.
Scott: Thankfully, they seem to realize that there were people who had said five, but didn't have anything added to it.
Scott: So they had a special upgrade pack for five bucks.
Scott: They got you everything but the brave new world and then brave new world was on sale.
Scott: So I was able to get exactly all the things I didn't have for a very reasonable price.
Scott: Good on them for recognizing it on them.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: For having that that package.
Rym: But then we're in Australia at PAX and there is this great moment where we're talking to the security guard hanging out outside of PAX.
Rym: And basically the guys like, yeah, steam sale.
Rym: You realize you should check it at like one in the morning.
Scott: I think it was three in the morning.
Scott: Yeah, because usually it updates at one p.m.
Scott: in New York.
Scott: And I think it updates at one like a 10 or 11 in the morning in California.
Scott: Where's yet where where valve is.
Rym: That was the night we'd arrived in Melbourne.
Rym: So I kind of that was the moment I realized, oh shit, son, we're a long way away from home.
Rym: Yeah, it was for Australian gamers.
Rym: Check it.
Scott: They're really interesting, though, because it's like we would be finishing up like up Tuesday's almost over.
Scott: Oh, in New York.
Scott: Tuesday is just starting.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Assholes enjoy our already preused day.
Rym: We had this day.
Scott: You realize it's already.
Scott: it's what this is a Tuesday show, right?
Scott: It's already Wednesday in Australia.
Scott: I know they're already Wednesdaying, probably sleeping or about to wake up.
Scott: And we are still not done with Tuesday yet.
Rym: So of all the news we could have talked about, I mean, Dragon's Crown is having its fur both between the people mad about it.
Rym: I mean, fewer and fewer and people mad about being mad about it.
Rym: And people saying it's sexist and people saying it is sexist and people.
Rym: It's all over the place.
Rym: But I really don't care, though.
Scott: I also don't care, though.
Rym: The game, apparently, but I'm getting people I trust is a fun game.
Rym: I'm again, you're going to get it.
Scott: I'm again.
Rym: OK, but it's just really.
Scott: all the art I've seen is just hideous, whether sexist or not.
Scott: It's just hideous, but it's unpleasant to behold.
Rym: It's supposed to be hideous on purpose, which in a way.
Scott: Yeah, I can recognize that.
Scott: But I still personally, I'm not made pleasure by gazing my eyes upon it.
Scott: So I would not subject myself to that.
Scott: Look at two anime movies.
Rym: Sort of a Stranger was a sort of a straightforward action drama anime.
Rym: And then there was Skycrawlers, which was slow and repetitive and slow.
Scott: And neither one was displeasing to my brain.
Rym: Yeah, for most people, slow, long, slow, repetitive, long, repetitive and slow do not a great movie make.
Rym: And they find those their attention spans are small.
Scott: But that because the move that my attention span is the size of my tolerance for ugliness.
Rym: My point is that that movie was a perfect confluence of form and function.
Rym: It is possible that in the case of this game, the hideous art is designed to complement the hideous gameplay.
Scott: I do not trust that anyone who would create that hideous art would be simultaneously wise enough to develop the other part.
Rym: I would have been more likely to play it if it had looked like Penny Arcade's rendering.
Scott: That is true.
Rym: But yeah, of all the news I could talk about, there actually is something I do want to talk about because it's basically the inverse of the news I was talking about back when the Wii came out.
Rym: But in a way, it's the same news.
Rym: So turns out that even now, the Wii U is literally being outsold on a day to day basis by the Wii.
Rym: The Wii, a dead, deprecated console is selling more than Nintendo's flagship product.
Scott: Hooray!
Rym: That'll teach you a lesson.
Scott: I hope Nintendo learns a lesson.
Rym: I don't think they have.
Scott: They never will.
Rym: It is possible because Nintendo was not profitable and they have returned to profitability.
Rym: It is entirely possible that the majority of their return to profitability was nothing more than a currency fluctuation.
Scott: Though that happens when you're a foreign company.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: If you live in one country and make all your money from another country, think about it.
Scott: A British pound is worth a lot of money, right?
Rym: I'm in that boat with my actual day job company.
Scott: We worked in India and had rupees, but we did business in the UK and all our income was pounds coming to India digitally.
Scott: We would be raking in so much.
Rym: Scott, I'll put it this way.
Rym: I know people who worked in the US, moved to India, continued to work for the company in the US, making their original US salary in India.
Scott: And living like kings.
Rym: Those people are not living like kings.
Rym: They are living like God kings.
Scott: God kings.
Rym: I would almost consider moving to India.
Scott: If it didn't smell like poop.
Scott: Listen, there's plenty of other places we can move and be just as God kingly.
Rym: How about Estonia?
Scott: Not the worst.
Rym: I hear there's a lot of nerdery going on in Estonia.
Scott: I mean, it could even be somewhere.
Scott: that's, you know.
Rym: How about Australia, where American dollar's weaker?
Scott: Only slightly.
Scott: It was effectively equal.
Scott: I didn't have to pay attention to it.
Rym: It's interesting how the dollar was slightly weaker than their dollar, but yet things cost 50% more in their own dollar.
Scott: But also the tax.
Scott: Let's save it.
Scott: Save all the Australian Turk.
Rym: But I don't think Nintendo is learning their lesson.
Rym: Because what Nintendo seems to be doing is, one, the DS, which has become the 3DS, that product line is still doing fine, though I think it's still seriously getting hurt by mobile.
Rym: A lot of people aren't going to buy their shovelware.
Scott: I don't know if the 3DS is doing as well as the DS GBA, but it's still doing really fucking well.
Rym: But the thing is, look at what they're focusing on.
Rym: There are third-party games, they're really good, but the shovelware is not doing as well.
Rym: Because no one's going to buy $40 shovelware for the expensive 3DS when they can buy $1 shovelware from the $1 app store.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: I only play shovelware on my phone.
Scott: I don't play no shovelware on my 3DS.
Rym: Meanwhile, me, who's tired of Nintendo, Nintendo who betrayed me and all us hardcore so-called gamers, recently just bought a pile of 3DS games.
Rym: But I'm not going to buy the Wii U, because there's literally no game that's worthwhile on the console.
Scott: One positive for Nintendo.
Scott: You know those little StreetPass games?
Rym: Yeah, Candy Box.
Rym: Those games are all Candy Box.
Rym: I can't believe you're playing them.
Rym: You paid money to play those games.
Scott: The same Candy Box package for $15, right?
Scott: Do you know how much money Nintendo has made in total?
Rym: Oh, Nintendo knows.
Scott: Nintendo made, I think the number in the article I read was a total of $8 million from sales of the Candy Box package alone.
Rym: So, Nintendo has learned...
Scott: I might be remembering the number wrong.
Rym: Look it up.
Rym: This is why I'm saying Nintendo didn't learn their lesson.
Rym: Nintendo, when they moved from the GameCube, which had wonderful tech demos and experiments, that was like the height of Nintendo.
Rym: Not from a business perspective, not from any perspective, but me as a gamer wanting to play Nintendo games.
Scott: Just because you happened to be in an environment in which it was perfect.
Scott: If we were in college right now, the Wii U would actually be kind of okay.
Rym: Kind of okay, but it wouldn't be as good as the GameCube.
Scott: The Wii U would have been, if you were in college four years earlier, the Wii would have been our GameCube, right?
Scott: Because it would have been the multiplayer system of choice.
Rym: Except I think we would have used the Wii to play a lot of multiplayer GameCube games.
Scott: Possibly.
Rym: But that's a separate discussion.
Scott: But there was Mario Party Wii.
Rym: But Nintendo moved from its previous demographics to the Blue Water strategy, the open oceans.
Rym: And they started going after these casual light markets and all these things.
Rym: And I don't want to try to say that casual gaming is bad, because that's a really loaded term anyway.
Rym: But Nintendo is still going after that kind of market and is really ignoring gamers like me.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So, I don't know what their future is, because that kind of- Where's our 3DS Advance Wars, bitches?
Rym: Yeah, well there's Fire Emblem instead, which, seriously guys, Fire Emblem- Not as good as Advance Wars.
Rym: Kind of fun, but it's just mediocre dating game coupled with Crystal Warriors.
Scott: I have a feeling the 3DS one has a little bit more dating than the previous ones did.
Scott: Not that the other ones didn't have it.
Rym: No, I've gone through emulation and looked at old, but these games are Baby's First Advance Wars.
Rym: Which means that the Pokemon Tactics game is Baby's First, Baby's First.
Scott: Baby's First.
Rym: I don't have a better way to describe it.
Scott: Anyway, yeah, Nintendo.
Rym: It's adopted.
Rym: looking so good, I feel like you need to break open the safe that has your secret backup strategy and realize that what it says in there is a monolith with the simple phrase- Pokemon MMO, bitches.
Scott: And also, Advance Wars.
Rym: So, I was thinking of Roanoke and I realized that the perfect comic- The island?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: You know the mystery of where everyone disappeared?
Scott: Everyone disappeared, yes.
Rym: And they found- So, imagine the Nintendo offices, empty.
Rym: Nintendo is out of business.
Rym: Archaeologists come into the Nintendo headquarters.
Rym: They find all the abandoned Wii U's and the abandoned game consoles.
Rym: And in Miyamoto's office, they find, written on a single piece of paper, in fact carved into his desk, the words, "Pokemon
Rym: MMO.".
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: So, this is a really interesting news.
Scott: I posted it on the forum and had a discussion, but as I know, people who listen to the show aren't in the forum and people in the forum don't listen to the show.
Scott: Always funny.
Scott: Yeah, and it was just a really fascinating thing that happened in the gaming world, so I really want to discuss it.
Scott: So, here's the deal.
Scott: Fighting game community, right?
Scott: It has ups and downs, positives and negatives, but, you know, fighting games I respect as a competitive skill-based game and it's, you know, they have real competitions.
Scott: It's totally cool.
Scott: There was a tournament in New York and these two guys got to the finals and in the opinion of the guy who was organizing the tournament, named Spooky, he thought that the two players getting to the finals, who were in the finals, were colluding.
Scott: Now, what were they colluding, right?
Scott: They were battling in the final round to see who would be the champion of this tournament and win the prize.
Scott: What could they possibly collude on?
Scott: That would be like the two teams in the Super Bowl.
Scott: Were they gambling?
Rym: So, the Super Bowl, it's the Lions versus the Browns.
Rym: Do they agree?
Scott: This is big teams.
Rym: Do they agree to make it a draw?
Scott: You can't.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Do they agree to play forever in overtime, trolling their entire rest of the world?
Rym: They would die.
Rym: They could make it a while.
Scott: Are they allowed to bring food out for them?
Scott: But they both really want to win the Super Bowl, so that's not going to happen, right?
Scott: In this case...
Rym: Would they?
Rym: Because I could... All right, so here's what they could do.
Rym: If two teams got to the Super Bowl...
Scott: You're just dragging the show out with nonsense.
Rym: And they agreed that they should play to a draw for as long as they possibly can, that game would go down in history, make everyone involved.
Scott: It would not benefit the teams.
Scott: The teams, they would basically call orange immediately and try to win the Super Bowl because everyone really wants to win it badly.
Scott: And only one side can win.
Scott: Anyways, in this case, that was not such, right?
Scott: These guys basically realized, huh, if I win this tournament, I get the prize money.
Scott: If I lose, I get significantly less.
Scott: If I collude with this guy, we can basically both agree to split all this prize money between us.
Scott: We don't care about this tournament that much.
Scott: It's not the Super Bowl.
Scott: It's a lesser tournament.
Scott: It's like a New York City tournament, right?
Scott: So let's agree to split the prize money.
Scott: Now, there isn't evidence that they did this, but it was suspected that they did this because apparently if you watch them play the final match, they weren't playing the characters they're really good at.
Scott: They were obviously not trying to win, right, with their full might.
Scott: They were, you know, it's arguable that they may have been, but most likely they were not putting forth their full effort to win and they were not putting on a good show for these spectators, right?
Scott: You know, it'd be like if you, like that badminton in the Olympics, right?
Scott: Except in the badminton in the Olympics, they were losing in order to win the big tournament.
Scott: Here, they were losing, or at least, you know, losing sort of on purpose.
Rym: If it's true, it's a very simple function.
Rym: And you already alluded to this.
Rym: Their utility function is the money and the lifestyle that that money supports.
Scott: Right, they would rather have half of the total prize pool for first and second than try to, you know, than risk having the second place prize, which is not enough.
Scott: Now note, this is only possible.
Scott: And don't really care about the benefit of getting the big first place prize.
Rym: This is only possible due to a combination of tournament structure and the fact that it's a competitive direct game as opposed to, say, golf.
Rym: Golf has similar prize structures, yet there is no way for two players to collude to share the top spots because they're all playing solitary.
Scott: Well, they're not trying to tie, right?
Scott: They were just basically saying, "Okay, we already know who wins.
Scott: We're going to just share it, so let's just stick around," right?
Scott: As opposed to, "Let's put
Scott: forth.".
Rym: What they have both bought from each other is security of not having to risk losing.
Scott: No.
Scott: The money.
Scott: The reason that they did not put forth the full effort in winning, right?
Scott: Because it's like, "Okay, we've decided to split the money no matter what, so why not try to win and put in a show anyway, thus guaranteeing that, you know, the person who's in charge of the tournament doesn't think we've colluded and isn't going to shut it down," which he did, and that the people get a good show.
Scott: The reason they don't do that is because they don't want to reveal their full power, right?
Scott: They don't want to show off.
Scott: If they want to play to win, they actually might have to use their strongest techniques, and thus other people in the community and other places who they're going to fight in bigger, more important tournaments that they care about will see those techniques.
Scott: Much like if a football team had a play, a trick play that was so good, that it was going to win the game, right?
Scott: But if they used it during the regular season to win a game, then they couldn't use it in the Super Bowl later because the other team might see it coming.
Rym: Game theory, guys.
Rym: Everyone's as smart as you are.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So they wanted to keep basically their moves and their combos and their strategies a secret so that they would still be fresh and surprising at a more important tournament that they cared about.
Scott: A football team in the Super Bowl is going to pull out all the stops, right?
Scott: This was the finals.
Scott: People should pull out all the stops in the finals.
Rym: But it wasn't the final final because the Super Bowl...
Scott: It was the finals of this tournament, not finals of some other tournament that was more important.
Scott: So because they were both able to keep their secrets to hopefully do better in a later tournament and share the prize, they put on a shit show for the spectators.
Rym: Now the real reason why this is impossible, like look at baseball for example.
Rym: Yes, it is conceivable.
Rym: maybe someone came up with a new style of pitching that is just better in some way.
Scott: But you can't duplicate it by watching the guy.
Scott: You need a guy who can do it.
Rym: But even if you watch it, figure out, "Oh, it's
Rym: possible.".
Rym: I mean look at atomic bomb research.
Scott: Yes, we know that we know how to throw the knuckle ball.
Scott: Guess what?
Scott: You're going to have to practice a lot before you can throw it as well as that guy.
Rym: But a lot of the reason that other people were able to develop atomic weapons after the U.S.
Rym: did was because once the U.S.
Rym: detonated one, even though detonating it didn't tell you how they did it, it proved that it was possible.
Rym: Once you know it's possible, you know what to train, you know what to practice.
Scott: It's a little more obvious because you can just get the streamed video of the tournament, right?
Scott: Or a recorded video or whatever and then just watch it frame by frame and see, "Oh, I see what he did
Scott: there.".
Rym: So why does this never happen?
Rym: How come there hasn't been a World Series where suddenly something crazy happened?
Rym: Because that sport has been around for a long time and there literally are no more secrets or trick plays.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: There is nothing left you can do.
Rym: that is novel in baseball.
Rym: That's true.
Rym: Literally nothing.
Rym: Football, there is almost nothing you can do.
Rym: that is novel.
Scott: Now the reason that you can do things now, here's the thing though.
Scott: Some fighting games, there is nothing, it's Street Fighter II, there's nothing you can do.
Scott: that's novel.
Scott: I'm pretty sure it's all been done, right?
Scott: But they keep updating shit.
Scott: Street Fighter IV is actually getting another update.
Scott: They're making like hyper Street Fighter IV or Ultimate or some ridiculous, you know.
Scott: At first it was Street Fighter IV, then Arcade Edition.
Scott: Now they're coming out with another update and the reason is that they're having longer and longer development times.
Scott: So Street Fighter V probably isn't going to be here for many years yet.
Scott: They're talking like 2018 or something.
Scott: So they're going to keep updating Street Fighter IV on the side to keep Street Fighter alive, right?
Scott: Keep adding characters and updating stuff with these updates that they charge money for.
Scott: And use that until Street Fighter V is ready.
Scott: But by adding characters, by changing things, right?
Scott: The game keeps changing.
Scott: There's novel things, you know.
Scott: There's so many characters now.
Scott: There's always something you can think up that hasn't been done before.
Scott: And the word on the street is that with this new update to Street Fighter IV, their goal is not to balance the characters by like making the top class characters weaker, but basically to make every character stronger, right?
Scott: So it's like, imagine if it was Dragon Ball, right?
Scott: It's like, well, Super Saiyan Goku is the strongest, right?
Scott: So rather than say, well, it's unfair to pick him, let's make him weaker.
Scott: It's like, no, let's make everyone else as strong as that.
Scott: And then that way we'll even the tables.
Scott: We're going to see how that turns out.
Scott: That's pretty interesting.
Scott: I want to see what happens.
Rym: Well, I think there's a sort of meta issue here that because this tournament system of games that are professional, you know, video games basically, where there's actually a scene around it, there's money around it, is so new and so young that the small number of people
Scott: And you might be like, oh, it's like decades old.
Scott: Yeah, baseball is like a century old.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Hockey predates good modern video technology.
Scott: American football is new.
Scott: And you know what?
Scott: The rules change a lot all the time.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Right.
Rym: But all these sports also have in common that there are long standing rules bodies that have semi monopolies over these sports.
Scott: And that's the other important thing.
Scott: When you have one governing body for the whole sport, that governing body can actually control people, right?
Scott: It can be like, look, we're going to ban you from the sport.
Scott: There are no meaningful matches in this sport.
Scott: That we do not govern, but now we can kick you out.
Rym: If one video game league says, yeah, we're banning you because you cheated.
Rym: And that guy's popular.
Scott: You just go play in another one.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: They're basically one.
Scott: It's like if we ban people from our net runner tournament for like poor sportsmanship, it's like, okay, there's a hundred other gaming stores.
Scott: They can go to a net runner tournament at.
Scott: They just can't go to that one.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Right.
Rym: It's like, you know, but also these kinds of games.
Rym: Notice how there's a very small number of people in the top tier rotata.
Rym: That's because it takes a lot of practice and dedication to get to that point in these games.
Rym: And the people who have the time to do that pretty much need that to be their lifestyle.
Rym: So they literally need to win enough tournaments to fund their lives, to continue playing the game, to be good enough at it, to continue winning tournaments.
Rym: It's a vicious cycle.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: As a result, they can not risk losing that money stream.
Rym: They need a steady income from the tournament scene.
Rym: And the tournament tournament scene is too immature to provide that to more than a very small number of people.
Rym: And that small community of people all know each other really well and are actually really insular and really segregated from a lot of the rest of the gaming community.
Scott: You know, you think it's an.
Scott: it's an individual sport, right?
Scott: And the way individual sports like tennis and golf, the way that those work, the way that people can devote their lives to be a pro golfer, a pro tennis player is because the prize payout goes all the way down.
Scott: If you were in a PGA golf tournament and you come in like 30th place, you get thousands of dollars.
Rym: You've all seen Happy Gilmore, right?
Scott: You get tons of money for not coming in anywhere close to first place just for showing up.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Last place.
Scott: I'm pretty sure it gets a not insignificant amount of money depending on the tournament.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Even if it's not a major tournament.
Scott: You know, and if it's like the U.S.
Scott: Open, like the U.S.
Scott: Open, you know, you know, all those ones that say open on them.
Scott: It's called open because it's open.
Scott: If you're good enough, you're in.
Scott: You don't have to be you don't have to be a pro.
Scott: You don't have to be anything special.
Scott: It's just you play into it.
Rym: There's also a structure of related industries that make enough money to subsidize a lot of this.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: All that money comes from like golf ads, you know, and all the commercials when you watch it on TV.
Rym: How much money do you think?
Rym: the vending services, hot dogs and Red Bull or whatever, and every video game tournament in America combined is compared to one football game.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So there aren't these structures in place.
Rym: And basically everything we've talked about has created a kind of toxic tournament culture.
Scott: Anyway, let's move on.
Rym: It's an interesting story.
Rym: So things of the day.
Rym: I'm kind of excited to be able to do this again.
Rym: I got charged up quite a lot.
Scott: I can't remember what things of the days I've used, but I have a zillion of them.
Rym: I have saved several.
Rym: But the one I want to talk about now is a game in the Google Play Store.
Rym: that is now my new favorite game.
Rym: Send me to heaven.
Rym: It's an app.
Rym: You can download it.
Scott: It's in the Google Play Store.
Scott: So is it only for Android?
Rym: Supposedly only for Android.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: I don't have Android.
Rym: So if this game, if you actually play this game and you don't need the app to play it, you can play the game without the app if you're clever or if you have a friend helping you.
Rym: I take no responsibility if you play this game.
Rym: So send me to heaven.
Scott: You just kill somebody?
Rym: It's a sport game.
Rym: Player is supposed to throw his phone as high as possible and catch it.
Scott: No, I'll throw some other phone as high as possible.
Rym: The app should measure the height of the phone.
Rym: fly from the player's hand.
Rym: The higher, the better.
Rym: There's a leaderboard.
Scott: Nope.
Scott: I will do that.
Scott: I should get a phone just to play that and we'll use the water balloon slingshot or a model rocket.
Rym: I love the idea.
Scott: Just like a throwaway phone.
Rym: I love the idea of games like this because it's almost, it's like an art installation.
Rym: It's like watching someone continuously run into that first goomba over and over again.
Rym: Even if this is a joke, the, the idea of a game like this real world consequences for something minor.
Scott: And I'm pretty sure, how does that phone measure how high it went?
Scott: I think it's just a trick to get you to break your phone.
Rym: Well, I mean, my GPS actually, if I put it in a real time mode and I get a calibrated does a pretty good job of detecting elevation changes.
Scott: Really?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But when the GPS, so wouldn't it just be telling you the elevation of the spot on the map you're standing?
Rym: So if you go, no, no, it tells you the elevation of where you are.
Rym: Really?
Rym: It's just not, it's not super accurate sometimes because it needs a lot of calibration because you really need a barometer for that shit.
Rym: The way the satellites are, it's better at your spatial two dimensional, well, two dimensional relative to your perception position.
Scott: Anyway, anyway, I think of the day.
Scott: So when I was a kid, I had He-Man toys, which were kind of cool.
Scott: I had Battle Damage, He-Man, Skeletor.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And one of the toys I had was, I also had both of those was Mossman and Mossman was kind of fuzzy and he smelled funny.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And Mossman was pretty cool.
Scott: The thing is, there was another guy I did not have, and his name was Stinkor and Stinkor smelled sort of just like Mossman.
Scott: What is interesting is that if you find an old Stinkor figure today, he still stinks.
Scott: It's like 30 years old, this action figure.
Rym: That's kind of crazy.
Scott: Why does Stinkor still stink even though dude is 30 years old?
Scott: action figure, right?
Scott: Usually an old toy, whatever it is, doesn't work anymore.
Scott: You find a Battle Damage He-Man, guess what?
Scott: That Battle Damage is just permanently stuck on full damage, right?
Scott: You find like a Teddy Ruxpin, he ain't telling you any stories.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: It's just not going to happen.
Scott: Glow worm, no glow.
Scott: It's just, he's too old.
Scott: He's dead.
Scott: It's not going to happen.
Scott: But for some reason, Stinkor still stinks.
Scott: How does Stinkor still stink?
Scott: This is a really, really incredible article that tells you why Stinkor still stinks.
Scott: Basically, they put patchouli oil in the plastic.
Rym: Just like actually in the plastic.
Scott: But the rest of this article tells you all sorts of other interesting things about Stinkor.
Scott: So you should check it out.
Rym: Stinkor is the kind of thing that you would expect to be a parody of a real toy in a movie.
Rym: That's the kind of thing you see an ad for in the background in Robocop.
Scott: Even He-Man, which was basically the sell toys garbage, right?
Scott: The people making the show refused to put Stinkor in the show.
Scott: He only actually appeared, I think, in some crappy comic spinoff or something.
Scott: They wouldn't even put him in the show because he was just too far.
Rym: No matter how low a man goes, he's got to have a line.
Rym: Even a beggar sneers at someone who's too poor to give him alms.
Scott: Yep, exactly.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: So, in the meta moment, holy fuck, we're back.
Scott: Holy shit.
Rym: It's been a long time since we've done GeekNights.
Scott: And we're going to only do GeekNights for a few weeks and then go to Seattle.
Rym: Yep, we're going to be presenting at least one panel of PAX on Monday, Bad Games.
Scott: Monday?
Scott: Is this PAX?
Scott: Holy shit, four days?
Rym: Four days of PAX.
Rym: I can hardly contain myself.
Rym: I'm actually really excited.
Scott: So much PAX, playing all the games.
Scott: This PAX is going to be dedicated to three things.
Scott: Number one, all four things.
Rym: Alright, so let's see if four things are the same thing.
Rym: I want to dedicate it to playing multiple games of Eclipse.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Tabletop RPGs.
Rym: Hanging out with strangers.
Rym: Going to some concerts because there's additional concerts.
Scott: There is one extra concert because extra day.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Also, I have an extra day.
Rym: And the thing is, you might think that one extra day doesn't seem like that big a deal.
Rym: Let me tell you something, kids.
Rym: When we first went to MAGFest, it was four days long.
Rym: It felt like I was there forever.
Rym: It felt like I walked into this place and then I walked out months afterward.
Rym: Somehow that extra day, because you get, at a normal con, Friday...
Scott: But this isn't Thursday, Friday, Saturday, Sunday.
Scott: This is Friday, Saturday, Sunday, Monday.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: So now we're going to get the Thursday pregame, full on Friday, full on Saturday, full on Sunday, and then gimped Monday.
Rym: Usually you get half on Friday, full on Saturday, gimped Sunday.
Scott: Anyway, so here's what I'm going to do in this pack.
Scott: Number one, tabletop RPGs all the way.
Scott: I'm going to sign up.
Scott: I'm going to find the guys who are running the games on demand.
Scott: I'm going to be like, "I'm GMing.
Scott: Hook it up.
Scott: Let's
Scott: go.".
Rym: I'm going to find someone else to run Torchbearer for me because I haven't learned it yet.
Scott: I'll do it.
Scott: Two, right?
Scott: I'm going to play Netrunner, of course.
Rym: Of course.
Scott: Of course.
Scott: There's actually going to be a PAX tabletop official Netrunner tournament, but I don't know.
Scott: It was listed as doing a single elimination, which is wrong.
Scott: That's not a Netrunner tournament.
Scott: So I might have to go and volunteer to temporarily administer the tournament, see if the enforcers are down with that.
Scott: I'm sure they will be, right?
Scott: Three, the regular PAX business, of course.
Scott: And four, 3DS shit, because there's going to be Smash Bros.
Rym: Oh, you mean your candy box?
Scott: I'm pretty sure there's going to be Smash Bros.
Scott: by then.
Rym: So I've noticed something.
Rym: I've noticed, since the 3DS came out, a very different culture of pickup gaming that basically precludes what you're expecting to happen.
Rym: So when we first got the regular DS, you go to any con and DictoChat would be full to the point that you couldn't join.
Rym: DictoChat?
Rym: People were just drawing penises all over the place.
Scott: No one used a swap note.
Rym: You go to any panel room at any convention, even like Otakon, in the earliest days of the regular DS.
Scott: DictoChat.
Rym: And DictoChat was just full.
Rym: And if you just put it in looking for game mode, like look for download play, there'd be like ten games going on.
Rym: I have turned on download play in many locations since I got my 3DS, including PAX Australia.
Rym: Never, ever have I seen a pickup game.
Scott: Because everyone's playing candy box?
Rym: Because everyone's playing candy box or they're playing single player Animal Crossing and that's it.
Scott: I think it was Smash Bros.
Scott: hits.
Rym: Nope, you're going to have to find an individual person and say, "Yo, you.
Rym: Specific
Rym: person.".
Scott: Man, at PAX that's going to be so hard.
Scott: I'm never going to find anybody.
Rym: Yeah, you're going to try to do that and you're going to say, "Sorry, I'm in the middle of Animal
Rym: Crossing."
Rym: Or, "I'm busy with my street
Rym: passes.".
Scott: Animal Crossing is already starting to fade.
Rym: No, it's not.
Rym: What are you basing that on?
Scott: The thread hasn't bumped in a while.
Rym: Oh, that's because they're all playing Animal Crossing.
Rym: There's nothing left for them to say.
Scott: Other metas.
Scott: The Book Club book is?
Rym: Stasi-land.
Rym: True accounts of what it was like inside of and around the Stasi.
Rym: You know, the secret police in East Germany during the Soviet Union and after the fall of the Berlin Wall and all that business.
Scott: You mean before the fall of the Wall?
Rym: Yeah, so after the fall of the Wall is when most of these stories are told or take place.
Scott: Oh, really?
Rym: Some of the stories are, yeah, this guy was in the Stasi and now he's a normal person.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Rym: A lot of stuff like that.
Rym: You obviously have not read the Book Club book yet.
Scott: No, but I thought most of the stories, while they may have been told after the fall, they happened before.
Rym: Ah, but a lot of the parts of the stories happen after and a lot of the relevant information happens after.
Rym: Like, there's a group of people who are basically the MRAs of bullshit secret police spying.
Rym: Who are like, "What we did was justified and you guys are persecuting us for doing what we were supposed to be
Rym: doing.".
Scott: Nope.
Scott: We've already been through that, guys.
Rym: Yeah, I feel like this book is a good Book Club book.
Scott: In the same country.
Scott: We've been through this in the same country.
Rym: Because we're kind of going through this again right now and not enough people seem mad about this.
Scott: People with bread and circuses.
Rym: You've got to get mad.
Scott: Bread and circuses.
Scott: Anyway, other meta moments.
Scott: If you're, I guess, a new person, this is the first episode we've done.
Scott: You should go find us everywhere that we are on the internet.
Scott: Which is Twitter.
Scott: Which is Facebook.
Scott: Which is Google Plus.
Scott: Which is our forum.
Rym: All our, oh, not all our.
Rym: Maybe half of our PAX lectures ever are all on YouTube for you to watch.
Scott: We also have a newsletter and I'm going to send another one out soon.
Scott: Oh shit.
Scott: We just haven't done any new episodes that I can write about in the newsletter.
Scott: So, maybe next week I'll send the next newsletter.
Rym: And you saw some of the trickle already.
Rym: There will be a long form trickle of videos and things and pictures from PAX Australia as we get them together.
Rym: And ConnectiCon.
Rym: I have video of a bunch of stuff from ConnectiCon.
Scott: ConnectiCon was right before PAX Australia and we haven't talked about that yet.
Scott: That was a big deal.
Rym: In fact, I did.
Rym: Dave Riley and Ajay showed up.
Rym: They did their panel.
Rym: I have video and audio of it.
Rym: I'm going to upload it.
Rym: You can watch it.
Rym: I want to use this as ammo to convince Dave to come to more conventions like MAGFest and PAX.
Scott: You should really just go to MAGFest, seriously.
Rym: MAGFest is kind of up your alley.
Scott: Drinking and gaming.
Rym: Drinking and gaming with chill people.
Scott: I mean, come on.
Rym: There are non-chill parts of MAGFest.
Rym: The stink in the corner.
Scott: You don't go there.
Rym: Yeah, just stay out of that corner.
Rym: But yeah, the whole reason we flew halfway around the world.
Rym: 25 hours of traveling each way, skipping an entire day, was to go to PAXOS.
Rym: The first PAXOS.
Rym: So we reviewed basically the first PAX we went to and, you know, the first PAX East.
Rym: And we don't really do a full review of every PAX we go to because we go to several a year.
Scott: And it's mostly the same every time and certain people who like convention shows and certain ones who don't.
Scott: So we try to, you know, balance between the two.
Scott: Having them and also not having them.
Scott: So I will say one thing.
Rym: All of you who tell us that no one wants to hear the convention episodes.
Rym: Seriously guys, half the people who talk to us tell us the exact opposite.
Rym: Stop trying to pretend that you're the majority.
Scott: It's half and half, who knows.
Scott: But we've got to talk about PAX Australia, right?
Rym: It's the first one.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: And it's a big deal.
Scott: Because Australia is desperate for nerdery.
Scott: And this was the first time anyone brought them some real nerdery.
Scott: So they were very, very grateful.
Rym: Yeah, and you know what?
Rym: The one thing that I can say that is absolutely apparent about nerds in Australia is that they are way more dedicated to their nerdery than the average nerd in the US.
Scott: You have to be.
Rym: Yeah, things cost way more money.
Scott: The supply of nerdery is lower.
Rym: You live in a country that doesn't have free speech.
Scott: The cost of nerdery is higher, right?
Rym: Yeah, we went to a comic shop that was nearby the con.
Scott: The difficulty of finding other nerds is higher.
Rym: And in this comic shop there was a My Little Pony backpack.
Rym: It was a hundred goddamn dollars.
Scott: Holy shit.
Rym: There was manga.
Scott: That's like a twenty dollar throwaway thing in like an anime con dealer's room.
Rym: Five dollar manga was ten dollars.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: Four dollar comics were six dollars.
Scott: And the sign that said this week's comics, I was pretty sure those were last week's comics.
Scott: But they weren't that far behind because I did see a guy on the train reading Saga volume two.
Scott: So not too far behind, but still not up to date.
Scott: Everything is slow there.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: A lot of games don't legally get released because of the weird free speech laws there.
Scott: It's not a good place.
Scott: It's not the best place for nerds, but there are nerds there.
Scott: It's, you know, they're there for other reasons.
Scott: That's just where they live.
Scott: People live everywhere and you got to do what you got to do.
Rym: And it was very telling that we arrived on Thursday morning.
Rym: We walked around and then we decided to just go and get our badges, even though really we were supposed to get them Friday.
Rym: So we just got on the tram, went to the PAX grounds to see what was up.
Rym: And it was at the show grounds.
Rym: That's a horse racing track.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, the show grounds was also used for other things besides the horse racy thing.
Scott: But it was mostly an outdoor sort of kind of place where you would have rodeos or tractor pulls.
Rym: Now this appears to be because this is not a city or even a country that has convention centers like we're used to in the US.
Rym: Those things that we have like the BCC, the BCEC, they're kind of anomalies in the world.
Rym: There aren't that many places like that.
Rym: And the US seems to have more of them than anywhere else because they're mostly built by taxpayers and corruption.
Rym: But it was a show grounds.
Rym: So we get there and we don't know how to get in.
Rym: We're on this like dark street.
Rym: There's a fence.
Rym: Everything's dark.
Rym: We eventually find all these enforcers who also can't figure out how to get in.
Rym: And we all just start walking.
Rym: We eventually find a guy wearing an orange vest.
Rym: We go to walk in and he asks us if we're enforcers.
Rym: And we, of course, say yes because I kind of want to just go in and get my badge, even though we're not enforcers.
Scott: We weren't enforcers this time.
Rym: Yes, not at this packs.
Scott: Not right now, but I will be maybe next year.
Rym: And one, the guy was trusting and it just gave us orange visibility vest and told us how to get in so we could just walk in.
Scott: So I just carried my vest.
Scott: I'm like, I'm not wearing a twerky vest.
Rym: And they're like, no, you got to wear it because there were forklifts flying around at high velocity everywhere.
Scott: Yeah, whatever.
Rym: And two, the guy was a super nerd gamer.
Scott: He was also like a big chef.
Scott: This is a cool dude, the security guard at Paxos.
Rym: Yeah, he was working the security shift so that he could get a chance to walk around Pax because it was sold out.
Scott: Yeah, this guy was a cool dude.
Scott: I remember that guy.
Scott: Just like I remember Scottish dude from those other packs.
Scott: Scottish dude, if you're listening, email us or something.
Rym: You're an awesome dude.
Rym: We walked around the sci-fi museum in Seattle after Pax one year.
Scott: You remember that?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: You're that guy.
Scott: We're those guys.
Rym: And you're that guy.
Rym: And with our powers combined.
Scott: We saw you at Pax East, even.
Scott: Come on.
Rym: We can be those guys.
Scott: Come back to Pax East.
Rym: You should have come to Paxos so they could have made fun of your accent yet again.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But this guy, this cool security guard who was super cool, we hung out there for a while just talking to him and hanging out.
Rym: And one by one, all the enforcers who came up and joined our conversation led me to realize something very interesting.
Rym: Now I cannot say this is universal to Australia.
Rym: It might've just been because it was a Pax, but, and it's purely anecdotal, but I have to say everyone we met that night hanging out at the entrance to Pax was super chill, super into gaming.
Scott: Not that guy.
Rym: And when queried as to what kinds of games they like, they gave advanced and complicated answers filled with nuance.
Scott: Also mostly PC games.
Rym: Mostly PC gaming.
Rym: I pretty much rapidly got the impression that in Australia, console gaming is looked down on as kind of like baby gaming.
Rym: Like, yeah, if you can't get your PC to work, like you don't know how to get a gaming PC, then I guess you could buy an Xbox.
Scott: They literally had stores, physical stores on the street that looked like Newegg, the store.
Scott: There were more than one of these, right?
Scott: I really only saw one GameStop in the bottom of them all.
Scott: And it was pretty sad.
Scott: Basically there are as many of the PC buying stores as we have GameStops.
Rym: And you ask someone here, like if I ask a random person at Pax, like, hey, what kind of game are you?
Rym: Like what kind of games are you into?
Rym: They usually give a really shallow answer.
Rym: Now they might be a very deep gamer.
Rym: They might be really into gaming, but they give the initial safe, shallow answer.
Rym: Any random person asks this kind of like, yeah, so what are you playing?
Rym: They'd be like, LOL, but I only play these four characters.
Rym: Like that's the first thing they would say, or I really only play Counter-Strike 1.6.
Rym: Actually a lot of people said Counter-Strike 1.6.
Scott: A lot of people did say that.
Scott: And it's obvious why, because the consoles are too much money and the Steam sale is a savior to them, right?
Scott: Just like it's a savior to us, but to them even more so.
Rym: So we, you know, go in and we walk around and we realized at this moment of revelation, because there were hundreds and hundreds of people all over the place, and the enforcers were all getting their information and checking in.
Rym: And I realized at that moment that with the exception of maybe 10 or 15 people, none of them had ever enforced before.
Rym: And the vast majority of them had never experienced a PAX before.
Scott: I saw like five enforcers that I, I mean, you know, not counting, say Robert Koo or Heels, right?
Scott: It's like there were like five enforcers, maybe, that I knew from other PAXes.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Tops.
Rym: Though it also caused this weird moment where it was like that first PAX.
Rym: we went to way back in 2008, where it was really just me and Scott.
Rym: And we met some listeners and we didn't really know anyone in Seattle.
Rym: Didn't really know any enforcers.
Rym: It was all new to us.
Rym: So we kind of went into it with this mindset of we don't know anyone.
Rym: Let's, we're going to have to like find people.
Rym: People all seem to know who we were here and it was kind of weird.
Scott: That was weird.
Rym: It was really, really weird to be walking down the hall or I guess the, uh, the tent at PAX in Australia.
Rym: The first one ever.
Rym: we'd never presented, never, neither one of us ever been to Australia before.
Rym: And people are just like, Hey, Rym and Scott.
Rym: Hey, what's up?
Rym: Hey, we know you.
Rym: And we're like, Hey, all you people we don't know.
Rym: So yeah, literally big top.
Rym: We go to the big top where tabletop was.
Rym: It was a circus big top.
Scott: It was, this is a show grounds.
Scott: It was outside.
Scott: It was cold.
Rym: Like complete with those angled pillars that hold the tent up and those weird platforms and spotlights.
Scott: I guess they were doing what they had to work with down under.
Rym: It was a circus big top.
Rym: And let me tell you, shit was cold.
Scott: It was cold in there.
Rym: I was so cold.
Scott: We basically, you would always hang out by the, they had these heating blowing things near the entrances and it would always be little groups hanging out around them talking.
Scott: And we met a lot of cool people hanging out by the heaters.
Rym: Yeah, because that's where you hung out because it was fucking cold.
Scott: So we'd go by the heating blower, take turns standing directly in front of it or around it and chat it up.
Scott: And always cool people were standing there.
Rym: Well, cool temperature wise, trying to warm up.
Rym: Yes, but it was so cold and it was pouring rain for most of packs.
Rym: So you'd see people like working up the gumption to run across the significant distance in the rain to get from the big top.
Rym: And it's open fucking side through the rain to PC gaming, which was known like separate building, which I guess that's where like the press people watch the horse races.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: But yeah, things that were different about this pat.
Scott: I mean the packs, even though it had all this, you know, it was totally Australia, totally new.
Scott: It was mostly like other packs is only a smaller be outside and cold.
Scott: See, it was basically it was like an early packs.
Scott: It was like traveling in a time machine and going back to packs.
Scott: Oh, eight or seven, which I wasn't even at right where no one there knew how to packs, but they figure it out.
Scott: And they came to mostly the same conclusion that all the other packs had come to you and they did the same thing.
Scott: They were just.
Scott: it was.
Scott: they were figuring out like you go to the Q and A and it's like, oh, this feels like the Q and A from five years ago.
Scott: And I bet in five years this will feel like the Q and A packs.
Rym: We had a bet we were going to.
Rym: we wanted to make a packs as bingo.
Rym: We didn't have time to put it together because Connecticut.
Rym: But one of the things I wanted to put on it was emotionally charged P.A Q and A question.
Rym: The first question was basically a guy who's like friend died and didn't get to come to the con.
Rym: But he'd been away.
Rym: They'd win their whole lives for a pack.
Rym: And it was just so great to see them.
Rym: And it pretty much just went on for there.
Scott: It was just like that first paxies where all these people who have never gotten to meet Mike and Jerry before and never got to see this still happens at the other paxies, but not as much because everyone sort of already gotten it out of the system.
Scott: The majority of the stuff at the other paxies by this point is sort of like, hey, guys, what's up again?
Scott: How's that thing going that we do every time that we do this?
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Though I got to experience something great because I got up in line.
Rym: Actually, that emotional question was the third question.
Rym: The second question would have been me asking for the knuckle crack.
Scott: But someone else, the first guy in the other line had the knuckle crack.
Rym: I know.
Rym: So I got to experience a crowd of people who had never experienced the knuckle, knuckle crack, experiencing the knuckle.
Scott: And let me tell you, the oh, noise that they made was I'm building my knuckles up because I got to use them again in three weeks.
Scott: Be careful with that because we've only had like a month to recharge as opposed to the usual six months.
Rym: But people lined up early.
Rym: The keynote filled up as it should have.
Rym: The Q and A was full.
Scott: Everything filled because the rooms are small, but they still let in while the pax was physically smaller.
Scott: There was still.
Scott: it was sold out.
Scott: There was still tons of people everywhere.
Scott: So everything filled all the time.
Scott: I think every single panel except for the Skippy Theater filled one hundred percent.
Scott: I'm pretty sure.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: If not, the vast majority of them definitely filled.
Rym: People lined up.
Rym: Our panel was the first one of the.
Scott: it was in the first just like the first panel we did at Pax08.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Where we're like, I wonder if people are going to show up and then we go over to the panel room.
Scott: There's a line of people waiting.
Scott: It's somewhat significant.
Scott: We go inside and then the room is full.
Scott: We're like, well, one hundred percent full.
Scott: How about that?
Rym: Yep.
Rym: People lined up for a long time to see our panel and what was great.
Rym: Almost no one we knew lined up to see our panel.
Rym: Thank you, guys.
Scott: Finally, people we knew didn't fly to Australia to take seats away from new listeners.
Rym: It's like, yeah, dude, I'm glad that you really like my anime openers from around the world panel, but you've seen it three times and the room is full and there's someone outside who hasn't seen it.
Rym: And it's been the same three years in a row.
Rym: I have literally not changed the words that I have said.
Scott: We did the usual panel.
Scott: People liked it.
Scott: As we predicted, they don't have indie tabletop RPGs in Australia.
Rym: That was the main reason we did such an old standby panel for ourselves beyond Dungeons and Dragons.
Rym: And on the tram to Pax, we picked a random dude really good dog because he was a tabletop RPG.
Rym: We were talking to him.
Rym: He's like really into D&D.
Rym: Well, we queried him.
Scott: Pathfinder's big there.
Rym: He's really into Pathfinder.
Rym: I think most people are into Pathfinder.
Rym: And we were like, all right, we're going to list a bunch of games.
Rym: Tell us if you've heard of any of these.
Rym: Burning Wheel?
Rym: Nope.
Rym: Inspectors?
Rym: Any other game?
Rym: Nope.
Rym: What do you play?
Rym: Pathfinder?
Rym: And I used to play D&D third ed.
Scott: I think one guy mentioned L5R to me at a point during the weekend.
Scott: I saw actually two tables and tabletop playing L5R card game.
Scott: I saw those guys.
Rym: In fact, I saw those guys and I talked to him a little bit because they moved their table over by one of the heaters.
Scott: Yeah, but pretty much only the biggest games are like worthwhile for companies to send there, which is really interesting is if you the one thing that really interested me was how, you know, as usual, WotC takes about half the tabletop space.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Usually when they take up the tabletop space at a Pax Easton Prime, half of their WotC space is magic and half of it is D&D.
Scott: At Pax Australia, it was one hundred percent magic with no D&D.
Scott: They did not bring any D&D anything to Pax Australia.
Scott: They only brought magic.
Scott: Magic was huge there.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The local game store that we went to, I went there for a Netrunner tournament actually later in the week when Rym wasn't there.
Scott: It's pretty much just a magic store with a little bit of board games in the corner.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And this magic was just huge.
Scott: I mean, it's huge everywhere, but it was just the percentage wise, it was bigger.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Even though overall size, probably about the same as it was at Prime or, you know, whatever it is.
Scott: Magic is their game because magic is a big enough game that it's worth economically to send it to Australia, even though magic cards there, it's twice the cost they are here.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So, yeah, it's just like magic just took over almost all the gaming space.
Rym: There was a lot of board gaming going on, but the space that was not magic was pretty much all hardcore German style games.
Rym: And people really were only playing quality games.
Scott: I saw, you know, Cards Against Humanities and things around.
Scott: But yeah, it was mostly.
Scott: mostly I saw power grids.
Scott: I saw Agricolas all over.
Rym: Lots of Agricolas.
Scott: I saw more Agricolas and power grids than I saw settlerses.
Scott: There was some race for the galaxies.
Rym: I saw multiple games of Eclipse going on.
Scott: Puerto Rico's, you know, all that kind of stuff.
Rym: It was so hard to find tabletop space, though, that we basically, well, it's always hard to find tabletop.
Scott: It was hardest, maybe hard as we had tables.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: We got table space by not using tables at one point and going to the queue room, which was mostly empty and running some burning wheel over there.
Scott: So that was at the peak hour.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So they also had a three d s lounge, you know, a portable lounge.
Rym: No sumos.
Rym: They're just regular old bean bags.
Scott: They were sort of weird seat shaped bean bags.
Rym: They worked OK.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I'm I'm done with the bean bag as a thing to sit on.
Rym: No, they're not that good.
Scott: I'm rather sitting at the floor.
Rym: But yeah, pretty much everyone in that area seemed to mostly be playing candy box street pass.
Scott: I saw Animal Crossing's fire emblems.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: That's that's mostly what I saw.
Scott: They also had a TV just showing adventure time the whole time.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I guess copyright stuff like that is not a big deal.
Rym: They can just show stuff randomly.
Scott: It looked like someone just did that.
Rym: Speaking of not worrying about stuff, the fire marshals in Australia seem to be quite unconcerned with the level of fire marshallness that they're exuding.
Rym: But they look the same as our American fire marshals.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: They're just Australian.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: They have the same mustaches, same culture.
Rym: But they seemed I talked to one of them.
Rym: They seemed amazed that the enforcers managed the lines and everything so well that they basically after the first few minutes were like, yeah, whatever.
Rym: You guys got this.
Rym: They seemed surprised, too, that they limited the number of people in the panel rooms to the number of seats.
Rym: I overheard a conversation where I think it was the fire marshal said something like, you know, you could just let people stand at the back like, I'm not going to stop you.
Scott: They're like, yeah, no, we're not doing that.
Scott: What else was different and noteworthy?
Rym: Oh, there's quite a bit.
Rym: So one PC gaming is obviously way bigger there.
Rym: And there was more.
Rym: console gaming was a joke at this kind of a tiny little space.
Rym: A lot of times the TV, the TVs were not 100 percent occupied.
Rym: And because of the bad free speech in Australia, you needed to wear a wristband showing if you were above 18 or above 15, you couldn't go into certain areas unless you had the right colored wristband.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Even the expo hall, I think was you needed to get like certain booths in the expo hall.
Scott: You needed to be 18 to go into the booth.
Scott: And then didn't you have to be 15 period to get in there?
Rym: Even tabletop.
Rym: I don't remember the exact big top.
Rym: You needed your 15 plus wristband to get in.
Scott: Yeah, it's crazy.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: We had to show our ID every day to get a black wristband to be allowed to go to PC gaming.
Scott: That's what the problem of no free speech is.
Rym: But we went over to free PC gaming.
Rym: They only let you play for like 45 minutes because there was a constant crazy line.
Scott: We were definitely in there for less than four.
Scott: We were in there maybe a half hour.
Rym: I went over there to join the gun game counter strike tournament and it was already there's.
Rym: so many people were lined up that they doubled the size of the tournament effectively and still turned away.
Rym: Almost everyone who was standing there.
Rym: It was ridiculous.
Scott: gaming is king everywhere in the world except the US and Japan and in the PC gaming area.
Rym: It seemed like it was mostly league of legends.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: And counter strike.
Scott: Those are the top two games for sure.
Rym: Full of like portal co-ops, a handful of other things, but dota.
Scott: dota was up there, but not as nearly as big as legal interestingly.
Rym: Zero world of Warcraft.
Scott: Well, I don't think there was really internet in the, uh, I don't, I know there was cause.
Rym: I saw a number of people log out of the pack steam and log in with their own accounts.
Scott: Oh, I guess there was.
Rym: I saw lots of people doing that.
Scott: Maybe there was.
Rym: I am very vindicated in my skills at counter strike too, because I got to say when we played, uh, Scott, you did not do so well.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: You did not.
Rym: I won our second game, came in second place in the first game, notwithstanding of the one guy who was crazy better than everyone.
Rym: I beat him in the second game.
Scott: Listen, I killed people.
Scott: I wasn't down at the bottom, like just getting killed, not killing anybody.
Rym: In the first game you were second to the bottom.
Scott: I wasn't.
Rym: Yeah, you were second to the bottom.
Rym: I took screenshots that I cannot share because they're on that PC because I wasn't logged into my steam.
Rym: I should have taken a picture with my phone.
Scott: What are the games?
Scott: did you say you won that you didn't win that I won?
Rym: I don't remember what else we played.
Rym: You beat me more times than I beat you with that weird gear game.
Scott: Oh, gear game.
Scott: That was my game.
Scott: That's my web of power.
Rym: You weren't undefeated in that game though.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I think web of power is your web of power, obviously.
Rym: But yeah, PC gaming was super rockin the whole time.
Rym: And another side point about the 3DS lounge, the challenge that they had on the whiteboard was old school snaking Mario Kart.
Rym: Get the fastest ghost.
Rym: And I think the stage.
Rym: Yeah, the Waluigi.
Rym: It was some stage.
Rym: I think Waluigi pinball, right?
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Uh, yeah.
Rym: I looked that time.
Rym: I looked at my old copy of that game.
Rym: That time is fucking ridiculous.
Rym: Fucking ridiculous.
Scott: The guy probably just snaked the whole thing.
Rym: Yeah, but I snaked the whole thing and I could get nowhere near that.
Rym: So that guy must have snaked to a degree that is legendary.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: I'm sure the enforcers checked it out to make sure he wasn't cheating.
Rym: I'm sure they did.
Rym: It was an interesting note.
Rym: The expo hall, very tiny as it's very tiny, really.
Scott: I mean, usually in the expo hall, which is the party packs, I care about less than others.
Scott: Uh, you know, you walk around at once, you look at every booth and usually I see a bunch of things in there.
Scott: For example, at PAX East last year, I saw Shovel Night and I saw, uh, there was a tabletop dealer that looked at some board games they had.
Scott: We discovered spot it in there two years ago at PAX East, right?
Scott: I usually see things in there like, ooh, ooh, right at this PAX OS.
Scott: I basically saw nothing in that expo hall.
Scott: The only thing of interest to me was there was a booth for madman, which is pretty much the company that brings anime and manga to Australia as in the company.
Scott: There isn't another one.
Scott: It doesn't seem like to me it anyway, you know, and I was able to reconnoiter the anime manga situation well of Australia.
Rym: So that aside, the, the fact that there was more than one Edward Elric cosplayer at PAX Australia says something.
Scott: so anime and manga were bigger in Australia in general than I had thought.
Scott: They were.
Scott: I should, it should have been obvious because it's physically close to Japan, but it's big.
Rym: They were a big part of packs, pretty much everyone we met because we just met random people and hung out and played games with them.
Rym: In fact, I remember there's a couple that we played some games with at the end of one of those tabletop roles.
Rym: They were super cool.
Rym: We basically formed this group of smart people who would play games quickly and it was great.
Rym: And out of nowhere, I was like something, something anime, something Attack on Titan.
Rym: The guy was like something, something Attack on Titan.
Rym: And I'm like, wait a minute, wait a minute.
Rym: You speak of the anime.
Scott: Pretty much everyone spoke of the anime.
Scott: We went to this bar that was totally anime-ed out.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Instead of going to Gordon Beers after PAX, like we normally do, we went to the equivalent, but it was totally anime.
Rym: It was Asian beer cafe.
Scott: Asian beer cafe.
Scott: Just anime stuff all over the walls.
Scott: Astro Boy in the bathroom.
Rym: And the thing is, the place.
Scott: We were watching High School of the Dead on the TV.
Rym: The place was just normal semi-hip people hanging out.
Rym: It just happened to be super anime.
Scott: It was anime around just like, you know, here you can only find anime in an anime store or the anime corner of a Best Buy.
Rym: I'll be honest, it packs.
Rym: If I'm hanging out with someone new that I don't know and like something, something anime and anime comes up, I'll usually ask, oh, so what shows do you like?
Rym: And they'll, and usually they won't be able to mention much and I'll get to do my usual, oh, well, you should watch Cowboy Bebop.
Rym: That's probably up your alley.
Scott: You didn't need to do that in Australia.
Rym: Here, I was like, yeah, so what do you watch?
Rym: He's like, well, right now I'm watching Attack on Titan and all these other current shows.
Scott: Yeah, I've seen Utena.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: I was like, what are your favorite shows?
Rym: Like, well, Cowboy Bebop, duh.
Rym: So I don't know, Utena is pretty good.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: It's like, oh, well, let me tell you about this thing I do.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, I feel like we could have done just as well doing anime panels there.
Scott: Probably.
Scott: It was just, you know, usually in the
Scott: U.S.,
Scott: the thing that we try to push as GeekNights is the crossover of geekeries.
Rym: Because in the U.S.
Rym: it doesn't happen.
Rym: Right.
Scott: And there is less of it.
Scott: There is the, we always bring up Silver Age Spider-Man guy.
Scott: He doesn't even cross over into X-Men.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But it's like this guy at PAX who loves games.
Rym: X-Men, he doesn't cross over into Golden Age.
Scott: He doesn't cross over into tech or anime or comics or anything.
Scott: And he's just gaming guy in Australia.
Scott: It didn't seem like that guy was there.
Scott: People there who were geeks spread across the geekeries, especially the anime and the manga and the gaming.
Scott: They were, they were merged.
Scott: It was the same people.
Rym: There were anime vendors.
Rym: There were anime DVDs in the grab bag.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Like for real anime everywhere.
Rym: Everyone just kind of knows about it and watches it.
Scott: It wasn't like.
Scott: It was anime.
Rym: You know what I would say?
Scott: And manga.
Rym: It was an undercurrent that the average person you talk to was also a pretty knowledgeable fan of anime.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And happened to also be a gamer.
Scott: But they were behaving in a PAX fashion.
Scott: They did not behave in an AnimeCon fashion even though maybe like 10% of the cosplays were animes.
Rym: I think more than 10% when I'm thinking back.
Rym: I can go through all the pictures I took.
Scott: It's tough to say.
Rym: There were two separate Edward Elric cosplayers at a PAX.
Scott: It's true.
Rym: And part of that appears to be in 2013 that a lot of the other cons in Australia are pretty weak sauce.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It didn't like.
Scott: do those other cons even have panels?
Scott: Who speaks at them?
Scott: Who do they get to go?
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like they don't have, you know, that thing going on.
Scott: That supply of panel doers.
Rym: I think that we have granted packs for the longest time was still pretty much all industry and us.
Scott: I mean, meanwhile, PAX Prime, if you look at the schedule is looking to have not less industry, but because they added the fourth day, but they didn't get more industry to fill the panels.
Scott: It seems like they brought in, you know, a lot of the fan sort of content to fill in that space, which is good on them.
Rym: Good on them.
Scott: Good on them.
Rym: But yeah, I was just really surprised at the level of anime crossover and how casual it was.
Rym: I have a kind of theory that I'll get into more in another show someday, but basically I wonder if it's because there there's a deeper correlation.
Rym: All the people we met at this packs office, everyone was just super chill, was also super internetty.
Rym: They knew the same things we knew like new games that are coming out.
Rym: Even at packs in the US, I'll be like something, something said five and a random person I'm with will either make up some bullshit about it or not know that beyond the soil in
Scott: Australia where there's nothing, you know, the supplies of geeky or low, you have to be internetty.
Scott: You have to.
Rym: Yes, but I
Scott: think PC gamer, you have to be, there
Rym: might be non internetty nerds there like there are here, but here because of other means and because packs has been around for so long, non internetty people show up at packs here and people who are like gaming but aren't super hardcore about it show up to packs is here like that kid who thought that packs and the penny arcade expo were separate and thought that penny arcade was homestuck
Scott: right
Rym: at packs.
Rym: Us only internet people knew that packs us was happening and it sold out immediately solely to people who are on the internet.
Rym: That's true.
Rym: So it might be that we just happened to go to a packs that was literally only available to internet people and internet people are the kinds of people we're talking about.
Scott: Very well could be.
Rym: That is entirely possible.
Rym: Other things going on.
Rym: The tabletop library was the same as always.
Rym: The keynote was a great keynote.
Scott: I think it was actually, it was a typical keynote for packs, which is, you know, above our, you know, it's good.
Rym: It was the third or fourth best one of any packs I've been to.
Scott: I mean, it seemed like the same keynote over and over again, which is, you know, decent, but I'm sort of getting tired of the, here's how I got into the gaming industry.
Scott: Look at, let's play the woo game.
Scott: Let's play the woo game with all the old stuff that I liked when I was young and got me into gaming.
Rym: He talked a lot about the origins of monkey island.
Rym: that was actually really interesting.
Scott: That was the good part.
Scott: That was the fascinating part.
Rym: The fact that everyone who's ever given a packs keynote who I respect and who has interesting things to say and has made good games has said that star wars was pretty much the thing that got them going.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: That's like the third or fourth time that's been like, oh my God, star wars, which is, you know why?
Scott: Because all these people doing it are like these 40, 50 year old dudes.
Rym: But look at, look at the anime industry is the same thing.
Scott: Our super Mario brothers was their star wars.
Rym: Every time I go to an anime thing and there's a director and they're giving some speech, they're always talking about how star wars really pushed them.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Star wars.
Rym: I can't think of a movie that's had that effects in star wars.
Scott: Yet again, it's all these people who were inspired by film and went into gaming instead of Hollywood.
Rym: Well, is it better than the people who are inspired by gaming and then go into gaming?
Scott: You end up with more monkey islands and less eclipses.
Rym: Like the people are inspired by anime and then go into anime to make anime for people who are then inspired by that.
Scott: Listen, that's also a problem, right?
Rym: Yes, they're all problems.
Rym: Uh, anyway, the enforcer culture, there were a few little missteps, a couple of line snakes that collapsed, a couple of, you know, early missteps of this guy is new and doesn't know the official way to make a line go.
Rym: By Friday afternoon, you would be hard pressed to differentiate a Pax Aus enforcer from a Pax Prime enforcer, but for the color of their shirts, but for the nature of their dialect.
Scott: I was about to say, but for their accent, you could say, Hey, what else do we had to say about Pax Australia without talking about Australia?
Rym: I just went outside.
Scott: One thing that was really interesting.
Rym: I went outside to the grocery store that was next to the con and got a hot meat pie.
Rym: I bought meat pies for $2 and Red Bulls.
Rym: I probably could have just bought beer and walked into the convention center, past the convention center security, openly eating it and no fucks were given.
Scott: There were all the food came from these food carts at the packs.
Scott: Now people in Australia like food trucks and the people in Australia were like, all right, the food's okay.
Scott: And I was like, this food is light years beyond the food you will get at concessions at any con I've ever been to in the US.
Scott: The food is one half a step below the quality of New York, you know, the street truck food, right?
Rym: Yeah, that is the kind of food I would be okay eating now for lunch.
Scott: That burger.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: That burger I could get there was like a half step under Frites and Meats, right?
Scott: Which is really good.
Scott: You know, New York City burger truck.
Rym: And the dim sum I got from the convention center was great.
Scott: People were like, it's all right.
Scott: And I'm like, you have come to real packs and go to the concessions, right?
Scott: It PAX Prime.
Rym: It's $6 slice of pizza.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Go to subway, go to the Javits and get the friggin empanada.
Rym: Stand in line for an hour to get a crap.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: You'll fucking kill yourself.
Scott: Eat that shit.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Only cause it will poison you.
Scott: And because it will taste so bad, you will stab yourself afterwards.
Rym: This was also the first packs that we had.
Scott: Those people like Vegemite.
Scott: So fuck that.
Rym: I told you.
Rym: I was like, we should try Vegemite.
Scott: My coworker is now eating the Vegemite.
Scott: We'll get more to that in another day.
Rym: Oh my God.
Rym: We'll talk about this on Thursday.
Rym: The Vegemite.
Scott: Yeah, of course.
Rym: You might.
Scott: You have to talk about it when you're talking about us.
Rym: We do have to talk about it.
Rym: But, uh, we had to take, you know, the convention also lacked something that every other packs has.
Rym: There was no hotel gaming because there were no hotels.
Scott: That's correct.
Rym: You literally took a tram or a train, a significant distance to the convention that was far away or a car.
Rym: And then you left from there back and everyone was staying all over the city.
Rym: There was no place you would meet up.
Scott: In fact, and the hotels didn't really have the sort of lobbies that had gaming going on.
Rym: Ours especially didn't, even though our hotel, I think was 90% packs people.
Rym: There was no gaming going on in that lobby.
Scott: None, none whatsoever.
Rym: Now, interestingly, people did hang out after packs, but they all went to bars to hang out and they do that at regular packs too.
Rym: They do.
Rym: But that was the only place you could go hang out.
Scott: There was a place monobar that they really loved, but that place is like a, it's basically their barcade, but their barcade is just like a few TVs on the wall and it's really tiny.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Game consoles looked up my head in and I got to say something about bars in general in Australia.
Rym: This might be perception cause I didn't poke my head into all bars, but the bars I poked my head into both the nerdy ones and non nerdy ones, the music and bullshit was half as loud as an average US bar.
Scott: I think in New York is also particularly loud now everywhere.
Rym: Go to Boston, go to Seattle.
Rym: They're all just so fucking loud and I just, I've always hated.
Scott: There was a thing that says the places that are loud make money.
Scott: The place I know they do out of business.
Rym: I can talk at length about why that's the case, but I still hate it.
Rym: I would pay double just to not have it be loud.
Scott: Another interesting thing, right?
Scott: Is that at packs in the U S East or prime, all the official packs merge, especially the t-shirts that say packs on them and the scarves that say packs on them, sell the fuck out.
Scott: You could not get one on Sunday usually unless it's like a lady's extra small or some shit like that, right?
Scott: Add packs OS.
Scott: People were buying merch on the way out as they were being shoved out of packs as it was closed and there was still some left.
Scott: I don't know if Robert cool would be happy about that.
Scott: Uh, cause he bought merging amazing.
Scott: Never sell, but that was interesting that they were not buying the t-shirts.
Scott: They didn't sell up.
Rym: but uh, I bought the t-shirts because I'm, if I'm going to fly that far, that's going to have the fucking shirt.
Rym: Wear it to other packs and be like, yeah, yeah.
Rym: What?
Rym: But the official shirt, not the like year shirt, but just the night, the sort of stylized shirt is so great for so many reasons.
Scott: That whole set is great.
Scott: I know, but this one, I have the full set by the way.
Rym: It was the spider for one and two, the pal logo on the bottom really sealed the deal.
Scott: It definitely did.
Rym: But yeah, people see that it was a packs.
Rym: The people were like packs people, just more chill and hip for the reasons we talked about.
Rym: We'll see if that continues to be true.
Rym: I don't know how packs can grow in Melbourne.
Scott: There was, there was that other convention.
Scott: he plays that's next to the casino to the casino and I don't know if packs really wants to use casino space.
Rym: We check the space out to a degree.
Rym: It's okay.
Rym: It's not great.
Rym: It's not optimal.
Rym: I think they'd still be better off being there than being in the show grounds.
Scott: They're better off being sometime when it's warm and not cold.
Rym: Rumor has it it'll be in a warmer time next year.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I mean basically at the closing ceremonies, Jerry said, you know, packs will be in Australia next year.
Scott: So you didn't confirm a time or place.
Scott: I am 99% sure.
Scott: Melbourne and I admit there were people's basically saying, yeah, we heard it'll still be Melbourne and I am 80% sure.
Rym: summertime, maybe fall.
Rym: It will probably be a warmer time, not winter because that shit was, it was way too cold.
Rym: I wear my kilt one day and then nope.
Rym: Thus I wore the same increasingly getting a more and more dirty jeans.
Scott: Sadly, the next packs I probably, the first packs I won't go to since oh wait, we'll probably be, that doesn't, that's not a dev packs.
Scott: We'll probably be packs us 2013, 14 speaking of that unless someone pays for us to go.
Rym: So speaking of that, that was a lot of money.
Rym: Our panel seemed super successful, but two we, uh, there were a lot of GeekNights listeners at this pack.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't count them, but people basically kept coming up to us all the time talking, knowing who we were and or they saw us at our panel and they said our panel was good and I was like, all right, okay.
Rym: Uh, one guy actually brought up radio free equestria to me and he was like, yeah, you should do more of that.
Rym: No, he knew me as the radio free equestria guy cause I had a rainbow days on my badge.
Scott: Of course.
Rym: And I was like, yeah, you know, I'm here as a speaker.
Rym: He's like, oh, what'd you do?
Rym: And I was like, yeah, you know, well, you know, uh, gaming GeekNights.
Rym: Uh, and he thought that we were just the RFE guys.
Scott: Yeah, we're from Australia.
Scott: The RFE.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway, but there were so many listeners there.
Rym: It was kind of unnerving, which kind of proves what we've been going for all along that we come from the internet.
Rym: Our culture is on the internet.
Rym: So our people are not tied to geography.
Rym: They're tied to the geography solely of language.
Rym: Correct.
Rym: If you speak English and are a nerd, you might be our people.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Two, all the listeners there were pretty vociferously trying to get us to do a Kickstarter.
Rym: I wouldn't say all.
Scott: I would say there was at one point a group of people near us who suggested, well, because
Rym: everyone else had left and the convention was closed and we were still there because we did the classic trick of just stand there until everyone else leaves around you and then the doors close around you and now you're still inside
Scott: and now the train is gone.
Scott: You need to use the tram.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: My mom sent us a, she's texted me.
Rym: She was like, I don't know.
Rym: I didn't say it out loud at any point.
Rym: This is the first time I've ever said it.
Scott: It's like my internet name.
Scott: It's not a name you say.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: She tweeted at us.
Rym: She was like, yeah, dogs.
Rym: Last train out of Dodge just left.
Rym: And I was like, fucks.
Scott: Tram is much slower.
Rym: Yeah, but the tram was all packs and it was all the people that we kind of accidentally kept.
Scott: We had good times on trams or trains with other people.
Rym: Yes, actually really good times.
Rym: We basically gave impromptu GeekNights shows slash panels on the tram for a surprisingly captive audience in that they couldn't get off the tram.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So, but this group of people that was left was mostly GeekNights listeners and they were like, yeah, why don't you kickstart it?
Rym: We would all contribute to that.
Rym: We're like, yeah, right.
Rym: And they were like, no, really.
Rym: We would really contribute to that.
Rym: Really do it.
Scott: I don't know if that's a thing you can kickstart.
Scott: Buy me a trip to Australia.
Rym: Do you know how many kickstarters I've seen that are that?
Rym: The kickstarter would be, we will go to PAXOS 2014, do a panel at it, do a live GeekNights recording at it, and then the stretch goals will be things like we'll visit Sydney and do a meetup.
Scott: Why don't we ask our friends who work at kickstarter for advice in that department?
Rym: I looked at several kickstarters that were, what did you do?
Rym: There are so many kickstarters that are literally that.
Rym: What'd you do?
Rym: We could do that.
Rym: What are you going to interrupt the show to note that I knocked the Marantz over and unplugged it?
Rym: Uh, it's battery powered.
Rym: It's still recorded everything.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: We're not backing up this last two minutes of the show.
Scott: Let's just end the show now.
Rym: Don't end the show now.
Scott: What else do you have to say about PAX Australia?
Rym: I got a lot to say about PAX Australia, but I think it's better served by a straight up Australia show at this point.
Scott: Yeah, we pretty much, oh, the Megathon finale was the big Jenga that they always use.
Rym: Yeah, which to the crowd there was off the hook.
Scott: But to us it was a cop out.
Rym: I've seen that before and it wasn't even the final round.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I can understand why though because after the incident at the last PAX.
Scott: And you're out of showgrounds, pretty much anything you try will fail.
Scott: So great job with the pinball fake out.
Rym: Oh my God.
Rym: The thing is it got you, it got you and it didn't get me captain.
Rym: All right.
Rym: You were like, it's pinball, it's pinball.
Rym: I was like, there's no way it's pinball.
Rym: Do you think, do you really believe Scott Rubin that Robert Koo, the man who is the genius at this kind of thing?
Scott: I thought, okay, I was thinking that obviously not that dumb.
Scott: I was thinking the surprise would be what pinball it was and not well, there was that Metallica pinball in the expo, which was surprising because those are, that's like the newest pinball.
Rym: It was in the big top, right?
Scott: But it's kind of rare that pinball machine.
Scott: It's like they only made so many of them on earth.
Scott: So they have that many on.
Scott: Australia was a big deal.
Rym: There's just a row of them.
Rym: You could play them for charity.
Scott: Yeah, but no, I thought it was going to be like custom penny arcade pinball table or something insane like that.
Rym: But you thought that they would be so careless as to cover the pinball machine with a sheet, a form hugging sheet that made it obvious it was a pinball.
Rym: I was sure from the second I saw that it was a fake out.
Scott: I was thinking it could be pinball and the surprise of it would not be that it was pinball, but what pinball?
Scott: and he would freak out because of what pinball it was and not the fact that it was pinball.
Rym: Also pinball would not have been that interesting to watch.
Rym: Crane game.
Scott: That's true.
Scott: You do have that.
Rym: There were too many factors.
Rym: There was no way, no way.
Scott: I did not consider that.
Rym: if I had done so, I would have realized, but when they went around with the traditional guess what the omega finale will be, I'm very happy to report that multiple people had written knifey spoonie.
Rym: So yeah, maybe, maybe not coming back to PaxOz 2014, but I will not pay for it with my own money.
Rym: I might cause I might have some work excuses to go to Australia anyway.
Scott: It's not your own money.
Scott: That's a company.
Rym: So if I'm there, I'll pay my own money for all the other stuff.
Scott: Yeah, but I'm not paying for my own money for a $2,000 round trip plane ticket.
Scott: That's not happening again.
Rym: Whatevs.
Rym: That's not even a month's rent.
Scott: Not next year anyway.
Scott: Unless maybe, I mean, I could win a lottery for it with a ticket I did not buy.
Scott: Maybe I will find a lottery ticket on the ground.
Scott: Someone else bought and discarded.
Scott: that will happen to win.
Rym: My office did the pool as usual and I did not contribute.
Scott: Of course you are wise.
Scott: You will spend your dollars on an app on steam.
Rym: There was a FARC story.
Rym: I forget when, but I remember reading about this.
Rym: A guy didn't go into the pool and his office won like $10 million.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I don't want to be that guy, but I still didn't give him my five bucks.
Scott: What if you're that guy and everyone in your company quits?
Rym: I think if that happens, they might just give me some money anyway.
Rym: That's what I'm holding out on.
Scott: How much do you think they'll give you?
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: Imagine if you were in it and another guy at your company, think about the person at your company is the most annoying.
Scott: You know what?
Rym: If it's a small company.
Scott: They didn't put any money in it, where do you need to give them?
Rym: Well, it's the annoying guy.
Rym: So zero.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: You're the annoying guy.
Rym: I'm not the annoying guy.
Scott: You are.
Rym: I'm the weird guy.
Rym: I'm not the annoying guy.
Scott: You're fine.
Scott: The weirdest guy besides you.
Rym: The weirdest guy might get some money because he's so weird.
Rym: Everyone's afraid that he's going to go weird one day.
Scott: No.
Scott: We're done.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.