Rym: Hey, it's Wednesday October 9th, 2013.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Scott: Let's do this Didn't we already do that show?
Rym: well like really recently we kind of reviewed it.
Rym: You know we used to do this thing on gig nights where we'd preview a show like we'd watch one episode and say whether or Not was worth watching at all Because we had no ideas.
Scott: we had to milk every episode of GeekNights.
Rym: We could out of everything we watched and then we do the review which was the all right.
Rym: We've seen a bunch of the show should you watch it, but we don't spoil anything.
Rym: And then we would do the final thoughts which is the.
Rym: yeah, we'll just talk about it.
Rym: We assume you've seen it And we haven't actually been able to talk about attack on Titan on the show with spoilers.
Rym: We kind of danced around everything and that's what you want to do.
Scott: episode.
Scott: I kind of just want to be like fuck spoilers forever.
Scott: I don't believe it.
Rym: Oh, yeah But there's a good reason to review things without revealing everything about.
Scott: people won't listen to my podcast because they believe in spoilers.
Rym: the point Of a review is to tell someone whether or not media is worth consuming for them.
Rym: For them.
Rym: is the media worth consuming?
Scott: are you an anime fan?
Scott: Do you watch animes?
Scott: watch this show the end?
Rym: Yeah, but we can talk about why.
Rym: I mean people like her.
Rym: I mean, you don't need to know why some people we know really like kill la kill and some people we know Really don't like kill la kill.
Rym: I like kill la kill.
Scott: I like kill like.
Rym: I can describe what I like about the show.
Rym: Oh, which would tell some people why not to like it.
Rym: For example, if I say the words Scott kill la kill Reminds me aesthetically of an updated apocalypse zero awesome.
Rym: You might say something like awesome or fuck.
Rym: But a normal human being would say oh my god.
Rym: and now watch it.
Scott: well, that's just the thing is like why It's like the amount of time and effort it takes to get the reviews.
Scott: You could have just watched it and found out for yourself.
Rym: Not necessarily.
Rym: Yeah, watch a whole show all the episode one episode.
Rym: That's what the previews.
Scott: That's all we've watched.
Scott: Kill la kill.
Rym: Well kill la kill.
Rym: Yeah, so we'll get right into it.
Rym: Kill la kill came out very recently and it's worth talking about early because It kind of proved that trigger is not a flash in the pan, right?
Scott: So if you don't know there's a new anime studio on the scene called trigger.
Scott: They started by making inferno couple inferno cup.
Rym: Well, they started by doing two other piddly projects.
Scott: It's probably just contracts to get the money, right?
Scott: Yeah, you do like a video game FMV stuff like that one episode.
Rym: Just the animation of idol mask.
Scott: yeah Gonzo did the same sort of things, right?
Scott: They made like right.
Scott: but the first anime they made which is on YouTube is inferno.
Scott: And when you saw in finna cup, you knew whoever was making that.
Scott: Knew the deal.
Scott: the animation quality wasn't there in inferno couple which was kind of by design But you knew whoever was writing that thing was real anime.
Scott: That is the real deal.
Rym: could have been a flash in the play could have been a flash.
Scott: Look the anime boncho whoever it is that makes the peeping life and all that stuff, right?
Scott: they had turning girls, which is great and now the current one is like a Detective dog agency, which is in.
Rym: it's not turning girls Yep, or even look at the history of guy next guy next is all over the place.
Rym: Yeah, even Jillian mohoromatic Whoa, I remember a lot of people started watching mohoromatic is they were like guy next guy next.
Scott: at that time when that came out Gainax could do new wrong.
Rym: Yep, and then I watched mohoromatic and I was like what what what show bit same show God anyway, so but then little witch academia.
Scott: Yeah, so little witch academia was by trigger as well.
Scott: And that's like whoa, they can fucking animate can't they?
Scott: they had the skills They just didn't use them on inferno cup and we talked about little witch academia.
Rym: So I'll just link to that episode in.
Scott: little witch academia is great But it's possible yet again that a get another fluke right.
Scott: some weird YouTube show and a weird special young Animators funded project.
Rym: a cool one episode short.
Rym: I mean every genius party is great.
Scott: That's studio 4c there.
Rym: Yeah, but it's hard to turn one of those into an actual show.
Scott: I think it is Yeah, so but even still both of the.
Scott: it was studio 4c.
Scott: So it's still possible that this trigger.
Scott: the two things they had done were sort of special cases and they were both good.
Scott: So it's like are they really good or are they just special cases now?
Rym: They kick-started another episode of little witch academia waiting on that stuff.
Scott: We don't the jury's out.
Scott: But in the meantime, they have a real anime an original anime not based on a manga not based on a light novel not based on a visual novel not based on anything just its original anime TV series.
Scott: and They made it all on their own the writing and the animating.
Scott: and it's on TV now.
Scott: First episode was last week.
Scott: The second episode is tomorrow the Thursday the 10th.
Scott: Yep It's gonna be on the crunchy rolls.
Rym: If only I had thorns like a thistle.
Rym: Yes episode 2 so sexy I'm gonna faint.
Scott: Yeah, so it's kill la kill.
Scott: and Is this gonna be good based on episode 1?
Scott: conclusive 100%.
Scott: this isn't no Deal.
Rym: you may not like the new guy next some people will do.
Rym: But I know people who don't like you like him but watching this episode It brought it almost it was like the flashback.
Rym: Like if you were watching the show about me watching this episode to watch it again.
Scott: And I was like did someone actually just make that our Savior?
Scott: I bow to thee.
Rym: Yeah ground would go black and it would cut to flashbacks of me sitting in the audience of the RIT anime club or Sitting in the lounge in Peterson 3 watching a weird old anime that Scott found in the anime club library.
Rym: That's some old senior in the club told us to watch going.
Rym: Whoa Yeah, this get this show.
Rym: We'll talk about it again.
Scott: You know, it hasn't been in a long time.
Scott: I think it's anime season.
Scott: people have been like space dandy the anime that will save anime.
Rym: I think.
Scott: maybe kill it attack on Titan kill la kill space dandy The battle against the dread specter of moe As is well underway.
Scott: Well, maybe winning.
Rym: I've said this before but in more detail.
Rym: Madoka was the show that got people like us to watch anime again as it was coming out because it was just so great.
Rym: But attack on Titan got all the anime fans that weren't watching a lot of anime all of them Not just people like us to watch that show and then start watching other shows.
Rym: And now kill la kill and then the coming space dandy and suddenly there's all these shows coming out and we've got this huge audience of anime fans who kind of Came back to anime because of attack on Titan
Scott: not to mention a bunch of shows that were sort of under the radar that were Dug up say like a space brothers or an eccentric family that were just sort of sitting there hiding amongst the the dregs.
Scott: Yeah, I mean silver people people bothered to uncover because they got brought back to the yard.
Rym: and You know, once again when we reviewed all that anime from that season before it came out Still pretty accurate.
Scott: Hmm.
Scott: Yeah, so let's talk about kill la kill a little bit.
Rym: Okay animation is The best but it's it's this sort of retro cool, but with good modern techniques.
Scott: Yeah, it's somewhere between like remember that Kevin knows me that was the right the weird the enemy.
Scott: It's got a little bit of that a little bit of fist of the North Star.
Rym: It's got a little bit of not fist of the North Star more like otaku or toku juku.
Scott: Yeah, man school it also has a even a little bit of Akira in there right like those scenes will be giant red text and Zooming the camera just going down the town from the top of the school Zooming out like that.
Rym: all the characters new tenor have analogs.
Scott: in this show This it is a tenor plus something plus apocalypse zero.
Scott: I mean, it's like you have a student council that rules this school.
Scott: They're the elites that they have these powers And they right.
Scott: it's definitely something.
Scott: it's really lines up with the antenna a lot Yeah, but it's almost.
Rym: you know, the way I would almost say this this is kind of is even a walk about that.
Scott: It's just yep.
Scott: That's walk about right there Escaflowne.
Rym: the show was a show.
Rym: Yeah, and then there was the movie which was kind of whoa.
Rym: So there was a parallel thing.
Rym: It was not in the same universe It was kind of kind.
Rym: it was the same characters, but every character was sort of distilled and more intense Like focus.
Rym: take one aspect and then push it to the extreme of what that character was like.
Rym: a show.
Rym: Kill la kill kinda is.
Rym: you could say that it's kind of like that with you Tena that you look at these characters.
Rym: It's like yeah Take one part of utenna her tomboy bad attitude and just take it to the ridiculous extreme and give her half a pair of scissors.
Scott: So yeah, what the show is about is there's a horrible school that is ruled by a student council and they have uniforms.
Scott: They give them power.
Rym: Oh my god, the Goku seifuku, right?
Scott: So the one thing.
Scott: so most of the students are regular students and they're just busy victims trying to get through school without getting killed.
Rym: But they're all pretty chill with it.
Rym: They're like, this is just how it is.
Scott: Well, they're also kind of badass.
Scott: even the regular students, right?
Rym: There's zero star students are pretty badass, right?
Scott: So then I mean, it's a badass town that badass rabbit.
Rym: It's like the island that Kenshiro goes to at the end.
Scott: Oh, okay But anyway, so then this one-star uniforms two-star and three-star and the more stars the more powerful you are.
Scott: Those are the people who are favored by the student council who hands out the uniform and the opening.
Rym: basically.
Scott: So it's usually like the club.
Scott: the sport club captains are really powerful and stuff, right at the beginning of the show.
Rym: You get this, you know, the this there's a normal class going on in this obviously post-apocalyptic world Very very apocalypse zero style in there and then out of nowhere this crazy Trigun villain looking guy just breaks down the door and fucking murders a kid.
Rym: But the kid kind of deserved it because he tried to steal a one-star Goku uniform.
Scott: Yeah, one star is like you are a really good basketball player in the basketball team.
Scott: You know what a one star is like captain of the basketball team and three star is like There's these elite four who are under the student council president who don't even know how many stars they that girl Her surname is very similar to togas surname.
Scott: Yeah, right exactly.
Rym: Here you carry you in.
Scott: Yeah, but anyway, the three stars are the elite four people who are underneath the student council president.
Scott: Which is the disciplinary guy?
Scott: Who's the guy at the beginning?
Rym: Oh my god Dynamites, what's his name?
Scott: The guy who's in charge of all sport clubs the guy the girl who's in charge of all non sport clubs And then that weird guy with the computer.
Scott: Well, I don't know what he was in charge of.
Rym: So this nerdy kid who had stolen a one-star Goku uniform and the guy's like you shit bird You're not even worthy of wearing this.
Rym: go ahead put it on or I'll just kill you right now.
Rym: And he puts it on and he's immediately transformed into a handsome badass.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Well as bad as that body can get yeah But he turns handsome and he's awesome and then they just kill him because he's a three-star.
Scott: He's immune to one stars.
Rym: So there's a little bit of paranoia going on in there too.
Scott: red level blue love I mean, yeah that kind of people that kind of paranoid that people listening might not have understood what you meant.
Rym: Yeah, our paranoia the role-playing game was tabletop role-playing game, right?
Scott: Anyway, so this girl shows up in town who's clearly utenna and she goes to the school.
Scott: She works her way up there.
Scott: She gets harassed by walking.
Scott: She's got typical anime intro with a transfer student.
Scott: Yeah, and she you know, you find out she's looking for something, right?
Scott: She's up to no good and she's not afraid of any bullshit.
Scott: So she finally sees this student council president.
Scott: She's like who's the top dog around here?
Scott: That's the one I'm challenging you.
Scott: and she's got this giant half a scissor.
Scott: is her weapon.
Scott: It's basically a sword.
Rym: This show is all about those moments where a character who is more important than you Notices something and does the slight eyebrow raise and says interesting.
Rym: Hmm that happens all the time.
Scott: She's got this giant half a scissor and she's challenged.
Scott: She's coming from transfer student first day to challenging but basically the god of the school Yeah, like it and then shit goes down.
Rym: I cannot express to you how this show has done.
Scott: That's episode one.
Scott: It does not waste any time.
Rym: Madoka was a Legitimately generally good show.
Rym: it made me cry.
Rym: It made me care.
Rym: This show did something that no show is done.
Rym: That's new in a long time.
Rym: It made me say out loud.
Rym: Oh, fuck.
Scott: Yes That's right That's what this show is.
Scott: It's fuck.
Scott: Yeah the show.
Rym: Yeah, so Follow this show.
Rym: what watch one episode of it without thought if you like it or don't?
Rym: it doesn't matter.
Rym: if you care about Anime, you at least need to know that this show is happening because this show Might be important.
Scott: this show may eventually become right like the show that studio You know really made studio trigger like cemented in.
Rym: yeah, this might be triggers, right?
Scott: It's like guy next did important things before they made Ava, right?
Scott: Yeah icon animation Yeah, but that would Ava was like guy next cemented.
Scott: This could be the Evangelion of studio trigger this savior of anime.
Scott: Please save us.
Scott: Any other news is?
Scott: we did a geek bite so it's kind of inside.
Rym: I got a small geek bite Randomly found some episodes of Teen Titans go which is a read you're really got nothing to do.
Rym: No, it's a riri redo of Teen Titans.
Scott: Why did they really redo?
Scott: Why don't I just keep going with what they had what they kind of sucked?
Rym: I don't like Teen Titans.
Rym: Okay, I don't like the characters.
Scott: the original cartoon this you should try reading the original comic.
Scott: Yeah, I know Ben like all that Donna Troy bullshit the original Teen Titans cartoon.
Rym: What many people not just me complained that it was?
Rym: pseudo anime that it was an American style lame-o cartoon that took the tropes like the superficial tropes of what people would stereotypically associate with anime and just kind of rammed him into the show to take advantage of the then soaring popularity of quote-unquote anime.
Rym: you know that was in like 2002 2003 when anime was on this huge plateau peak before the steep decline.
Scott: Popularity coming back.
Rym: I think it's coming back, but It was not a good show.
Rym: I didn't like it.
Rym: there wasn't much going on there.
Rym: Teen Titans go which started in April this year is really funny and I need to watch more episodes before I review it fully but I Find it utterly hilarious.
Rym: and the reason why is simple one It doesn't.
Rym: it's funny for the same reason.
Rym: anime news Nina is funny to use a recent exam like a news.
Rym: Nina exactly Why do we like it?
Rym: because anime news Nina isn't afraid of?
Rym: actually Going to kind of dark places and making fun of itself and making a lot of.
Scott: I mostly like it because it it's one of those things where If you aren't a person who goes to anime cons and stuff like that Then none of those things will mean anything to you, right?
Scott: It's one of those really targeted It's really funny to a very small subset of people.
Rym: Yep But it also will Basically ridicule the kinds of people who also go to that site.
Rym: it ridicules the site's customers.
Rym: It'd be like if the New York Times ran a comic that just literally shat all over the culture of the people who read the New York Times.
Rym: You know the scary fanboy guy.
Rym: it is not a kind comic to that kind of person like our valued customers.
Rym: Yeah, exactly like that.
Rym: Okay So Teen Titans go kind of goes in that direction and that it's not like the comics and it's just.
Rym: it's more like Adventure Time In that it's goes to kind of weird and dark place.
Scott: Oh, I guess it's bandwagoning again.
Scott: Yeah, what's popular now?
Scott: Let's copy that.
Rym: Ah, but well done.
Rym: Hmm, and I've actually enjoyed the episodes that I've watched.
Rym: We'll see if I like it enough, but it's kind of dark.
Scott: I don't.
Scott: I don't have I don't need another show to watch.
Rym: I think people people die.
Rym: There's a lot of oddly sexual jokes that don't really seem to fit who you'd expect the show to be aimed at the shows Aimed at 30 year olds instead of 13 year olds.
Rym: Just put it like that.
Scott: That's what 30 year olds say when they like a show aimed at three year olds.
Rym: My little pony was aimed at 11 year olds.
Scott: Same thing.
Rym: It just happened to be popular among.
Scott: Yes, let's move on.
Rym: But anyway things of the day.
Rym: So you Scott's thinking that is pretty pretty good.
Rym: I did not see this.
Scott: so in the 70s, New York City, not the greatest right now like it is now and There was actually At that time the police were getting underfunded and not only did was their crime and heart, you know It was way worse than it is now.
Scott: It was like taxi driver kind of shit, right?
Scott: They were gonna Underfund the police and fire departments and such.
Scott: so what the police did at the police union made this pamphlet Welcome to fear city had like a scary skull on it.
Rym: when it's like this the graphic design of this is evocative.
Rym: I'll just give you everything I love from the year 1981.
Scott: It's basically a pamphlet that gives advice to tourists who are coming to New York City and like here's a here's a small excerpt.
Scott: Nevertheless some New Yorkers do manage to survive and even to keep their property intact.
Scott: The following guidelines have been prepared by a council of firefighters and law officers to help you Enjoy your visit to the city of New York in comfort and safety.
Scott: Good luck grim reaper face.
Rym: item Number three avoid public transportation.
Rym: item number four remain in Manhattan.
Scott: Hey do not leave valuables in your hotel room and do not deposit them in the hotel vault.
Scott: It's basically this, you know fear pamphlet and it's pretty hilarious.
Scott: I Want to print them out and hand them out.
Rym: I just want no I want to replace the year 1975 with the year 2013.
Scott: you also have to replace some other things like just your mayor beam.
Scott: Mayor beam is not the mayor anymore.
Rym: No tourist would know who the mayor is.
Scott: tourists know who the mayor is.
Rym: No, they'll think it's a funny name for Bloomberg because they both start with B and you know what.
Rym: blazio also starts with B So it'll be fine.
Scott: No, it's be a me.
Rym: Yeah, it starts with B. They'll think it's a stupid weird nickname.
Scott: As you.
Rym: it's de Blasio, yeah, but his be.
Scott: he did a reddit AMA.
Rym: Yeah, I like him a lot wasn't too bad?
Rym: I'm gonna vote for him.
Scott: Yeah, I get what choice.
Rym: I just go for the Republican creepy guy.
Scott: No I just don't.
Scott: the only thing is de Blasio is gonna do the thing that I really care about which is Fuck the cable companies so they can stop rubbing their nipples.
Rym: Yeah guys South Park started again.
Rym: watch it.
Rym: watch South Park, yeah, we don't talk about it much anymore.
Rym: on the show We watch every South Park immediately.
Rym: It's one of our favorite shows right up there with Adventure Time.
Scott: Oh today is Wednesday.
Scott: You know what there is today South Park.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: Yeah, you know what happened two days ago.
Rym: We didn't watch yet new Adventure Time - okay.
Rym: You're a little more behind than me.
Scott: I don't watch you adventure times as soon as they come out.
Scott: I do let him pile up a tiny bit.
Rym: Yeah, but that that infinity train.
Scott: Well, that was a good one on Monday.
Scott: This whole place is butter.
Rym: It is a Lot of you need to watch that up later.
Scott: The thing is the people it needs to help won't understand.
Rym: so speaking of fear city This is a really well done prank.
Rym: This guy rigged up a car to where he's hiding in the seat the driver's seat.
Scott: I've seen ones like that where the car drives up and there's no one there because he's disguised as a seat.
Rym: But but instead of having no one in the car.
Rym: He put a pretty realistic skeleton in the car.
Scott: Okay with his arms like set up the same guy who did the one where he.
Scott: yes same guy.
Rym: Yeah, go to this guy's channel.
Rym: It is nothing but pranks.
Scott: How does he run?
Scott: doesn't he run out of fast-food places to prank?
Rym: Look at this.
Rym: Look at this channel.
Rym: drive through rocky raccoon drive through floating money drive through.
Rym: my wallet catches on fire when I try to pay.
Rym: Drive through I get a shock and faint and then the car drives away on its own.
Rym: This guy is the master of the.
Rym: pull up to it through a drive-through window and scare the people there.
Rym: He's got one thing going for it's definitely somewhere in the south because he keeps going to chick-fil-a's and people keep saying y'all Oh, I randomly paused it.
Rym: I'm like.
Rym: the subtitle says y'all nice.
Rym: So the reason this prank works is that one.
Rym: it's dark.
Rym: So the skeleton looks kind of real good - even though a human who is rational will once their brain catches up Think to themselves.
Rym: There's no way that is a skeleton.
Scott: It is a skeleton.
Scott: Well any time you are a human course it is.
Scott: what else would it be?
Rym: and a skeleton is?
Rym: In a place that you did not expect a skeleton to be there is at least a moment of oh fuck There's one in my body.
Rym: Oh fuck Yeah, but if you see it and you don't expect to see it like if I look at an x-ray machine.
Rym: I love skeletons like the skeleton to be there, but like if I wake up in the morning I played magic back in the day.
Scott: I like to use drudge scale Stematically, I like skeletons.
Rym: if you're home right and you wake up in the morning and you go to the bathroom staff Oh, it's my favorite zone.
Rym: There's just a skeleton like laying in your tub.
Rym: I Predict there'd be at least a moment where you go.
Rym: Oh, whoa.
Scott: I'd be like yes free skeleton Sweet those are expensive.
Scott: So the real wonder if it's real.
Rym: the third reason this Frank's what prank works is that the skeleton drives up and doesn't do anything.
Rym: It just sits there.
Scott: Oh, it was so much better if the skeleton was like putting its hand out as you know There right.
Rym: if the people like lean in it leans forward like it's gonna ask him a question.
Rym: Usually they lose it then and it can also.
Rym: this is the final important piece.
Rym: It can drive the car away on its own.
Rym: so there's this moment where it pulls up and these people are kind of like a the fuck and then the woman's like Gonna just throw the food in the car and then it starts to drive away and she just loses it.
Rym: But then this guy in the background is like oh shit.
Rym: He leaving That.
Scott: that's the line right there.
Rym: Now if I were gonna do this prank one step better, I would buy a car from a junk lot with trash.
Rym: Acquire a real human skeleton.
Rym: rig it up like this.
Rym: So the car just drives up and that's it.
Rym: It just stays there with the real human skeleton.
Rym: Wait for that shit to go down.
Rym: wait for that to at least to show up.
Rym: Yeah, it's a real human skeleton.
Rym: Where'd it come from?
Scott: Oh my god the car sets on fire.
Rym: Yes Mm-hmm.
Rym: No, just the skeleton sets on fire.
Rym: That would ruin a few people's days and probably require some counseling.
Rym: but it's a little.
Scott: you wouldn't want the Fast-food restaurant to set on fire in there.
Rym: No, you gotta make sure just the skeleton, right?
Scott: Okay, so in meta moment book club book is Stasi land.
Rym: You should read it.
Rym: We got a bunch of video on the internet.
Rym: We did resume production of.
Rym: GeekNights presents utenna.
Rym: There is an episode I'm currently editing.
Rym: going to try to finish it before the weekend.
Scott: I'm uploading more netrunner videos.
Scott: for anyone who cares about that anymore.
Rym: We are going to accelerate the production of lively streamed GeekNights video in the near future Shaker classic salty vet tomorrow Thursdays at 9.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Cinemassacre.
Scott: It is October.
Scott: I keep forgetting to mention this cuz I'm watching it.
Scott: Monster madness monster madness at cinemassacre.com.
Scott: if you care anything about horror movies You should be watching that every day of every October for as long as you live.
Rym: Anything else not really follow us on Twitter share our videos.
Scott: the more people want to join the forum But joining is sort of broken ish right now.
Rym: I lost just so we can.
Scott: We've got like two people on the list, but I don't know what to do about it, right?
Rym: No, we interviewed the vanilla guy a long time ago.
Rym: We should call him up again and be like, yeah He's not gonna help us.
Rym: No, we should be like, you know, you guys just given up on the open-source side of vanilla.
Scott: They sort of haven't but it's just taking them a long time Basically given up on it, but not they actually un gave up a little partially recently.
Rym: Yeah, just give us access to updated repos.
Scott: They are that we can just get it on github, but it's not solid and I don't have time to make it solid.
Rym: Yeah, just throw it up.
Scott: Anyway, it's not gonna work too.
Scott: Well, yeah, it's kind of buggy.
Rym: We'll see what happens?
Scott: Yeah, I submitted a patch to it actually.
Rym: Ah anyway anyway Yeah, magfest is coming up.
Rym: We'll be there.
Rym: New York Comic Con is this weekend.
Rym: We will not be there because New York Comic Con kind of sucks.
Scott: Next the weekend after that is burning con and also a bunch of netrunner tournaments.
Rym: We will be there.
Rym: I'm running the the Very cleverly named scenario.
Scott: I haven't finished my scenario.
Rym: Let sleeping dogs die.
Scott: Monday is Columbus Day, which is a bullshit holiday, but I don't have to go to work.
Rym: I don't know if I have work or not.
Scott: I definitely do not.
Rym: I gotta figure that out.
Rym: I don't think I have work but nicey is not closed this year on Columbus Day.
Rym: good for them.
Rym: But I think my holiday schedule is just nicey's holiday.
Rym: I don't actually know.
Rym: Mmm.
Rym: I gotta figure that shit out.
Rym: Maybe I just not show up to work and act like?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: There's a holiday.
Rym: Yeah, exactly Except I know some people listen to the show.
Rym: So I'd have to edit that out if I was gonna do that.
Scott: just do it.
Scott: Anyway, you know what?
Rym: I think it is a holiday whatever.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I don't make it a holiday boss, man.
Rym: So, uh, yeah attack on Titan ended Season one.
Rym: there might not be more in a while years.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, maybe not years years.
Rym: Maybe not years.
Rym: There's a way they could do it in a shorter time Island episodes now They don't have to know they wouldn't do.
Rym: Island episodes.
Rym: that would kill that momentum.
Rym: but If you care about spoilers stop listening right now, and why would you even be attack on Titan?
Scott: Seriously, if you're an animal people have been talking about this show so the fuck much.
Scott: How can you just continue to ignore it?
Scott: Even we're talking about it.
Scott: That's yeah, we couldn't even ignore it.
Rym: Yeah We started.
Rym: why we went from.
Scott: I'll wait till that show to what we went from but then again I ignore all those shows that everyone else talks about like the Breaking Beds and whatever.
Rym: I watched a good chunk of Breaking Beds All right.
Rym: It's all right.
Rym: It's so uh, it's no house of cards.
Scott: I didn't?
Scott: I watched one episode of that man.
Rym: I really house of cards is my favorite Three-dimensional show in recent memory.
Rym: Yeah Whatever right up there with Archer South Park.
Rym: Yeah up Simpsons has actually been pretty good lately.
Scott: Well, someone's gonna hit you on that.
Rym: Yes, Simpsons has been Consistently as funny as like season 10 and 11.
Scott: I haven't seen a Simpsons a long-ass time.
Scott: Yeah, it's it's kind of back but I still remember it so much.
Scott: a guy at work was all like Is that some guy had a mug with two hammers on it and you're like, oh, yeah No, the other co-worker was like, is that a stonecutter's mug?
Scott: and I'm like.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: we know it's take off the stone of James.
Scott: Oh, yeah the stone of triumph.
Rym: Well the other day we were looking at Fark and there was that article about Reagan's arm being cut off and I was like there's Gonna be a picture of Jeb and I was Springfield's head being cut off in the first few comments on Fark.
Rym: sure enough Yep, and it was someone who's been reading Fark as long as I have so there's probably seen.
Scott: maybe I should just watch rewatch every Simpsons ever in order, you know Every.
Rym: I watched every episode of the Simpsons including the specials on the Tracy Allman show as They came out with my family up until the year 2000 hmm.
Rym: and then at RIT that year when we were freshmen We continued that and watched every episode as it came out on that 1974 color.
Rym: I didn't watch all of them almost all of them watched a few of them Most of them because we watch them while we're hanging out in the lounge before we play D&D.
Rym: Anyway, I digress fucking spoilers, uh Yeah, there's Titans in the walls.
Scott: I guess I don't know.
Scott: see now.
Scott: Here's the thing I'm based on.
Scott: there's people who've read the manga which is way ahead of the anime.
Rym: Oh, I got shit to say about the manga.
Rym: right and those people but we'll get to.
Scott: basically it's like, okay.
Scott: So when I see if I I didn't see the sting over the fry in that last episode I turned it off and people were like, oh you gotta go back and watch it.
Scott: So I go back and I see it and it's like, okay they show you they zoom into the hole in the wall and you see a Titan face and it's like You can interpret that as they're being literal Titans in the walls.
Scott: And apparently that's what it is.
Rym: Oh, I see you're coming from especially because the way it's drawn.
Scott: Yeah, and it's so quick.
Scott: It's like that could just be like the stinger of the last episode being like hey, you know Not literally being Titans in the walls.
Scott: It could also be interpreted as like a Titan looking through the hole in the wall Or who knows why you don't know what the hell.
Rym: it could just be interpreted as stay tuned or now.
Rym: all is not as it seems exactly, but the problem with attack on Titan now is Similar to what happened with full metal alchemist but to the extreme because of internet and progress of society.
Rym: The manga is coming out and there are now three classes of people with in regards to attack on Titan people who are reading the updated Scanslations of the manga.
Scott: well in English-speaking world.
Rym: Yes Well by four classes people in Japan sure people are reading the scans lated manga as it's coming out the way we used to do with death note.
Rym: People who are reading the legit Translations of the manga as it's coming out.
Rym: People who are only watching the anime and what I.
Scott: so the legit translations are Almost caught up with the anime base like one more volume and that'll be.
Scott: they'll be matching in English and they're coming out once a month.
Scott: So it's like there's probably a volume already out or coming out this month that will basically match the anime in terms of English Legitimately published English manga yep.
Scott: And then like next month or the month after you'll be ahead of the TV show in the legit English Mangas, but here's the problem.
Scott: scans are way ahead.
Rym: There's the problem.
Rym: I'm seeing commentary about the show both on the internet and in meatspace Seems to be driven by the false insight provided by those who have read ahead in the manga.
Rym: So it's not the problem of just oh someone spoiled something.
Rym: It's the problem of someone watching the anime sees a Titan in the wall at the end and goes And then the friend who is reading the manga way ahead says something like oh now You know about the wall Titans, and it's like.
Rym: I'm merely saying it with the definite article one You're spoiling, but that's that's one problem.
Scott: I don't care about that.
Rym: That is a problem though.
Rym: this separate problem Is the discussions that follow?
Rym: Trade Spoilers?
Scott: right if the anime was all that existed We would simply be saying are there literal Titans in the walls, or what's the deal with that?
Scott: yeah?
Scott: What happens is what are they trying to say there, but is it getting out?
Scott: What's going on instead?
Scott: We're saying oh?
Scott: I guess there's actual literal Titans in the walls and your friends who are reading the manga Will.
Rym: you'll see this watching the show and it's subtly different from the separate situation of someone who has seen a show.
Rym: is Guiding your commentary in a show like someone watching GeekNights presents, Utena We know what happens.
Rym: no, but we're instead of.
Rym: there's a subtle difference between Using what you know to provide subtle insight versus versus using what you know to pretend toward insight and people will say things like ah But how do you know instead of this meta talk?
Scott: Why do not we actually talk about attack on Titan all right?
Rym: I really like the show and actually I was really satisfied with where season one ended.
Rym: it didn't end on a cliffhanger in my opinion.
Scott: I was satisfied, but I would have liked a little bit more right.
Scott: It's like yeah, that was a good kind of place to stop.
Rym: You know what I wanted to see.
Rym: if there was a denim on at the end of season one That wasn't the Titan face out of like to have seen a shadowy noble figure like a king or someone.
Rym: Yeah, walking to a shadowy military person where you don't see who they are But they have one conversation.
Rym: like it was revealed it was it.
Rym: Oh Well, I guess you have to do the thing now.
Rym: very good, sir like one of those kinds of moments.
Scott: Oh, yeah, that could work.
Rym: That is what I want.
Scott: I definitely just want to know something about the goddamn king queen whatever the royal is.
Rym: well the question is is it a king bradley?
Scott: How could it not be?
Rym: or is it an?
Rym: Actually good king like the second in command?
Scott: unlikely because that guy the guy who control his name all right guy who runs the military He's all.
Scott: he's the guy who was the judge of the court-martial of Aaron.
Scott: that guy is the head of all three military parts the military police and The Garrison and the Survey Corps.
Scott: he's in charge of all trees the number one military guy.
Scott: only.
Scott: the king is above him now in Any other show.
Rym: and what I would have expected and what I did expect from attack on Titan?
Rym: That guy would have been dumb or bad in some obvious way.
Rym: But the fact that for all appearances in the anime he was fair intelligent and competent was amazing.
Scott: so one step away from the king is a guy who's Apparently good, so is the king really bad?
Rym: or at least not capricious and arbitrary, but fair and competent?
Rym: He reminds me of what a character like Hughes from Fullmetal Alchemist would be if they made it to middle age And were put in a position of power.
Scott: Yeah, so like immediately under him are you know Erwin the bald guy with the mustache Pixis?
Scott: Pixis I love Pixis, and I don't know who's in charge of the military police.
Rym: I don't know who's the head of the MPs.
Scott: I'm that's probably gonna be a bad person.
Scott: I don't.
Rym: I think it'll be an incompetent person and not a bad person.
Rym: I think it'll be a person that's not the greatest because it was obvious from toward the end that the military police are not themselves Individually evil except Annie.
Rym: They're just Is she that are selfish and mildly incompetent, right?
Scott: I mean look we know there is some badness to the nobility because Pixis is playing chess with that noble person.
Rym: But they might just be corrupt shitheads.
Scott: Yeah, he wasn't horribly evil like Hitler But he was obviously corrupt.
Scott: not a good bird not not on the side of goodness.
Scott: He was like I'll save my skin and be rich and live lavishly fucked if the Titans eat all the poor people.
Rym: his neutral evil Yeah, oh But The noble.
Rym: I don't think the nobles themselves are evil, I think they're just dumb, but there's definitely something up there, right?
Scott: This is the thing is that you know Annie was.
Scott: you know it's like yeah?
Scott: She was killing all these people and whatnot and she turns into a Titan and they smashed the walls and they liked it.
Scott: She was happy when Titans were in the city and everybody, but why?
Scott: why would they write?
Scott: It's clearly there is some battle between the people who can turn into the skinless Titans.
Scott: the colossal time I think is everyone maybe but the skinless Titans are you know that group the people who came from that town which is?
Scott: Obviously Rainer is the is the armored Titan there, and you have to be dumb not to figure that out.
Scott: I mean I haven't read any manga that says that or anything.
Scott: I Will bet a hundred thousand dollars that that is what he looks.
Scott: the same the same, right?
Scott: It's you to be dumb not to realize that?
Scott: yep It comes in the same town right.
Scott: then you got Annie.
Scott: Clearly.
Scott: obviously as soon as you saw that female Titan you knew it was her just as obvious Colossal Titan.
Scott: who knows who the fuck that is?
Rym: I do because someone spoiled it.
Rym: for me, okay?
Scott: But anyway, but they're all on the same team right and they're clearly I think that they are fighting against not the even though they killed the people in the towns than the civilians.
Scott: I think their actual fight that group is against the royalty right and they're that's what the fight is and Basically all of the civilians that they're killing all the Survey Corps people and whatever.
Scott: it's pretty much Just like you know.
Scott: those are.
Scott: they're working for my enemy, so the matrix exactly It's like.
Scott: well.
Scott: Yeah agent Smith.
Scott: Just took over that human who's not a bad person, but they're in the matrix They're part of the system.
Scott: you're fighting on behalf of the military Survey Corps person So you're my enemy right now even if I like you You know it's
Rym: possible and
Scott: they were they were trying to capture Aaron probably to bring him to their side and tell him what was up because he you Titan power on their side and having him be on the other side not so good.
Rym: This is.
Rym: what's interesting is if their goal was to actually fight against humanity and cause all this damage They could have succeeded along.
Rym: there was no reason for them to stop as far as we saw in the anime in that first attack.
Scott: Exactly because well they stopped in the second.
Scott: Oh the first attack.
Rym: Yeah first big attack where they took down the Titan took off all the guns on the top and kicked a hole in and then the armored Titan Trivially broke down the gate into the inner side.
Scott: yeah They could have just gotten well It's a long way from there to the doesn't matter wall that Titan.
Rym: He could just go poof be a Titan and break through the wall without anyone yeah helping him.
Rym: Hmm it is obvious that they could have just done it.
Rym: so either They didn't do it because that's not their goal, or they didn't do it because something happened that prevented them from doing it.
Rym: Was it Aaron?
Rym: was it?
Rym: we don't know.
Scott: well the first time right?
Scott: is they?
Scott: just they just busted through that town right whenever?
Scott: Aaron was small the second time.
Scott: Aaron's appearance basically Was what prevented them from breaking the second wall the inner wall of that city.
Scott: because remember they're breaking through like these cities that are Like little nipples on the edge, so they had to break two walls, which is why it's a little confusing.
Scott: It's like you know why was there the colossal Titan and then the shield Titan?
Scott: well there were two walls to break to get through Right the one in the outside of the city and then the one on the inside.
Rym: But if the colossal Titan can get in like perhaps Annie and Rainer Then why does he just go?
Rym: well you know when is?
Rym: if he's in the military police for example like Annie She could just gone poof and probably taken out Everybody on her own because look no one can stop her.
Rym: yeah No one can with.
Rym: the show is showing us the survey car can.
Rym: kind of yeah Every time they stopped her she trivially escaped and was immediately kicking ass again.
Scott: Maybe right well remember first of all right the strongest people are always joined the military police But they also are all lazy and haven't practiced in a while, but maybe right the king will just turn into a Titan and then what?
Rym: Yeah, I don't think that would happen though.
Scott: You know there could be people on the king's side who could turn into titans.
Rym: Situation there is a different as far as everything we've seen.
Rym: there is a huge differential in power and Yet the people who are have the advantage are not pressing that advantage, and we don't know why.
Rym: yep Originally early in the show I had suspected that maybe Those Titans that did that first attack were trying to cause enough damage.
Scott: or remember humanity.
Rym: It was a false.
Rym: that's.
Scott: that's my other Theory.
Scott: right is that they are actually on the side of the king.
Scott: remember after that there was that thing where they had to send.
Scott: there Was you know too many people.
Scott: they had to send them all out?
Scott: To go get killed.
Scott: and that killed of a whole bunch of the populations that the food needs were getting went down.
Scott: Maybe the royal people wanted that right to serve their own purpose.
Rym: I thought it was more subtle.
Rym: I thought that maybe the royalty wanted the status quo and that these people who can turn into Titans did what they did Despite all the casualties to force humanity to confront their problems and fight back against the regular Titans.
Scott: but a false flag.
Scott: but if the Those big Titans could have just gone on behalf of humanity and gone out and killed all the Titans because they're so powerful Maybe not that colossal Titan could just go around killing all the Titans.
Rym: ah but the sheer number of Titans.
Rym: And there's obviously a Titan spawner somewhere gauntlet style.
Scott: It's got to be something like that.
Rym: so many Titans.
Scott: Yeah, who knows what the deal is?
Scott: it's the basement will tell us yeah at least at least you know.
Scott: They didn't show us the basement, which is like okay?
Scott: You gotta hold it off for some amount of time otherwise the characters are trying to get.
Scott: at least they were like Let's get to that fucking basement.
Scott: It's like okay.
Scott: At least they recognize it, and they just want to fucking go.
Scott: They just can't legitimately Okay with that.
Rym: how many times in a full metal alchemist was like go right there That's the mystery will wait blah blah blah blah blah blah plod plod plod right at least here, right?
Scott: It's like yeah, and he's the fucking site.
Scott: They knew it wasn't some bullshit like.
Scott: I wonder who it is.
Scott: It's like we know who it is that scene.
Rym: I didn't realize what they were up to until they went down.
Scott: I didn't either.
Rym: and then I was like oh They know yeah when they went down and Annie was like I'm not going down there, and then it cut to Aaron's face, and suddenly you see like his fist is clenched He's trembling and he turns around that moment.
Rym: I was like oh shit, son.
Rym: Oh shit, son That was one of my favorite scenes in the show.
Rym: is that confrontation not the fight afterward just that confrontation?
Rym: I also like how the survey cars plan there was Actually really good, and they just got fucked by the fact that she had an extra that she had that ring like.
Rym: she had also Had a really good plan.
Scott: Yeah, I mean really the only thing that The only thing that makes Annie so invincible is that her power of creating the armored spot on her body right.
Rym: without that power She would have been fucked so hard so many times and she can just tighten and then when she gets untightened She gets tighten again immediately.
Rym: She's never tired.
Scott: Yeah, well suppose.
Scott: Maybe it's cuz she's you know keeps the skin off Tightened again.
Scott: Immediately after killing she got tired a little bit from running a lot.
Scott: She's super powered and super good.
Rym: despite all that she just trivially kicked Aaron's ass twice.
Scott: Yeah, Aaron had to go all super angry mode Style.
Scott: yeah, it's a mecha show by the way.
Scott: I mean people have said this it's obvious, but yeah, it's a mega show.
Rym: I think all people can turn into Titans.
Scott: obviously That either, but then why did Aaron need to have an injection to make it happen?
Rym: I don't think he did.
Rym: I think there's something else going on there.
Rym: But the other thing could be going on.
Rym: is the Titans?
Rym: either the mindless Titans are driverless or the person in them is Passive like they're subsumed in like when Aaron was in that one time and his Titan just going apeshit doing Titan shit.
Rym: And yet he inside of the Titan is having this paradise dream.
Rym: Maybe maybe they all just have people having those paradise dreams.
Rym: I'm also kind of worried that in the very beginning of the show the first episode right away Aaron has a dream slash flashback to things that happen later in the show Mmm.
Rym: What the fuck?
Rym: Is the show?
Rym: is he in a Titan the whole time?
Scott: Don't give me that shit.
Rym: They're an outside world.
Scott: beyond all this the walls of actually the walls of his mind.
Rym: is it matrix?
Rym: How come?
Rym: is it a time loop Final Fantasy 1 style?
Rym: Yeah?
Rym: Why does he have flashbacks to the future from the Anyway future from the past.
Scott: I don't know He's.
Scott: he died in that first time.
Scott: he died is still in the Titans belly.
Rym: Oh, that was so great when that happened because I didn't know I was watching the show.
Rym: and You know shows like this will have an opener with characters.
Rym: most of those characters die.
Scott: Then there's a new opener later with different characters right and it's like they were killing off characters left and right.
Scott: and even though Aaron Was the main it's like at that point in the show Mikasa could have been the main as well Yeah, and it could have easily been like best friend dead early in the show.
Scott: and now Mikasa is the main.
Rym: when he died I was like oh Yeah, this is awesome, and then with that Titan that kind of looked like him appeared.
Rym: I didn't think it was him coming back.
Rym: I thought maybe it was something like oh Titan ate him and took on some of his aspects huh, maybe and then later is like oh, it's literally him.
Scott: yeah I figured when I saw that I knew it was him when they cut him out of the Titan.
Rym: I didn't expect that.
Rym: and then when he wasn't wounded and was wearing different clothes That is when I started thinking back to the flash forward to the flashback, and I started worrying about time loops.
Rym: It's just a dream.
Scott: Yeah, who knows who knows?
Rym: Knows and some of the people who read the manga ahead I'm gonna.
Scott: I'm gonna read it when you know the next volume comes out.
Rym: There is a way They could Darryl Surratt calculated this based on the manga production rate and the rate at which the show covered the manga.
Rym: they could do a 13 episode show next year like in the summer at the same pace of the current show and Then it's possible by 2015.
Rym: They'd be able to do another 13 episode show.
Rym: They couldn't maybe do a 13 episode show and then do some OAVs of side material.
Scott: There was a material that was in the manga Which is you know in the part of the manga to the TV show covered?
Scott: It's not in the future, right?
Scott: So it's something you should know at this point, but you didn't.
Scott: because you watch a TV show There's a scene where they show in the past.
Scott: basically some soldier of the Survey Corps out in the wilderness is basically all alone and out of fuel and whatever and just walking and is writing in a journal and like a Titan approaches right.
Scott: and the Titan comes and talks to this and is you know comes near this person.
Scott: it's one of the mindless ones and The Titan like bows before this person and talks about like Lady Wymer Which is we all know the giant slain by Odin.
Scott: and is you know that they made the earth out of?
Rym: Well, you should know.
Scott: right if you don't know what Wymer is what the mythology come on.
Scott: This is like mythology one Not even 101 just one you know anyway.
Scott: So and then the Titan eats the person but the journal is left there And then it shows you Levi and friends picking up the journal and it's like oh who is so-and-so?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: you know they're like.
Scott: oh so-and-so is dead.
Scott: This is what so-and-so died for and he's got the journal.
Scott: so you know Levi and the science lady and Erwin.
Scott: they know About that and I think there was like an OAV or direct to DVD.
Scott: I think that was already made actually or something like.
Scott: that material was covered in animation somewhere.
Rym: I really like science lady.
Rym: I think she is my favorite actual character because she is so crazy.
Scott: favorite actual character.
Rym: It's be I like Erwin Levi and her the most.
Rym: I like Mikasa a lot But Levi is sort of the king Cosmo.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: Well, I like you know people Levi is he breaks the mold.
Rym: he's a mold breaker of that stone-cold consummate badass Because he's actually really emotional and sensitive and earnest and good And he's a great like.
Rym: the character is not as straightforward as it would appear Mm-hmm, and it's obvious that he's not as straightforward as it appears And it's obvious that he struggles with things and he's sad about things and that he has a really complex and deep personality.
Rym: I like that about a stone-cold badass.
Rym: Erwin is just the tactical badass.
Scott: The show seems to really be pushing.
Scott: you know its literal message that it Says to you like 20 times which is yeah if you want to be able to change the world You just got to become an evil fucker.
Rym: or maybe give up your humanity to you know Rock the boat not necessarily become evil, but become not necessarily But be willing to sacrifice great things and force other people against their will to make similar sacrifices.
Rym: Yep Yeah, yeah, I think everyone's a Titan number pretty I'm kind of obvious.
Rym: or maybe certain people are Titans Maybe the people in the walls, so there's this old SG 1 episode Stargate the TV show Which I like even though it's dumb and the.
Rym: to summarize the episode the SG 1 team opens a Stargate.
Rym: You know what the deal is that's g1 at all.
Scott: It's.
Scott: they have a Stargate and they go to places.
Scott: It's sort of like sliders only in the Stargate.
Rym: universe takes place after the Stargate movie and basically it's the researchers Messing around with the Stargate and they start plugging in other coordinates, and they start finding these gates everywhere.
Rym: So they open a gate to one place and it's this besieged Citadel deep underground in a planet like Earth.
Rym: and these people The outside world is waging a genocidal war against them and they're the last holdouts.
Rym: So the Stargate people agree to help them.
Rym: So they start piloting these remote robot drones helping them fight against this outside enemy That is clearly waging a war of genocide against them.
Rym: Yada yada yada, it turns out they were the Nazis.
Rym: It's the Nazis last Citadel.
Rym: Yeah, the Nazis the people in this fortress are horrible people.
Rym: They all deserve to die.
Rym: They are from within the Citadel trying to poison the atmosphere and kill everyone on the outside.
Rym: And then the Stargate people like yeah, fuck you guys and they just leave.
Rym: Leave them to die, right?
Scott: And I feel like the royalty is the same thing.
Rym: Maybe possibly or maybe the whole city is just.
Rym: they've said the Titans are out there to kill everyone else in the world and They're supposed to hold out inside till everyone's gone, right?
Scott: And it's also the sort of obviousness of that.
Scott: Titans are some sort of tool some sort of lost tool technology Like we lost our mecha technology the openers and closers all that.
Rym: now Shaka look in imagery exactly, right?
Scott: That's clearly the God Warriors.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, it's like but how?
Scott: the real question is not necessarily how do the Titans work or what their deal is.
Rym: Yeah, lightning bolt from the sky really what right.
Scott: mom more curious about how?
Scott: what happened that made the technology lost?
Scott: That's the event not the event.
Scott: We're like, oh we invented Titan technology or we invented human technology.
Scott: Yeah, we were right.
Scott: but Well, how did you go from the world in which Titans were a tool that people could use for things to the world in which?
Scott: people didn't even fucking know what the deal with Titans are except for maybe the king and other people we don't even know about.
Scott: and These walls were built and there was suddenly an inside and outside and no one remembers what happened.
Scott: Big O style.
Rym: No It seems like the the elites and the leaders know way more than we do and way more than the other characters do.
Rym: But for whatever reason they don't say things.
Scott: because how did that?
Scott: how did they know it?
Scott: And how did everyone else forget it?
Rym: because notice how in certain crazy and how come his dad and Aaron's dad knows some normal characters Flip out about things that happen.
Rym: but people in leadership positions kind of don't.
Rym: They're like, it's a Titan.
Rym: It's this kind of Titan this kind of thing.
Rym: Like they're more.
Rym: they're surprisingly calm about things that Me watching the show would I would consider a major revelation about.
Scott: yeah, it's like we consider it's like it's.
Scott: on the one hand We think it's cool that they're smart and that they just you know They're not doing dumb things like everyone knew.
Scott: there could be you know an evil Titan among the ranks.
Rym: Well, wait, how the fuck did he know the idea that a human can turn into a Titan alone?
Rym: Should have been crazy except a lot of people didn't seem particularly surprised by that.
Rym: Yep, that is the one of the biggest triggers.
Rym: that thing right there.
Rym: when it turned out Aaron get her to a tight I was like, oh fuck.
Rym: How are people gonna react to this and notice how the normal soldiers flip the fuck out?
Rym: Everybody else was like well he can turn into a Titan so we have to manage this As though Perhaps they have knowledge of people who can turn into Titans already or in right away is like there might be traders in the ranks.
Rym: He'd been planning to catch the traders who would be a traitor for the Titans, but a Titan.
Rym: How do they know all this stuff?
Rym: Manga cow won't tell me in the mind the anime yet.
Rym: I gotta wait.
Rym: I'm not gonna read the manga.
Scott: I'm reading the officially published ones.
Rym: I'm going to wait for Whatever happens with the anime.
Rym: It's popular enough.
Rym: I think there will be more.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.