Rym: It's Tuesday June 24th 2014.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: sportsmanship games.
Rym: woman in the ship Gender neutral men ship.
Rym: let's do this.
Rym: So there's been a problem between me and Scott for a number of years.
Rym: what problem?
Scott: So you make annoying noises.
Rym: when we got here when we got home to do the show Scott was watching the biking anime.
Rym: We're hanging out doing our thing.
Rym: Scott's really wondering what I'm about to bring up.
Rym: and then what this conversation?
Rym: And then I had a snack before the show as I want to know.
Scott: I know you're talking about now.
Rym: so Scott what is wrong with eating croutons or as I like to call them advanced crackers, would you?
Scott: Take ketchup and just like fucking drink it.
Rym: Well, that's a condiment and A crouton is a condiment.
Rym: You do not shake croutons out of a dispenser on your table.
Scott: Yeah, come in a bag or a container and you shake them onto salads.
Scott: You do not have you ever seen any restaurant in the world.
Scott: just serve croutons to eat straight up.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: They're in the Buffet all the time the salad bar.
Scott: They're meant to put on the south.
Rym: Who are you to say what they're meant to be done?
Rym: They're there?
Rym: no next to other things.
Scott: I'm just glad I don't have to come up with any more reasons not to do this because everyone listening already is on my side.
Scott: So
Rym: I ask all of you out there if you believe in anything that is good or holy and you enjoy actual food something to go go to your kitchen go find your finger croutons
Scott: and just
Rym: eat one like it's a cracker and Realize that there is nothing stopping you from doing that anytime you want.
Scott: Yeah your sense of self-worth Your Pride as a human being.
Rym: so speaking of same pride that you would lose if you drank ketchup is the same pride you lose When you eat a crouton, so speaking of pride in being a human being it is the steam summer sale and something Something amazing happened.
Rym: I no longer care about steam sales.
Scott: Yeah, I have all these games.
Scott: It's not video game season right now.
Scott: There's no game.
Rym: I'm playing a lot of video games.
Scott: My problem is I'm playing basically no video games.
Rym: Yeah, you're not playing any board games either.
Scott: There's nothing on the steam sale that I really want or urgently need to play right now, I mean that brothers game.
Scott: Okay, it's some artsy thing.
Rym: It's probably is a good interactive amusement and experience.
Scott: It looks like it looks like an entertaining software for three dollars doesn't look like a game, but that doesn't bother me I'll.
Rym: so my trouble is not that I don't be on sale again.
Scott: It's not going anywhere.
Rym: My problem is again right now in any fashion that I do not want to buy these games.
Rym: My problem is that four times so far this team's summer sale four.
Rym: I saw a game and thought wow, I would definitely play that game for that price.
Rym: I clicked on it with the intention of purchasing is purchasing it and Instead of taking me to the shopping cart It took me to a screen that said in green you already own name of game that you just clicked on play now And I in every case I would go what really?
Rym: and I go to my library and sure enough there it is.
Rym: It's even installed.
Scott: I thought FTL the expansion you had to buy.
Scott: Nope, because I bought regular actually kick-started FTL zillion years ago.
Scott: I have all the FTL.
Scott: I didn't have to buy anything.
Scott: I went to click on the FTL expansion thing.
Scott: It's like you already have FTL.
Scott: I'm like, oh, alrighty then.
Rym: Yeah, so I've been playing a lot of FTL lately.
Scott: I played zero FTL lately.
Rym: I've had a lot of flying to do lately.
Rym: Advanced mode makes that game.
Rym: you could play that game for the next ten years and never get tired of it.
Scott: But I didn't even play more than I.
Rym: you suck at FTL Not that I suck.
Scott: I just have no interest in it's like I'm done.
Rym: you beat it on like beginner mode.
Scott: Yeah, what interest do I have in playing it with a different ship or on a harder mode?
Rym: None, the game is completely different in those modes.
Scott: I have no interest in that.
Rym: I don't understand why the game is engaging.
Scott: I've already beaten it and seen the end.
Scott: What more is there?
Rym: Yeah, so you.
Rym: so if you beat Mega Man 2 on baby mode, then you've beaten it a hundred percent.
Scott: Mega Man 2 doesn't have baby mode.
Rym: Yeah, it does.
Rym: You're Japanese only?
Scott: Of course.
Rym: So if someone played Mega Man 2 on easy mode Then they're not in person.
Scott: They say they've lost the same pride that they would lose if they ate a crouton or drank ketchup.
Rym: Oh, I see how it is Exactly.
Rym: Seriously, Scott's really bad at FTL.
Rym: I've watched him play.
Rym: It's not pretty to watch.
Rym: What do you mean?
Scott: you click you wait for your shit to recharge?
Rym: Yeah, so how come you can't beat it on normal?
Rym: I can beat it on normal almost every time I play Because I don't give a shit.
Rym: Yeah, sure.
Scott: Let's play some netrunner.
Rym: So actually I should be playing some netrunners soon because I saw that some other friends of ours Conrad was playing some netrunner recently.
Scott: Why is he not coming to play netrunner with us or at least at the NYU Game Center near him?
Rym: I think he just learned how to play and seemed to really like it But why wasn't he listening to me telling to play like?
Rym: it's something that appeared on the steam summer sale just now?
Rym: that I think is interesting is Murdered soul suspect which is one of.
Scott: I've never heard of this ever really.
Scott: what is?
Rym: it is one of two.
Rym: You're a ghost detective games.
Scott: What's the other ghost detective game?
Rym: I don't remember but I kept confusing them.
Scott: ghost trick, which is really good and is like DS game.
Rym: No, these are both PC games.
Rym: Okay, but this game uh.
Rym: So the tagline on the game in all caps is the hardest murder to solve is your own Dun dun.
Rym: dun which I think is objectively true.
Scott: Do you know you're a ghost?
Rym: You basically are surprised that there is an afterlife after you were murdered and you try to solve your murder But you're a ghost who walks around the real world.
Rym: Yes, you walk around but time is still flowing.
Scott: So you're not.
Scott: you're still at you.
Scott: basically you're dead and then up there you are looking at your corpse.
Scott: Yep, and time keeps moving on.
Rym: You basically go around like trying to figure out what happened figure out who murdered you and why.
Rym: and there's this plot.
Rym: It has the popular user-defined tags of spooky detective supernatural mystery.
Rym: I was doing those, you know I saw the Square Enix panel about this at PAX because I was running that room at the time and I Might have related this anecdote to you earlier.
Rym: But just to reiterate the first or second question that came out of the audience was oh, that's why you know about this.
Rym: Yes One of the greatest questions anyone has ever asked at a panel at a game convention ever and the question was So is this a game?
Rym: Could I like not solve my own murder?
Rym: Could I fail to figure out who murdered me?
Rym: and the people on the panel didn't answer for a little while and then they're slow Halting answer basically was summarized - no you cannot fail to solve your murder.
Rym: This is not a game.
Scott: It's an entertainment software.
Rym: Yes, or at best.
Rym: It might be an ideal game.
Rym: It might be a series of interesting decisions.
Rym: Anyway that all lead to the same Game, it's basically monkey island.
Rym: So it's interesting that this game already release date June 3rd 2014 so less than a month ago is 33% off.
Scott: That's you know, I mean, that's not a big sale.
Scott: It's still what 33 bucks.
Scott: Yeah But this is one of those triple-a square Enix games the South Park game which I actually kind of want to play.
Scott: I really want to play that discounted but it's still 40 bucks.
Rym: So yeah, the thing is the reason I want to play the and it's also Ubisoft.
Scott: fuck you Ubisoft.
Rym: The only reason I want to play the South Park games because it's basically an episode of South Park.
Scott: That's exactly the only reason I want to play it as well.
Scott: It's been a South Park drought usually the South Park in the fall and then South Park in the spring.
Scott: There was no spring South Park, you know how seasons work for there is no spring South Park this year.
Rym: Well, you know how I knew the last season the South Park.
Scott: my guys It only takes you 24 hours to make a goddamn episode.
Scott: Yeah, I saw crying some out.
Rym: Why do I not get seven episodes a week?
Rym: I mean you guys could clearly do it.
Rym: Seriously, you know what if they did you brag about it?
Rym: I imagine six episodes would come out and then nothing.
Rym: Eventually, the police would be called they'd go to the studio and everyone would be actual crab people would emerge.
Rym: Ooh The Metacritic score in this game is 62.
Rym: As far as I'm concerned, I mean, I guess anything under a hundred means the game is garbage.
Scott: I don't know I don't care about scores.
Rym: Do I?
Rym: but I just find out what that means.
Rym: the point of all that is that In ex I'm somehow no longer excited about the steam summer sales because I already bought all the games I wanted to buy in the last steam sale and I appear to already own almost every game.
Rym: That's under $8.
Scott: I have a desire to go biking.
Scott: I don't have a desire to play a video game.
Scott: So if you try to sell me video games That's like trying to sell food to a guy who just finished dinner and dessert and second dessert Yep.
Rym: Now maybe because even if it's free foie gras, it's like.
Scott: well, I would really love free foie gras.
Scott: That's really amazing quality two milkshakes and a really great price.
Scott: But there is literally no way I could eat anything not even if it's a way far thing.
Rym: But I never forget.
Rym: I tried to buy games that I already own Four times so far.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: I mean and here's the worst thing It's not like I like bought the games and never installed them.
Rym: two of them Not only had I installed but I had logged at least an hour or two in them.
Scott: Okay, so Skyrim They were selling the complete Skyrim right?
Scott: Somehow I got the incomplete Skyrim.
Scott: I think someone bought it for me.
Scott: Thank you I played it a whole bunch and it was pretty good, you know, just same as the oblivion which I enjoyed and beat.
Scott: and You know, I played it.
Scott: I got really far.
Scott: I found a lot of towns and did a lot of stuff and did a bunch of quests and was going on my way to Fus Ro Don shit and whatever right.
Rym: and then I tell me did you have Fus at least?
Scott: Yeah I had.
Scott: I think I had more than that.
Scott: Did you have Ro?
Scott: I might add the whole thing I don't remember.
Rym: So you got down as well.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Did you find Sailor Jupiter?
Scott: I killed a bunch of dragons.
Rym: Dragons are really Sadly easy to kill in that game.
Scott: Yeah, well not early on but yeah once you.
Rym: yeah But like it's really disappointing when it's like, oh, there's a dragon I'll just run backwards shooting my arrows at it and then it'll.
Scott: I never use arrows like a sissy.
Rym: Oh, all right, then it'll inexplicably keep landing near me and let me hit it.
Rym: Yeah, why doesn't the Reagan just constantly hover over me firing flame until I die?
Rym: Why does it ever land?
Scott: It is not wise anyway.
Scott: So, you know, I had a bunch of good times for a few days and then I just stopped and I never loaded it again.
Scott: It's still installed.
Scott: so why would I pay to add all the DLC shit to it that I haven't even Thought I had any desire to turn on the regular one.
Rym: The lesson I have learned is much more horrifying because when I bought fallout 3 I got Jip because I should have just waited for the ultimate edition.
Scott: I didn't know there was gonna be ultimate shit.
Rym: Yes, now I've learned every game like that will have an ultimate shit.
Rym: That'll be way better than the original game.
Scott: I mean, I mean, I wouldn't buy Skyrim until it was the ultimate shit.
Scott: I mean if I didn't have it at all, I probably would have bought it.
Scott: right now.
Rym: Fallout New Vegas is under seven dollars right now.
Scott: Yeah, I have the ultimate of that and I played it for like five minutes not fallout 3 level of quality.
Rym: Yeah It did the part.
Rym: if you cared about the fighting tactical kind of stuff.
Rym: It did that better.
Rym: but Most of what I actually expect to like about Fallout games is either the emergent behavior that doesn't really happen anymore or Just walking around the crazy post-apocalyptic Landscape which needs to have a bunch of stuff not just a bunch of empty buildings.
Rym: I can't walk into.
Scott: Yeah, well follow new vegas is a desert.
Scott: I know I didn't even get to vegas cuz it was so blue.
Rym: I didn't even get to vegas.
Rym: No, you didn't even beat the mothership on FTL.
Rym: I Did in baby mode?
Scott: That's I don't care what mode it is, yeah, really I don't care at all.
Rym: Well, then I've beaten Megaman 2 a bunch of times.
Scott: Are you telling me you can't beat Megaman 2 on non baby mode?
Scott: Is that what you're telling me?
Rym: You can't beat FTL on non baby.
Scott: telling me eat croutons and drink ketchup.
Rym: I Grutons, I tell you what you want ever race If you beat FTL on normal mode before I beat Megaman 2 on normal mode.
Rym: I'll eat a hat Tiny chocolate my hat.
Rym: So in other gaming news, I don't know if you have a gaming news.
Scott: I do.
Rym: okay The sports ball player bid another sports ball player and that's a controversy.
Scott: Well, yeah, let's talk about this gaming news Just quickly, right?
Scott: So there's a Sonic the Hedgehog 2 HD fan project.
Scott: So some fans want to remake Sonic 2 the best Sonic you mean.
Rym: some fans want to get sued in HD, right?
Scott: So that's the news, right?
Scott: So I would play this actually cuz I really like Sonic 2 more.
Scott: It's the best of all the Sonic's the only good one.
Rym: I'm not gonna be.
Scott: yeah Some of the other ones are not bad, but yeah, but it's vastly superior to you.
Rym: play Sonic 2.
Rym: Most of them are not worth playing sure.
Scott: So a direct HD remake where it's the exact same game only looks a lot better.
Scott: That would be really good.
Scott: It would be like bionic commander rearmed.
Rym: I'll be all about except that was not a direct remake.
Rym: That was a direct.
Rym: that was like a spiritual remake.
Rym: that actually changed a bunch of things for the better Right, but anyway, like a DuckTales game that had all the bullshit.
Scott: This would be a good thing if fans made it but I've noticed in my long gaming life If you look around when fans try to do things like translation projects or hacks and mods.
Scott: Gaming companies don't seem to care that mother Translations are still out there, right?
Scott: You know Final Fantasy translations are out there game companies.
Scott: Don't try to stop you if you do that.
Rym: I got a C&D about a Final Fantasy 5 ROM translation I had hanging around back in the geocities days.
Scott: But when you try to do this, remember the people trying to make Chrono Trigger 3d.
Scott: Yeah, you get shut the fuck down But these people abandon this project, but now they are picking it back up.
Scott: start the clock to see how quickly it gets shut down, but Sega you you know, you're looking to not suck and make a Sonic game that people actually want to play.
Scott: Why don't you just do this for the fans instead of having fans do it themselves?
Rym: But you have to do it right.
Rym: that DuckTales game looked like it was gonna be the greatest.
Rym: It was gonna be bionic commander rearmed with ducks But instead it was just like like they were faithful to the wrong parts of the DuckTales game.
Rym: Yeah, kind of like how modern MOBAs are faithful to the wrong parts of Dota.
Scott: That's why I actually you're right.
Scott: It's it's weird because in that bionic commander rearmed you had people who a were clearly huge fans of bionic commando But B also had game development skills.
Scott: Yeah, but see remember we you know We do a lot of pan need to get both things together good gaming knowledge and skills Plus also being a fan but not being a fan boy.
Rym: I was looking at our you know, our list of panels and it's a rare.
Scott: It's a rare conflagration.
Rym: I was trying to figure out like what panel I want to do.
Rym: it packs us.
Rym: if you don't go like which one would I?
Rym: Be happy to do on my own.
Rym: Mm-hmm And I think I'll do.
Rym: losing should be fun.
Rym: But I remembered that we did that other panel years ago that we didn't get video of because we were in a hurry to get The Omega thon called egregiously unrealized potential.
Rym: and in that panel We talked at length about bionic commander rearmed.
Rym: and how remember?
Rym: that game was not the main game.
Rym: That was just a promotional game to promote the real bionic commandos.
Rym: No one gave a fuck about that sold so poorly that bionic commando Rearmed got a sequel and the new bionic commando is dead.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So that's a topic.
Rym: being faithful to the right parts Yeah, anyway, if anyone has video of that egregiously unrealized potential panel, we did it a packs many years ago.
Rym: Let me know.
Rym: I would like to put some form of that on YouTube if I could anyway.
Scott: So let's talk about the biting.
Rym: So it's to me.
Rym: It's not news that a soccer player bit another soccer player.
Rym: That's just like ridiculous.
Scott: See the thing there.
Scott: It surprised me a little bit.
Scott: I mean things like this have happened before head butts and bites, right?
Scott: Yep, but you know, they're not too common.
Scott: It's that someone was like ow and pretending to be it, but they weren't pretending.
Scott: they actually got injured by someone.
Scott: Yeah That's a more shocking part of it.
Rym: You see that HD zoomed in photo and there's a fucking bite mark there.
Scott: Also some guy bet a bunch of money.
Scott: There was a people were betting 175 to one odds that this guy would bite someone in the World Cup because he had bitten people twice before.
Rym: that's what Amazes me this people made that bet and one I would have bet.
Rym: I would have bet money on that if I knew I could Bet on that.
Scott: Yeah, well you can in every other country.
Rym: It's I mean Mike Tyson bit a guy.
Rym: once This guy bit two people.
Scott: we don't know who he bit outside the boxing ring.
Rym: well This guy in the context of soccer Bit multiple people was punished for it and yet was allowed to continue playing.
Rym: I imagine if a hockey player bit another hockey player, they would never play in the NHL again.
Scott: Maybe there's a long time.
Rym: You take your gloves off you punch each other then you both go sit in the box.
Rym: If was someone bit I think there'd just be a lawsuit like criminal charges outside of the game.
Rym: So soccer's weird and messed up and I just find this hilarious.
Rym: but anyway things of the day Got a thing of the day the most interesting thing you've seen in the last day I do but I forgot what it was.
Scott: Really?
Rym: Yes, really old man.
Scott: Do your thing of the day.
Rym: Old man Scott.
Rym: Yes, old man Scott forgot.
Scott: I didn't keep the link open.
Scott: I remembered what it was.
Scott: So, you know our friends over at super art fight.
Rym: There are some of the best people.
Rym: super art fight is one of the best.
Scott: Maybe you should come see them at Kinetic Con right in the final round.
Rym: There's gonna be a mystery Art fighter and I don't know who it is And I really want to know if it were if I didn't know but the ideal art fighter if I could think of anyone in The world to get in there.
Rym: There's only two people.
Rym: Hmm.
Rym: I would either want to get Banksy Oh my god, or I would want to get Mike Krahulik.
Rym: I would also like to see Katie Cook could probably do a pretty good job.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: She's really fast.
Rym: I think she can be.
Scott: she has art skills.
Rym: She could definitely do it because based on her style I think she could pull it off.
Rym: Like I think she could draw quick enough in the art fight style to make it happen.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: There's the undefeated Yuka Ota.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know.
Scott: Is she going to Kinetic Con?
Scott: She didn't go last year I don't know.
Rym: don't think she's on any of the panels I put together.
Scott: Well Sergio Aragones would also is also one of my number one people to be in the art fight.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know Banksy There are plenty of people who'd be amazing in art fight.
Rym: actually Banksy would be a good guest of Kinetic Con.
Scott: Yeah, good.
Scott: Good luck with that.
Rym: You never know.
Rym: That's the kind of weird thing.
Rym: I'll go for it.
Scott: Anyway, so super art fight is doing much more internetting.
Scott: They got a podcast going on.
Scott: They got all kinds of stuff, right?
Scott: So then they have another thing on YouTube.
Scott: on their YouTube channel Super art stream and in super art stream number 10 Appears another artist who would be excellent at super art fighting Casey Green.
Rym: Oh There are shoe set sir.
Scott: So you should watch super art stream number 10.
Scott: It only has 64 views.
Scott: Seriously.
Scott: What the fuck?
Scott: That should be like, you know, it should say 301 plus right now because they can't count the views.
Rym: Yeah guys my video of like Twilight Sparkle getting Kanye'd has more views than I mean.
Scott: in the thumbnail for the stream Which I guess they did via Google Hangout There is a drawing he has done of a cross between the Goodyear blimp and a narwhal in our year.
Scott: Nor your blimp and that's just the thumbnail.
Scott: there's an hour and 14 minutes of this.
Rym: In the meta moment.
Rym: the book club book is I guess you do my thing of the day.
Scott: Do you have a thing of the day or are you an old man?
Rym: Remember Arnold farts and egg ate?
Scott: too many crotons.
Scott: crotons can only remember tons.
Scott: You can only remember the 80s Things of the day.
Scott: Thing of the two decades ago.
Rym: three days ago is not a super cut in the traditional sense.
Rym: This is one of those things.
Rym: basically they took extended clips from Arnold Schwarzenegger movies, which are great already and They've added farts but not in the way most people do.
Scott: most people just add farts when someone's making a funny face.
Scott: It looks like they would be farting but they're not actually farting.
Rym: these are added to moments where there is the Combination of the face and the movement and the reaction of other people to something else That make them perfect.
Rym: and the first one is Conan and he's sitting there and then he farts and then the other guy kind of looks him like up and then he says something to the effect of Have you ever felt wind like this?
Rym: Like it's that level of craft.
Rym: The book club book is a canticle for Liebowitz the precursor to all the other post-apocalyptic fiction Sci-fi pretty much ever where everyone's trapped with the remaining human society is sealed in in some way.
Rym: I read the whole thing.
Rym: It's worth reading.
Scott: I read like a few chapters.
Scott: I'm gonna finish it sooner.
Rym: However, the only thing I will say is that it reads the way your typical like Sophomore junior year like the book you have to read for a class and do analysis of it.
Rym: It's quite rambling and Having read more than Scott though Scott agrees with me from the beginning.
Rym: I think You got to know a decent amount about both Jews and Catholicism or this book makes no fucking sense.
Rym: Like this is some inside baseball on Judaism and Catholicism And it only gets more inside baseball as time goes on.
Rym: you've also got to know a little bit about actual nuclear doctrine like nuclear war as It was portrayed in the 50s and 60s like the term counter value.
Rym: You need to understand what that actually means.
Scott: All right, any other meta things?
Scott: you should go and find us all over the internet and all the places that we exist.
Rym: Yes, we have uploaded.
Rym: to highlight some of them We have uploaded two significant videos recently our lecture from PAX East this last this most recent year.
Rym: Why no one will game with you a panel that to be perfectly honest might be a little too real to real.
Rym: You might feel a little uncomfortable watching that one - we have another episode of GeekNights presents shoujo kakame You Tena.
Scott: we are analyzing every fucking episode almost done with the first third of the show.
Scott: Yes, almost first arc get two arcs left.
Rym: It's up It's a big.
Rym: this episode is significantly longer than the actual long.
Scott: Take us a year two years.
Rym: Okay, so you bought a year to do.
Scott: Will be done in 2016 2017.
Rym: give or take Mm-hmm, and we are going to also Scott's uploaded videos of the most recent netrunner tournament in Boston the Cambridge regionals big time.
Scott: Yeah, I'm running know what the fuck but New York won.
Scott: take that everywhere else.
Rym: your Jersey made it past the finish line.
Scott: exactly.
Scott: Our Jersey made it over the line.
Scott: Yeah, in fact of the final 16 cut Like 25% were people wearing our Jersey damn straight.
Rym: So and July 10th 11th 12th 13th That's right four days motherfuckers Connecticut.
Scott: Oh who should have said something about that?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, Connecticut is a one of the better conventions out there But it's an everything convention.
Rym: We run the panels and workshops department.
Rym: We've been doing this for many years.
Rym: This con is off the fucking hook and you should be there and also we are doing a bunch of panels at it.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So according to Merriam-webster sportsmanship quotes fair play Respect for opponents and polite behavior by someone who's competing in a sport or other competition.
Rym: Mm-hmm conduct as in fairness respect for one's opponent and graciousness in winning or losing becoming to one participating in a sports.
Rym: He's a great player who's also admired for his sportsmanship.
Rym: Rhymes with sportsmanship Airmen ship a thwart ship.
Scott: What the fuck is that?
Rym: Then that's the only positive thing that's come out of you reading that dictionary entry Being across the ship from side to side So a thwart ship with and longitudinal frame wide.
Rym: So being across ships, I guess if I'm on the side of the ship the port side And I'm starboard then we are a thwart ship a thwart ship Thwart ship when I'm in the passenger seat here in the driver's seat.
Scott: We were a thwart car.
Rym: I Guess that's your word of the day.
Rym: so yeah, we're thinking about sportsmanship because Frankly the guy biting the guy the guy biting the guy and then Scott's been attending tournaments of things recently.
Scott: I have one that runner tournaments mostly.
Rym: but yes sportsmanship comes up very often at net runner tournaments and it's entirely distinct from separate issues like cheating Because the different we've done shows on cheating we have.
Rym: the difference between sportsmanship and cheating is that sportsmanship is the unwritten Unspoken rules of the game.
Scott: Well, it's not necessarily rules of the game.
Scott: It's just rules.
Scott: It's just like Conducting yourself within it.
Scott: So it's like rules of society, right?
Scott: There's nothing to do with the game.
Scott: it's just when you are playing a game there are certain rules of society and Conduct that change and only apply while you are playing in a seriously competitive game or not seriously competitive game.
Rym: for example in my day-to-day life if Scott crosses me in some way I can say fuck you you motherfucker and flip him off and that's totally acceptable.
Rym: But if I did that at like a settlers tournament at PAX I would probably at least be frowned at if not booted from the tournament by the people running it.
Scott: Yeah, it's like if there's a bunch of pieces of wood sitting on a table and I scoop them all into a box nicely.
Scott: That's perfectly acceptable behavior.
Scott: But if in the were in the middle of a game and those are the pieces of the game and the game is not ended Yeah, that's cheating.
Rym: Actually, that's not.
Scott: Well, it's maybe.
Rym: you made a whole bunch of illegal.
Rym: You made like eight thousand illegal moves.
Scott: I'm just saying There Is certain conduct right, you know For everyday life there are rules of conduct that are not necessarily laws or written rules or things that you must do.
Scott: there are just you know societal things where if you do them people will really hate you and you'll be a jerk and an asshole.
Scott: and During a game any kind of game more rules apply than usual or different rules apply compared to usual.
Rym: There's another fine point there that sportsmanship stuff is very.
Rym: there's usually no defined objective line.
Rym: There's almost no way to objectively say this is the line between just being a dick and unsportsmanlike.
Scott: Yeah, I mean look it's like you can't write a rule like no trash talk because a lot of trash talk is perfectly Okay, and it's very sportsmanlike.
Scott: In fact, it would be unsportsmanlike to not trash talk at all in some cases.
Scott: But though at the same time trash talk goes over the line when does it go over the line?
Scott: that's completely subjective.
Rym: Well, of course though then again There's the gray area between these two.
Rym: where on the sportsmanlike conduct is an offense of which one can be Punished in some fashion or for which one can be punished in some fashion in some sports They're all in American football.
Rym: if I spike the ball in an inappropriate manner and there's definitions of what isn't is not an inappropriate spike or Celebration I could get in trouble.
Scott: three humps.
Rym: Yeah Like there's some like you're there are.
Rym: what are the exact rules about celebration?
Rym: like you can celebrate in some okay So you can't.
Scott: you cannot have a loud right not have a group Celebration right.
Scott: you need to celebrate on your own.
Scott: You cannot use a prop in the celebration and the ball counts a prop you cannot like taunt the other team Right.
Scott: So like you can't like point at the guy like if you like push the guy over and ran in for a touchdown.
Scott: But while you're celebrating you can't point and laugh at that guy.
Scott: Yeah, right Those are just some of the rules.
Scott: pretty much you celebrate on your own, you know You can do generic things like saying yeah, the Lambo leap is grandfathered in you know That's pretty much it.
Scott: I mean, I'm sure there's more details than that.
Rym: But but is that that's almost like?
Rym: like I said, this is this gray area where that's where a game has rules Describing what is and is not sportsmanlike.
Rym: I don't think that actually counts as sportsmanship because it once the game has rules about it That's just the rules of the game.
Scott: well in the netrunner tournament rules, right and I'm think the same goes for pretty much every You know game that has official tournament rules that you're gonna play in a game store, you know magic settlers, etc.
Scott: There's a rule that says the judge can you know punish you for unsportsmanlike behaviors, right?
Scott: And it's that's really all it says.
Scott: it's like one sentence and it's like yeah Someone's being unsportsmanlike the judge can kick them out or do whatever they got to do Which can be problematic if people have different definitions of acceptable behavior.
Rym: Yep, and it's increasing.
Rym: It's especially problematic at lower levels of professionalism.
Scott: So yeah, what usually ends up happening is everyone has to be on their.
Scott: you know Your best.
Scott: you have to.
Scott: you have to lean towards your better behavior because you don't know this judge.
Scott: If you're just going to some random store in Cambridge, yeah, where the judges are actually great by the way of course it's interesting because We shouldn't necessarily like it.
Rym: Ideally you shouldn't need to explain to people like yo dog.
Rym: You shouldn't whip your dick out every time you score a point and netrunner.
Rym: That would be a great celebration.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: So here is an example of something that actually actually happened recently, right?
Scott: So and the team covenant is like a big-time store out in Tulsa, Oklahoma.
Scott: Right and they do a lot of netrunner there as well as Game of Thrones and other fantasy flight games and they're.
Scott: they have Big internet presence, you know in terms of like.
Scott: they stream all their stuff on Twitch And all kinds of right.
Scott: they make lots of videos on YouTube.
Scott: They're really popular.
Scott: So their netrunner regional tournament at their store was streaming live and I'm watching it and It gets to the elimination rounds and this dude comes and he has a lot of play mats.
Scott: cuz he played in a lot of Tournaments.
Scott: if I would have kept all the play mats from the tournaments I went to I'd have like five or six, right?
Scott: But I only have one because I got rid of all the other ones.
Scott: cuz what I want all these fucking play mats for?
Scott: They're all so ugly, but he had a lot of play mats.
Scott: So he sits down and he puts down the first play mat.
Scott: He puts on another play mat directly on top of it and then another one and then another one.
Scott: Yeah, he puts every play mat.
Scott: He owns into like an inch thick stack.
Scott: That's cool.
Scott: And then he starts playing, right?
Scott: So everyone in the stream is like death to Matt, man Fuck you, right?
Scott: Cuz you it's kind of being an asshole move.
Scott: now unbeknownst to us That was like an inside joke for those people like.
Scott: they knew the deal.
Scott: But to us, you know spectators not knowing them.
Scott: that looked like unsportsmanlike conduct to us.
Scott: But he said as soon as he sat down before he did it We heard him say it on the stream.
Scott: I asked the judges and they said this isn't unsportsmanlike conduct It's just being a douchebag.
Scott: So I'm gonna do it and he starts landing up the play mats right.
Scott: So there that's the kind of example of something that actually happened in real life.
Rym: So there's you've never judge yourself.
Rym: I think that's perfectly acceptable.
Scott: I agree with the judge.
Scott: That is not unsportsmanlike conduct, but it is douchebag move.
Scott: I would not do that move and I would and I would look down upon the person who did that move and That guy lost.
Scott: he got what he deserved.
Rym: so in some high school sports, especially in the more acted like the not like The academic sports like the quiz bowls and the signs Olympiads all the game that you play now.
Rym: I saw this in some of the non basically non football sports as well.
Rym: Mm-hmm It was you could basically get in trouble if you beat the other team too badly.
Scott: High school level that I see that discussion a lot on.
Scott: Like sport like, you know real sports like TV and shit like sports commentators Like if some high school team beats another high school team in basketball like a hundred to two They'll be like what happened here.
Scott: This is wrong, right.
Scott: or even in pro sports It's like, you know, if a football team is like winning by 20 and they just keep trying to score touchdowns They'll be like, oh they're running up the score as bullshit.
Scott: Don't do that.
Scott: Yep, and You know, I mean for the high school situation or the kids situation I think the problem was a who even scheduled this game between really good team and really out.
Rym: Well, usually it's just because one town just one year is a bunch of really Do about that be.
Scott: why didn't they just forfeit or whatever, right?
Scott: Why did they make let that game go on right?
Scott: It's like, you know that that's shouldn't happen but in pro sports, it's like, okay, this is an NFL football team.
Scott: The score is gonna be with the score is gonna be.
Rym: I think college applies in the same way like watching Newman lose the game 24 goals to nothing in hockey.
Rym: Yeah is one of those wonderful things you can see in the world and World Cup which is you know topical.
Scott: right in the group Rounds at least they actively reward you for running up the score because the score differential matters.
Scott: So you better run up this car.
Scott: Otherwise, what are you doing?
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Well, I guess there this is.
Rym: there's actually a pretty clear way to say this.
Rym: What is the intent of the match in this case for little kids and like elementary schools?
Rym: The intent is for a bunch of kids to have fun and play the game.
Scott: the actual You know The intent is not for the kids to have fun.
Scott: The intent is for the parents to have fun taking photos of the kids going on.
Rym: Well, I think the difference is is it between and they feel like they're good parents between elementary schools Or elementary school teams?
Rym: or is it the little league that's separate from the school.
Rym: Yes for the little league Yeah, that's all.
Rym: that's mostly for the parents But for the schools, it's just part of the educational process.
Rym: but I feel like in almost all cases it is never really fair to Punish teams for that kind of behavior because that's kind of the behavior I would expect someone to put up against me.
Rym: Like I'd almost feel worse if someone could trivially score against me and after they beat me by a whole much just Stopped like just obviously stop trying.
Scott: Well, that's almost that.
Scott: it depends on how they do it.
Scott: Right, like if you're playing basketball Someone who just gets a basket right runs to the other end of the court steals the ball scores a basket and repeats, right?
Scott: That's really frustrating.
Scott: But if you imagine if the guy has the ball and he just he doesn't shoot and score he just keeps it away Just keeps it away from you.
Scott: You can't get it from just keeps it away And just running out the clock keeping it away keeping it away And then when the clock runs out, he like throws it out of bounds.
Scott: you go get it He steals it and then keeps it away until the shot clock runs out again.
Rym: Is that more or less sportsman-like than just shooting it?
Scott: It depends on the manner in which he keeps it away, right?
Rym: But now are you obligated to fake like you're trying but fail for the entire rest of a one-sided match?
Scott: I Think you know, this is why in Little League.
Scott: They have the mercy rule.
Rym: Yep So it mostly comes down to the organizers of an event deciding what the goal of that event is and Probably what the marketing around that event will be like.
Rym: they don't want you know A lot of online type games and especially like the PC competitive gaming circuits and the fighting game competitive circuits They have some image problems with people who aren't inside their little communities.
Scott: Well, look at hearthstone.
Scott: hearthstone for all its problems of you know money right and winning and collectible shit.
Scott: They solved all these problems.
Scott: You just can't communicate with the person other than like these like six or eight built-in things You can say which are like well played threatened Yeah, so already every time the other player fucks up well played.
Scott: Yep I mean, but that's all you can say.
Scott: you can only use those pre-built built pre-built in messages.
Rym: Would you consider it unspoken like if I sent that message after every move the other player made for the entire match?
Scott: if you do That they can.
Scott: there's a button.
Scott: they can just mute and they see nothing that you say.
Scott: You can push those buttons as much as you want.
Scott: They'll never see the message.
Rym: Yeah, do I know they muted me?
Scott: No So pretty much it's like unsportsmanlike.
Scott: conduct can't happen.
Scott: The only thing you can do this.
Scott: unsportsmanlike is basically like if you have the match in hand Like you can whiz win anytime you want like this turn you could just win Instead of just winning.
Scott: you just drag it out Like you.
Scott: just let him go for another turn right and still let them try to do something.
Rym: I do that pretty much all the time when I'm playing neuroshima hacks when I'm open.
Scott: That's like the only thing that you can do in in Hearthstone.
Scott: That's unsportsmanlike.
Scott: So what about like and if you're against a serious opponent who is actually competitive with you, you can't afford to do that.
Rym: So our friend Chie recalled in Dominion her primary strategy Seemed to be to come up with a combo that would both win the game And cause some sort of ridiculous near infinite loop to occur Just to rub it in.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Is that unsportsmanlike?
Scott: I mean, that's how you play Dominion.
Scott: It's optimal play, right?
Scott: But I mean, let's say is you know, is it unsportsmanlike to just be better than your opponent, right?
Scott: so let's say you know, it's like you're Michael Jordan and you get into a basketball game and Against some other team and they're just not Michael Jordan and you win Easily, yep without much effort.
Rym: Was that a failure of matchmaking failure of the rules of the game?
Scott: if me and Rym play by the commando if we play nidhogg Is that is it just unsportsmanlike for that for us to play in the first place?
Scott: Yeah, I mean is Rym just supposed to like not commando.
Rym: Yeah, like you when we play a street fighter You're like fine only like jabs.
Rym: I will use Jab only like jab only.
Rym: just you're just in the corners.
Scott: I'm handicapping myself and then still winning.
Scott: Is that unsportsmanlike?
Scott: Insult you or is that balancing?
Rym: I remember I finally beat you when you were like fine only jabs and I will never jump and then I beat you barely.
Rym: Really what it comes down to in that front is if you're playing a game with someone where there is no Obvious and easy way to deal with your extreme skill disparity You just shouldn't play games with that type of person or that person or that game.
Rym: Yes, like for example dance dance revolution handles this really well.
Rym: You can play maniac mode right next to someone playing beginner mode and it doesn't matter doesn't do anything.
Rym: In fact, they feel like they're helping because if you start to fail they keep you alive.
Scott: They keep they keep your quarter alive.
Scott: Yes, you don't lose your money.
Rym: So it's partly an aspect of game design.
Rym: if you're designing a game You have to think a lot about what unsportsmanlike behaviors does the game allow and encourage?
Rym: And do you care mm-hmm I mean counter-strike if you have a server and you turn on all talk That is just ripe for the lots of unsportsmanlike contacts But at the same time with the right crowd.
Rym: if that's your goal like these sort of semi casual games that can be super fun.
Scott: So in terms of recommendations as a game player, right?
Scott: I recommend that you be sportsmanlike and not be a dickhead.
Rym: What is the definition of sportsmanship then?
Rym: are we you just have that?
Scott: you just have to?
Scott: if you're not a dick Then you have good judgment already and you know, yep, right.
Scott: so just use the good judgment that you have because a lot of people have good judgment and aren't dicks and Intentionally decide not to obey their better judgment.
Scott: true become and do dickish things.
Rym: But then there's that guy is the people who don't have good judgment But there's also the people.
Scott: there's no way to just tell them what good judgment is because it's subjective.
Scott: You have to just know yep, you have to be a socially aware individual.
Rym: And that's pretty much all it comes down to at least in everything but professional sports.
Rym: and like we said in professional sports Oh, you can start by not biting your opponent.
Scott: That's a good start.
Scott: Yeah, if you're not sure about what to do Start by not biting.
Rym: Oh, you know don't bite Don't tell them to go fuck themselves.
Scott: Well, I mean that depends right?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: it's like if I lose to someone I can be like, oh go fuck yourself.
Scott: There's the thing if you're.
Scott: but then I could be like hey Maybe you should go fuck yourself.
Scott: And if I say in a funny way, that could be totally.
Rym: All right It can be but if you're a person who doesn't already know if it can be if it can be.
Scott: All right, don't do it.
Rym: Yeah, the rule is unless yeah, you know, you can get away with it.
Scott: Don't do it if there's any uncertainty whatsoever.
Scott: Don't say or do whatever you were thinking or not or thinking about doing.
Scott: Opting to just not say or not do something Well is always safer than doing something unless it's saying good game.
Scott: You could say good game.
Scott: You can't get hurt doing that.
Rym: So here's a separate related question.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Thanks for playing.
Rym: or you know, this was relevant in like quiz bowl.
Rym: It's relevant in a lot of video games.
Rym: Good luck.
Rym: Good luck games.
Scott: So well played.
Rym: what about situations where there are things in the context of a game that are not in any sense either in the rules of the game or the rules of the tournament structure or the rules of the community like the written rules of the community organization, they're in no way against the rules, but they are part of the widely accepted unwritten social rules of the game.
Scott: like You want to talk about the bowing in Star Wars?
Rym: Is that you want to talk about the bowing in Star Wars or the things that would be considered cheating?
Rym: Except that they're not actually breaking any rules like observing other teams and taking notes.
Rym: That's what.
Rym: if there's some game we'll do that all the time.
Rym: Yes, and there are some games where the community greatly frowns upon that but it's hard to have rules against it.
Scott: They don't have specific rules in that run of the specific rule.
Scott: No scouting.
Rym: Yep What's the definition of scouting?
Scott: if the tournament judge thinks that you're going around looking at other people playing to figure out what's in?
Scott: Their deck so that when you play them, you know what they got Then they can just kick you out.
Rym: Yeah So is.
Rym: would it be unethical to have a friend go to the place where you know The people are gonna be in the tournament in the weeks before the tournament play and practice on their decks?
Scott: You can't you?
Scott: only time you can't scout is during the tournament.
Rym: Yep So would it be considered unsportsmanlike for you?
Rym: just hypothetical to have me go to Oklahoma or whatever for a month and Join the netrunner community there and hang out and play with these people and figure out what decks they're gonna use in the tournament?
Rym: They give you all that info.
Scott: People basically know whatever.
Scott: it doesn't really matter.
Rym: Yeah, but I'm saying it so there's a no way unsportsmanlike.
Scott: No, not really.
Rym: All right I'm just curious.
Scott: some I mean there might be a scandal if some No one no one cares.
Scott: Well, the other publishes their friggin decks on the internet.
Rym: is where we joined those Star Wars Servers those
Scott: Jedi Knight -
Rym: we played a lot of that
Scott: played that game when it was brand new because oh my god It was pretty much quake 3 mod But everything was Star Wars and it was FPS but also lightsaber for the lightsaber
Rym: combat was actually pretty fun.
Scott: yeah, so you play lightsaber duels against random people on the internet and people had this thing where.
Scott: but when the duel started they would You make their characters bow in game like crouch and uncrouch or lean look at the ground and then look forward again.
Rym: Whenever someone did that one I would force lighten them immediately which they always said.
Rym: no force lightning But I do it anyway And then I just rush in and fucking cut them.
Scott: I would just immediately push these when as soon as they started to bow I would time it and use the strongest Powerful lightsaber attack that was really slow and his suit at a time.
Scott: It's such that when their head was down it hit and then decapitated.
Scott: them is over.
Rym: I would usually also as soon as the lightsaber duel started back up pull out my blaster and start shooting them.
Scott: Yeah, that's also a good move.
Rym: I got kicked from a lot of servers.
Scott: Yeah, people would kick because it's their server.
Rym: they have a right to kick you if they want but But eventually you find the server where the mod isn't there and then you'd go nuts because that is in no way part of the Rules of the game only the rules of the community.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Were we being unsportsmanlike?
Scott: No, I don't think so.
Rym: We were violating all the rules of the community to an extreme degree.
Scott: Yeah, I Don't feel bad about that.
Scott: I would do it again.
Rym: I in fact not only do not feel bad about I'm kind of proud of it.
Scott: Yeah, I would do it the same way again.
Rym: I remember when one guy got so mad at me.
Rym: He's like for he said no force lightning.
Rym: that he told me and I quote.
Rym: that's unethical.
Scott: Do you snake in Mario Kart?
Rym: I Was the champion of snakes?
Scott: Okay, that is the same thing.
Rym: I have the scars to prove it.
Scott: Okay, then We're done here.
Rym: But I remember when that guy said that I said and I quote But I'm on the dark side and I proceeded to follow him around the server for doing nothing But force lightning him to death until he eventually quit.
Rym: nice roleplay Yeah, I wasn't griefing I was role-playing mm-hmm.
Rym: I was I was I was dark Sith.
Rym: What do you want?
Rym: this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott special?
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursday.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.