Rym: It's Tuesday, February 4th, 2014.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights!
Scott: Tonight, the stakes for the vampires.
Rym: Let's do this!
Rym: So I see you two have been reading Dr.
Rym: McNinja lately.
Scott: What have I not read?
Scott: What time in the past, say, I don't know, decade, or have I not read Dr.
Scott: McNinja?
Rym: There was a period of about a month where I just kind of forgot to read it, for whatever reason.
Scott: Thanks to Comic Rocket, I don't miss webcomics really anymore.
Rym: You sound like an ad.
Rym: Thanks to Comic Rocket, I no longer...
Scott: Comic Rocket, you should really work on your mobile support so I could read webcomics on the go.
Scott: Because it's pretty bad right now.
Rym: It barely works.
Rym: I prefer reading my webcomics on big screens because a lot of the ones I read actually have really good art.
Scott: Well, thank you for this Retina iPad mini screen.
Rym: Yeah, where the fuck is my Retina monitor?
Rym: I want like a 26 inch Retina monitor.
Scott: Dell has 4K ultra sharps.
Scott: The cheap one sucks.
Scott: The expensive one's expensive.
Scott: Really expensive.
Rym: Actually, all I really want is a laptop like the laptop I have, but with a Retina style display.
Scott: You know, I'm going to get a 4K camera if the rumors are true.
Scott: It's supposed to be announced Friday according to rumor sites.
Scott: I don't have a 4K screen to check the video, huh?
Rym: You also might have to get a faster computer.
Scott: Why?
Scott: My computer's pretty much as close to the fastest computer you can buy.
Rym: It depends on your rendering pipeline and what you're going to do with that video.
Scott: Probably cut it down to 1080p's.
Rym: Actually, I think you can upload higher resolution to YouTube.
Scott: You can, but...
Rym: Well, I guess I'll say this.
Rym: If you do that, you'll have to come over here to upload it, I think.
Rym: So, I've been playing a lot of Nidhogg.
Scott: I do not play Nidhogg that often.
Rym: Many of you, you probably should have watched our stream on Nidhogg, because we talked about it a lot.
Scott: I have a Twitch channel.
Scott: Check it out.
Rym: Yeah, go to Scott's Twitch, watch us playing Nidhogg, and you'll hear our commentary.
Rym: You'll see Scott getting increasingly frustrated and angry.
Scott: Listen, it's airhogged.
Scott: If you played a bunch of Nidhogg, I barely played it.
Scott: I played, like, a couple hours.
Scott: That's a significant amount for a simple game.
Rym: Yep, and now it's too late.
Rym: You'll never catch up.
Scott: I could go home and I could play for you, like, all night, and then I would come back and I'd be set, unless you play also all night.
Rym: Nah, you're 100 years too early at this point.
Scott: What?
Rym: So, I've been playing Nidhogg, and there's no one to play with, really.
Rym: Like, I can play with Emily at home and stuff, but I can't, like, play...
Scott: Go to Magfest.
Scott: There'll be someone to play with.
Scott: People even play Magical Drop and Windjammers.
Rym: So, every time I've tried to play online, I've joined the matchmaking system, gotten a match right away, and I win.
Rym: And within an hour, I will have driven every single human out of the matchmaking system.
Scott: Well, because it's interesting how that matchmaking system works, as opposed to other games.
Scott: It's rather unique, the free online, sort of, public multiplayer mode, right, where it has sort of a queue.
Scott: It's more like a ladder, and you work your way up to the top of the ladder, and once you get to the top, pretty much people have to challenge you.
Scott: So, you're just sitting there being challenged over and over again, and if you never lose, you just stay on top.
Scott: And so, if you just keep beating everyone, and you stay on top of the ladder too long, everyone else in the game will slowly quit.
Scott: 'Cause the guy in second place is like, "Fuck
Scott: this."
Scott: And the guy in third place is like, "Fuck
Scott: And then, all the other people aren't good enough, you trounce the hell out of them, and you basically just... The person in second place keeps quitting if you keep winning until you're all alone.
Rym: And there's also not that many people in the first place.
Rym: There'll be, like, 10 or 20 people playing.
Scott: Right, so everyone can see that you're just sitting up there, undefeated.
Rym: Basically, every time I play, what happens is, eventually, like, I'll play someone.
Rym: I beat him.
Rym: We play for a while, against each other, because other people come in, usually it's just me and one guy.
Rym: Eventually, they rage quit.
Rym: From a game.
Rym: Like, it'd be in the middle of a game, they see it's me.
Scott: Nidhogg is so... I understand rage quitting as a general thing.
Rym: Yeah, if you're bad at it, it's gonna be over.
Scott: I can understand why someone would rage quit in a game, period.
Scott: Why would you rage quit in a game that is, like, 30 seconds long?
Scott: You wanna know why?
Rym: I'll tell you why.
Scott: Does it have a record, like Mario Kart?
Scott: No.
Rym: There's no record.
Scott: You have no idea how good people are.
Scott: So you're not even hurting yourself in any way, versus losing.
Rym: Zero.
Rym: So here's why people rage quit.
Rym: The way it works is, you're basically, whoever's player one picks the map, and when you both hit ready, you just fight.
Rym: The only information you get, unless you chat with each other, is the name.
Rym: Like, the Steam name.
Rym: So, what'll happen is, someone will be playing against me, and I trounce them, and then, once you beat someone, you play the same person again, if you want, most of the time.
Rym: So, they'll join the game again.
Scott: They see it's you.
Rym: They see me trouncing them, and they quit, hoping to get another player.
Rym: But there aren't other players, because I've already driven everyone else away.
Rym: So the ready room reappears, it's just me, and then the same name that just rage quit joins again.
Rym: And then immediately rage quits once they recognize my name.
Scott: One time I played Dr.
Scott: Mario on the Wii, and I was just like, "Online!
Scott: Make me play against
Scott: someone!".
Scott: And much to my surprise, even though, this was like a few months ago, so the game is already mad old, someone was actually there playing.
Scott: I was like,
Scott: "Whoa!".
Rym: You made that kid's day.
Rym: He's been waiting.
Scott: Yeah, we played some Dr.
Scott: Mario, and they were really fucking good, but I'm also really good at Dr.
Scott: Mario.
Scott: But not, you know, super good, but better than everyone else I know.
Scott: And, you know, it was close, I lost, and then it was close, I won, and then it was close, I lost.
Scott: And it was like,
Scott: "Alright.".
Scott: But then it's like, even though it was close, I'm like, "I'm done with
Scott: this.".
Scott: There's only one person to play against.
Scott: The game ended.
Scott: It's like, "Okay, play someone
Scott: new.".
Scott: The same person you just played is the only person playing Dr.
Scott: Mario Wii.
Rym: So, I love Nidhogg, but I want to very briefly go over, now that I've played it a lot, and I understand how it works really well, it has some problems.
Rym: And it's kind of worrying that it has these problems.
Scott: Alright, so the person who's played it many more hours, do you see problems besides the problems that we, at, like, first glance, possible problems?
Rym: Uh, basically, no.
Rym: Well, there's two problems, fundamentally.
Rym: Problem number one, you need to be able to auto-kill yourself to start in front of the other player.
Rym: That has to be a button.
Rym: Because running off the other side of the screen is not intuitive.
Rym: Now, it's fine if that is also an option.
Scott: Not killing yourself is also not intuitive.
Scott: Well, not killing yourself.
Scott: It should be a respawn button, not a suicide button.
Rym: What the button should do is, when you hit the button, it should make you disappear, as though you had died, and it respawns you at whatever its respawn logic is.
Scott: Well, they should show you the respawn timer, too.
Scott: Or whatever, you know, like, they should show you the spot and the time.
Rym: Okay, so one thing, so if we're getting into all one, I'll just put, I'll frame it this way.
Rym: Here's what I would change.
Rym: I would say that you can hit a button at any time to respawn, but as soon as you hit that button, it starts counting down the default respawn timer as though you had been killed.
Rym: And then, at that time, you always spawn in front of your opponent.
Rym: Immediately.
Rym: And if you hit the button to respawn again, then the respawn timer starts counting down again.
Rym: I would add a variant, where instead of a respawn timer, you have five respawns, let's say.
Rym: Just five.
Rym: And they slowly regenerate.
Rym: You can respawn immediately if you want, but if you use all five, you gotta wait for at least one to regenerate.
Scott: Right, because it's annoying.
Scott: There are situations where someone will, basically, the strategy of losing your sword, running and jumping over the opponent, right?
Scott: So the only way they can stop you is by hitting you with their sword.
Rym: Which is pretty trivial to do.
Scott: Right, which is, you can do it, but you basically have one chance, right?
Scott: So it's like, you can do it if you know what you're doing, but you can't consistently doing it 100% of the time is an extremely small margin of error.
Scott: And because they go so fast when they're just running without a sword at all, you lose a whole screen.
Scott: Even if you're like, "Shit, I missed it, I didn't kill them," run off the screen to die, you will not respawn in time before they make it to the next screen.
Scott: And you lose a whole screen in like a fraction of a second.
Rym: Which is fine, I like severe consequences.
Scott: Right, but it basically means the best strategy in the world is force your opponent to be perfect, and unless you're 100% perfect, I win.
Scott: And the game's over in two seconds.
Rym: But, both players have the same capacity to do these things.
Scott: Right, but then that first kill makes fucking all the difference in the world.
Rym: Yeah, except against skilled players, when I do run into them, you can't just jump over them.
Rym: Sure.
Rym: And other people can't just jump over me.
Scott: I think the way to solve this would be to make the throwing sword travel much faster.
Scott: Such that when you throw a sword, it doesn't have to go instant, like they can't even react to it, but it should go faster than a person who is running with no sword.
Rym: It does!
Scott: Nah, you sort of get away from it.
Rym: No, it goes faster.
Scott: It doesn't seem like it's me.
Rym: It definitely goes faster.
Rym: But the thing is, it doesn't matter, because I'll roll under it.
Rym: That's true.
Rym: When and how to respawn in front of your opponent, and make it clear when and where you will respawn and when you'll respawn.
Rym: The time and everything all has to be open.
Rym: It shouldn't be hidden.
Rym: I shouldn't have to do the bullshit I'm doing lately, where I'll back up or move forward to make sure that when I kill a person, or when I die, like if I don't have a sword and I know I'm going to die, I'll make sure that it happens in such a way that is advantageous to me on the respawn, because I know where that shit is.
Rym: And I hate that in games.
Rym: But I do want to leave the option to run off the back of the screen, because a lot of times what I'll do is I'll run back like I'm going to run away, then I'll turn around and whip a sword at their back, and then run off the screen.
Scott: If they're a whole screen away, how's that going to hit?
Rym: So, I throw the sword, it's coming at them faster than they can run, then I respawn.
Rym: on the other side of them, there's a sword flying.
Scott: I've never been able to, by that time, they're already on the other screen.
Scott: How is...
Rym: I don't know, you're terrible at this game?
Scott: If I run off the screen, 99% of the time the person makes the next screen before I can respawn.
Rym: Yeah, that's just because you're kind of bad.
Scott: I'm running off the screen as soon as I have to.
Rym: Some of the screens are wider than others, you've got to take all this into account.
Rym: But anyway, the other thing that bothers me, and it worries me that this game was the artisanal game that was in development for so long, yet it has these fundamental problems, the actual direct sword fighting, as in move forward, move back, move the things up and down, at least with the controllers we have available on PCs, are actually kind of fucking fiddly.
Scott: It is a little bit fiddly.
Rym: And when I do find a very skilled player, you'll find that even to extremely skilled players, the odds of someone successfully disarming another person by anything other than random dumb fucking luck, pretty much zero.
Rym: You don't elegantly in, out, in, out, sword, down, up, kill.
Scott: The up and down is pretty good.
Scott: No, it's not.
Scott: But the left and right of just taking a step forward and a step backwards is a little fiddly.
Scott: They need to make it easier to just be like step, step, step, lunge, right?
Rym: They need to tighten up the controls, that's it.
Rym: It's like Super Meat Boy.
Rym: It needs Super Meat Boy level of control to be a real competitive game.
Rym: As it is, it's a little fiddly, and I worry that they're not going to make it better.
Scott: Probably not.
Rym: So, it's still fun, but I think it's going to be my air hockey.
Scott: I think it already is your air hockey.
Rym: So, speaking of air hockey, this man's air hockey is Jeopardy.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So, what's the guy's name again?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I have the name of the other guy.
Scott: Oh, I mean, Ken Jennings?
Scott: Who's the new guy?
Rym: No, no.
Rym: Not Ken Jennings.
Rym: I have the name of the guy we're going to talk about from that other game.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Scott: So specific.
Scott: Yeah?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Michael Larson.
Scott: Yeah, so the last time there was news about Jeopardy at all was Ken Jennings, who was just a really smart dude, right?
Scott: And he just won lots of Jeopardy.
Scott: But there's a new guy.
Scott: His name is... Why don't you tell me the guy's name, Arthur Chu, right?
Rym: Arthur Chu.
Scott: Arthur Chu.
Scott: So he's basically, you know, Ken Jennings just sort of won with his incredible trivia knowledges, right?
Scott: He just got all their freaking answers.
Scott: What this guy does is he's really good at trivia.
Scott: I mean, you're not going to win Jeopardy if you get all the questions wrong, right?
Scott: But, I mean, answers wrong.
Scott: Or questions.
Rym: Well, yeah, questions.
Rym: You're correct.
Scott: But he's basically playing Jeopardy the game itself differently from anyone else ever has, and that is awesome.
Rym: Now, what's extra interesting about this is that in high school, I was in Quiz Bowl, which is kind of like a big boy version of Jeopardy.
Rym: And I say that because the questions are about the same caliber, but the difference is that the way it's designed, it's usually team on team, you can buzz in at any time.
Rym: Jeopardy, from what I have read, was designed to be that way, and test audiences found that it made them feel stupid because people buzzed in early all the time, and you didn't really get a chance to see the questions.
Rym: Right.
Scott: A lot of the way Jeopardy works, remember, it's a TV show that makes money.
Scott: It makes a lot of money.
Scott: That's why it's been around for decades, right?
Scott: I mean, I would watch Jeopardy in the 80s, right?
Scott: You know, Alex Trebek is mad old.
Rym: Shuck it, Trebek.
Scott: So they don't let you buzz in until he finishes reading the question, and, you know, all these stuff to make it.
Rym: Yeah, there's an article that talks about the timing.
Rym: Like, when you're allowed to buzz in, and if you buzz in early, you're fucked.
Scott: So basically, it just so happens that the way, if you want to play Jeopardy to win, and you already have the trivia knowledge required, part of the strategies it takes to win, which are within the rules of the game as it stands, make it bad for TV.
Scott: So normally when you play Jeopardy, right, what most people do is they will start with the, pick a category they know, if they have control of the board, start at the easiest question, work their way down to rack up as much safe money as they can, right?
Scott: And if they think a category is getting too hard, they'll switch to, like, their second best category, start at the easy and work their way down to the hard.
Scott: Because if you choose the hard category, you're going to lose, you're going to mess it up and someone else, you know, you lose control, whatever.
Scott: What this guy does is he basically, and that makes it good for television to start at the easy and work down to the hard because the viewer is following and sort of working up from easy to hard also, right?
Scott: And it's good for people watching TV for it to progress that way.
Scott: He just goes and gets all the hard ones near the bottom and the bottom two rows randomly all over the place not caring about the category because he's looking for the Daily Double.
Scott: He either is going to get the Daily Double because, A, he can make a fuck ton of money on that and get such a huge lead, right, because it's more valuable.
Rym: And he'll have a bunch of money to bet already because he's gotten a bunch of the other hard questions.
Scott: Or, he'll simply bet zero on the Daily Double and be like, "Denied!
Scott: No one else can get the Daily Double and take a big jump and get away from
Scott: me.".
Scott: And he knows the Daily Double is down there in the bottom somewhere, so he's just looking for it.
Scott: He's hunting for it real hard.
Scott: And this pissed off a lot of Jeopardy!
Scott: viewers because they don't like that, right?
Scott: Some guy actually playing to win?
Scott: Scoff, right?
Rym: Yeah, fans are calling him a villain.
Scott: Yeah, he's a hero in my eyes.
Scott: Anyway, the second thing he's doing is, remember, the way Jeopardy!
Scott: works is if you win, you have the most money after the final, right?
Scott: Then you get to play Jeopardy!
Scott: again the next day.
Scott: And as long as you can keep playing Jeopardy!
Scott: the next day, you can keep getting basically free money in exchange for answering trivia questions.
Scott: So, all your goal in Jeopardy!
Scott: is get to the next day.
Scott: How do you get to the next day?
Scott: Have more money than everyone else at the end of the day.
Scott: Or tie.
Scott: So, mostly, in the final
Scott: Jeopardy!,
Scott: when you bid, how much you're betting that?
Scott: you know that question, right?
Scott: Most people will look and be like, "Okay, I got a hundred, Rym's got fifty, he's gotta bet everything, you know, to tie me, so I'm gonna bet one, so when I get it right, I'm gonna
Scott: win.".
Scott: But if I bet one and I lose, and Rym gets it right, then I lose and I don't make it to tomorrow.
Rym: But if I bet zero...
Scott: I should bet zero, that way, no matter what, I'll make it to tomorrow.
Scott: So you take that math and apply it to the actual numbers they're using, and basically, this guy always bids to tie.
Scott: He doesn't care if you also get to play tomorrow.
Scott: What does he give a shit?
Rym: In fact, he's already beaten you, so he'd rather have you than a stranger.
Scott: As long as he gets to go to tomorrow, he doesn't care about tying, and that makes it boring for viewers, because you get all these ties, they want to see a win.
Rym: But think about that, he's bringing someone he already beat with him to the next day.
Rym: That's like if I pick a loser from the losing team.
Scott: Worst case scenario, he ties, right?
Scott: If everyone else gets it wrong and he gets it right, you know, in the best case scenario, he just wins.
Rym: But if I play the Mets, can I pick one of their bad players and be like, "Yeah, I get to play against you again
Rym: tomorrow.".
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, yeah, I mean, if I was in jeopardy, I'd be like, "Look, don't worry about winning or losing.
Scott: Let's all conspire together to always tie, so all three of us and no one else will ever get to drink from this free money pool for the rest of our
Scott: lives.".
Rym: Now, this guy is not doing anything special, but look, the game was already designed in a lot of ways.
Scott: Why did it take decades for anyone to do this?
Rym: Why indeed?
Rym: Well, this has happened in the past, guys.
Rym: So, way back in the 80s, there was a game show that I used to watch semi-religiously.
Scott: That's happened in jeopardy, though.
Rym: No.
Rym: Called Press Your Luck.
Scott: Oh, good show.
Scott: And there was a gentleman- People have to know about this.
Scott: Everyone knows about this.
Rym: I hope so, but just in case, I'll link to it.
Rym: There's a gentleman named Michael Arson who watched it on TV and realized, "Oh, there's a pattern.
Rym: All I have to do is get on the show and I can rack up an infinite never-ending game of infinite
Rym: money.".
Rym: And he actually did it.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So, the fact that it didn't happen in jeopardy, I think, is solely because the kinds of people who were interested in Jeopardy were the kinds of people who were interested in Quizzy-type stuff.
Scott: Exactly.
Rym: And they're not interested in games as a whole.
Scott: People who go to get on Jeopardy are almost always 100% focused on the buzzer and the trivia, right?
Rym: The same way with The Price is Right.
Rym: Oh, Scott and I will be playing some Jeopardy on Super Nintendo in the near future.
Scott: But all I've done is tried to get the trivia.
Scott: I've never actually thought about, "Hey, is there a strategy to picking
Scott: these?".
Scott: It's like, "No, they're all going to get picked at some
Scott: point.".
Scott: See, no, no.
Rym: I thought about that a lot.
Scott: And whoever knows the most and buzzes in, you'll win if you just get them right.
Rym: When I was a kid, I had the Wheel of Fortune and Jeopardy home games.
Scott: The ones with the physical ones?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The board games?
Scott: My cousin had those.
Scott: Those are good.
Rym: The Wheel of Fortune one was crazy good.
Scott: Yeah, I wish you could get some of those and play them for reals.
Rym: I've got it.
Scott: We don't have it here.
Rym: I could get my mom to mail it here.
Scott: Maybe we could buy a more modern one at Toys R Us.
Rym: No, I want the one from the '80s.
Scott: Well, then let's go out on eBay and get maybe a '70s one or something, or a '90s one.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Anyway, so we would play these, and I didn't do everything he did because I wasn't that smart.
Rym: I was a little kid.
Rym: But I always wondered, watching TV, why anyone went for the easy questions first.
Rym: It's like in Jeopardy.
Scott: Because if you control it, you're getting free monies.
Rym: Yeah, but if you go for the hard questions first...
Scott: Because you're picking the category that's more advantageous to you, and you're picking easy questions that you know you're going to get and the other people aren't going to get.
Rym: But at the same time, what if you hesitate slightly and the other person buzzes in?
Rym: You might as well decide the game earlier.
Rym: Have more money available earlier.
Rym: And if you can't answer the hard questions, you're fucked.
Scott: Of course.
Rym: You were fucked anyway if you couldn't answer the hard questions.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: It's the same strategy as if you play Jenga with someone, go for that fucking bottom immediately.
Rym: Destabilize it as much as possible, as early as possible.
Rym: There's no reason to make the game go on longer if you're confident in your skills to not knock it over.
Rym: That's the strategy there.
Rym: So I always wondered why people on Jeopardy were kind of derpy about it.
Rym: But in Quiz Bowl...
Scott: They're derpy.
Scott: We've proven that.
Scott: This guy's not derpy.
Scott: He's my hero.
Rym: If you find some video of high school Quiz Bowl, they put all that strategy together.
Rym: They'll have metrics on word counts.
Rym: Like how many words, like you're on a team, right?
Rym: So if anyone on the team buzzes in, your whole team's chance is shot.
Rym: So we had a rule of one person was the only person for a given type of question who was allowed to buzz in within the first five words.
Rym: Because he was the one who was most likely to get it.
Rym: So we'd have strategies around that.
Rym: We'd hear things like a Midsummer night and someone just buzzes in and says William Shakespeare something something.
Rym: And sometimes it would work.
Rym: For certain kinds of questions, one guy would always...
Scott: How do you know?
Scott: the answer wasn't like the name of a character?
Scott: Like Puck?
Rym: Yeah, so we'd, based on the odds, we'd also study the questions from previous tournaments because a lot of times they'd recycle them.
Rym: So yeah, one guy I knew would always hold the buzzer like under his chin.
Rym: Like he'd hold it up and he'd put his chin on the buzzer and he'd like mash down with his chin to buzz in because he swore he could buzz in faster that way.
Scott: No, probably not.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: Anyway, I just want to read a quote from the guy, right, that makes, to show you why he's our hero.
Scott: "All of the things I'm doing are very obvious logical ways to maximize your chances of winning that are well within the
Scott: rules.".
Scott: He said, "It's hard for me to take seriously the argument that I should give up that kind of money just for the sake of making the viewing audience feel
Scott: comfortable.".
Scott: Fuck yes.
Rym: Yup, if Jeopardy!
Rym: cared about the audience, they'd change the rules.
Scott: If I'm playing a board game and someone's upset that I'm like dicking the mother, I'm saying, I'm gonna say, "All of the things I'm doing are very obvious logical ways to maximize my chances of winning that are well within the rules.
Scott: It's hard for me to take seriously the argument that I should give up that kind of money just for the sake of making the other players feel
Scott: comfortable.".
Rym: Also, I point out that if the game is so broken that an obvious strategy is way overpowered, then the game's broken.
Scott: Well, I mean, Jeopardy!
Scott: isn't broken because it doesn't really matter what the rules are.
Scott: You have to know the trivia, right?
Scott: If you know the trivia, you can win it.
Scott: Even though I know the strategies this guy has, I can't win in Jeopardy!
Scott: I'll just be like, "What the fuck?
Scott: I don't
Scott: know.".
Scott: They'll be like, "You know, this scholar from the 15th century wrote this obscure
Scott: work.".
Scott: And I'll be like, "Doo, doo, doo.
Scott: No fucking
Scott: clue.".
Scott: Who is no fucking clue?
Scott: Sorry.
Rym: So I know a bunch of people who tried out Jeopardy!
Scott: Yes, it was no fucking clue.
Rym: You do get an indication of what the topics are going to be and what the questions are going to be.
Rym: You get some stuff ahead of time.
Rym: It's not just random, random, anything from any possible realm of knowledge.
Rym: There's a little bit of guidance.
Scott: It's usually realms of knowledge I do not have.
Rym: Well, you can't name 14th century composers.
Scott: I can name some of them, but I can't tell who's 14.
Scott: I know some which century they are, but some I don't.
Rym: You can't name famous poets.
Scott: I can name a couple.
Rym: Yeats and Keats.
Scott: Robert Frost.
Rym: No.
Scott: Okay, there's one.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: Obvious.
Rym: Shel Silverstein.
Rym: Yes, that's one.
Rym: So the next time you're watching The Price is Right, ask yourself this.
Rym: Is there any reason in this fucking earth to not bid either $1 more than another person or $1 if you bid last in The Price is Right?
Rym: And the answer is no.
Scott: If you bid last, no.
Rym: Yes, and if you bid second to last, you might still want to do one of those options.
Scott: Of course, but the problem with being second to last is someone who's bid $1 more than you.
Rym: Yep, so then you have to play that, but I've noticed that people don't really take that into account.
Scott: You know what I want to do in Price is Right?
Scott: If I'm not bidding last, I want to help the person who is going before me so that they get... Help the correct person get up on stage so that I then bid last next time.
Rym: Exactly.
Scott: Unless it's the final battle.
Rym: Guys, play to win games or don't play them.
Scott: Or play games where there's no winning, like apples to apples.
Rym: Are you a player of games?
Rym: Are you simply the king of a shitty civilization that's going to collapse?
Rym: So anyway, things of the day.
Rym: You got a thing of the day?
Scott: I do have a thing of the day.
Scott: I think it's in Germany or somewhere where they speak German.
Scott: It sounds like German anyway.
Scott: But yeah, this guy, he's walking down the street.
Scott: He gets to a crosswalk, a pretty big crosswalk, and he notices the button for changing the light and letting the blind people know when the light is changing and whatnot.
Scott: Has this touchscreen attached to it.
Scott: And the touchscreen has a pretty cool user interface.
Scott: When it's safe to go, it fills up with green completely.
Scott: But the green basically empties out, and from the top down, the screen turns gray slowly until there's a sliver of green that then disappears.
Scott: And that lets you know how long there is left before the light changes back to red.
Scott: And vice versa.
Scott: When it is red, it drains out from the bottom, as if someone opened up the drain in the sink, until it is all gray again.
Scott: And that lets you know how long you're going to have to wait until walking is a possibility.
Scott: Because the red light is so long, and it's this touchscreen computer doing this, which is really helpful to begin with, it lets you do something pretty cool during the red light to pass the time.
Rym: Oh, by the way, it's fake.
Scott: Is it fake?
Rym: Yeah, I'm looking at the video again.
Rym: One, you can see the fucking, like, masking Alias artifacts around his finger.
Rym: And if you watch it, you can actually-- Are you sure it's fake?
Rym: Yes, I'm sure it's fake.
Rym: You can actually see the animation tracking incorrectly a little bit.
Scott: Alright, it's possibly fake.
Scott: Fake or not, good idea.
Rym: Also, in the text of the description, it says it's fake.
Rym: You just obviously didn't--.
Scott: No, this could be real, no.
Rym: Uh, Scott?
Scott: I do not read descriptions on videos.
Rym: Well, because it's all in German, for one.
Scott: Then how do you know it says fake?
Scott: Because I translated it.
Scott: Oh, well, this is a fake video of a thing that should be real.
Scott: Where you can play Pong against a person on the other side of the street while they're waiting for the crosswalk as well.
Scott: We should make this with Arduinos and stick it to two light posts in New York.
Rym: Yeah, we should.
Scott: And use wireless for them to communicate.
Rym: Here's the brilliance of this idea.
Rym: I don't think you guys really understand why this is brilliant.
Rym: So you're playing against a human being.
Scott: Who's on the other side of the street, who's a stranger.
Rym: Anyone who's waiting at the light that you're waiting at, you're going to pass them when the light turns green.
Rym: So you're guaranteed to meet the human being you just played with to high-five.
Rym: This would be the best way to pick up ladies or gentlemen or whatever your taste might be.
Rym: Because anyone who's cool enough to play this, lose to me and still be cool about it after I cross is probably a cool person.
Rym: Notice the implied "they're gonna lose to
Rym: me.".
Rym: So you guys know that aside from GeekNights and as yet unannounced things and all these different things I do in my life, one of my jobs is being a product manager for a Wall Street enterprise software and services company.
Rym: So I give a lot of pitches.
Rym: I sit through a lot of pitches of other people.
Rym: I interact with enterprise-y software in a very sort of high-level way.
Rym: And I would like to say that this video, my thing of the day, which is simply called "The Pitch Web Design," is almost exactly how these things go, 99% of the time.
Rym: Replace the web aspect with another type of industry.
Rym: It's pretty much just drag and drops everywhere.
Rym: I also like how the guy says "homepage" instead of
Rym: "homepage."
Rym: I'm going to start saying it that way.
Rym: In a moment, the Book Club book was?
Scott: "Idadoo" by William Gibson.
Scott: We're done with it.
Scott: Cyberpunk classic of all time.
Rym: It is definitely a classic.
Rym: And having read it again, because I hadn't read it in a long time, I like it a lot.
Scott: It's really good.
Rym: Despite its flaws, I like it a lot because a lot of the things in it are happening now.
Rym: But at the same time, a lot of the things in it are nowhere near happening.
Scott: And a lot of the things happened and we're done with pass machines.
Rym: Some of it's so dated, like the geopolitical situation, like the Russians.
Scott: On Thursday, we will talk about that.
Rym: We will talk about that.
Rym: The next Book Club book is "Wool" because everyone's fucking trying to get me to read that book.
Scott: Like sheep and you go "bzzzz" and the wool comes off.
Rym: Yes, but it's post-apocalyptic and also in the similar genre.
Rym: So we're on a roll with this stuff.
Rym: Of course, the Geek Knight's book as opposed to Book Club is just the Prince of Nothing books.
Scott: Let's imagine that again.
Rym: You should really read those first.
Rym: And the Rym book series is the E.N.M.
Rym: Banks culture series.
Rym: Because after we did Player of Games, I read almost every goddamn culture book.
Rym: And every one of them is great without exception.
Scott: Let's see, you should visit us on the internet.
Scott: We both have YouTube channels.
Scott: Mine has a lot of Netrunner videos.
Scott: Rym has Utenna videos.
Scott: You should visit my Twitch channel.
Rym: You should visit our forum, which is rocking lately in a big way.
Scott: You should follow us on Twitter where you can make fun of listeners who hate the new Twitter interface.
Rym: Oh my god, that guy is so mad about the new Twitter.
Scott: It's like, I've never seen someone so mad about something so trivial that they were unable to change.
Scott: I wanted to pity him, but I couldn't.
Scott: I just laughed at his patheticness.
Rym: What if Kill La Kill's Goku?
Rym: uniform stars are shaped that way because everything is actually Southern Cross?
Scott: Can the show really get any better?
Scott: That is one way it could get better.
Scott: There is nothing you could say that is going to make it any worse.
Scott: It's only going to get better.
Scott: And that's not because it's bad.
Scott: It's because it's just invulnerable.
Rym: Oh my god, that guy was so mad.
Rym: Whatever, you'll accept any shit thrown at you.
Rym: Mine is not the place to save those who won't save themselves.
Scott: Save me from this Twitter redesign.
Rym: This slight redesign of a few pixels, non-functional, at the top of a webpage.
Rym: You shoving bullshit down people's throats certainly doesn't make life any better.
Rym: I call bullshit when I see it.
Rym: That's who I am.
Rym: That's who I will always be.
Scott: Always be the guy who gets incredibly indignant and mad over trivial matters that are beyond your control.
Rym: I like when he sent us this quote, "Those who accept their fate find happiness.
Rym: Those who defy it
Rym: glory.".
Scott: The glory enraging futilely against the Twitter redesign.
Scott: So glorious.
Scott: Seriously, it's not even a redesign.
Scott: They inverted the color scheme.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: Wow, much hero.
Scott: So glory.
Rym: Such, such wow.
Rym: Wow.
Rym: Yeah, you'll also see me pretty much constantly making fun of Patrick Rothfuss and the King Killer Chronicle lately.
Scott: Yeah, aren't you glad that was a book?
Scott: Without it, you would have no material right now.
Rym: You see, someone recommends a book to me and I read it.
Rym: There's three possible outcomes.
Rym: The worst outcome is that it's mediocre.
Rym: If it's really good, I got a great new book to read.
Rym: If it's really bad, I get to exult in explaining exactly why it's bad.
Scott: It's a virtual boy situation.
Scott: It's like, "Yeah, I'll buy that brand new Nintendo console.
Scott: Worst case, it's a virtual
Scott: boy.".
Scott: Owning a virtual boy is pretty awesome even though it sucks.
Scott: Yeah, having read, you know, The Name of the Wind or at least partially having read it and knowing its true nature.
Scott: Yeah, it's not a good book, but having read it is like owning a virtual boy.
Scott: Now, you can make fun of it and understand when other people make fun of it.
Rym: I also realized today that it's basically about a nice guy not having sex with women until he seduces the goddess of sex and becomes a sex god for everyone except the girl he actually likes and it's so male.
Rym: Anyway, for all its problems...
Scott: I want to go back, listen to the actual book club episode we did on it.
Scott: I think, you know, we said bad things about it, but I think it's basically, even though it's not like we've reread it, but our opinion of it has just gotten worse over time.
Rym: Well, what didn't help is that it was bad, but not, like it was still enjoyable.
Rym: But then I read the second book.
Scott: I didn't read the second book.
Scott: I only heard you talking about reading the second book.
Scott: I own the second book.
Scott: It's unread.
Scott: Don't read it.
Rym: I'm not reading it.
Scott: Unless you really want to find... I think I'm just going to sell it on Amazon or something.
Rym: He has sex with so many people, but not the one girl he likes because he's a nice guy.
Rym: Nice guy.
Rym: So, I realize that the magic in this world is called sympathy.
Rym: He uses sympathy to get girls to have sex with him.
Rym: This book, and there's no way that was on purpose.
Rym: That's just, oh my god, these books.
Scott: Anyway...
Rym: So that's been my Twitter lately.
Rym: Yeah, follow our stuff on the internet.
Rym: And yeah, Otena, there's a new episode of it.
Scott: Our Otena.
Scott: This new episode of GeekNights presents Otena.
Scott: There isn't a new episode of Otena and there never will be.
Rym: If there's ever a new episode of Otena...
Scott: What the fuck would happen in that episode?
Rym: They could just do a Sailor Moon style Evangelion remake.
Scott: Oh, return to Otari?
Rym: Yes, you are not a prince.
Scott: Revolutionary girl... Matthew?
Rym: Anyway, so stakes.
Scott: Stakes?
Scott: We're not talking about the vampire kind.
Rym: Even though it's spelled the same way.
Scott: We're talking about consequences and rewards attached to winning and losing games.
Rym: I'm taking it back to a simpler time.
Rym: Time was 1987 or '88.
Scott: When you were like six years old.
Rym: I was a young kid hanging out with other young kids.
Rym: And we'd play games like Paper, Rock, Scissors.
Rym: That's a good game.
Rym: Or Run to That Tree.
Scott: Whoever touches a tree first wins.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Or loses.
Rym: And then you're trying to drag someone else over to the tree and shove them into it.
Rym: That was actually way more fun.
Rym: So, a common thing we would do is add some stakes to any game like that.
Rym: Whoever loses has to get the slick slap, is what they called it.
Scott: You lick your fingers and on the wrist, pow.
Rym: There's a technique to it.
Rym: I've realized that young people, some kids get it and some kids don't.
Scott: And that was another thing.
Scott: If you won and you got the reward of being able to slap the person you have defeated.
Scott: And you were good at it?
Scott: But you're really bad at slapping the arm.
Scott: Everyone's like, "Yeah, I let you win because what are you going to
Scott: do?".
Scott: "Oh, it didn't
Scott: hurt.".
Scott: And then if they win once, then when they do it to you, it's like,
Scott: "Ah!".
Rym: Well, you got to lick just the top bit of your fingers.
Rym: And then you got to slap it just so perfectly right on the inside of the arm.
Scott: You basically got to pretend your whole arm is a whip.
Rym: You got to move your foot like you're a pitcher in a Major League Baseball game.
Rym: So, did that add anything to our gaming?
Scott: Well, I was thinking about this recently because I was watching some Korean television.
Scott: In Korean television, they like to play all sorts of games.
Scott: Various kinds of childhood or just casual games like, "Throw the paper at the paper to make it flip
Scott: over."
Scott: Or, "Roll the
Scott: coin."
Scott: Or, "Flick the ghost stone to knock the other ghost stone off the
Scott: board.".
Scott: That sort of thing, right?
Scott: Yup.
Scott: And a common thing they will do is add punishments for the loser or rewards for the winner or both.
Rym: Like, "Eat a
Rym: lemon.".
Scott: Right, like, "Oh, whoever loses this game has to eat a lemon slice and can't spit it out.
Scott: You just got to chew it and swallow the whole
Scott: thing.".
Scott: And so suddenly, it's like, "Oh, shit.
Scott: This game
Scott: matters.".
Scott: And I was thinking when I was watching this, like, that's just a typical thing they do.
Scott: Wait a minute.
Scott: We play a lot of games with people, right?
Scott: And often, you play games with people who don't care about winning.
Scott: Because when you win, what does that mean?
Scott: You can say you won.
Scott: And if you lose, what does it mean?
Scott: You can say you lost.
Rym: Now, one could argue that that's an intrinsic reward.
Scott: And also, I'm playing a lot of Netrunners lately.
Scott: Not that I have, right?
Scott: That's news to anyone.
Scott: But at Netrunner tournaments, like, I only care about winning.
Scott: Like, being able to say, "I
Scott: won.".
Scott: Other people there, like, care about winning because they want this swag that you get when you win.
Scott: Like, I've given away most of the swag I've won.
Scott: Like, I won a playmat at the recent tournament.
Scott: It's an ugly playmat.
Scott: I like my solid black playmat that I bought for eight bucks on Amazon.
Scott: It has all these stains on it.
Scott: More than I like that one because I don't like that art.
Scott: And the guy, I was like, "Who's in second place?
Scott: Here you go,
Scott: bro.".
Scott: And he's like, "Oh my god, thank
Scott: you.".
Scott: And I'm like, "It's a fucking playmat.
Scott: It's like who gives a shit,
Scott: dude?".
Scott: Right?
Scott: I could just buy them if I wanted it that badly.
Scott: And these people are playing for the swag.
Scott: There's a reward involved.
Scott: And so I started thinking about, you know, we've done a show on gambling.
Scott: But I think gambling is only a small subset of just stakes for games in general.
Rym: And stakes in games are way more common than you think.
Rym: Look at old Magic.
Rym: I mean, Magic the Gathering had rules for putting up antis in the game.
Rym: There were cards that affected the antis.
Scott: In the original Magic the Gathering, the rule was supposed to be that you would, before playing a game, shuffle your deck randomly and pick out a card and put it to the side.
Scott: And then play Magic with the remaining cards.
Scott: So a card is randomly removed from your deck you can't play with, right?
Scott: Then whoever wins takes both cards and is now the owner of both cards.
Scott: And they even had cards in the game that said things like...
Rym: Like there were cards that were protect.
Rym: Like a bronze tablet could change.
Rym: Like you could steal a fucking card from someone and keep it.
Scott: There was that bird.
Scott: I own your card.
Rym: The jeweled bird was the card that you could swap in to protect a different card that went into the ante.
Scott: Yeah, but now they have a jeweled bird.
Rym: Yeah, which wasn't valuable until people started playing the game.
Rym: And the jeweled bird was actually super rare and expensive.
Scott: But anyway, it's like, you know, the game had stakes built in and they got rid of them, right?
Scott: Because of the way it affected play.
Scott: So it got me thinking about situations where you go to conventions.
Scott: And there's a lot of incompatibility, especially in tabletop board gaming worlds, communities, between the people who care about winning and are competitive, like us, and the people who don't care about winning.
Scott: Even in video games there's this conflict.
Scott: And those kinds of people generally can't play with each other well.
Scott: It's not a good experience.
Scott: And I was like, if you added stakes, rewards and/or punishments, right, rewards for winners, punishments for losers of some kind, could you get the people who didn't care about winning to suddenly care about winning and change their behavior so that everyone could play together, right?
Scott: Or could you use some reward or punishment to make the people who were competitive not care or at least get their behavior to change in such a way to get the games to go smoother when there were non-competitive players also playing?
Rym: So, as I've put a lot of thought into this, I don't think it actually helps.
Rym: I've read a lot of studies that show that in general if you give someone extrinsic rewards for a game or a task, like you'll win this ugly play mat if you win the tournament, people start playing for that goal and not for the intrinsic enjoyment of the game or winning itself.
Rym: I have noticed that.
Rym: Studies that show it can actually decrease your enjoyment and decrease your willingness to play the game when there is no longer an extrinsic reward.
Scott: That is the thing that I've noticed.
Scott: the most, right, is that I'll see people who will be like, "Hey,".
Scott: I'll be like, "Hey, you go to the Netrunner on
Scott: Sunday?".
Scott: They'll be like, "Do they have
Scott: prizes?".
Scott: And I'm like, "Uh, I don't know, do
Scott: they?".
Scott: And they'll be like, "It's the same prize as last time?
Scott: I don't want to
Scott: go.".
Scott: Right?
Scott: It's like they're only going to the tournament because they might, because if they don't have the prize that they want, they're not going to go.
Scott: Some other guy was seriously talking about going to Bulgaria because there was a Netrunner tournament with a 1,300 euro prize for the winner.
Scott: It's like, "But you're not going to win.
Scott: You're just going to go on a trip to Bulgaria.
Scott: Are you crazy?
Scott: What is wrong with
Scott: you?".
Scott: I mean, not that Bulgaria is not nice.
Scott: I wouldn't want to just go there.
Scott: But I'm not going there for a Netrunner tournament.
Rym: But at the same time, our friend from the example in the beginning of the show is playing only for the extrinsic reward of the money.
Rym: Or, is it more subtle?
Rym: Are there people for whom extrinsic rewards do not affect them in that same way?
Rym: I mean, I don't know much about these studies to be able to really speak to them.
Scott: And is punishment different than the reward, right?
Scott: What if we went to a Netrunner tournament and it's like, "Okay guys, whoever comes in last place has to eat a
Scott: bug."
Scott: Has to eat something nasty.
Rym: All bug.
Rym: We have this bowl of dead bugs that we found.
Scott: Would you enter that tournament?
Rym: Yeah, well there's an adventure time.
Scott: Would you enter it in the first place?
Scott: Because remember, the store wants to maximize entrance because they get an entry fee from everyone, right?
Scott: Two, if you were in that tournament, how would you play differently than if you were just playing for no stakes at all?
Rym: Oh my god, the last ante card in Magic was $19.95.
Scott: Yeah, that's about right.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: I'm old.
Rym: But I don't know.
Rym: I think if I had to guess, being not a psychologist, these kinds of rewards are only effective, or punishments, if one, they're very low stakes.
Rym: It has to be on the level of the lick and stick.
Scott: Right, that's what I'm talking about.
Scott: I was thinking, practically speaking, right?
Rym: Or the slick and slap.
Scott: Right, is that we play a lot of games, often with people who don't care about winning.
Scott: And it's like, could I get them to up their game by having some, you know, inconsequential punishment?
Scott: Something that everyone would agree to, right?
Scott: Because if you have some ridiculous punishment, like, yeah, you get, you know, smacked on the butt, then it's like, no one's gonna agree to that.
Rym: I would agree to that.
Scott: Yeah, but some people will not agree to that.
Scott: And if you actually tried to enforce it, they would not allow it, right?
Scott: And you'd just be like, fuck no, and if you did it, then you would go to jail.
Scott: But if I have a punishment like whoever loses has to take this really sour candy and grab a fistful of it and hold it in their mouth, right?
Scott: For like 20 seconds, people might agree to do that, and if they lost, would actually do it.
Rym: I've found that the best way I've gotten, because you don't come to board game nights anymore, because you're a netrunner.
Scott: No, I don't have time for that shit anymore.
Rym: Yeah, even though you're gonna miss out on some Hans and Jotonica and Ginkgopolis.
Scott: I'll play them plenty when it's time.
Rym: So, what I've found is that the best way to get someone motivated to play to win is to get them to play enough, even if they're not 100% playing to win, until they get close to victory or win a few times.
Scott: So they get a taste of it.
Rym: Yes, once they taste that blood.
Scott: When they taste the intrinsic award, they don't need an extrinsic motivator.
Scott: I mean, look at one of our- Because they realized how, like we have, how awesome it is to just win, baby.
Rym: Yep, look at some of our friends, I won't name names, they might be embarrassed, one of whom is really good at Zendo.
Rym: Once that person realized they were very good at Zendo, they suddenly tasted the blood in the water.
Rym: And I've seen that happen with a lot of our friends.
Rym: So I think that's a better way than stakes to get people to take games seriously.
Scott: That's true in general, look how demotivated the people were playing against you at Nidhogg, simply because they felt they could not win.
Scott: So they just didn't even try to win because they felt they couldn't, even though they may have wanted to originally.
Rym: I got to the point that I'd start faking it, like I would let them kill me a bunch of times, I'd let them get all the way to the edge.
Scott: They didn't have the willpower to keep trying and trying and trying, right?
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Whereas me, it took me over a year to win a Netrunner tournament, and I only won when no one really showed up.
Scott: And the people who should have beat me got in a draw, so I got lucky.
Rym: So I think stakes like that, especially these low stakes.
Scott: But the point is, I'm willing to just keep, I know what winning other games is like, and I want to win just to win.
Scott: So I keep playing no matter what, where other people would become demoralized after not winning in short order and quit.
Scott: Or they would win immediately and just keep playing because now they feel like they can win.
Rym: So it is not out of the realm to use Nidhogg as an example.
Rym: Maybe when I play against new people, I should make it feel close, but let them win a couple of games against me first, and then pull out the claws.
Scott: It's called hustling.
Rym: Yeah, here's my problem.
Rym: I've tried to actually hustle people in my life.
Scott: You know what stands in the way of hustling?
Scott: Two things, morals and pride.
Rym: Yeah, one thing stands in that way, and that's pride.
Scott: Pride only.
Rym: I tried to legit hustle some people at poker.
Rym: during that time we were trying to win that PS2.
Scott: First of all, there was another guy there who was just winning.
Rym: Yeah, well he hustled because he wormed his way into the game, lost a bunch, and then suddenly started winning every hand, and his friends used social pressure to keep other people in the game.
Scott: What did we put all our money on?
Scott: Was it red or black?
Rym: I don't remember.
Scott: We should have put it on the other one.
Scott: We would have had that PS2.
Rym: You know what we put it on?
Rym: Wrong.
Scott: That's right, we put it on wrong.
Scott: We should have put it on right.
Rym: Never been on wrong.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: There was a one out of two chance.
Scott: we could have had a PS2 right away.
Scott: We didn't.
Rym: But those low stakes like that I think only work, or at least only are not detrimental, if they're associated with games that are simple or closer to the party genre.
Rym: If you play spot it with the slap, that would probably be fine.
Rym: That would go really well.
Rym: I'd love that.
Rym: People would be really into that.
Scott: I think spot it would be better with a lemon.
Rym: A lemon might be good.
Scott: Anyone who ever left holding all the cards as to eat the lemon slice.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Or drink a shot of lemon juice.
Scott: Just 100% lemon juice.
Rym: But partly that's because the intrinsic value of winning that game is not as important.
Scott: Also, the other thing is that depending on what the punishment or reward is.
Scott: If the reward is just, say, money.
Scott: The winner enjoys the money, but no one else enjoys the reward.
Scott: The eating lemon punishment is enjoyed by all.
Scott: All players enjoy that, including the person eating the lemon.
Scott: They simultaneously enjoy and hate the punishment.
Rym: That's why the key is that the stakes have to be low enough to where getting the punishment.
Scott: If it's a punishment, they have to be low.
Scott: It's a reward.
Scott: They can be any scale.
Rym: Yes, but the punishment has to, well, if the reward is too high.
Scott: People get too serious.
Scott: It becomes serious business and people would be killing each other to get the million dollars.
Rym: Which would be fine if it's a game like Puerto Rico.
Rym: If I was playing Puerto Rico for a million dollars, that would be the best thing ever.
Scott: Go look at Major League Gaming and stuff.
Scott: The Dotads and such of the world.
Scott: The Magic Tournaments.
Scott: The kind of culture that exists there.
Scott: Where the prizes are so large.
Scott: That culture exists because the prizes are so large and those people need that money.
Scott: They're banking on that money to live because they're pro players.
Scott: Like pro poker, pro golf.
Scott: You see that kind of culture will emerge.
Scott: If the prizes are low, like in Netrunner, then you see a different culture.
Scott: Even though there's still those people who are affected by the extrinsic award.
Scott: The culture of, "I'm playing Netrunner for my life.
Scott: I'm super serious about this.
Scott: Fuck all you
Scott: guys."
Scott: Does not exist.
Scott: Everyone's just like, "Hey, good job winning.
Scott: Yeah, what's
Scott: up?".
Scott: Because they care about the prize, but don't care that much about the prize.
Scott: Because it's not ridiculous.
Rym: So the stake has to be kind of on the level of those jackass shows.
Rym: Where you're all kind of in this together.
Scott: The injury to the emergency room trip.
Rym: But that's low stakes for that group of people.
Rym: For the group that's playing, the stakes have to be low relative to the tolerances of everyone in that group.
Scott: So if you have a group of ridiculous daredevils, the punishment could be like, "Oh, you gotta skydive up to
Scott: whatever.".
Scott: Because for them, it's like, "Okay,
Scott: whatevs.".
Rym: It has to be a punishment that the person getting punished will enjoy and laugh along with.
Rym: Like that level or else it's no good.
Rym: Otherwise you're just going to further demotivate the people.
Scott: Even if I say, "Yes, I agree to play in this game and have this
Scott: punishment."
Scott: If at the end I lose and I say, "Actually, no, you're not doing that punishment to
Scott: me."
Scott: And then you do it, then I can call the police and that's a problem.
Rym: What if we signed a contract ahead of time?
Scott: I don't even know if that would fly.
Rym: I think it would depend on the nature of the punishment.
Scott: Obviously, obviously.
Rym: Eat this bug.
Scott: Yeah, if I signed a contract that said, "I will eat the bug," and then I refused to eat it, it's like, "Could you sue me for breach of
Scott: contract?"
Scott: Probably.
Rym: I'm sure some lawyer will chime in and be like, "Well...".
Scott: It's like, "You can't make me eat a fucking bug.
Scott: Really?".
Rym: Why would you sign a contract saying you'd eat a bug?
Scott: Because I thought I would do it, but then I developed a bug phobia afterwards.
Scott: When I was actually confronted with the situation, I realized I changed my mind.
Rym: So, I'm going to read for you a card from Magic that did stuff with the ante to give everyone out there an idea of what this shit was like.
Rym: It wasn't just, "Play for
Rym: keepsies.".
Rym: So, Temerian Fiends caused one colorless and two black.
Rym: It's a creature.
Rym: One, one.
Scott: So you can just play that, like, fucking the third turn of the game.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: First text, "Remove Temerian Fiends from your deck if you're not playing for
Rym: ante.".
Scott: So you can only play it if you're playing for ante.
Scott: Actually, that card is ridiculously strong because when you don't play for ante, your deck just legally got smaller by four copies.
Scott: So now you have a 56-card deck instead of a 60-card deck.
Rym: I don't know which rule would take precedence.
Rym: Right?
Rym: It might remove you below the limit and then you're just immediately disqualified.
Scott: I think that's it.
Scott: Anyway, continue.
Rym: "Spend three black mana and sacrifice Temerian
Rym: Fiends.".
Scott: Well, you already have three black mana, most likely, because you used two colorless and a black to install it.
Scott: Don't listen to this shit.
Scott: Summon it.
Scott: Sorry.
Rym: "The owner of target artifact may ante the top card of his or her library if the player does not exchange ownership of that artifact and Temerian
Rym: Fiends.".
Scott: So if someone has an artifact card, it's like, "Give me that
Scott: artifact."
Scott: To keep.
Scott: Or, "Give me the top card of your deck and...".
Rym: I'll give you the Temerian Fiends in return.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So basically it punishes anyone who plays an artifact.
Scott: that's worth a lot of money.
Scott: Oh, you're playing Alpha Magic, Black Lotus, Moxes, all artifacts.
Rym: Yeah, ante was awesome.
Scott: Yes, it was.
Scott: "Give me that Black
Scott: Lotus.".
Scott: I don't want to.
Scott: "Give me the top card of your
Scott: deck.".
Scott: Mox Emerald.
Rym: Fuck.
Scott: Oh, another Black Lotus, because you're allowed to have four, right?
Rym: Uh, yeah.
Rym: Though Black Lotus and Sol Ring and all those things were restricted to one pretty early on before they were banned.
Scott: I have a Sol Ring.
Rym: Oh, ante is strictly forbidden in DCI-sanctioned play currently.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: They banned it really early on.
Rym: In unsanctioned games, we're not prohibited by law.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: That's boring.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: Maybe we could make a game, right, to where somehow to work the ante in, right, where it's like...
Rym: I see where you're going with this.
Scott: It's more like Dominion, but you play multiple games, right?
Scott: But you still ante the game cards from the game, and then you get them back, and then you have to play another game.
Scott: So you're not anteing for the thing you're going to keep, because at the end of the day, you're shuffling all the cards back in the box, because it's a board game, right, that comes in a box.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: But you're playing multiple times with the same cards that you drafted or something.
Rym: Here's two other ways to go.
Scott: I see where you're going with this.
Scott: And by winning, you're getting your deck at least... You're changing your deck at least by getting cards added, and then you have to play again before putting the game away.
Rym: I'm branching this in two directions now.
Rym: Direction A is kind of like Risk Legacy.
Rym: If you do certain things in the game...
Scott: Oh, Dominion Legacy?
Rym: You can steal a token from someone, like Safe Cracker.
Rym: So you get the Safe Cracker token.
Rym: It has some minor effect in the game.
Rym: You can accumulate them across games, but there's still metal tokens.
Rym: I guess you could cheat by buying copies of the game.
Rym: Each game has two of them.
Rym: So buy like ten copies of the game.
Rym: Well, that's great, because I made the game anyway.
Rym: The other way I would go, which is a little more subtle.
Rym: Make a game like Netrunner that comes in a big box that has maybe a deck for everyone, and you're supposed to play for Anti with all the people who bought in on that big box.
Rym: Something like that.
Rym: Maybe it has ten decks, and you play with these decks.
Rym: Like ten friends each have a deck, and you play from your set, and that's it.
Scott: The thing is, someone would just buy one box for themselves and just make an awesome deck.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: That's why these are concept ideas.
Scott: This is why I play Netrunner.
Scott: It's perfect, right?
Scott: Everyone has every card.
Scott: Everyone can make any deck they want.
Rym: Nidhogg, everyone has every move.
Rym: You can just play whatever strategy you want to play.
Scott: It's good for the same reason, but it doesn't have the customizing, which is fun.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.