Rym: It's Tuesday, December 8th, 2015.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights Tonight.
Rym: Starwall and ResPublica.
Rym: Kind of an odd combination there.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So our friends Laura and Scott have a huge party like once or twice a year.
Rym: And we went this year over the weekend taking trains to get to and from Philly and all this business.
Rym: But something astounding happened.
Rym: Scott, our friend Chase and I, on the way home we're standing at a SEPTA station, like a light rail station, waiting for the train to take us to Philly so we could take our respective buses.
Scott: Isn't it actually a light rail?
Rym: It's more like commuter rail, I guess.
Scott: But it's just.
Scott: the train isn't very long.
Rym: I mean, you know what it's like?
Scott: It's a full-size train.
Rym: It's like a slow metro north.
Scott: Didn't go that slow.
Rym: It went slow until it got out of the one-track area, at least.
Rym: So we're standing there.
Rym: It's like this train would fuck you up if it hit you.
Scott: I mean, there is no train on earth, even the lightest rail.
Rym: An HO-scale train would not fuck you up if it hit you.
Scott: Dude, it would still hurt if it hit your foot.
Scott: You'd be like, "Ow,
Scott: fuck.".
Rym: So we're standing there.
Scott: Especially if it's going full speed.
Rym: And Chase points out and says, "Hey, isn't that car stopped on the train
Rym: tracks?".
Rym: And we look up and sure enough, there's this woman sitting in a car, just parked on the train tracks, waiting to turn left or whatever.
Scott: Well, yeah, because it's like you pull out.
Scott: People pull out into the intersection to make a left.
Scott: They block the box and then they go.
Scott: And in the city, when you block the box, well, you're in the box.
Scott: But in the suburbs, usually you block the box and the light turns green and then you go.
Scott: And the train comes by.
Scott: how often?
Scott: It's like you don't really believe it.
Rym: Except those trains came by every 20-ish minutes.
Rym: Actually, less than 20 minutes because there's one one way and then one the other way.
Scott: Yeah, but I guess, you know, when you drove your car everywhere, how often, when you came across a train crossing, was there actually a train?
Rym: Still often, but I grew up in a place in the Midwest where there's a lot of freight tracks that just go across the street.
Scott: I mean, I think I've waited in my car for trains to go by maybe like three times ever, maybe only twice.
Rym: All right, I waited for a train almost once a week.
Rym: That's just where I grew up.
Rym: And the septic trains, they're going like pretty often.
Rym: But so anyway, this woman sitting there and she's like, "Hey, wouldn't it be funny if she's got hit by the
Rym: train?".
Rym: And we were just being jerks and laughing.
Scott: Just kind of hoping she would get hit by the train.
Rym: And then we hear the train noises.
Rym: And then the gate comes down behind her and the other gate comes down.
Rym: The train's coming and she's just sitting there like fucking around on her phone.
Rym: So I'm like walking over, kind of like, because it's like right there.
Rym: And I see bit by bit like everyone on the train.
Scott: I'm getting my phone ready so we can get some world stuff.
Rym: Everyone on the train platform is like kind of watching like, "Oh, what's going
Rym: on?".
Rym: A bunch of people nearby start honking.
Rym: She still doesn't notice.
Rym: Finally, I hear somewhere near her says, "What the
Rym: fuck?".
Rym: Start screaming at her.
Rym: And suddenly she looks up and looks at the train.
Rym: And the train is blaring its horn at this point and bearing down on her.
Scott: And she's stopping.
Rym: She floors it suddenly after she like freaks out, drives through, stops, and then looks around and then drives away, probably embarrassed, as fast as she can.
Scott: I mean, you know, in the Scott world, you lose your driver's license forever.
Scott: Never allowed to drive again ever anywhere.
Scott: And also you wouldn't have been allowed to drive in the first place because you wouldn't have passed the driving test.
Rym: So Lady gets a couple of strikes for that.
Rym: But what makes the story astounding is that 100% of the trains that came by had a similar thing happen.
Scott: You mean the one other train that came by?
Rym: Yes, two trains.
Rym: The next train that came, the train that we were going to ride on, comes up, and again, there was a car stopped, and the gate comes down behind him, doesn't notice right away, and then floors it and gets out of the way.
Rym: But he did get out of the way like 30 seconds earlier than the other Lady did.
Rym: I was pretty much expecting to have to run over there and see if someone was alive.
Scott: Yet another reason not to live in the suburbs.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Cities only.
Scott: Also this city only.
Rym: It was just remarkable to me that 100% of the trains that were coming by almost hit a car because people don't know how to drive in Pennsylvania.
Scott: I'm telling you, the problem is that people can basically skirt the edge of danger without actually getting punished, right?
Scott: It's sort of like if you're standing on top of a mountain, or maybe a mesa, right?
Scott: It's flat on top.
Scott: You can be safe standing in the middle, and you can be safe tap-dancing on the edge as long as you don't actually fall.
Scott: Nothing bad will happen to you.
Scott: So then people just tap-dance on the edge all the fucking time.
Rym: But it's not just that.
Rym: It's people tap-dancing on the edge who have never had a tap-dancing lesson.
Scott: Sure, and what we should do is if someone's tap-dancing on the edge, we should not allow them to get lucky and not fall.
Scott: We should just push everyone who is standing on the edge.
Rym: I would not push them.
Rym: I would pull them back, put a little fence and say, "You can't go past the fence
Rym: anymore.".
Scott: That works too, but shooting them with a gun, it's like...
Rym: Okay, all right.
Scott: If you want to skirt death, then make the consequences go from low... When there's a situation...
Rym: The actual technical term for this is "shaking hands with
Rym: danger.".
Scott: Right.
Scott: We should basically, when someone is shaking hands with danger, we should make it so that 100% of the time they get bit.
Scott: Then people will stop shaking hands with danger because they know that getting bit is a guaranteed thing and not some, "Oh, I'll be safe this
Scott: time.".
Rym: So I would argue that if we go your way, then everyone who gets bit dies and there's no one who survives to tell the tale of the barbarian who came and killed everyone.
Scott: That's not true.
Scott: For example, people always hold the subway doors open, and I'm like, "Let's just put buzz saws on the inside of the subway
Scott: doors.".
Scott: So if you put your hand in there, you lose your hand.
Rym: Scott, this is where you...
Scott: Nobody will friggin' put their hand in there.
Rym: This is where you are an extremist, and I am merely a radical, because you say buzz saws, I say tasers.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: What's wrong with the buzz saw?
Rym: I would just go back to the old subway doors.
Rym: that would literally crush you.
Scott: But crushing delays the train.
Scott: The buzz saw means the train can just go with your hand on board.
Rym: You know, I did notice today, I thought about something...
Scott: Or your body on board and your hand on the platform.
Rym: Today, because the 7 train was delayed, so the entire platform was full of people, so I thought of something that I never really... Like, I don't think of consciously, because I'm used to living in New York, because I'm standing on the edge of the platform.
Rym: And the train's coming, and of course, I'm just like, "The platform's completely full of people.
Rym: I can't
Rym: move.".
Rym: And the train's going by at a high speed, like two inches away from my face.
Rym: And I was just standing there reading the Kindle.
Scott: That's why I don't stand in the yellow area.
Rym: Yeah, but I kind of had to.
Rym: I couldn't have gotten on the train.
Scott: Get on the next one.
Rym: There was trouble.
Rym: I would not have been home if I had not forced my way onto that train.
Rym: Don't take that train.
Scott: Use a different one.
Rym: I tap dance on the edge of the Mesa, but I have at least had a few tap dancing lessons.
Rym: Or at least, I continue to tap dance safely.
Rym: You just keep going skiing.
Scott: You know what?
Rym: I have never parked my car on fucking train tracks.
Rym: But you go skiing.
Rym: That's pretty much the same.
Rym: I feel like rule one of driving a car is anytime you stop it, just look to the left and just see if you're on train tracks.
Rym: At least make sure.
Rym: Just make sure your hand is not in a toaster.
Scott: I mean, I never had to look left to see if I'm on train tracks because I look ahead and see railroad crossing signs and I don't go across.
Rym: But at least you went through.
Rym: You have this mental model of, "Alright, I'm stopping my car.
Rym: Am I on train tracks?
Rym: No.".
Rym: So anyway, got any gaming news?
Scott: I do have a gaming news.
Scott: If you don't know, it's Hanukkah.
Scott: Oh shit.
Scott: Time for some light festivals or magic oils and latkes, which is the real oil.
Rym: The real magical oil.
Rym: There's a menorah over the entrance to my building.
Rym: It had white lights when I came in this morning.
Rym: And then when I left, it was the same menorah with blue lights.
Scott: That's nice.
Scott: Cool fancy menorah.
Scott: Anyway, I don't know how much everyone listening knows about Jewishness, but on Hanukkah, there's actually a game that goes with Hanukkah, unlike a lot of other holidays, which don't have their own games.
Scott: Hanukkah has an official game, which is great for nerds, and the game is dreidel.
Scott: And what is dreidel?
Scott: If you don't know, it's a top, like you spin it.
Rym: It's a D4.
Rym: In Mega Man 3.
Rym: It's a four-sided die.
Scott: It's effectively a D4.
Scott: And basically, the way it works is you have some pool of chips or goodies or candy or guilt or whatever it is.
Rym: Just actual money.
Scott: Actual whatever.
Scott: And when you spin it, if you get a gimel, which is G, you fucking get everything, right?
Scott: If you get hay, you get half.
Scott: If you get nun, you get bupkis.
Scott: And if you get the other one-- What's the other one?
Scott: Shin, maybe?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I think it's shin.
Scott: You lose half, right?
Scott: So it's really, in the words of our friend Joshua, dreidel is an awful game.
Rym: Like, I'd rather play Monopoly.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So-- It's on the level of war.
Scott: So he made this post, and it says, let's fix dreidel.
Scott: Jewish game designers, let's get on this.
Rym: This is so great.
Scott: So here's the rules for the fixing dreidel, I guess.
Scott: I don't even know if this is a contest, but here's the rules for designing a game to fix dreidel.
Scott: So the dreidel has to be in the name of the game, and it has to feature the dreidel centrally, if not entirely.
Scott: It has to be playable with a reasonable number of dreidels from one to, I don't know, a dozen or something.
Scott: The number you might have in your box of Hanukkah stuff.
Scott: It has to obey all the mitzvah and the minhagim.
Rym: Regarding the chag.
Rym: Chag?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So basically, if you don't know the-- What's drash?
Scott: OK.
Scott: So let's say you're a rabbi.
Scott: OK?
Scott: And somebody asks you a rabbi kind of question.
Rym: A rabbi, can I eat this kind of thing on this particular-- Well, more like rabbi.
Scott: Why do we-- what is the meaning behind this particular thing?
Rym: I'm thinking of a Simpsons not rabbi.
Rym: Should I buy a Ford or a Chevy?
Scott: Right.
Scott: No, not that kind of rabbi.
Scott: So basically, what the rabbi will do is, depending on who you are, he'll give you a different kind of explanation.
Scott: Right?
Scott: There's the explanation that he would give to somebody who's an intelligent adult, knows a lot of Torah shit, the real explanation.
Scott: And then there's the explanation for the common person that he's going to give, probably to someone who only comes on the high holiday or a goyim.
Rym: It's like the science equivalent of wash your hands because I said so versus wash your hands because they're covered in bacteria.
Scott: Yes, exactly.
Scott: So basically, you've got to have some religious action going on, some meaning to your game related to Hanukkah.
Rym: So what's chag?
Rym: What's chag?
Scott: I'm not sure.
Scott: So anyway, one of them is-- I don't know.
Scott: Anyway, use only things that a family is likely to have around on Hanukkah.
Rym: Already burning candles, oil lamps, drunk adults.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It has to be playable by everyone.
Scott: You can't be having some game the little kids can't play.
Rym: Anyone old enough to clumsily spin a dreidel.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It has to be playable by someone who's smart and someone-- it can't be like a game where it's-- the kids can play, but the adults are like, oh my god.
Rym: Quote, "Mature kids who can develop strategies, weigh risks, and do other mature adult-like
Rym: behaviors.".
Scott: Be playable by adults of a much shorter attention span than kids and need to be entertained with systems like deal-making, ribald puns, cost-benefit analysis, and drinking.
Scott: It has to be a public domain game.
Scott: So this prize is here.
Scott: First prize, in retrospect, centuries from now, this will be how everyone has always played dreidel.
Scott: It will be an obvious Minhag that every child learns.
Scott: Second prize, in retrospect, centuries from now, this will be how everyone has always played dreidel, but everyone knows that lots of people play it wrong.
Scott: So yeah, if you can design a game around dreidel, or any game you can design for D4s and put on a Hanukkah theme is going to meet the criteria.
Rym: I mean, think of it this way.
Rym: The best way to prove your mettle as a game designer is to set some arbitrary constraints and try to make a simple game that meets a bunch of parameters within those constraints.
Scott: So, dreidel game design contest.
Rym: I expect good ideas in the forum.
Rym: I want to see what you guys come up with.
Scott: I can't come up with anything.
Rym: I kind of came up with a role-playing game, but it's like a cut-down version of the sword that uses D4.
Scott: Can't be a role-playing game.
Rym: Why not?
Scott: A role-playing game doesn't, you can't do that.
Rym: Why can't it be?
Scott: It's some one person drew to Maccabee, the other person.
Rym: Still working out the details.
Rym: So, in other news, this is kind of relevant to GeekNights and also gaming in a general sense.
Rym: So, this article talks about how linguists have identified an accent or a dialect or some combination.
Rym: that seems to exist pretty much entirely on YouTube and Twitch channels, which in retrospect makes a lot of sense, because there was a lot of evidence that once TV became standard, I mean, that's when the standard American Midwestern generic neutral accent became the media accent, because suddenly, as TV became more and more national, most people were hearing voices on a regular basis that were like this default, like you sort of melded together with a generic accent.
Rym: So, unless you have a very strong regional accent that you also hear, you'll eventually drift toward this common one, like generation over generation.
Rym: The internet is interesting in that communities of people are continuously sharing podcasts and YouTube videos and Let's Plays, and this article talks about what the YouTube accent looks like, and it's kind of fascinating, because Scott and I both do a lot of these things, as do most of our podcaster friends, almost every Let's Play person I've ever seen who's popular, and actually Crash Course, all those guys.
Rym: They do this so close to the way it's described that it's uncanny.
Rym: So, I'd recommend you read this.
Rym: I mean, this is what it comes down to, and you can read the article, look at all the details, there's a bunch of follow-up stories and everything, but the components are, one, over-stressed vowels.
Rym: So, like, instead of making a schwa, you'll say the syllables, and the vowel syllables, at least, very strongly in words you say.
Rym: You won't kind of "eh" the syllables.
Rym: Like, exactly, instead of exactly, or exactly.
Rym: Like, you'll stress all those bits along the way.
Rym: Sneaking extra vowels in between consonants.
Rym: So, instead of trapping, they'll actually, you'll hear the sort of terrapping, you'll hear this "eh" coming in, like splitting up the bits.
Rym: There's technical terms for all this, but I don't know shit about linguistics, so I'm not even going to try.
Rym: A lot more long vowels, long consonants as well, and actually, lots of aspiration and plosives.
Rym: So, people who need pop filters tend to be the kinds of people who do this accent by default.
Rym: And it's interesting, because the accent, it was described variously as intellectual used car salesman voice, or educated carnival barker.
Rym: But, after I read this article, I went and watched a whole bunch of let's plays and everything, and I started hearing it, I started noticing it, I started hearing it in both of us.
Rym: And it seems like what this accent does is it creates this sense that the person speaking knows more about what they're talking about than they might, that they're speaking-- I thought that that's any accent from the UK, but only when used in the US.
Rym: Ah, that is also true.
Rym: But it also includes enough patter and padding and things-- Except for chav accents.
Scott: And pikey, where no one understands what you're saying.
Rym: The conversation sort of keeps going, and pregnant pauses are not interrupted by someone expecting to ask a question or talk to you, but get that TED Talk style sort of like, "The pause means what they just said was really
Rym: profound.".
Rym: And I just think this is fascinating, and I encourage you all to read this, and if you're going to do a podcast and you don't have radio training, I don't know, just read this article and try to do those things and listen to what other people do.
Scott: I don't think this is something you can do constantly, I mean, consciously.
Scott: I think the way you acquire this is just by watching a lot of YouTube and then making a lot of YouTube, and it'll happen without you even knowing it happens.
Rym: Will kids growing up watching Let's Plays all the time have that accent more so than their parents' accent?
Scott: Just in everyday life?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: They're all trying to sell each other?
Scott: Talk to the teacher in Carl's salesman voice?
Scott: "Step right up, check this homework care, I got an A+ coming
Scott: through.".
Rym: But it's also that it's an accent that typically in the past was only seen in people who are lecturing to an audience, but now that that sort of lecturing-to-an-audience style is so common in pop culture...
Scott: No, the only time you'll talk to people is to lecture to them.
Rym: Oh yeah, that's true.
Scott: Otherwise you'll just type at them if it's a conversation.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day!
Rym: This is just an animated gif, but it is so delicious.
Scott: I mean, it's a good gif, but Rym is going way crazy over it.
Rym: As you watch this, imagine that the rocket, in fact, has sentience and a malevolent intelligence and that it has decided to do this of its own will.
Rym: Because it's just a bottle rocket.
Scott: It's not a bottle rocket, it's a model rocket.
Rym: It's like a model rocket, but dude, it just hits the igniter, and just as he's hit it, it starts falling over.
Scott: That igniter chord is way shorter than we used to use.
Scott: We used to use way longer ones.
Rym: But it's falling forward, directly toward him, just as he has ignited it.
Rym: And there's the moment of "oh
Rym: shit.".
Scott: I think what's actually happening is that the chord is so short, he pulled on the remote, which is what pulled it towards him.
Rym: Yeah, but there's no motion there, unless it was cut off before the gif.
Scott: You can't see the chord because it's so low res.
Rym: But his hands do not move.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: It might have just fallen.
Rym: I mean, I've had model rockets fall just because...
Scott: It's definitely possible.
Scott: It doesn't matter.
Scott: The point is, it hit him in the butt.
Rym: Yes, the sublime moment of, there's the parapetia, where he realizes what is happening immediately, and is doing what any human being would do, and then the rocket reaches out and just bops him on the butt.
Scott: Get a longer chord next time.
Rym: Hey, some of the model rockets I had back in the day, before I had an electric ignition system, you'd light a fucking fuse.
Scott: I've never used a non-electric ignition system for a model rocket.
Scott: The electric ones came later.
Scott: For a model rocket, I've never used a non-electric one.
Rym: Were you a Quest kid or an Estes kid?
Scott: I never did it myself.
Scott: I always did it at summer camp or school or whatever, right?
Scott: So whatever they bought.
Scott: So sometimes it was one, and sometimes it was the other.
Scott: At nerd summer camp, it was the best, because they just had the catalogs fucking there.
Scott: And the way it would work is, first, you'd have to go in and make some shitty little wizard rocket to prove that you could make a rocket.
Rym: That basically involves literally glue a tube to some fins, stick a cone in the top, tie one string between the inside.
Scott: I was painting it, right?
Scott: But anyway.
Rym: Spray paint.
Scott: So once you made the wizard and proved that you could make a rocket.
Rym: Actually, the wizard came pre-painted, I think.
Scott: No, it didn't.
Scott: Not this one.
Scott: Anyway, once you made a wizard, right?
Scott: I don't know if it was actually a kit, right?
Rym: It's not the wizard.
Rym: The wizard's the famous Estes rocket.
Scott: Right, but the point is, it was basically, right?
Scott: They didn't... It was like a model rocket hut, and they just had tons and tons of fucking supplies.
Scott: No, no.
Rym: You're right.
Rym: You have to paint it and then put the decals on it.
Scott: Right, but they didn't give you the kit.
Scott: You just basically made... You took a cardboard tube that was wizard-sized, and you took some fins out of the box, right?
Scott: They didn't have kits.
Scott: They just had stuff.
Scott: So you made the rocket, right?
Scott: And once you've leveled up enough, you know, making different rockets, they would let you just sort of do whatever the fuck you wanted, as long as they would look at your plan and be like, "Okay, you can do that.
Scott: That's not going to kill
Scott: anybody.".
Rym: Three stages, three G engines each, metal nose cone.
Scott: Right, so then, twice during camp, right?
Scott: At the end of the eight-week camp, at the end of the fourth week and the end of the eighth week, they would do model rocket day, where everyone would just sit on the lawn and launch every rocket.
Scott: And at the beginning of the day, no one would go, because it was just like wizard, wizard, wizard, wizard, wizard, right?
Scott: But then, once he got past lunchtime, it was like, "All right, Johnny's two stages
Scott: coming.".
Scott: And you'd see they'd have all the rockets set up on the lawn that were waiting to launch.
Scott: And you would see, like, at the end of the line, this kid had one that was like a one-foot circumference tube.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: And he's just like, "You're just waiting for the good
Scott: shit.".
Rym: Depending on where you grew up, engines went up to G instead of just D. Oh, yeah.
Scott: I mean, this is in the middle of nowhere Pennsylvania summer camp of nerds.
Scott: So, like, some kids would make ones that had, like, not stages, but, like, a bundle of four rockets at the bottom.
Rym: Yup, I made some of those.
Rym: I made one that was multiple stage with that.
Scott: You had people, like, a double parachute set up going on, all kinds, you know, fins in the middle.
Rym: I lost three-quarters of any of the rockets I ever made.
Scott: Right, you know, but that was a good day.
Scott: Anyway, my thing of the day.
Scott: So, sometimes at a sporting event, you know, there's people on the field, especially when it's a televised sporting event or rink or court or whatever field of play, who have microphones on them for various reasons.
Scott: Maybe they're communicating with their coaches or other players.
Scott: Maybe they're, you know, maybe they're refs and they need to talk to the whole, you know, people in attendance.
Scott: or they need to talk to the television.
Scott: or maybe they just mic'd up some players, you know, so they can hear the quarterback going, like, "Blue 22," whatever.
Scott: And on occasion, intentionally or unintentionally, you hear things on those microphones, being a spectator, either in the stands or at home watching on television, that you were not supposed to hear, you, you know, shouldn't be hearing or are unusual to hear because you're not on the field of play.
Scott: That's not a place that you experience as a spectator.
Rym: Not like one fan just happens to be close to one of the mics and, like, you hear that guy yell a lot.
Scott: No, things the players, refs or coaches are saying.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Now, this happens relatively frequently.
Scott: There was an incident very recently at an ice hockey game.
Scott: And here, my thing of the day, is a compilation video of some of the best times that this has happened over the years.
Scott: And it's a very recently made video, so it includes that very recent incident.
Scott: Actually, quite a few incidents from just the past few weeks, as well as many from over the years.
Rym: Many classics.
Scott: I've seen, I'd already seen about at least more than half of these, but there were still some that were new to me.
Scott: I imagine most will be new to you.
Rym: In the meantime, the Book Club was the wheel of time.
Rym: I'm on, like, book seven.
Rym: I know stuff.
Scott: I stopped reading, and I did not pick up since we last mentioned.
Rym: Yup, so I'll probably do a new book club soon, but might just burn through the rest of these books.
Rym: Like, I'm kind of just churning through them at this point.
Scott: You're not even halfway done, even if I said.
Rym: I know, but at the same time.
Scott: Aren't there, like, 13 books or something like that?
Rym: 14, I think?
Scott: Okay.
Scott: So I'm about halfway.
Rym: I just got to kill time before the next Prince of Nothing book comes out.
Scott: Must have killed time, boy.
Rym: Can I get five bucks to go get loaded?
Rym: So, we can officially announce we have at least two panels at PAX South 2016.
Scott: And I'm definitely going because I bought a plane ticket, and I reserved a hotel room, and man is it cheap.
Rym: Yeah, it is cheaper from us in New York to go to PAX South, like, in total, than it is to go to PAX East in Boston.
Scott: Well, not if you count the time, but, you know, the money cost.
Rym: Yeah, the cost of the flights, not much more than Amtrak to Boston.
Rym: Hotel, less than half what it costs for a hotel in Boston.
Scott: PAX South, as far as I know, is not sold out.
Rym: It is not.
Scott: As the other PAX's are, so it's like, if you want to go to PAX, and you can't go to East or Prime or whatever, even if you frickin' live in Seattle or Boston, it'll probably be cheaper for you to go.
Rym: Also, that convention center is great.
Rym: There's great food there.
Scott: It's okay, it's not great, it's okay.
Rym: I'll put it this way, if I were running a convention... The food is decent.
Rym: It's better than PAX East food.
Rym: I would rather have it in that facility, if I could have the facility independent of the things around it, than any of the convention centers in Boston.
Scott: Uh, sure.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But anyway, on Saturday, January 30th at 1pm in the Bobcat Theater, we are doing Atari game design.
Rym: And on Sunday...
Scott: That's Rims idea.
Rym: January 31st at 1pm in the Bobcat Theater, the exact same time and place the next day.
Rym: Designing game rules.
Scott: Alrighty.
Rym: It's gonna be good stuff.
Rym: I may or may not be on a third panel without Scott, because Scott doesn't care about the topic, but that is to be seen.
Rym: If that happens, it'll be Saturday after the Atari game design panel.
Scott: I'll be playing games the rest of the time.
Rym: We're gonna get MAGFest between the two of us.
Rym: We're on like six or seven panels.
Rym: I assume PAX East, Anime Boston, PAX Prime, and then pack around.
Rym: And of course, the Patreon is still live.
Rym: We're getting close to our first stretch goal.
Scott: So, uh, yeah.
Scott: That's all you.
Rym: Keep pushing, guys.
Rym: And submissions are open for the December Q&A.
Rym: And we already got three questions, two of which are really good questions.
Rym: And also I learned...
Scott: The third is not a good question?
Scott: Eh.
Rym: So here's what I've learned so far.
Rym: Everyone who has asked a question has seen Monty Python and the Holy Grail, and most of them have memorized the script.
Scott: I'm just curious.
Scott: How do we know this?
Rym: 'Cause they said so.
Rym: They might be lying.
Rym: I put a poll question into each one of these.
Scott: But what nerd hasn't seen it?
Rym: I'm curious.
Rym: And two, you know the red envelope, white envelope thing you suggested?
Rym: Literally no one who has submitted a question knows what the fuck I'm talking about.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: So that tells us that people who are our Patreon patrons either don't go to PAX's...
Scott: They don't even watch PAX on Twitch.
Rym: Or if they go to PAX, they don't go to the keynote and the Q&A.
Rym: Like, they don't know.
Scott: They don't know.
Rym: Yeah, 'cause the... Or they haven't gone recently.
Rym: The poll choice I put was, "Is this a red envelope
Rym: question?".
Rym: And the answer choices are yes, no, WTF is a red envelope question.
Scott: We haven't had a red envelope question.
Scott: It would be hard to ask one.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, those are questions...
Scott: What red envelope question could you even ask me?
Rym: I could think of ones they could ask us.
Rym: that would be pressing and stuff about family, about diseases and illness, about tragedies.
Rym: What do you want to know?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I don't want to know.
Rym: I'm saying someone might have a weird...
Scott: What does anyone want to know?
Rym: I mean, the thing is, we don't have kids, so it's not like... A lot of people, when they ask Mike and Jerry the red envelope questions, it's always something intimate about raising your kids.
Scott: Right, so the answer is either, "Okay, I'll tell you," or, "Mind your own fucking
Scott: business.".
Scott: That's the answer, so you can't red envelope me.
Rym: You were the one who said, "We should have a red envelope, white envelope system,".
Rym: so I did it.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And so far, they're all.
Rym: WTF is a red envelope.
Rym: So, at this party that I talked about before, the aforementioned party, after which we almost saw the people die in their cars hit by trains, the king of the day, other than board games, was local multiplayer games on an HTPC.
Rym: Like, that shit was rocking for the entire party without cease.
Scott: Yes, I mean, this isn't someone who owns a X-Bone or PS4, right?
Scott: And neither do I.
Rym: He has a GameCube and a Wii, but no one was playing those.
Scott: No Wii U, right?
Scott: Their DSs weren't coming out for whatever reason.
Rym: I asked if I was to bring my DS, but I realized that no one ever wants to play Smash with me.
Rym: No one ever wants to play Advance Wars with me.
Rym: No one wants to play Mario Kart with me.
Scott: No one wants to play Dr.
Scott: Mario with me.
Rym: I'll play that with you if you'll play any of those other games with me.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, well then.
Scott: So, and, you know, all the good multiplayer-type games are Wii GameCube types for local multiplayer.
Scott: When we're limited to the selection of Steam, and these, you know, I mean, we didn't try the entire Steam library of local co-op games, but so many of the games were two-player local co-ops, so those are ruled out, you know?
Rym: Or local multiplayer, not necessarily co-op.
Scott: Right, because otherwise you could play, like, Rocket League, or you could play Resident Evil.
Scott: Like, there's a lot of two-player co-op Resident Evils.
Scott: Like, I think all of them since five are local, right?
Rym: But if you have, like, if you want four people to play a game together, there's a lot of options on Steam, and most of them are not good games.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Even if they're competitive or cooperative, it didn't really matter.
Scott: Local multiplayer games with more than two players in the Steam library were hard to come by, and when we did find them, they were often bad.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: Now, half of them were bad because the games were bad, and half were bad because they just, like, didn't support controllers right, or the menus were incomprehensible, or just the game wouldn't go full screen, or all sorts of weird nonsense.
Rym: But, two games stood out.
Scott: I mean, we just, opening up Long Live the Queen, and just discussing as we played was more fun than many of these actual multiplayer games.
Rym: Even though we didn't make it, I was interested to go down the road of let's be a badass swordswoman.
Scott: Never gone down that road before.
Scott: We failed every single test except for the one.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: So, the one game that basically lasted about half the party, and we've already talked about it, is the Jackbox Games.
Rym: That is like...
Scott: We did a whole episode on them.
Scott: They're still great.
Scott: They're always great.
Rym: That is Party Game A++++.
Scott: And everything else was not A++.
Rym: Though, I just want to point out, almost everyone who's playing the Jackbox Games was, like, super into it and loving it, but there was one person, and I won't name a name or anything, this person was playing, I think, Fibbage.
Rym: And halfway through, they were uncomfortable and did not like the game and were hoping it would end and never wanted to play it again, were really salty about playing it.
Rym: What?
Rym: Which was interesting.
Scott: How could you be salty playing Fibbage?
Rym: I don't know, but there was someone who was very salty about Fibbage, and there were a couple people who I overheard got a little salty about the Drawful one because they can't draw, which is weird.
Scott: I can't draw either.
Rym: Not only can I not draw, I negative draw.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And yet, that game was great, but I digress.
Rym: That was 50% of the play.
Rym: The other half was Starwall.
Rym: People were going crazy about this game.
Scott: Well, Starwall is a game I knew about a long time ago, mostly because, I don't know where I saw it on the internet, but I remember sending it to Rym when I discovered it.
Scott: Like, "Hey, Gnarwals, check this game.
Scott: Why don't you play this
Scott: game?".
Scott: I didn't know anything about it.
Scott: Other than that, it was one of those indie, local multiplayer type of games.
Rym: It's Gnarwals plus Nidhogg.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, now that we played it, we finally got around to playing it at this party.
Rym: So, this game, people kept rotating in and out playing it for hours and hours and hours and hours and hours, yelling and screaming and disrupting the German board games we were trying to play.
Scott: I played it a bit, and it was fun for a bit, but then I was done with it.
Rym: I'm not done with it.
Rym: I really like it.
Rym: And I kind of got good at it the more I played it.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, it's clearly a game where you can get good at it.
Scott: There is some skill going on.
Scott: But it's like the skill ramp was like... It seemed like the skill ramp wasn't a bad ramp, poorly shaped, but it said like the first bunch of steps were not steps of learning skills, but instead dealing with controls that are intentionally bad or... I actually don't think... Some combination of intentionally and accidentally bad.
Rym: It's interesting because I actually don't think they're bad.
Rym: I think they're very intuitive.
Rym: What I noticed was people who kept asking like, "How do I turn?
Rym: How do I move?
Rym: How do I
Rym: whatever?".
Rym: Couldn't understand the game and wanted someone to explain how to move.
Scott: It's asteroids controls, but they're wobbly and limited.
Rym: Well, what it is, is that you can kind of direct your narwhal.
Rym: Star wall, I guess.
Rym: And you can hold A to kind of accelerate.
Rym: And if you wiggle your body right, you can kind of go faster.
Rym: You've just got your sword point on the end of your narwhal, and you're trying to stab the other narwhals in the heart.
Scott: Right, so I didn't realize the heart part right away.
Scott: We didn't like study the rule.
Scott: We just started playing immediately.
Scott: And I thought I just had to stab other narwhals.
Scott: I didn't realize there was this heart I had to stab.
Rym: I've noticed a lot of people who are bad at laser tag have the same problem.
Rym: They think, because they don't know how anything works in the world, that you just shoot the other person.
Rym: Like, they don't realize you have to shoot that one spot on their body pack.
Scott: That actually can detect that they got shot, yeah.
Scott: Right, but this, it wasn't that I, you know, was too dumb.
Scott: It's just I didn't see it.
Scott: And I just lost, and I'm like, "Why did I
Scott: lose?".
Rym: That's kind of an aside, because I noticed something.
Rym: The games where you had to look at the controls and like really think about them, or you could not play at all, tended to be the worst of the games we tried on Steam.
Rym: And the games like this where, like, you could pretty much play it okay by looking at zero rules.
Scott: I mean, as soon as someone told me about the heart, I was like, "Oh, okay, I didn't need any more rules
Scott: explanations.".
Scott: Yeah, the rest was intuitive.
Rym: I mean, basically, you fly around, and it's all around using the physics and dueling and trying to, like, maneuver yourself to where you can hit the narwhal in their heart without getting hit yourself.
Scott: With your narwhal pointy-toothed.
Rym: Yeah, which is extra interesting because your heart's only on one side of your body and you're playing in a two-dimensional space where you can kind of rotate freely.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Now, the one thing that I found out as we played that was kind of annoying is that when you start the game, your narwhal is facing either to the left or to the right, depending on your spawn location.
Scott: And you can never flip your narwhal to face the other way ever.
Rym: Which I think is fine.
Scott: Well, I mean, it's not necessarily good or bad.
Rym: The game is a four-player or a two-player game.
Rym: Never play this three-player.
Scott: If you play with three players, you'll have two, perhaps left-facing narwhals and one right-facing one.
Rym: But as we've talked about in the past, three-player competitive games that are not races are usually bullshit.
Rym: Right.
Rym: And this would have that same problem.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But, I mean, so if it's two-on-two, though, but then you've got these different, you've got, like, three different ending situations, right?
Scott: You've got the lefty-lefty, the righty-righty, and the mixed, you know, final confrontation between two narwhals.
Rym: But it also means... It also means that two of the narwhals favor one area of the board and two of the narwhals favor another area of the board.
Rym: Right.
Scott: Now, the reason for this, if your narwhal was symmetrical, then it wouldn't matter.
Scott: But your heart is on the bottom of your narwhal, which means if you flip, if you're a right-facing narwhal, that means, so you're facing to the right, you can hit people to the right, and your heart is on the ground, because there's gravity on most of the maps.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, just relatively, that's a protected position when you're facing to the right.
Scott: If you flip over because you want to stab someone to your left, then, suddenly, your heart is facing up and is exposed.
Scott: So, that's why there's a righty-lefty thing going on.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: But the thing is, you can't, well, one, I would say, I'd give strategy or talk about, like, "Oh, well, you can't just lay there because then you won't
Rym: win.".
Scott: Obviously, you can't just lay there.
Scott: It'd be really dumb.
Rym: But, the game does something very well.
Rym: It has the old Atari Ortho game thing, where there are a million different modes.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: And some of them are better than others.
Scott: And the maps are different.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: There's a ton of different maps.
Rym: So, the game is always just novel enough to keep anyone who's playing it casually from getting good enough to dominate everyone else and have the air hockey problem.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You can play stock.
Scott: You can play time.
Scott: You could, like, I was getting a lot of kills, but I was losing because I was, you know, in my offensiveness, I was also taking hits.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: And I'd be like, "The second one left alive at the end," and then I'd lose, but I had, like, most kills or second most kills.
Scott: Well, there's a most kills mode that doesn't care how many times you die, of course, except for the fact that when you die, you're giving someone else a kill.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: To just distribute your deaths evenly among your opponents.
Rym: But, in hours and hours and hours of people playing, there were two people who played a lot more than everyone else.
Scott: And they did get better than everyone else, showing that there was definitely skill involved.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: That could be learned and practiced.
Rym: I like the game a lot, actually.
Rym: And I kind of want to get it, because I think it's a good game to play idly while you're waiting for other people to come and play a game.
Scott: I think it's an okay party game, but it's not so great that I would play it on my own, or want to play it, or...
Rym: I kind of want to play it on my own to become good enough at it to do the Nidhogg.
Scott: Sure, you can do that if you want, but... It's not strong enough to interest me, because it's just, like, the depth really isn't there.
Rym: I think the depth is there, and you're just not going to invest in it.
Rym: It's like Smash Brothers.
Scott: Definitely not investing.
Rym: Are you, like, focus cancel or whatever nonsense in Smash Brothers?
Scott: No, but at least I can see, even though I'm not going to do it in either game, in Smash Brothers or those kind of games, at least I can see the depth, right?
Scott: It's like I'm swimming in a pool, and I know I'm not diving deep, but I can see the bottom.
Scott: In this game, it's like I look down, and it's sort of dark, and I'm like, "Well, is it really shallow or deep?
Scott: I can't even
Scott: tell.".
Rym: See, I can kind of see the bottom.
Scott: And I'm definitely not swimming down there.
Rym: I could see deeper, I think, because I definitely saw that there were very clear...
Scott: I think I'd have to swim deeper to begin to see deeper, right?
Rym: I guess I did swim a little deeper, because I was playing it for a while again, after the first time you played, and I got kind of good, okay, pretty quick, until people started ganging up on me.
Rym: George was getting better than he should have.
Scott: Starting to do politics in a four-player game.
Scott: See, what they really did... You know what this reminded me?
Scott: Is that the game that we really need for this situation is Video Ball.
Scott: That's the game.
Rym: No, no, no.
Rym: The problem is, as much as I want it to be Video Ball, Video Ball is more like Rocket League, casual people sitting down to play will do nothing but own goal, get pissed, and stop.
Scott: But the one thing with Video Ball is you can do four-player local, which Rocket League can't do easily, unless you've got like four computers.
Rym: You know what I would say then?
Rym: You bust out star walls if you have the barely gamers to semi-serious gamers set at your party.
Rym: And if it's all people like me and Scott and like the front of the crew...
Scott: Also, Video Ball can totally work if no one is good at it.
Scott: No, no.
Scott: The same with Soul Calibur, Street Fighter work if no one's good, or Smash Brothers.
Rym: I think Video Ball will work less good because Video Ball has a lot of own-goaling if you suck.
Scott: Maybe.
Rym: I mean, I scored own goals, and I have some basic gaming aptitude.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: I mean, they serve the same purpose.
Rym: I think they're similarly competitive.
Rym: The only real difference is that this can be a team game, but we were mostly playing it solo.
Rym: Video Ball is only a team game.
Rym: I wouldn't play Video Ball one-on-one.
Rym: Just like I wouldn't play Rocket League one-on-one.
Scott: Starwall can be four players.
Scott: Everyone's individual.
Scott: Video Ball has to be teams.
Scott: It's more like Mario Tennis.
Rym: So, yeah, I was about to say, I was aiming toward that.
Rym: Video Ball fits in the niche of Mario Tennis, and notice even in our group, it was hard to get Mario Tennis going because you needed teams to say, "We will play this game as
Rym: teams.".
Scott: Team Scott.
Rym: Starwall.
Rym: Team Scott.
Rym: What, with your boo?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But, Narwhal, Starwall, can do the one-on-one-on-one-on-one where everyone plays until someone gets bored and they hand a controller over to someone else, and because only the host is going to own this game, most likely, no one's going to practice it at home and get good like they do at Smash.
Scott: Yeah, it'd be hard to practice.
Scott: Who are you going to practice Starwall against at home?
Scott: The AI?
Rym: So, unless your friend group, this becomes your Windjammers, it'll pretty much always be air hockey without the air hockey problem.
Scott: Maybe.
Rym: I mean, I enjoyed it.
Rym: I think it's a great game.
Scott: The theme is good.
Scott: It's got that, you know, neon Geometry Wars kind of style that I like that a lot of indie games have.
Scott: It's polished.
Scott: But also, Narwhals.
Rym: It's polished.
Scott: And you can customize your Narwhal before the game starts to really stand out, and that way you can really identify who you are.
Rym: But it's polished.
Rym: It's consistent.
Rym: It's well-designed.
Rym: It has good aesthetics.
Rym: It plays easily.
Rym: It's intuitive to the most.
Scott: Controls might be a little flaky.
Rym: I don't think they're flaky at all.
Rym: I don't think they're flaky.
Rym: They're very consistent.
Scott: They're consistently not perfect.
Rym: No, no.
Rym: Flaky would be like some of those mediocre platformers where they don't work.
Scott: Yeah, it's not that bad.
Scott: It's not one of those ones where you're just like, "Fuck this.
Scott: The controls are so
Scott: bad.".
Scott: They're just slightly like,
Scott: "Eh.".
Rym: I don't think they're eh.
Rym: I think they're actually really good.
Rym: They're eh.
Rym: I felt like I had a lot of control on my Starwall.
Scott: Not really.
Rym: Let's play some one-on-one.
Rym: I think something might have it.
Rym: I think I might just be way better at this game than you.
Scott: Possibly.
Scott: But the theme of it being also Narwhals in space.
Rym: But it also, it did everything.
Rym: If you want to be this directly competitive single screen local, or you could do this game online just as easily, but single screen orthogame in the style of old Atari competitive games, this game did that to a T. Because, I mean, those games aren't all great.
Rym: As long as you do the formula well, you'll succeed and you'll be a niche like Slot Racers.
Scott: All right, so we have to talk about Res Publica because you put it in the title of the episode.
Rym: Res Publica is a Knizia game that I had never played until PAX.
Scott: I had never played it until this weekend.
Rym: Yeah, Chris busts it out.
Scott: I played it once and that's all I need to play.
Rym: I like it because the only game I can think of that has a mechanic even close to this, in terms of the mechanic.
Rym: that's interesting in this game, is Hanabi.
Scott: Yeah, but Hanabi is better by a lot.
Rym: This is a game where there's two resources and you're trying to build the most stuff by making sets of dudes.
Scott: Right, there's two decks of cards.
Scott: You have to make sets and succeed in the first deck of cards and you can start getting cards from the second deck and the second deck is actually worth victory points.
Scott: So it's pretty much build a machine and then score and then the game's over.
Rym: But the mechanic, and this is all I want to focus on, the game itself, play it if you're a game designer and you want to see how this works.
Scott: It's really straightforward and simple and not really the greatest, but...
Rym: Well, it could be.
Scott: It's really just, here's this game mechanic, let's implement it in the simplest possible, most straightforward way and the end.
Rym: But the mechanic is such, so think about games like Bonanza, about games like Hanabi.
Scott: I think Bonanza does it better, Hanabi does it better.
Rym: No, I think Bonanza does it worse, but Bonanza's a more fun game.
Scott: Maybe.
Rym: Because there's no information economy in Bonanza, really, not like the strict one here.
Scott: That's true, in Bonanza you could just be like, "Yeah, I got ten cool
Scott: green.".
Rym: In fact, imagine Bonanza if you used some of the ideas from this game.
Rym: Maybe.
Rym: Anyway, so here's the mechanic.
Rym: On your turn, you'll have a hand of cards and you either say, "I have something," or, "I want
Rym: something.".
Scott: So in saying that, you're giving information away.
Scott: Obviously, if you say you have something, you have to have it.
Scott: You can't say you have something you don't have.
Scott: And if you say you want something, well, that's the only thing that you could get.
Scott: So clearly, you must have something that goes with the thing you want in your hand, otherwise you wouldn't be saying that.
Rym: So I offer a contract.
Rym: I have two Langebaarden.
Rym: That means I will give you two Langebaarden for whatever you offer.
Scott: Right, so you go around the table.
Scott: So since Rym started with an "I have," everyone else has to reply with an "I have," right?
Scott: So Rym said he has two Langebaarden.
Scott: I have two Schiffbau.
Rym: And everyone else says, "I have one Schiffbau.
Rym: I have three
Rym: cards.".
Scott: Yup.
Rym: And who cares what they are?
Rym: And you go around, and then I can choose not to trade, or I can pick one of those deals and do it.
Scott: So if he picks me, he has to give me two Langebaarden and I have to give him two Schiffbau, because that's what we said that we had.
Rym: Oh yeah, the copy of the game we have is just in German.
Scott: We can't negotiate, right?
Scott: We have to do what we said was the thing.
Rym: Yeah, it's a very structured market.
Rym: So if I say, "I want," then Scott would say, "I
Rym: want.".
Scott: Yeah, you have to reply to a "want" with a "want" and a "have" with a
Scott: "have.".
Scott: So if he says he wants a Schiffbau, I have to, A, have to have a Schiffbau.
Scott: I can't say I want something if I don't have the Schiffbau that he wants.
Rym: So to step it up a little further, you can have up to two clauses and an "and" or an "or" between them.
Rym: So I could say, "I want two Schiffbau or two
Rym: Langebaarden.".
Scott: So that means I can reply with a "want" as long as I have either two Schiffbau or two Langebaarden.
Scott: And then I would say, "I want
Scott: something.".
Scott: So now, if we actually, Rym chooses me for the deal, it's up to me whether to give him the Schiffbaus or the Langebaarden.
Scott: Because I said "or," I decide which of those "ors" I'm going to give.
Rym: Yeah, so if I say, "I have X or Y," fuck you.
Rym: You don't get to pick which one.
Rym: So "I have or" is kind of a dick deal, but you can use that to share information.
Scott: Something I thought about immediately after playing that I never did during the game was, could I lie using an "or"?
Scott: For example, I have one Schiffbau in my hand.
Scott: Could I say, "I have one Schiffbau or one something I don't have," and then always give the Schiffbau?
Rym: No, you cannot.
Rym: I'm reasonably sure.
Rym: No one did that because I don't think you can.
Scott: Because when I give him, if you give someone something after an "or," you give it to them.
Scott: face down so that only you and they know what you actually gave and no one else does.
Rym: So think about this.
Rym: When I'm saying my "haves" and "wants," I might have a part of the clause.
Rym: that is something I actually want to do, but I'm also trying to share information.
Rym: I'm trying to impart.
Rym: Say it's my turn and I offer something to Scott, I might also be saying something because I want Chris to offer me something on his turn, and I'm trying to share information without saying too much information.
Scott: Right, you're negotiating without directly negotiating.
Scott: By saying that you want something, someone just said they have one something and it goes around and no one has anything, and then you're like, "I want two of that something you just said you had one
Scott: of.".
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But you've got to be careful because if you share too much information, like if Scott keeps talking about how he has Langobarden, he's trying to get rid of him, and then suddenly he says, "I--" Can you look up some more of the cards that say Langobarden and Schiffvowels?
Rym: Vickenger?
Scott: Anglo-Saxons.
Rym: Anglo-Saxons and Vickengers?
Scott: Vickengers, okay, there we go.
Rym: Schiffvowel.
Scott: Schiffvowel.
Rym: But if Scott keeps saying, "I have Langobarden, I have Langobarden," then suddenly he's like, "I want
Rym: Langobarden?".
Rym: Well, yeah, no one's going to give him fucking Langobarden now because he's going to make his set.
Rym: He suddenly got by luck close enough to be there to his set.
Rym: So the game is a pretty rough game if you really play to win because you've got to keep track of what people have and want based on these negotiated contracts and this information economy.
Rym: It was too much for me to ever bother trying to do fully.
Scott: Yeah, I'm like, at the beginning of the game, I started to get a picture in my head of what were in people's hands, and before it got around to table one, so I gave the fuck up.
Rym: So, information economy games.
Scott: I would say, if you're just a casual gamer-- I ended up just sort of associating one card with each player at any given turn.
Rym: Well, it's like in T&E.
Rym: All I think about is, for everyone else, what do they have the least of?
Rym: And I try to keep track of that, and I ignore everything else.
Scott: They have the least of the thing no one has any of.
Rym: So, do not get this game just as a general gamer.
Rym: I'd honestly only recommend it if, one, you're a Rainier Canisia fan, like you really just want to go through his works.
Scott: Or if you're a game designer and you want to study this mechanic.
Rym: Yes, if you're a game designer who is interested in information economies, because there aren't that many games that do it well, and I suspect information-- Or if you're some sort of game researcher or something.
Rym: Yeah, information economy games are rare, and they might be a way to solve some of the problems of shitty co-op games like Pandemic.
Scott: Right, but yeah, there's a lot you can learn from this game, but there's not a lot of fun that normal people could have playing this game, or anyone could have playing this game.
Scott: It's like, I played it once, and I don't need to play it again, really.
Scott: I understand it now.
Rym: So the third type of person to play it is, if you're one of those people who has played every game, this is novel, and you'll get pure novelty from it, because you haven't played a game like it before.
Scott: Yeah, a few times.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, some people have played most of the games in the PAX library, and you're sitting there like, "Eh, what do I play?
Rym: that isn't Tiggers and
Rym: Euphrates?".
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patrons this week are... The only really important thing I can tell you guys is if you didn't notice, the poll for the December Q&A episode is up.
Rym: You can go vote in that now, submit your questions.
Rym: And the November Q&A is already up, so if you haven't logged in to Patreon in a while, make sure you log in because everyone who's giving us any amount of money can listen to that episode.
Rym: And we talk about some pretty good stuff.
Rym: It was actually a full-on real episode.
Rym: So stay tuned for new stuff.
Rym: A lot of things are in pre-production, and you heard about all the panels we're doing.
Rym: And now I leave you with your moment of literally the opposite of zen.
Scott: Can you be mincemeat?
Rym: fine not to touch anything?
Scott: All right, I guess I wasn't thinking.
Scott: You weren't thinking?
Rym: You mean you'll work on engines and machinery and not thinking your own personal safety?
Rym: Here, here.
Scott: Shake hands with danger.
Rym: Shake hands with danger.
Rym: Be the guy who ought to know.
Rym: I used to laugh at safety.
Scott: Now they call me.
Rym: Three-finger Joe.
Rym: Danger.
Rym: Danger, danger.
Rym: Danger, danger, danger, danger, danger, danger, danger, danger.
Rym: Shake hands with danger.
Rym: Find it anywhere you choose.
Rym: Be careless for a moment.
Rym: Spend a lifetime with the blues.
Rym: Glenn knows the risk of striking hard against badly chipped metal.
Rym: But he's wearing safety glasses, and there's a macho thing involved here.
Rym: Glenn doesn't want his friends to stare at him for being overly cautious.
Rym: So, Glenn shakes hands with danger.