Rym: It's Thursday July 23rd 2015. my name is Rym.
Rym: My name is El Scotto, and this is El GeekNights.
Rym: Oh tonight we're gonna talk about belts and onions.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: So I uploaded a video that I can't talk about because of my promise to not talk about something till the end of summer But I'll link to it.
Rym: You can watch this video great Didn't that be a thing of day or meta moment?
Scott: Why is that an opening bit?
Rym: Because it's the closest I can get to talking about that topic Because that topic is the thing that affects my life on a day-to-day basis.
Rym: Everybody's gaga.
Rym: So uh last night for about 30 seconds.
Rym: I thought I was dying.
Scott: Don't you think that pretty often?
Scott: How about that time in RIT when like you couldn't breathe because your throat was allergies or whatever?
Rym: I didn't think I was dying.
Rym: I just thought that really really sucks.
Scott: What about the time we had Lyme disease?
Rym: Uh that time I thought I was dying.
Rym: that was the other time.
Rym: That of course that time I remember what about a time something went through your leg.
Rym: I didn't think I was dying.
Rym: I just thought this is gonna hurt like a motherfucker when I go to the doctor.
Rym: Mm-hmm and Actually didn't cuz they don't me up.
Scott: What about that time you got a rocket to the face, uh Never actually gotten a rocket to the face.
Rym: No Bottle rocket hit me in the shoulder one time.
Rym: We played quake you got Face, I believe the wrong thing.
Scott: You died.
Rym: I believe they're kind of dramatic.
Scott: They're bits of you all over the place primarily hitting you and they're not called bits.
Rym: They're called Gibbs.
Scott: understand So you definitely died whatever.
Scott: at the time you jump tried to jump over that hole and fell in.
Rym: So I'm laying in bed.
Rym: No sleep, and I wake up and Just one like the typical like you fell asleep in a weird way.
Rym: your arm fell asleep.
Rym: Both my arms were numb.
Rym: I've had that and my neck hurt.
Rym: So I'm like, uh, and I kind of like wiggle my shoulders My arms just like yeah, I've had that.
Rym: Yeah, and my neck is like feels thick and heavy and I'm like am I having a stroke?
Rym: No, I lay there for a second stroke feels like and then and then like two or three seconds later My brain like the rest of the brain wakes up and says ah, dude Think about how you're laying.
Rym: and basically I was laying with like one arm behind My neck like holding my head back and my other arm was like crossed underneath it.
Rym: I had tied myself in a knot and cut off circulation of my arms.
Scott: Yeah, let's have it any once or twice.
Rym: Yep But it was interesting as part of my but you know The the lower part of the brain wakes up and says yo dog emergency time and then the rest of the brain says yeah You're just a moron Stan you're back if that happens to me I'm just.
Scott: I'm just like I've never thought I was dying when that happened.
Scott: I was just like fuck.
Scott: and then I basically like wobble my torso to flap the arms around like What angel is that that has the paper arms?
Rym: Oh Not milk Don't remember the name, you know the ones up?
Scott: Yeah, yeah, and then I just you know They just wobble around until they start working again.
Scott: And it's kind of fun because like your arm is sort of like a dead piece of meat you can sort of grab it like if a one arm is working you can sort of grab the dead arm and like Flap it at things like like it's a club.
Rym: Usually it's one arm that goes.
Rym: Sham's shell is this guy with the flappy.
Scott: Yes that guy.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Sham shell with the weird head Anthropod like angel with deadly quote whips of light.
Scott: I'm watching I'm not your home.
Scott: Why would I watch anything else when there's such a good show?
Rym: Well, that's the problem of all things in life.
Rym: And this is like, I don't know if it just happens when you get older and you've seen a lot of stuff.
Rym: But I could spend a month like if I was locked like I couldn't go outside because the weather was bad.
Rym: I just watch.
Rym: Ava has good bebop Monica.
Scott: Did they finish the matrix movies?
Scott: That you cannot watch all these movies.
Rym: You cannot buy five five five.
Rym: I could watch it or Stella five five five again.
Rym: Recently So the wiki lists all the angels.
Rym: cuz I just went to look at a picture of all the angels to remember which one it Was.
Rym: the picture at the end is just a bunch of people and it's like humans.
Rym: Okay, the 18th angel or the 13th angel.
Rym: Oh shit.
Rym: So in the original anime humans are the 18th angel.
Rym: spoilers dudes.
Rym: in the manga Humans are the 13th as opposed to the 18th.
Scott: There were less.
Scott: Yes, which ones weren't in the manga.
Rym: Uh The third angel which is also not in the anime It's only in the remake.
Rym: one dot one dot one dot one dot one.
Scott: I haven't even seen that one.
Rym: It looks like a dinosaur skeleton also discovered in permafrost prior to sounds cool.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: I'm into this.
Scott: What other?
Scott: which other one?
Scott: sandal fawn which is which one?
Rym: Oh, that's the volcano one.
Rym: That's not in the manga or the remake.
Rym: It's only in the anime.
Rym: Oh Interesting same with the big spider one that they catch the strip in the acid.
Scott: I've seen the spider one.
Rym: It's only in the anime, okay Yeah, so the anime has the most the only one that's in the end.
Rym: That's not in the anime.
Scott: had more monster of the week going on.
Scott: Yeah more monsters for the weeks All right.
Rym: This article is getting complicated quickly.
Rym: I'm just gonna pass that on.
Rym: Read this wiki I do have a news.
Rym: so when I worked at IBM and all those places before Like there's this weird culture in American companies where people don't talk about their salaries and also among friends.
Rym: There's a weird social culture where people don't talk.
Scott: I mean, I said, I mean, it's an American and also other certain countries.
Scott: I mean there are countries where it's not a thing but most cultures on earth I think where people have jobs that pay money the culture is not to discuss Salaries.
Scott: now people might feel bad Like if you tell them, you know It's like if you find out someone who's like new just got hired is making more than you who's been there for five years You know, it's gonna cause dry.
Scott: It's just people want to avoid drama So they don't tell anyone.
Rym: but at the same time I feel like both of those factors combined Hurts a lot of people who are way underpaid for the work.
Scott: Yes this this culture absolutely favors companies and Employers and fucks employees.
Scott: if you're an employee Even though you're worried that there might be drama with other employees if you share your salaries with each other You have no one's be mad at except your employer and your employer is the one who is happy that you are not sharing that Information because then they would have to pay a lot more money or people would quit and they'd have to hire someone else.
Scott: Yeah, and since all the information is public they're gonna have to pay that person more money.
Scott: Anyway, now a lot of super big bureaucratic companies is why unions are awesome And people who are in unions even today what unions aren't strong as they used to be Still get more stuff than people aren't in unions.
Rym: So, uh, like big corporate bureaucratic companies sometimes especially if they're super bureaucracies Like if you know someone's band or level or whatever.
Rym: like people know what the salaries are within a range and bonuses are sometimes public Yeah, and government work.
Scott: Someone's an executive like a public company.
Scott: This thing is public, you know, everyone knows.
Rym: like government military It's like what government rank are you?
Rym: Well, I know exactly how much money you make and how many vacation days you get.
Scott: Yeah, because there's some structure to it.
Rym: So when I worked at a company, I want to say which one.
Rym: just because one day I was sitting around and a guy was bitching about his salary and I was like, wow
Scott: I've never actually heard anyone bitch about he
Rym: was he was just pissed off in general because he'd been doing like all this night work He didn't want to be doing and I was
Scott: like just say no.
Rym: So I was just like how much do they pay you?
Rym: and he's like.
Rym: he says a number and I said He's like what.
Rym: and I'm like, yeah I make like 20 grand more than that and I do way less work than you.
Rym: and he was like what?
Rym: Fuck this and he quit that week.
Scott: Fuck.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I hope he did.
Rym: Well.
Scott: Yeah, you go good, dude.
Rym: so when I worked for a broker-dealer in the finance world like Money was well, that was the company where one I Got a really low salary because I didn't know.
Rym: I asked for like 70k Because I thought that was you know, a lot of money back then and they were like, yeah.
Rym: Yes, we will pay you that Sure, and if only later did they be like, okay.
Rym: Yeah, we're not gonna take advantage of you But we're only later not immediately because they're still jerks.
Rym: They waited until my my you know, quote-unquote probation, which was 30 days.
Rym: So I worked for 30 days and then they gave me like a 30k race.
Rym: so, uh One day years later.
Rym: We're all like my team's all sitting around in the office and we'd been just kind of annoyed and bored for a While we'd all been thinking about quitting.
Rym: So the guy who quit soon after that was like, yeah so I'm probably gonna quit soon.
Rym: and then we just started talking openly about our salaries and bonuses and everything and once we realized who all got paid what it explained a lot and We pretty much all quit Like all of us everyone within a few months of that.
Rym: So the news is that a bunch of Google employees shared their salaries with each other.
Rym: They're smart.
Scott: they would figure this sort of thing out wouldn't they?
Rym: and They.
Rym: basically it's just.
Rym: it's like when you're playing but I mean you work at Google.
Scott: You're probably you're a developer and not the security mature.
Scott: I'm sure even the security guard gets paid nicely.
Scott: Yeah, you're Google You're making money.
Scott: You shouldn't really have anything to be upset or have drama about if you reveal your salary to someone else.
Rym: Yeah, but at the same time Companies even Google it appears pay as little as they can get away with.
Scott: Why wouldn't they?
Scott: they're a for-profit company?
Scott: That's why unions are good.
Scott: Yeah, if you're in one.
Rym: So apparently Google's management actually flipped out about this and there's a whole drama thread.
Rym: you can read all this stuff.
Scott: You can't stop you from talking.
Scott: There's no love.
Rym: so a lot of company fire them if you want.
Scott: you can do that for any reason.
Rym: Uh, it depends on the state actually.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: I don't know what California is up to but So they could fire you if they wanted to.
Rym: well It depends because a lot of companies more recently like in the last decade Part of your employment agreement because usually there's some kind of NDA like I won't release company secrets or whatever.
Rym: They actually cover your compensation Under that would challenge that shit in court.
Scott: be like you can't do that.
Rym: I have had stock options and equity in companies in my life that I was not actually legally allowed to disclose Unless I was exercising them.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So This is a complicated issue.
Rym: All I want to say is I urge all of you out there to Be open about your salaries with your at least your friends Like.
Rym: I know friend drama money can often be a problem.
Scott: But I mean even even if you you know It's like come on Like.
Scott: I haven't discussed all our salaries and exact numbers with all my friends.
Scott: They know how much everyone knows who's making more money than other people, right?
Scott: Who makes more money?
Scott: the Rym the Rym working in the fight in the finance company in New York City right.
Scott: or the art teacher in The sticks.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: It's not a secret.
Rym: We all know the Scott who flew to Pax Australia for the fuck of it Or the other friends who stopped going to the PAX East because they can really only afford one con a year and they go to Magpies, right?
Scott: It's like we know this.
Scott: it doesn't.
Scott: no one's feelings are gonna be hurt by the truth that everybody knows if they are hurt By just pure knowledge.
Scott: I'm not talking about I mean if they're not hurt with the general knowledge If they're hurt by the numb they're hurt when you reveal the numbers.
Scott: Why weren't they hurt before when they knew already but didn't know an exact?
Rym: Oh, of course, if you use those numbers to be a dick, you're like I make seven times your salary.
Scott: Then why are you friends with them in the first?
Rym: So, but what I urge you is if you have friends who work in your industry I would suggest Sharing your salaries with each other because odds are one of you is getting ripped the fuck off And knowing what all your friends are being paid in your industry can do nothing but benefit workers.
Rym: And frankly workers are the only people that matter Labor.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, even though labor is actually not valuable anymore.
Rym: I've recently arguing at length with people that Communism as a concept is failed not socialism, but communism was destroyed by modernity.
Rym: Like well, I guess post modernity industrialization in the sense that labor is actually not that valuable anymore.
Rym: Nope, like the workers are not the means of production capital and technology are the means of production.
Scott: Yeah, the tech worker is always that picture of all the workers right holding up the big plate with all the big fat.
Rym: They're all right, they're all next to the computer that has one person typing at it exactly.
Scott: It's like we could all let go of the plate and it would float on money and rock.
Rym: So seriously guys like I'm curious actually because I have said my salary on GeekNights Many times in the past like a number.
Scott: Only reason I don't say my exact number because I actually don't fucking know.
Scott: Yeah I started with a number that I don't even remember.
Scott: that was just slightly more than what I had in my last company and Then I got a raise every single year.
Scott: See I don't get like.
Scott: that's like a percent.
Scott: That's like one and a half or five.
Scott: I think was was it five?
Scott: I can't even know if it's one and a half or five percent.
Rym: See I don't get raises, but I get complicated compensation.
Scott: Mine's really straightforward.
Scott: but there's been a raise like every year and it actually sort of happens frequently like my boss just like oh By the way, you got a raise.
Scott: I got you the most raise you're allowed to get and it's like Okay That seems like this happened yesterday and it seems like it happens pretty often But I don't ask for it.
Scott: It just happens.
Scott: No, I don't know the actual number.
Scott: now I know the amount of money that I get in a that goes into my checking account but that is nowhere near the salary that I have if I multiply it by 24 because I get it twice a month because They're taking so much stuff out.
Scott: The taxes are coming out.
Scott: The health care is coming out.
Scott: The 401k is a large is like 15 percent or something that's coming out.
Scott: So it's like I don't do a lot of math to figure out the exact number or ask HR which I really don't care.
Rym: yeah, but uh Yeah, it's just an interesting thing.
Rym: We'll see if this Story continues into any meaningful Dialogues.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So what did Google do to these employees?
Rym: Nothing, there's just a big drama right now.
Scott: I deal with it.
Scott: So in a money related issue as well, right?
Scott: We've talked a lot and GeekNights about ads and how Internet ads are fake and it's a big scam or whatever, you know.
Scott: But this guy he wrote this really short thing Called why you will never escape ads by paying for content, right?
Scott: Cuz we're always like, oh you pay for Netflix.
Scott: Why should I have to see ads?
Scott: I'm paying for Hulu.
Scott: why should I have to see ads.
Scott: and he brings up a point that is common sense once you hear it.
Scott: and But I had never thought of it exactly in quite this way.
Scott: and the thing is advertisers They want people to see ads right?
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Who do they want to see ads?
Rym: Ideally people who are either dumb or who are likely to become customers of their thing.
Scott: Mmm That is incorrect.
Scott: According to him people who are buying ads want people who have money to see their ads.
Scott: someone who can afford to pay to make ads go away is Somebody who has fucking money and he can buy shit.
Rym: god damn it.
Scott: So you want god damn it.
Rym: Think of it from this angle, right?
Scott: So the more you are willing to pay to keep ads away.
Scott: So think about it.
Scott: Let's say you charged a hundred dollars a month to have no ad.
Scott: Netflix, right?
Scott: Advertisers are gonna be like, holy fuck.
Scott: There's a group of people who can afford a hundred bucks a month to not see ads.
Rym: I'll be I'll be a thousand bucks.
Scott: Pay so much money to have my ads target only those people.
Scott: the more ads The more people will pay to keep ads away the more advertisers will pay to show ads to specifically that group of people.
Scott: So this is why you cannot pay to make ads go away because the more that you pay to make ads go away.
Scott: Suddenly Netflix is there with like a car company telling them we will give you a five million dollars to let us advertise to the paying Customers who are paying a hundred bucks a month and Netflix has to be like, uh, do we just say no to like five million?
Scott: Dollars for nothing.
Scott: It's a hard choice.
Rym: Well, I mean as noted Hulu even if you pay still has ads.
Scott: and then this guy also refers to another article that I haven't Read.
Scott: it's is actually a three paragraph deal, right?
Scott: But it's just.
Scott: the point is so good.
Scott: He says consider the recent opinion piece by Thomas Wells.
Scott: is advertising morally justifiable.
Rym: I read that article By Thomas.
Scott: well, so You know read this three paragraphs pretty much.
Scott: I already told you everything the three paragraphs have to say.
Scott: But then read the other one.
Scott: is advertising morally justifiable?
Scott: perhaps in the future quote I mean quote.
Scott: perhaps in the future It will be just as illegal to broadcast this type of material as it is to mass distribute malware because that's what advertising is.
Scott: It's brain malware.
Rym: So there was another article that I'm not going to talk about in depth because I kind of want to talk about this on Monday.
Rym: smartphone apps a bunch of them have been collecting 850 million dollars in fraudulent revenue by Hosting ads not displaying the ads but just lying and saying people saw the ads there's a good, you know, we already know that like a huge percentage of all ad Clicks and ad views just pretty much across the board are fake either from botnets or whatever.
Rym: And that's not even counting all the ads that don't get shown because of ad block It.
Rym: it might actually be way higher than that.
Rym: I would push that estimate up to 70 80 percent and this is just even more evidence for that.
Rym: So advertising is a big circle jerk scam Independent of the even more disturbing concept that you brought up that I hadn't thought of until just now.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Also was a kid.
Rym: We had cable way early and we had HBO from old satellite dish way early.
Scott: there weren't ads back then Like there were not HBO's deal pay for the content and not no ads.
Scott: Yeah, which is why he has a lot of money.
Rym: But then we got cable and cable showed movies and had all these channels and there weren't ads.
Rym: when we first had Cable was new.
Scott: It didn't have ads.
Scott: That was its deal.
Scott: Yeah, and then it had ads.
Scott: Yep, because of probably this reason Well had three deals.
Rym: The first deal was you live in a town that doesn't get reception will have one community antenna and a cable that distributes the stuff From that and sure.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, but knowing that that that era is Irrelevant and archaic and is not in any way.
Scott: Well, I mean you probably in your antenna Days, right?
Scott: You probably only got like Detroit TV.
Rym: No, we got like 19 channels plus.
Scott: Yeah, okay.
Scott: So we were in Connecticut.
Scott: So on antenna, we had all New York stations.
Rym: No, we got like 30 channels.
Rym: I'm enumerating my head.
Rym: We had to channel 2 2 4 7 14. we're all like major networks plus 20 and 50.
Scott: But like we had two of each major network because we had New York and Connecticut.
Scott: Yeah, it'd be like I got Canada.
Scott: We had two different NBC's two different ABC's two different CBS's - right so you could watch even though a lot of times they would Both show the same thing like well footballs on New York NBC and Connecticut NBC.
Scott: Oh, you had nightly news on ABC to get Connecticut nightly news on 8 and you get New York 7.
Scott: You know eyewitness news on 7 even though they're both ABC.
Rym: we get a lot of Wisconsin content, you know 8 o'clock 7 central.
Scott: We had two PBS's and then there were all the local stations right like channel 20 or 21 like, Connecticut station.
Scott: You watch cartoons after school like that, but then we also had New York ones like 11 where you can watch the Mets and whatnot.
Scott: Yeah, so we had like double stations within the antenna days Which is probably a lot of the reason why we didn't get cable for so long also because it was expensive.
Rym: We I remember Channel 9 was Canadian TV and that had all the cartoons like the best cartoons all the Canadian TV.
Scott: I mean the government cartoons, right?
Rym: Yeah Anyway, also in that was the one Inspector Gadget was on at a better time on the Canadian network than it was on whatever I forget what channel.
Scott: They're also Saturday morning cartoons in those days.
Rym: Yeah, there were.
Rym: there were so things of the day.
Rym: So this is actually pretty cool.
Rym: I have a video here that is happy family family of kittens bird and puppy.
Scott: What kind of bird is it?
Rym: Oh, just like a little parakeet.
Rym: Okay, so the interesting thing about this video is that is from 1955 but word in color.
Rym: This is just YouTube from today.
Rym: Okay, it's just but the reason this is on YouTube.
Scott: it looks like it was shot though in a studio not in a home.
Rym: it was because There was no amateur video production back then like this.
Scott: Yeah, how you gonna set up a big old film camera from the 50s at home?
Rym: Yeah with a giant light that's giving anyone cancer or whatever.
Rym: Yeah, so Associated Press and British movie tone got together and they have uploaded it's what it says Million minutes of historical video added to YouTube.
Scott: What's the license on this video?
Rym: Uh Copyright AP.
Rym: Yeah, you can't reuse it.
Rym: It's not public domain, but you can watch it.
Rym: Yeah, you need licensing to use it, but you can watch it.
Rym: They just put it all up for everyone.
Scott: It's just one YouTube channel.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: Well, it's on this YouTube channel.
Scott: I haven't lives it organized.
Rym: Anyway, seems to be.
Rym: you can go to a website like search for stuff.
Rym: There's lots of cool that's useful like the bombing of Pearl Harbor like some first-hand stuff.
Rym: I don't need to see the the 1906 San Francisco earthquake.
Scott: What are the good things to see?
Rym: more kittens happy family of kittens bird.
Rym: There's a lot of that a lot of old building construction like things.
Rym: I have not fully gone through this yet.
Scott: We got to find the nerd stuff.
Scott: Where are the nerds from the 50s 120 years of video?
Rym: The only thing that bothers me about this other than it should be creative commons in some fashion But I'll take it is That minutes does not seem like the optimum unit to use to measure this.
Scott: It's they got to have the most impressive number they can visit.
Scott: how many videos they'd be like.
Scott: Yeah about a thousand videos.
Rym: I would have put it in hours or perhaps day.
Scott: like a thousand videos are uploaded to YouTube like every second.
Scott: Yeah, there's.
Scott: no you can't really brag about like we uploaded a thousand YouTube videos.
Rym: Yeah, good job But really minutes dude, like we see what you're doing there.
Scott: Anyway, so for my thing of the day I dug back to my what used to be the most common source of things of the day.
Rym: Oh reaching back for glory the glory of Japanese television.
Scott: So there's a show on Japanese television called gonna mispronounce the name Sekai.
Scott: no hot a mod a tech which means Riddles at the ends of the earth exclamation point and I recognized Sekai and literally nothing else.
Scott: Yes The attack is spelled ITT EQ, which I've never seen as a Japanese spelling before and a romanization anyway.
Scott: so in this video they are demonstrating a Material called the predator shield, which is basically like a glass that you would use at a zoo to keep you know Animals in.
Rym: oh, so not like predator shield.
Scott: No, you know something you would use You know maybe like on windows of a vehicle on a safari an actual predator like a bear not right a predator.
Scott: And in this video there's a schoolgirl or a girl a woman in a schoolgirl outfit inside of a box that is Six sides sealed with oh good god.
Scott: She looks terrified.
Scott: He is terrified With predator shield.
Scott: I don't know how she's breathing.
Scott: There must be a hole in it somewhere.
Rym: Yeah, there's a hole right there.
Scott: Okay, and There's just a real fucking bear like rawr.
Scott: I'm a bear.
Scott: go go Like Attacking this box that she's in and she's holding a camera pointing at the bear.
Scott: She's somehow managing to keep the camera aimed at the.
Scott: now She's not look at this while also being terrified for her life because this bear is actually ferociously attacking this box.
Scott: Thankfully, it seems that the predator shield product works and protects you from bears But it doesn't mean you should subject someone to being in a box that is attacked by a bear.
Scott: You could have put say I don't know Honey in the box and had it be attacked by the bear to prove the bear could not get the honey.
Scott: And that would have been an ample demonstrate that it would not be Japanese television.
Scott: No, it would not.
Scott: nor would it be a thing of the day.
Rym: in the meta moment The book club book is the wheel of time.
Scott: I read a bunch more of yesterday.
Rym: How far'd you get like what happened recently?
Scott: They're running away from the town the bear line.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, a lot of bears going on.
Rym: Yes, they're in the inn and so, uh, it kind of gets left behind.
Rym: I'm pretty sure.
Rym: a chuckle fuck in the alley totally ratted them out.
Scott: Yeah, they even said man that chuckle fuck is gonna ride us out.
Scott: and then yeah that that anyone's gonna ride us out It's gonna be that dude.
Rym: and then yeah pretty sure that conversation they had with that guy Those two Matt and Rand they should have just stabbed that dude.
Rym: They should stab Rand and Perrin.
Scott: These guys got to learn a lot more from other long quest adventures like my man, you know, oh the water Like Tetsuro just gun people fucking down.
Scott: Yeah shoot first to survive in this galaxy account Mecca.
Rym: He didn't even give him a chance just like but dude, right, you know, that's how it's got to be.
Scott: You got the heron sword.
Scott: That should be as good as a heron spear.
Scott: It seems to be right.
Scott: Just let it go.
Rym: but Those fucking kids It's like every time something important happens two of them will go off and be like, man, please don't tell anyone.
Rym: Yeah We shouldn't tell the wizard is trying to save us or the knight who has saved our lives so many times or the bard who's super Smart and knows what to do.
Rym: Let's just not fucking.
Scott: yeah that bard Definitely seemed like an untrustworthy character.
Rym: He's the most trustworthy He.
Scott: now he's obviously like.
Scott: he's just a super skilled awesome trustworthy bard.
Scott: Unlike he's like not he's forky.
Rym: He's not spooning in any way, you know why he's so forky cuz.
Rym: he's a selfish prick, but he doesn't want to die.
Scott: Why would you want to die?
Scott: He's also mad skilled.
Scott: He's so high-level.
Rym: He's skilled and self-preserved.
Scott: I think he might be like my favorite fictional bard.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: He's kind of a prick.
Rym: Not that there's that many bards He's like, I think he's like 12th level like 12th level bard like for serious bard business.
Scott: He's got you know, I mean he captivates the room every time without even trying.
Rym: Yeah, anyway, but yeah those kids just oh I had a dream about the big bad.
Rym: Yeah, don't tell anyone about that.
Scott: We all had the same dream.
Rym: Let's not tell the wizard No, my fingers literally bleeding after the thing happened in the dream not gonna tell anyone about that.
Scott: Yeah Anyway, the most important news is that very very soon the week before Labor Day weekend unusually is penny arcade Expo prime 2015 the real one.
Scott: the packs not the side shows the main event.
Rym: Yeah, this isn't fucking Ravenna.
Rym: This is the Rome of packs once a year bitches.
Scott: It's coming.
Scott: It's real soon.
Scott: six days Matters between now and one month from now.
Rym: I have six days of paxing.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: Yeah, so on Sunday We're doing the far future of gaming.
Rym: It's actually a panel.
Rym: Yeah, there's for not a lecturer.
Rym: We've got four really smart people and us too.
Rym: Yeah, and then on Monday sports are games, which Us too.
Rym: Yes, but that panel like we submitted this shit like six months ago Suddenly a lot of for real stuff is happening in the gaming world.
Rym: That's making that panel like way more.
Scott: At first the panel was just gonna be about like hey nerds just cuz your nerds don't be disrespecting sports their games.
Rym: Yeah, like football's more German board game than test of athleticism in some regard.
Scott: now It's like got a two-topic deal because eSports and whatnot.
Rym: Yeah from the drug use to now drug testing Cheating is so much to talk about.
Scott: I don't know if we're gonna fit it in the hour.
Rym: Yeah, cuz I don't want to drop the original concept of the panel I want to add this thing is gonna be a half and half.
Rym: I think it will be yeah, and then of course, I'm lecturing at kai fu on UX and Story games and game design and I who is not spelled the way you think.
Scott: so if you want to find shy food Yeah, computer human interaction forum of Oregon.
Rym: It's in or I can't believe I remembered what that acronym stood for.
Scott: You're gonna you know If you're gonna speak there, you should know.
Scott: Yeah, like.
Scott: hey everybody.
Scott: Welcome to PAX.
Rym: I mean yeah, so At ConnectiCon not only did mice the slides I used for our losing panel still have a bunch of references to pass But it literally ended with.
Rym: now enjoy packs.
Rym: Yeah, so, uh, yeah We're like those rock stars.
Rym: Just don't even fucking know what town they're in anymore.
Scott: Hey everybody, New York This is Philly.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Fuck you, Philly, New York You know I imagine a comedy skit where the van comes out and they're like Hello, New York and guys like it's Philly and the guy just like drops his mic and walks off the stage.
Scott: concerts canceled Just say go.
Scott: Oh, yeah Assholes so belts When I run another Thursday show ideas unless it's book club.
Scott: So
Rym: I was a kid and pretty much
Scott: pretty much down to types of food and articles of clothing
Rym: when I was young like as a little kid a belt was something that my mom made me wear when I had to wear a suit to go To like a wedding or a funeral.
Scott: or yeah I did not wear a belt until like I was in high school except if I was dressing up.
Rym: Yep, and a lot of that was you don't tuck your shirt in and if you're not talking to shirt in Probably don't need the belt unless your pants don't fit All right.
Scott: And the only reason to wear the belt because if you're tucking the shirt in is because pants look stupid.
Scott: if they're sticking out There's no belt on them.
Scott: Just a bunch of loops and shit with nothing.
Rym: If you tuck your shirt in and you're not wearing a belt you like that's it game over man.
Scott: Looks it looks bad.
Rym: I mean, it's not styling.
Rym: Well, there's.
Rym: no you don't have to.
Scott: you have to know anything about fashion to know that That's not good.
Rym: in fact, there's no excuse.
Rym: cuz what your if your pants don't have belt loops, so it's what like sweatpants?
Rym: Yeah, you tucked your shirt into your sweatpants, dude.
Rym: Okay Once in high school I started wearing a belt because I started wearing slightly more fashionable jeans and I would occasionally do the thing Where you'd.
Rym: I'd tuck a shirt in But then I'd have another shirt or something on and wear like a jacket or something.
Scott: I wore a belt to keep pants from falling down.
Rym: I had one belt.
Rym: I got a really nice like black leather belt.
Rym: It's the only belt I ever wore no matter what because I just never kind of like how.
Rym: I only owned one tie a thin Black silk tie.
Scott: I had one belt but it was not a black belt was brown.
Scott: And this was when the style of the time was not the onion style But it was the style where the belt was a bunch of like thin strips of leather.
Scott: We're rated Bell that we're all braided together.
Rym: I was not the style when I was in high school where I lived.
Scott: It was the style for quite a time where I was.
Scott: what year you're talking like you would go to the store And that's the only belts they had.
Rym: What year are you talking about?
Scott: I don't remember.
Scott: I just remember that's the kind of belt I had for a long time.
Rym: Maybe even into RIT I had that same belt, you know, actually I'll bet it comes down to because you know The internet wasn't really fully internet back then.
Rym: I Suspect that fashion varied widely depending on where you live like Michigan kind of behind the curve like in high school you know, it was actually kind of what like the Semi cool slacker skater, you know, like the the so popular set like the sub genius they often wear like semi baggy black or blue jeans a flannel shirt like over the top unbuttoned just like open and Like an ironic t-shirt like the dare shirt underneath that.
Scott: that's a typical 90s fashion.
Rym: Yeah Maybe you'd wear some like boots and get the boot cut jeans.
Rym: maybe I Wore boots a lot in high school.
Rym: I wore like engineer's boots or motorcycle boots, but that was just.
Rym: you know I've lived in Michigan.
Rym: I had a mustache.
Rym: That's how things were.
Scott: Rym is not the person to look at for fashion with his toe shoes and his kilt.
Rym: See, I'm not worried.
Scott: I didn't count for Non sporting mean-spirited in the sense of a sense of fashion with the toe shoes and the kill.
Scott: that ain't recent Look at you right Rym from high school had the same fashion stuff.
Scott: You just didn't have the same money and there weren't the same.
Scott: if I weren't the same things on offer you tell the guys exist.
Rym: If I could have gotten you till I killed in high school, I would have fucking been wearing that.
Scott: That's what I'm saying.
Rym: However, even I have not changed even that I would have known better than to go with the trilby Because that the trilby went from.
Rym: that seems like a cool idea to all hell.
Rym: no in about 30 seconds anyway, but When I got to college, I just had that same belt.
Rym: one day belt broke.
Scott: Yeah, my weave II belt.
Scott: I think you know, I remember that we've.
Scott: I think it might have died And then I I think it died twice and I think I replaced it with a weave II belt.
Scott: I don't know when it died.
Scott: I just remember twice having belts die and one time replacing it with a similar belt and then again replacing it with a Not weave II belt.
Rym: see now the reason I want a black belt.
Scott: his belts last a fucking long time.
Scott: What are you doing to it?
Scott: Yeah, but I just rub in your like hips against the wall every day or something.
Rym: But you had a brown belt.
Rym: So did you all?
Rym: did you have a black belt for when you were dressed up or yes?
Scott: I had a black shiny belt for wearing a suit.
Rym: You only wore when you were.
Scott: that I only wore when required.
Rym: Yep, so I chose black because all the jewelry I wore was mostly silver.
Rym: so it was like black and I had a silver buckle on it like silver.
Rym: ish and Basically if I I couldn't wear although I couldn't wear gold jewelry really because I wouldn't match the belt I wasn't gonna own multiple belts.
Rym: that just seemed crazy.
Rym: I didn't wear jewelry.
Rym: So yeah, I did so.
Rym: yeah but I had to buy a new belt and I bought an identical black belt that lasted me until like it died a couple years ago.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: so, uh, I didn't expand my belt purchases until relatively recently because I kick-started this weirdo belt and Now I have four of these things and they're the only belts I wear wearing clothes one of them.
Scott: Yeah, so we are not sponsoring this belt.
Scott: They don't pay us any money.
Scott: They don't know us.
Rym: Yeah, but pretty much.
Rym: This belt is great in the sense that it solved a problem that I kind of wish had been solved for me with belts earlier That you cut it to be the exact perfect size when you buy it and it is literally the perfect size And it has no belt holes in it at all.
Scott: Yeah, that's you know, not only belt lengths can be an issue, right?
Scott: But you know, especially if you're some in-between size and the store only has like, you know, 30 and 40 It's like I need 35, bro.
Scott: You know, why don't you make that?
Scott: you cut the belt but the belt is attached to the buckle.
Rym: you can't and you don't need all those holes because like are you your rates not gonna fluctuate that much?
Rym: right?
Scott: so?
Scott: but the real Issue is the holes.
Scott: because even if you have holes on the belt, even if the belt has a lot of holes Okay, so you pull the belt and use the closest hole.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Well, this one's too tight.
Scott: that was not tight enough and you poke a hole in the belt in the middle But you shouldn't do right and now it's the right size.
Scott: But you just ruined your belt by poking a crappy hole in it.
Rym: Plus if you use one hole for even like a little while.
Rym: Then it kind of gets worn in on that hole and it looks stupid.
Rym: if you use any other hole Yep, so you can't be like, uh better loosen the belt Then you lose some weight and you tighten up the belt.
Scott: You know one stop in the summer because you lose the your hibernation fat or whatever and it's like now this ugly beat-up Hole is sticking out where everyone could see it.
Rym: But yeah, so I kick-started.
Rym: this belt is great.
Rym: So now I pretty much I own four of this belt and I only own one other kind of belt in the world.
Scott: I bought one buckle for this belt system and I bought two belts a brown one a brown one in a black one.
Scott: I don't think you can change the buckles that well, I did it work fine, and I don't change it too often either.
Rym: Yeah, but what if you change it like often I buy?
Rym: what if I have to do it often I would buy one because I won't wear brown belts because literally nothing I own goes with a brown belt.
Scott: I rarely use the brown one, but sometimes I use the brown one.
Rym: So I have basically Three black ones with three different buckles on them.
Scott: I don't need different buckles.
Rym: Well, the thing is one of them I wear every day to work.
Rym: So it's getting kind of beat up.
Scott: The buckles getting beat up?
Scott: I've never had a buckle break.
Rym: I'm wearing it every day all the time.
Rym: I wear
Scott: them most days
Rym: Yeah and then I got one with like the like a Black buckle like black metal that go like it kind of blends in really well when I wear like formal wear But I own but basically two of those belts I wear like twice a year.
Rym: So that cuz when you wear a nice suit like you want the bulk of the belt It just looks perfect.
Rym: You want a belt that is like wrinkles in it Like it looks like the shitty belt and it suddenly stands out and detracts.
Rym: Yeah, it's like oh nice three-piece suit and Shabby shoes that you obviously also wear to work, right?
Scott: It's like if you're wearing a suit and like you have a shoe and there's like a big gash on it.
Scott: It's just like, you know, it's like anything that's like perfect just sort of blends in and is not unseen.
Scott: But anything that's like a you know, a negative mark like sticks out like like this do like it's glowing Yeah, like the hip like the the weak spot on a boss.
Rym: Yeah, that's totally the weak spot.
Rym: And then the fourth one I got.
Rym: I bought the gray belt.
Rym: But now I realized that I don't.
Rym: I don't really have anything that goes with it.
Rym: So I've never worn it.
Rym: There's no.
Scott: when would any of you ever see anyone wearing a gray belt?
Rym: Uh, actually I was looking through my clothes there I found like some I looked through like cuz I have a bunch of white jeans with a gray suit.
Scott: Do you wear a gray belt?
Rym: No, I wouldn't wear a gray belt with a gray.
Scott: What do you wear a gray belt with?
Scott: I wear a gray belt, but I guess when you wear gray socks, what do you wear gray socks with?
Rym: old You wear it with old.
Scott: that's old man clothes.
Rym: Yeah, you wear that with old.
Rym: so when I'm 70 start wearing that gray fucking belt with my white fucking pants.
Scott: Even that's weird.
Rym: Usually the gray belt actually works really well because I have one pair of proper jeans not like the spandex II like hipster stuff that I usually wear but they're like old-school like heavy straight down jeans and they're white like fucking white white white.
Rym: and They work really well with that gray belt, but I don't guess it's kind of yeah But I've never seen you wear white jeans.
Rym: Well, cuz I don't wear them that often because they don't stay white love.
Scott: Yeah, I bought white shorts and I was like, these are gonna get really dirty really fast.
Scott: They did but I'm just like.
Scott: well fuck I knew that was gonna have these shorts is okay But I don't.
Rym: that's the other thing I realized long ago.
Rym: This is the other kind of belt I have.
Rym: wearing a leather belt with shorts looks really stupid.
Scott: Not if they're like nice shirts Where's nice shorts?
Rym: I wear comfortable summer shorts.
Rym: I have a pair of like, you know, the kind we're like.
Scott: you see the guy who's a model standing on the sailing boat And he's all like, oh, yeah.
Rym: Yeah, but here's the problem.
Rym: I wear shorts and I'm like biking or it's hot out or whatever.
Rym: I sweat and when leather belts get sweaty they start to deform.
Scott: Yeah, I'm not Doing any sort of physical activity, but I need a belt.
Rym: so I have a bunch of canvas belts that I use for Anything that doesn't need a real belt.
Rym: So a lot of the shorts I bought recently like come with that like kind of fake Oh fabric belt.
Scott: This one I'm wearing right now came with a belt the ones I'm wearing now.
Rym: I don't have the belt in but they can also came with.
Rym: it's not a canvas belt.
Rym: It's just a fabric belt Some sort of woven thing.
Scott: It's sort of durable and then it's basically just on the other end instead of a buckle.
Scott: There's sort of like these two metal loops Yep, and so the size is only gonna be perfect because there's no holes you just pull it through these Yeah, but because it's not leather.
Rym: It's comfortable in the summer and it matches the pants.
Scott: because it came with the pan.
Scott: Yeah, I don't have to do any thinking if you don't know anything about fashion.
Rym: I keep all those belts with the the short that they came with exactly and I well, yeah, maybe I could mix them up.
Rym: No, I don't know how that works.
Rym: It'll probably look stupid and I wouldn't understand why.
Rym: why bother?
Rym: Yeah, exactly.
Scott: It was like Oh shorts plus free belt.
Scott: Hey, not bad But I don't have to wear my other belt.
Rym: so when I was a kid, I was a Cub Scout, right?
Rym: Cub Scouts had that military belt with the weird like the metal buckle.
Scott: Oh, I had that.
Rym: Yeah, it has like a weird pin.
Scott: Yeah, I know the one.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Yeah, so I had that and you know what?
Rym: I always hated that thing.
Rym: I thought it was stupid.
Rym: It's a stupid belt buckle, but I did have a use for that kind of belt in my modern life Because now one of the things that I do, you know Hiking and running and like track like like running through the mountains of Hong Kong or whatever.
Rym: I often need a belt for the kinds of pants that I wear to keep them like secure and like in the right place.
Rym: Can't use my leather belt and those woven belts Like.
Rym: I don't want to get those dirty or fucked up because they go with those shorts And I don't want to ruin them.
Rym: And also I need a belt that's dirty.
Scott: You're gonna ruin the shorts before you ruin the belt.
Scott: It depends.
Scott: How's the belt gonna get ruined?
Rym: So I bought a bunch of a bunch.
Rym: I bought two Canvas belts on Amazon.
Scott: How many belts do you have?
Rym: So they're like two dollars.
Scott: You have like one belt to a hundred belts.
Scott: I got like one belt for each short.
Rym: I have one leather belt for daily use and two other belts.
Rym: Three leather belts for like dressing up like fashion I have.
Rym: every pair of shorts has the belt it came with.
Scott: Are you sure you're just using these belts for wearing and you don't have an abundance of belts for other activities?
Rym: If I was gonna use other activities I can think of different kinds of velour belts but The canvas belts were like two dollars.
Rym: They're as strong as a seat belt.
Rym: They got the two loops in the front.
Rym: Just like though yours do.
Rym: those are for Camping hiking rock climbing that kind of shit.
Rym: Mmm, like hang some stuff off of my bed.
Scott: I don't think I need a different belt for that.
Rym: You don't do that stuff.
Rym: So you don't need that kind of belt.
Rym: I'm not gonna wear a leather belt like I can do the mountains But the belt that goes to the shorts is I'm not gonna take it off of the shorts and like put it on my pants That I'm wearing on the mountain.
Rym: That seems like a pain anyway.
Rym: the Yeah, plus I could use those belts to like splint a leg on the woods if I ever like.
Rym: mess up my leg.
Scott: So the one kind of belt that never really understood I guess it's just not the style of these parts or times is the giant cowboy fancy belt buckle like the really fucking big one.
Rym: I think those things look hideous, but other people have other tastes.
Scott: So I think someone wearing one Looks hideous.
Scott: if you're actually a full-on cowboy at least matches what the rest of your way.
Rym: That's fine.
Rym: Like if you're if you've got like a if you have a bolo tie on You are allowed to wear a narrow range of weird belt buckles, right?
Rym: That's okay.
Scott: The thing is like if someone say has a collection of these things.
Scott: I think that's kind of cool like.
Scott: look at them like because they're.
Scott: it's like it's a more advertising space for your geekery, right?
Scott: It's sort of like you can have a belt buckle for your favorite sports team or your fur.
Scott: You give it like a netrunner belt buckle or does you can.
Scott: it's a. it's space to put something awesome The kind of thing that you would put on a tattoo.
Scott: Yeah, alright a t-shirt on your face, but it's usually Confederate flags or like bullets Obviously, it's usually guns or better bikes or bullets or cows or something stupid right, but just the aesthetic of it is usually very Uncool.
Scott: you have to sort of go all-in on it to make it work.
Scott: And if you're the kind of person that it works for You know some cowboy person I'm usually gonna have a skeptical view of you unless you prove otherwise.
Rym: Actually, you know what?
Rym: It's like the trilby and the fedora.
Rym: They look great on a Person who is wearing all the other clothes that go with that kind of hat.
Rym: in the year 1930 some or even today like I go to fancy like Wall Street parties, right?
Rym: Occasionally you see someone who's wearing like a fancy Wall Street party in the art deco ballroom But they're wearing like a snappy semi period jacket and they're basically in the Waldorf Astoria ballroom Like those kinds of hands in the modern hotel ballroom.
Rym: Those kinds of hats were the old hotel if you double down on it and wear all the things that go with it.
Rym: But if you're wearing an expensive fashion hat like that With a nerd t-shirt a tweed jacket Utilikil toe shoes vape pen It's just like the belt buckle, you know,
Scott: you go around the city and sometimes you see that old guy whose fashion is just like Yeah, it's like damn.
Scott: where the hell that old man get his clothes like chase?
Rym: chase was describing a guy like that.
Rym: It was this old.
Scott: that old guy get his clothes so long ago that he's still wearing them.
Scott: Or is there some?
Scott: I'm sure there's someplace in the city I can go to get the clothes that look so amazing.
Scott: when you're an old man You're so style so jazz, so I learned the secret of how to look like that.
Rym: unless your hobby is fashion you go to a Place and give them a lot of money.
Rym: Yeah, you go to a fashion tailor and you say make me look good Here's a bunch of money and they will give you a bunch of outfits and you just wear those outfits and never question them.
Rym: Mm-hmm, so I'm actually talking to a dude.
Rym: So cuz I got some because I got some shirts right from my co-worker friend who started a shirt business.
Rym: Yes, and you get some like this really like slick bespoke shirts made in Turkey.
Scott: so bespoke.
Rym: Well, he showed talked about the machines and like how many different cut like shirt nerd.
Rym: Well, cuz I got some special shorts for bouldering.
Rym: The difference is these shorts are wearing bouldering.
Rym: the front will just get scraped off by the rocks in the wall.
Rym: It's like sandpaper.
Rym: Okay, and might hurt myself to like I'll scrape myself.
Rym: So the shorts are like really durable like really heavy But they also have more pieces of fabric than like normal shorts do like here.
Rym: crotch kind of just comes together like normal pants.
Rym: do These things have gussets in the crotch for full range of movement all the stuff you need like there.
Rym: They're specialized equipment for a specific sport.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So the reason normal shorts don't have that stuff even though they're a lot more comfortable.
Scott: as you're just walking and cuz it looks stupid.
Rym: No You wouldn't even see you wouldn't even know if I was wearing these shorts.
Rym: unless you like put your face under my crotch And I took a good look.
Rym: It's way more Expensive to have the machine that can do those extra pieces of fabric when you're making the shorts in the factory The shirts are the same way.
Rym: So this guy's like yeah I had to get this machine that can do this kind of cut and this kind of cut and this kind of thing.
Rym: and I learned a bunch of stuff about shirts.
Rym: so he knows some people who make like the ultra like, you know, this like the Three-piece suit that like a famous person wears to like the Oscars.
Rym: that's like a unique suit.
Rym: That's weird.
Rym: They make that kind of stuff.
Rym: So He offered introduced me and I might be able to get like one suit from these people.
Scott: Doesn't still gonna cost you thousands of dollars.
Rym: They might work with me just because they seem like really super cool news.
Scott: It's not cheap because them thousands of dollars to make the suit the material.
Rym: Well, yeah that but maybe I might be able to get a deal where I'll pay for the materials.
Rym: But they're not gonna charge me like what they would charge for their time.
Rym: But it's not gonna be I it's gonna be iron monkey style.
Scott: so you get a $10,000 suit for $6,000.
Scott: maybe.
Scott: yeah That's still I wouldn't buy it.
Rym: I think they might charge more than 10,000 for one of their like ultra.
Rym: Yeah, probably but so I hadn't met them.
Rym: but he described them.
Rym: and then later on to Wall Street party I saw a person and I was like, oh damn because the suit this guy was wearing was crazy.
Scott: What kind of belt was he wearing?
Rym: I didn't even notice because the suit was so crazy.
Scott: That's what happens a lot, right?
Scott: It's like, you know I think about these old guys with their so style that I see in the city and it's like what kind of belt were they?
Scott: Wearing?
Rym: I can't even imagine it cuz the purpose of the belt is just to blend in.
Rym: if you notice the belt the suit fuck.
Scott: The belt is functional unlike the suspenders.
Rym: You're only functional if your pants are really heavy like a fireman Uh, or if you you like 20 style pants don't have belt loops.
Scott: That's true, too.
Rym: So you have to wear suspenders like.
Rym: that's just how it goes.
Scott: hide those suspenders.
Rym: You don't show them off Yeah, unless you're of a businessman style taking your jacket off.
Rym: That's right anyway, so the suit was crazy and it was like on the edge of being the Scuzzy suit that a homeless person in the 20s would wear but Well done on purpose to be fashion like it.
Rym: the suit was crazy.
Rym: And then later I was like was that one of the people he was like, how'd you guess?
Rym: Was it the suit?
Scott: Yeah, if I had you know if I cared if I was actually I pay someone to make me look good Right, but like I would get I want to you know I don't actually want to be looking like the old guy who's so style.
Scott: I want to be like, you know, the ultimate badass dude with the black suit.
Scott: It looks so dangerous.
Rym: Yeah, the guy who's wearing an all black suit black shirt black tie black belt buckle black everything He's got an obsidian ring and a black knuckle buster.
Scott: like that guy must be a secret agent over there.
Scott: Look how badass he is.
Scott: Yes Doesn't say where that is a dangerous individual.
Scott: The problem is I don't have the body of a dangerous individual So I put that suit on it.
Scott: They'll be like who's that guy with the hunch wearing a suit that doesn't fit?
Rym: You can possibly pay someone to give you a dangerous looking body - how does that work personal trainer?
Rym: He's gonna make you go these and take you to a gym and tell you to do stuff But I can't even do the push-up.
Rym: He'll figure it out.
Scott: I'm not gonna magically do the push-up.
Rym: if they tell me to maybe you'll make you do the knee push-up.
Scott: I've tried to do.
Rym: I can't make you do the wall push-up.
Scott: I Mean, that's a push sideways.
Rym: Yeah, I can push sideways until you can push down.
Scott: Why would I pay money for that?
Rym: so you want to.
Rym: so think of this.
Rym: I can do like a bunch of pull-ups like.
Rym: I Just do a bunch of pull-ups.
Scott: You see the pinky pull-up guy.
Rym: I can't do that.
Rym: Okay, I can.
Scott: some guys just recently set the record for pinky pull-ups.
Rym: I can do zero.
Rym: I can do me too.
Scott: We're tied.
Rym: I can do a quarter of one and probably break my pinky.
Scott: We're tied great.
Scott: I'm just as strong as you.
Scott: we can do the same number.
Rym: I can do like eight nine ten pull-ups like easy, but So rock climbing.
Rym: there's an exercise thing called a campus board, which is basically these little wooden nubblies.
Rym: It's not the people who decide to kick you out of college Sticking out of a wall like thin pieces of wood sticking out of a wall Like you grab them like this with your fingertips.
Rym: I've seen that but then they go up the wall at an angle like this Mm-hmm.
Scott: So I haven't seen that.
Rym: I can get like Two or three steps up that thing before I fall off Flailing like a monster the whole time.
Rym: just woodley woodley woodley woodley.
Rym: But then I see people who are way better than me rock climbing who basically just walk up the thing with two fingers if you change like Boop-boop-boop-boop-boop Yeah.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: I guess if I paid a personal trainer they could make me like that over time.
Scott: Are you gonna do that?
Scott: No The other thing that yeah, you know, we're getting way off the belt topic right for your higher personal trainer.
Scott: How do you know they're not like Randy bullshit personal trainer and they're legit personal trainer.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: maybe their certifications?
Scott: Maybe you're gonna start being like.
Scott: alright, you know We did these exercises.
Scott: go home and drink these herbs and take this nutrition.
Rym: No, are you a dietitian or neutral?
Rym: which one's the real one?
Rym: dietitian dieticians?
Rym: the real one nutritionist is the fake one.
Scott: Anyone can call themselves a nutritionist.
Scott: Yeah anyone I could be I'm a nutritionist.
Scott: eat Drink only juice water and milk and milkshakes and hot chocolate.
Scott: Don't drink coffee.
Scott: Don't drink soda.
Scott: Don't drink alcohol.
Scott: eat whatever you want, especially if it's delicious.
Scott: That is the Scott nutritionist advice.
Scott: I think we're done here on poison.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I don't think we need to talk about timing belts.
Rym: No This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.