Guest 0: [Laughter] Alright, let's do a show.
Rym: So we are here with Joe and Conrad.
Scott: People who are here too often.
Scott: Yay!
Scott: Actually, Joe has not been here before.
Rym: Partly when we wanted to start up our old, we used to do those profiles in geek.
Rym: I think the last one we really did was Gerald from anime world order.
Scott: That was not a shtick that lasted long.
Guest 0: I was worried it was me.
Rym: I want to bring it back.
Rym: I want to bring it back hard.
Scott: Well, it's all you.
Rym: We've never had Josephine on the show.
Rym: [Coughing] Uh oh.
Guest 0: And we never will.
Guest 0: Rym died.
Guest 0: Portons.
Rym: But no, we've never had Josephine on the show.
Rym: And also, shameless self-promotion because there's a Kickstarter that we kind of want you guys to plug a little bit right now.
Guest 1: Go to hustlecatgame.com.
Guest 0: Hustlecatgame.com.
Rym: So what is Hustlecat?
Guest 1: Hustlecat is a visual novel that's set in a cat cafe.
Scott: Is it a cat cafe?
Scott: like it's a normal cafe and then you can pet cats in the back?
Guest 1: I mean, it's a cat cafe where there's food and coffee and cats and cakes.
Scott: Do you buy cats there?
Guest 1: You can.
Guest 0: You cannot buy cats.
Guest 1: No?
Guest 1: They're all up for adoption like many of the fine cat cafes in both New York and D.C.
Scott: So it's like a normal world cat cafe.
Scott: It's not a supernatural cat cafe.
Guest 1: It's a normal world cat cafe except for there's a magical curse for all of your.
Scott: You just said it wasn't supernatural and then you immediately talked about a magical curse.
Guest 1: The cat cafe itself is fine.
Guest 1: Oh, okay.
Guest 1: Yes.
Guest 1: It's just the people who work in the cat cafe also turn into cats and take shifts as cats.
Guest 1: And it's a dating sim and there are six cute people and Scott is making the world's worst face to me but it is a dating sim.
Guest 1: We are $8,000 away from goal on Kickstarter.
Guest 1: Actually a little less than that.
Scott: It's not that much money at all.
Guest 1: And we've got seven days left and no, it's going great.
Guest 1: We've got some great artists on deck.
Guest 1: We've got a really passionate musician who's ready to do these kind of like chill but upbeat, you know, happy tracks.
Scott: I want to date a guy that would be playing on the radio in the cat cafe.
Guest 0: Well, they're kind of actually like.
Guest 0: a lot of the stuff he's been working on recently has been like Shibuya K influenced, which like I think brings like like honestly, if you like Capsule.
Scott: Is the cat cafe in Japan?
Guest 0: It is in magic town, magic world.
Scott: That's good.
Guest 1: It's in the quote unquote big city.
Guest 1: And some of the great features besides the music and art are that you get to define the look of your character by like hair length and skin tone.
Scott: Oh, you made like a cat character creator thing.
Guest 1: Yeah.
Guest 1: You get to pick your pronoun.
Scott: Are you a cat?
Rym: Now the pronoun is independent of the look, right?
Scott: Correct.
Scott: Yeah.
Guest 1: Everything is like specifically, you know, non-binary gendered and you just basically get to do everything like you can in Saints Row 4, which was my favorite part of Saints Row 4.
Guest 1: The fact that you could give like the male voice actor to a beautiful, large female bodied woman.
Scott: Oh, is there voice acting?
Guest 1: No, there won't be voice acting.
Scott: Not even like meow, meow.
Guest 1: Do you want to do voice acting?
Guest 1: Are you auditioning?
Rym: We found our muse.
Guest 0: It's getting in the tank.
Scott: So can you?
Scott: can you turn into a cat too, or there's only the other people?
Guest 1: That is a secret.
Scott: OK.
Scott: If I date the right person, well I learn.
Rym: That definitely means yes.
Scott: Can you turn into a dog?
Scott: Are there dogs?
Guest 1: A hustle dog coming to the...
Scott: There isn't a dog.
Scott: cat interaction situation.
Guest 0: Two million dollar stretch goal, hustle dog.
Rym: You know, the only one of these cafes I've ever been to in the real world is a rabbit cafe.
Rym: And the funniest thing about it was that there are all these rabbits, they're like normal rabbits, but there's one rabbit who is the boss rabbit, Pumpu.
Rym: Like, he was a manly little rabbit and he was very social and kind of aggressive and not at all like rabbits I've known.
Rym: So he would like come over and like check you out and play with you and do a lot of weird stuff.
Rym: And he literally tried to steal my wallet.
Scott: I'll only ask you a few more stupid questions.
Scott: Is there catnip?
Guest 1: There should be catnip.
Guest 0: There should be catnip.
Scott: Catnip is good.
Guest 0: So neither of us are the writers.
Scott: Is there like a scratching post situation?
Guest 0: So, again, neither of us are the writers.
Guest 0: We're programming and Jo is on production.
Scott: So you didn't get anything from the writers yet?
Guest 0: We've gotten a lot of stuff from the writers.
Guest 1: Yeah.
Scott: But you don't know if there's catnip involved yet.
Guest 1: I do know that a cat eats Chinese food and a cat eats pizza.
Scott: There might accidentally be catnip in a lot of Chinese food.
Scott: That could be a thing.
Scott: Really?
Scott: Or pizza.
Scott: Who knows?
Guest 0: You thought it was oregano, but it was actually catnip.
Guest 0: You're high as hell on these dollar slices.
Guest 1: It's a true fact that we took out all of the MSG and replaced it exclusively with catnip.
Guest 0: Catnip, I knew it.
Rym: So the interesting thing, and part of the reason why I wanted to get you on the show for GeekNights as a profile geek.
Scott: Because we need a Thursday episode badly.
Rym: Yeah, because I'm going out of town.
Rym: I got to go to a wedding on Thursday, so I'm going to be gone.
Scott: That's why.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But also, I want to bring profiles and geek back.
Rym: So this is basically an original project, right?
Guest 1: Yes.
Rym: So what goes into making a game of this scale?
Rym: Just as a company, as you guys producing this kind of thing.
Guest 1: Well, I think the first thing I did when I came on the project was make a calendar for everybody.
Guest 1: So organization is required.
Guest 1: No matter what scale of a game you make.
Guest 1: This past year, we've put out a 35,000 word game, a 17,000 word game.
Guest 1: And now this one's looking to be a pretty significant.
Scott: That's interesting.
Scott: You mentioned my words.
Guest 1: Yeah, it's a visual novel.
Guest 1: It's mostly all reading.
Guest 1: So the word count is kind of accurately gauges how much effort someone is willing to put into it.
Guest 1: The biggest Kickstarter ever for a visual novel.
Guest 1: localization just happened.
Scott: Was that you or someone else?
Guest 0: It was Muff Love.
Guest 0: Oh, yeah.
Guest 1: But another one was very popular.
Guest 1: And Grisaia rings in at about 400,000 words.
Guest 1: Oh, wow.
Guest 1: And people are incredibly excited about it.
Scott: So for scale, I guess like how many words was like Tokimeki Memorial on the PlayStation?
Guest 0: Toki Memo is like a different benchmark because that game kind of had those like RNG elements and a lot of gameplay elements that you don't necessarily find in the visual novel.
Rym: I was thinking it was like a stat builder.
Guest 0: Yeah, yeah.
Guest 0: I think Joe's benchmark of Grisaia being close to half a million words is kind of the benchmark.
Guest 0: I know Muff Love, the series, was close to that.
Guest 0: Fate/Stay was just like a mind-numbing word count.
Rym: Well, The Hobbit is 95,000 words.
Scott: So if you play the game through reading really fast and pressing A a whole bunch and sort of making decisions rather quickly, like how many words per hour is kind of like typical?
Guest 0: Can we just benchmark everything by The Hobbit?
Guest 0: We all read The Hobbit when we were counting to take you to read The Hobbit.
Rym: I have no idea how long anything took when I was a kid.
Scott: Well, because I mean, we just read like four freaking Wheel of Time books in like a month.
Scott: And those are like this big.
Rym: Have you guys read The Wheel of Time?
Guest 1: I have not.
Guest 1: I have and I'm so sorry.
Rym: How far did you get?
Rym: Book three.
Guest 1: Oh, when I realized that Perrin and Matt were doing the exact same thing, exact same time.
Scott: Only Perrin's way cooler.
Rym: Perrin's awesome.
Rym: And Matt just needs to shut up.
Rym: He needs to be quiet.
Rym: Calm down.
Rym: Be quiet.
Guest 1: Oh, he found a knife.
Guest 1: It's scary for like 3000 pages.
Rym: Matt, why are you acting so strange?
Scott: Why do you keep doing things this spontaneously without thinking about them at all?
Scott: You guys are just selling me on this book.
Rym: You know, I keep.
Rym: we make fun of it so much, but we read four of them in a row.
Scott: And they're this big.
Guest 0: They're like four and a half Song of Ice and Fire books.
Guest 0: So I feel you.
Guest 0: Whoa.
Guest 0: We've all been there.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I knew not to start this.
Rym: I read every Forgotten Realms book except the ones.
Guest 1: But yeah, no, they're branching paths.
Guest 1: So sometimes people like to backtrack and make different dating decisions.
Guest 1: So it kind of changes based on how much patience you have.
Guest 1: We have friends who just roll through these games and like consume them voraciously.
Rym: So how do you how do you write or plan something like that in terms of like someone writing a novel?
Rym: Like a lot of people might use specialized software, but it comes down to there's chapters and there's just one big work.
Rym: How do you write a branching thing?
Rym: Like you just use notepad or word or Google Docs or like how do they?
Rym: are there?
Rym: tools like specialized tools?
Guest 1: Some people like to draw it out.
Guest 1: I really like because I'm also in the middle of writing a game for date night.
Guest 1: Oh, but I like to plan it out in in a program called Twine, which helps you kind of illustrate like it gives you a GUI for like kind of branching decisions.
Guest 1: Special plug.
Guest 1: We are talking about branching narratives at gamer X in mid-December.
Guest 1: So if you're going to be in San Jose and I think it's December 10th through 13th.
Guest 1: That's a good place to be in December.
Scott: It won't be free.
Guest 1: Right.
Guest 1: So the two of us and the writer of puzzle cat are going to be there talking about this kind of thing and talking about what it's like to write like a bi character and, you know, kind of make sexuality decisions based on, you know, who the character defines themselves as.
Guest 1: That'll be neat.
Rym: But something that always bothered me in any game that ever let you date people is that some options just wouldn't like couldn't.
Scott: We were playing ruin factory four and all Rym wants to do is date everyone's mom.
Rym: And I'm like, well, no, I wanted to date the dragon and it wasn't working out.
Rym: Like she was being super nice to me, but she wouldn't date me.
Rym: And then I look online, you can't date the dragon.
Rym: So that was bullshit.
Rym: Then I decided to date all the moms instead.
Rym: And you can't date them either.
Rym: If you rank the characters I wanted to date, literally everyone I want is at the top of the list and none of them are dateable.
Rym: And then you get down to like the stupid warrior girl.
Rym: I don't care where your girls.
Scott: It was my choice.
Guest 0: Well, I know.
Guest 0: I know this was actually somewhat of a point of contention for a dragon age.
Guest 0: The character Cassandra, I believe, would only date men and not women.
Guest 0: And so this is actually a point.
Scott: But that's that character.
Scott: It's not you.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: Right, right.
Guest 0: But this has actually become a kind of a point of conversation.
Guest 0: It's something I'm really interested in tackling on.
Scott: this panel is like, there's a lot of people on.
Scott: most people on this earth won't date me.
Scott: It's like, what can I do about it?
Guest 0: I mean, you know, half of the population is a good looking guy.
Scott: OK, over here.
Rym: We're thinking about updating the GeekNights shirt.
Rym: I'm actually wearing our own GeekNights shirt right now.
Rym: I'm thinking about doing a stretch goal on the Patreon and having a classic Scott and new Scott variant.
Rym: Oh, replace the top hair with the face hair.
Guest 0: Oh, southern migration.
Guest 1: What was that?
Guest 1: Oh, was it like Willy Willy?
Guest 1: What was that toy that had like the iron filings in it where you could change the hair?
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: Like any dollar store.
Scott: It's a great toy.
Rym: I'll bet you that's a Cracker Barrel kind of thing.
Guest 1: Can you make Scott's face into one of those?
Rym: I guess I could.
Rym: That'll be a backer reward, I guess.
Scott: So how much?
Rym: in terms of a project like this, because I know a lot of our fans and people, they want to do Kickstarters.
Rym: They do like small projects or anything.
Rym: How much work do you do for a project like this before the Kickstarter get launched?
Rym: Like how much of the game is already designed or written or concepted out before someone clicks like launch and Kickstarter?
Guest 1: More work than you expect, no matter how much work you do.
Guest 1: As the person who took it upon herself to write every word that you see in the Kickstarter, like on the Kickstarter page when you go to hustlecatgame.com.
Guest 1: Going to plug that again.
Guest 1: It's a lot of work just to put the text together.
Guest 1: And then you realize that you need things like demos and assets and reasons to get people to buy a game.
Guest 1: As it turns out, they won't do that without anything to look at.
Rym: They will if it's a tabletop game, apparently.
Scott: Isn't that always sort of weird, though?
Scott: It wasn't the point of Kickstarter to be like, "Hey, I have an idea for something.
Scott: I haven't done it yet.
Scott: I need money in order to do
Scott: it.".
Scott: But the reality is you actually have to do a whole bunch of work for no money.
Scott: And if Kickstarter fails, then you can't do the thing at all and you just wasted a bunch of time.
Guest 1: I guess visual novels, I mean, you have two aspects just to the word.
Guest 1: You have to have visuals and you have to know what the story's about.
Guest 1: So you see a lot of visual novel Kickstarters and all they've got are, "These are the five cute characters.
Guest 1: You'll get to
Guest 1: smooch.".
Guest 1: And it's usually like five hot dudes.
Guest 1: Sometimes you are a dude.
Guest 1: Sometimes you are a lady.
Guest 1: But usually for visual novels, you'll just see the five hot dudes and which members of the band they are.
Guest 1: And also, you're a high school girl who's very scared.
Rym: Because I've noticed that with tabletop Kickstarters and a lot of other kinds of game projects where people will kickstart their idea and they've literally done no actual work up to that point.
Rym: And those games, people back them for some reason.
Rym: But then the games are terrible.
Scott: It's so tough because on the one hand, I feel like you're trying to mitigate your risk of taking on a big project with no funding.
Scott: But all you've got is an idea to start with.
Scott: You don't want to start doing work on something that you're not going to be able to fund and waste your time and effort.
Scott: So you want to start a Kickstarter with not a lot of work done.
Scott: But as someone who's going to kickstart something, why would I kickstart something if you haven't demonstrated to me that it's definitely going to happen?
Guest 1: Yeah, I guess all of my friends who are trying to make tabletop games have just workshopped it to death at Gen Con.
Guest 1: They've been working for years just tweaking the text and getting people to test play.
Guest 1: And like that, I think the effort pays off exponentially.
Guest 1: So the total goal for our Kickstarter is twenty five thousand.
Guest 1: We're way above average for asking price for visual novels.
Guest 1: You'll see them.
Scott: But you have a proven track record.
Scott: You have succeeded in the past many times.
Guest 0: Yeah, we we we launched a game that we kickstarted and we did so within a year of the Kickstarter.
Guest 0: And that is a point of pride for all of us.
Guest 0: You know, I couldn't and I mean, I will I will throw it to Joe here because, like, I would say she was responsible for ensuring that that happened.
Guest 0: But, you know, I'm incredibly proud of that.
Guest 0: And then we made we know the devil with AV in 10 to 12 weeks.
Guest 0: Yeah.
Guest 0: Top to bottom.
Guest 0: You know, we we we ship man.
Guest 1: And it's a point of pride for me.
Scott: Yeah, 12 weeks is crazy.
Guest 0: It should be.
Guest 0: Yeah.
Guest 1: And it just requires organization.
Guest 1: And like in terms of my job, it comes down to sending out an email a day saying, where's my stuff?
Guest 1: Why are people so mad at that?
Rym: Why?
Rym: It seems like one of the most important business skills in the world is can you read and respond to emails in a timely fashion?
Rym: Like that gets you already above like four fifths of the population.
Guest 0: I'll tell you right now, I'm terrible at it.
Guest 0: I know you are sitting next to me like it wouldn't get like she.
Guest 0: You know, this this collaborative partnership between us, I think is is like just the dopest.
Guest 0: We're you know, we're moving so fast right now.
Guest 0: And it's it's only because Joe's here to wrangle all of us.
Scott: Well, 12 weeks is insane, right?
Guest 0: It was nuts, dude.
Guest 0: I can't even tell you.
Scott: Anyway, were you cheating and like working at night like you do?
Scott: Yes.
Rym: He was working last night.
Rym: So really, we went out drinking last night and then they're like, OK, we should go finish the work we're working on.
Guest 0: I was up until two.
Guest 0: We had to ship a. we had to ship a offline binary of the German translation of Starfighter Eclipse coming very soon.
Guest 0: It is integrated.
Guest 0: Yeah.
Guest 0: So that'll be up.
Guest 0: God.
Guest 0: Very, very soon.
Guest 1: Very soon.
Rym: Are you going to be working tonight?
Guest 1: Yes.
Guest 0: Yeah.
Guest 0: You know, we have to do it.
Guest 0: You know, for what it's worth, you know, running running a small like no business is profitable in its early years, like not a single one unless, you know, you're you're just doing insider trading and mad, mad investment scams, which we're not.
Guest 0: You know, we we're like an honest, legitimate company.
Guest 0: We make and sell products, you know, and it's very difficult for small businesses in particular.
Rym: And, you know, we're no exception, especially because you didn't take you didn't get like five million dollars in seed capital.
Scott: Yes, a star, because honestly, you got to do with someone else.
Scott: Exactly.
Guest 0: I want to touch on this point, too, is the trend in in games and the way games get made, I find very disheartening.
Guest 0: I wanted to make games the way I wanted to make games.
Guest 0: I wanted to bring a diverse crew on board to tell their stories.
Guest 0: And what I didn't want was, you know, some some Peter Thiel to come to my house and be like, oh, yeah, but like, can can you fuck these girls?
Scott: Can you fuck them?
Guest 0: Like, he's a West Coast VC.
Guest 0: Sorry.
Scott: OK, so I know who he is now.
Guest 1: But yeah, as a side note, Mountain Dew, if you want us to make a dating sim between six different Mountain Dew flavors and give us five million dollars.
Guest 0: We do take contract work.
Guest 0: Don't get me wrong, but we will not dilute equity.
Guest 0: We will take contract work, though.
Guest 0: So so fancy.
Guest 0: Get at me.
Scott: Actually, a Mountain Dew dating sim would probably because I can just be all the beverages PepsiCo owns like a whole bunch of just be hard.
Rym: It was for Roger Rabbit to have Disney and Warner Brothers characters in it at the same time.
Guest 0: So hard M&M's.
Guest 0: We're not even thinking about it.
Scott: Red and green.
Guest 1: Oh, no.
Guest 1: Gross.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I worry, actually.
Scott: Red goes away for the whole middle of the game.
Rym: I don't care what you worry.
Rym: I'm still thinking about M&M's fucking.
Rym: What do they?
Rym: what do they crack them?
Scott: Even M&M's makes that joke in their own commercials.
Scott: So, you know, that's not really much of a stretch to your hand, but not in your mouth.
Rym: There's a plot point where someone's colorblind.
Rym: They can't tell them apart.
Rym: Oh, no.
Rym: But I also worry not not to rag on M&M's.
Rym: I don't.
Rym: But I imagine there are properties like M&M's where the people would say things like, oh, no, no, can't be gay.
Rym: Oh, no, they can't.
Rym: Those two can't date because Lego wouldn't allow this.
Guest 0: Yeah.
Guest 0: And this is exactly the kind of stuff that I want to avoid.
Guest 0: Like, I want to avoid that kind of investor influence where it's like, well, you know, well, we don't.
Guest 0: we don't think this demo wants to see like this kind of presentation or this kind of inclusion.
Guest 0: And I got.
Guest 0: no I got no time for that shit.
Guest 0: Like, if I'm going to if I'm going to make this company succeed, I'm going to do it on my own terms.
Guest 0: And, you know, that that's just how it is.
Scott: I wonder if instead of contract, like getting a contract from someone like they're paying you basically to make an advertisement for them to do the reverse deal where you buy a license to a property and use it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The same way that, like, IDW buys the license to make My Little Pony comics.
Guest 0: It can be hard because that does require a significant upfront investment.
Guest 0: We've explored this kind of opportunity before.
Guest 0: We, you know, are definitely open to doing partnership stuff where rather than like buying a property and and, you know, something of that nature, there's like a severe back end split or something like that.
Guest 0: That's the kind of stuff we would take on in a heartbeat, you know?
Rym: Yeah, I guess it is because I mean, I way back, I at least started looking to getting licenses to some anime for things just to see like what it would cost.
Rym: And yeah, that is not feasible.
Scott: You negotiate, obviously.
Rym: But no, it is not feasible, even if you've got money for a lot of properties, because it's there's a there's cash upfront and heavy restrictions, at least from what I could gather.
Rym: And this is for like unknown properties.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So ostensibly, Ram, you wanted to do this as a profiling geek.
Scott: We've never had just so they're game the whole time.
Guest 1: Yeah, exactly.
Rym: But this is fun.
Rym: But John, so this person you are making these projects, but what's the real you like?
Rym: So I got to know what are three anime that you like and watched and would watch again?
Guest 1: Oh, my God.
Guest 1: That is an incredibly tough question.
Scott: Because we know you like anime.
Scott: We didn't ask that question.
Rym: But we used to like.
Rym: you can't ask the question, like, what's your favorite movie?
Rym: Because then, like, it's hard for people to narrow it down.
Rym: It's like, what are three?
Guest 1: All right.
Rym: For me, it's like Utena, Cowboy Bebop, Escaflowne.
Guest 1: OK, off the top of my head.
Guest 1: I grew up watching Fushigi Yugi.
Guest 1: Oh, I'll never let it go.
Guest 1: I'll never let it go.
Rym: That was all.
Rym: That might have been one of the first anime that did the thing where the theme song comes in before the end of the episode.
Rym: Sometimes really sad shit.
Scott: The alien nine thing.
Rym: Oh, that's the other thing.
Rym: Right.
Scott: OK.
Guest 1: Number two around host club.
Guest 1: Hands down.
Guest 1: And I'll go past year.
Guest 1: I've watched Gachamon Crowds.
Guest 1: Still love it.
Guest 1: We started before we started recording.
Guest 1: We had a little conversation about Gachamon Crowd.
Guest 1: It's just it's cute and it's it's optimistic.
Guest 1: And I like that, like some anime, they'll do like a midseason spin and get really grim, like Hajime from Gachamon Crowds.
Guest 1: She stays really upbeat no matter what happens.
Guest 1: She doesn't have that moment like that anime heroine anxiety moment that Utena has, for instance, where she's like, what if I can't do this?
Guest 1: I quit.
Guest 1: And then half an episode later, she's like, wait, that's why I'm doing it.
Guest 1: I reverse quit.
Guest 1: Yeah.
Guest 1: Now I can fight all these monsters again.
Guest 1: Hajime is consistently believes that she and her team can fight all the monsters, even when the stakes are super duper bad.
Rym: All right.
Scott: So same question games.
Guest 1: Oh, gosh.
Guest 1: OK, I can.
Guest 1: I can barely even narrow down three games in the past year because we've blown through the campaign for lovers in a dangerous space time.
Scott: My friends are going to the Netrunner World Championships and one of them doesn't like to fly.
Scott: So they're taking the train and he's like, Scott, can I can I borrow a controller?
Scott: You can show the brain so we can play the game on the train.
Guest 1: Oh, my gosh.
Guest 1: It's incredible.
Guest 1: And the best thing is, like we listen to Polygon's quality control podcast.
Guest 1: And Griffin McElroy was like, look, this game is incredibly hard.
Guest 1: You have to be a good gamer to play this.
Guest 1: And I looked over at Conrad and I was like, I'm a good gamer.
Guest 1: Did you know?
Guest 1: Because neither of us did.
Guest 0: Apparently, I knew she's better than me at Gears and Halo.
Guest 1: Two dropsy the clown.
Scott: I don't even know what that is.
Scott: Tell me about that.
Guest 1: I dig a point and click adventure game, but I tried playing the release of groom Fandango.
Guest 1: It was just so old and so slow.
Guest 1: dropsy the clown kind of hits that sweet spot, that machinarium hit.
Guest 1: for me where you solve these like very enclosed, perfect puzzles.
Guest 1: The art is cute.
Guest 1: The the creator of the game, I think comes from like something awful stock.
Guest 1: So the humor is very gonzo, but also like a little bit sweet.
Guest 1: Like it's about a clown who was was raised by like a normal human dude.
Guest 1: Think like Superman, George and Martha Kent.
Guest 1: And and he gets accused of starting a fire that kills his mom.
Guest 1: And so he has to go around town, his town, helping people out with their problems to redeem his character.
Guest 1: And one of the actions you can always take is hug.
Guest 1: You can hug a tree to make it happy.
Guest 1: You can hug a squirrel.
Guest 1: You you hug various things to solve various problems.
Rym: And the hug ever go badly.
Guest 1: Oh, yes.
Guest 1: The hug can go badly like cactus.
Guest 1: Like if you don't solve someone's problem and try to hug them, they yell at you in a truly devastating fashion.
Guest 0: There's also no words in the game.
Guest 0: It's all pictograms and gestures, which I thought was very cool.
Guest 1: Yeah.
Guest 1: But like and even though there's no words, there's like limited kind of sound effects of voice acting.
Guest 1: So you can tell audibly when someone's mad at you.
Scott: How do I get?
Scott: this game is on steam or whatever.
Guest 1: it is on steam.
Guest 1: Yeah.
Guest 1: And you can buy it from the guy.
Guest 1: You can tweet at him.
Guest 1: He's super cool.
Guest 1: And like the game is just great.
Guest 1: You know, you don't really need a guide to help you.
Guest 1: And I think the difference between like new school and old school point and click adventures is that the old school adventures would give you a stopping point.
Guest 1: And if you couldn't solve this puzzle, you just couldn't keep going in the game.
Guest 1: Like I'm thinking of the first hour of Grim Fandango, where if you don't have bread to help the balloon animal guy, you just can't proceed.
Guest 1: But Dropsy has this huge map.
Guest 1: And if you get stuck at a point, you can just go and solve someone else's problem for a moment.
Guest 1: And then it makes you feel good.
Guest 1: And there are big, like longer puzzles to solve and very short, discrete puzzles to solve.
Guest 1: And you always feel great when you when you figure it out.
Rym: It's interesting.
Rym: That's an aspect that when you think about all the adventure games, like a lot of the ones that are really popular were just a linear plot through a story of click to make it continue.
Rym: But then there's the few like some of the king's quest, but not many of them.
Rym: The quest for glories that had that more open world wander around.
Scott: I've tried to play some point and click adventures in recent years, but mostly like LucasArtsy ones.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And I just got faxed from the Internet because I'm like, screw this nonsense.
Scott: Anything I don't remember from my childhood, I don't have time for this.
Scott: Right.
Guest 1: I just remember the most sounds good.
Guest 1: The most frustrating point for me as a point and click adventure enthusiast was playing the longest journey and having to suffer through the travel time of going into the police department, getting a can of soda and then actually having to go 15 minutes through various screens in the game to go to a paint can shaker.
Guest 1: So you could shake up the soda in a paint can shaker, go back to the police department and give it to a cop just so he busts open like a foamy soda can.
Guest 1: It was infuriating.
Rym: Police Quest, you had to actually get in the car and know your way around town.
Scott: You had to go in the elevator, push the know which floor to go to to go to your office.
Guest 0: I'm not trying to put you on blast here, but you can't venerate Quest for Glory to and then complain about maze traversal and police.
Rym: But at least in Quest for Glory to why?
Rym: I mean, it was the DRM of the day, like that maze was unsolvable unless you had the physical map.
Rym: That's how they did DRM to the game.
Rym: Did a turnabout.
Rym: because if you play Quest for Glory through to the end, there's a point where you're because once you get somewhere, you can just click and get there.
Rym: You don't have to ever like go in the mazes again.
Rym: But later in the game, something happens and you click to go somewhere and suddenly the game shows you in the middle of the maze.
Rym: You're like, what?
Rym: And then there's stuff going on.
Guest 0: That was cool.
Guest 0: All right.
Guest 0: Yeah, that was dope.
Rym: Quest for Glory 2 had its problems.
Rym: Yeah, but it was awesome.
Rym: It was the best.
Rym: It was so good.
Rym: Those games are more like staff builders, though.
Rym: There was a lot of game going on.
Guest 0: Yeah.
Guest 0: And I think I could only play them when I was young.
Rym: I could play them again, too.
Rym: I could play again.
Guest 1: I think I'm still on the hook for one game, so I'm going to plug Black Closet.
Guest 1: It's the new game by the team that did Long Live the Queen, which is the staff builder game.
Scott: Long Live the Queen was good.
Guest 1: And it is fantastic.
Guest 1: It's very like in the mood, Utena-esque.
Guest 1: You play the president of the student council of kind of like a fake world girls academy.
Rym: So am I a guy or girl?
Rym: is the matter?
Rym: Am I a girl?
Guest 1: You are a girl.
Guest 1: You're definitely a girl.
Guest 1: And you have to save the reputation of your school and the reputation of the student council.
Guest 1: And like various small scale problems happen and you have to send your minions to go solve the problems for you.
Rym: So you're Nanami.
Guest 1: Yeah.
Guest 1: So your minions have various stats and you use them to different effects.
Guest 1: So sometimes you question a girl who you think stole like another girl's homework and then the girl seems suspicious.
Guest 1: And after that, you can harass her or you can stalk her and see what she's up to.
Guest 1: But if you get caught, the consequences hurt.
Guest 1: Like they burn the student council's reputation.
Scott: You're not actually stalking a minion.
Scott: is stalking a minion and coming back to you with information.
Scott: Yeah.
Guest 1: Or or failing horribly.
Guest 1: The whole thing works off of a series of stats and then d 20 dice rolls.
Guest 1: It feels very satisfying when you win and it feels very devastating when you lose.
Scott: So it's so.
Scott: it's got more randomness than long.
Scott: live the queen because you live the queen.
Scott: It was like if your stat is up to here, you're going to succeed.
Scott: And if it's not, you're not pretty much right.
Guest 1: Yeah.
Guest 1: So it has a little element of randomness and then you can also like.
Guest 1: it has a bit of an RPG element, too.
Guest 1: So you can.
Guest 1: you can level up your minions very, very slowly.
Guest 1: So you have to be very deliberate.
Guest 1: I've heard from a couple of people that it takes like at least three runs before you feel super comfortable with, you know, how you're managing your team and how you go about solving the various crimes.
Guest 1: It's amazing, though, the experience of playing it is just so satisfying that I could be into that.
Rym: You could be like, what's your name in Yurikuma managing the invisible storm?
Scott: All right.
Scott: So obviously you're a nerdy person.
Scott: No one on the show would not be a nerdy person.
Scott: What are you into that is not nerdy or unexpected?
Guest 1: I collect handbags.
Guest 1: There you go.
Guest 1: I collect brand name handbags and like the really expensive ones.
Guest 1: Not the really super expensive ones, but my handbag collection is more expensive than my clothes and shoes collection.
Guest 1: Oh, gosh.
Guest 1: It made me more expensive than my Pokemon collection.
Rym: Do you lock them up in Lucite and protect them for future generations?
Scott: No, I use them to carry things.
Guest 1: Yes, I use them to carry things.
Guest 1: I get them super messy.
Guest 1: I spilled drinks in them.
Guest 1: I spilled a beer on myself right before we started recording.
Scott: Do you care about like the bootleg ones or is it got to be legit?
Guest 1: You know, it feels better if it's legit and mid range than if it's bootleg and like high scale.
Guest 1: Though I have been told I'm for the record, I'm Taiwanese.
Guest 1: And my family insists that if I ever want to visit, I don't have to pay for a plane ticket.
Guest 1: I should just send them a bunch of coach bags and they'll sell them on the street for three times the price to pay for my airfare.
Guest 1: Wow.
Guest 1: Maybe that's where the legacy comes from away.
Scott: So you could just buy legitimate ones.
Scott: Right.
Guest 1: The legitimate price, like at outlet stores.
Guest 1: Right.
Guest 1: And then would sell legally by real ones.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But they'll resell over there for more money than you pay.
Guest 1: An Abercrombie and Fitch T-shirt will sell for one hundred dollars.
Scott: But customs won't stop you.
Scott: Send bring these over.
Guest 1: They might.
Rym: T-shirt might be easier.
Rym: But yeah, it's tough.
Scott: I mean, you know, guys don't really need this Kickstarter action if you got the side job.
Guest 0: We want to get out of.
Guest 0: you know, we've sold bags on Canal Street for a long time.
Guest 0: We're looking to move uptown.
Scott: So what is like?
Scott: so, you know, you have this big head.
Scott: What are like your favorite handbags like the, you know, the ones you like to use the most often?
Guest 1: OK, so so this is where the nerd stuff comes back in.
Rym: You got to be a nerd.
Scott: And what makes these ones better than the other ones?
Guest 1: I measure everyone by how precisely my current devices fit into them.
Guest 1: So I have a Marc Jacobs bag that I bought entirely because my my MacBook Air 11 inch fits perfectly inside the slot.
Guest 1: No, no extra space.
Guest 1: My my current like little backpack.
Guest 1: Same reason I have like an iPad mini that and I have several handbags that perfectly fit it.
Rym: So if you buy a new iPhone and it's a different form factor, does that change the ranking?
Guest 1: Yes, absolutely.
Guest 1: Oh, no, absolutely.
Guest 1: I get different bags.
Guest 1: They have to.
Guest 1: I have to size out the pockets.
Guest 1: It gets really insane.
Guest 1: And that's probably why the collection is so big.
Scott: Is there like a bag community you're in?
Scott: It's like trading or like forums online where the bag people hang out.
Guest 1: I suffer with my own shame.
Guest 1: OK.
Rym: That's not shame.
Guest 1: That's that's a nerdy thing.
Rym: So what's the worst one?
Rym: You feel like you have one that just like really sucks.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Bad handbag.
Scott: Yeah.
Guest 1: It's hard to open.
Guest 1: It's really stiff.
Guest 1: It sits weird on my shoulder and kind of hurts my skin sometimes when I wear a tank top.
Guest 1: So, yeah, no, that one's rough.
Guest 1: Try before you buy.
Rym: So in terms of regular old American TV and movies, or at least American ish, like what's a good movie you've seen recently that you would advocate other people seeing?
Guest 1: Am I allowed to say Mad Max Fury?
Rym: I was assuming you were going to say that because no movie has been better than that since that came out.
Guest 1: No, absolutely.
Guest 1: And I will say all of my favorite movies this year have involved Fury in some way.
Guest 1: Mad Max Fury Road, Furious seven.
Guest 1: I cried like a baby.
Rym: Well, because it got all sad and real.
Rym: I heard.
Guest 1: Oh, super.
Guest 1: It was super real.
Guest 1: And if you've if you've watched them from the very beginning and I did a marathon, you know, one through seven, including Tokyo Drift.
Guest 1: And man, that build up the way they dealt with Paul Walker's unfortunate death, like just incredible.
Guest 1: Of course, Mad Max Fury Road.
Rym: I died.
Rym: Not the actor.
Guest 1: Yeah, no, not the character.
Rym: The actor died.
Rym: The human died.
Scott: That shows that I know the human is dead.
Guest 0: Very sad, actually.
Guest 0: Good guy.
Guest 1: And gosh, Inside Out comes out on DVD next week.
Guest 1: I've had it preordered since the day that I watched it.
Rym: I only saw it recently.
Rym: I was on a plane and I watched Mad Max one and then I watched Inside Out.
Guest 1: And man, Inside Out is just beautiful.
Guest 1: Like they perfectly cast Lewis Black as the angry one.
Rym: What if they just like handcuff?
Scott: What if they just handcuff?
Rym: sadness, though, instead of messing everything up and getting shot away?
Guest 1: Oh, then we wouldn't learn totally important lessons about pubescence.
Rym: Yeah, but she might have worked like the initial problem might have worked out OK.
Guest 0: Also, is that is that just what you do with people who tinker with stuff?
Guest 0: You put them in handcuffs?
Rym: Mr.
Guest 0: Jailbreak, Jailbreak, Android phone.
Guest 0: Is that the plan now, dog?
Rym: Well, it's a Sony phone, so measures need to be taken.
Rym: No, I'm trying to convince Scott to watch Mad Max because he hasn't seen it yet.
Rym: He doesn't realize that it is better than every other Mad Max movie combined.
Guest 1: Oh, man, I just watched Beyond the Thunderdome with an actually Conrad Kraling's mom.
Rym: We got we got us about Conrad's mom.
Guest 1: Yeah, we got wine drunk.
Guest 1: I shit you not.
Guest 1: Her name is actually Sigrid Kraling.
Guest 1: Her father is actually Siegfried.
Rym: And those are those are one giant sword.
Scott: Is it like really like bigger, taller than he is?
Guest 0: I wish, man.
Guest 0: If you if you know where that is, please let me know.
Rym: Siegfried wielded the ring and turned into a dragon.
Scott: I'm talking about Soul Calibur.
Scott: We're talking about the actual Siegfried.
Rym: Of the actual Siegfried?
Scott: I'm talking about the guy who hits you twice over the head and then flips you on your back with the sword in the nuts.
Rym: I was talking about the historical Siegfried.
Guest 1: I'm sorry, boss.
Guest 1: Some of us played Cassandra.
Guest 1: It's not the size of the sword.
Guest 1: It's how you I guess how you hip bump a person off a map.
Rym: So fun fact, apparently, like I'm really good at Soul Calibur, at least two.
Rym: I didn't really play once after that.
Rym: But I'm good.
Scott: I'll find someone who's actually pro and you will just not even hit them once.
Rym: Well, yeah, I actually could talk about like among us.
Rym: I'm good at Voldo somehow.
Scott: You're better at Voldo than any other character.
Rym: Like, I don't know how Voldo just synced with me and that's disturbing.
Guest 1: Yeah, that's because fighting games, the gimp is so terrifying that people just concede to you.
Guest 0: Also, Rym, you got some.
Guest 0: I saw your bedroom door was cracked open earlier.
Guest 0: You got some shit in there, man.
Rym: Like, I'm not surprised.
Guest 0: I think you're channeling.
Scott: Those bunnies.
Rym: Yeah, wow.
Rym: Well, they've got some apple treats that our friend Kat got them for a gift and they're into those things.
Rym: So they'll grab them and run away with them and hide them somewhere.
Rym: But then they see me looking and they run over and get it out of the place that they think I saw it in and hide it somewhere else.
Rym: But they're rabid so I can just see where they're hiding it again.
Rym: So it's not like like they think they're tricking me, I think.
Scott: Maybe there is something hidden that they've actually got a good spot and you don't know that spot because they hid it when you weren't looking.
Rym: It's like when I played a wreck boy and I found all those blocks behind his little trash can or whatever.
Scott: You guys get any pet action over there in Brooklyn?
Guest 1: I have.
Guest 1: well, I have two cats.
Guest 1: They're the world's greatest cats.
Scott: They transform into boys.
Guest 1: Gosh, I'm so glad they don't because they're super sloppy and awful.
Guest 1: No, they they're I have the most dog like cats you'll ever see.
Guest 1: They greet me at the door.
Guest 1: They chase me around the house.
Guest 1: One of them plays fetch.
Guest 1: They're named Quinn for Harley Quinn and Frank for Frank Castle.
Guest 1: Frank Frank Castle canonical Marvel multiverse character Frank Castle.
Rym: Oh, that's the because that's where the all the other animals.
Guest 1: Yeah, yeah.
Guest 1: Peter Parker.
Rym: OK, I learned about that recently.
Rym: I was saving that to be a thing of the day.
Rym: I didn't know that was real.
Rym: I thought it was something someone made up because it's.
Scott: Yeah, someone did make it up.
Scott: You know, Marvel made it up.
Rym: I'm talking about the historic anyway.
Scott: It's old spider has been around a long time.
Guest 1: Yeah, I'm
Scott: so angry
Guest 0: right now.
Scott: Are you angry at Spider-Ham?
Guest 1: Yeah, that's that.
Guest 1: I should be angry.
Guest 0: We should all be angry.
Guest 1: Peter Parker.
Guest 1: Spider-Ham writes itself.
Guest 0: We should all be angry at the existence of Peter.
Guest 1: I saw it's hilarious.
Rym: I saw the Howard deduct movie.
Rym: So nothing like second only to Squirrel Girl.
Rym: Squirrel Girl is pretty cool.
Guest 0: Squirrel Girl is dope.
Rym: Yeah, the new the newer comics.
Scott: The Ryan North Squirrel Girl.
Scott: Yeah.
Guest 1: And I forgot that was Ryan North.
Rym: I did, too.
Rym: Oh, so Marvel or DC?
Scott: Oh, yes.
Scott: You got two different cats fighting there.
Guest 1: I can't help it.
Guest 1: I'm a long term Batman fan.
Rym: OK, do you like any DC other than Batman and things that are tied to Batman?
Guest 1: I love the Justice League cartoon series.
Scott: Oh, you don't like, say, a booster gold or a green lantern.
Guest 1: I do love Superman singles.
Guest 1: So Superman for all seasons is fantastic.
Guest 1: Brian Azzarello's Lex Luthor comic.
Guest 1: Fantastic.
Guest 1: What what else is in DC?
Guest 1: All right.
Guest 1: Question answered.
Guest 1: Teen Titans Go is great.
Rym: Teen Titans Go is literally the greatest Teen Titans.
Rym: I consider that the Teen Titans canon.
Guest 1: Yeah, no, absolutely.
Guest 1: The pie song should be playing all the time.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I like that piece and love piece.
Scott: And I dare you to read 80s Teen Titans and tell me what's happening.
Guest 1: Challenge accepted.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So DC, because what is your favorite Batman version of all the Batmans that have existed?
Rym: There's a lot of Batmans.
Guest 0: There's a bat ham.
Guest 0: I'm leaving the show.
Rym: I guess Batman's already got back going on.
Guest 1: So Batman has spiders.
Scott: I mean, you know, there's like Adam West, corny Batman.
Scott: The Silver Age Batman is original Batman who had a gun.
Guest 1: Right.
Rym: OK, so the Dark Knight Returns, like that one particular movie Batman.
Rym: There's the Mask of the Phantasm.
Rym: B-TAS, but serious.
Guest 1: B-TAS Batman is my favorite.
Guest 1: There's a beautiful theater around in D.C.
Guest 1: that on one of our first dates, Conrad and I went to go see Mask of the Phantasm and he fell asleep.
Guest 0: Well, I was on crunch at the time.
Rym: How did you realize that you would have known where the Joker came from?
Guest 1: But but Mask of the Phantasm is great, but also like everything in that kind of Paul Dini verse Batman, the animated series stuff.
Guest 1: I don't know if people have seen Return of the Joker, which is a Batman Beyond movie, but the unrated version of Return of the Joker, which is set in the Batman Beyond universe is amazing.
Guest 1: And if you are a Tim Drake fan, it will break your heart.
Guest 1: And it's so like I don't love Batman when he's super duper dark.
Guest 1: This is, I would say, gritty detective stuff in a very cool way.
Guest 1: And that kid from Boy Meets World killed it.
Rym: I could be into that.
Scott: The guy from Boy Meets World is in a Batman.
Guest 1: Will Friedl does Terry McGinnis' voice.
Scott: OK.
Guest 1: So, Eric.
Guest 1: No?
Guest 1: I don't know.
Scott: So the friend.
Guest 1: Yeah, the cute best friend.
Guest 1: OK.
Guest 1: Yeah.
Guest 1: He does the voice of Terry McGinnis' Batman Beyond.
Guest 1: And he is fantastic.
Guest 1: Like, kills it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And he was still alive.
Guest 1: No, you got to check out Return of the Joker.
Guest 1: It's it's just absolutely stunning.
Guest 1: And you get to see this weird Joker stuff.
Guest 1: Of course, Mark Hamill does the voice of the Joker.
Guest 1: Of course.
Guest 1: Yeah.
Guest 1: And he's phenomenal.
Scott: He's fighting about that lately.
Scott: There was some drama, right?
Scott: What?
Scott: There was something like he didn't do it for something and he is doing it for something else.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: There's something weird going on.
Rym: That laugh.
Scott: I didn't know enough about it to tell the details.
Guest 1: But comics wise, long Halloween Batman for sure.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So what is the most recent long novel that you read?
Guest 1: OK.
Guest 1: Conrad's going to make fun of me, but this book is amazing.
Guest 1: Why not?
Guest 1: It's called Mort.
Guest 1: M O R T parentheses E. It's a.
Scott: Who's the author?
Guest 1: God, I can't remember the author's name.
Scott: Well, go to Amazon.
Guest 1: It is a post apocalyptic dystopian book.
Guest 1: Sounds good.
Guest 1: Where ants have been planning the downfall of humanity since Egyptian times.
Guest 1: And they finally breed ants with hormones that they release into the air and make all land based animals sentient and human sized.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Next book club book selection.
Rym: I think that is actually the next book club book.
Guest 1: Animal militia men take over the world, do a huge purge of all humans, and then it goes into this like kind of animal farm, but upright walking.
Rym: This is the prequel to Bojack Horseman.
Scott: Hey, Ram, you want to kill all humans?
Guest 1: Yeah.
Guest 1: And there's like an elaborate global conspiracy.
Guest 1: They have these beautiful scenes where the only way the animals can interface with ants, because ants communicate via hormone, is that the ants created a translator module that the animals can use, but they plug directly into the hive mind.
Guest 1: So it takes like a special animal of certain intelligence to kind of process all the information that comes into them from the hive mind.
Guest 1: The best part about this book, though, is that it's beautifully written.
Guest 1: Like the premise is really silly and I've been made fun of for being like a furry.
Scott: Oh, I can see some furry assumptions, but I mean, ants are not furry.
Rym: I think they're never.
Scott: I mean, is that called an ante?
Scott: What does that call?
Rym: I think that's just furry at this point.
Scott: It has an exoskeleton.
Guest 0: The ants are trying to create a fur-topia.
Guest 0: Like, I get it.
Guest 0: I get it.
Guest 0: Much love.
Guest 0: Much respect.
Guest 1: But the writing is beautiful.
Scott: Is there a lot of sex in the book?
Guest 1: Well, there is cuddling.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: I mean, there's a queen ant.
Scott: What are you going to do?
Scott: It's how it goes.
Rym: It's got Jedi told us all about that.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, when he's like, I need more soldiers.
Rym: I'd like, we're running out of bug room and she's like, all right, come with me.
Rym: And he's like, where are we going to make more bug room?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: That's just how it goes.
Scott: Let's see.
Rym: What's this review says.
Rym: Think Orwell's animal farm combined with Heinlein's Starship Troopers.
Guest 1: But it's, it's beautifully written.
Guest 1: The plot makes a whole bunch of sense.
Guest 1: Like the main character's name is Mort.
Guest 1: You know, he's the titular character and his drive is just really easy to empathize with the whole time.
Guest 1: Like, uh, it's, it's just fantastic.
Guest 1: There, there's this whole segment where all the animals get to give themselves names, but you have to earn it.
Guest 1: And there's this one like sad nerdy cat who wants to name himself Tiberius, but he never, ever, ever earns it.
Rym: Ooh.
Rym: This other thing says it's homeward bound crossed with a canticle for Liebowitz.
Scott: Why does it, why does everything have to be crossed with something?
Guest 0: So out of curiosity, uh, the protagonist of this book, who or what is it?
Guest 1: He's a cat.
Scott: It's a cat.
Guest 1: And he's, there's, there's actually a really cool moment where they talk about the division of pre versus post apocalyptic animals where the, the house pets that were neutered or spayed are like subclass citizens.
Guest 1: So in the new society who have to prove themselves.
Guest 1: And it's, it's really super intense.
Rym: Are you both down with the, uh, Rick and Morty?
Guest 1: Oh gosh, I haven't seen any yet.
Guest 0: I also haven't.
Rym: I won't say anything then cause I could, there's a segue there that I'm going to leave out because it's spoilers.
Rym: You should watch Rick and Morty.
Rym: Scott won't watch it, but you guys will like it.
Rym: Scott won't watch anything.
Scott: I have to watch the world series in four minutes.
Rym: He won't even watch Bojack.
Guest 0: One Punch Man.
Scott: One Punch Man.
Scott: Why aren't you watching One Punch Man?
Rym: Spoiler, Scotty punches.
Scott: The most important anime of our time.
Guest 0: I'm not watching One Punch Man cause my Japanese isn't good enough to watch TV in the background anymore.
Scott: I don't watch anything in the background ever.
Scott: I give everything I ever watch or read my full attention, which is probably why I watch a lot less things than everyone else.
Guest 1: Yeah.
Guest 1: Don't start a game company.
Guest 0: Just avoid that entirely.
Rym: It's interesting when you guys have this very entrepreneurial drive because as much as we both, I mean, we have designed a lot of games and then at the end of the day, we look at ourselves and we say, I could just go to work for eight hours a day.
Rym: And just play with the money from that.
Rym: All the other.
Scott: Like it's a serious question, right?
Scott: Like it's actually really serious, right?
Scott: So the reason I don't do what you do is because I'm very, very afraid that if I fail, I'll be homeless.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's possible.
Scott: it could happen.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then I see people who are, who have successful startups and the vast majority of them I've learned, this is more true over time, is that they're almost all rich people who have no risk of being homeless if they fail.
Scott: You're not fabulously wealthy.
Scott: Correct.
Scott: Are you, are you deathly afraid of like, how do you deal with it?
Scott: if you are?
Guest 0: So I touched on this last time I was on the show.
Guest 0: I've always been a freelancer.
Guest 0: I'm very good at being scrappy and finding solutions to problems.
Guest 0: Even when stuff got really bad, you know, I always landed on my feet and you do that long enough and you kind of just get the feeling that like, even when things are bad, they'll probably be okay.
Guest 0: Also, my billable now is much higher than when I was 20.
Guest 0: So that's nice.
Guest 0: But, uh, you know, personally it's, it is scary, but it's not like scary.
Guest 0: Like you're standing on the edge of a cliff or you're skydiving.
Guest 0: Scary.
Scott: You know, I almost feel like rent makes it really scary.
Guest 1: Yes.
Rym: Well, I mean, I've thought about that a lot.
Rym: If I ever did something similar, I would have to leave New York, like pretty much immediately to make that happen.
Rym: So just burn rate wise.
Rym: But it's almost like I feel like, cause other people have expressed this in the sentiment that they said a salary job is very addictive because you get very comfortable with that sort of being there and people who start freelancing.
Scott: I'm not comfortable being there.
Scott: I'm just comfortable getting money all the time.
Guest 1: I will say as a person who quit her job to work for a gaming startup, I miss that feeling of getting paid.
Scott: What was your job before?
Guest 1: Yeah.
Guest 1: Well, I will say to answer your question from earlier.
Guest 1: I wasn't as worried about quitting my job and jumping into this like goofy lifestyle because I had six years professional experience doing web project management.
Guest 1: So in grown up jobs where the work was very meaningless, but my skills were very meaningful.
Guest 1: That's essentially what I'm doing for date night to a project.
Guest 1: So like eventually if we go bankrupt and we, you know, we're on the streets, I'll actually be able to just say on my resume, I was a project manager and I can jump right back in.
Guest 0: Yeah.
Guest 0: There's no break in our resumes, you know?
Guest 0: So like in the worst case scenario, we'll just get different high paying jobs and that will be the end of it.
Guest 0: Like for us, it's not, personally, I'm not that scared.
Guest 0: Are you?
Guest 1: No.
Guest 0: I hope not.
Guest 0: Cool.
Guest 1: Not really.
Guest 1: It is very scary kind of watching my bank account go lower and lower.
Scott: I think you're also a pet, right?
Scott: You're at the point where you made a game in 12 weeks, right?
Scott: So that's like you've already, you know, you can actually produce something.
Scott: You have produced things, right?
Scott: I think the scariness for me would come in the before succeeding part.
Rym: I mean, it's got, we, as much as we talk about this, we've never actually made a vertical slice of a game.
Scott: Never made anything.
Guest 0: Make a radio show.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: That doesn't take much.
Scott: You sit around and talk.
Scott: Anyone can do this.
Guest 1: Yeah.
Guest 1: Pitch us the GeekNights dating SIM and let us know how that goes.
Scott: Nice dating SIM.
Scott: You're, you're commuting on your, it's everyone's go commuter, right?
Rym: It's Scott.
Rym: So you have three dialogue options in most places.
Scott: You can commute on a train or a car.
Scott: You can't listen to a podcast on a bike.
Scott: You listen to GeekNights.
Scott: You can't really talk to anyone cause you listen to GeekNights on the train.
Scott: You get to work, you go home.
Scott: There isn't another episode of the GeekNights cause we only make two a week.
Guest 0: But you know what there is?
Scott: You have to date someone on the train.
Guest 0: An older episode of one punch, man.
Scott: There's only three or four episodes so far.
Scott: You can watch the show.
Scott: It's on Hulu and Crunchyroll.
Scott: The manga just, I just got to first.
Scott: two volumes of the manga just came in the mail.
Scott: Uh, they're publishing it in English now.
Rym: Just like you haven't watched Steven universe.
Rym: You haven't watched.
Scott: It's in my queue.
Scott: It's just sitting there waiting.
Rym: Some of these things should go to the top of the queue.
Scott: Uh, the world series is happening right now.
Rym: The world series is going to be at the top.
Rym: I'll let you, I'll let you have that.
Guest 0: That's time limited.
Rym: I'm watching a lot of hockey.
Guest 1: The world series of what?
Guest 1: Dude.
Guest 1: I only watch hockey too.
Guest 1: What, what's the world series?
Rym: So you're, uh, what team do you recruit?
Rym: For in hockey?
Guest 1: C a P S caps, caps, caps, sabers.
Scott: What's up?
Scott: You mean C H O K E choke, choke, choke.
Rym: You know, the sabers are not the blue jackets.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: It's even.
Scott: Would you rather have a team that's gloriously shitty?
Scott: Like the lion jackets, lions, the cubs where you just never win or right.
Scott: It's much worse to be a fan of the caps.
Scott: You've got Ovechkin.
Scott: You get to the play.
Guest 1: And then you cannot win anything.
Scott: Like the San Diego chargers.
Scott: Oh yeah.
Scott: We're really good.
Scott: No, you're not.
Scott: You can't get past it.
Guest 1: I will say I am biased because I did.
Guest 1: the apartment that I used to rent like four or five years ago was actually in the building where the caps have their practices.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Guest 1: So you could, you could always go upstairs and watch them for free.
Guest 1: and uh, they're fantastic on the ice.
Guest 1: Like they look great.
Guest 1: They do choke in the playoffs every year.
Rym: And they're respectable teams.
Scott: It's very useful for us.
Scott: Rangers.
Scott: They choked against the rain.
Guest 1: And then you lost to Florida.
Guest 1: Cause Florida, there's no ice in Florida.
Scott: You lost to Tampa.
Scott: You didn't lose to Florida.
Scott: It's very different teams.
Rym: I want to point out that those Tampa games were weird.
Rym: Like really swingy.
Scott: Tampa was playing like they were playing a sort of like a Stanley cup more recently than the New York Rangers.
Rym: But they also wiped out the red wings.
Rym: Like they were surprisingly doing well in the plan.
Scott: Tampa has been a good team for a long time.
Scott: The Florida is a different story.
Guest 1: All right.
Rym: The only people I feel bad for is the Blackhawks because the real last year was like their last guest.
Scott: Why are there two hockey teams in Florida?
Scott: That's the real question.
Guest 1: I will say I always feel bad for the Bruins because it must suck to live in Boston.
Guest 1: Yeah.
Guest 1: Every Boston sports team can suck it.
Scott: I'm okay.
Scott: You know, a lot of people in New York are all hating on Boston.
Scott: It's like, I'm okay with Boston.
Guest 1: It's like, I'm like, I'm like, okay, Boston.
Scott: Philly needs to dine to five Philadelphia.
Guest 1: Right.
Scott: Cause I mean, like I've been to, I've been to Patriots games, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, they got the stupid horn they blow in third down, but I mean, they're not awful people.
Guest 1: Like I still, yes, they are.
Guest 1: They run the score whenever they can.
Guest 1: They run the dam.
Scott: Do you mean they're trying to win?
Scott: I respect that.
Guest 1: They're not just trying to win.
Guest 1: They're trying to be mean.
Rym: Stop them.
Scott: How come you can't stop that?
Guest 1: Because you suck.
Scott: That's like saying a bully is being, is just trying to play a game and try to win and be good at it.
Rym: Did Conrad ever tell you about caps are up by two goals?
Scott: Should they just stop scoring and just skate around in a circle?
Guest 1: Yes.
Rym: No.
Scott: Because a win is still a win.
Scott: And that's why you can't make it past the playoffs in the first round.
Guest 0: This is why we make dating sims.
Guest 1: I'll put that right out.
Scott: The reason I hate Philadelphia teams is because it's about, it's not about what the teams do, right?
Scott: I mean, they're just playing the sport, whatever sport happens to be.
Scott: The fans are a piece of shit, right?
Scott: If you go to Boston, sure.
Guest 1: Some red Sox fans, some red fans are shit, right?
Scott: Some red Sox fans might give you some lip, but they're not going to do anything to you.
Guest 1: Boston kickstarter.
Scott: Philadelphia throwing snowballs at Santa Claus, right?
Scott: They're starting there.
Scott: When they, when they win, they set their town on fire.
Scott: Who knows what they're going to do when they lose.
Guest 0: I want you to know as a date night to representative, we love your city and thank you so much for your support in our kickstart.
Rym: You know, Boston also you have a pack, so things are going okay.
Guest 1: You have a path.
Guest 0: that yeah.
Guest 0: In the worst place in the world zone was that I cannot imagine.
Rym: Imagine packs at the job.
Guest 1: Oh God.
Guest 1: Having, having hosted a couple of conferences in Philadelphia, Philadelphia is a nightmare.
Rym: It packs worth the Javits.
Rym: I wouldn't go.
Guest 1: How about fighting words.
Rym: you've been to the Javits.
Guest 1: I've been to the job.
Guest 0: I didn't even go to New York, the damn Javits.
Scott: But at least you could fill the whole con in the Javits.
Guest 1: I'm like in Seattle and bless, I loved my time at PAX Prime.
Guest 1: I did not love my time trying to figure out even which building I was supposed to be in and any given time.
Scott: Yeah, we, we have the luxury of being experts who've been there many times.
Scott: If this is my first ever PAX Prime, yeah, I would be like, because it used to not be that way.
Rym: Like in all these expanded things, like they split off like one by one first year we went, they weren't even using the entire main building.
Guest 1: I will say marijuana is legal in Washington.
Guest 1: I could not find any packs room.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Just hanging out with the wrong people.
Rym: The funny thing is, so fun fact, many of our friends had never had marijuana before and we were enjoying ourselves, but there was a moment late at night where we're playing a game.
Rym: Everyone in the game except Scott had consumed a considerable amount of marijuana and yet Scott was the one who was having giggling fits and like flipping out and messing up in the game.
Scott: That was later.
Rym: You were just giggling.
Rym: We were playing.
Rym: It was the last game of fresh fish.
Rym: You were just giggling the whole time.
Scott: That came by a lot.
Rym: And you were giggling.
Scott: I was running up to score my cards right next to the mood.
Guest 1: There's no better aphrodisiac than good company.
Guest 0: So Joe, any other topic, please.
Rym: So Conrad went to RIT with us and RIT at a hockey team and a RIT was a division two team and when division two disappeared, they were division three team.
Scott: There was no division two.
Rym: They were a two team.
Rym: They were two.
Rym: Two was removed.
Scott: That was a zillion years ago.
Scott: That was decades ago.
Rym: That was a good two team was pushed into three because of NCAA rules because there's no football team there.
Rym: So there was a game, a famous game, RIT beat a team from Newman, 24 to nothing.
Scott: Ice hockey.
Rym: They continued to score goals as fast as possible without abating.
Rym: In fact, they played harder in the last five minutes.
Rym: They were trying to get it to 30.
Guest 0: Listen, RIT doesn't have much.
Guest 0: We have so little.
Guest 0: Just give us this one thing.
Guest 0: Okay.
Guest 1: I did hear it's easier to get into Harvard if you play ice hockey because they always lose to Yale and they cannot be doing that.
Guest 0: What does that say about Yale's recruitment tactics though?
Scott: It's actually like historically, like, you know, because Yale doesn't do all like the shady sports stuff that like, you know, Florida or California universities will do to get like a plus sports teams that are like, you know, nationally renowned or whatever.
Scott: But historically speaking, Yale, like the Yale bowl is there.
Scott: That is like, you know, the home of sports at college is Yale, right?
Rym: So old days where people are guys are wearing fur coats and also those little.
Scott: also the Yale bowl is a crazy place to watch football.
Scott: You should go.
Scott: It doesn't look like anything else.
Scott: It actually looks like a bowl.
Rym: It's like like a soup bowl.
Scott: It's a really weird place to go.
Scott: I've been there once.
Rym: It's like what kind of bowl?
Rym: Like.
Scott: there's like, go look at a picture of the Yale bowl.
Scott: It's like it's.
Scott: it's like there's just a field and then there's just a bowl coming down.
Guest 1: I will say Rym.
Guest 1: You and Emily have got to visit us in DC at some point because less than five miles away from where I live is the ice stadium where both the caps practice, but also the FBI and the Secret Service have their annual ice hockey face off.
Scott: We hate both of them.
Scott: I guess I might root for the Secret Service.
Rym: Yeah, I would rather the Secret Service be company, even though they paid you a visit because we need.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: A long time ago.
Guest 1: It's like the Army Navy of ice hockey.
Rym: But worse, I've told the story and it's like five times fine.
Rym: But it happened.
Rym: It involved a slash dot thread and a suggestion about DDO, messing them with posts on other forums.
Rym: And it led to an interview.
Rym: All right.
Scott: I got to make a move soon.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: This is our going along anyway.
Rym: So watch the Mets definitely win the World Series.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Who knows?
Rym: Hundred percent.
Scott: Can't say.
Rym: See, I'm not I'm not from New York.
Rym: So I'm confident saying, oh, the Red Wings will win the Stanley Cup because that won't curse them.
Rym: But apparently the New Yorker and you if you say, yeah, we're up by four, the third period will be fine.
Rym: They'll immediately lose.
Guest 0: So I'm from Buffalo.
Guest 0: We weren't even allowed to breathe at those games last week.
Guest 1: Disrupt the ball.
Scott: So, Ram, when the year that you met me, right.
Scott: Do you remember anything about, you know, my personal affectation?
Rym: Which one?
Scott: I wore a Mets hat for like five years of my life every single day because you grew up.
Rym: You grew up.
Rym: Mets fan.
Scott: I didn't.
Scott: I didn't grow up.
Scott: But I've always been.
Scott: You grew up.
Scott: Born is genetic.
Rym: They picked it into you.
Scott: I have not worn a Mets hat since like two thousand.
Rym: Did you buy a new Mets hat?
Scott: For the first day I've worn a Mets hat since two thousand over fourteen, fifteen years ago.
Guest 0: I'm changing my handle to Scott's Mets hat, right?
Rym: I'll change mine to Mets win World Series guaranteed 100 percent.
Guest 0: One hundred percent.
Guest 0: Definitely.
Rym: And my icon will be Babe Ruth pointing.
Scott: Babe Ruth has never hung the Mets.
Rym: So it's got some like you had.
Rym: one last question, right?
Scott: You wrap this up somehow so we can get that.
Rym: That's your yeah.
Rym: That's your question.
Scott: Yes.
Guest 1: OK.
Guest 1: Shoot up.
Rym: I mean, hustle cat.
Rym: We're going to plug the crap out of because it's you can you can date cats and it sounds like you can also be a cat.
Guest 1: Yeah.
Guest 1: So let's do a plug for that.
Rym: Gosh.
Rym: There's only like a week left.
Guest 0: So it's a game dot com.
Guest 0: Eight days left.
Guest 0: Please.
Guest 0: Your support means the world to us.
Guest 0: Thank you so much.
Guest 1: No, absolutely.
Guest 1: And we've made a point to answer every single Kickstarter comment, every single email that's come in.
Scott: Or are there a lot of them?
Guest 0: What is there has been answered.
Guest 1: And we we just you know, our goal is to see more cute games that have meaning, you know, and we definitely want to see this happen.
Guest 1: Please, please, please help us.
Guest 1: Also, you know, that man is awesome dot com.
Guest 0: Same as always.
Guest 0: It's there.
Guest 0: Games are on it.
Guest 0: You can play them.
Rym: So if you had to date someone in the BoJack universe, who would it be?
Rym: Both of you.
Guest 1: Princess Caroline.
Guest 0: Princess Caroline.
Rym: I want to.
Rym: Princess Caroline is pretty bad ass.
Guest 0: She's the dopest dude.
Guest 0: Basically dating Princess Caroline.
Guest 0: So that's nice for me.
Rym: But I was about to like a more subtle implication that that is true.
Rym: But you just went full on.
Guest 0: No.
Guest 0: Fuck it.
Rym: That's that's a persona right there.
Guest 0: All right.
Guest 0: Thank you so much again.
Guest 1: Yeah, thanks.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our Web site at front row crew dot com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci tech Mondays, gaming Tuesdays, anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And again, per the text on our Patreon, which says, and I quote, This is super dumb.
Rym: But if you support us this much, Rym will say your name at the end of each episode after the credits, along with some ultra dumb stinger content.
Rym: We're talking Rym.
Rym: YouTube likes dumb.
Rym: So once again, I'm going to read these in money giving order.
Rym: So I already see something here.
Rym: So to the gentleman who's going to be the one, two, three, four, well, or lady, I don't know, fifth person, my hat is off to you.
Rym: So without further ado, the patrons of GeekNights this episode are James David White, Christian Koontz, Jessica L. Barlow, Mechanical Mind, Rym eats Poop, Edgar Mendez, William Eisenroz, Chris Midkiff, Chris Knox, Flame Darkfire, Samuel Corddry, Daniel Redman, Chris Sadad, Doug Snyder, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer, and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: And now I present to you something really dumb.
Rym: [Singing] Welcome to the show that hasn't been named, starring Rym and Scott, version alpha, alpha, alpha one, the first one.
Scott: Oh, so you're going to start with crazy thing thing.
Scott: My day was kind of boring.
Scott: I was real tired at work and I almost fell asleep.
Scott: I saw a guy the way from my work to the train station and he was big, tall, fat guy, not fat, not crazy obese, just fat guy.
Scott: And he had a top hat with a feather in it.
Scott: He was walking kind of funny, like the penguin almost.
Guest 1: And then when I got to the train station, there was a shorter fat guy with a mustache and he had a boulder hat on.
Guest 1: So I saw two funny hats in rapid succession.