Rym: It's Monday, June 29th, 2015.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: If one were to build a PC today, what should one buy?
Rym: The answer is kind of to wait until September.
Rym: Let's do this.
Scott: So this weekend despite it being summertime the weather was not the greatest weather.
Rym: it was actually really good that the weather was crappy because I had a lot of ConnectiCon work to finish and had it been sunny that might not have gotten done.
Scott: I also had a lot of ConnectiCon work to finish as well as cleaning my apartment which is the dirtiest ever.
Scott: it was so dirty that I dusted and the spot that I dusted immediately upon looking back upon it as the dust sweepy thing passed over had dust on it.
Rym: I gotta tell you once I bought that that fancy air filter and I just leave it on whenever I'm not home.
Rym: that really really cut down on the dust in the apartment.
Scott: Should I really spend some bunch of money on a big loud machine?
Rym: Thing is the difference is I have more need of it because we also have a lot of bunny fluff floating around the apartment.
Scott: Also I leave my windows open.
Rym: Oh yeah if you leave your windows open that's just.
Rym: that's your air filter versus Queens at that point Pretty much.
Scott: You should see the filth that is on like in the windows like on the windowsills and whatnot.
Rym: I washed the outside of my windows not that long ago.
Rym: The squeegee turned black.
Scott: Yeah I need to get a squeegee anyway.
Scott: Oh that's what I forgot to buy on Amazon.
Scott: anyway.
Rym: I got a really good squeegee by the way.
Scott: So after I did all the cleaning of the you know I cleaned from the back to the front so everything went out the front door right.
Scott: I asked how to do the laundry that has been piling up.
Scott: so I go to do the laundry and you know my laundry room changed from using quarters using a magic card.
Scott: Yeah a while ago and I've talked about how you can hack the card or whatever right.
Rym: Yeah your apartment building also seems to have the slowest fucking washers in the world.
Scott: They're a little faster now since they changed them.
Rym: Mine are 22 minutes.
Scott: These are like 40-something minutes.
Rym: Ugh I could not live like that.
Rym: You live like an animal.
Scott: Maybe I'll bring my clothes here because when I went over to the fridge to get the card that is you know attached to a fridge magnet it was not there.
Rym: What?
Rym: How do you... I... Did someone steal it?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: the card was gone and the card is basically cash because it stores all its information.
Scott: in itself there's no internet or database.
Scott: so you could hack the card and fill it with a bunch of money if you could decrypt it.
Scott: but the card was gone and I searched for it in all likely places and it was gone and I figured well there's only like at most 40 bucks on there probably less.
Rym: There's only one option you must have put it somewhere weird and forgotten about it.
Scott: I always put it back on the fridge but it was there.
Rym: Well apparently you didn't.
Scott: So I went downstairs.
Scott: I'm like huh maybe someone left their card in the laundry room and someone did and I checked the serial number and it wasn't mine.
Scott: so I'd go to try to fill it up with money on the internet because that's how it works.
Scott: it's really weird and it says nope that card belongs to someone else fuck you and I'm like alrighty.
Rym: then so I filled out the form Wait so you tried to steal someone else's card.
Scott: No they left it in the laundry room just like it had been there for a long time.
Rym: Okay how long like?
Rym: yeah like two minutes.
Scott: It had 75 cents left on it.
Scott: it didn't even do one load.
Scott: so I put the card back and I fill out the form to say mail me a new card.
Scott: but meanwhile I can't do laundry.
Scott: I can't put quarters in.
Scott: you have to have the card.
Rym: Well you could bring your laundry here but that means going home and taking the subway and not biking.
Scott: So I gave up as much laundry as I could to the Greek lady to wash for me.
Scott: I hope it's ready when I get home because I don't have any clothes to wear.
Rym: I am out of underwear.
Rym: in fact I bike to work wearing my bike shorts but I can't wear those like in the office because they're a biker diaper with like the big pad on the butt The chamois.
Scott: So uh Chamois.
Rym: So I leave at work and was commando.
Rym: commando because I don't have any more clean underwear.
Scott: Just wear dirty underwear.
Rym: Well so I could wear.
Scott: Wear your loincloths.
Rym: I have boxers and loincloths and those are fine but I can't really like bike to work in those or anything.
Rym: uh my actual like nice underwear like the super tight like the sports ones those are all dirty and dirty.
Rym: sports.
Rym: well wear smells like dead things like it.
Rym: that shit needs to be washed.
Scott: The smell won't escape your pants.
Rym: It might It might It might It might.
Scott: Anyway so that really sucked.
Scott: I couldn't do my laundry.
Rym: You know it's funny how the failover uh scenario.
Scott: I couldn't even carry all my laundry to the Greek lady because I only have two laundry bags.
Scott: when I pick it up tonight I'm probably gonna bring her some more.
Rym: You uh you waited too long to do laundry.
Scott: I did wait a very long time to do laundry.
Scott: I would have noticed the card missing probably closer to the time that it went missing because who knows how long it's been gone.
Scott: You know it's funny because my work had something happen where like May it's a good chance it may have just fallen off that fridge magnet thing and into like a bag and got thrown out in the trash.
Rym: That's not infeasible.
Scott: No it's very feasible.
Rym: I would not leave something important stuck to my fridge.
Rym: It has.
Scott: it came with this magnet like it was intended to be put onto this magnet.
Scott: it has like a little card sleeve.
Rym: I have one drawer and in that drawer is everything important.
Scott: I have a drawer as such but that drawer also includes other things.
Rym: Yeah you know what that drawer has my wallet my passport my uh keys.
Rym: uh my extra credit cards my second wallet has a shit I don't have to carry everywhere I go like oyster cards and stuff I'm gonna put.
Scott: when I get the replacement card it's probably gonna be empty.
Scott: I'm gonna fill it up with new money which sucks.
Scott: but uh I will be sure to put it in a better place and I'm probably never gonna lose it again.
Rym: Yeah you know as much as I'd like a card like that in my apartment building.
Rym: those systems I'm not super trusting of like the RIT.
Rym: one never worked that well either.
Scott: The RIT one was better because at least that one used internet Exactly except when the system was down.
Rym: and then fuck you you can't do laundry.
Rym: no one can do laundry.
Rym: there's no fail-safe fallback.
Rym: That's also a problem At least with quarters as shitty as they are.
Rym: the fallback is I can go to the bank and get quarters.
Scott: They should let you use quarters when the thing isn't working.
Rym: I in fact only recently burned through.
Scott: But then they have to send someone to pick up the quarters.
Scott: that's why the system makes them so much money more than quarters do because now they have to whole employee.
Scott: they don't have to hire if the money just gets you know sent to them also That is true like a. They also get the money immediately like there's 75 cents on that card in the laundry room that no one's ever gonna use ever.
Scott: they got that 75 cents and no one had to do any laundry.
Scott: yep They also don't have to pay for any water or any soap or anything.
Scott: all they do is maintain the machines.
Scott: that's it.
Scott: yeah it's like install machines maintain them.
Scott: money just comes.
Scott: it's the greatest business.
Scott: have one customer service person on staff or anyone who calls with a problem with their card.
Rym: Well that's what like in the old days like crappy businesses run by old people.
Rym: they'd rather you pay cash because they don't want to pay those credit card transaction fees modern smart businesses.
Rym: they'd rather you pay with your card no matter what because handling cash is a pain in the ass you notice to all.
Rym: modern hit businesses have a garbage like.
Rym: sometimes they don't even have a cash machine like a cash drawer.
Rym: I've got hooked up to their POS.
Rym: they have an iPad with a square or something on it to process payments all automatic and if you pay cash they're like and they get out like a change box and just shove the money in there because cash is such a tiny minority of what they do so in the news.
Rym: this is relatively recent news.
Rym: I'm kind of surprised how little people are talking about it.
Rym: but this news builds upon a lot of things that have happened recently and by recently I mean over the last few years.
Rym: so I'm not gonna explain it all to you because frankly you can read this shit on the internet.
Rym: but if you haven't been attention.
Rym: USB 2 is like super old and obsolete USB 3.
Scott: I have a lot of USB 2 devices and a lot of devices that use USB 2.
Rym: now yeah but it doesn't matter because USB 3 is 100% backward compatible.
Scott: that is true.
Rym: the problem with USB 3 is that the cables on the B end are way different and kind of stupid.
Rym: so if you ever see like a phone or device like a hard drive that on the hard drive end has like a USB B connector with like this other bullshit connector stacked on top of it or like a USB micro that has like another micro kind of stuck next to it that is how USB 3 connected for the most part.
Rym: so a lot of people and also the A end is different.
Scott: people didn't realize it's the same shape.
Rym: so it fits yeah but it has more connectors like yes it does so long.
Rym: story short thunderbolt was sort of the successor to firewire which is completely dead at this point even though all pro audio stuff pretty much still requires firewire and that's not going to go anytime soon.
Rym: as a result that means I need firewire because we still use a maki onyx.
Rym: I'm not replacing that thing.
Rym: that thing was real expensive but USB 3 kind of came about is useful is kind of adopted but thunderbolt way faster does a lot more things.
Rym: USB 3.1 has come out.
Rym: USB 3.1 and thunderbolt 3 are going to use the same cable.
Scott: so even no matter what device you have you're going to be good.
Scott: you're going to see a lot of similar cables everywhere replacing all the USB cable and that cable is going to use the USB C standard.
Rym: now I've talked about this on an older episode of GeekNights when I realized that nobody seems to know how USB works and what an A and a B end is and why I got a bad idea.
Rym: so USB C it doesn't matter what direction you plug it in much like a lightning cable yes but the important thing is thunderbolt 3 and USB 3.1 are both going to use the same cable even though they are very different formats.
Rym: protocols yes.
Rym: so as a result there finally is effectively one cable.
Rym: to rule them all.
Scott: a lot of people are going to end up plugging in a USB device into perhaps a computer that only has thunderbolt or a thunderbolt device into like a PC that only has USB.
Rym: there will not be computers that do not have USB for a long time.
Rym: there might be ones that don't have thunderbolts like no go try to build a PC with thunderbolt.
Rym: you're not going to be able to right see by a PC.
Scott: it's going to have a USB C port with USB 3.1. you'll buy some thunderbolt device and plug it in and it'll be like uh what there's actually a good reason why that's probably not going to happen.
Rym: so thunderbolt is way expensive to implement.
Rym: devices that use thunderbolt 3 are going to be pretty expensive and specialized things.
Rym: so pretty much people who don't know better are going to end up buying USB stuff and plugging it into USB.
Rym: I can't imagine.
Rym: many people will buy thunderbolt things and try to plug them into devices that don't support thunderbolt.
Scott: that could happen.
Rym: but thunderbolt 3 supports dual 4k displays.
Rym: yeah 40 gigabits per second 100 watts of power bi-directional.
Rym: so you could have a computer charging a thing or a thing charging a laptop.
Rym: theoretically same cable same port right.
Scott: so this is made by apple and of course apple just loves external things connected with cables.
Scott: they hate opening a computer and putting stuff in.
Scott: they think it's more.
Scott: you know the standalone device is beautiful but then in actual use it gets bundled in a mess of wires.
Scott: is you got to plug it into everything?
Scott: whereas a pc it's like okay I'm a little bit ugly but you know what.
Scott: I don't get any uglier because you put everything inside me.
Rym: well we're kind of past that though because a modern computer like if you have a workstation you're gonna have a bunch of ssd's inside of it and then you connect to a san or a daz or a naz for all your big time storage and then like mouse keyboard
Scott: what's a daz
Rym: desktop attached storage?
Rym: okay the difference it's like the difference between.
Rym: yeah if you get a drobo with thunderbolt the idea is you plug it into your computer and it's a big external hard drive.
Rym: yeah it's a big external hard drive.
Rym: that's super fast.
Rym: you can like edit video off.
Scott: you can't share it with anyone unless you use your computer's sharing exactly.
Rym: but thunderbolt the thing is this is really intel's thing and you know apple is irrelevant.
Rym: the important part is this is going to be a standard for pcs and for pretty much everything going down the road.
Rym: so we're finally standardizing on a pretty good cable and a pretty good set of formats and my only concern is whether or not pro audio hardware is gonna catch up anytime soon and give it enough time.
Scott: I think you know I can see this kind of cable.
Scott: only be.
Scott: this is like sort of like the.
Scott: I don't want to say it's the blu-ray but it's like the DVD of cables right.
Rym: it's the last cable.
Scott: there will be another cable after it that some people will use but this will be the last cable.
Scott: wireless stuff will replace this cable right.
Scott: wireless charging is actually somewhat there.
Scott: now you can charge small batteries with it.
Rym: yeah listen remember this cable also is not going to replace long-haul cables.
Rym: that's gonna be fiber and stuff.
Scott: we're talking about locals you know serial device connections right.
Scott: this is gonna be the lat the DVD of cables.
Scott: wireless will take over afterwards the same way that digital is replaced physical media yep and so eventually all devices that still have cables are gonna.
Scott: that are consumer things will be using this kind phones everything.
Rym: so if you're gonna buy if you're thinking so Rym you're talking about build new computers.
Rym: should I think about this when building a new computer?
Rym: fuck no Thunderbolt 3 is not gonna be in a computer you buy anytime soon.
Scott: if you buy a Mac today it'll have it yeah but if you buy the the trash cans it was Nicky GeekNights.
Rym: if you want a performance desktop you're gonna buy a PC sure.
Rym: so my advice to you if you want to be forward compatible in regard to this is to one stock up on cards that will do firewire like a PCI.
Rym: what II 1x card that'll do firewire?
Rym: find one they're like 20 bucks.
Rym: that works with all your firewire shit.
Rym: buy four or five of them because they're cheap and hoard them because firewire is dead.
Scott: and then the next computer you buy does not have a PCI Express slot.
Rym: yes it will because PCI Express has continued forever.
Rym: we'll talk about them in the other bed.
Rym: you know what the current PCI Express is.
Rym: are like X 32?
Rym: no it's still like 16. is the same as it was in 2008. okay except there's 2.0 and 3.0. so there's the 16 16 4 versus the 16 or dual 8 mm-hmm and I'll talk about it.
Rym: the main bit whatever my computer's way obsolete.
Rym: but do that and make sure whatever motherboard you get if you buy a new computer has two PCI X 16 slots for your video card and maybe two video cards maybe two you don't need to be okay.
Rym: yeah it's a good way to be forward compatible but make sure you've got a PCI X for slot for X because that is the slot you'll need at minimum to buy a card to plug in.
Rym: that will give you Thunderbolt ports in Thunderbolt 3 when that or USB 3.1 ports oh yeah USB 3.1 could go there too.
Rym: but anyway yeah.
Rym: but PCI Express the 4x slot.
Rym: make sure you got one of those.
Rym: I guess you could use the 16 slot.
Rym: I guess that would work.
Rym: maybe I'm not really an expert on that.
Scott: so why no tech news?
Scott: to speak of that you can tell because Rym didn't do tech news either.
Rym: there's tons of tech news you just don't give a shit about.
Rym: it is the worst.
Scott: if we had to do tech news roundup today we would be so fucked.
Rym: the Supreme Court just ruled that they're gonna.
Rym: that's a ruling.
Rym: they said their ruling was.
Rym: they said they hear the case and then they let the lower court's decision stand meaning you can't.
Scott: I thought they denied the written said we're not listening they the lower court's ruling stance.
Rym: uh-huh the lower court's ruling was complicated.
Rym: it was basically that the API's and all that stuff could be copyrighted can be copyrighted.
Scott: you can still use them cuz fair use?
Rym: no that there is an argument to be made that Google specific use may have been fair use and there is a separate court case to be had for that.
Scott: well that's the important one.
Rym: the problem is I really should have ruled the other way.
Scott: well yeah that would have been much better.
Rym: is the road we're going at?
Scott: the end of the road is a dark road.
Rym: however Swift might be the way to get out of that dark road down the road.
Scott: whatever.
Scott: alright that's news.
Scott: so since there's no tech news I want to talk about a tech thing that I've purchased and used recently.
Scott: who we found out about this thing?
Scott: thanks to our friend Alan who works at YouTube.
Scott: he told us about the cerebral live wedge.
Scott: the cerebral live wedge is a thing that is very expensive.
Scott: it's like a thousand dollars.
Scott: you might be learning like whoa stop talking about how rich you are.
Scott: it's like look.
Scott: I was very hesitant to purchase this thousand dollar device.
Rym: I almost bought it and then Scott messaged me and said yeah I bought one.
Scott: so whatever.
Rym: well I'll put it this way this is a tenth the cost of a tricaster.
Rym: yes which is the what we want but we're not going to buy exactly.
Scott: you think about it that way.
Scott: yeah right it's like.
Scott: my camera is $1,700.
Scott: you can get it for less than that now.
Scott: but I bought it was brand new.
Scott: it's a 4k like ultra amazing video camera.
Scott: but you know what the red camera is like tens of thousands of dollars.
Scott: it's like well that's a good deal.
Scott: then right it's like exactly.
Scott: those are the best thing if you can afford it.
Scott: the best things to buy are those things that are still expensive.
Scott: but I have like amazing features that approach the levels of the ridiculously professionally expensive things but aren't quite there.
Scott: and that is what the live wedge is.
Rym: so it's.
Rym: if there's a it's that edge between.
Rym: no because we talk about this a lot.
Rym: there's consumer stuff like a Sony camcorder.
Rym: you just buy.
Scott: yeah it best buy.
Rym: yeah there's pro stuff like this is a studio camera cost tens of thousands of dollars.
Rym: it doesn't come with any lenses or the power supply.
Scott: it has this gigantic lens.
Scott: a guy has to sit on a truck with it.
Rym: next to the football stadium there's pro sumer which is kind of the level of.
Rym: I have a weird use case that normal people don't care about but I do not need what.
Rym: like George Miller used to film Mad Max I bought the more expensive GoPro instead of the cheap one exactly like I think the line with some accessories for my surfing video the line between consumer and pro sumer is.
Rym: I have a use case that consumers stuff can't handle like for example for live streaming which is what Scott's about to talk about with the live wedge.
Rym: if you're a consumer then you're probably just gonna buy.
Scott: you can use a webcam yeah or you're just gonna use some software you're gonna use like X split maybe you're probably just OBS.
Rym: it'll all just work.
Rym: fine.
Scott: if you're more serious you'll buy it.
Scott: the Elgato.
Rym: yep the Elgato is not a professional piece of equipment no but it edges into that pro sumer territory because it's a dedicated piece of expensive hardware that solves a
Scott: hundred and something but yeah
Rym: and it solves some problems that a lot of people who do in live streams do not have
Scott: on a live stream my xbox yep
Rym: or I want to live stream a device with a separate device like I want to live stream my computer with a different computer doing the actual streaming possibly with multiple cameras or audio or whatever.
Rym: I have a complicated use case the live which is kind of like it's it's in that Twilight Zone between prosumer and professional.
Scott: so it's made by some weird Japanese company called cerebo that no one ever heard of and the way it works is.
Scott: it's really quite small.
Scott: you didn't realize how small it is until you get it and on the back are six HDMI ports.
Scott: four of them are inputs one two three and four.
Scott: yeah one of them is the output.
Scott: that one you plug into a TV and you'll basically see what is being streamed in real time and the other one is the preview and that shows you on the TV.
Scott: if you plug it in.
Scott: basically it cuts your TV into four boxes like goldeneye and you can see the four inputs right and what they are.
Scott: so you can like you have two TVs.
Scott: you can sort of have the actual output and the four boxes and then you can sort of switch between the four inputs like it's a real TV show like you know.
Scott: camera one is you know rims face and camera two is Scott's face and input three is.
Scott: you know the board game they're playing and input four is like.
Scott: you know the logo GeekNights logo and you switch between the four like it's actual TV.
Scott: yep it can also do picture in picture.
Scott: so we could put like the night's logo and a little square in the corner and like do like the nightly news does on TV where it's like it appears and disappears and changes pictures right and to populate that you could say have a laptop with it with the logo full screen with an HDMI output going into output.
Scott: you know input number four.
Scott: or you can just put a bunch of JPEGs or movie files onto an SD card put the SD card into the live wedge and use any of those images or videos as a camera.
Scott: so like if you have a recorded video you can make that right.
Scott: you can like do a whole fucking nightly news show with this thing.
Scott: it's ridiculous.
Scott: yeah.
Rym: now the other important thing is that it has all those sort of features for command and control.
Rym: like you can also have a separate from all that audio channel.
Scott: yep there's a red and white RCA audio input that is separate from all the other.
Scott: you know you still get audio inputs on the four HDMI eyes but there's a separate audio input so you can have like just commentary while you switch between different views.
Scott: so think about this like here's the example you're watching a karate tournament and there's four mats where people are fighting and you're the commentator and you can.
Scott: you know you see the fight starting on Matt too.
Scott: so you push the second camera.
Scott: you start talking that fight ends.
Scott: you switch to Matt three.
Scott: you know that kind of you set it up to where.
Scott: like the audio you got four cameras with four HDMI cables coming in.
Rym: yep so the audio from each of the four cameras will come in whichever one you're looking at.
Rym: maybe at like half volume or quarter volume.
Rym: you can.
Scott: it doesn't mix or you can touch it.
Rym: and then at full volume is you talking no matter what you talking through the mixer.
Rym: that's then connected to the live wedge.
Scott: yep now how do you control this live wedge?
Scott: on the surface of the live wage is a little LCD screen.
Scott: it's not.
Scott: it's like a really crappy LCD screen.
Scott: you can control it a lot through that screen surprisingly because there's a big wheel with a button in the middle like an old iPod on the right and you can use that to work with the interface.
Scott: there's also four buttons underneath the screen that let you switch between the four cameras.
Scott: it doesn't even have an on/off switch just to plug it in to turn it on.
Scott: it's kind of ridiculous.
Scott: I guess it can also record to the SD card.
Scott: I guess it's worth mentioning.
Scott: but the most important thing is that it has an Ethernet port.
Scott: so you plug it straight into the internet.
Scott: that's right.
Scott: you don't need the Elgato needs a computer to do streaming.
Scott: you have to plug the Elgato with USB into a real computer.
Scott: that then does the streaming part.
Scott: with software the Elgato does all the streaming on its own.
Scott: it is a standalone streaming device.
Scott: it requires no computer.
Scott: you can have the live wedge a camera internet and you're good.
Scott: no computers necessary no laptop so nothing.
Scott: so to control it what you actually do is use your iPad.
Scott: I think it's iPad only there might.
Scott: I don't know if this iPhone software.
Scott: I think it's iPad only.
Scott: you can either a plug the live wedge into the internet with Ethernet and then connect to the live wedge with Wi-Fi the live wedge you tell it to become a Wi-Fi access point.
Scott: you connect your iPad directly to the live wedge and then open up the live wedge app and now you can control it with the iPad.
Scott: or you can if you have really good Wi-Fi have the live wedge connect to the internet with Wi-Fi and then as long as you connect your iPad to the same network by Wi-Fi it will see the live wedge on the network and connect to it with the app.
Rym: so now you have an awesome tiny screen just to control all this stuff live on the screen.
Scott: on the iPad you can control everything the picture and picture which camera mix the audio and the settings check the YouTube check the new stream check whatever's.
Scott: you can do everything in the iPad app.
Scott: it's a little bit finicky in the user interface but it's since they got some firmware updates and some app updates it is now stable like there's no crashy bits or anything.
Scott: it's just a little finicky interface wise.
Scott: it also does some other fancy shit like green screen and chroma key type stuff.
Scott: you can resize the picture in picture and move it around.
Scott: it does transitions like when you switch from camera one to two you can do a cut or a fade or a wipe or all kinds.
Scott: that right it does all this kind of stuff you don't realize that it can do.
Rym: and now yeah you can do that stuff in post-production if you're making like a big video.
Scott: this is live stream.
Scott: it does it right real time.
Rym: so think about the two uses.
Rym: either we can live stream complicated events with high production values or we can record things like we normally do but we can do all most of the post-production live.
Rym: so like the Daily Show you upload the video that night instead of a week later.
Scott: there's only one flaw that I can find with the live wedge and that is it doesn't actually stream in 1080p.
Scott: it streams in 720p max because it's not like.
Scott: it has some crazy ridiculous CPU in there you know with a whole ton of RAM and a video card to process MPEG videos right which in a way is fun because then the thing is people don't even notice like they're watching.
Scott: your stream like 720p looks fucking great.
Scott: yeah especially if your input is good.
Scott: if your input is high quality the output is gonna be high quality.
Rym: right though I gotta say cuz we uploaded our first 4k video to YouTube.
Scott: 4k looks really good.
Rym: so you're lucky.
Scott: but you're lucky if your computer can play it.
Rym: yeah.
Rym: so like I cannot display 4k so I have a 4k screen.
Rym: no so to test it I opened it in VLC and I had it show one-to-one.
Rym: so despite my two monitors it's like this huge image like way I can only see a part of the image at a time at one-to-one pixel.
Rym: yeah let me tell you it looks amazing.
Rym: yeah even with like the low shitty light and you're just like carrying the camera around.
Scott: for example with my camera I could have my camera record in 4k while outputting to the stream so that way we could live stream and then later on take the recorded video from the one camera right.
Rym: so think about this with Premiere and like post-processing.
Rym: here's an amazing workflow.
Rym: you run the LiveWedge.
Rym: all the cameras are recording to their own individual SD cards mm-hmm audio and video.
Rym: our Marantz is recording audio to his compact flash because it's ancient and uses compact flash.
Rym: the mixer is also sending the audio you know to the LiveWedge.
Rym: the LiveWedge is recording a 720p video of the final mix all the cuts and everything.
Scott: I don't really I mean LiveWedge.
Scott: I said it can record and it can but I'm not a big fan of.
Rym: no no here's what you do.
Rym: so it's recording the actual mix with all the transitions that for the synchronizing and yeah and it's live streaming.
Rym: then after the event Scott just gives me all the SD cards.
Scott: you're gonna have to put a really big SD card in that in that live way.
Rym: yeah yeah but I dump all the SD cards onto my computer.
Rym: I drag them all into Premiere and I say sync all this shit up and then I just replace all the video clips from the 720p live stream version with the 4k clips from all the cameras and have the ultra high quality version to upload.
Scott: you could do that.
Scott: yes I've tested various things with the LiveWedge.
Scott: I tested a like output from HDMI on my ex like a not my Xbox but like you know my HD PC right into the LiveWedge totally worked.
Scott: laptop right into LiveWedge totally works.
Scott: GoPro HDMI cable into the LiveWedge totally worked right.
Scott: the only time I had a problem was when I had like an HDMI splitter and put one half of it into the.
Scott: you didn't really like.
Rym: that's the one thing the Elgato is useful for.
Rym: if you want to live stream a game on a TV but you're playing that game while you live stream it.
Scott: yeah that's the thing.
Scott: is that the the one feet.
Scott: that's the thing.
Scott: the Elgato has an HDMI output with no delay on it so you can play a video game that's being live streamed but that HDMI pass through on the Elgato.
Scott: if you try to do that with the LiveWedge is gonna be a delay.
Scott: it's not gonna go well in your favor.
Scott: you need the HDMI splitter but the HDMI splitter at least the one that I have the the LiveWedge did not like the output from that splitter.
Rym: here's the problem.
Rym: that is that the fault there is HDMI and it's bullshit.
Rym: copyrighted protection.
Scott: I don't know if it has to do with the kind of protection because I was using output from just my HD PC which is not HDCP but it's still the way HDMI was designed.
Scott: I think it's just cuz.
Rym: I have a cheapo splitter and if I bought a fancy splitter my HDMI is not designed to be split because that was an avenue of piracy.
Scott: sure maybe?
Rym: yeah that's one aspect to it.
Rym: anyway.
Scott: yeah if you do a lot of live streaming or if you have to do some fancy live streaming where multiple cameras switching in real time is a thing you're gonna want to help you out with you should consider buying or renting this LiveWedge deal.
Scott: it's really small and portable.
Scott: I don't recommend using it unless you are near a spot with.
Scott: obviously you need to be near something with power but you can get power from like a big battery or something.
Scott: it doesn't take a lot of power.
Scott: you need to be near some wired internet or some ridiculously fast wireless internet unless you're using it or it won't be enough bandwidth to stream unless you're using it to record and then upload later.
Scott: but that's the nicest part.
Scott: is that like it just sort of like really?
Scott: you go like YouTube you make a new live event you go to the iPad app you see the event there you just push stream and you don't worry about any of these finicky settings or anything like.
Scott: the interface is kind of clunky.
Scott: it gets it right.
Scott: it just streams and the stream.
Scott: as long as the internet is good it just streams great and in fact even when the internet was bad it streamed as good as you could hope for in given the bad stuff stance.
Rym: now also stay tuned because Scott's learning how to use this thing really well and we've like upgraded our lighting and like all our other equipment and like those microphones.
Rym: the only reason we haven't been doing a lot of big content is we have one.
Rym: we don't have a studio so doing big video content means I literally destroy my entire living room for a full day or a full weekend and two.
Rym: it's got to be crappy weather outside or we're not gonna do it.
Scott: so yeah if you consider the cerebral live wedge or not they make some other products too but I don't know about those.
Rym: the live wedge is the best tool that does that.
Rym: unless you have tens of thousands of dollars to spend and
Scott: you need if you really need 1080p's right maybe wait for the live wedge -
Rym: yeah yeah
Scott: but maybe I could just when that comes maybe I'll sell the live wedge one by the leverage - or may you see how much you
Rym: keep the live wedge one?
Rym: because a lot of times having a secondary device can be really really useful daddy to streams.
Rym: well though like YouTube you can have your primary and secondary stream.
Rym: so YouTube if your primary stream fails it'll just cut to the secondary stream seamlessly sure.
Rym: so you can have the 720p backup stream going over like a different ISP or something.
Rym: maybe yeah anyway things of the day this is just some white kid who raps really really really fast and it's actually pretty impressive white kid.
Scott: I mean that's somewhat impressive but you spend way too much time practicing that because you have anything better to do with your life.
Rym: he seems to be doing a little bit.
Rym: he's done.
Rym: he's got a lot of those like Barker I don't know enough about terminology but he can.
Rym: he is ad-libbing some of it and using those tricks to keep going even when he lost the thread anyway.
Rym: but it just it's pretty impressive.
Rym: I like this.
Scott: so there is an event every year known as the Goodwood Festival of Speed.
Scott: it is a more like.
Scott: it's sort of like Otakon only replace anime with cars.
Scott: that's you can consider it like that sort of right.
Scott: and at the Goodwood Festival of Speed this year recently someone broke there.
Scott: this is particular track and you know where it goes.
Scott: up a hill it's like this little uphill run.
Scott: it's about a mile long and they race various things up this hill.
Scott: and one of the things that someone raced up the hill this year was a Nissan Juke.
Scott: and they raced the Nissan Juke up the hill and to see what time they could get to try to break the record.
Scott: it's like well how could you break the record of Nissan Juke?
Scott: well it wasn't just the record for fastest up the hill.
Scott: that record was set in this other video that I'll also link by an f1 car in 1999 when they actually had real engines 41 seconds.
Scott: yeah right it's a two-minute record set for going up the hill on two wheels and not a bicycle or a motorcycle a Nissan Juke which has four wheels but they only use two of them.
Rym: the best part of the video is the advertising banner on the bottom of the car.
Scott: that is very nice.
Rym: it's kind of amazing.
Scott: this guy who does this is apparently like one of the world's best stunt drivers who does like shows and all this kind of cool stuff like he'll get out of the car and get back into it and do all sorts of ridiculous shit.
Scott: so I'm gonna try to find that guy's name and search for him on YouTube and see what kind of awesome shit he's done.
Scott: you know maybe I'll be a fan of his.
Scott: huh.
Rym: in the moment we have uploaded a ton of videos.
Rym: the most recent one is our 4k video walkthrough of the Pac South the first Pac South Expo Hall.
Scott: I watched this video.
Scott: it actually wasn't bad.
Rym: yeah like it is twice as good as the first time.
Rym: we attempted that we learned a lot.
Scott: this video is not awful.
Scott: a little bit of shakiness.
Rym: yeah I tried.
Rym: I tried to use a lot of filters.
Rym: see if I could like get rid of the shakiness.
Rym: technology is not quite there yet I'll bring them up did.
Scott: is that when I forgot the monopod I yeah I think so I won't forget it next time.
Rym: yeah but stay tuned we're getting better at that crap but I think we're a lot better at doing that sort of.
Scott: you want to buy me this much fancier monopod that has a Manfrotto clip on the top.
Rym: you might be better off buying that second Marantz.
Scott: I'm gonna keep using my $20 monopod.
Rym: but uh yeah the videos.
Rym: actually the thing is what.
Rym: it was so long ago that when I watched it to edit the video together because we walked through the expo hall for like three hours and I cut this thing down to like 20 something minutes of just the interesting things we saw.
Rym: there's a lot of interesting games that I forgot about that I need to go back and see if they came out.
Scott: yet there were a lot of interesting games.
Scott: but when I saw them I'm like yeah I don't need to play this.
Rym: yeah yeah except video ball.
Rym: I just want video ball.
Rym: I want video ball more than I want most things.
Rym: I kind of wanted to know also one of the games that we were really excited about that it was a free space shooter that looked just like way.
Rym: pro apparently it's an MMO.
Rym: okay so I don't know that could be good if it actually relies on skill cuz I'm pretty good at flying a spaceship and shooting people but if it requires leveling up but anyway we'll see about that.
Rym: I think elite dangerous was the game.
Scott: oh that's like famous because like the the flying like super matters and so I've heard a lot of crazy shit about that.
Rym: well we watched the guy at PAX and that was legit.
Rym: free space shooter like.
Scott: is that the one we're like?
Scott: you gotta like even docking.
Scott: you have to manually control the ship and like shit is crazy in that game.
Scott: that's the kind of thing we're like.
Scott: that's your whole life.
Scott: if you do that yeah you should maybe investigate that.
Scott: that's your might be your cuz I?
Rym: yeah maybe.
Rym: maybe I've heard some things but yeah otherwise the booklet book is the first book of I guess the eight Wheel of Time books are there.
Scott: eight are there.
Rym: I don't know how many there are.
Scott: there's a called the eye of the world.
Rym: it's a fantasy story about some fancy people doing fantasy stuff.
Rym: wizards candidates.
Rym: yeah magics gender-based magic private ventures.
Scott: yeah swords even shield the heron blade horses and armor proper nouns.
Rym: he's not a fighter he's a warder evil dude.
Rym: she's not a wizard or a maid.
Scott: she's like scary names in made-up languages.
Rym: that guy with the fucking kind of deserved it.
Rym: did you get that?
Rym: did you read further?
Scott: no I watched.
Rym: or a Mona guitar instead or I like or they're not in the same genre.
Rym: they don't compete.
Scott: but yeah they could be for time.
Rym: that is true.
Rym: otherwise Connecticut is coming up in two weeks super soon.
Rym: Hartford Connecticut the weekend of July 9th.
Scott: if you are a nerd and listening to this and you are within distance of Hartford Connecticut you have no excuse.
Scott: unless something more important is happening in your life you should be at Connecticut.
Scott: oh man it's gonna be amazing.
Rym: yeah it is.
Scott: it is not the biggest convention.
Scott: it is not the best convention but it is the best convention per capita that I know of in terms of the amount of awesomeness per person.
Scott: I know of no convention that beats.
Rym: yeah like Connecticut is a better gaming con than any non packs non magfest gaming con in America.
Scott: I mean maybe there's like a VGG con or whatever but it's like those cons that are more are full on 100% gaming like Gen Con and origins.
Scott: like they got issues that Connecticut do not have.
Scott: right you know panels how many we might have more panels I think than one year.
Scott: we had conventions one year when we had the biggest when we had not.
Rym: well we had 11 panel rooms.
Rym: we've cut back a little bit and like we've spaced our we've paced ourselves a little more.
Rym: we had like 288 panels right.
Scott: and also if you consider all all geeky conventions right from the top of Maine going south it's pretty much anime Boston one Connecticut - there's no other big convention out in that geographic area.
Scott: right what next?
Scott: what's the next convention after that?
Scott: New York Comic Con is the next one after that geographically.
Scott: so why the hell would you miss Connecticut if you are in that area?
Scott: seriously?
Rym: yeah Connecticut is on the.
Scott: where else are you gonna go like the?
Scott: the sad you know washed up pro wrestler next to the sports card table place.
Rym: we're not just saying this because we run the entire like panels and workshops special events.
Scott: I would go to Connecticut if I was not.
Scott: I might even just quit Connecticut to save myself some work but still go to it and enjoy it.
Rym: there are the number of cons we would go to not being guests and not being in charge less than less than we have friends that come to Connecticut and work with us on staff.
Scott: but we also have many friends who go to Connecticut and pay money for badges and play games the whole time but also go to some panels.
Rym: yeah I like we're the con is legit it's really legit.
Scott: yeah go listen to some really old episode we did about an early Connecticut on to laugh.
Rym: yeah in fact a good time.
Scott: listen to GeekNights 2006 Connecticut.
Rym: the only problem with Connecticut is the problem that most con have.
Rym: there is just no food over there.
Scott: you can eat the Convention Center ice cream for whatever it costs.
Rym: oh my god there was a year where I ate open late one day I think on Friday.
Rym: that was the year back before we.
Scott: if you approach Connecticut from the Albany direction you can go to the bells and if you approach from the south you can get it to.
Scott: Bell is in Milford Connecticut.
Scott: don't approach from the east just bring food with you.
Rym: yeah no drive past to Milford by.
Scott: that's a way south it's like not.
Rym: I would detour up to an hour to get to Bell but meanwhile you're taking a bus or a train.
Rym: take an Amtrak because fuck that.
Scott: no it doesn't stop at the Bell's does it?
Rym: no?
Rym: but uh multiple years in a row I've been stuck in ridiculous traffic on a bus or in a car trying to get home from Connecticut to New York.
Scott: so we'll find a way around this problem.
Rym: just take the Amtrak.
Rym: it's like 40 bucks each way.
Scott: just go take a train the Metro North train oh and then take a car from my mom's house.
Rym: oh you know we were debating.
Rym: actually cuz remember that one year you me Emily and Judith took the train and then we took the car from your parents house and hung out there like we ate food even and we stopped on the way home.
Rym: it was good time.
Rym: hmm yeah that could be good.
Scott: anyway I can like and then I can go to develop.
Rym: you can go to but if you should I?
Scott: should I take a picture there and that and not bring you a sandwich?
Scott: should I bring you a sandwich?
Rym: I'll pay you.
Scott: should I be like my uncle who showed up at the all-star game that we gave him tickets to in Boston with a sandwich that he got at the deli near his house in Queens but did not have a more than one sandwich?
Scott: or should I be a nice person?
Rym: you should get me a de Bella's.
Scott: should I get you a de Bella's but perhaps not the one you asked for or perhaps just a small smell.
Rym: the small would almost be the worst cuz that's just enough for me to enjoy it.
Scott: maybe I'll get.
Scott: I'll give you a small and then secretly give you a second small of a different kind.
Rym: I can't think of any de Bella's saw that I wouldn't eat.
Rym: I mean I will get you lettuce only I would eat that cuz that bread.
Scott: I will get you lettuce on the bad bread choice.
Rym: oh no no it's got to be the sesame.
Scott: no see the plain bread.
Rym: who gets the plain bread?
Scott: the plain bread with lettuce?
Scott: so are you even worse plain bread with just American cheese?
Rym: in terms of the history of me buying computers cuz Scott I both posted the history of computers.
Rym: cuz as you said in 1994 Rym got a 486 sx2.
Rym: that was the first computer that was in my house.
Scott: yeah I guess mine was 95 because I was 13 486 dx4 100 megahertz 4 megabytes of RAM later upgraded to 8 or even 16.
Rym: I forget mine had 4 and I upgraded it to a.
Scott: I had a 4x CD-ROM.
Scott: I could install doom 2 like BAM.
Scott: I didn't.
Scott: if I ran out of space on my 700 and something megabyte hard drive.
Scott: I just uninstalled doom 2 and install something else and then reinstall cuz it took like two seconds.
Scott: I had a play games off.
Scott: the CD-ROM is so fast.
Rym: I had a 2x CD-ROM and more importantly cuz that's half as much X as I had to play doom 2 or doom.
Rym: I had to use a boot disk or hold f5 when I booted to go into minimal DOS mode loading no drivers manually loaded a mouse drive.
Scott: I had the vastly superior PC DOS on this IBM computer that originally came with OS to warp that I later replaced Windows 95.
Rym: Scott and I were like completely out of sync in terms of computers.
Rym: at any given time one of us had a computer that left the other computer.
Rym: the other one of ours computer.
Scott: so far in the dust it was it seems like such a small difference right about a 486 50 vs.
Scott: 486 100.
Rym: it's like twice as fast to have a computer twice as fast as my current computer you can't.
Scott: I was able to play mech warrior 2 on the full settings if I full installed which I could if I deleted a lot of stuff.
Rym: so in 1997 I got a Pentium 200 megahertz.
Rym: well that computer was a god tier computer you brought to RIT.
Rym: no so in 99 Scott got a Pentium 3.
Scott: oh yeah I bought that with the money I earned at working summer camp.
Rym: the BX motherboard.
Scott: that is that is the first computer that I built with my hands.
Scott: it had the BX chipset the most reliable motherboard chipset to ever exist.
Scott: that shit never blue-screened even one time.
Scott: it booted at the first go and it even even when I stopped using that computer it still works just fine.
Scott: if I could find it I bet it still works I think it might be my closet.
Rym: yeah maybe now it's interesting because there was a long plateau in the Pentium 3 era.
Rym: 400 450 500 megahertz like computers did not get faster very quickly for a while.
Rym: nope and to go faster was expensive that Pentium 3 450.
Scott: also when I bought it the day I bought it it came with.
Scott: well I didn't come with.
Scott: I bought it with I built it.
Scott: the TNT - the TNT - by the way was the brand new video card at the time.
Scott: oh how cute how cute.
Rym: you bought a video card that opened GL.
Rym: you I had one of the first video cards that had opened GL.
Scott: this was the first video card that was for reals.
Rym: the other there were previous video cards like there was the voodoo - bullshit with the drivers that ever color gamut.
Scott: but there was the TNT which was like sort of.
Scott: this was the TNT - though that was like a major.
Scott: that was like basically the first modern video card that had real power.
Scott: was that AGP I could play?
Scott: I could play you know all the modern games like the half-lives and the quakes and all those games at the full FPS choco mobile armor division all the late 90s early 2000s tribes - no I had those games I could play now.
Rym: what's interesting is Scott bought that computer in 1999 and compared to the computer I had at that time they were like my computer.
Rym: my computer was garbage about in 99.
Scott: yeah not 92 no 99 but mine was 97. yep.
Rym: so one year after Scott got that penny at two years rims computer was garbage.
Rym: yes but one year after Scott's Pentium 3 AMD when I brought that Pentium 3 to RIT Rym brought a new computer to RIT I brought an AMD k7 800 megahertz.
Rym: fucking monster.
Rym: that computer tower that computer a full tower was.
Scott: I'll never forget the whole town.
Rym: that thing was.
Rym: it was so tall it weighed like 30 pounds like that thing.
Rym: it wasn't even full.
Scott: it just had a bunch of scuzzy shit in it.
Scott: yeah I had a scuzzy easily been a mid tower even a mini tower but he just put so many drives in it and stuff like.
Rym: yeah I had a raid I had a bunch of hard drives rated together I had a scuzzy bus for all my shit.
Rym: oh my god that computer that computer.
Rym: think about that difference.
Rym: but what happened was AMD came onto the scene and said yo dog you want a processor that costs like a quarter.
Rym: what Pentiums do?
Scott: are you a poor college student?
Scott: you can't afford these overpriced Pentium 4s.
Rym: now.
Rym: before that the k6 is.
Rym: we're about as fast as the Pentiums but not nearly as reliable.
Rym: you had to be a nerd to make that shit work.
Rym: Greg Hartman yeah had the k6 - yeah but like if you got him to work.
Rym: they were way cheap and they were as fast but the k7 was like double the speed.
Scott: yeah so uh yeah yeah then we leapfrog back and forth for a while later in the college years I bought the Athlon which again was much more speedy for the price but very unreliable.
Scott: yeah not not be.
Scott: I was very disappointed coming from the BX chipset motherboard.
Rym: of course I have to say right around that time I had to replace my AMD k7 with a Thunderbird.
Rym: it was a 200 megahertz faster.
Scott: oh that was the cat.
Scott: the capacitor explode.
Rym: yeah the capacitor explosions.
Rym: we've talked about that.
Scott: that era sure but uh it's unreliable.
Scott: BX chipset don't have capacitor explosions.
Rym: in 2007 2008 we actually synced up.
Rym: we both bought the same computer the core 2 duo mm-hmm.
Scott: that was when we were in the beacon days.
Rym: yeah then I needed a faster computer because we were starting to edge into doing video and my computer was having some bus issues because that jank as a bit motherboard I had.
Rym: so I bought the core i7 920 in 2009. the computer I built in 2009 is the computer I'm still using to this day.
Rym: yep Scott.
Rym: meanwhile a few years ago bought 2012 yes bought a much faster computer that is still an i7.
Scott: yeah I mean if you have my computer already is three years old.
Scott: I bought in July 2012 and if you look at the computer rims thinking about getting the only difference between the rent the computer Rym is thinking of getting is that it's 0.5 gigahertz more.
Scott: yep and that's like computers change so much.
Scott: we're like a one year apart between a 486 50 and a 486 100. we're like a couple years apart between a 450 and an 800 mega.
Scott: right.
Scott: and now we're like three years back and it's like all right same amount of RAM.
Scott: pretty much video cards like my 680 can still play all the games just fine even though it's three years old.
Scott: really it's like what you know.
Scott: I don't need any upgrades at all.
Scott: I'm gonna.
Scott: probably every computer I've gotten has lasted four to five years.
Scott: this is probably last six or seven yeah eight.
Rym: so if you bought a computer pretty much from 2011 onward there's not really much reason to buy a new computer anytime soon.
Scott: the listeners law having some trouble in the home PC department yeah but my computers from 2009.
Rym: so that might not seem like that big a deal because like I have a core i7 it is wicked fast.
Rym: like I added 4k video on this computer and it works pretty well.
Scott: GPU does most of the work.
Scott: you'd be surprised how much work a GPU does that core to do.
Scott: I upgraded the GPU at one point and that like made even though I didn't change anything else.
Scott: suddenly everything was way better in the games department.
Rym: yeah like out to this.
Rym: like my computer now if I turn off that CUDA renderer in the previews and I try to even watch a video in all eight of my hyper cores.
Rym: just go 100% yep and stay at 100%.
Rym: yeah but so my computer does not have USB 3. whoa my computer does not.
Scott: mine has mostly USB 2 but still in the front and the back has a couple USB 3.
Rym: USB 3 did not exist when I built my computer.
Rym: Wow my computer does not have PCI Express 3. whoa I have I have to.
Scott: I love.
Scott: mine has three.
Scott: mine might only have two.
Rym: I have to 16x PCI Express 2. meaning there is a warning from my gtx 770 video card that says yo dawg you're not getting the full power of this video card.
Scott: mine might only have two might not have three.
Rym: m.2 did not exist as a form factor.
Scott: yeah no I didn't have that on that either.
Rym: yeah but you don't need that really.
Rym: yeah no I only have three gigabit per second SATA not six.
Scott: I have six.
Rym: yeah I do not have six.
Rym: so the bottlenecks in my computer not on my drive support six.
Rym: so here are the bottlenecks.
Rym: I'm running into one if I want to use like OBS to like live stream a complicated game on my computer.
Rym: now some things.
Scott: I can use my G you can use the Nvidia to help you out with that.
Rym: I can for some games.
Rym: not all games.
Scott: mine works with X split because I paid for the X split.
Scott: I can do with pretty much everything.
Rym: true but like OBS will also use the video card if I use the shadow play.
Rym: you're saying yeah we'll use the shadow play but I can still use CUDA to do the rendering right.
Rym: but there's all these ancillary things going on like if I'm doing an emulator like emulators are not that CPU efficient and there's a lot of things.
Rym: basically three gigahertz is the sweet spot.
Rym: you want to be just above three gigahertz.
Scott: three and a half.
Rym: I've got two point seven.
Rym: that's how fucking old my core i7 is.
Scott: really.
Scott: that much difference.
Scott: yeah seven three and a half yes there is seven and four.
Scott: that'd be a big difference.
Rym: yeah that's the thing.
Rym: if I build this new computer for not for like 400 bucks not even I can have a four core eight cores with hyper threading four gigahertz core i7 not bad yeah not bad at all but there's not.
Rym: so the other things I'm running into my OS is on a spinning disk.
Rym: because when I built this computer when I built the computer I installed Windows on a 32 gigabyte SSD.
Rym: because let me tell you what in 2009 SSDs were not cheap.
Rym: nowadays Windows won't fit on a 32 gigabyte SSD.
Rym: yeah I transferred it to a spinning disk.
Rym: it would be a giant pain in the ass to transfer it back to an SSD.
Scott: I have a small SSD but I also have a big one that I bought.
Scott: that's ticked.
Scott: I have a 256 and a 128. nowadays you can get like terabyte ones.
Scott: yeah.
Rym: so here's the thing with.
Rym: if I build a new computer I can get a 512 gigabyte m.2 SSD which it looks like a RAM chip.
Scott: yeah pretty much literally.
Rym: just stick it in the motherboard.
Rym: yep on a special connector.
Rym: yeah.
Scott: so my OS you don't even need SATA ports.
Scott: yeah my OS and all my apps you know.
Scott: the best part about that is is that you don't need to wire a cable from the power supply over to the drive.
Scott: yeah you just put it in the motherboard.
Scott: it's done.
Scott: that's part of it.
Scott: yeah.
Rym: so the other thing is it'll be six gigabits per second instead of three and IO is the single biggest bottleneck.
Rym: now not even the fact that Windows is not a spinning disk is actually that doesn't matter much because of ready cache and I have you know so much.
Rym: RAM like that doesn't matter.
Rym: my computer is slow when I reboot rebooted for like an hour but once it's like everything's cached and in RAM it's fine.
Rym: when I'm doing video editing and I got a bunch of 4k videos they're on SSDs they're on three gigabit per second SSDs.
Rym: that's actually not enough and my disk IO buses max out when I'm doing a lot of the other real bonus of the m2 thing is that you can have a really small case.
Rym: yeah I'd really don't like big case.
Scott: it's like the GPU and the power supply are the only big things left that go in the case.
Scott: otherwise you could pretty much as a flat motherboard right and that's it you could have like this really flat computer.
Scott: that's ridiculous.
Scott: that like a video card except for the fact that this GPU and a power supply right if you have a bunch of Express cards for like firewire right but like if you don't need the other stuff.
Scott: you could maybe lay the GPU sideways and save a ton of space but that power supply is just hanging on the edge there.
Scott: it could still be really really small though if you wanted it to maybe a specially shaped power supply like an l-shaped one.
Rym: yeah I don't know but you know all these other things like USB 3 I'd really like to have.
Scott: yeah that's good to have.
Rym: so I was speccing out like and I specked out what computer I built today and I specked out two versions.
Rym: I specked out the.
Rym: I need to shave money where I can like.
Rym: yeah there's a $350 motherboard but this $210 motherboard is pretty much just as good like.
Rym: you can shave like.
Scott: what is the difference between a 350 and 200?
Scott: so you want to know the difference?
Scott: well get a different spot.
Scott: why would I ever spy the $300 motherboard?
Scott: that makes no sense.
Scott: well I can't imagine what it does that I would need.
Rym: here's what I've been thinking about and I realized this because I didn't experiment - that's a ridiculous motherboard you don't need.
Scott: I can see it from here.
Rym: it is a ridiculous motherboard you don't need except there's a few things.
Scott: what it's ridiculous?
Rym: plastic cover not cool but plastic means you don't have to dust it.
Rym: that's bullshit.
Scott: just have a positive pressure case next.
Rym: now you'll still get Dustin whatever.
Rym: so one.
Rym: if you amortize the money you spend on a computer over that useful time anything someone tells themselves to buy the $300 not.
Rym: the moral of all this at the end Scott is I'm not buying this computer.
Rym: okay I'm not buying it sure but I'm gonna tell you the things.
Scott: this motherboard what this motherboard looks like.
Rym: if I see it again in person there is no reason cheaper motherboards could not do what this motherboard does.
Rym: all right.
Rym: so one this motherboard actually has a pretty clever thing.
Rym: it has this cooler built into the motherboard every mother.
Rym: but it's no not like this.
Scott: you're believing the advertising?
Rym: and no no so they're sure this cross cut like cooling thing would actually be really good.
Rym: okay if you're gonna overclock which I'm not gonna so it's not useful to me don't need to overclock.
Rym: the processor I'm gonna buy is four gigahertz stock right?
Rym: yeah yeah.
Rym: but so here's the thing.
Rym: when you put RAM into it you don't have to push it down with both sides and then click it.
Rym: all the cards.
Rym: you'll stick them in from the side and just push them down from one side.
Rym: they're designed to slide in from an angle with only one Clippy.
Scott: so this thing you're going to do once in your entire life.
Scott: yeah just clip RAM sticks into the motherboard.
Scott: you're willing to pay an extra hundred dollars for that experience of clicking ramp guys in one.
Rym: what did I just say?
Scott: I'm not buying this computer.
Scott: I'll take the harder to click in RAM sticks for $100.
Scott: savings please.
Rym: it's also actually reinforced on the bottom with these big steel plates so you can just fucking push on it.
Scott: if that one time that you put the motherboard in the case you don't have to be careful.
Rym: yeah yeah that one time I've seen people push ram in here a little click motherboards they suck.
Rym: well also they're usually buying some crap.
Rym: Oh motherboard yeah anyway now doesn't really have much else to offer.
Rym: that actually matters like this.
Rym: why even talking about the stupid motherboard other than it has twice as many USB 3 ports as any other one of those motherboards?
Scott: how many?
Rym: uh one two three four five six and then it has four.
Rym: it has a six USB threes two USB twos and a bunch of other stuff.
Scott: yeah of course it's not big deal yeah.
Rym: but other than that like the more expensive motherboards unless you're overclocking or doing something weird like they have all these things that only matter if you're fucking with the computer.
Rym: a lot like it's all these buttons.
Scott: yeah if you're taking RAM in and out all the time to test a bunch of different RAM sticks absolutely I'm buying the extra hundred other mother boy.
Rym: yep it's got like extra buttons like you can do a memory test just by hitting a button on the motherboard without even I do that so often yeah but so I'm always slightly wary of stuff like that.
Scott: like really is there a problem with this motherboard that I need to keep doing memory tests all the time again?
Rym: if you're like overclocking or some crap?
Rym: sure yeah yeah but even then think of it this way.
Rym: the weird crazy motherboard is like a hundred bucks more than the normal motherboard like.
Rym: it's interesting how the prices don't actually really scale that much.
Rym: there's still a really minimal range of price.
Scott: dollars is a lot because it's 33% of the price.
Rym: yeah but in the grand scheme of a computer if you're buying a computer for upgrade ability the money I spent that computer in 2009 amortized until 2015. all the things I spent money on forward compatibility kind of washed out mm-hmm.
Rym: but the real the real sweet spot is that right now there is pretty much one processor to buy the core i7 4790. it's four gigahertz it's 350 bucks.
Rym: it's four cores.
Rym: cost as much as a fancy motherboard yeah but you can buy the much cheaper motherboard and this processor and oh that's a good move.
Rym: it comes with a stock cooler that works just fine.
Rym: yeah if you're not gonna overclock which you shouldn't shouldn't 32 gigabytes of RAM is like 150 bucks.
Rym: I still have.
Scott: 32 gigabytes of RAM was cheap when I bought my computer because I still I had 32 gigabytes of RAM then and I still do now and it's still.
Scott: I've never filled it up.
Scott: even when I had like a virtual machine minimized and I was playing a full-screen Scott I filled up my current computer and an Adobe app open.
Rym: my current computers.
Rym: RAM is actually really slow and my web browsers are open and minimized when I hold my computer is my computer has something that disappeared.
Rym: hmm six dim slots three-way interleaving in the RAM.
Rym: that's gone.
Rym: that doesn't exist anymore okay so I have six dims in my computer.
Scott: right now I have four eights.
Rym: I think yeah but yes for like 1200 bucks you can build an amazing badass computer.
Scott: assuming you already know my computer was like not that much money well maybe I should.
Scott: was it was this the time that I spent too much money I forget?
Rym: yeah I looked at all.
Rym: I went through all my old Newegg invoices.
Scott: I think the reason it was.
Scott: I haven't.
Scott: I can't look at it right now but I think the reason mine is expensive because I went all out and got the ridiculous 680 which is like the top-of-the-line video card at the time.
Rym: yeah see this assumes I'm not buying a video card but it assumes I'm buying a really fast m.2 SATA like you know six gigabit per second.
Scott: yeah I never.
Scott: I don't include the storage in the cost of the computer.
Rym: I'm including the storage because now storage is the primary bottleneck.
Scott: I may have to buy some storage though even though I'm not buying a new computer anytime soon because I might have SSDs.
Scott: I have a big SSD I think it's a 512 you know for my OS and program files and then I have a smaller one.
Scott: I think it's a 128 for like the Adobe app swap space.
Scott: yep I have a swap space used to be my primary SSD when I had in the previous in the core two and then I you know moved it down.
Scott: I just cascade all the SSDs down to less important do and I've got a NES which has all my backups and all sorts of other stuff.
Scott: but I still have some giant magnetic discs for like my documents my photos yeah.
Rym: so nowadays I was looking videos.
Rym: you know how much a two terabyte 7200 rpm spin in this cost.
Scott: how much 60 bucks?
Scott: are you sure that's not the weirdo cheap unreliable like you know what.
Rym: just buy four of them and put them in a raid 10.
Scott: I think when Windows 10 comes out I think I'm gonna buy and replace my magnetic discs with some other bigger ones so I can know what we're out of space for videos and I can I'm going to have more comfortably edit the videos.
Rym: I'm gonna have all SSDs for everything except like video that I'm not working on anymore and like photos and stuff for there.
Rym: I'm just getting like four two terabyte drives and just raid them up and just stick them in the case hmm cuz for like that'll make my Lightroom workflow a million times easier.
Scott: frankly yeah I just weaver Windows 10 so I can do the clean install and everything will be yes.
Rym: also Windows 10 is gonna have some really fancy drive volume stuff.
Scott: so like wait like how's that gonna work?
Rym: so you know windows can kind of do like raid stuff.
Rym: now on its own it can.
Rym: it's actually pretty good it just it's not worth it.
Rym: the word on the street is that Windows 10 is volume management obviates the need for some of that motherboard.
Rym: bullshit raid.
Rym: hmm and you can just tell it like hey these four drives they're actually one drive and it just does it and this is the kind of parody I want and it's actually performing and cool and some smart people have been telling me some stuff.
Scott: I don't want any parody in my computer right cuz?
Rym: oh yeah you do.
Scott: I'm just using backups on the NAS which is parody.
Scott: I want more space and speed in my in the computer.
Rym: yeah but thing are so cheap that just do a raid 10 a four discs.
Rym: two of them are just mirrors of the other two the drive the disk anymore space.
Rym: each you'll have four terabytes of usable space.
Rym: it's four terabytes of usable space a hundred percent redundant with double throughput.
Scott: on reads that I guess right now I've got a one terabyte in to 500 so that'll cost you doubling my space under 400 bucks.
Scott: yeah it's cheap.
Rym: that's cheaper than a Drobo and you don't have to buy some proprietary external thing that then you know Lightroom freaks out because like the NAS is asleep or whatever.
Scott: that actually would be nice though if you could get like I was talking about before the small computer if you could just you know put the video card on the side and make the power supply smaller yeah if you can get the really small computer that still didn't sacrifice anything power wise then the DAS suddenly becomes great.
Scott: sitting next to that right because you just like shove the DAS under the desk somewhere but a long cable hide it away you know.
Scott: keep the small computer within reach so you can hit the power button and then he's just all monitors everywhere mouse keyboard yeah.
Rym: so anyway that the whole sum of all this is what I decided is like Scott doesn't need to upgrade.
Rym: I do need to upgrade but there is no reason upgrade right now because when I built my computer in 2009 it lasted until 2000 and fucking 16. the computer I build in 2006 will 15.
Rym: I guess.
Rym: cuz I'm gonna buy it before the end of this year but near the end of this year.
Rym: September is when to do it.
Rym: wait till September.
Scott: why September?
Rym: because if you wait a little bit longer Intel Skylake is coming.
Rym: okay the next Intel architecture.
Rym: this is the talk the architecture shape.
Scott: big one.
Rym: this replaces Broadwell.
Rym: huh Broadwell had a really short life.
Rym: okay skylake actually is a big jump forward.
Scott: what are they doing in sky like this?
Rym: okay skylakes.
Rym: one is gonna support DDR4 which is already starting to appear.
Rym: okay.
Rym: so DDR3 is reaching end of life.
Rym: skylake specifically is going to backward compatibility.
Rym: support DDR3 in case you have some six-liner so you can build a new computer at the end of the year with a brand new skylake core i7.
Rym: like ridiculous thing but with existing RAM that's super cheap.
Rym: and then two years later when DDR4 is cheap just upgrade mm-hmm.
Scott: is it gonna be that much faster to have DDR4 instead of three?
Rym: DDR3 was that much faster than two was it?
Rym: yeah yeah there was RAM.
Rym: getting faster mattered a lot.
Rym: just we've been in this DDR3 like I can't 1333 for a long time anyway.
Rym: yeah also having more RAM having it faster kind of matters.
Rym: there's tons of other stuff in skylake but the gist of it is that skylake is gonna start having support for things like Thunderbolt 3 and the motherboards and the chipsets.
Rym: supposedly there's a new chipset coming the sunrise point.
Scott: they're just coming out with crazier and crazier names every day.
Rym: but as far as I can tell point skylake is the next like really big micro architecture shift from Intel.
Rym: so if you're gonna buy a brand new computer might as well just start using.
Scott: we should make a computer hardware company that makes PC parts and use all cyberpunk names for everything who be like yeah our new chip the Matsumoto Taka Drive whatever.
Rym: but you know you you want me you want to build a computer for maximum forward compatibility and follow the Rym lifestyle of spend a lot of money on a crazy computer and then use it forever.
Rym: wait until September because August is when skylake supposedly is gonna come out.
Rym: skylake will have the most forward compatibility.
Scott: I think about this for a second.
Scott: look.
Scott: up in the sky there's clouds and shit and a lake.
Scott: it's just water up there but there's no ground holding the water into a lake shape.
Scott: that's just water in a lake shape up in the sky and for once birds are swimming in it fish.
Rym: it's easy to fall into a trap.
Rym: in of September comes ooh skylake.
Rym: see what you can look at Intel's roadmap you can look at Wikipedia and you can see cannon lake is coming.
Rym: cannon lake is after skylake boom.
Rym: that's when they go down to 10 nanometers.
Rym: 10 all right 10. here's why this is not a problem.
Rym: that's not coming out till 2017. so if you're gonna upgrade upgrade in 2015 don't wait two more years.
Scott: so yeah uh the 10 nanometers will matter more in the laptop area.
Rym: well yeah the thing is cannon lake is a tick.
Rym: it's not a huge change.
Rym: they're just shrinking skylake basically.
Scott: next it'll be sky ocean.
Scott: yeah well in an ocean the the successor.
Rym: there's debate over this next successor but it seems like skylake is the confluence of.
Rym: chipsets are getting more modern big changes in architecture long cycle.
Rym: skylake is gonna be the beginning of a long forward curve.
Rym: so the computer I specked out that I'm going to sorry you suck now.
Rym: yeah AMD is I mean on entity sort of got burned by.
Scott: you know evil monopoly.
Scott: but I mean chips.
Scott: quality is the quality.
Rym: yeah guys like when I when I put installed a case seven like shit didn't work on the first boot.
Rym: Thunderbird shit didn't work on the first boot.
Scott: I have a whole lot member I. you know I said I only had an Athlon one out of my four computers.
Scott: as an AMD.
Scott: I got a lot of AMD motherboards a lot of AMD chips because that shit broke a lot.
Rym: yep meanwhile all my Intel stuff is a hundred percent fine.
Rym: in fact when I buy my new computer my existing one super powerful still I'm turning it into a dedicated Civ 5 pit boss server.
Rym: okay it'll run that just fine.
Scott: yeah it's a little overkill.
Rym: no because you actually need a computer that can fully run Civ 5 as though you're playing it as a client to be a pit boss server because of poor architecture decisions.
Rym: okay so you have to be a player to be a pit boss server all right.
Rym: so yeah I kind of do need it for that which kind of sucks.
Rym: but this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.