Rym: So, of all the weird recruiter messages I get in email and LinkedIn, how come none of them are ever like, "Hey, you want to work at a game
Rym: studio?"?
Rym: It's always like, "Hey, do you want a terrible
Rym: job?".
Scott: How come it's at least never like, "Hey, I realize that looking at your profile here that the job I'm offering is not better than what you have, so I'm not going to bother
Scott: you.".
Scott: And then when you do get an email, it's like, "Oh, I actually have a better job than what you have
Scott: there.".
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, only one recruiter that's bothered me- If you check someone's LinkedIn profile and it says like, "Oh, yes, they've been working at Disney World for five years.
Scott: They're in charge of taste-testing funnel
Scott: cakes.".
Rym: Let's see if they want to be a janitor.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like, you can't come to them and be like, "Hey, I got this great opportunity for you at
Scott: Quasi-Pac."
Scott: Pastoral tech.
Scott: In Connecticut, you know, taste-testing soda.
Scott: It's like, "That's not as good as funnel cake or Disney
Scott: World.".
Rym: But, I got probably my favorite one ever recently, it was in LinkedIn and it was literally just- If anyone goes to me in LinkedIn, I just click ignore so they don't even get to me.
Rym: So this one was weird because it gave a salary off the bat and basically was a tantamount to an offer, but I'm going to quote, "Help, Brandon ampersand Q-U-O-T semi-colon Rym ampersand Q-U-O-T semi-colon
Rym: comma.".
Scott: Spam message.
Rym: Hope all is well.
Scott: It's obviously a spam, not an actual person.
Scott: Most of the time, it's an actual person, just a dumb one or a desperate one.
Rym: But to their credit, the job they offered me was actually something that I technically am capable of doing.
Rym: It was fixed production support specialist, which I have done and I know how to do, so their bot must have- And not many people on earth can do.
Rym: Yeah, which is scary and surprising because it's real easy.
Rym: Like real easy.
Scott: So if they'll pay $145K for that- I know a lot of people who could use $145K, who are smart enough and capable of learning that.
Rym: I know you want to make video games, but you're not gonna.
Scott: So instead, learn this- And even if you're gonna, you're not going to be John Carmack successful at it.
Scott: It's just, I mean, it's possible, but it's so unlikely.
Scott: Just learn this tag equals value nonsense and get a job doing fix whatever and you'll make money and then- And then you can make video games when you're not at this boring desk that you're sitting at for eight hours a day.
Scott: And with $140K, if you live the way you're living now with your low income, you'll save up enough, you can just like quit and not work for some time.
Rym: I mean, seriously, I learned that protocol in about a week and after a few years, I probably am one of the world's leading experts on that stupid thing.
Scott: Well, who invented it?
Rym: A consortium for the industry so that it would be neutral.
Scott: But I mean, there's no person who's like primarily responsible.
Scott: that you could, you know.
Rym: There are people like that, however- Who are actually on the consortium?
Rym: Well, I am a member.
Rym: I'm on some of the working groups, actually.
Scott: But I mean, who was on the original consortium?
Rym: So the original protocol is garbage.
Scott: If you quit your job, do you lose your position on the consortium?
Rym: Yeah, actually, because you have to work for a company that's sponsoring it to pay for it, which is fine because me being on ... Years ago, me being like in that group meant, "Oh, I'm going to try really hard to make this protocol
Rym: better.".
Rym: Now, it's just a bunch of conference calls that I dial into and then immediately mute.
Scott: Right?
Scott: Someone's on those conference calls talking.
Rym: Yeah, and it's always either someone whose job at their company is to push the protocol in a direction for selfish needs or people who are trying to get a job somewhere else and are trying to grandstand and show off.
Rym: So after I explained to people for like the 18th time what Bitcoin and blockchain actually do, I just stopped bothering.
Rym: But that's not gaming.
Rym: That's not anything related to Tuesday.
Rym: That's just things going on.
Scott: It could be related to gaming.
Rym: It could be.
Rym: Pick a game in the fixed protocol.
Rym: Use the fixed protocol as your middleware in the game.
Scott: All right, it's called Stock Exchange.
Scott: Here's how it works.
Rym: Actually, if someone made a game or a simulator or something that would ... You know all those programming games?
Rym: Make a game like that.
Rym: that's like, "You're trying to pull the Superman 3.
Rym: Here's a bunch of stock exchanges.
Rym: You're a broker," or whatever, and you just start spoofing and hacking the fixed protocol and all that nonsense.
Rym: That could be a moderately fun game.
Rym: Anyway, got any news?
Rym: Gaming news?
Scott: There's a lot of little gaming news because this weekend that just passed, November, whatever it was, was the most gaming weekend.
Scott: that wasn't a PAX all year.
Rym: I really wanted to go to a portion of that, but south of Staten Island is kind of far away.
Scott: Let's talk about all the things that happened this weekend.
Scott: Number one, smallest possible thing, the 20-sided store in Brooklyn, New York, which has been like sort of renovating and not having events for like a couple months, had a Netrunner tournament again that I didn't go to, but we're back in business in Brooklyn, baby.
Scott: All right, number two thing that happened on this epic gaming weekend.
Scott: Also Netrunner-related, the Fantasy Flight Games World Championships were this weekend.
Scott: Don't go to Minnesota just to play games, kids.
Rym: That's a bad idea, but do- We went to San Antonio just to play games.
Scott: Just by me specifically to play one game, right?
Scott: But do sit at home and watch on Twitch as the same guy wins again with a deck.
Scott: that is a cancer upon all of Netrunner, but it happened.
Rym: Why don't you just play that deck?
Scott: If you want to win, sure, go ahead, but it really fucking sucks.
Scott: It's boring as hell.
Rym: Dude, there was the era in Magic when you would just play like a red burn deck and it would beat 95% of people.
Scott: This is worse than that.
Scott: Anyway, it's not Netrunner.
Scott: So yeah, this also included, so the guy who won the X-Wing Championship won it for the third year in a row.
Scott: The guy who won Netrunner won it for the second year in a row, but there were plenty of awesome games of Netrunner and other Fantasy Flight Games to be seen, and also plenty of news and updates from the championship, so exciting things there.
Scott: The BlizzCon was this weekend, which had the Hearthstone World Championships, among other things.
Scott: Totally, a guy won who never won before, and there were some epic games of Hearthstone to be seen, and what was interesting there was almost the opposite of the Netrunner situation, where in Hearthstone, the number one deck people are complaining about is this secret paladin who I really like, because paladins sucked for a long time, and I like paladins the most thematically, and I like secrets thematically, so the fact that secret paladin is like the best is the awesomest, but the guy who won the World Championship didn't use no secret paladin, so it shows what all the people complaining about secret paladin know.
Scott: They don't know shit.
Scott: Secret paladin not that good, but I like to be a secret paladin, so also the games that happened here in the finals, they're pretty amazing games.
Scott: if you like to watch some Hearthstone, and the final gaming news from this past weekend, it was the Extra Life gaming marathon weekend.
Scott: Extra Life is like a charity where you play game marathons and you raise money for the children or whatever.
Rym: Multiple of our friends ran events for this.
Rym: We did not, nor did we go to any, because we sucked.
Scott: I think there were the most number of gaming marathon charity drive stream things this weekend for all the people who weren't watching BlizzCon, who weren't watching Fantasy Play Championships.
Scott: There were a zillion different charity streams to watch of people marathoning this and that.
Rym: I was sitting in my house editing tabletop videos.
Scott: I was sitting in my house watching these streams.
Scott: I didn't even watch football.
Scott: It was also a football weekend.
Rym: I did learn, finally, how to color correct to make my old shitty camcorder kind of match the colors of your actual camera.
Rym: I learned how to do that.
Rym: That's what I did.
Rym: That's the game I played.
Scott: Couldn't you just take a screenshot and drag it over, tell it to speed grade, whatever.
Scott: Anyway, so yeah, mad gaming things happened this past weekend.
Scott: If you missed any or all of them, they're all on the internets for you to check out post-hoc.
Rym: So Fallout 4 is being rated 9 to 9.5 out of 10.
Scott: I mean, that was a guarantee, right?
Scott: I mean, it really couldn't have been rated anything less than nine.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: The level of buzz and excitement seems to be equal to when Fallout 3 came out, despite the fact that this is the second time a Fallout reimagining has occurred.
Rym: So I'm going to play it when it actually gets released.
Rym: Game of the Year edition, 2016 Steam sale.
Scott: Holiday sale, 2016.
Scott: Fallout 4 is going to happen.
Rym: Listen, I know it's a good game.
Rym: Fallout 3 was a good game.
Scott: I played Fallout 3.
Scott: I had a good time playing Fallout 3 and then never played it again.
Scott: I want to play Fallout 4, but I didn't.
Rym: But here's my problem.
Rym: I played Fallout 3 and then they added a bunch of stuff to make it way better.
Scott: That was a mistake that was made.
Rym: And it was good enough to play.
Scott: I actually don't remember if I bought it or if someone gifted it to me.
Scott: If you gifted it to me, thanks.
Scott: But yeah, I should have waited for the $10 Game of the Year edition.
Rym: If they make a game like that better, the game itself is really good, but it's not good enough to play more than once all the way through.
Scott: And it's a single player game.
Scott: Also, I remember I played New Vegas and I couldn't finish it because I guess it wasn't as good.
Scott: Maybe I should go back to that.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Scott: While I'm waiting for the next year, I'll just play New Vegas.
Rym: But I remember way back I saw someone took just Fallout 3, the Game of the Year fully decked out like Super Max edition compared to what the original game was at release and showed a few areas just side by side.
Rym: They're like completely different games sometimes.
Scott: Because they didn't finish the game, they just released it when they had to in time for the holiday season, right?
Scott: Black Friday is real soon.
Scott: People are buying PS4s and things and getting Fallout 4 for free with them, right?
Scott: So it's helping everybody in the money department.
Rym: Now I'm not going to lie, if Fallout 4 were just installed on Steam right now and I hadn't actually bought it- I would be playing it right now.
Rym: I'd probably double click on it as soon as I finish the show tonight.
Scott: Sure, probably.
Scott: But- I'm going to click on Rocket League instead though.
Rym: I'm not eating that marshmallow.
Rym: I'm going to wait.
Rym: This is going to be the Game of the Year edition.
Rym: But I noticed something weird.
Rym: A lot of people have also noticed this.
Rym: So the reviews all have numbers because that's just the stupid thing that people do.
Rym: So 9 out of 10, 9.5 out of 10.
Scott: But all the reviews attached to those numbers- Does he mean the words that no one reads?
Rym: The words actually talk a lot about kind of empty, not that much to do, gets boring after a few hours.
Rym: But glitchy.
Scott: I read about a guy who got stuck in elevators and he was so sad he had to load a really old save.
Rym: That's actually an article I've got up here in a tab right now.
Rym: But there is an update, supposedly that person had not updated, they had a pre-release copy that was buggy and they hadn't downloaded the latest PS4 system update.
Rym: That update, that news, 5.13 PM, so not long ago.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: So yeah, this is people, it's like dudes, update your shit.
Scott: I always say this a lot, but no matter what you've got going on, people are always hesitant to install updates.
Scott: Your Creative Cloud, update everything.
Rym: There are situations, I will give you, yes there are situations.
Rym: For example, my laptop, old Lenovo, like an X230, it's on Windows 7.
Rym: I have the icon to upgrade it to Windows 10.
Rym: I was, when I got that notification of you can upgrade, two days later about to fly on a three week business trip where I needed to use my laptop a whole bunch.
Rym: So I did not click install until I got back from that trip.
Scott: Sure, that makes sense.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Because it would have erased everything.
Rym: So yes, there are situations.
Scott: But I mean, don't, you know, unless, that's a reason in your life, that's not a technological reason.
Scott: Technologically, update fucking everything all the time.
Scott: Unless you know for a fact something specific is like evil out there.
Rym: Yeah, or like you're responsible for a hundred computers.
Rym: Update one of them, make sure it works and then update the rest of them.
Rym: But the edge cases, it's like the people who say I'm not fat, my high BMI is because I lift weights.
Rym: Well, yeah.
Scott: And this way you can avoid problems.
Scott: You know, you think, oh, it'll be such a problem.
Scott: I update my Photoshop.
Scott: They might move a button on you.
Scott: Yeah, that's not a big deal.
Scott: You know what's a big deal?
Scott: Writing an article that makes you look like a dumb ass because your elevators didn't work when everyone else already had the patch.
Scott: That's a problem.
Scott: That's a much bigger problem.
Rym: Like Creative Cloud, like look at the change log of Premiere.
Rym: A lot of those bugs are, yeah, your project's just fucked now.
Rym: or yeah, that just won't render because reasons.
Rym: So I saw a dude, because I was looking for, I was having a problem the other day.
Rym: That's where I tweeted my haiku from Adobe Premiere because when a render fails, it's supposed to give you like a log and an error, like it could have file somewhere.
Rym: No.
Rym: You know what that file says most of the time when it fails, unknown error and nothing, no information, no way to get more out of it.
Rym: So I was Googling like, is anyone having this problem right now with this particular thing?
Scott: The Adobe forums are actually surprisingly good.
Rym: Yeah, but I found a dude who was like, I'm having this problem.
Rym: It was the same kind of problem, but he had a screenshot.
Rym: I'm like, Ooh, cause he was doing a similar thing to what I was doing.
Rym: I click on his screenshot.
Rym: He is clearly running like a CS4 premiere and I'm like, dude, it's 2015.
Rym: Just let it go.
Rym: But, uh, I just, I, the comment I make is the numbers on game.
Rym: reviews seem to be driven by expectations and the words of the part that actually matter.
Scott: I just don't read or look at any reviews at all because I already know what this game's going to be.
Scott: I don't need a review to tell me what fallout four is going to be.
Scott: And that is fallout three with better graphics and all new maps and all new bad guys and all new stories and characters.
Scott: But otherwise the same game, mechanically speaking.
Rym: Well, when I, when I trust for review, I pretty much just trust the word of mouth of a handful of people.
Scott: All I need are two words, fallout and then the number four, I see actually only one word and one number.
Scott: That tells me everything I need to know.
Scott: Why do you?
Rym: Maybe not.
Rym: What if the game was transcended somehow?
Scott: Like they just went way overboard and find out when I played it.
Rym: Oh, you're not going to find out because someone tweeted like, Hey guys, I'm sure I would hear just through the buzz.
Scott: I don't need to read a review.
Scott: It's like I'd hear a rumbling like what follow up for is nothing like fallout three.
Scott: It's a completely new kind of game.
Rym: Whoa.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: But that's it.
Rym: I hear a rumble.
Scott: That would have been a news.
Scott: I don't see any rumblings.
Scott: Therefore, all I heard is for her because I
Rym: guess my perspective is few skewed just from getting like press releases and sort of like following the meta ahead of things instead of like, also
Scott: I saw their cute videos, which I talked about all the different stats and those were
Rym: really good videos.
Scott: Those videos also taught me everything needs to know.
Rym: Those videos were on par with the team fortress two video.
Rym: I think they were better if you did you watch all the team because they made more team fortress two videos.
Scott: But these ones are more timeless.
Rym: Uh, no, I don't know.
Rym: I can watch those heavy videos over and over and you're not bad, but you know, anyway, the only other thing is there's a game out.
Rym: I've not played it yet, but I will tell you now that it's one of those like short games that's going to be big.
Rym: So if you need a game to do a panel about at a con, the game that you're going to want to do is called undertale.
Scott: Everyone keeps rumbling about this, but isn't it just like a JRPG with like a fortune styling?
Rym: Well, it's interesting.
Rym: you say fortune styling because I wouldn't say that it's like a, so imagine an homage to earthbound.
Rym: that's short and to the point without any repetitiveness.
Scott: So it takes how many minutes?
Rym: Like it's like a six hour game.
Rym: That's short enough ish, but it's got RPG style combat except that combat actually ends up being platforming or shmuping or bullet hell.
Scott: and it's got bullet hell.
Scott: What's the difference?
Rym: Uh, well sometimes you're platforming around obstacles with gravity.
Rym: Sometimes you're flying a heart around avoiding bullet hell.
Rym: Sometimes you're flying a heart around shooting at things, that kind of stuff.
Rym: It's got a great soundtrack and it's got a lot of those, you know, an RPGs have all those like dialogue choices and things that don't mean anything.
Rym: from what I can gather in this game, everything means something.
Rym: So every choice you make will have some effect on the game later.
Rym: So there's nothing but checkoffs.
Scott: It could be just a small effect.
Rym: Yeah, but it's little things like there's a spider girl who attacks you, but way early in the game there's an item that's like you go to this bake shop and for 9999 gold, you can buy a spider like pastry.
Rym: If you buy one, she's like, Oh, I guess you bought one of my pastries.
Rym: Cool.
Rym: I guess you're cool with spiders.
Rym: Stuff like that.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: It's also got like real plot stuff, but, uh, if you want to play that game, I'd suggest playing it now.
Rym: ish because it's going to be like five nights at Freddy's and the internet's going to increasingly go apeshit over this thing.
Scott: I'm thinking the internet's already gone apeshit, I've seen this referred to all over the place.
Rym: So if you're
Scott: the kind of person who made this thing,
Rym: if you're the cat, well, I'm going to wait and do a full review of it, but I'm going to play it cause I'm kind of into this, but if you're the kind of person who is afraid of spoilers and that game looks at all like ups up your alley, just play it now because it's going to get spoiled.
Scott: How can you spoil something with so many possible endings with so many dialogue choices?
Rym: Well, cause there's some tropes and some themes and secret endings and also delightful things that happen in certain situations.
Rym: One of them was spoiled for me involving an inventory item called annoying dog.
Scott: That's a Rym thing for sure.
Scott: Like dog and Rym likes annoying.
Rym: So Scott, I'm going to spoil this for you now.
Rym: See what happens guys.
Rym: So you come to this room, there's this artifact, like a fancy artifact with a secret.
Rym: You're like, yes.
Rym: If you try to pick up the artifact, it's like, can't pick up artifact, have too many dogs and inventory.
Rym: And so you go to your inventory and of course you do have that annoying dog.
Rym: So if you drop the annoying dog to get rid of it, then the dog is just on the screen with you and it runs over to the artifact, merges with the artifact and just runs away.
Rym: The end.
Rym: And it plays a really great song while it does it.
Scott: Go in a different room.
Scott: Drop the dog.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I haven't played the game, but I'm gonna.
Rym: Things of the day.
Rym: So I got a tiny thing of the day, but it's not enough.
Rym: So I got a real thing of the day too.
Rym: The tiny thing is someone noticed, this is a thing on Kotaku that, you know, Call of Duty games are pretty scripted and there's not that much FPS and going on most of the time.
Rym: So they noticed that in a particular long mission where you're like in a, like you're the guy man in the turret while the game is driving the car, he just sits there looking around.
Rym: Just enjoying life, looking around.
Rym: And it turns out that that particular scenario, literally nothing you do has any impact on the game.
Rym: And it's just a like movie that plays out while you ride.
Rym: So you might as well just not even shoot.
Rym: Just kind of enjoy the experience.
Scott: Enjoy the scenario or just don't waste your time in this garbage game.
Rym: They're not the worst games.
Rym: They're just.
Scott: But it's still not worth your time.
Rym: What if you were unemployed and wealthy and you'd beached enough?
Rym: Like now it's cold.
Scott: Go to somewhere where it's warm and continue beaching.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway, my real thing of the day is I remembered this Donald Duck cartoon from ages ago and I just randomly found it the other day.
Rym: It's from nineteen fifty nine, which means there's some casual racism in the middle.
Rym: Just be warned.
Rym: It was it was nineteen fifty nine.
Rym: That's how Disney.
Scott: Seventy seven or fifty eight.
Scott: No, it's fifty nine.
Rym: But this is one of those workplace safety videos like shake hands with danger, featuring Donald Duck.
Scott: Yeah, well, you know, Donald and the duck characters, Donald and Daffy, you know, they like to be the ones that are on the receiving end of the pain scenarios.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But the story of this one is Donald Duck just fucking dies.
Rym: The end.
Rym: It's.
Scott: Oh, OK.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Also, he has a shook hands with danger and appears to have a stereotypical 50s housewife who is not Daisy.
Rym: I don't think it's Daisy.
Rym: If it's Daisy.
Rym: Daisy's not doing so hot anymore.
Rym: OK.
Rym: Anyway.
Rym: Well, that guy's my man.
Rym: That's fate.
Scott: That's fate.
Rym: I thought fate has a good voice actor, too.
Scott: I thought that was Hemingway Von Duck.
Rym: When you hear the voice.
Rym: But anyway, we're earnest quacking way.
Rym: It's the hat and the eyes.
Scott: I know.
Scott: Anyway, thing of the day.
Scott: So, you know, people they like to make cakes that are also objects and it's like you can't believe it's a cake.
Scott: It looks like a sculpture.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And you know, people like to make delicious cakes that are beautiful for weddings and such.
Scott: Well, this there was a cake convention.
Scott: That's basically like the packs of cakes or cake conventions.
Rym: Yeah, we're doing panels at those now.
Scott: You don't know anything about cake.
Rym: Our food, our food topics are real popular on gig nights.
Rym: I think we could do a food panel at a cake convention.
Scott: All the people coming to your panel are people who bake cakes for a living.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: The panel is going to be about like hot dogs or something.
Scott: But anyway, anyway, so these people had their little booth at the cake convention to advertise their cake making facilities and prowess and the cake they put on display.
Scott: They wanted to show off the fact that they could make both the sculpture cakes and also the wedding cakes.
Scott: So their sculpture, you could just look at the sculpture.
Scott: It is the nerdiest, best cake I've seen.
Scott: And, you know, what if there's not?
Scott: if I just describe it to you, you won't need to look at it.
Rym: In the moment, the booklet book was The Wheel of Time.
Rym: Book one, famous, famous nerd book.
Rym: We read it.
Rym: We reviewed it.
Rym: We kept reading the next four books after that.
Rym: So there's some there.
Rym: If you want a fantasy book, the novel will probably do a nice little like follow up episode of the first four or five books or so.
Rym: we have a Patreon.
Rym: If you give us as little as just one dollar, it's one penny, one dollar a month.
Rym: You can't give a penny at least a dollar.
Scott: I think worth a penny.
Rym: You'll get some stuff.
Rym: Go check it out.
Rym: We released the original nice T-shirt and let me tell you, the printing technology of this version of the T-shirt way better than what I was able to put together back in like 2007.
Scott: Do we actually have one?
Rym: Yeah, it's.
Rym: so there's two colors now.
Rym: You can get the shirt in cranberry like that red or gray and it looks great.
Rym: It's also got the little gig nuts logo on the back like we always wanted to do, like Pax does.
Rym: That's not bad.
Rym: And it's unlike what we did before, we had one die that we paid for basically for the screening.
Rym: So it was the same size no matter what.
Rym: Amazon just handles it.
Rym: So there's like three different kinds, like man, woman, youth and a million different sizes and actually scale the images to work for all of them.
Scott: That's cool.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And I don't have to keep a giant crate of T-shirts in the apartment and take them to the post office every day.
Scott: Well, if you want to waste your money on a shirt, you can go get a different one.
Scott: That looks a lot better than this one.
Rym: Six people have bought our shirt.
Scott: It's a pretty good shirt.
Scott: Why?
Scott: Just go for the same money.
Scott: You could have gotten like a nice awesome threadless shirt or something.
Scott: Or what's a really good shirt these days?
Rym: Really good shirt these days?
Scott: You know, the shirt with your favorite sports team on it.
Rym: Just not the Eagles, except so I point out or any other Philadelphia team sports team shirts.
Rym: At least get a jersey and jerseys, especially like NHL hockey jerseys, not cheap.
Rym: There's a reason I wear my old like before they swapped dark and light again for home versus away Fedorov jersey.
Scott: I think this year might be the year where I'm going to get my my plan of sports jersey coming in a Rangers jersey right now.
Scott: See, because I never bought jerseys because it was too risky.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You're just going to injure someone or something.
Rym: See, you New York sports fans like and you can't.
Rym: is not a concern in the middle.
Scott: I can't get a jersey of someone with a short contract.
Scott: It's got to be someone who's going to be there for a long.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Like if I get my tanner glass jersey, I'd already be fine.
Scott: You can get a jersey of someone who's like, you know, not playing anymore.
Scott: Like an old veteran who is already the best.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So my plan.
Rym: See, that's the seller cap problem in the old days.
Rym: Like good person on a team.
Scott: They're there forever.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So I'm going to get me.
Scott: I'll get like a Rangers jersey, but on the Rangers jersey.
Scott: Is it?
Scott: No, it's not going to say Ruben.
Scott: It'll say like number 10 Manning.
Scott: And then I'll get like.
Scott: I'll get like a Mets jersey and on the Mets jersey, it'll be like 11 Messier.
Scott: That is actually a really good idea.
Scott: And I'll get a Giants jersey and the Giants jersey will be like, you know, five.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Or Harvey is, you know, so that's clear.
Scott: And that way you can you can wear like one.
Scott: I don't have to wear the Rangers jersey to MSG.
Scott: I could just wear my men's jersey to MSG.
Rym: That says 11 minutes here on the bonus points because someone who notices what's up.
Scott: If I go to a Rangers, if I go in a Rangers game, we're in the Rangers jersey.
Scott: It still says 10 Manning on the back.
Scott: So people would be like, oh, Giants fan.
Rym: So they changed the format of NHL jersey.
Rym: So I got my old Fedorov jersey.
Scott: I got to figure out what size because they're all designed to have pads under them.
Rym: So what I'm going to do is I'm going to get a Rangers jersey this year because the Rangers are doing real well so far.
Scott: Look at this front runner.
Scott: Not even.
Scott: No, you don't even have loyalty, let alone superstition.
Rym: What about?
Rym: I've been loyal to the Red Wings my whole life and I still am.
Scott: Why are you buying a Rangers jersey?
Rym: Because they're my number two and I've lived in New York for a long time.
Scott: OK, I got a lot of number twos.
Scott: I am not going to ever buy a jersey for any number two ever.
Rym: The thing is, I got to admit, I want the Red Wings to win the Stanley Cup.
Rym: I don't think this is their year, but the Rangers, I think, have a real shot.
Scott: The trick is with the Rangers jersey, you got to buy the one that doesn't say Rangers on the front has to be the one that says New York on the front.
Scott: No, that's the key.
Rym: See, I don't buy your New York cursing issues here.
Scott: That's the problem.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But so my plan is you don't know enough of the history of what's happened.
Rym: The Red Wings jersey will fit over the Rangers jersey.
Rym: So if I go to a game that matters, like if it comes down to Red Wings, Rangers, somehow I can wear both.
Rym: And as soon as the Red Wings lose, I can take that off and reveal my Rangers.
Scott: That's the worst thing I've ever heard.
Rym: But I'm a fan of both teams.
Rym: In fact, I'd be OK if this.
Rym: Yeah, well, no, there's some teams I would not be OK with.
Scott: If someone sort of beaten you up in the parking lot or sidewalk.
Rym: Look, as long as I would just let them, as long as Philadelphia.
Scott: And if some cops came to stop it, I'd be like, whoa, hold up.
Scott: That guy who's wearing both jerseys, he's like, oh, OK.
Scott: And they'd wait a minute before they took.
Rym: As long as Philadelphia, the New Jersey Devils, the Avalanche don't win the Stanley Cup.
Rym: That's really all I care about.
Scott: You don't have to worry about the Avalanche.
Rym: No, I don't.
Rym: They're done.
Rym: They've pretty much been done for a long time.
Rym: Anyway, so we've talked about this when we've reviewed other games in general, many, many, many times.
Rym: We actually submitted to do a lecture on this at PAX Prime, but they wanted our esports lecture instead.
Rym: So we're keeping this in the wing.
Rym: We might do this as a straight up lecture at a future convention, maybe PAX South or maybe MagFest, but rules of games are a real important thing.
Rym: And especially when it comes to Kickstarter tabletop games, I feel like that is like the first thing that they seem to fuck up.
Rym: And I don't know why and how it is that like the rules of a game are actually the hardest thing for people to deal with.
Scott: Because people don't want to read the rules because reading rules sucks.
Rym: But look at this.
Rym: It's a problem across all kinds of games.
Rym: So tabletop, you have the situation of no one wants to read the rules of the game because reading rules is not fun.
Scott: It's a pain in the ass.
Rym: You just don't want to teach the game.
Scott: But teaching is not so bad if you know the rules already.
Rym: But then you've got the situation of the people who want to play the game, but don't want to learn the rules, which is fine.
Scott: There are people.
Scott: Yeah, I still I don't mind teaching a game.
Scott: What I mind is people who don't want to like pay attention when you're teaching, they're just like, just let me play and I'll figure it out.
Rym: It's which would be fine, except those same people get super butter when they lose the game at the end because they didn't know about the special victory points.
Scott: Yeah, maybe they should listen to the rules.
Rym: But you have the added dimension there with tabletop that and people teach the.
Scott: sometimes you don't read the rules.
Scott: Someone teaches them to you and they teach him wrong.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So but you have the problem where you have to implement the rules.
Rym: You have to know them and implement them.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: But video games actually have the same problem, because when you design a game like the rules of the game are your code and independently, there's also the argument that the rules of the game are what you give, what information you give the player to where they will then assume things about how the game behaves.
Scott: Well, it's the Mega Man, Mega Man video, right?
Scott: The guy points out how.
Scott: Mega Man X, you don't need to know the rules.
Scott: You don't need to read the instruction book to play Mega Man X. You just start pushing buttons.
Scott: And, you know, I like to imagine, you know, the rules of a video game or any game as sort of like these walls encircling like rails.
Rym: They're like you're playing a bumper bowling.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like imagine, you know, the entire universe is a big white sheet.
Scott: And you can do anything except the laws of physics are on the edges keeping you in.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You can't do things that break the laws of physics, but you can do anything else.
Scott: You know, those are the rules of the universe.
Scott: You know, these walls.
Scott: Well, and a game is a much smaller space.
Scott: So inside the laws of physics is another wall, right?
Scott: A circular wall you can't get out of.
Scott: And that's the rules of a particular game.
Scott: And so you're inside these walls and you don't know the rules to the game.
Scott: You can't see the walls.
Scott: You don't know where they are, but you know that they exist.
Scott: So you start moving around and exploring the space of what will this game let me do?
Scott: And eventually you bump into a wall.
Scott: It's like, for example, you're playing Super Mario Brothers.
Scott: You press A and you jump and you're like, oh boy, you can see Mario jumps that high.
Scott: That's what you just encountered a wall.
Scott: And you're sort of as you're exploring this space, you figure out, you know, by sort of putting your hand against the wall and pushing the limits right where the walls are.
Scott: You can learn a video game.
Scott: that's simple enough just by trying and trying and trying and seeing what the game lets you do.
Rym: And even complex games.
Scott: And you don't need someone to teach you the rules.
Scott: You need to read a rule book.
Scott: You don't need someone to tell you where the walls are, though.
Scott: That could help.
Scott: It's not necessary.
Scott: You don't need those tutorial bullshit that's in every game these days, because you can just explore the rules space and discover the rules of the game.
Scott: But if a game is too fucking complicated, like I know Europa Universalis, whatever, or even subterfuge.
Rym: Right.
Scott: You need something to read to tell you what things do.
Scott: I mean, you could explore because the game's code is keeping you in.
Scott: You could explore and figure out the rules.
Scott: But if you do, you will.
Scott: It'll take so long because the rule, the shape of those those walls are so complicated, like with Europa Universalis.
Rym: I remember we were trying to play a game with a bunch of friends and I see all these sliders of political stuff and I'm like, huh?
Rym: And I take one and I move it a little bit.
Rym: Think wondering, I wonder what that'll do.
Rym: And suddenly, like all my people died and everything was over.
Rym: Right.
Rym: And that didn't help me.
Rym: That didn't tell me where the wall was.
Rym: It just killed me.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: So the game is too complicated, even though you could theoretically explore to figure out the way the game works because it's a video game.
Scott: It's just too big.
Scott: There's too much going on.
Scott: It's not a nice, simple rocket league that you can figure out.
Rym: Now, the worst thing is a single player non-competitive game can have the same sort of adverse problem.
Rym: So imagine this.
Rym: Imagine a game like Fallout or like a very long form game where like it's a long single player, 20, 30, 40 hour narrative.
Rym: Tactics games and fire emblems and things have these problems a lot.
Rym: Yogurt battles.
Rym: Like, yeah, you can play the game and bumper around and you're fine.
Rym: But then you get 20 hours into the game and find out that, oh, because you did do the magic thing 18 hours ago because he didn't know because blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Rym: Now you can't do the other thing.
Rym: Fuck you.
Rym: Start over.
Rym: And no, the answer to that is to not start over.
Rym: The answer is not play games like that.
Rym: Exactly.
Rym: That's why people want strategy guides and facts for games like that.
Scott: But I think a lot of those games are made in such a way as to intentionally sell a strategy guide.
Scott: Ogre battles, ogre battle 64 specifically.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Where you have to like go ogre battle.
Scott: If you don't know, ogre battle 64 is like an in-game calendar and clock that is always progressing.
Scott: And if you had in order to get like this particular really strong unit, you have to go back to the very first map of the whole game, go into the map at a certain day at a certain time and go into this house at a certain day at a certain time and talk to the person there.
Scott: And at the beginning of the game, this is basically like, you know, in Zelda one, you go into it and it's like.
Scott: old man says something like the dog got this like smoke.
Scott: It's that kind of house.
Scott: Imagine if if you went into the old man's like room at November 30th, 2027, the old man said, oh, I bet you'd like to have 75 bombs instead of saying to don, go dislike smoke and be like, get the fuck old man.
Scott: How was I supposed to possibly know that?
Rym: Well, the strategy guide will cost you five fifty nine ninety nine.
Scott: Well, I think the strategy guide for that game is twenty five.
Scott: But and I only know this because my brother bought that strategy guide.
Scott: But anyway.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So it's even possible for a video game if the walls of the game are complex enough that you can't learn them on your own.
Scott: But a board game, any tabletop game whatsoever.
Scott: There are no walls.
Scott: If you don't read the rule book and don't have a rule book or whatever, you can do whatever you want.
Scott: It's like take a monopoly board, open it up, just throw it on the board.
Scott: It's like you can just reach into the bank and grab all the five hundreds and put them in front of you.
Scott: It doesn't stop you.
Scott: You can take your little battleship or iron, because those are the best pieces, and just move them on the boardwalk.
Scott: Nothing stopping you from doing that.
Rym: So maybe your friends, but they didn't read the rules, so they don't actually have any basis for what they're doing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like you just do stuff.
Scott: You just take a properties, just grab them and put them.
Scott: It's like there's no physical thing preventing you from doing whatever you want.
Scott: You need to.
Scott: The people playing the game need to know the rules correctly and then enforce the rules upon themselves and the other players in order to play a tabletop game of any kind or an RPG or anything.
Scott: So what that means?
Scott: to know the rules, a human being has to know them.
Scott: That means a human being has to read them.
Scott: and now I sucks balls.
Rym: I noticed something very interesting recently because a lot of popular tabletop games like Juggers and Euphrates, I think Pandemic and all those kinds of games.
Rym: There are tablet and phone versions like Carcassonne that give you the bump against the rails method of learning without the frustration of your ruining a game that a bunch of other people are trying to play.
Scott: Right.
Scott: There's also people out there who seem to like they don't want to be taught the rules or read them.
Scott: They just want someone else to read them.
Scott: And then they want to bump against the walls enforced by a human being.
Scott: Like I know settlers, you don't.
Scott: But you want to play settlers immediately and just start playing and have me tell you what to do.
Rym: Can I can I build a settlement there?
Scott: No, you can't because you don't have a grain.
Rym: What about there?
Scott: You know, because that's one space away from someone else.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's like basically just learn the game by bumping where to make a human being be the bumpers, be the walls for you.
Scott: And while that can work and you might be really nice to provide that from someone.
Rym: I'm not that nice anymore.
Scott: It's that's really rude, I think, to ask someone to do that for you.
Scott: It's like you can't be bothered to read or listen to the explanation that they're going to offer you.
Scott: So you're just like insisting that they be a computer for you.
Scott: It's like, fuck you.
Scott: You know, that's so rude.
Rym: But that might be one way around this problem for tabletop, or at least one way to really help is by releasing a version of your game that's digital.
Rym: It's not the same fun experience for a lot of reasons.
Rym: like the UX is not there.
Scott: But people who play Carcassonne on their iPad can then play Carcassonne in person with a lot less trouble.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But at the same time, I've noticed that those kinds of people will often miss a rule or not actually understand how something goes down.
Scott: Because when?
Scott: well, this is something I noticed, too, because a lot of people play these janky ghetto, non-official online net runners.
Scott: And especially when a game automates something for you without you doing it explicitly, when you play in person and you have to actually do something, you may not realize after playing it digitally.
Scott: that that was a thing.
Scott: For example, you play Carcassonne just on your phone and you get to the end of the scoring and it's done.
Scott: You might not actually fully realize how farms are scored.
Rym: And there's also three variants of how to score farms.
Rym: Right.
Scott: And if you play, you know, Netrunner, it's like a lot of people come in to play Netrunner in person after playing it with some janky online thing.
Scott: And they'll forget like, oh, that thing gives me a credit every turn.
Scott: I was getting that credit automatically every turn.
Scott: I keep forgetting to give it to myself.
Scott: And now they fucked up, because when you play that game in person, you have to remember a lot of things and go through it very methodically.
Scott: But you don't develop that methodology because you don't need it when you're at computers doing it for you.
Rym: Now, I feel like there's a whole separate topic we could do if we did that lecture, for example, or just in the show on writing rules, which actually has two factors, again, because if you're looking at a video game effectively writing the rules is either the game design itself or what you present to the player, be it a rule book, tutorials, bumpers, Megaman, Megaman, whatever
Scott: it is to
Rym: give the person the map to the game.
Rym: But with tabletop, it's the words you wrote in that book and the examples you give.
Rym: And pretty much every Kickstarter tabletop game I've ever seen, with very few exceptions, has the second worst rules ever.
Rym: Hell is being the worst.
Scott: Well, some things you can do.
Scott: if you're making a tabletop game these days, if it's not like a giant RPG with a million rules, you can make videos on YouTube explaining the rules, which might be better than a rule book and might be more helpful.
Scott: But there's still.
Scott: someone has to watch it and pay attention to it and comprehend it.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Right.
Scott: I mean, just look at the stupid Wil Wheaton tabletop show.
Scott: That's a you know, how many times they got the rules wrong.
Rym: They had one job.
Rym: Yeah, they couldn't do that.
Rym: Their only goal was to play tabletop game and teach you how to play it.
Rym: And they couldn't even manage that.
Scott: Yeah, I think they ranted about that when it was a news.
Scott: So we'll pass on it again.
Rym: Yeah, you can go read about all that.
Rym: But but it's real simple in a lot of ways.
Rym: It's just people.
Rym: don't put the care into it.
Rym: It's like the people who are writing the rules to tabletop games lately in the
Rym: U.S.,
Rym: especially.
Rym: It's like they've never read the rules to the old classic German games, which had very, very well-written rules.
Rym: You got to look at it like an RFC.
Rym: You've got there's like there's pretty standard language for describing a process.
Rym: Use, you know, terms like may, may not really only need is may and must.
Scott: You really shouldn't use things like shall, because it's a little ambiguous.
Scott: Right.
Scott: May and must are the key words.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Never on your turn.
Rym: You may draw a card at the start.
Rym: You must discard a card at the end.
Rym: That is unambiguous.
Rym: Your language has to be unambiguous.
Scott: I feel like then there cannot be situations where, you know, oh, what if I, you know, it's like, all right, first you play a card, then you draw a card.
Scott: That's your whole turn.
Scott: Play a card, draw a card.
Scott: Well, what if I play this card that says draw two cards?
Scott: Do I still draw a card at the end of my turn?
Scott: Because you said I had this and that.
Scott: And it's like there's a maximum hand size or not.
Scott: It's like it doesn't say anything about whether there's a maximum hand size.
Scott: Oh, I guess I just have this giant hand of cards now.
Rym: And then the answer is, yes, play.
Rym: You should like.
Scott: when you play a game, when you read the rules, like, for example, if you wanted the people to have a no maximum hand size, you can't just not say anything.
Scott: You actually have to say, oh, yes, you may have as many cards in your hand as you wish.
Scott: You need to be explicit about every single detail.
Scott: So no one can possibly have any questions or contradictions of any kind whatsoever.
Rym: You also can't bury that shit in the middle of a paragraph describing something else.
Scott: Yeah, the structure needs to be step one, the objective of the game.
Rym: The objective of the game is to win two.
Scott: Well, how?
Scott: what constitutes winning?
Rym: You win by collecting the most victory points at the end of the game.
Scott: Then the setup of the game.
Rym: Take these X pieces, arrange them like this.
Rym: Twenty dollars to each person.
Rym: Everyone starts with two cards.
Scott: Well, these are what these pieces are called.
Rym: The oldest player goes first.
Rym: This is a merchant.
Rym: This is a trader.
Rym: This is a dog.
Rym: Right.
Scott: Then turn structure.
Scott: Do these things in this order very specifically, so on and so forth.
Rym: You may do this, then you may do one of these one and only one.
Rym: That is one of your favorite terms.
Rym: One and only one of these three possible action.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Then you say what constitutes the game ending?
Rym: The game ends when someone runs out of dogs or there are more than 20 dogs out on the board.
Rym: And then you say how to determine who won after the end is ahead of the victory points in this specific order, this specific way, wherever the most wins.
Rym: In the case of a tie to have a fistfight in the winner of the fistfight.
Rym: When if the fistfight is also a draw, then rejoice in your shared victory.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That's how you write every game.
Scott: Every tabletop game rulebook should be written that way ever.
Rym: If your rulebook does not follow that basic format, either you are a genius or more likely your game sucks.
Scott: It's the old, you know, it's the old cliche, right?
Scott: You can break the rules once you know the rules.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Once you've already mastered the rules, then you're allowed to break them.
Rym: Yeah, that applies to every profession in the world.
Rym: When I took music theory classes, the professor was like, these are the rules of writing music.
Rym: If you follow those rules, you're guaranteed to result in music that a human can listen to and not want to vomit.
Rym: If you break these rules, may God help you.
Scott: So there are common mistakes I see in tabletop, but also RPG rules.
Scott: Common mistake number one, writing the same rules in like different places in the book so people can't, when people want to look something up, they can't find it or it's in two different places and it's worded slightly differently in both places.
Rym: Luke.
Scott: Sorry, Luke.
Scott: And they're like, oh, God damn it.
Scott: So pissed off.
Scott: If there's a rule about, say, you know, the dogs, all the dog-related rules should be in the dog section.
Rym: Now you can reference and restate those rules in other places.
Scott: With the exact same language, not differing by a single word.
Rym: But all the rules about dogs have to be in the dog chapter.
Scott: Every single one.
Rym: There can be no exception.
Rym: that is not in the dog section regarding dogs.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: The other common mistake number two, not accounting for all possible game states.
Scott: Yeah, there might be a scenario where, oh, well, OK, we've read all the rules and we're playing the game.
Scott: Oh, wait a minute.
Scott: There's three guys in that place and two guys in that place.
Scott: But the rule says that, wow, that's not a possibility that the rules accounted for.
Scott: I don't know what to do now.
Rym: Now, this is handled, one, by being super clever and actually playtesting your game so thoroughly that the odds of a situation that could occur actually occurring at some point approaches one.
Rym: But even if you don't do that, there's a pretty easy way out.
Rym: You've got to have a very consistent guiding principle in the rules so that if there is an unaccounted for situation, the rest of the body of rules combined allows players to deduce the correct behavior.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Imagine if there's a game with cards and one card said, get five dollars no matter what.
Scott: And another person had a card that said, cancel someone else's card no matter what, which no matter what wins.
Rym: And now you've got to go through the rest of the rules and see how similar situations are handled.
Scott: And if your rules are well written, any education will be able to look up that particular card in the in the reference of the rule book.
Scott: And it'll say, aha, no matter what cards cannot be beaten, no matter what, even by other no matter what cards.
Rym: So Glory to Rome is a great example of this.
Rym: It actually has really well written rules, despite the fact that somehow everyone fucks up this game and plays it wrong.
Rym: But they don't read the rules.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: If you don't read them, it doesn't matter how written they are.
Rym: But if you read the rules of Glory to Rome, they have a very clear guiding principle that if a card ends up doing something crazy.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Like everything is absolute.
Rym: The rules make it very clear that whatever happens, happens.
Rym: And that is absolute.
Rym: If it seems broken, well, yeah, go for it.
Rym: So independent of that, later in the other section of the book, it lists every single card in the game, explains that card in deep detail, deeper than you think you need.
Rym: And it then lists pretty much every possible interaction that card could have with another card that might be strange or difficult to parse.
Rym: So by having both a consistent guiding principle and very clear examples of all the interactions, they cover themselves 100 percent.
Rym: And the few situations that aren't covered by those rules, and there are a few, are easily decided by a reading of the rest of the rules.
Scott: Like it talks about.
Scott: like if you look and the thing is, they do it both ways.
Scott: I'm pretty sure they do it both ways.
Scott: It's been a while since I read that rule book, but like let's say there's the sewer and the latrine.
Scott: I don't even know if those cards work together or not, but I don't forget what the latrine does.
Scott: But let's say for example, yeah, let's pretend that they work together, the sewer and the latrine, because it makes sense that they would based on their theme.
Scott: Pretend it's not even glory to Rome, just in case I'm, you know, being stupid.
Scott: If you look in the sewer card in that reference next to sewer, it'll tell you the rule for interacting with the latrine.
Scott: If you look in the latrine section, it'll tell you about the sewer.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: In exactly the same language.
Scott: That way, no matter which one you look up, you'll find it and you won't be like, derp, derp, derp, derp.
Rym: But number three, you know, rule, common to say.
Rym: number three, inconsistency, that only works if your rules are actually consistent.
Rym: If you have rules and then you have the list of examples, but the exceptions and the interactions don't really like, they don't make sense.
Rym: Like you read them like, oh, that's weird.
Rym: I guess those two cards just work a different way.
Rym: One, that usually means the game failed in playtesting and the game designer just kind of made a hack.
Rym: And two, the game probably sucks.
Rym: Inconsistent rules are worse than missing rules.
Scott: The more mistakes a rule book has like this, you clearly, the less thought and the less testing the people who made the game put into it is a sign the game is probably not good and not worth playing.
Rym: That usually comes out of, I've seen this happen.
Scott: It's very rare you see a really good game with really poorly written rules and it's really rare you see a really bad game with really good rules.
Rym: When I see a popular game that has bad rules, or especially a kickstarted tabletop game, usually what I think happened is they had mostly their friends playtesting the game.
Rym: And, you know, a group of people playing the same game over and over starts to assume a game culture and game expectations.
Rym: So like when me, Scott and our friend Alex, we played Puerto Rico hundreds and hundreds of times, we sort of got into a rhythm and the expectations about how to play that if we played suddenly with a third different person other than Alex, the game might go way differently and we might not expect things to go the way they went.
Rym: So if the same people keep playtesting your game, they might start playing a rule wrong and there's no one to point it out to them and they just assume that's how the game works and they never look at the rule book again so they never notice the ambiguity.
Rym: The inconsistency is also a problem in general in terms of if your rules have a lot of exceptions, like if your game is relatively simple, like it's a standard German style tabletop game that takes one and a half hours to play but your rule book is 40 pages long, the game's probably overcomplicated and poorly designed.
Rym: The rules should be pretty succinct.
Rym: If a concept can't be explained succinctly, most likely there's something wrong with your game.
Scott: There's also a lot of situations, I forgot to mention this earlier, video games especially, where there are hidden rules that you couldn't possibly, even if you bumped into every wall, it would be so next to impossible to figure them out because they're hidden.
Scott: For example, if you give somebody a brand new game of Street Fighter 2, they might see that Ryu is throwing Hadoukens at them, but if it wasn't printed on the cabinet how to do a Hadouken, there's no way that they would ever figure that out.
Scott: How would they ever figure out how to do it?
Scott: It would be so difficult.
Rym: Trial and error.
Rym: Game facts.
Scott: Like they're smashing the joystick around.
Scott: One might pop out, but they won't know what they did.
Scott: And then even if I see people, they'll use diagrams, right?
Scott: And the diagram shows the joystick making the quarter circle and then the punch button.
Scott: And there'll be usually like a plus sign in between them.
Rym: Doesn't tell you about the timing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Even if you have that, right?
Scott: You might know, okay, I'll move the joystick down to the bottom, then make it a quarter circle.
Scott: so now it's facing forward and then push a button.
Scott: Wait, do I push the button after the stick reaches forward or just as the stick reaches forward?
Scott: Or do I hold the button down the whole time while I'm moving the stick in this motion?
Scott: Or do I hit the button and then move the stick?
Rym: What about the frame timing stuff of like preloading additional actions and all that frame nonsense?
Scott: Right.
Scott: None of that is explained to you in any of these things.
Scott: And there's no.
Scott: it's because it's so obtuse.
Scott: It's almost impossible to figure it out without someone just telling you or showing you.
Scott: And the game does a very bad job of telling you or showing you.
Scott: And that is a real big problem.
Rym: Now that is an example.
Rym: That's why I do believe, you know, in our game design panels, I talk a lot about how designing for tabletop will teach you the fundamentals of all game design because the game has to be simple enough to be played with physical pieces.
Rym: So you can't make it stupidly complicated unless you're crazy.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Look at how complicated like Master of Orion is.
Scott: And that's not even that complicated.
Scott: But look at Eclipse.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Eclipse had to simplify so much versus Master of Orion to fit itself onto a board.
Scott: And it still has a gigantic board with a million pieces.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: But writing rules and designing games in the same way, if you design tabletop games, it forces you to understand the core elements of games.
Rym: Whereas if you're designing a video game, you can do anything.
Rym: And you might write a lot of code that does a lot of stuff in the game that doesn't actually have any documentation that the user can see.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And then look at something like, you know, the fancy, fancy war games.
Scott: It's like, yeah, they're really complicated.
Scott: Some, you know, advanced squad leader and whatnot.
Scott: But the way they get that across is lots of incomprehensible chits in a gigantic book and lots of paper and pencils and dice and stuff.
Scott: And it's like.
Scott: that's how they managed to fit that crazy complexity onto a board.
Scott: game is a huge, huge book.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: It's like, screw that shit.
Rym: Amateur mistake.
Scott: And no one got time for that.
Rym: If you're writing tabletop rules, use examples in parallel to have the document that explains the game, but have a sidebar.
Rym: that's just showing examples of every one of those concepts along the way.
Rym: That'll save you so much trouble.
Rym: And if you can't show succinct examples, again, your game's probably not that well designed.
Rym: Nope.
Rym: We've gone on about an hour.
Rym: I think that's enough.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Write good rules.
Rym: Read the rules.
Rym: If a game has bad rules, don't play it.
Rym: Don't mistake good game design for good theme.
Rym: That's kind of an orthogonal decision.
Rym: Learn what the word orthogonal means.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's an important word in a lot of game rules.
Rym: Actually, you know, this is the final topic.
Rym: So I have been on panels, and this came up at PAX Dev, at MAGFest, at PAX regulars, all over the place in private conversations.
Rym: There is a war in the, like, how to write game rules and express them to players space.
Rym: And there are two opposing philosophies.
Rym: Philosophy number one is that you should use very precise language with jargon, explain the jargon, and educate your player base to get them to a higher level understanding.
Rym: Like, everyone who plays tabletop games should eventually learn what the word orthogonal means and use it correctly in terms of movement on a grid.
Rym: The opposite school of thought is that you should always write your rules at a seventh grade level for accessibility purposes so that anyone can understand the game.
Scott: It depends on what game you're making.
Scott: The advanced squad leader rulebook should probably just use the word orthogonal, and the rulebook for, I don't know, oshi, probably shouldn't say orthogonal in it, or if it should, it should teach you what the hell that means, because that might be played by someone who has never seen that word before in their entire life.
Rym: So that is what I think we should do, and that's where I fall on that, what you just said there.
Rym: You should use the jargon words.
Scott: Are you really going to say that the advanced squad leader rulebook needs to explain the meaning of the word orthogonal?
Scott: Because I don't think so.
Rym: You may want to have a glossary in the back, but at least for a mass market game, you should use the jargon to explain.
Rym: Like, you should say it is a draft.
Rym: You should use those terms, but your glossary should explain what those mean.
Rym: so that, one, you're basically educating players.
Rym: If more people playing tabletop games know what the word orthogonal means, then we're all going to have a good time.
Rym: It's going to be a lot easier to get people to learn games.
Scott: And if you want, you can always put, you know, the brief version of the rules on BoardGameGeek or something, and they'll just say the same exact rules, but simplified, so you can print them out on one sheet, like, "Oh yeah, draft five cards in a round robin, like Seven Wonders,".
Scott: and then, you know, you don't need...
Rym: So along those lines, last amateur hour mistake, have a section that's usually on a single page by itself that explains all the numbers and fiddly bits you need to set up before a game.
Rym: Like, how much money does everyone get?
Rym: Wait, how many cards do we draw at the start?
Rym: Yeah, I can't express to you how hard it is to figure that out for most tabletop games.
Scott: We're looking at it every time for Bonanza.
Scott: How many cards do we start with?
Rym: I just wrote it in permanent marker on the inside of the box.
Scott: Good idea.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And as promised, because I said in the Patreon quote, "This is super dumb, but if you support us this much, Rym, we'll say your name at the end of each episode after the credits, along with some ultra dumb stinger
Rym: content.".
Rym: We're talking Rims.
Rym: YouTube likes dumb.
Rym: So, without further ado, in order of the amount of money that you're getting to us on a monthly basis, one person is definitely gaming this system, which is beautiful.
Rym: Rebecca Dunn, Nicholas Barlow, James David White, Christian Kuntz, Jessica L. Barlow, Mechanical Mind, Brian Cedroni, Rochelle Mantanona, Finn Eric Solvarod, Rym eats Poop, Edgar Mendez, William Eisenroze, Chris Midd... I drop my microphone, Chris Knox, Flame Darkfire, Samuel Cordery, Daniel Redman, Chris Haddad, Doug Snyder, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer, and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: I can't express to you how stressful it is to try to read a whole bunch of people's names in a row and not really butcher the pronunciation.
Rym: And now I present to you the opposite of A Moment of Zen, the thing that I just do at the end of all these episodes.
Scott: All of the food in Toronto is made of edible oil products.
Scott: They don't have bagels in Toronto.
Scott: They have donuts.
Scott: Donuts made of edible oil.
Rym: I don't like donuts.
Rym: They don't have bagels.
Scott: I don't want to go to Toronto.
Scott: People don't have faces in Toronto.
Scott: They have cigarette ads instead.
Rym: They listen to your phone calls.
Scott: There's a tower in Toronto that controls people's minds.
Scott: It's illegal to possess brightly coloured balloons in Toronto.
Rym: Illegal to own brightly coloured balloons.
Scott: All of the children in Toronto must wear suits.
Scott: Even the girls.
Rym: Three-piece suits.
Rym: The buildings in Toronto have no windows.
Scott: I don't want to go.
Scott: Everyone lives in subterranean caverns filled with donuts made of edible oil.