Rym: It's Monday July 27th 2015.
Rym: I'm Rym I am a Scott and this is an episode of GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We're gonna talk about when things go away You know like services and things just disappear or when I go away.
Rym: Yeah, couldn't really come up with a better title for this one.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So I biked like a hundred and thirty miles this weekend Many miles a good weekend for biking actually.
Rym: in fact we were thinking like oh We'll make some video.
Rym: like we got a big backlog of video to make.
Rym: we'll make some video on Sunday.
Rym: And I was like Scott.
Scott: Let's make some video on Sunday, and then on Sunday I was waiting for you to be like hey Let's make some video, but you didn't.
Scott: so I played a video game all day.
Rym: Yeah, and I was like I'm gonna make some video after I go biking, and I just went biking way all day Biking all day Saturday, but not Sunday.
Rym: yep I biked to Rockaway with Emily and then we walked around and like stood in the water for a while.
Rym: Then we biked back up home.
Scott: Why did you go in the water?
Rym: Because we didn't bring our swimsuits cuz we didn't think we'd swim and then we got there and we wanted to swim And next time we're bringing our swimsuits.
Rym: So uh then the way back wasn't long enough.
Rym: I guess.
Rym: so we looped around Prospect Park a bunch and then went home.
Rym: Then we went back out again like back the way we came to go to some pig roasts thing that was down in Williamsburg With some friends.
Rym: that was cool mm-hmm But it was the pig roast was not as there.
Rym: I could have had more pig.
Scott: It was a. it was a.
Rym: there's mostly a beer roast with pig.
Rym: the pig was super good But I could eat more mm-hmm.
Rym: Whatever, I feel like this right.
Rym: It seems like this bar.
Rym: what they did is they got some other company to come and just like roast a pig and then they Just sold tickets.
Rym: like it was a big event.
Rym: But really it was just a restaurant that had another tiny restaurant with contractors inside of it running one item on a separate menu.
Rym: So they didn't put a lot like the pig was like.
Rym: effort was put into the pig part But the restaurant did not put effort into the whole.
Rym: like this is a pig roast aspect of it mm-hmm.
Scott: So you know there's the John Brown barbecue right over here.
Rym: I do know because cliffs at LIC members get a discount once a week, so you know it's.
Scott: you know It's pretty good there, but sometimes the service is in.
Scott: the service There is super as there is not, but the cornbread is yeah.
Rym: As you walk in there in the evening like yeah, we're out of everything right, so there's a place down near I.
Scott: just we found using Google Maps near the game store where we play netrunner called fat.
Scott: so I don't know if you heard of that.
Scott: It's my house.
Scott: Yeah, it's mildly famous for that place.
Scott: Yeah, we went to that place after a netrunner tournament two weeks ago, and that was they did not even have cornbread.
Scott: They just gave you like dinner rolls that come from a bag from the grocery store.
Scott: But everything else it's by the pound and it is Like all the other things besides cornbread, which they didn't even have.
Scott: maybe they have it other times.
Scott: They didn't have it the day we went Way better than John Brown barbecue our money.
Scott: But the ribs the sauce the be everything was All right, I'm into this.
Scott: so and they even have free water.
Scott: we could fill up our water bottles.
Scott: So maybe you know next Sunday there's a netrunner, I don't know.
Scott: is there anything else happening next Sunday?
Rym: next Sunday yeah Possibly a bunch of things.
Rym: maybe some of our friends might bike here And then we'll have a weekend hanging out or possibly go out to Rhode Island or maybe also go to the shore.
Rym: Everything happens next week.
Scott: next Sunday is August first second right.
Rym: yeah I guess August then.
Scott: so summer streets is Saturday.
Scott: But yeah on Sunday After the netrunner tournament you can go over there again.
Scott: No, I can eat that every two weeks, and then I die happy even if it shortens my life Few years.
Rym: so for once it being Monday.
Rym: We have some science news Because the night's Monday is supposed to be technology and science.
Rym: We don't know anything about science though once we got an astronomer on the show our friend Timo know stuff about stuff But we're not really Scientists.
Rym: like my knowledge of science kind of camps out at AP biology and AP physics that I took in high school In computer science.
Scott: is science in name only?
Scott: yeah, I mean there are some people who do Research and experiments and follow the scientific method regards to computers that you know.
Scott: that is not me.
Rym: so you know what you remember.
Rym: the Five tastes the unique tastes that the human tongue can detect independently correct.
Scott: sweetness yeah saltiness.
Rym: Sourness yeah bitterness yep, so those are the four that we knew for a long time.
Rym: Not that long ago a fifth one was discovered the hippie taste of umami umami.
Rym: Yes, the thing that only a hippie or foodie would say or you know that basically is just the taste of MSG.
Scott: if you say that word then your brow is Like taped to your forehead like yeah, but it's a thing.
Rym: It's a real thing.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, it's not you know, but it's sort of like yeah, you till it killed is comfortable, but you're wearing it.
Rym: So scientists like at Purdue Super recently have real evidence that there is in fact a sixth taste.
Scott: How do they even like?
Scott: how did they determine that it's actually a different taste?
Rym: oh real easily actually.
Scott: What's the experiment?
Rym: like the experiment's always been the same.
Rym: you make a series of?
Rym: uniform materials like a uniform paste of some kind.
Rym: so the texture is the same no matter what mm-hmm and you compose each of these of one specific type of chemical or a combination of chemicals and you ask people to categorize them based on taste and You control to make sure they're not using odor.
Rym: Maybe they don't have an odor whatever you do so that it's purely based on the receptors in the tongue Like so the sixth taste is fat.
Rym: Okay, now normally it was always assumed that humans taste fat because of its texture.
Rym: It has that like kind of soapy feeling like that kind of like the slippery smooth.
Rym: So no it turns out we can actually taste the fat directly and even better.
Rym: we Never noticed this before.
Rym: because humans if you ask them to categorize you give them a bunch of pace and say Here are five categories to put these food these things in.
Rym: you know the five basic things.
Rym: They'll categorize all the fat along with the bitter.
Rym: But if you give them six categories and one of them is called fat or fatty They will reliably put all the fatty things in that separate fatty category, but I mean put it under bitter.
Scott: Okay, so an apple is sweet.
Scott: Yeah, and a banana is sweet.
Rym: Yeah, and a bread is sweet.
Scott: I'm in a sugar bread sure like a melon pond.
Scott: Yeah, right, but they don't taste the same.
Rym: No They don't because it's much like sounds.
Rym: God you your your actual sensation of taste.
Scott: And I would still if you take you wrote the categories in the paper as apple melon pond and banana.
Rym: Ah, but there's a difference there.
Rym: Those are complex Manifold flavors that are caused by these.
Rym: six basic things are different.
Scott: So if you take these six pastes that they are using in this experiment Yeah, combine them in the correct proportion.
Scott: You could create any flavor including banana.
Scott: Yes, or I don't know foie gras.
Rym: That is in fact true.
Scott: I would like to see that proven the opportunity those six pace and combine them in the correct proportion to make banana.
Rym: now The problem is that the human sensation has two other factors the texture Which we use for a lot of reasons.
Rym: a lot of people have trouble with certain kinds of textures and the smell.
Rym: So there's three sets of things that determine our taste.
Rym: But it is interesting that we have a specific receptor for fat.
Scott: and further like you're holding your nose and eating it Yeah, you'll still taste.
Scott: Oh, I got you.
Rym: So here's the thing.
Scott: I got you.
Rym: Apparently fat tastes like shit.
Rym: Humans categorically reject food that triggers this in any significant quantity because the only time our tongue is Stimulated by that receptor a whole bunch without the other ones overpowering.
Rym: It is rancid and decaying meat.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So yeah, that's why humans tended to put it in the bitter category Mmm, and while we're on this topic, you know that map of where you taste different things on your tongue is bullshit Complete bullshit always been bullshit.
Rym: That was net.
Rym: there was never any evidence of that.
Scott: Yeah, I mean swimming after eating doesn't give you cramps either.
Rym: you watch the same video that I watch recently.
Scott: I think I mean, I think I knew before that that it was bullshit.
Scott: But it's something my mom would always stop me from going in the pool after I eat.
Rym: My mom was always like, yeah That's BS.
Rym: Just go swimming.
Scott: But I think I already knew it was B. I was just reminded that it was BS.
Rym: Well, I remember as a kid I was like wait, so what if I just get in the tub?
Rym: Get a cramp just sitting?
Scott: oh no a cramp big deal.
Scott: I want to go in the pool now Warm the sun's out.
Scott: It's going down soon.
Scott: I just ate.
Rym: Yep The only reason I ever had a way to actually go in the pool is because my dad was testing the pH and like doing All that stuff.
Scott: I had to skim it first.
Rym: Yeah, I jump in without skimming is giving later skimming.
Scott: I don't want to swim a bunch of leaves though.
Scott: Yeah, I Was more worried about the pH and you jump off that ladder about leaves in the face.
Scott: Yeah, not good.
Rym: So a second science news, so Scott, did you ever study any Quantum theory.
Scott: I know the things a layman knows about quantum physics But not just a layman layman a nerd layman who's watched some you know, read some issues of National Geographic Or watch some TV shows on Discovery or PBS.
Scott: So like read a few fictions and maybe like one or two non fictions like a Stephen Hawking book So long time ago that I forget most of.
Rym: yeah, so but what I'm making clear here because I'm in a similar boat.
Rym: we Barely, if at all know what we're about to talk about.
Scott: so you're Two or three a lot more about chemistry than I know about Quantum physics.
Rym: at least a few of you are going to be really unhappy with us.
Scott: for the next like four minutes I'll just say less to be less stupid because we don't know about something.
Scott: people on the earth.
Scott: 10 Lee don't learn this lesson.
Scott: It's a really good lesson to learn.
Scott: when you don't know about something Don't talk, you know, there's a sign on happiness.
Rym: Not that long ago where a guy is like standing me a guys at a computer and guys standing behind I'm just bitching about a bunch of stuff like his life's going bad.
Rym: He's talking about all his problems and the guy was like the guy who was sitting there quietly listening just turns around and says You know what a wise man once said that's relevant to your situation and the guy's like what he's like nothing.
Rym: so Quarks, right.
Rym: so Quarks as far as we can tell basically the fundamental particle.
Scott: I thought there was something even smaller.
Scott: what I Thought there was something small.
Rym: No.
Scott: All right shows what I know that core.
Scott: Well in the very least Cory said I didn't know anything.
Rym: work seemed to be fundamental and Combination of them make up like our baryons and mesons like the higher like protons they write a proton is three quarks and a neutron is some number or something.
Rym: and so Did you take any?
Rym: well, but here's what I remember from like high school quantum mechanics.
Scott: So even if you remember correctly, which is a long time ago This was like this information if you remembered it correctly is like 15 20 years out of date.
Rym: Yeah, what I know about quantum physics is pretty much what I did in like 1999 and 2000 in high school and then probably Mixed in with that is stuff.
Rym: I read in like slashdot articles in college.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: That's my knowledge here.
Rym: So You know, there's charges right like positive and negative.
Rym: So an atom by default has to have a neutral charge.
Scott: if it doesn't then it could be some sort of you know Isotope like an extra.
Rym: No, it's gonna.
Rym: it's gonna be an ion.
Rym: It's not gonna be charged.
Scott: in that case Isotope is a different number of neutrons.
Scott: Yeah, it could have.
Rym: you know, good have an extra electron here there You know, but then but if it has extra electrons, it's gonna have extra protons to have a neutral charge.
Scott: Well, it'll be a different.
Rym: It'll be charged proton.
Rym: Yes, it'll be charged stable.
Rym: So Quarks are the same way.
Rym: For another attribute that we you know, we talked about with colors.
Rym: So there's three colors of quarks and they each also have their anti color.
Rym: So there's six three and then three anti kind of like how there's one positive charge and one negative charge.
Rym: with electric Dark works like two-thirds one-third like there's they're not I don't know you don't know.
Rym: Okay, pretty sure quarks are like a two-thirds of a charge or a one-third of a charge and they gotta add up to a whole.
Rym: Well, anyway, we're not talking about electricity.
Rym: We're talking about the color stuff.
Rym: So in the color stuff to have a stable higher order particle What I remember learning is that they have to be the color has to turn to whites.
Scott: Yep so
Rym: either it's white because you have one of each quark of either the normal, you know that the quarks or one of each of the anti quarks so the color will be white or Have a quark and it's anti color quark -
Scott: yep
Rym: So I remember when I would when I learned this.
Scott: they're not actually different colors It's just a symbol that hat it's just.
Scott: you know, something happens.
Rym: This thing is color.
Scott: So right, obviously, you know It's just a symbology representation that happens to line up.
Rym: Yes, but they have this attribute that we call color.
Rym: so dumb young Rym and pretty much any layman will say well What if I had like four quarks or six quarks, but they still add up to white?
Rym: couldn't that be a thing?
Rym: Yes, and it's interesting that in quantum mechanics the layman like well the rules say this.
Rym: So what about that?
Rym: Yeah, totally true.
Rym: and we just fucking apparently with the LHC discovered proof of Penta quarks.
Scott: Yeah, I mean that's how it works right you come up with some rules and you say well According these rules explain the things that we are seeing.
Scott: Wait, but those rules that explain the thing that you are seeing if those rules are true Then we should also be able to see this thing that we've never seen before.
Scott: Let's see if we can see that.
Scott: if we can then those rules are probably the right rules and if we can't those rules Are wrong and we need to come up with a different explanation for the things We already saw.
Scott: that also includes the new thing that we just you know saw or didn't see.
Scott: so we've had these rules that have explained all the things we've seen so far and Those rules suggest we should be able to see this new thing.
Scott: and we did.
Scott: which means those rules We came up with are more right than rules.
Scott: We came up with before.
Rym: So this is super cool Because it implies that a whole wing of quantum stuff around weird numbers of quarks or even just like a bunch of glue on like Gluons together without any quarks in them, which I think according to this article.
Rym: We call them glue balls.
Rym: They're just glue ons.
Scott: Nice.
Rym: So, uh Yeah, a whole wing of quantum mechanics seems to have a little more evidence.
Rym: However, that's what you get from reading the summaries.
Rym: Here's the actual Title of the paper with the experiment.
Rym: I don't even know how to read this.
Rym: I don't know what the Observation of Jerry over weird VP resonance.
Scott: It's a Greek character.
Scott: Isn't it a phi?
Scott: What the hell is that?
Scott: It's a U with a sword through it.
Rym: A whole bunch of math decays.
Scott: What is that Greek letter?
Rym: Observations of exotic structures in mass of.
Scott: Copy and paste that Greek letter into Google.
Scott: So it'll take which one.
Rym: there's a bunch of them The U with the sword through it.
Rym: You want that one?
Scott: Yeah, that's the one I don't know.
Rym: I Love that I can copy paste that stuff.
Scott: There's psi Psi, not phi.
Scott: Psi.
Scott: There you go.
Rym: So yeah, science news.
Rym: Psi waves Psi beam.
Scott: Okay, so tech news.
Scott: today.
Scott: We're recording this on Monday cuz a Monday show but most people listen to Monday shows cuz we put them out at night.
Scott: Listen to the morning commute on Tuesday.
Scott: If you're listening to this on Tuesday, guess what today Tuesday the the black Tuesday It's always.
Scott: I guess it's not actually black Tuesday black Tuesday the second Tuesday of the month.
Rym: But anyway, July 28th Windows 10 I'm actually kind of excited released.
Scott: if you sign up for the free Windows 10 you can get it.
Rym: Yep, apparently you'll be able to get it even if you didn't sign up, but you might have to wait a little while, right?
Scott: So the the way we've confirmed that it works right is in your little notification area you sign up You know for the update which I did in all three of my Windows computers And then that computer somehow is gonna get the update All right, and then once you've updated I guess you're gonna do an in-place upgrade just from the internet
Rym: Which honestly in the past like as
Scott: I would.
Rym: okay ish Yeah Okay Ish I have never in my life been comfortable updating windows in place on a system I actually use.
Rym: well
Scott: if you were smart and put windows in a separate partition or drive based on your computing situation You are it has been confirmed going to be able to create Some sort of boot media like a USB stick or something and then be able to do a clean install.
Scott: This has been confirmed.
Rym: That's why I kept tweeting that.
Rym: seriously guys if you have a Windows 7 computer and Windows is not running on an SSD Cuz it's an old computer.
Rym: I mean as these are it's kind of recent that there you can buy an SSD.
Rym: That's affordable.
Rym: That's big enough.
Rym: Buy an SSD like a 256 gigabyte one.
Scott: Their computer has room for it.
Rym: Yeah, they're way cheap.
Rym: Mm-hmm upgrade windows make the install media reinstall windows onto that drive your computer will get like twice as fast.
Scott: Yep, yeah, I've got an SSD with Windows and program files.
Scott: So and I've got a bunch of other hard drives that just have storage and I have a second SSD That's just for swapping when we're editing videos.
Rym: and yeah, I have that plus a few more anyway.
Scott: So I'm gonna unplug the storage drives.
Scott: Just I know windows won't fuck with them.
Scott: But just in case then upgrade windows on just the SSD that has windows I can reinstall all the program files.
Scott: Who cares about delete those?
Scott: Yeah And it helps because then I'll be sure to get everything up-to-date and be able to make sure that all those programs work Well with Windows 10 and uninstall them if they don't.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: You also and also all there's a bunch of programs You've installed over time.
Scott: You don't use any that you don't use and it's like you don't know.
Scott: you don't use them and you don't go bother to go Uninstall them.
Scott: So this way you're only gonna install, you know I rec always tell this to people and they don't listen to me right as they go.
Scott: and whether it's a phone or their computer They got like a long list of programs and they're like what app should I install?
Scott: what program should I get?
Scott: And they just install a whole bunch of shit.
Scott: Don't do that when you install Windows 10 and you're gonna do a clean install because you listen to us, right?
Scott: Don't?
Scott: even I install like Chrome Until you actually go at the moment where you say you're going to use it.
Scott: That is when you install it.
Scott: So it's like like, you know, you're gonna install steam at some point.
Scott: But don't immediately go and get steam right.
Scott: install Windows 10 and then just start using your computer as you would use it.
Scott: and Then when you get to the point where it's like I want to play a video game and I do not have steam When you think to go click on the steam icon, it's not there.
Scott: That is the moment.
Scott: You should install steam now.
Rym: realistically There's a few things I do always install right away because I just install chrome within probably the first minute and so Minutes off the top of my head.
Rym: the things I will install immediately when I upgrade my first computer and then re you know Do this thing and you're just all doby stuff adobe style steam chrome Notepad plus plus because I just use the shit out of that thing.
Rym: I use them putty.
Rym: Well, I guess we might not need putty anymore.
Scott: Maybe there's rumors of an SSH client, but it has to be in there already.
Rym: Yeah, if it's not already in there, I'm selling putty.
Scott: right.
Scott: but I mean don't install putty until the moment you're about to SSH.
Rym: I'm gonna need buddy to an SSH like that day.
Scott: most like right, but don't do it Immediately do it the later in the day when you do it.
Rym: Yeah, I know I'm gonna need it.
Rym: It's a good.
Scott: It's a good strategy Trust me because then you basically if what happens is even if you get it perfectly right and you only install the programs You're actually used as you made a list and you know what you know, you wrote track your usage or something, right?
Scott: What happens is when you do that initial setup?
Scott: You're gonna spend a whole bunch of time installing all these programs and it's gonna take like an hour.
Scott: if you just wait It'll still spread out those installs over a day or even a week.
Rym: the one trouble is Like some games take like two hours to install.
Scott: well good Don't waste those two hours unless you're actually gonna play.
Rym: well No, you start them and then they go in the background if you know, you're gonna play it.
Scott: Yeah, counter-strike is probably a safe bet for you.
Rym: Yeah counter-strike said five Necrodancer actually because now this is done and playing the shit out of that game.
Rym: So Yeah, there's.
Scott: that's what you got to know about Windows 10 update.
Rym: and there are two news is about Windows 10 that are very important.
Rym: One Windows 10. if you have the home edition Windows updates will be automatic and mandatory.
Rym: You cannot defer them.
Rym: You cannot pause them.
Rym: You cannot undo them.
Rym: You're gonna just reboot.
Scott: fuck you as far as I know.
Scott: That's a good thing.
Scott: I a lot of people do not do Windows updates and then they get fucked.
Rym: I have zero problem with this because one If you're using Windows home and This bother chrome updates see chrome updates this way and no one gives a shit.
Scott: But when other things, you know make you manually update and they try to go become the chrome model people complain And it's like how come you're not complaining about chrome?
Scott: They already do this even better.
Rym: The the most common complaint is I have a special snowflake use case where my production system, whatever Yeah, I Pro.
Rym: if yeah, if you buy Windows Pro then you have that capability.
Scott: I mean I have I assume because I have Windows 7 Pro on my desktop that I'm gonna get Pro on that desktop and my Others have home premium.
Scott: So I assume they're gonna get home.
Scott: So I'm probably on the pro.
Scott: I'm gonna turn on the auto updates cuz I update everything anyway.
Rym: Yeah, so Windows 10 Pro you can delay them, but you cannot actually prevent them, but that's fine.
Rym: That's what you should be doing.
Scott: fine.
Scott: Also, and if your complaint is but I'm an enterprise as long as we start my computer while I'm using it I don't give a shit.
Rym: Yeah, so pay for Pro if you don't want that to happen.
Rym: and If you need like lockdown control of a bunch of other people's Windows computers, you could already do that.
Rym: Yeah The enterprise Windows crap will do the same thing.
Rym: Doing that since like Windows 95 and T days so you can still stage your production updates into a UAT environment.
Rym: You really need to.
Rym: now Pretty much everyone complaining about this is super butter for no good reason.
Rym: So I defy anyone to give us a an actually legitimate good reason.
Rym: The only one I can see at all is that some people are worried that Microsoft might at some point Remove functionality or lock things down in a way that you can't prevent.
Scott: All right, fine.
Scott: Well, it's not like I've bought a new PC recently.
Scott: so if something if Windows 10 fucks me over.
Scott: I can always go back to Windows 7 and I can always go run Linux.
Scott: So my computers aren't useless.
Scott: cuz remember and I'll just buy Macs the next time I need a computer.
Rym: all the you know.
Rym: Back in the 90s when there was real fear of like government crackdowns on internet free speech and oh, you know The CBD tPA type stuff there was a renaissance of people preparing to run alternative systems.
Rym: We're not really in real danger of that right now.
Rym: And if danger of that appeared like if CBD tPA like shit Started coming down the pipe and windows all the smart nerds would bail faster than you could blink.
Rym: Something would appear that started working and then all the not as well-versed and computers people would be able to Stand on their shoulders and use the stuff they put together.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So I'm not too worried about.
Rym: I'm not worried about NATO FEMA death camps coming in with the windows updates.
Rym: It's what I'm.
Scott: also enough money would divert to alternative platforms, right?
Scott: Like, you know Chromebooks still out there.
Rym: Things of the day.
Rym: So this is the red wall and not nice with the swords not the mice with the swords.
Rym: So there's this wall here and this wall This is a photo gallery had just a area that was painted red.
Rym: The rest of it wasn't painted.
Scott: It's who did that and why.
Rym: uh, that was the question.
Rym: So the red area got covered in graffiti and They kept covering graffiti up with red.
Rym: So a guy went and spray-painted the word red there.
Scott: Oh, is it like an issue?
Scott: Is that why it's red?
Scott: originally to cover up a graffiti that probably couldn't clean.
Rym: So that was interesting as a brick wall.
Rym: So then more graffiti appeared and Then they painted it with a different shade of red that looked like shit.
Rym: Okay, so they have this splotchy red covering the new graffiti.
Rym: So the guy was like, huh?
Rym: So he painted the word red somewhere different.
Scott: There must be an old person who lives nearby who's calling three one one to get the graffiti removers to do something.
Scott: So sure enough is New York, right?
Scott: It looks like New York.
Rym: I don't actually know where it is.
Scott: Looks in New York.
Rym: So he does it again Does it again, so he just keeps painting the word red and they keep painting this darker red until eventually Red question mark he typed.
Rym: he paints red with a question mark in black above the red paint on the regular bricks.
Rym: Mmm So they power washed it.
Scott: Yeah instead of spraying.
Rym: So if it's on the red paint they painted a different red.
Rym: if it's not on the red paint they power wash it.
Rym: So then he wrote pressure wash on the hair and paint red to see what they do.
Rym: Mm-hmm, and they painted it red.
Scott: Yeah About this.
Rym: Well, so you can you can find then the right extended.
Scott: Whoa It was too much red.
Rym: You went above the line.
Rym: So he started painting in other places and Eventually the entire thing gets painted red and it's done.
Rym: So This is super funny and I didn't 100% verify that I catch this person.
Scott: It's painting the same place over and over again.
Scott: You think aha the same person is doing graffiti repeatedly in the same plot.
Rym: Wait, wait Scott, you're asking that question.
Scott: put up one crappy camera.
Scott: You'll catch them.
Rym: We know people who's by.
Rym: we know a person a good friend who's bike was stolen in New York Who found her bike on Craigslist like the next day for sale at an address down the street?
Rym: There is zero doubt.
Rym: It was her bike and the cops literally gave zero fucks and said don't worry about it Don't call us for this shit.
Scott: So be a law that they have to do something and you can sue them if they don't.
Rym: maybe yeah.
Rym: So yeah, this is just super entertaining.
Scott: I mean you could you maybe even could sue the cops.
Scott: you know many lawsuits the New York Police Department gets.
Scott: Maybe maybe they'll just say yeah, they pay a lot of money out.
Scott: Our tax money is paid to a lot of lawsuits against the cops every year.
Rym: Anyway, you got a thing of the day.
Scott: I do so.
Scott: this is actually it not, you know, it's a technology thing Right related to my works.
Scott: I mean the kind of work that I do which is making websites.
Scott: So an issue with websites these days is that the thing people really want to do with websites the most especially new ones is They want the websites to be real time Not real time in the way that you know, I'm operating system token bus, right?
Scott: People don't know a real-time program, you know.
Scott: Like serious real time is for things that need to happen in software within a real amount of time.
Scott: For example, the best example people always use is the pacemaker.
Scott: if I'm writing software for a pacemaker It has to figure out when to beat in Time to beat.
Scott: if it takes 10 minutes to figure out the rate at which it should beat the person is dead.
Rym: now You can't make super fast systems that are real-time because it's actually really hard to make real-time systems, right?
Scott: It's a real real-time systems.
Scott: It's like this has to do.
Scott: it's computing within an amount of real time.
Scott: This must do all this math within three seconds.
Scott: Otherwise, it's not gonna have.
Rym: so in think that's a real-time Deterministic processing times and latency, right?
Scott: That's real time.
Scott: So the not real time is almost all computing which is the CPU does it as fast as it can.
Rym: So you're talking a site like yeah, I need my game my gauges to be moving around, right?
Scott: So when people talk about real-time web what they're talking about is basically Sort of using a TCP IP like push/pull over HTTP web sockets.
Scott: exactly right you visit a website, but you know you edit, you know.
Scott: Normally when you're good to a website you fill out a form you push submit or post it makes a post Database gets updated then data comes back.
Scott: a real-time website.
Scott: For example, you'd be editing your comment and every time you backspace it backspaces and every time you know And everyone else can see this like, you know Google Drive Google Docs where you edit a doc and everyone can see that doc editing and you can see the doc edited by other people And it happens as soon as you type.
Scott: That's a real-time web.
Rym: That's a lot of what I'm actually having built right now and Mike I need I'm making I'm basically getting rid old swing clients Making these real-time.
Scott: well most of the web frameworks the popular ones out there like Django which I use and Ruby which Ron rails Which a lot of people use said embers pretty good.
Scott: He's amber is a different thing.
Scott: That's a front-end thingy.
Rym: So These you're saying like the full.
Scott: yeah I'm at the back end.
Scott: web frameworks these days that are really popular.
Scott: right our bay based on the model of you know Request server renders a response and sends it.
Scott: They're not really built for the real-time web and in order to be built for the real-time web You need like a fundamentally different sort of setup.
Scott: Alright, and the big problem is that even if you were to make a real-time front-end, you know For your application right you use an ember or you know angular or some kind of JavaScript the back-end.
Scott: You set up web sockets and you set up some sort of API a restful API with a web socket connection that gives live updates.
Scott: Behind that the database is not really real-time.
Scott: You need some kind of weirdo Database.
Scott: you can't just use a normal relational database because an SQL query how are you gonna know?
Scott: say Rym visits the website and he updates the Google Doc and In it through the web socket connection.
Scott: So rims connection to the.
Scott: a web server writes to the database.
Scott: How does my?
Scott: You know connection to the web socket application.
Scott: know the database got updated.
Scott: Are the are all the different, you know, all the web servers communicating with each other sideways.
Scott: Then how do you scale out these web servers?
Rym: Is that what was the database like?
Rym: call a stored procedure that dumps something on a queue that goes out to like?
Scott: This guy in Python only right pretty much all you know this thing.
Scott: Writing only in Python.
Rym: I forgot you showed me this video, right?
Scott: He sets up using Postgres in Python this exact thing and his code is so Right.
Scott: He basically every view every URL in his API is a class that has four methods get put post and web socket, right.
Scott: So he's.
Scott: it's like, you know, he uses work Zoe and some other things that you know, you might not know about To just establish web sockets really easily and then and Postgres.
Scott: He's just using a normal old Postgres connection, which is just a relational database.
Rym: Like it's not right.
Rym: It's not any of this modern like no sequel nonsense.
Rym: It's a relational straight-up like select.
Scott: He sets up Basically a trigger to say aha whenever this table is updated Publish a notification here.
Rym: What's he using to publish Postgres?
Scott: Oh These features to do this and he shows you how to set it up to where the application will be notified.
Scott: So Rym on his connects to the app of the web socket.
Scott: He put he sends over some info.
Scott: he updates the Google Doc it gets saved to the database with an update statement The database that has the trigger database or triggers.
Scott: So now over my website connection it goes.
Scott: Hey Yeah This just changed poop and now my will update my browser Immediately as soon as Rym does his thing.
Scott: and this is the exact technology you could use to make say The a jack like game like we discussed last week.
Rym: This is a nice.
Scott: This is a young person and this is coded.
Rym: So, well, this is like a young person simply because like I said that the kind of cruftier way to do that is to use Like JMS cues and things that are triggered from internal database using only Python and Postgres and then it's up to you.
Scott: I mean all it results in is a restful API with a website connection.
Scott: So it's up to you on the front end using JavaScript and some JavaScript framework of your choice Which could be anything because it's just a normal old restful API, you know You can use your embers your angulars your reacts your whatever you like To connect to this and make an application out of it.
Scott: All right, so I think this is a really good example of The way of making ultra modern, you know Websites.
Scott: if you're gonna make a brand new web applications today, you should make it this way and you'll be future-proof for a good long time.
Rym: So our main topic things going away things disappearing because I didn't do a meta moment.
Rym: All right, the meta moment the booklet book is the wheel of time.
Rym: It just keeps on turning.
Scott: I'm getting along.
Rym: I'm getting along too.
Scott: They're uh, they're all party split up.
Rym: One of them's a werewolf, I guess.
Scott: Yeah, I ever got to that part.
Rym: Oh, wow.
Rym: Yeah, you caught up mostly.
Rym: Okay, so they're in fact, we just met the tinkers That's right.
Scott: I got met them too.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So we're about the same point unless you got past the tinkers.
Scott: Maybe.
Scott: yeah, I don't know.
Rym: I'm pretty much in the middle.
Rym: Oh, it's about where I am.
Rym: All right, we're about the same point then.
Rym: Problem is super nice out.
Rym: I only read a bunch today because I had a subway commute.
Scott: Hopefully I won't have that commute the rest of the week since I lost my iPad died And I'm not gonna get a new one for a while.
Scott: I am doing only reading once I'm in bed.
Scott: That's a new rule.
Rym: Oh, so yeah, you could buy the iPad Pro that's rumored to be coming.
Scott: Maybe I will.
Scott: Well, you see what it is.
Rym: So the rumor is that it's just a gigantic iPad.
Scott: How big could it be?
Scott: is a bit.
Scott: if it's too big for my messenger bag, then it's too bad.
Rym: It looks like it's as big as the screen on a MacBook Pro.
Rym: Maybe yeah, I don't know.
Scott: I had to go to the Apple store and check it out.
Rym: Yeah, it's like Cuz.
Scott: I mean I had the you know, the mini iPad and I really like that and it was perfectly big enough.
Scott: But I was kind of thinking about getting the normal size one.
Rym: Yeah Because I don't.
Scott: but if there's a pro one if it's like even harder better faster stronger in addition to being big But it's not too big.
Scott: I could I could see that working but I'd be worried like, okay, it's in my messenger bag crack Exactly when it's bigger.
Rym: It's flexier and more, you know, maybe just get the Apple care with it.
Rym: Maybe the good thing is I need you know by how much is it gonna cost - if it's $2,000 It's my.
Rym: I don't need like that middle ground of like a phablet or a tiny tablet.
Rym: Cuz why I buy there's three tiers of things tiny phone Normal size tablet full laptop for doing real work.
Rym: Right?
Rym: Those are my three things I'll probably just get like.
Scott: I guess they'll come out with iPad air 3 probably in mini 4.
Scott: Yeah, whatever they come out with Yeah, I have to see what the deal is good for.
Rym: good for airplanes Even though there's coming rules.
Scott: that good for notion of hex.
Rym: So if you like if you're traveling and you want to bring your laptop to like use at the destination for like real work And you also bring your iPad there's a good chance that the rules are gonna change and you cannot check Laptops period.
Rym: you have to bring them in carry-on.
Rym: All right, so you'll have to bring your laptop and your tablet through security.
Rym: You can't check one of them.
Rym: All right, that's very likely to ever check.
Scott: I don't check any Electronics anyway, cuz I don't trust that shit.
Rym: I checked most of my electronics.
Scott: a will steal.
Scott: It won't be there when you get there.
Rym: It's never happened to me.
Scott: I mean, I'll check like wires and chargers and that sort of.
Rym: I check them or answers that check my cameras.
Scott: Yeah, I don't check the camera.
Rym: I would not check the Mackie.
Rym: I would.
Rym: I would package this up in a box and bring it special anyway.
Scott: Anyway, or at least I would carry through security and then once you get you can be like, alright put this in the check Like a stroller, you know when people have babies they do that thing.
Rym: We should have a stroller with all our audio equipment.
Scott: One other meta news beside, you know, two other meta news is a meta news number one - because we already the book club.
Scott: Yep Pax is way soon Pax Prime.
Rym: We're gonna be there.
Rym: Scott will be there for four days You know, you'll be there for six days.
Scott: It's Pax The packs the convention that puts all of the conventions behind it the packs.
Rym: Yep, and it's interesting because Across the board based on a couple conventions that I noticed this happen and then I started asking around and it's a pretty Not worrying but interesting trend.
Rym: a lot of fan conventions in 2015 had significantly lower attendance.
Scott: But not Pax.
Scott: Pax sells out boom every time.
Scott: Yep, Pax sold out even faster.
Scott: Pax on the rise, other cons going down.
Scott: What does that tell you?
Rym: So, uh, yeah We're gonna be there far.
Rym: future of gaming on Sunday and sports are games very topical now.
Scott: I'm gonna start working on that right now.
Rym: you start working on that.
Rym: I'll start working on the far future one in earnest.
Scott: a bunch of questions for that one.
Rym: Yep Well, no what I need to do because I what I wanted to do at magfest But we ended up not doing for various reasons is if we're talking about like 30 years in the future 40 years in the future a lot of a slide for each one of these things.
Rym: That's like here's the state of this thing 30 years ago.
Rym: So you can see like wow, we came from that to today in that span of time.
Rym: What's that distance into the future of stuff?
Scott: Anyway, so the final meta moment is that we have a lot of things on the internet.
Scott: I mean if you already listen to this podcast, you probably found us on the internet in a bunch of places.
Rym: But we are in your pro mode already.
Rym: Most people find our other things I never find but we're in the internet and all the places.
Scott: I saw a bunch of like we've received like a more Facebook likes in this week.
Scott: then Yeah, we got like four or five likes on Facebook at the whole in this week Which is usually as many as you get in a month.
Scott: So You should find us if we're is a place on the internet.
Scott: we even have a reddit that's unused.
Rym: Yeah Subreddit.
Rym: the last post was me saying wow, we still we have a reddit.
Rym: Yeah, I didn't even know Scott made this.
Scott: We have a subreddit.
Scott: We've got Google+ we got Facebook.
Scott: We got so much places on the internet that have our stuff on them.
Scott: You should go and make sure whichever place that you use you got a tumblr Rym.
Scott: stop doing and I'm gonna start it up Actually because I'm going to put some content out soon that we got a newsletter They haven't written in months that I haven't forgotten about.
Rym: in fact I'm gonna make sure I don't shit talk on this.
Rym: what I'm putting together is, you know We run the panels and workshops department at Connecticut which happened, you know a couple weeks ago and was super awesome.
Rym: it was the best year for panels pretty much ever and We have all the data on the exact number of people who went to every panel and a whole host all the panels.
Rym: Yeah, we missed a few so I was actually able to backfill in the head.
Rym: We only missed like seven because people didn't fill them out and by asking around people Remembered enough to arrive reasonable estimates to fill in those few holes.
Rym: There's two panels.
Rym: I have no idea how many people went to.
Rym: I'm thinking about emailing the panelists and Trying to ask them without them.
Rym: You're like 108 whatever the size of the room was.
Rym: But I'm going to publish that data to a depth that I have never published it before and Take that every other count.
Rym: who doesn't do anything with that data?
Rym: if they even collect it It'd be of great interest to very few people.
Scott: Yep But yeah, go and follow us and all the internet places that you use whatever you like and maybe also share.
Scott: I don't want to tell people to share but I mean you can share our stuff because You know if we did something that you like, you know, it doesn't hurt to share most in the red.
Scott: I mean I share all your shit When you tell me to.
Scott: so this is why I usually don't tell you to.
Scott: but apparently telling people to do this works.
Rym: I guess yeah on me.
Scott: I'm the opposite.
Rym: I'll put it this way the more you share our shit around and like tell conventions and things like oh get these guys The more we'll actually do like.
Rym: we only do the stuff that we.
Scott: kind of it's like when someone says please rate and subscribe I'm like go fuck yourself.
Scott: Well, if So I don't like to do that.
Scott: But apparently those are the people who get the most rates and subscribe.
Rym: if you want another thousand Episodes of GeekNights over 50 not 15 over 10 years.
Scott: It'll just happen.
Rym: We'll just happen.
Rym: but Like a lot of you have been bothering send me money to pay so I don't die I'll do.
Rym: you've been bothering me about the next GeekNights presents utenna and Those come out a lot faster.
Rym: if you guys make us more popular.
Rym: That's true.
Rym: like Faster than you think they'll come out.
Rym: I'm motivated primarily by vainglory.
Scott: I'm motivated by not the things Rym is motivated by.
Rym: what are you motivated by in terms of GeekNights?
Rym: I've heard my in my order number one habit one vain.
Rym: Okay vainglory Wanting to eventually make money off of this and not do a normal job.
Scott: boredom on we inhabit.
Rym: Yeah have.
Rym: it's a big part I got to admit have it and on week.
Rym: if you want us to be motivated by another factor and do more content It would take a lot of money.
Scott: You know, I'm not unmotivated by money, but it takes a very large amount of money $380,000 a year.
Rym: We will make GeekNights content 40 hours a week forever.
Rym: I Would do nothing but make you yeah, I would be big but a lot of the content would be.
Rym: here's my bike to the beach But we make it Anyway, so a bunch of this other news all was kind of related Which is why we came with the idea than doing in the show.
Rym: So it's just more tech news, but there's a theme.
Rym: Google is blocking access to an API that I didn't know they had.
Rym: I didn't know it because it was an undocumented unofficial.
Scott: How did you even learn about this undocumented API?
Scott: Do you just like inspect the?
Scott: you know, Google made an API for themselves?
Scott: You must have inspected it figured it out maybe documented it unofficially for other people and then people started using it.
Rym: That seems to be the case.
Rym: Sometimes I've noticed Google and other people will publish info like hey, here's this API But don't rely on it for anything.
Rym: It might change or go away.
Rym: We don't support it.
Scott: Well also like I just said if you make a website in the modern way, right the way I just described it The restful API and the web socket someone can just.
Scott: you know, your whole application is JavaScript.
Scott: Someone could just make an alternate JavaScript that for your client for your website for your API You know or they could make it, you know a mobile app that just uses your API and connects to your website.
Scott: They figure it out.
Scott: It's not hard.
Scott: It's all public, you know.
Scott: Yeah, they can just inspect the packets or if they you know, look at your JavaScript code figure out how your API works.
Rym: So yeah, Google's autocomplete API apparently is a really cool thing.
Rym: I didn't know I could mess around with it But I guess as of August 10th I won't be able to mess around with it anymore.
Rym: and they gave their usual like in the interest of maintaining the integrity of Autocomplete as part of search.
Rym: So what I suspect happened, but they didn't say so I don't know is that some people were probably Fucking around with these either to mine data about how Google's page ranky stuff works or to otherwise do SEO manipulation.
Scott: So they were like or just have autocomplete on their websites.
Scott: That was as good as Google's instead of the crappy one that they have.
Rym: Yep, that is my second idea of what's going on, but it turns out they're not just killing that That's the one everyone knew and cared about.
Rym: they're throwing away like 80 of these things.
Scott: Well, probably cuz it's not enough users and there's a lot of maintenance to do.
Scott: Yeah, if you ever if you ever logged in like, you know your Google like API.
Scott: you can get a Google like coder developer account And you get this like control panel of API looking at it right here.
Rym: Look at all these API's right.
Rym: There's a control panel app engine admin API version 1 beta 4, right?
Scott: There's a Google civic information API, right?
Scott: So you basically enable these individually on your account because they all have their own like terms of service agreements for each one.
Scott: and then you can get documentation and start using any one of these or all of them.
Scott: and There's a lot of them and I'm surprised like how many there are they about how many employees at Google are there for each?
Scott: one of these things.
Scott: so if one of them is not being used or isn't important or Wasn't you know isn't in this control panel?
Scott: You probably shouldn't be using it.
Rym: Oh, no, I read that wrong.
Rym: they are just getting rid of that one and There are 80 that are supported and a bunch more that are unsupported.
Rym: Mm-hmm Frankly all the people who are super mad about this If your business relies on using someone else's undocumented API You really have a loose understanding of what it means to have a business.
Scott: Well, I mean so many people use beta unsupported unreleased Production ready stuff right?
Scott: I mean Docker.
Scott: I was you know, I'm trying to learn about Docker because apparently it's the real deal.
Scott: It's not you know, it seems to be actually my industry.
Rym: A lot of people are looking at it.
Scott: It's not a fad It's a real deal.
Scott: So I'm learning it right now to be pro at it.
Rym: I might ask you questions about it later because I haven't looked at it too much.
Rym: But right.
Scott: so I Was watching some video tutorials and things of that nature and I was some of the earliest ones.
Scott: He's like yeah, Docker is not production ready But some of these companies that you see logos of right here.
Scott: are you all these companies?
Scott: You see logos ever using it and some of them are using in production Even though we told him not to and every company was a big major company every single one.
Scott: But the guy who made Docker is standing right there giving this presentation saying it's not production ready.
Scott: Some of these companies are using in production.
Rym: It's like what the fuck someone posted actually on Slashed out of all things a Here's here's why you don't use these one.
Rym: use Google API service to deploy at customer three.
Rym: Wait for it to get cancelled by Google.
Scott: Yes So yeah, this happens a lot in computing right?
Scott: Is there anything that you develop any technology develop always depends on?
Scott: Other people right.
Scott: there is nothing that you can make in computing that depends on no company other than your own or no other body of You know workers technologists unless you are someone like say Intel Intel has.
Scott: They make their own chips and their own fabs.
Rym: Intel relies heavily on Fabrication manufacturing research Technology for a lot of other sources, but I mean tell I mean, they're really low-level.
Scott: they're relying on like silicon mines.
Scott: They probably even own the mines for all we know, right?
Scott: It's like they have their own C compiler that compiles the micro cut, right?
Scott: They do almost everything.
Scott: They don't rely very much on other people, right?
Rym: You know what?
Rym: They probably rely on other people for their internal email?
Scott: probably yeah, like Core product, right, but that's what I'm saying.
Rym: A lot of people if your company Pro just is taking a bunch of other people's services and linking them together Then you can be displaced by anyone pretty much.
Rym: So the key is you.
Rym: there's always that like the debate and finance always build versus buy.
Rym: like you build something or buy it And the answer I always give people is what's your business?
Rym: Like what's the thing you're selling?
Rym: build that part?
Rym: Otherwise, you're not selling anything.
Scott: Yep, and buy everything else.
Scott: Yes, buy every other thing cuz that's not a thing that you do.
Scott: You know, you can put your full efforts towards the thing that you do.
Rym: Yeah, don't write an email don't write a web framework to host your competitor.
Scott: They make chips, right?
Scott: So when it comes to chips, we just talked about they.
Scott: that's all the stuff they build.
Scott: They build the chips because that's their business but their email they don't have some.
Scott: I hope they don't have some like You know version of it, you know exchange that they made their hope.
Scott: They're just using Exchange or Gmail or send mail or something.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: I Mean, we're professionals.
Rym: even we back when we had unlimited free time spent a couple months making squirrel mail work with their own mail server.
Scott: They were like fuck this that's when Gmail wouldn't work with your domain.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway, those are bad old days.
Scott: Yeah this you know this happens so often in the world of computing where something you use or something you rely on that is made by someone else is end-of-life cancelled deprecated just immediately turned off for whatever reason Right, and there's so many different scenarios that you have to deal with.
Scott: but you also many times you said we expect it in advance.
Rym: Well, not even just if you don't expect it at least Anticipated.
Rym: and they are kind of different things like for example the US military, right?
Rym: we have a plan for what if Canada invades and Mexico nukes, Texas, like what would we do?
Rym: We have like we have these plans for every ridiculous ridiculous Yeah, but you don't need ridiculous No But I'm saying they have people whose job it is to take a weird scenario and just as an exercise examine like alright What would we do?
Rym: and obviously like the low-ranking dude or the intern is working on the Mexico nukes us plan.
Rym: But the smart people who actually like matter are looking at the what if Russia for real invades the rest of Ukraine?
Rym: like, you know, we have a plan that will just enact if you're a company or Just a hobbyist.
Rym: You should at least have an idea even if you don't come with a plan At least have a list somewhere that says here are the things that if they change or go away could fuck us.
Rym: So at least you got it in the back of your head, right?
Scott: So here's some basic strategies right for dealing with these sorts of situations, right?
Scott: So the first situation you have to worry about is the end of lifing situation Which is where they're moving on from one thing to another.
Scott: thing has become the hot new deal like Java 7 is and they're not.
Scott: they're not supporting the old one.
Scott: So for example Windows XP right you can still use Windows XP, but Microsoft doesn't putting patches out anymore for it.
Scott: You can't call them up and get tech support for it.
Scott: It's dead But you can still run it if you want.
Scott: So if your application only runs on Windows XP You're kind of hosed.
Rym: so, you know, it's like it's like buying a used car Like you can't like you get to the point where you're not gonna get any more warranty support.
Rym: You're on your own, but it'll keep working forever.
Scott: Right?
Scott: So in these situations, right?
Scott: There's a few things you can do.
Scott: number one You can figure out if it's possible that you could just keep it going on your own right.
Scott: if you go to Windows XP machine in a pretty secure isolated environment and it's really stable and you know that you know One can be attacking it and it isn't really security threats or anything and it works with the application as it is.
Scott: You can just leave it there the same way.
Scott: You can leave your cobalt mainframe running.
Rym: You will still have a long-term problem of eventually computer hardware that it'll run on might not exist.
Scott: That is true.
Rym: Like you really expect Windows one to run on a mod
Scott: You might not be able to you know If that if this RAM in that computer dies and it's a PC 100 RAM or something You might not be able to get a PC 100
Rym: Mitigate that you stock up in that shit now and you have a little mini warehouse of your own That you know to keep going another 50 years.
Rym: sure thing like that's for real.
Rym: That's.
Rym: I was an IBM.
Rym: people do that We had old hardware like that.
Rym: So, you know we did.
Rym: we had like 50 or 60 of this one kind of machine just in a warehouse.
Rym: So that's enough.
Rym: if we have not.
Rym: if well we I don't work there anymore.
Scott: Even if all of those don't work you can put to put together working ones and you know what.
Rym: by the time CPU from one ran from another if that old system hasn't been replaced by the time all that hardware is gone Well, you know what?
Rym: It's time, right?
Scott: The other thing you can do is when things are end-of-life They tell you in advance.
Scott: people knew Windows XP was dying for a long time.
Scott: They announced when things are gonna die.
Scott: so far in advance.
Rym: Yeah Oracle has already talked about when Java 8 is gonna be end-of-life and when Java 9 like they should be Knowing that and being prepared for it when it happens and keeping your shit up to date.
Scott: You've got a lot.
Scott: Windows 7 was out.
Scott: I think when Windows XP died You should have been moving your shit to the other platform by then.
Scott: Yeah, you have time deal with it Okay.
Scott: So there's the other problem.
Scott: is the the sudden death the most the worrisome one, which is like yeah Oh you were using this.
Scott: Let's say using a documented Google API and Google just like oh, we're turning off YouTube Yep.
Rym: No, so here's this imagine if Google just shut down Gmail.
Rym: that's a better example?
Rym: sure because Gmail is the core.
Rym: like a Lot of big companies use Google platform for mail, right?
Scott: Obviously, this is unlikely to happen But if it could it could just say Gmail's off the end.
Rym: now the way I look at it for huge things like that The my risk-reward assessment of that risk itself is.
Rym: that was a weird way to phrase that if I'm fucked by it People way bigger than me are fucked so much more that no one will even notice my problem, right?
Scott: You don't worry too much about that.
Scott: But let's say you use some other email provider that's smaller.
Scott: your ISP's email also unlikely to go.
Scott: But maybe it does.
Scott: maybe your ISP is like yeah, we're not providing email anymore, right?
Scott: Yeah So in either case it's really easy to just back up your stuff in more than one place.
Scott: anything That's.
Scott: remember the easiest thing to do to explain the cloud to other people and yourself is take any sentence where you say the cloud.
Scott: My email is stored in the cloud.
Scott: Replace the cloud with someone else's computer.
Scott: My email is stored and someone else's computer Which means oh shit.
Scott: It's on someone else's computer.
Scott: I don't have a copy of it.
Scott: Also on my computer.
Scott: Download your email archive once in a while.
Scott: You can do it pretty easily It's not a big deal.
Rym: what I'm kind of thinking about doing ever know I gotta have a partner to do it with because I'm gonna have.
Rym: I'm gonna have when I upgrade computers in September - Pretty powerful computers that are pretty rock-solid.
Rym: So I'm thinking about I mean like Drobo's like Daz's and devices can kind of do this.
Rym: you can have two and if they have the same size You can tell them to be basically master master mirror to each other.
Rym: So like Scott and I could each buy a Daz or a NAS.
Rym: Yes, use that.
Rym: but if we had the same one and we set up some software they would replicate to each other.
Scott: So we're not necessary.
Rym: No, but I'm saying you could do something like that.
Rym: I'm thinking about setting that up with two computers just filled with a shit ton of cheapo spinning discs.
Scott: Do whatever you want like DRBD a mode share whatever you mode.
Rym: I forget which ones the asynchronous anyway.
Scott: So yeah If you just back your stuff up in more than one place I have my photos in like five different services and also local storage like there is no way My photo collection could ever be lost if like flicker goes down.
Scott: It's also in like Google+ and Amazon photos and my computer and my NAS.
Scott: It's like I'm safe.
Rym: That's kind of why I want to Daz though Cuz it's a pain in the ass to use a lot of those services with things that are stored in multiple places.
Scott: It's really easy for me to do that.
Rym: It's not just annoying.
Scott: photos are the easiest thing cuz everyone makes applications that automatically deals with photos.
Scott: Yeah to a point but my music is on Amazon and local storage and NAS, right?
Scott: It's like I have everything in so many places.
Rym: My videos are so much bigger.
Rym: I'm not dumping those in most of the places.
Rym: I archive that anyway.
Scott: See it backups, right?
Scott: but another thing you can do is Make sure you control your DNS.
Scott: cuz if Gmail goes down and your email address is at Gmail You just lost your actual email address, even though you backed up your old emails.
Scott: You ain't getting new ones.
Rym: Yeah, Scott and I could point front row crew comm at a different place.
Scott: I could set up in 12 hours.
Scott: I could set up a new email server and My email address would remain the same and all new emails would go somewhere else.
Scott: So it's important to control your own DNS entries Like if your hosting provider shuts down you can move your DNS and point it at web servers somewhere else Even if you have to host them yourself in your own.
Rym: I've noticed a cool trend just kind of along these lines cuz you probably have if you're a company or something a bunch of internal API's and things.
Rym: Mm-hmm modern systems.
Rym: people stopped versioning API's like well, there's the new version of the API.
Rym: get used to it.
Rym: Instead they just spin up another API that has the new features and leave the old one up basically forever.
Scott: Yeah, I see some people do it that way when they have like.
Scott: they rarely make changes to the API and they make big changes.
Scott: They do it that way like Twitter's like oh, here's the old Twitter API Facebook.
Scott: I actually did this a lot.
Rym: Here's the old Facebook API and the new one and it's good when you have lots of consumers of the API that are important But over whom you either don't have a lot of control or you don't really understand their use case.
Scott: Right, but if you or technology changes, right?
Scott: It's like oh we'd had a we had this kind of API But now everyone's using WebSocket API's will make a new one.
Scott: based on that We keep the old one because we keep the old one because you don't want to ruin everyone's applications But we're gonna turn it off eventually.
Scott: Yeah So yeah in those cases you mean if you're using someone's API like that You just have to pay attention to what they're doing.
Scott: So Facebook changes their API.
Scott: You just got to keep up with their changes, right?
Scott: It's it's up to you.
Scott: I mean, hopefully they're doing versioning and things like that to you know, make it so they don't screw you which they're.
Scott: you know They know the bigger they are the less likely they are to screw over users.
Rym: I'm trying to find this article.
Rym: So I read an essay was an article from a little while ago But it talked about because now I want to kind of shift because we've gone on for a full GeekNights episode.
Rym: okay, but on the consumer side services disappear all the time like just basic stuff like.
Rym: So Nintendo had a TV service on the.
Scott: you never heard of it.
Rym: that I had never heard of.
Rym: that Apparently is shutting down in a few weeks.
Rym: Okay, and Apparently it let you like watch TV But then the Wii U controller would like be your remote control and let you do DVRs and we use and give you a quote.
Rym: second screen experience and The quote in this summary is it was awkward and fumbling and less than a year later Xbox one came along with HDMI passthrough voice control TV.
Rym: that made Nintendo TV look silly.
Rym: Yes So if you're a consumer and you use services Stuff's just gonna disappear all the time.
Rym: You've got to be ready to just be constantly sailing from consumer ship to consumer ship.
Rym: Like I bought a Palm Pre that platform failed.
Rym: I'm on it.
Scott: I know I'm on Android like you also just had to do a better job of either not being an early adopter.
Scott: If you're an early adopter, sometimes you're gonna get it wrong, which is fine Just like if you.
Scott: with that if you are an early adopter, you can do a better job of guessing What's gonna sink or swim.
Scott: and if you're if you're in doubt about something sinking?
Scott: Make sure that it's gonna be something like Google Glass or Virtual Boy where even if it dies It'll still be like this precious artifact even you know, that'll be hilarious.
Scott: years and years later.
Scott: You don't want to buy a Palm Pre.
Scott: that's gonna be a worthless piece of silicon like VR technology right now.
Rym: Right, like there's been all this VR stuff Any VR platform you buy is gonna be eclipsed in three or four years.
Rym: So if you drop 10 20 grand on crazy crap Like make sure it's worth it to you to have had that like bleeding-edge experience Cuz yet.
Scott: or make you know, wait until you see who the winner is and then buy in right, you know I didn't buy the iPhone one about the iPhone 3G why?
Rym: that's the reason.
Rym: there is an article that was analyzing a trend where?
Rym: There's a small percent.
Rym: So when you think of like a new social network or new thing There's like this like that five or six percent of people who use the one that fails.
Scott: There are people who used Google Buzz and we're into it up.
Rym: Scott and I and all of their people use Friendster.
Scott: Yeah, we used Orca we use the aliens took it over.
Rym: We used or cut Google like that social network from before Facebook as Our real social network like we all used it on a daily basis for a while.
Rym: That was weird to think back to those days like yeah, so, uh, but this article talked about how it Appears based on some initial studies that it's basically the same five or six percent of people Every time every time what they get they get it wrong.
Rym: Yes, so these people whatever social network they join they foretell its doom.
Scott: they these people bought zoons.
Rym: Yes, they choose the technology that's going to fail before we know it's going to fail because they earnestly think it will succeed.
Scott: Maybe they just have different taste from everyone else.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: So now that the essay was talking about gene for bad taste Yeah, we got to track these people down more.
Rym: So basically that's one of the one of the like.
Rym: a comment was like yes I really want to study this.
Rym: if you've used like more than four or five Platforms that have failed like seriously email us.
Scott: Yeah, if you use like a zoon and a palm free Google wave Google wave and like you were into those things Those are your jam and you're upset that they all got cancelled.
Rym: Yeah, like you had a Nokia engage you.
Scott: really your DNA is Valuable to market research.
Rym: Yeah, you're the failure case not the like.
Rym: you are the canary in the coal mine.
Scott: So the next time you go to buy something buy the thing you think sucks But also tell us the thing that you think is good so that we know and then we can make investment decisions.
Scott: And you should play the stock market also.
Scott: person who knows what?
Rym: Well, I just bought this new mp3 player.
Scott: better short the stock of the company or ah I'm feeling like I like that mp3 player better.
Scott: I'll buy the other brand and short sell the one I wanted.
Scott: That's what you should the prep.
Rym: So I suspect part of it is that those people have niche use cases because those niche use case people also tend to be split 50/50 in my Experience and anecdotal opinion between people who are super pro and have a very specific need.
Rym: That's weird and people are just dumb.
Scott: Well, I think I think it's also sort of a slippery slope, right?
Scott: You buy one thing that sucks and that sort of fills gaps in your needs and then you go to buy something.
Scott: Oh you buy the thing that fills the gap In your needs that are different than everyone else's gaps.
Scott: You already have one failed piece of crowd.
Rym: It's like what I had the palm pre like back when smartphones were still like not really like a hundred percent there yet Because the thing the pre did is it unified all of your communications into one thread?
Rym: That was crazy and powerful and now Google Hangout sort of does it but like Twitter didn't run on that thing.
Rym: No, so I couldn't use Twitter.
Rym: so I would have used Twitter But because I had a web Twitter or text Twitter.
Rym: Yeah, that was web browsers didn't work that great back then and text Twitter.
Rym: No Huh, so yeah, that was just interesting.
Rym: so Now I'm hungry.
Rym: Yeah, I'm hungry as get anything else to say.
Scott: There's one strategy you can use and I just want to say is real quick.
Scott: So I use Amazon Web Services a lot especially at work and Some of the Amazon Web Services like RDS is like run a MySQL server.
Scott: Okay, if they take that away you can just run MySQL.
Scott: so it's not a problem.
Scott: but other things like s3 It's like that's a proprietary thing.
Rym: Yeah, if s3 goes down and you wrote an app that like specifically uses it and its API's right.
Scott: So when you write your app to use something like s3 you should either a make your app modular in a way such that you can switch from s3 to some other storage engine that accomplishes the same task or B you should probably do both these things B write something that has the same API as Amazon.
Scott: s3 sits in the middle, right and Yeah, so that way if Amazon s3 goes down you wrote a replacement for it that looks to your application Exactly the same as s3 but isn't s3?
Scott: You can go on github and they're like storage engines that have the same API as s3.
Scott: just done this.
Rym: So like databases right say you integrate your system use like an embedded database for shit.
Scott: So yeah, make it modular where yeah, you could stick Postgres or Oracle or like Sybase, there are a lot of things out there that just you can use the MySQL client to connect and talk to them even though They aren't MySQL.
Scott: They use they just clone the MySQL API, but here's the secret for using their interface.
Rym: You don't need to actually implement all those other ones just implement the one you need but have that wrapper there.
Rym: Yep, that'll save you so much grief down the road.
Scott: Yeah, it's a really good.
Rym: Okay, I found an article.
Rym: So this isn't the article I read.
Scott: this is going long.
Rym: This is even wider.
Rym: This is consumers who vote for.
Rym: tell Retail doom Wow, they're talking about like Frito Lay like basic consumer goods.
Rym: But it seems like it's actually the exact same concepts.
Rym: I'm gonna link to this article that I didn't fully read yet and if I can find the other article I will link you to.
Rym: Okay, and now I Know I hungry.
Rym: I need some food.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott special Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.