Rym: It's Monday April 6th 2015.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight FPGAs and all those related things.
Rym: Let's do this Been a while.
Rym: since we've done a Monday show It's just every like.
Rym: the weeks we kept missing happened to be weeks where we'd come back on a Tuesday Thursday.
Scott: That's generally how things work if you go away on a weekend.
Scott: Monday's a bad day Yeah, also Monday's the day with the least ideas.
Scott: Well, they were the most likely to bail on it.
Rym: We came up with this idea behind the last show.
Rym: sure and Thank the gods.
Rym: Convention season is done for us until July with Connecticut.
Scott: Yeah, I mean usually convention season is summer.
Scott: usually, right?
Scott: That's what you know.
Rym: We always say usually it was usually for us like five years ago.
Scott: I'm saying conventions originally Historically, we're all mostly in the summer and the big ones still are the you know, the Gen cons the San Diego comic cons Whatever, but the big summer cons that we used to go to we stopped going to.
Scott: conventions are supposed to be in the summer.
Scott: That's when kids aren't in school so they can go.
Scott: wait a minute.
Scott: Wait a minute They can go.
Rym: by that logic.
Rym: I only want conventions that are during school Sure.
Scott: I'm just saying if you're the convention runner you want to get the most people to come.
Scott: they're usually in summer.
Scott: But all the other conventions the ones we go to mostly had to abandon summer to get away from the mega Conventions that were in the summer taking up all the people's.
Scott: so we end up going like a bunch of spring conventions and winter conventions.
Scott: Pax prime is the very end of summer.
Scott: Pax East is like an enemy.
Scott: I was like the beginning of spring and then what made it was pushed to the edges of the summer.
Rym: Because there are four Pax's and they're in different parts of the country or the world They end up like they can be clustered way outside of the norm of like of the convention circuit in the Northeast.
Scott: But this is fine by me because it means I don't have to do anything in summer except enjoy summer.
Scott: I don't have like to abandon some awesome summer weekend to go stay in a giant building somewhere.
Rym: But yeah, I'm gonna.
Rym: I'll keep it short because it's not gonna turn into the biking show.
Rym: But today was the first day first day of the season.
Rym: I biked to work still too cold.
Rym: What the fuck?
Rym: It's like 60 degrees.
Scott: Yeah, which means when you bike it's like 45 degrees Scott.
Rym: You're you're a little baby Like.
Rym: I don't even know what to say.
Scott: I'm gonna shave your head and then I'm gonna send you bike.
Rym: We're a hat.
Rym: you gotta wear a helmet.
Scott: Anyway, a hat is not good.
Rym: I mean I biked to work today and there's no happy medium either.
Scott: Your head is melting because you put a hat on.
Rym: my head is not the factory.
Rym: I was wearing shorts in a t-shirt Like I was wearing a button shirt.
Rym: that I got hot and I unbuttoned.
Scott: did the bridge not blowing mighty wind across?
Rym: it did.
Rym: But you know what I was biking so hard.
Rym: I was still hot.
Scott: why are you biking so hard?
Rym: I always like it Scott.
Rym: So this is the most awesome.
Rym: I biked to working back today and I got used to Strava.
Rym: running hard all winter Really paid off.
Rym: my time not only didn't go down significantly over the winter But my first commute home from work took 30 minutes and historically my best time ever Was 26 minutes.
Scott: my commute is about 30 minutes.
Rym: my commute six points eight six point eight miles.
Scott: Mine's five miles.
Rym: Yeah, five miles.
Rym: Really?
Rym: Yeah It takes you fall.
Rym: I guess you got that Astoria stuff.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So can you do six point eight miles in?
Rym: 26 minutes.
Scott: I don't buy card.
Scott: I just sort of mosey and it takes me 30 minutes to do five miles.
Scott: So I don't know how fast I would go.
Scott: as if I was trying.
Rym: I always bike to damage my body So I don't bike to damage heart like damage levels.
Rym: I bike to hard levels.
Rym: I bike to.
Rym: how fast can I go?
Rym: Without getting to the point where I cannot breathe fast enough to replenish oxygen I do not exert myself.
Scott: I exert myself to the point at which if I exerted any more I would feel uncomfortable.
Scott: I do not feel uncomfortable at any time.
Rym: You still want to do that race?
Rym: I don't think we should race.
Rym: What kind of race we were talking last year?
Rym: We would do a race.
Rym: We're just we both leave at the same time.
Rym: first one to the sand and rock away.
Rym: Sure, take any route you want.
Scott: Sure.
Rym: You wanna race?
Rym: You wanna do it?
Scott: Yeah, why not?
Rym: We should both go pro it giving commentary the whole way.
Scott: So this is the shortcut I'm taking and I'm moseying along.
Scott: Meanwhile Rym pushed himself way hard and he's on the bridge.
Scott: He's dying.
Scott: dying You mean winning and here's me catching up to him on the bridge just sort of moseying and I'm behind him and I pushed him Off the bridge.
Scott: now he can't win You would.
Rym: the thing is you wouldn't.
Rym: we would not be on the bridge at the same time You wouldn't be able to push me off.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Rym: My main strategy when there's danger is to run away faster than whoever it is.
Rym: He's trying to hurt me.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: Well good I'll just I'll just stay right behind you until you pass out and then go to the beach.
Rym: Yeah, unlike my man Midosuji.
Rym: I think I think I can power through to the end.
Rym: That's what Midosuji thought too Yeah, but he wasn't as powerful as I am apparently.
Rym: Okay Yeah You got any news on this tech Monday back from anime Boston back from zinc icon.
Scott: It's News, I don't know.
Scott: It might actually be an old thing That was just recently again re brought up on the internet or it might be new on it I can't tell but it's just kind of cool.
Scott: Estonia a country on the other side of the world You know, I'm sure this country has problems.
Scott: I'm actually gonna be honest and say I don't know a whole lot about Estonia.
Scott: I know it's in Eastern Europe.
Rym: It is perhaps a member of the Baltic states as along with Latvia and Lithuania.
Scott: Yes, that is about all I know.
Scott: But I know one more thing about Estonia now.
Rym: super techie It's.
Rym: I mean the whole Eastern Europe is pretty techie, but it's still in a different way than we are and above other states is Particularly techie at the government level.
Rym: sure has been for a long time.
Scott: So one thing Estonia offers and it sounds awesome when you hear what it is, which it's less awesome in reality is E-residency, so at first you're thinking holy shit I could be an Estonia resident but digitally and not have to go there and that is sort of true.
Scott: But it's not as awesome as you would think.
Scott: but at the same time I mean most kid most punk kids out there.
Scott: I you know if they're like me when we were in our like sea land thinking days.
Scott: Yeah, they're thinking gonna renounce my u.s.
Scott: Citizenship.
Scott: I'll be in Estonia e-resident.
Scott: I'll live on the internet.
Scott: Sovereign citizen can't fuck with me, right?
Scott: That's it.
Scott: That's what the punk kids are thinking right now.
Scott: But sorry punk kids is not what this is.
Rym: see sadly though I knew the thing that this was because I already knew about this from Estonia But because of what they're calling it.
Rym: It's not entirely obvious that it's the same thing right away, right?
Scott: So what this is is you become an Estonia e-resident you apply and they give you like a card and the card has some you Know digital keys in it, you know for.
Scott: you know Secure signatures private public key deal and you can use that card with those keys to legally sign Documents like contracts in Estonia.
Scott: So this is ridiculously useful if you want to conduct business in Estonia like I'm a US citizen, but I want to open up an Estonian business or Open up a web store that sells things to Estonia or any sort of Estonian business deal.
Scott: Maybe I got a sign.
Rym: while you know, look at the US.
Rym: you either Scribble some ink on a dead tree.
Rym: Yeah, or You try to use PGP signatures that no one can figure out.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Or you have to use a hundred percent Adobe workflow And even then it's not like.
Rym: it's not the same level of cryptographic trust.
Scott: No, not really.
Scott: It's also trust Adobe and government, right?
Scott: Yeah but yeah If you want to do business in Estonia You can get one of these things and it's really freaking useful and cool and modern and I don't know why every country doesn't have The US.
Scott: every country is not Estonia.
Rym: This should have appeared in the US like they're in the 90s But they banned exporting this encryption in the 90s.
Rym: That's why it was a weapon.
Scott: Sure.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, you know the Zimmerman stuff, right?
Rym: I mean I've said this for easily 20 years now the US when you're born instead of getting a piece of paper With a stamp printed you shouldn't need a bird.
Scott: You shouldn't need a birth certificate a driver's license a social security card.
Scott: You shouldn't need all these fucking cars.
Rym: I'm specific one.
Scott: Yeah one government card one key on there that should do every single thing there is to do.
Rym: every citizen when they're born should be given a private key and By the.
Rym: basically it's a thing that you can use to cryptographically not for like Hiding things not for like encrypting things but cryptographic signing so you can prove who you are And you can prove if you did something or not in an official capacity.
Scott: It just needs two factors, you know.
Scott: one the card itself with the keys, but these are encrypted.
Scott: So the second factor is the password to decrypt the key to do the signing.
Rym: this technology Since the 80s and the fact that other than in Estonia It is not in common use for the things that it is better every human being on earth.
Rym: Yeah, it's like it.
Rym: this solves.
Scott: Guess what?
Scott: There's plenty more keys than there will ever be human beings to ever exist.
Rym: this technology solves a Ridiculous number of the real-world problems that people in the industrialized world have been facing for a hundred years and Estonia is deploying it.
Scott: So good job, Estonia.
Scott: Yeah, you are inching up on the list of countries to run away to.
Scott: Should we need a country to run away to and the other ones don't cut it?
Rym: Yeah, the thing is right now.
Rym: top of that list is still Australia.
Rym: at this point in New Zealand They speak English there.
Scott: That's a bonus.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: It's super nice and warm Tropical coral reef, that's a bonus.
Rym: Not more racist than the US.
Scott: They have a pax.
Scott: That's a bonus.
Rym: They do have a pax.
Rym: think about it.
Rym: We can flee and still be going to pax every year and suddenly going to Japan.
Rym: not that big a deal.
Scott: You want to just go to Japan and let's have a weekend trip to the hot springs Same as a weekend trip to Florida.
Rym: Yeah, so yeah, Australia's real high on my run away list, but Estonia surprisingly not.
Rym: I mean, it's cold there relative to other places.
Rym: Sure, I mean It's latitude wise.
Rym: it's like at the top of Scotland.
Rym: So Yeah Why do all the nice places have to be in the shitty places?
Scott: Because the warm places while awesome and warm are full of like disease because also nasty poison.
Rym: things live where it's warm Yeah, but also bad governments often Yes, which is not necessarily the fault of the places or the climate.
Rym: but pretty much, you know What who you can blame for this.
Scott: banana British that them too.
Rym: Yeah, the British and bananas the bees.
Scott: Yeah, blame the bees What kind of news you got?
Rym: All right, so you die.
Rym: or how day if you're our company American You know, we ever.
Rym: I don't want to get into like the all the side Societal stuff of self-driving cars, but I cannot stress this enough.
Rym: This shit is moving way faster than you guys realize.
Scott: Yeah It's like a lot of times.
Scott: there's new fancy Technologies and some of them actually happen and some of them don't.
Rym: like Amazon drones like.
Rym: yeah, they're moving fast, but they're not ready yet.
Scott: Yeah, you're not gonna see.
Scott: it's like, you know, we saw we've seen flexible screens Right the kind you can roll around your finger for a long time.
Rym: I saw a laser projected keyboard That's virtual that you type on a desk with like ten years ago more like 20 years ago.
Scott: Yeah, I've seen the flexible screen since at least 10 15 20 years ago, but self-driving Yeah, but the self-driving car which we only saw a few years ago.
Rym: They're already ready for primetime.
Rym: This is gonna happen like not even gonna happen.
Rym: It did happen.
Scott: the existing technology Invest in self-driving car.
Scott: if there's a company where I could afford the shares that wasn't Google might be Hyundai.
Scott: Well, they're not exactly a small company.
Rym: That's so.
Rym: I don't know how much you know, I bet there's an ADR.
Rym: I'll look at Korean.
Rym: That's yeah, you'd have to invest through an ADR.
Rym: That's how I bought all that Toyota stock.
Scott: Yeah, it's pain in the ass.
Rym: No, it's not.
Rym: Scott trade just has ADRs.
Rym: Anyway, they're not special.
Rym: They act the same as the regular stock.
Rym: You don't need to do anything.
Scott: continue.
Rym: so The technology as it literally exists today right now is Safer than humans at highway speeds and in sit like it's already better.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: If we never advance this technology further We would still be obligated from a moral standpoint to deploy it today because fewer people would die.
Scott: Yes more at morally speaking.
Scott: You should not be allowed to drive a car.
Scott: A human being has no reason to ever drive a car in public.
Scott: Only unlike racetracks and other special events should be person be allowed to drive.
Scott: So otherwise you are simply risking death or risking murder.
Rym: So laws and all these things are just like not catching up.
Rym: I mean look states are banning the sale of Tesla's.
Rym: they're not self-driving.
Rym: They're just electric.
Rym: Yeah, so Hyundai this year 2015 is selling a car that you can just buy that has Autopilot that you can just use.
Scott: but the whole point is that if a car is autopilot, I don't have to buy it.
Scott: The whole point is that there would just be cars around and I go outside and one does up to me and I get in.
Rym: Yeah, you say that's the difference.
Rym: that requires a broader infrastructure and all these other changes.
Scott: What changes does it need?
Rym: that technology isn't a hundred percent there yet?
Rym: Oh the technology of the car knows to come together pick up drop-off load balancing like there's stuff.
Rym: like there's a lot of infrastructure and Research still has to happen there.
Rym: forget the laws ignore laws Just technology.
Rym: the the car picks me up drops me off to school and like I don't have to do anything is not there yet.
Rym: But what Hyundai is selling is you can be in this car this real car that will cost like 60k Like it's not that expensive for what it does.
Scott: That's more expensive than a BMW.
Scott: Yeah, I mean there are BMWs more than that But they're also some less than here are the two features it'll have.
Rym: if you're on a highway or freeway you turn on autopilot and You just let go the steering wheel and take your feet off the pedals and do whatever And it'll just drive All right, it'll follow the road a hundred percent it'll break it'll do speed It'll do everything.
Scott: I would you know, I would get in it.
Scott: I would let the you know, I'd have to see it first, right?
Scott: Yeah, I'd let the guy test right.
Rym: You're not allowed to.
Rym: here's the thing.
Rym: because of laws like you wouldn't be allowed to just like let crawl into the back and go To sleep.
Scott: No, no, no, but I want it.
Scott: Like if I was gonna if they had these for sale in the US I would go there.
Scott: I'd let the dealer take it out.
Scott: Yeah You turn on the autopilot and he lets it go.
Scott: and if I see that when I'm sitting the passenger seat if I see that I'm not dead.
Scott: Yep, then I'll do it.
Rym: I would tell him to go with my phone live-streaming back to me.
Scott: Oh sure.
Rym: Good idea But the other thing it'll do is it has a traffic jam mode.
Rym: If you're in a traffic jam of any kind and a need to tell it or just do it You just be like traffic jam.
Rym: Then what it'll do?
Rym: same thing let go and instead of highway stuff What it'll do is it'll just basically follow the car in front of it and deal with shit.
Scott: But you got to keep your eye open for when the traffic jams about to end I'm pretty sure it'll be like traffic jam ending traffic jam ending or something.
Rym: So this is a real car that you'll be able to buy this year in only Korea cuz the crew.
Scott: no u.s All right.
Scott: So yeah, you wanna buy one and split it.
Rym: I kind of You can pay for the parking spot I mean, but here's the problem.
Scott: I'll pay for the insurance for the price of this car.
Rym: We could each buy a brand new Lotus Elis a and oh, yeah That's a shame but BMW is releasing something similar likely either this year or next year.
Rym: Google seems to be the one powering both of these cars, but that's that's just rumors.
Rym: I have money.
Scott: I should buy a Lotus Elis.
Scott: yeah, so I What am I gonna do in the winter?
Rym: I can't die or not drive not drive.
Rym: I cannot wait for this shit Like you do not understand.
Rym: because imagine this world Even if it only does it on freeways like even if the technology was only that of only Freeway mode like it'll drive you to your exit and then get you off at the exit and you have to drive to and from the freeway.
Rym: that turns every freeway in America into a Always running.
Rym: the train comes exactly when you want it to bullet train.
Rym: Mm-hmm All you have to do is drive to the train station.
Scott: Well, it's not a bullet train.
Scott: a bullet train goes 500 miles an hour.
Scott: Yeah, but this goes five times slower.
Rym: Yeah, so it'll be like a cell six times.
Rym: It'll be like in a cella that literally Every exit every entrance and exit ramp in the entire country is in a cella station and the Express trains go from the station.
Rym: You got on to the station you got off Except there's all this traffic.
Scott: Yeah, but an accident.
Rym: Yeah, well, but the car is probably better with those accidents than I am.
Scott: you might crash into you.
Rym: Yeah, the car.
Rym: but the thing is they were gonna crash into you.
Rym: Anyway, sure plus I mean trains kill people Sure, not as many as cars.
Scott: Yeah cars still way more people than skiing kill me kill more people than anything.
Rym: Yeah Actually, there's a scary side note.
Rym: You know what kills more people in New York City than homicide right now?
Rym: Oh Drugs snow specifically just heroin overdoses.
Scott: Well, that's the drug that's gonna kill you mostly.
Rym: Yeah that that mean meth will kill you but in that long span of like you're dead Because of life choices.
Rym: Well, it's cuz.
Scott: the heroin is too strong, you know Given the same heroin they used to now they're given the heroin It's like.
Rym: what is that?
Rym: Is that your political party?
Rym: The rent is too damn high.
Rym: The heroin is too damn strong, right?
Scott: They just dilute that shit then it wouldn't kill people so instantly.
Rym: So one more little news because this is a rumor that like just came out LG apparently accidentally published a blog post early and then deleted it and It appears that Apple has an 8k resolution iMac for this year.
Scott: This seems a bit ridiculous.
Rym: like that is 7680 by 4320.
Scott: it's hard to believe that this is real.
Rym: if that monitor is not like 60 inches if it's not for monitors stuck together, I mean I'm kind of like the.
Rym: this seems to be legit.
Rym: No people are talking about this like this.
Rym: like this leak is legit.
Scott: so April Fool's late.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Let's keep an eye on it.
Rym: It's amazing.
Rym: I think you may you pointed out We were talking about this before the show how even if this isn't true only Apple is doing this.
Scott: Yeah, all the other companies usually I make fun of Apple because a thing that they do is they'll copy other people's technology Make it better obviously and then come out with it act like it's new like they invented it like iPhone.
Scott: It's like dude, we had palm trios like seven years ago.
Scott: Where have you been?
Scott: Oh, but this one doesn't suck.
Scott: Tablets view Sonic and Microsoft are making tablets like five six years.
Scott: Where have you been?
Scott: Oh yours doesn't suck, right?
Scott: Oh, we had virtual desktops on Linux and Unix and like the 80s.
Scott: What are you doing?
Scott: Yeah, actually spaces are actually like really much.
Rym: panels came out and suddenly like everyone's got this like 1080p monitor and I'm like what the fuck I had 1600 by whatever on my CRT.
Scott: Yeah Everyone has touch pads on their laptops.
Scott: Oh this Apple one doesn't suck.
Scott: Yeah So, you know people had 4k displays, but it's like Apple pretty much has run away with it.
Scott: They're dominating it.
Scott: they came out with the retina before everyone else and They're better than everyone else.
Scott: Yeah, they are and if this is true, they're not even like letting like Windows still can't really do 4k Yeah, and they're all apples like.
Scott: oh, well while we're ahead of you, let's run to 8k.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Scott: You suck.
Scott: Yeah, the thing is the hardware can do it.
Scott: the video cards have DisplayPort.
Scott: they can push it.
Rym: I mean, you know what it's like.
Rym: It's like an advanced wars or like a max are mad weak compared to Windows.
Scott: most Windows PCs that are any good.
Scott: Why doesn't someone make these fucking monitors standalone?
Scott: Dell your 4k monitors are garbage.
Rym: Yeah Well, there's a lot of things that have to change like sample.
Scott: Yeah Windows software Why don't you update?
Rym: Apple can get away with a lot because the monitor is basically baked in with the computer.
Rym: Yes I mean DVI can't push that DVI can't even push 4k.
Rym: the new DVI can the new DVI But you need.
Rym: you need the full like double cable, too.
Scott: No, you don't need the double cable with your DVI if you use the main DisplayPort this yeah DisplayPort DisplayPort.
Rym: Yeah, I was talking like DVI DVI.
Scott: No, no, but DisplayPort.
Scott: if you've old DisplayPort 1.0 I guess I think is the old version the one you're using now, you know I lost track you would need.
Scott: you would need two cables or 4k But if you had the new version DisplayPort 2.0 or whatever version number it frickin is.
Scott: Then you could use one DisplayPort cable for a 4k monitor.
Rym: You know why I lost track of all that.
Rym: 1920 by 1200 is basically the best you're gonna do in Windows.
Scott: pretty much.
Scott: I mean you could get a 2560 monitor, but it's gonna be either a really big monitor or not.
Scott: So it's.
Scott: it's not about the.
Scott: it's like Windows can do the high resolutions.
Scott: It's just it only does them for a big monitor if you have a small monitor with a high resolution.
Scott: with the increased pixel density Some things scale some things don't.
Scott: you can't see anything because everything is so goddamn small.
Scott: Yep That's why like you'll get 2560.
Scott: I'm like a 27 inch is fine, but Apple's doing like that on 19 inch level Everything's you get like.
Scott: can I even read this text zoom zoom zoom.
Rym: so 8k approaches the resolution of that thing in wool.
Rym: Yeah, yeah Kinda.
Rym: so We'll see what the deal is with this.
Rym: But if it really is this year, I think that the moral of this year and last year has been wait for September 2015.
Rym: Yeah, everything is happening in September 2015.
Scott: Apple 6 iPhone 6s.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Oh my god, if there is a smaller iPhone I like you cannot understand how fast my Nexus 4 will just fall out of my pocket as I'm running toward an Apple store.
Scott: I think the rumor is they're gonna make one that's the same as the iPhone 5 size.
Rym: I could deal with that at this point because remember the phone I was thinking about getting was the Sony Xperia z3 Compact.
Rym: the compact is about the same size as my Nexus 4.
Rym: Mmm knock it like I've rivaled.
Rym: I've given up.
Rym: This is the smallest you're gonna get for a long time.
Scott: I'm gonna get the iPhone 7 mini in 2016.
Rym: Yeah, cuz that's gonna happen.
Scott: iPhone nano.
Rym: what I'm gonna get in September is whatever iPad air they announced.
Scott: probably The big iPad is too big.
Rym: Yeah, well, I don't know.
Scott: I'm just gonna get a bigger iPad mini because the one I have run out of space even though it's perfectly fine.
Rym: But he already though.
Rym: Here's the problem.
Rym: I Use my laptop primarily to do the kinds of things that are hard to do on a tablet But when I'm on an airplane I use my laptop primarily to do the things that I should be doing on a tablet once Almost never use the laptop Almost never.
Rym: Yeah, I do.
Rym: You know, I do a lot of typing words when I'm away.
Rym: Yeah I don't type that many words at once But then you and Emily does she just carries around like a little Bluetooth keyboard.
Scott: You can also do that.
Rym: Yeah, so it's pretty much September.
Rym: I'm either getting a surface pro or an iPad.
Scott: the regular surface 3 the non Pro surface 3 is coming.
Rym: Yeah, I can wait.
Scott: No, I mean no one wants it, but the surface Pro is just better.
Scott: Yeah, but if you want to save a lot of money, they got rid of that Windows RT bullshit I think.
Scott: I think it's real windows now.
Scott: So like you don't need the power of the surface Pro.
Scott: I guess we're gonna have to wait for reviews to come out.
Scott: But the real the regular non Pro surface 3 might not be garbage might might I mean honestly or might be garbage Surface pros and services in general.
Rym: They're the only Portable non just a tablet like a not real computer.
Rym: I've seen in a long time that has the basically universal praise that used to be reserved for like Lenovo ThinkPad type things.
Rym: anyway things of the day.
Rym: This person has a bunny like we have bunnies like Neil deGrasse.
Rym: Tyson has bunnies and he made the Game of Thrones throne out of carrots.
Rym: Okay for the bunny and the bunny ate it and the bunny is just like oh my gosh.
Rym: and just sits there eating it.
Rym: It's really fun.
Scott: It's a lot of carrot.
Scott: Isn't the bunny gonna get full and sick?
Rym: Well, it looks like he made it out of a lot of carrot shavings down here Mmm, I also attach it to cardboard which the bunny likes to eat.
Rym: Yeah, but they don't eat it.
Rym: They bite it Mmm, so I just thought this is cute.
Rym: Also.
Rym: I had a better thing in the day.
Rym: There was this amazing world star fight, but it disappeared from YouTube, but I didn't have time to find it again.
Scott: I'm sure it's on world star.
Rym: I will find it and it'll be my thing of the day in the future because there's some special.
Scott: pretty sure you just go to World star and click random that.
Rym: yeah, but this fight what the way I would describe it was a combinatorial explosion of fighting.
Rym: It was like this one guy starts fighting with this other guy and there's people watching and then someone starts going like world star World star and this other guy's like man shut up and it starts fighting with the guy who's yelling world star.
Scott: Okay, never shouting world star.
Scott: Yeah And it escalates from there as if yesterday I had seen a fight.
Rym: I may have yelled But the funny the guy yelling world star was videoing it and then he got attacked.
Rym: and the videos from someone else who was videoing It.
Rym: and by the end of the video the video ends with that guy getting attacked.
Rym: But I couldn't show that to you because it disappeared.
Rym: so behold the iron throne out of carrots for me.
Rym: I love how the video is called.
Rym: built the iron throne out of carrots for my rabbit.
Rym: I like titles of things like that.
Scott: Well Rym.
Scott: Yeah, you're gonna call when there's something strange in your bed my bed in your bed He drinks the piss an invisible man In your bed, I can't believe.
Rym: Scott showed this to me.
Rym: creepy ghost bed the whole time.
Rym: I'm watching it.
Rym: I'm like man.
Rym: Yeah, tub thumping like Neil Cicierega's thing.
Rym: This is just like that Neil Cicierega thing.
Rym: Oh my god I had no idea.
Rym: was actually just yeah, Neil Cicierega made this.
Scott: I thought like he Rym was saying like this is just like this Neil Cicierega's other thing.
Scott: I thought you had seen what YouTube channel it was and thus knew that he made it
Rym: But I did not cuz I clicked on the link and just maximized immediately and started playing and I wasn't sure what this was gonna be Until I learned about the man live sleeping in my bed.
Scott: Well, this is busting goes bed busting.
Rym: this Has already replaced the original Ghostbusters theme in my head.
Rym: I Can't it is.
Rym: This is in fact the original Ghostbusters theme.
Rym: now sure In the meta moment the book club book is still water ship down.
Rym: It is a story about rabbits and while it has much allegory that can be right into it The author himself has said that is just a story about rabbits trying to find a new home.
Rym: as We talked about an anime Boston in our panel.
Rym: Mm-hmm Our next convention is Connecticut, which is in July.
Rym: so we had a long.
Scott: as much as that seems like it's a long way away.
Scott: It's like 13 weeks away.
Scott: Yeah This weekend in New York City is the mocha festival mocha fest.
Rym: We'll be there one of the days with a bunch of friends doing our things in a new location.
Scott: Don't go to the armory.
Scott: You will be lonely there.
Scott: Yeah, you maybe get shot there because it's an armory.
Scott: I don't know if that'll happen.
Scott: But yeah, don't go to the wrong place.
Scott: It's in a new place.
Scott: check their website to figure out where that place is.
Scott: I think it's in Chelsea or some shit If you wanted to present at Connecticut.
Rym: the submission deadline ended like a week ago guys.
Rym: So the form is still open and you can still submit.
Rym: However, I am just scheduling stuff on a daily basis.
Scott: right now you get negative points for being late.
Rym: Yeah, so submit your shit guys Connecticut is a rockin con.
Rym: if you've just joined us from anime Boston and somehow you Listened all the way to this point Every night of GeekNights is different.
Rym: So this is the Monday night.
Rym: So it's technology and neck beards and Linux and stuff.
Rym: So you probably want the Wednesday GeekNights, which is actually anime and manga and comics and all that stuff.
Scott: Or maybe you're an awesome person who appreciates more than one thing in life.
Scott: Yeah, you should listen to all four nights.
Rym: But if you go to our website for recruit comm I did post the list of all The anime we showed and talked about in that short form anime panel.
Scott: We have a presence on the internet in every place that is on the internet.
Scott: So you should go to your favorite, you know Facebook's Twitter's our website any place that there is things and Connect with us in a connecting way.
Rym: Yes And also if you did not yet, press the button.
Rym: do not fucking press the button.
Rym: wait for it guys Jesus maybe it happened already.
Rym: No, it did not.
Rym: No, it didn't know Scott.
Rym: I'm invested in this button.
Rym: The button's fine.
Scott: I stopped paying attention.
Rym: Yeah, I wonder why you stopped paying attention Filthy 60.
Rym: I can't believe you pushed the button.
Scott: I didn't know what was going on.
Scott: I just saw.
Scott: I just went to the website.
Rym: you had one shot.
Scott: I saw that there was a button so I pressed it.
Scott: I looked up what the button did.
Scott: afterwards cuz I'm like, wow, I press that button.
Scott: Nothing happened.
Scott: What the fuck?
Rym: I hope against hope that when that's countdown timer hits zero All that happens is that entire subreddit is deleted forever immediately.
Rym: And that's it.
Rym: Nothing else.
Rym: No word is ever said again.
Rym: Okay, that would be the best possible ending But my goal is to be one of the last human beings to press that button.
Rym: Okay?
Rym: So yeah FPGAs which I guess we've never talked about on GeekNights.
Scott: So FPGA is like a weird thing that only ridiculously Technological people even know exist or care about.
Rym: so Scott I learned about like at RIT We had a class on the history of computing.
Rym: We talked about this shit a lot.
Scott: I just I fully like.
Scott: I knew sort of what they were But I didn't fully learn about them until I was on a co-op that There was what they had them and I learned really super more what they were.
Rym: so I knew about them because I worked at IBM When they were.
Rym: when like I was I literally worked in the factory Like support like all the machines like the computers on the factory floor that like did shit.
Rym: that was my job.
Rym: It was the factor that made the cell processor Which is in this class of this type of computing.
Scott: It's not an FPGA No, it's not.
Rym: but a lot of the things I wanted like kudos aren't really FPGAs either.
Rym: They're not even close Yeah, but they serve the same purpose Really for my industry and for most people that I mean.
Scott: So we see your problem is you're thinking about an FPGA from the perspective of I have a job I want to get done.
Scott: Yeah, and these are different things that do the job But that's not you know.
Scott: And some of them might be FPGAs and some of them might be not but that's not what makes an FPGA special.
Scott: the thing that makes an FPGA special is the fact that what it is and how it works is crazy regardless of whether if It's actually useful or not.
Rym: and it's something that you'll think this is crazy.
Rym: It's existed for a long time.
Scott: It's existed for a long time.
Scott: So let me explain to you now.
Scott: Alright, so FPGA stands for field programmable gate array, which is complete gibberish, but it sounds kind of awesome.
Rym: It is a gate array that you can program in the field, right?
Scott: So think about this.
Scott: I buy a microchip.
Scott: this microchip is way simple.
Scott: It's like four and gates lined up.
Rym: It's I had a bunch of those as a kid, right?
Scott: It's like on the left side there's eight pins and on the right side is four pins.
Scott: It's just four and gates all together.
Scott: All right, it's four and gates all together.
Scott: I can't change it It's.
Scott: it is what it is.
Scott: And if I want to make a circuit board I need to get more chips and connect them together on the circuit board and do all kinds of stuff Right with wires in between these chips.
Scott: if I want say a processor like a CPU I buy a CPU.
Scott: maybe I buy an 8086 CPU or I buy I don't know a core 2 duo.
Rym: So that thing has a fucking million million million million of these gates on it Sure, but it's still.
Scott: it is what it is, right?
Scott: I see an Intel CPU takes in Intel assembly instructions executes them and outputs what it's supposed to output.
Scott: That's what it does.
Scott: It does one thing and you can program it.
Scott: it can execute programs that are arbitrary in general But it can only do that one thing it is a one job chip.
Rym: now at the same time that job is generic because a stand like an x86 chip is Designed to be a generic processor.
Rym: you can write code in C or C++ or Python or whatever and Just it'll compile and work on that chip.
Rym: If you throw a thread at a core on that chip, it'll execute.
Rym: Yep, don't have to worry like what kind of chip it is.
Scott: So an FPGA is crazy.
Scott: It's a chip right with a ton of freaking gates.
Scott: Well, they're not really gates.
Scott: They're basically logic blocks Right and each logic block can be configured right to be sort of any kind of gate or even fancier than a gate in many cases.
Scott: And all of these blocks are all connected to each other by a whole bunch of.
Scott: we'll call them highways Simply because that's a good metaphor for it.
Scott: So it's like imagine if Every house on the street could perform one logical operation and you could change.
Scott: any house could do any one logical operation and you could connect the houses in any fucking way you wanted and every and you could keep rearranging them willy-nilly all day long and You could basically make any chip out of this chip.
Scott: So the idea is a shape-shifting chip.
Scott: It can take any form.
Rym: Yeah, so think about this.
Rym: if you want if you have an NES it's got its hardware.
Scott: It has.
Scott: yeah, there's some chip.
Scott: That's the NES CPU and all it can be is an NES.
Scott: if you have an FPGA You could actually if you had an FPGA big enough you could program the FPGA to become The same chip that is in the NES.
Scott: as long as it digital it can't do any analog business.
Rym: So think about that.
Rym: if you normally if you want to run like an NES on your computer You emulate it in software on top of a general-purpose CPU and that works very well.
Scott: There's not.
Rym: if there's a lot of overhead like.
Rym: there's a reason why modern consoles are not emulatable easily.
Scott: Yes, that is true.
Rym: I mean a lot of older consoles aren't even emulatable very easily.
Scott: you could write.
Scott: So basically an FPGA works is that when it is no power, it's blank.
Scott: It's super blank and if the power ever goes out it erases.
Scott: so fuck you don't let the power go out And when it turns on it actually takes a while to boot.
Scott: It's not a quick booting thing.
Scott: like you if you made a device based on FPGAs Every time you turned it on unless you had some infinite battery life keeping that FPGA going you would have to wait a little bit for it to get started.
Scott: and What happens is this one part of the day FPGA that looks for some flash memory external flash memory.
Scott: Some of them now have internal flash memory, but usually external flash memory.
Scott: You wouldn't use something slower than flash memory.
Scott: that'd be a bad idea.
Scott: and It looks in that flash memory for a program written in Basically like some sort of HDL or VHDL language Which is not like any programming language you're used to because it's not a series of instructions saying do this then do this then do This.
Scott: it's a series of instructions saying you're a chip become this shape and then once the FPGA is done loading it becomes the shape that was described by the Program in the hardware definition language in the flash memory and as long as it is powered on it retains that shape.
Rym: So in practical terms because I you know I'm not a developer so I come at this from this very like the other standard of like like this the view of What would you use this for?
Rym: there are really only two uses for FPGAs.
Scott: There are quite a few.
Rym: Well, the core I'm talking like at the highest highest level Rapid prototyping.
Rym: Yes of something that eventually you expect to print a real chip, right?
Scott: So like let's say you're developing.
Scott: I don't know battery controller like a special Some sort of small microprocessor, but it's specialized.
Scott: You don't want to use a generic general-purpose Microprocessor even though that's probably a really good idea.
Rym: Yeah well you want to make a special chip just For your hardware product like imagine a heart like you need a hard real-time system for something.
Scott: They're very specialized sure, but you're still working on it.
Scott: So you just have an FPGA and you keep reprogramming it all the time until it's just right And then once you have the FPGA programmed properly you say alright, let's make a chip exactly identical to this.
Scott: You know the way I shaped this FPGA.
Scott: and then you make a real chip.
Scott: You can even do crazy stuff these days like design chips like in your chip layout program like draw Transistors and and gates and everything all lined up and then actually have that converted into the HDL to send to an FPGA which is crazy.
Rym: the other application is if you have a use of Computers that requires such low latency and such hard determinism or real-timeness as in like real-time OS that the very specific and technical term and if you're in one of those cases like The best example I could come up with is financials because that's where a lot pretty much all this stuff gets used in the real world is say you want to have a computer that's looking at the market looking at market data and Sending orders to react to that market data.
Rym: if you have an algorithm that requires an extreme extreme low latency you would want a chip that Physically takes the market data and turns it into orders.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: You could do that.
Rym: Yep, and that is the kind of thing that people use these for ultra ultra high-performance highly specialized things or rapid prototyping or just QA testing of a special purpose device Nothing FPHC even if you need ridiculous low latency.
Scott: Right, you could just get like a modern CPU like the craziest one.
Scott: You could buy some Xeon nonsense.
Scott: You say that and write a program in assembly and get it to do the thing.
Rym: now We found that there's this.
Rym: there's this barrier on be under around 10 microseconds where soft real-time systems like software running on an x86 chip you just cannot Have.
Scott: you can also do non x86 but with the Anything.
Scott: but the FPGA is especially good at that.
Scott: The regular CPU is not especially good at is being parallel.
Scott: You see if you buy some even the best Intel chip was like an 8 core or 4 cores faking 8 cores or whatever Like some 30 like upper cores, right?
Scott: Sure If you get an FPGA if it has enough gates in it if that is enough logic blocks in it usually FPGAs the especially the big ones have way more input output pins than any CPU is gonna have and have way more freaking gates total because you're gonna need Them.
Scott: but if you're doing something that doesn't take up the whole FPGA you can sort of take that hardware definition language and just copy paste like five or six times in a row or maybe a hundred times or maybe a thousand times and that one FPGA will actually be 1,000 or a hundred or a whole bunch of the chip that you need stacked up.
Scott: so and now each one of those is Independent of the other ones.
Scott: I have the whole working in perfect parallel.
Rym: I have this image that I'm looking at this from a presentation on FPGAs and Intel stuff and everything and basically like a dedicated Pro like a regular Xeon as you throw threads at it you get more and more performance.
Rym: But until Scott said there's only so many cores you can put in one of those things And once you hit that peak of threads, there is literally like you can't do more, right?
Scott: even if you're doing some simple job like adding one and one you want to basically add one and one as many times as You can.
Scott: well even the best CPU you can buy a new egg can only Simultaneously add one and one so many times at once.
Scott: at some point It's going to have to wait for one of the one plus ones to finish adding up to two Before it starts doing another one.
Scott: with an FPGA an adder doesn't take up many logic blocks.
Scott: It probably takes up one of them, right?
Scott: It's a really simple operation.
Scott: So if you have an FPGA with like a Thousand friggin logic blocks in it.
Scott: Each one of them can add one and one simultaneously and As long as you have enough output pins, you can output twos on all of them simultaneously.
Scott: so this is a hundred percent Simultaneously not like there would be no waiting whatsoever for the next two ones to come in For the next twos to go out.
Rym: So this is where this is why I brought up the cell processor.
Rym: because the actual real-world use for this that massive like that massively parallel Processing.
Rym: the problem with using FPGAs to do that is that you can't just write like your code like oh Yeah I'll use like 800 threads or a thousand threads or whatever and just compile it and have it work on an FPGA.
Rym: there is a layer between That code that logic and the FPGA and that layer is a developer who will charge you millions of dollars.
Scott: Yes, here's the problems with FPGAs.
Scott: I mean, it seems like a miracle right?
Scott: Why wouldn't every chip just be an FPGA?
Scott: I mean throw out my core to whatever it is.
Scott: Or i7 put an FPGA in my computer and then I can just upgrade it.
Scott: if they come out with a better CPU design I'll just download it upgrade my FPGA.
Scott: It doesn't matter that it erases when the computer turns on.
Scott: I can just up I can flash that bit of flash memory with a new CPU design and I'll never have to upgrade my FPGA or anything.
Rym: that's great until one anything ever changes yeah, and then you have to rewrite all your code probably yeah or two if You make any mistakes writing your code.
Scott: Yeah, so at all FPGA problem number one.
Scott: It is ridiculously difficult to program you to be a genius.
Scott: I can't do it.
Rym: I know a few people who will do write code for it like like not like we do.
Scott: I can do the tutorial Simple like yeah make the FPGA do math, but I can't like.
Rym: see I look one.
Rym: I'm like you're looking at the level of like FPGA like at its core, right?
Scott: But that's like the level you have to discuss it as because and the real world modern FPGAs are insane And they're all completely different.
Scott: They have memory now.
Scott: They have like analog things in them.
Scott: now They got all sorts of crazy shit in them.
Rym: You'll get like a PCI X card that just has these things on it and you'll get this SDK and these Documentation that will basically tell you to code in a way that you have never coded before genius to read it and understand it.
Rym: It's a lot like in Java like people were like zero GC Java code Because that makes Java like as deterministic as non Java like garbage collection doesn't occur Yeah, but to write code like that is obtuse to say the least.
Rym: And if you fuck anything up all those games are out the window.
Rym: Yeah, it's that it's like that times a million with all the FPGA platforms and vendors sell like FPGA cards.
Rym: They're all different.
Rym: You have to be an expert in that implementation.
Scott: if you get just the like the documents like Explaining all the features of just one of these things like the data file or whatever That could be your whole job in life.
Rym: Yes If you become an expert in one FPGA platform You could get a job at like a hedge fund and it doesn't help not only Right.
Scott: Are there like multiple different eight PGA's that are all really really different.
Scott: There's two minutes more than one vendor.
Scott: There's two major vendors and they both use different words to refer to everything.
Scott: There's no standard terminology.
Scott: So like if you learn like one vendors FPGAs You're gonna be really confused if you suddenly have to work on one from the other.
Rym: vendor Problem in practice at least in my industry and it's funny because the reason this came up is because I mentioned I'm on a panel in Mumbai on April 22nd called low latency trading what is working and what is not.
Rym: and there are four topics We're discussing and it's me and a bunch of like managing directs all these like people wouldn't be.
Scott: amount of money You had to pay someone to develop your FPGA stuff not be able to make up for the money.
Rym: I wonder what rims gonna say on this panel.
Scott: So and the time it takes to make it here the for time want to be obsolete by the time you're done developing.
Rym: Here are the four topics on this panel.
Rym: Let's see if you can pick out which ones.
Rym: rims got a lot to say about.
Scott: All right, all of them.
Rym: the use of fix and low latency trading environments.
Scott: That's what you do.
Rym: FPGA cards.
Rym: Yep, the adoption of the fixed protocol in Indian markets and Setting the clocks in India the need for the precision time protocol.
Rym: There you go.
Rym: Yeah I'm gonna shit all over PTP.
Scott: Anyway, anyway, so let me talk about all the other problems.
Rym: FPGAs Okay, then I'll talk about how this is actually done in the real world.
Scott: So for another problem They have they don't give a shit about power.
Scott: They will just drain your fucking battery.
Scott: Fuck you, right?
Scott: It takes a lot of power to keep that going because our low power FPGA.
Scott: Yeah, that's still not as low power as regular dedicated process.
Rym: Yeah, the problem is like even alternative solutions like using GPUs.
Scott: GPUs
Rym: are not low power No,
Scott: but I mean in addition to the power that it takes to actually You know do the processing and run the clocks or whatever you got going on with the FPGA You also have extra power going in to sort of keep it in the shape that you want it to be in.
Scott: as soon as The power is cut all those transistors just go clunk back to zero.
Rym: now That kind of problem is mostly been dealt with over the years.
Rym: the same way that hard drives.
Rym: you like hard drives unless you have a shit server have got some form of write caching meaning writes are coming in to the disk and The thing between your program in the disk tells the program.
Rym: Yeah, I got it.
Rym: Yeah, but it's not actually on the disk yet It's in a buffer somewhere and they either have capacitors or they're caching it to flash.
Rym: They're doing things to persist that data.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: That's a solved problem.
Scott: Also FPGAs Right while so let's consider this scenario right we take an FPGA and FPGAs are fast.
Scott: It's a mean it's.
Scott: it's a hardware device.
Scott: It's it's ridiculously fast hardware speed.
Scott: Yeah, but if I program an FPGA to do the same thing as a 486 unless it's some crazy big FPGA It's still probably gonna be slower at that then a 486 would be yep.
Rym: So you have to solve a very constrained problem with.
Scott: but if I put two 486 is in one FPGA.
Scott: now Daddy's cooking.
Rym: So think of this like an FPGA to do everything that my computer from 1996 does would be a nightmare.
Rym: You're right, but an FPGA that encodes h2 64 video That would be so much better than a general-purpose processor that you wouldn't believe it.
Rym: Yeah orders of magnitude faster.
Scott: Now we already talked about how expensive it is to get someone to write, you know to configure and program.
Rym: Fucking chips are.
Scott: The chips are also redic expensive.
Rym: now you have some at work, but they're not.
Rym: they're not real FPGAs.
Rym: They're basically this company called solar flare their network cards that have sort of an excellent use of FPGA.
Rym: Yes hardware progress.
Rym: So say I'm doing a packet capture, right?
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: I can have the filtering happen in the hardware.
Rym: Yep, that is crazy and awesome.
Rym: I could have reactive loops I could have the card to have code or if certain kinds of data come in Data comes back out without even hitting my buses.
Rym: Yep, like that's the kind of shit you can do, right?
Rym: but that's not just an FPGA.
Rym: that is a Specific.
Rym: it's like one layer above that.
Rym: it's using similar types of technology or solving similar problems.
Rym: But you're another layer.
Rym: abstracted like it solves network related massively parallel or high-performance problems.
Scott: But yeah, they're really expensive They're not.
Scott: I mean if you get the big fancy ones, they could be a lot of money But I mean even cheap ones right small ones She still more money that like life.
Scott: you take an FPGA and you program it to do something simple And then you want to put that in an actual product.
Scott: You're just pissing away money.
Scott: You were better off buying a chip that was already equivalent to whatever you made that FPGA do so here.
Rym: a recent solar flare.
Rym: So a solar flan flare on the 70 like a 7-series card, you know, it's just a network card.
Rym: I can buy one on Amazon for a thousand dollars.
Rym: Yeah Your card on your server cost zero because that comes with your mother built in in the motherboard.
Scott: Yeah, when the days when we bought them they were five bucks.
Rym: Yes, and that was this card has it's a Thousand-dollar network card.
Rym: So if you design software that needs this solar flare card.
Rym: Everyone who buys your software also has to buy a thousand-dollar network card.
Scott: Yeah, so it's not about networking right.
Scott: networking is a thing that's really easy to do in parallel, right?
Scott: You have a whole lot of Ethernet cables coming in to a switch or something and you got a whole bunch of packets.
Rym: It's a whole lot of packets that need to be muxed and demuxed to applications.
Rym: It's like the perfect storm.
Rym: Yeah, the FPGA or the specialized hardware can like split Incoming TCP packets inside of one fancy FPGA.
Scott: You can basically put like hundreds of little chips that in hardware each can process TCP IP packets all the way from the Ethernet all the way up to that level.
Scott: and so this chip is basically doing all that work in hardware at ridiculously high speed and It only passes on the packets to the computer that you need.
Scott: you could have like a hundred Ethernet Gigabit Ethernet cards plugged into your computer with this one FPGA just taking care of everything.
Rym: now I think just from my like professional perspective like the work I do and just my life as a technologist.
Rym: I Super useful for but high performance computing.
Rym: I think that is a dead end.
Scott: Yeah I mean in these days You're probably better off just getting a whole bunch of regular CPUs for the parallel or you want to.
Scott: you need to have a very very Specific or limited use case to need an FPGA.
Scott: certain industries certain kinds of devices certain people, you know They still need them.
Rym: It's not like we should stop making them But like even in my industry right like in software with Java we're down to like sub 20 microsecond processing times for these things.
Rym: right things we're talking about.
Rym: a Well programmed FPGA could probably do that similar task down to about At best like 8 to 10.
Rym: Mm-hmm If 10 microseconds matters.
Rym: that much like how much you're willing to pay to save 10 microseconds.
Scott: Yeah, and are you ready?
Scott: What?
Scott: what happens when it messes up?
Rym: If the if anything changes in the market and you have to do something differently, yeah You gotta hire that million-dollar developer again.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: There's not too many people out there who can do something that complicated, right?
Scott: It's like programming it to be an Ethernet card is already pretty complex.
Scott: Programming to do anything fancier is really hard.
Rym: So in my opinion the real way to do this kind of thing because the problem most people are solving is some massively parallel problem Like Video encoding.
Scott: it has to be something digital right if it's usually has high input output.
Scott: high input output That's what all the pins are for.
Scott: Yeah, or So it has to be purely digital.
Scott: You can't be doing any like analog processing on there.
Scott: What you can do though is you can get a whole bunch of ADCs Stack those up next to an FPGA and then the FPGA can do a bunch of work.
Rym: These are the worst things in the world.
Scott: No, they're not.
Scott: I'm not saying that.
Scott: I'm saying Welcome to heat and power sure but like let's say you have I don't know radio signals coming in from like 20 like a thousand antennas.
Rym: Yeah so you do a.
Scott: you have an ADC on each one and you can have like one FPGA processing all those radio signals in parallel and Then outputting it to a bunch of storage devices really quickly.
Scott: So I would practice but you could just do that with much more.
Scott: less work Would be to just stack up a whole bunch of regular old CPUs one per antenna.
Rym: It comes down to like.
Rym: do you need some sort of hardware advantage?
Rym: Do you need a hard real-time solution?
Rym: Do you have like you have some very specific constraint?
Rym: most of the time you don't or you do but the money you would take?
Rym: To actually meet that constraint Obviates the need.
Rym: so in practice Honestly use like use a framework that is easier to code in.
Rym: that is also massively parallel like Nvidia's CUDA stuff.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I mean if you you you Scott could write code that would take advantage of CUDA Yes, anyway, anyone who can code can do that.
Rym: Yes, and like right now like in fact I have done so and that stuff is already used.
Rym: CUDA cores like CUDA processing is used in a lot of practical Applications that are not like ridiculous finance like billion-dollar solutions and There's a new thing on the horizon that I didn't know a lot about But I've been learning a lot about it lately probably as I'm talking on that panel, but Intel Had.
Rym: this is what's gonna replace FPGA.
Rym: I think Intel has their Xeon Phi coprocessor.
Rym: The vague idea is that these new Xeon chips and the boards that support them will have normal Xeon cores and then they have these like vector cores that do this shit.
Rym: and The important part is not the hardware.
Rym: The hardware is amazing and all these kinds of things like When people who are experts of this try to explain to me like the cache concurrency problems they deal with and like what kinds of buffers are used and like how like Physically how the chips are laid out and how you should allocate memory in your applications to match that.
Rym: I'm not smart enough to understand that stuff.
Rym: But as a result, the hardware is not the interesting solution.
Rym: The interesting solution is the software support to allow normal developers to use this shit.
Rym: So Intel is a company I think that has the resources to provide the tools that many people who work at Intel are at the FPGA programming genius level.
Rym: Yes, but you can't use those solutions relying only on people like that.
Rym: You need a layer in between.
Rym: I mean how many people still write assembly like that happens?
Rym: many there are uses for that But most of the work in the world gets done at least a couple of layers above assembly.
Rym: Yeah, so Intel's PHY framework PHI Been learning a lot about it.
Rym: And basically it looks like that.
Rym: This is as best I can tell.
Rym: like these things will take.
Rym: threads like you can just write C code Like you don't need to worry a lot about what's going underneath.
Rym: You just have to worry about advertising.
Rym: Yeah, well, this is more than just advertising.
Rym: I have a pretty thick slide deck here of a. This is a class on how to write the code.
Scott: I should make a thick slide deck.
Rym: you want to see this.
Rym: shit like this goes way beyond the level I can really understand without this.
Rym: make a crazy slide deck and everyone will believe it maybe but this is like a crash course I'm looking at on how to write code for these things and This looks way more doable.
Rym: and the other problem the other reason I think this is interesting that is Intel.
Rym: Intel has the ability to make these things just exist on everyone's computers.
Rym: if If these coprocessors are just kind of standard on high-end servers You can write code that assumes they're there.
Rym: You can't do that with just FPGAs.
Scott: See an FPGA is a thing.
Scott: it's useful in the world in many places, but most for most people it's never useful and It's just mostly.
Scott: the thing about them is that like the fact that they exist is like some like miraculous Amazing thing.
Scott: it's like it's a chip that you can program to become any chip Which then itself can be programmed if you want it to be.
Rym: oh my god.
Rym: It just runs Linux.
Rym: Okay, I gotta read a lot more about this before I talk about it in depth on the show.
Scott: But yeah If you're more if that if the fact the concept that an FPGA is a chip that can become other chips Fascinates you.
Scott: just go on YouTube.
Scott: There's like a bunch of videos all about this.
Scott: that will be incomprehensible, but will make you go.
Scott: Whoa.
Scott: That's crazy.
Rym: Oh, but if you want to get a job unless you're doing integrated circuits for like hardware product applications Either look at this Intel stuff or get really good at Nvidia's CUDA stuff because that is actual practical useful money-making skill.
Scott: Well, I mean if you learn FPGAs, you can also make a lot of money if you're like VHDL or something.
Scott: But you're going.
Scott: the places you can work are only places that are actually using those they're gonna work at like a battery company.
Rym: You're gonna work at a hedge fund.
Scott: There there are places that you can work if you learn it and you're working the NSA like doing signal processing yeah, who knows what you're gonna do, but For most people in the real world, you will never need them and rarely will they be the correct optimal choice.
Rym: Yeah, anything look at these other things because there's.
Rym: there's a more general application to these other things like CUDA.
Scott: Yeah, if FPGAs were really the awesomest we would already.
Scott: it's like there's not some weird reason.
Scott: We don't all have them in our computer.
Rym: Yeah, well kind of like.
Rym: remember, you know, like RISC systems versus CISC systems or like token ring was deterministic.
Rym: Well, yeah and token ring is gone now, even though it was better in a lot of ways than Ethernet.
Rym: I wonder why that is.
Scott: beta max is gone now in a lot of ways.
Rym: in VHS This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat Lee for web design and Brand ok for the logos.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.