Rym: It's Wednesday December 2nd 2015.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight the manga Inuyashiki by Hiroyoku.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: Alright I'll talk about something stupid.
Scott: Alright.
Scott: so this morning I woke up and you know I check my internet like I usually do.
Rym: Good start.
Scott: Yeah including you know the regular parts of the internet the webcomic.
Rym: Yeah the Civ 5 turn.
Scott: The Civ 5 turn.
Scott: Actually I didn't have a Civ 5 turn this morning.
Scott: It wasn't my turn.
Rym: Yeah the way the timing is.
Scott: Or was it?
Scott: I don't remember.
Rym: I got the second half of the game right because there's a bunch of people like with the time zone.
Rym: so the people at the end of the day are very likely to take their turn early and keep the game going but in the morning it's a race condition between Yumi, Scojo, and Alex for who takes their turn.
Scott: So then I check the you know in the course of internet.
Scott: I check the kpop internet as usual and it was like freaking out.
Scott: and I was like why?
Scott: why is they freaking out?
Scott: and apparently just time zones and not paying too much attention to that.
Scott: Apparently the like Korean equivalent of Grammy Awards was this morning or last night or this morning.
Scott: it was this morning here on my way to work but it was this night for them.
Scott: I don't even I don't know the times.
Rym: Alright so that explains that.
Scott: So apparently it was streaming live on Twitch.
Scott: so while I'm putting my clothes on I'm like alright let's see what's going on there.
Scott: and it was way different.
Scott: like.
Scott: obviously award shows are dumb.
Scott: like even if it's a award show or something I care about like this video game awards are gonna happen like right now.
Scott: it's the end of the year.
Scott: there's a lot of award shows in general now even though what?
Scott: for some reason?
Scott: Grammys and Oscars and things like the beginning of the year and not the I don't know.
Scott: but anyway so I'm watching it and I. there's so many things different about it from what we usually have here.
Scott: so first of all in the US the Grammy Awards are like an industry thing.
Scott: you know it's like the music industry.
Scott: there is no music industry single group there in Asia right.
Scott: all the awards are from different companies like there's.
Scott: imagine if instead of say like I guess for television we have like Golden Globe or Emmy Awards.
Scott: imagine if instead of Emmy Awards it was the NBC TV Awards the ABC TV Awards the CBS TV Awards the Fox TV Awards.
Rym: I feel like we had things like that at different points like there but there does not exist.
Scott: imagine if there didn't exist in Emmys.
Scott: all of TV.
Scott: so right so it's really just.
Scott: it's even less of an award show.
Scott: it's just congratulations on our own thing right?
Scott: so this awards that happened this morning last night was the MAMA Awards which is the Mnet Asian Music Awards which is like Mnet is a TV network.
Scott: it's also a record company which is like CJ E&M.
Scott: so imagine like if MTV was also producing music and had an award show but gave awards to all of the music and it says is the Asian Music Awards but it's like 90% Korean.
Scott: but also the Pet Shop Boys showed up for some reason and doing an award or were they just?
Scott: I guess they always get like one big Western group to come to give some second.
Rym: I thought you're gonna be like they always get the Pet Shop Boys like achievement inspiration award or something.
Rym: it'd be funnier if it was always the Pet Shop Boys would be really weird yeah.
Scott: and so the weird things about it other than that is it number one.
Scott: I mean at least in the US the Grammys the Oscars which are rigged in terms of the awards are given out by a bunch of old white dudes.
Scott: yep it didn't seem like the awards are given based on merit at all.
Scott: they let people vote but fan voting is a small percentage of the awards.
Scott: they're really just give it out what seems to be by rigging like like some.
Scott: you know all the different kpop artists are in different companies and like the same company kept winning and this the company was also giving the most performances.
Scott: it's just like.
Scott: clearly just buy these awards from so it's even less meaningful to win the award right.
Scott: but what was interesting the good parts is that number one the performances were definitely not lip-synced in any way.
Rym: oh man that that that already means it's a better award show.
Scott: the reason they weren't lip-synced in any way is because you go to the Grammys.
Scott: who's in the audience of the Grammys?
Scott: people who don't want to be there but it's just all famous people in front to back this there's like a little area where the famous people and people receiving awards sit.
Rym: oh it's normal people.
Scott: it's just a fucking concert you can buy tickets to.
Rym: so it's basically a best-of concert.
Scott: it's just the best of concert but also like insane shit happens.
Scott: maybe we should go to it someday you want to go to Asia to this thing with 90% of the audience is screaming teenage girls.
Rym: ah you know what it would be worth spectacle.
Scott: it was in Hong Kong actually this year.
Scott: I think last year it was in a different country.
Rym: oh I have excuses to go there.
Rym: I could I could make that happen.
Scott: Chow Yun fat gave the final award unrelated to music.
Scott: they just get the most famous person they can get to come like tonight the orderly presented by Mike Tyson and carrot top.
Scott: but you know usually they're always promoting on TV like performances by so-and-so so-and-so so right.
Scott: there are performances by people who are unannounced to shock the hell out of everybody right.
Scott: so imagine if you go and you're like oh man I'm really exceeded excited to see.
Scott: you know I don't know one person because they're on the list couldn't name one band.
Scott: I'm really excited to see Rammstein all right and suddenly machine supremacy just on the stage.
Scott: you didn't even fucking know that was gonna happen.
Rym: it's there they are and you're like oh my god I feel like we should go.
Scott: there's a lot easier things that we can go to.
Rym: yeah you know what.
Rym: that's probably not any less easy than going to like f1 or something like I feel like if you want to go to a kpop thing I think I heard the Big Bang is coming around the country.
Scott: I'll probably see them in New Jersey where they'll be 90% screaming teenage Korean girls.
Rym: yeah I mean we went to the ticket.
Scott: tickets will probably be like hundreds of dollars.
Rym: we did go to the New York Tokyo musical festival.
Scott: it will be more fun than that for sure yeah but it's all gonna be expensive to sit anywhere.
Scott: good you could just watch it on YouTube and screaming teenage girls.
Scott: it's like.
Scott: would you go to a Bieber concert?
Rym: well I don't like Bieber.
Scott: I think that is one thing.
Scott: is that somehow you know I don't know if anyone listening knows or cares who Big Bang is but it's like this boy band.
Scott: but they're talented and they write their own music and for some reason dudes also like them.
Rym: well I like them.
Scott: so all right it's really weird.
Scott: imagine a man just imagine if you liked Bieber and like respected him.
Scott: we're like dude.
Scott: he's the awesomest.
Scott: only there were five of him and they were all different but the same wall of people is at the concert sure.
Rym: so in I guess anime Wednesday topic news.
Scott: it wasn't even news.
Rym: I got news coming.
Rym: yeah so the anime news network is doing its annual mega poll of the best anime.
Scott: every website is doing its annual mega poll the anime news network.
Rym: one is always interesting because you forget when anime came out like wasn't your pedal this year?
Rym: I don't remember me.
Rym: scroll down here and see because they have their rules.
Rym: they have a pretty good set of rules about what counts as this year and not as this year.
Rym: all right.
Rym: so one punch man counts.
Scott: yes so winner no first place.
Rym: well winner winner chicken dinner.
Scott: is your pedal count?
Rym: is your Akuma's on there?
Rym: I don't see it.
Scott: actually yo a mushi pedal.
Rym: perhaps under the wise there's just Yamada kun yada man night young black right.
Scott: I guess it doesn't count.
Rym: yugioh yurikuma arashi.
Rym: what about the movie?
Scott: I didn't see but I'm pretty sure is in second in just layer.
Rym: wait is it's not an alphabetical order?
Scott: just use your control F anyway.
Scott: but I mean I haven't seen it yet because it's hard to see.
Scott: but I'm pretty sure the boy in the beast is gonna be second place.
Scott: it's a one punch man.
Rym: a good thing to do every year is just scroll down this list and see how many of those shows you watch and you might forget that some show is a better idea.
Scott: just wait for the poll to fucking finish see what one and then watch those a lot of people you know you vote for five in the poll.
Rym: yeah and it's anime news network people who are voting meaning that one or two good shows and three to four terrible shows are gonna be at the top.
Scott: hmm I'm sure you can tell by just by looking at the names which ones are which I the name contains the word punch not probably a good choice if the name contains love love.
Scott: ooh probably a bad job yeah.
Scott: but at the same time Yurikuma.
Scott: I voted for that one Yurikuma not actually my sister oh is she?
Scott: yeah?
Rym: so these are always fun and you should scroll down because there were some good shows this year like Ushio and Tara.
Rym: I was digging that.
Rym: I gotta finish that.
Scott: and one punch man.
Scott: yeah one punch man he who punches only one time Yurikuma the man but once that that Lupin single puncher.
Rym: so yeah you got news.
Scott: uh there's the sad news I'm like.
Scott: I'm pretty sure everyone heard last week but or when it happened I wasn't even last week it was like a few days ago.
Scott: so Shigeru Mizuki if you don't know who that is is the guy who made Kitaro and also you know Kitaro and a bunch of other mangas but all his other mangas weren't about yokai and stuff.
Scott: they were like.
Scott: there's one about Hitler.
Scott: that's coming out in English real soon.
Rym: I didn't know that was coming out in English.
Scott: yeah it's coming out.
Scott: and then there's the one I just got perhaps I think the final volume of which is show our history of Japan which is like the entire history of Japan.
Scott: well the Showa era at least right.
Scott: and so he's like.
Scott: you know after Tezuka he's like.
Scott: you know I know he's the best manga creator but he's like.
Rym: it's hard for me to be super objective there because I really like Kitaro.
Scott: oh yeah it's super good.
Rym: but that's partly because I also really like yokai and Kitaro was the right balance of yokai being both terrifying and silly at the same time which is the best way to consume yokai.
Scott: it's like in some way like Tezuka is like the Disney and also the Stan Lee and also the Will Eisner of.
Scott: you know Japan all at once even though Miyazaki sort of also the Disney in a way yeah.
Scott: but Mizuki it's like there's no one to compare him to.
Scott: it's like.
Scott: was he the Jim Henson?
Scott: not really he didn't raise all the children's with his puppet show right but I guess he has the sort that you know.
Scott: it doesn't have an equivalency there but he's the same sort of level of status right in terms of importance to the.
Scott: you know the culture right.
Rym: I guess what you should do is if you've never heard of this like any of what we're talking about go check out Kitaro right just to get the ball rolling and then the ball can keep rolling.
Rym: yeah.
Scott: so anyway he died like a few days ago.
Scott: but dude the man was 93 and he lost his arm in the war.
Scott: the war right.
Scott: so no not that one.
Scott: it's like this is ultimate badass dude who made all these amazing important mangas like incredibly important dude.
Scott: so I mean it's not like a surprise.
Scott: it was 93 but yeah.
Rym: so in lighter news to uh to make you feel a little bit better the Pikachu build-a-bear is releasing this month.
Rym: you can build a Pikachu.
Scott: I guess we know some people who are doing that.
Rym: he can come with either a pokeball costume or a Charizard costume.
Scott: there you go.
Rym: I feel like we should go there.
Scott: you do that.
Scott: it's a lot of money.
Scott: it's a reason I'm not gonna go there.
Rym: yeah let's see get the Pikachu alone is 28 bucks.
Scott: it's actually not that bad yeah.
Scott: but I mean you want to remix that shit right because you gotta get like Star Wars stuff and they have pony stuff at build-a-bear.
Scott: how do I know this?
Scott: cuz I walk past one and I looked in the window on my way to play netrunner and so I'm pretty sure they let you mix that shit up.
Scott: you can put like Star Wars.
Scott: you know you can put a Darth Vader head on a Pikachu body with the Charmander costume and a My Little Pony feet or you know accessory or something hooves.
Scott: yeah I'm sure you could.
Scott: yeah I'm sure they would let you do that if you paid the money but I'm sure it also costs a hoof and a hoof.
Rym: this is yet another example of build-a-bear causing that odd dichotomy where a bunch of 20 to 30 year old people are gonna be making little stuffed animals right next to a bunch of like four year olds with their parents.
Scott: that odd dichotomy when Rym wants to go to the kpop concert in Jersey right next to the teenage girls.
Rym: yeah I'm glad to see this cultural mixing.
Rym: I'm glad to see generations enjoying their pop culture together even though you still should not go to the local elementary school and see if anyone wants to play Pokemon with you.
Rym: but anyway things of the day many of the things of the day we've had over the years were created by one man Neil Cicierega.
Rym: he is probably the avatar of the expression of the internet in the modern world.
Rym: he's the master and king of remixes.
Rym: I'm not even gonna list the things he's done because now he has a patreon and basically he's just offering to continue doing what he's been doing.
Scott: how much money is getting in his patreon?
Rym: he's already up to $1,000 a much.
Scott: is our patreon like 200?
Scott: are you saying that we're only five times less than Neil Cicierega currently?
Scott: yes that is where we stand as I figured he was like 50 times more than us not five times more than us.
Rym: so inter.
Rym: actually in terms of content created if you just go by hours we probably made more.
Scott: I mean it just by hours.
Scott: we're catching up with shit like bonanza.
Rym: but god this patreon is extra special because one you know when you make a patreon because as you know GeekNights has a patreon you have to say like what you're creating.
Rym: so we're creating podcasts and lectures and these other things Neil Cicierega is creating star dot star.
Rym: if you give him a dollar you are really nice.
Rym: if you give him $2 you get his entire discography from 1999 to 2014 and if he raises his stretch goal if he starts getting $50,000 a month that'll happen which is less no more.
Rym: it is more than what we are asking for.
Rym: the will.
Rym: quit our jobs and do get away this $2 a month for the discography.
Rym: 50 yeah $2 it's too much.
Rym: well you could donate for a month get the link and then stop donating.
Scott: if you give it all away for free on YouTube and I pay for YouTube bread so I'm already paying every time I listen to his shit he'll get a piece but you get one big old download which might be like flag files or something.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: find out but the video part is on YouTube.
Rym: - yeah no this is just his discography right which I assume is just the audio.
Rym: yeah but yeah I'd like to have that just as a file set of like flax or 96 kbps.
Rym: you do that and give me the files but I'm gonna read this thing cuz I'm kind of a fanboy of this dude.
Rym: hi I'm Neil Cisarega.
Rym: I'm a web artist and web comedian.
Rym: I've been webbing around since 2001 the year.
Scott: all of those things are accurate.
Rym: I make everything from original videos to mash.
Rym: oh so mash and ups are links but the H in between them is not.
Rym: I gotta click on that later.
Rym: comedy videos animated gifs harmless hoaxes etc.
Rym: and that's it.
Rym: he just has this animated gif showing a bunch of things he's done.
Rym: he is a man who knows who he is ranging from hiyako juichi to puppet pals to eight legs.
Rym: okay remember that one.
Scott: yeah I know every work he's done.
Scott: I'm surprised he did not include however the cow.
Rym: so my thing of the day is that that man is asking for money to continue doing what he has done.
Scott: he's gonna continue no matter what.
Rym: yeah I know but so are we.
Rym: so if we are hypocritical for doing a patreon he is equally hypocritical.
Rym: you should back his patreon first and if you have money left over you can also back us anyway.
Scott: so what do you think of when you think of Alan Moore a watchman?
Rym: okay also a picture of Alan Moore like a picture of his face that those are the two things I think of particularly his wedding.
Scott: okay so apparently I did not know this until just recently and it was a saved up thing of the day.
Scott: who in 1981?
Scott: whoa whoa or 82.
Scott: Alan Moore was making comics.
Scott: as he's way older than us he made some comics.
Scott: he in fact made one two three four five five comics and these comics were published in the magazine obviously in the UK all right because that's where he was at the time.
Scott: they weren't published in the US for another 15 years and I guess they were still unknown but now they're gonna be more widely known.
Scott: he published these comics in the magazine known as Marvel Star Wars UK.
Rym: well wait what?
Scott: here are?
Scott: five Star Wars comics by Alan Moore whoa.
Rym: so are they trippy?
Rym: are they gritty?
Rym: are they weird?
Scott: they are Star Wars comics by Alan Moore.
Scott: the end.
Rym: in the moment we're going to be at Pac South.
Scott: officially our schedule is done.
Rym: I'm pulling it up but it's gonna be easy for once because we're doing two lectures at Pac South.
Rym: they are brand new lectures.
Rym: we're not recycling anything it's all you.
Rym: and well yeah one of them doesn't need slides really.
Rym: so that's that's a bonus.
Rym: they're both at 1 p.m.
Rym: in the Bobcat theater one on Saturday and one on Sunday.
Rym: so on Saturday July 30th at 1 p.m.
Rym: in the Bobcat theater we're doing Atari game design and on Sunday do you know about it.
Rym: sorry I know a lot about.
Rym: no we're not talking about coding Atari games.
Scott: and you can I slept to study the technical limitations of the Atari because that's how greatly influenced the design of those games and I have studied a bunch of that.
Rym: and the thing is the idea is that if you want to design a board game you want to study game design.
Rym: you should probably start with like Atari video game fundamentals because you can look at the screen and literally count pixels.
Rym: there's not that much complexity that can be hidden from you in terms of game design player interaction.
Rym: so we're gonna go through that in great detail.
Rym: and then Sunday January 31st at 1 p.m.
Rym: in the Bobcat theater we're going to be doing designing game rules like why Hellas is an unplayable game and why most Kickstarter games have terrible rules.
Rym: we're gonna be at mag fest do a between Scott and I. we're gonna be on like seven panels but anything that's all still in the works scheduling and whatnot.
Rym: I think our schedule is actually done in terms of what we're gonna be on.
Rym: we're just waiting for you know when?
Rym: and then I guess when is all we really care about?
Rym: we're gonna be a PAX East probably doing a bunch of stuff and enforcing pec south needs enforcers.
Rym: so you should sign up for that and back us on patreon if you've already backed Neil Cicierega.
Rym: so we're finally reviewing manga and comics again.
Rym: as you might have noticed partly cuz Scott's just been giving me things to say and read them mm-hmm.
Rym: but this this is a pretty good manga and I feel like you guys should read it.
Rym: well comic I think I didn't.
Scott: I say I was gonna say comic instead of you couldn't even stick to your own thing for like five.
Rym: so Inuyashiki is a slice of life about an old man with a terrible family who's dying of stomach cancer.
Rym: all right.
Scott: so this manga.
Scott: I found out about this because I was looking down the list of things to buy and I said oh there's a manga there and that is not just some typical shonen or shoujo garbage manga.
Scott: it clearly is different just based on the cover alone.
Scott: oh and the person who made is the guy who made gone.
Scott: so just something that I think I would probably like and I know is really violent but I just haven't read it because I haven't not because I don't want to.
Scott: I'm pretty sure I'll like it if I did read it.
Scott: yep and so but this is volume one.
Scott: so let me pick this up.
Scott: and yeah it's about this old guy whose family was really the worst family.
Scott: like you know he's a salaryman Japan doing a shitty job.
Scott: he hates doing it.
Rym: he's finally saved up enough money to be fully retired to have a house to live with his family in peace for his dad for his you know old years.
Rym: he looks way older than he is just because of a life of stress and misery and his family is the worst family.
Scott: his wife clearly doesn't love him or anything.
Scott: how they got married I'd love to see the past.
Scott: there haven't been any flashbacks like that showing you anything you know from how this started.
Scott: right.
Rym: I mean they're not the worst in like they're not Nazis or anything.
Rym: they're just.
Scott: they're just really.
Scott: they don't appreciate or love their or care about their father even though everything they have is because of him and the kids are way spoiled.
Scott: there's when they show up at the new house you know there's like a guy coming out of a Ferrari in this you know in this other house and they're like that's not our house the nice one.
Scott: well we had this shitty house in the back and it's like dude you're living in like a shithole.
Rym: two seconds ago was the shitty house in the back like.
Rym: I would kill to live in a house like that.
Scott: hell yeah yeah and that dude.
Scott: I'll be friends with the guy with the Ferrari living out front.
Scott: maybe give me a ride yeah whatever.
Scott: but now these kids are so shitty and it's just.
Rym: it's 20 pages.
Rym: the first 20-ish pages are just continual gut punches to you watching this guy suffer through all of this just and it's one of those ones we're like.
Scott: I almost couldn't take it the same way.
Scott: there's been a few other things like this where I'm like dude just just like.
Scott: kill your family like dude.
Scott: just punch them.
Scott: it's like you know just do something it's like and the person is.
Scott: you know I really can't stand it a lot easily when there's someone who's just like being victimized and just done in a story.
Scott: it just doesn't do anything.
Scott: at least run away or something right.
Scott: just stop giving them money just like you got all the money just like you own the house sell that fucking house let them be homeless and be like see ya.
Rym: so I mean it gets to the point.
Rym: this all happens like right in the beginning.
Rym: we're like you're really feeling depressed.
Rym: this is not going well.
Rym: and then he finds out he has stomach cancer and a few months to live and he can't.
Scott: it's like well now you wasted your whole life - you can't even run away and he can't even tell his family because they literally will not listen to him.
Rym: talk long enough for him to tell them that he's dying.
Scott: they also won't give a shit.
Rym: and then the line that shit that made this manga go from depressing to amazing.
Rym: there the words.
Rym: I'm gonna quote the words where I went.
Rym: holy shit what.
Rym: but we only have weapon grade units in stock.
Rym: I mean I've got a spoiler to kind of sell you on reading this thing but we're not gonna.
Rym: I mean there's not you're just.
Rym: it's a comic.
Rym: read it like it's just read it but basically a UFO or something crashes into a park.
Scott: it's totally random like just out of nowhere.
Scott: it's not completely out of nowhere but it's mostly out of nowhere.
Scott: the guys in the park with the dog the only thing that he loves.
Rym: it loves him that his family hates by the way and didn't want him to get but he got it and taking care of his dog dogs.
Scott: great dog is good.
Scott: it's a good dog anyway he's hanging with in the park with the dog being all sad but hanging with the dog.
Scott: so that's nice and aliens just show up and you're probably thinking well this sounds like the stupidest thing ever.
Scott: so I'm just gonna read the dialogue and I was what I was hesitant while reading.
Scott: I'm like really this is why I thought I was gonna get some serious drama and I ended up getting some alien garbage.
Rym: really there is one page of just dialogue of the aliens talking to each other.
Rym: any damage nothing here.
Rym: however we did destroy two of this planet's intelligent life-forms daddy to intelligent life.
Rym: so there's them hanging out there.
Scott: when they first said that I thought is the dog intelligent?
Rym: yeah can we rebuild them?
Rym: I'm afraid not.
Rym: then at least recreate their outer appearances as quickly as you can convincing enough that they don't realize we tampered with them.
Rym: but sir we only have weapon grade units in stock.
Rym: wait no they'll destroy the entire planet.
Rym: that's not our problem.
Rym: we need to disengage at once and they just fucking leave.
Scott: so this guy wakes up.
Scott: he doesn't know.
Scott: you know he knows.
Scott: he just thinks as he's himself.
Rym: yeah he comes home and his family's like where the fuck were you?
Rym: you piece of shit.
Scott: yeah he doesn't realize anything but he's not himself.
Scott: he eventually discovers he's now a robot that is not himself that he died.
Scott: yeah the doctors are like whoa actually just a robot with all the memories of the person who died and he's basically super powerful and super invincible.
Scott: and of course yes there is another person who the same who also died and was replaced by a robot who's clearly gonna be the villain or something.
Rym: yeah he is major Kusanagi except he's a frail old man.
Rym: and the best part about this comic is that once he realizes what's going on he isn't really that horrified.
Rym: he basically just becomes a superhero.
Rym: he's like.
Rym: you know what this is awesome.
Scott: uh I was gonna die of stomach cancer anyway I died a real alien.
Rym: yeah he has this revelation to.
Rym: he was like well I'm someone different.
Rym: I don't need to pay for these pieces of shit anymore.
Rym: my family like.
Rym: I don't have to help them.
Rym: I can do whatever I want.
Scott: yeah but that family yeah.
Rym: but then I guess the second moment where this went from like just a pretty good thing to really great is the hacking montage.
Rym: that I don't want to spoil because there's a lot of reasons why that scene was great one.
Rym: it was realistic like really realistic which never happens in comics like this - it was actually subtle.
Rym: like instead of having the usual manga BS of you know a whole bunch of people explaining like well what's Twitter blah blah blah blah blah and then like late spoon feeding you what he's doing it just shows you this montage of what he's doing like screenshots of Twitter and screenshots of YouTube and then it cuts to.
Rym: these kids are all on the phone with their parents and it doesn't like.
Scott: well cuz you assume the audience for this thing right?
Scott: is Japanese kids?
Scott: they fucking know.
Scott: yeah they don't need to be explained to them what Twitter is like what the fuck.
Rym: but there's a lot of nuance in this comic that is not there and a lot of other manga I have read.
Rym: that makes me really appreciate the subtlety that like it just I appreciate.
Scott: I really want to see volume 2 a lot and it's not out yet at least not in English and I'm like oh my god give me to volume 2.
Rym: yep although all the characters are meeting other than his family are pretty great and it ain't like the this volume.
Rym: the first trade ends on a really good spot but then there's like a little like next step like sort of dinner.
Scott: it's not a cliffhanger but it's like they're showing you what the story is actually gonna be because it's you know obviously only partially about the drama with him and his family.
Scott: right you know they're sort of showing you.
Scott: this is what to expect from the rest of this manga.
Scott: yeah and it's like oh that is if that's what's to expect then give me more please.
Scott: yes sir I would like some more.
Rym: the art is super consistently good.
Scott: the yeah the art and guns is always like crazy good yeah it sort of has that realisticness of like the backgrounds of Death Note.
Scott: but the character you know because Death Note he always does like like he draws the backgrounds in Death Note like architecturally like everything is super straight lines with hyper details and then the characters like normal anime characters.
Scott: in this it's like okay the backgrounds are just as Death Note II but perhaps a little less.
Scott: you know straight line architectural but still you know plenty of details going on which is the way the people are more realistic you know and less stereotypically anime.
Scott: ish you know their faces are really really good right they're close.
Scott: they're somewhere in between those you know stereotypical anime style and like the Ikegami you know real people manga style like somewhere halfway like think about the faces in sanctuary when a character is watching something and reacting to it in a complex and intense manner.
Rym: it's like that but with this old man seeing in justice around him swallowing it because he knows he's powerless to do anything about it and being really conflicted about it and all this like the guy looks like he's about to explode every single panel but he's just bottling it all in and hiding
Scott: it.
Scott: he's gonna explode now big time but he did explode.
Scott: one day might destroy the world.
Scott: that powerful enough to destroy the world.
Scott: that's not our problem.
Rym: I also like the bum guy.
Rym: the bum guys like.
Rym: I feel like that's gonna be a sidekick.
Rym: that's gonna be his Robin.
Scott: sure why not go bum guy?
Scott: go.
Scott: yeah I don't know if we'll see the bum guy again.
Rym: I'll bet we see the bum guy again.
Rym: okay I'm confident.
Scott: but yeah I guess if you like this I'm also gonna try to find slash read guns.
Scott: so I don't see if you like this.
Rym: you wouldn't like see those by the other guy kid in the end as much as anime posters and Gantz all over his walls.
Scott: yeah people always do that.
Scott: yeah I mean in one punch man.
Scott: well you know there's all kinds of stuff referencing the manga the other the other manga.
Scott: that one is working.
Rym: we also notice the rich guy in the house in front is what a famous manga artist.
Rym: yeah pretty sure that's the guy thousand air in there.
Scott: yeah that's interesting that in the manga Inuyashiki you can read guns.
Rym: so I guess it's set in a world where Gantz exists meaning it's probably just set straight up in our world.
Scott: yeah probably yeah.
Rym: I don't know what else I can say because I just want you guys that's all.
Scott: it's only one volume.
Scott: what else can happen in it?
Rym: yeah but without us just like going through and telling you everything that happens which is really read it to you.
Scott: yeah but yeah you can.
Scott: you know you might even just based on what we've always done is really summarize the plot.
Scott: but I mean it.
Scott: you know it makes you feel when you start reading it like frustrated with the shitty family but then you want to take out your aggression on them and you know stand up for this old man and then and you know the rest of it is all right.
Scott: well the old man's a super powerful robot.
Scott: now sorry family shit.
Rym: it's like when Astro Boy remembers like oh I can just punch people.
Scott: boom Astro Boy vs One Punch Man.
Rym: well we know who'd win.
Rym: obviously this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: the amazing patrons of tonight's GeekNights are in order of the amount of money they give us on a monthly basis even though I got to make sure you give at least a little bit of that money to feel sus regga Nicholas Brando Rebecca Dunn James David White Christian coons Jess mechanical mind Renee from New Zealand Robert Lee Ryan parent drew up and lender rare Lavelle Brian's a droney Rochelle Montanona Finn Eric Silverado Rym eats poop kinetic man William Eisen rose Aaron series Chris midkiff Chris Knox flame dark fire Samuel Cordery Daniel Redmond Chris had died Doug Snyder Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: so we did just record right after we did the show the November Q&A.
Rym: so I'm gonna wait a few days just because I'm lazy and there's a Rangers game that I want to go watch the rest of because it's pretty good right now and Emily is not home she's visiting family and things for the holidays.
Rym: so pretty much she's gonna eat a bowl of croutons and ranch dressing for dinner and watch the Rangers game and then either play undertale or rocket League until I fall asleep.
Rym: but yeah that'll go up patrons only soon as they get a chance.
Rym: and then soon I will open the submission for questions for the December Q&A.
Rym: and now I leave you with your moment of literally the opposite of Zen.