Rym: It's Monday November 2nd 2015.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: Don't drop your phone Let's do this.
Rym: So, uh, Emily and I kind of went to Disney for didn't extended period didn't any world?
Rym: There is a. there's a wedding of some friends that I kind of Sort of booked and did the thing all at the last minute Like I booked flights like a week before.
Scott: it's not a hard place to go to Disney world Didn't he?
Scott: world and Vegas are like the two easiest places to go to you.
Rym: like you can go whenever the hell you want I'm gonna say that Vegas is easier to go to than didn't it?
Scott: I mean if you have I'm just saying like if you have money and You can go like at the drop of a hat you can get on a plane and get a hotel at either of those locations.
Rym: Yeah, so so.
Rym: actually though we got to stay because the wedding was for a military family.
Rym: We got to stay at a resort that is otherwise only accessible to Military people.
Scott: that's cool.
Rym: Yeah shades of green.
Rym: It's like right in the park next to the Polynesian and ever knew it existed and it was actually kind of cool Except we had to show a special ID card the whole time.
Rym: We were there to get back into the facility Okay, but otherwise, it was great.
Rym: well The pavilion do a special show where we'll review Didney world because we've just been there now and I got a lot to say there in the 90s.
Rym: Yeah, we do a three-way show.
Rym: the three of us because I got I got updates like some things have changed and some things have not Changed.
Rym: and the only thing I want to say this relevant to Monday GeekNights.
Rym: Is that Universal Studios has an app for like.
Rym: hey, I'm at Universal Studios and it's awesome.
Rym: Didney has an app for I'm at didn't?
Scott: it sucks.
Scott: It's garbage.
Rym: Okay, it has.
Scott: One of the worst UX is you should figure out which companies that hired to make each app.
Scott: I mean, they're super higher than one.
Rym: They're so superficially similar and like the way they're laid out that I actually suspect they're made by the same company.
Rym: But like in the didney app if you want to see the map of the park You're in.
Rym: that's actually really hard to do.
Scott: That's the most important thing.
Scott: and if you don't have to carry on a stupid paper map with me And
Rym: if you want to do a fast pass of like hey I want to ride Space Mountain and then it'll tell you like alright come back at one and you can skip most of the line And do like a quick thing, which they do.
Rym: It's free.
Rym: Yeah Good luck getting the app to actually set that up for you.
Scott: Here's what I don't understand.
Scott: You need it back in the day.
Scott: Yeah, but it is, you know technology related, right?
Scott: So I went to didn't?
Scott: he rolled the 90s.
Rym: I went to did knee in 97 and when I went in like 89 sure and I wanted to go on the Splash Mountain I just got in line and waited like three hours.
Scott: I didn't wait three hours.
Scott: I went a good time.
Scott: I waited like less than an hour.
Rym: Well, cuz the lines got stuff going on.
Scott: Yeah, and then I did a little Splash Mountain and I was on my way.
Scott: But nowadays I get a little line to Splash Mountain.
Scott: I get to the top.
Scott: I got this phone I do not want to take with me on the Splash Mountain.
Scott: Yeah So where the fuck do you put your phone if you go to Disney World when you splash on the mountain?
Scott: And how do you get it back when you've done splashing?
Rym: so at Universal?
Rym: There are lockers outside of every ride that are free and fingerprint controlled.
Scott: That's pretty good.
Rym: at other resorts like Cedar Point There's lockers on the platforms that you just put your stuff in and then when you come back on the ride You take your stuff out.
Scott: You hope no one takes your shit.
Rym: They keep an eye on it.
Scott: Like it's usually fine Does it say leave your stuff here your own risk?
Rym: So that was never a problem for me.
Rym: Also, if you're going to it, I mean honestly Most rides at did knee.
Rym: in fact, I'd say every ride at did knee you can just keep your phone in pocket.
Scott: Yeah, I think you can take your phone on the teacups.
Rym: It's the only thing on every roller coaster and did knee Just fine from a don't lose your phone perspective except the Splash Mountain.
Rym: You know what Splash Mountain?
Rym: your phone would be fine.
Rym: You don't get that wet.
Scott: you get pretty wet.
Scott: Don't get that wet.
Scott: It's not called Dries Bone Mountain or Desert Island Mountain.
Rym: It's Splash Mountain not Drench Mountain Not.
Rym: uh, oh, what's the name of the Russian roulette thing at Cedar Point?
Scott: Did you go to Universal Studios or did you go to the Adventure Island?
Scott: Both!
Rym: Okay, because there's Halloween shit going down.
Rym: So we went to Universal Studios for like the whole day and then at five they basically kicked everybody out Because starting at seven until midnight It was special haunted Jason vs.
Rym: Freddy like fucked up nightmare land.
Rym: Okay, which actually looked really cool.
Scott: Why did you go to that?
Rym: Because instead we you know, we didn't only had a few days.
Rym: so instead we went over to Islands of Adventure and Rode the dragon challenge a bunch of times because that's that's the twin rollercoasters used to be dueling dragons.
Rym: Yeah, it is so in all that's pretty good in all of like.
Scott: did you ride the Incredible Hulk that sneakily?
Rym: No, it's fucking shut down and they've torn half of it apart.
Rym: They're renovating it.
Scott: Oh, did you ride the spider-man ride?
Scott: No, but I rode the Simpsons ride which that was not there when I went there.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So, you know what the Simpsons ride is Kind of amazing.
Rym: That's a spider-man.
Scott: The spider-man ride was amazing in the 90s I'm sure.
Scott: I'm sure the Simpsons ride is the MGM.
Rym: back to the future ride.
Rym: We're.
Scott: no that way ghetto because it's super old was way amazing.
Scott: They updated it.
Rym: Oh, let me tell you the the technology the Harry Potter area was off the fucking hook.
Scott: Well that used to be generic fantasy area with the dragons.
Rym: there are two Harry Potter places.
Scott: when I was there It was a generic fantasy area.
Rym: Yeah, it is kind of off the hook, but the the sort of rollercoaster 4d ish rides that are the Harry Potter at the two sides way Impressive from a tech standpoint.
Scott: Did they have this other Popeye water ride there?
Scott: They change.
Rym: I saw that we didn't ride it.
Scott: That's a really good water ride.
Scott: you get in a giant tube and it goes all over and you know what?
Scott: You can't bring your phone on.
Rym: But it was interesting because honestly there are only a handful of roller coasters in the entire.
Rym: did the universal area that are on par With.
Rym: what about?
Scott: it's a theme park.
Scott: It's not a thrill park exactly.
Rym: They have fun thrills but not a lot dueling dragons the Hulk which I didn't ride The Hollywood rocket in Universal which I didn't ride as a kid because I guess it wasn't there.
Scott: I don't know what that is.
Rym: So it's actually a legit roller coaster.
Rym: But it's weird because it wasn't like the kinds of roller coasters I'm familiar with.
Rym: so I went and looked up the deal because like there's only like three or four companies that make legit roller coasters.
Rym: There's Intamin there's aerodynamics.
Rym: There's the M&B.
Rym: That's pretty much it.
Rym: Like no one else makes roller coasters worth a shit and I Couldn't like.
Rym: I know a lot about roller coasters.
Rym: like Emily started to learn that I'm that guy.
Rym: if roller coasters come up Like let me tell you about a guy who's more that guy than you.
Rym: I you know, I thought that but there's only a few.
Rym: I'm actually kind of up there.
Rym: But the roller coaster was weird.
Rym: So finally like we're having drinks later and I went on Wikipedia and I'm looking up the deal Universal apparently made this thing on their own.
Rym: It was like an outsider roller coaster.
Rym: So that's why it didn't have like the normal roller coaster tropes and it did weird stuff that for good reasons other roller coasters Don't do.
Rym: It was fun, but it was weird.
Scott: Did you go to Epcot land?
Scott: Yeah, go to the back where all the countries are.
Scott: There's a Viking boat ride still there that was shut down.
Rym: we couldn't ride it.
Scott: No Viking boat Time.
Rym: I was like, there's this log flume like.
Rym: I kept looking for it.
Rym: And then finally we figured out that it's just shut down.
Rym: There was a food festival going on so independent.
Scott: it's always a food Double food festival.
Rym: So there's double food.
Rym: So there's normal Epcot, right?
Scott: I have the food of every country in each country.
Scott: Yes, that's the point.
Rym: So in between all the countries that have been there forever They added twice as many little countries that were just a food pop-up stand.
Rym: So twice as much food.
Scott: Is figment still there?
Rym: I learned a lot about figment.
Scott: We uh, figment's my boy.
Rym: Emily had this vague memory of figment.
Rym: Figment's my boy And the little squares you jump on at the end.
Rym: Yeah, so Emily had this vague memory of that.
Scott: So I remember figment very clearly.
Rym: Yeah, so Imagination The moral of figment was basically hey, I'm science dad here to teach you about science and figments like oh fuck No, you're not.
Rym: I'm gonna fart all over everybody.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: So I think we'll do a show on Disney separately.
Scott: But seriously the dragon what's?
Scott: no another there's no other dragons.
Scott: I mean Pete's dragon doesn't even really show up at Disney World.
Rym: I know they should bring that back.
Rym: Dueling dragons is there but that's Harry Potter.
Scott: That's not even.
Scott: that's not Disney World It's universal.
Rym: it's all the same thing as far as I'm concerned.
Scott: It's two completely different companies have nothing to do with each other.
Rym: Yeah, but I mean you're talking about different parks.
Scott: because Is that Nickelodeon's thing still universal?
Rym: MGM which is now Disney Hollywood Studios.
Rym: Those are also separate parks.
Scott: So well the MGM is part of Disney World.
Scott: Well, no.
Rym: Yeah, but it's a separate park with a separate ticket.
Scott: It's always been a separate park.
Rym: I know but now it's not MGM.
Scott: Now the thing is when you go to Disney World You're supposed to buy the three park ticket and you could take the monorail to go between the three parks.
Rym: You can the park hopper.
Rym: I know all about that.
Scott: Is it the same old-ass monorail from like the 60s unchanged?
Scott: Yeah, it's a good monorail.
Rym: I also learned a lot about the monorail and how that technology.
Rym: so I was looking up like who's died at Disney and I found the monorail article.
Rym: and apparently in the 80s one of the cars caught on fire and almost killed everybody on it and apparently some dead like Fucking kicked the windows out and pulled everyone to safety on the roof and they hid from the fire and took like some crazy.
Scott: How did they get onto the roof of the monorail?
Rym: Yeah, some crazy crap went down.
Rym: apparently there's a Wikipedia article about it.
Scott: I mean if you go out the window of the monorail, you're going down.
Rym: Yeah, it's not that tall.
Rym: You could get off of that.
Rym: You could jump from that and maybe break a leg But otherwise be okay.
Rym: You could hit the trees.
Scott: It's high up.
Scott: At least I remember it being high up.
Rym: Yeah, you know what?
Rym: I remember a lot of things being way higher up and bigger that I went back as an adult.
Rym: Not so big Okay.
Rym: Anyway, the Disney app Garbage.
Rym: If you want to navigate around Disney, just use Google Maps.
Scott: Oh, Google Maps?
Scott: Not a paper map?
Rym: No, just use Google Maps.
Scott: Google Maps has like all the rides and everything?
Scott: Yeah Pretty good.
Rym: So you got any tech news?
Scott: Not really.
Scott: This is non tech news, but our friends are non friends at anonymous.
Rym: Some of them might be our friends.
Rym: I mean anonymous.
Rym: I mean, I'm an anonymous I guess.
Scott: Sure, whatever They are doing this thing where they are releasing the identities of thousands of people in the KKK Supposedly they got it from like hacking a Twitter account and like following threads from that.
Scott: So the official statement that well the statement that somebody made who claims to be
Rym: all statements from anonymous or official statements
Scott: Obviously, yes They're basically saying look We're not doing this because of what you believe because obviously anonymous super believes in freedom of speech even racist speech Which we also believe in the big nights but the KKK was threatening or at least some KKK people were threatening to engage violently in Ferguson protests, you know because they're the KKK.
Rym: Well because the KKK has a history of one being a bunch of racist dickbags, but Has a history of they are.
Scott: that is there as what they are.
Rym: But secondly also as a history of people who go to packs of a history of being gamers But it's also as a history of being a straight up Rym and Scott of a history of being podcast.
Rym: Ah, yeah, but a straight-up Terrorist organization.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: So so they're like, but because you are gonna be violent.
Scott: That's why we're gonna attack you and you know, what a plus.
Scott: Let's find out who these kke people are and make their lives miserable.
Rym: now The the nuance is it's a leak from anonymous which could be basically some guy.
Rym: Yeah so Some comes down to you on the internet things like corroborating evidence because I poked around the leak and a lot of those addresses are dot.
Rym: Are you addresses?
Rym: which is already a little odd?
Scott: People are getting Russian email addresses to hide themselves.
Rym: I would not suspect them to be that smart.
Rym: and the other part of this is that ice it looks like a lot of the Phone numbers are also complete bogus.
Rym: Like a lot of merges fax machines like random companies.
Rym: So I'll wait for this to be vetted.
Scott: The point is even whether it's the information is accurate, right?
Scott: I want you know, a lot of people are saying well look at this here, right?
Scott: We don't like the KKK But we also don't like revealing people's identities and which I also.
Rym: that's a conflict that I have in my day-to-day Life and their personal information.
Scott: and they're like, you know, it's not cool if you go and put like, you know Say some feminist journalists information online so that people can harass her.
Scott: Why is it okay to put out the informationism KKK person to harass them?
Scott: And the answer I give to you is because principle is bullshit.
Scott: Who cares if it doesn't matter.
Scott: It's it's right.
Scott: It's like, you know, it's okay to kill some horribly sick and old person who's suffering.
Scott: It's not okay to kill some young and healthy.
Rym: Wait, wait, Scott.
Scott: You're perfectly okay to make the life of some KKK dickbag miserable.
Scott: It's not okay to make the life of a good person miserable.
Scott: It's all doing that.
Rym: Situations require a nuanced and individual approach when making decisions.
Scott: You don't say but there seems to be like people on the internet Especially people who like to argue on the internet like they can't escape Principle like they're like there would be like especially like libertarian types.
Scott: It's like they're like freedom and it's like they'll come across an issue and they apply their principle to it And even if they like don't agree with something like racism or you know, whatever it is, right?
Scott: They can't you know, they're like, oh my god, it'll be.
Scott: it's like.
Scott: well, it depends like Reverse cognitive dissonance like for example dissonance is when you contradict yourself, but you don't realize it You can't.
Scott: it's it right your brain is separating.
Scott: It's like the opposite.
Scott: It's like you.
Scott: you have to be consistent every time By being inconsistent Recognizing it and not giving it.
Rym: there's a way to get around there without being inconsistent and it's to have a complex Philosophical and ideological heuristic.
Rym: I mean my state.
Rym: I take a very absolutist stance on free speech Like I'm a radical.
Rym: when it comes to free speech I think that's probably the most one of the most important rights that humans have.
Rym: but at the same time I'm pretty okay with for example a university saying the MRAs can't have their club.
Rym: sure and I can back that up.
Rym: The problem is that people will make pronouncements like this from an ideological standpoint But they can't really argue their point that effectively because their point is actually very simple and thus very prone to holes that they then have to leap over with cognitive dissonance or Stubborn hobgoblin like fixation on a very simple idea.
Rym: Yes, so, you know what my stance on this is.
Rym: if the problem the problem is a leaks like this could be entirely fabricated to ruin someone's life.
Scott: yes, they could be but it's if someone is on the list who's not in the KKK that would be very very bad.
Rym: or if Lynch mobs appear on the internet the irony of saying it that way to go after like a gay rights activists.
Scott: That's not cool.
Scott: But yeah, Lynch mob appears to go after a KKK Lynch mob.
Scott: I'm down.
Scott: Let's all the fact.
Scott: I might even join up.
Rym: What if the lynch mob actually killed someone?
Scott: Is it a KKK person?
Rym: It's someone who was in the KKK at least within the last ten years.
Scott: Too regretful, I'm gonna put it this way.
Rym: this is a situation not feeling too bad about.
Rym: I'm gonna analogize this the way analogize Awesome graffiti.
Rym: if someone does some awesome graffiti and gets caught I feel like that they should still get fined for the graffiti But the judge should high-five them on their way to pay the fine.
Scott: don't high-five the KKK.
Rym: no no High five anonymous unless this leak is BS.
Scott: But yeah this kind of thing good that'd be a good deal.
Scott: right for every person on the list.
Scott: That's fake.
Scott: you get nothing for every person on the list.
Scott: That wasn't actually in the KKK.
Scott: We're gonna cane you once and for every person on the list who isn't a KKK We're gonna high-five you once and give you a cupcake.
Rym: There is a real interesting thing though.
Scott: with this sort of doxxing and information of We thought I mean it is free speech in and of itself to share information Even if it's someone's address and name and phone number.
Rym: But again this comes to the problem of.
Rym: there were lines that existed solely because technology was inefficient in Distributing that information like if someone's in 1700 they didn't even have the telephone.
Rym: when they made the First Amendment in 1980 It was real hard to know if someone was a criminal or in the past or Had like what.
Rym: if someone's like family was murdered or something like details about someone's past like that person was abused as a kid or?
Rym: Something that information was in the public domain in some fashion but was obscured by poor technology.
Scott: you would have to go to different towns to the halls of records and Hang out with some detectives and some clerks and read a lot of shit.
Rym: It meant there was a lot of information that was technically public but actually required a lot of effort and will to uncover.
Rym: Technology has now made it such that it requires Minimal will and zero effort to uncover that kind of information.
Scott: I don't know how but see private investigators seem to be in more work lately and not less Which I think is just because people are incompetent at searching.
Rym: Yeah, like you know the KKK guys I'm pretty sure their password to the Twitter account, which is how they got all this info was something like white power 69 to probably.
Rym: So Yeah, if this is all legit.
Rym: I'm just gonna smirk and otherwise not really have a strong opinion.
Rym: Whatever happens happens.
Rym: So Something happened in Turkey and you're a lot of you probably have a gobble turkey time soon.
Scott: Thank to the economy a couple weeks away the turkey time.
Rym: I heard Christmas music today my way to work.
Scott: Yeah, I was expecting the lights to be already on the trees outside work today But they're actually a little bit later than last year.
Scott: last year I'm pretty sure it was November like first as soon as Halloween was over.
Rym: I'm waiting for.
Rym: the real day is the day Robert coup plays Christmas music in the penny arcade office tomorrow.
Rym: So Turkey is in the middle of political turmoil.
Rym: turmoil and Erdogan I guess won the big election.
Scott: but Who is that person?
Scott: Is that a good?
Scott: is that the person you would have voted for if you lived in Turkey?
Rym: my opinion?
Scott: No, okay.
Scott: So not good.
Rym: long story short the Turkish government decided to delay daylight saving time Because the election.
Scott: and fuck you Oh wait, oh so that the election.
Scott: so people wouldn't like miss the election because getting the times.
Rym: Well, there's a lot of argument as to what the actual rationale was but it's not the worst reason.
Scott: Oh, I mean if election day happens to be the day where you set the clock back A lot of people might miss.
Rym: they decided this like a few days like not that long ago.
Scott: This is something that's.
Scott: you got to play that in advance.
Scott: Yeah, so like last second the Turkish government said they like saving time delayed.
Rym: So alright My lot of you out there probably don't know how your computer knows daylight saving time.
Scott: because and TV?
Rym: No, and TV doesn't do that and TV has nothing to do with that.
Rym: So operating systems have Zone files that say it's just big text files that say these are all the time zones from UTC.
Scott: You got to get a Windows update.
Rym: Yeah You had to get a Windows update.
Rym: Your phone had to get an but it would only matter if you're lived in Turkey or you interact with anyone in Turkey or at Meeting in with a calendar anywhere in Turkey or relied on any server that was in Turkey visited a website of a person in Turkey.
Scott: I got even worse because and I'll link wanted to know who you wanted to buy something from there.
Rym: So this actually happens kind of often but it happens in Countries that don't understand technology and their governments make these.
Rym: but so here's the list.
Rym: I'm gonna link this to you because when this shit happens Weird shit goes down.
Scott: an example is Java Internally a tiny minuscule meaningless island with a funny name.
Rym: That's a good way to describe that programming language.
Rym: Hey, oh Has its own zone files?
Rym: So normally people just keep Java up-to-date, but if you're running like an enterprise application on a server somewhere You don't update Java just every time it comes down because you know Java breaks shit.
Rym: So usually stage that stuff in.
Rym: so if you use any libraries within Java that are aware of time zones.
Rym: They might find out what time zone or whatever from the system, but Java uses its own embedded stuff.
Rym: So you either need to always keep your job a hundred percent up-to-date meaning when Turkey said we're gonna mess with the time for no good reason.
Rym: you'd better have gotten a Java update like immediately or Java might know a different time zone from your system.
Scott: Yeah, so in Ubuntu and most Linux systems that people are always who are made.
Scott: if your distro is maintained Somebody's updating the zone files.
Scott: so if you just keep getting updates automatically or by hand every day or whatever you're gonna get your updated zone files all the Time and almost all the software will use those own files.
Scott: However, let's say you got I don't know MySQL database Right MySQL database.
Scott: This is command called MySQL underscore TZ info underscore 2 as in TO Underscore SQL and what you do is you type this command then you press space Then you type in the path where your zone files are usually use your local like, you know zone file or whatever it is Right or use there's something local time.
Scott: Yeah And it will read the zone files and then insert into a database in MySQL like the MySQL database inside your MySQL database server all that zone information and Then you can now if you once you've done this and you sort of filled up your MySQL database with zone information You can now convert times within MySQL itself like in a query.
Scott: you can be like TZ convert unders, you know, whatever Which is really freaking handy because you're gonna put all the times in your database are gonna be UTC Always if you're smart, right and then you can just do select Convert time zone New York comma time, you know, whatever and then your when your query results come out.
Scott: They'll already be New York time.
Scott: You won't have to do anything in your application.
Rym: How many of you who use my SQL?
Rym: I've ever heard any of this?
Scott: All right.
Scott: Anyway, yeah, let's say now there's an Ubuntu update for Turkey just happened, right?
Scott: Did you reload your MySQL time zone info?
Scott: Because it doesn't do it on its own.
Scott: Yeah, if you try to convert a turkey time zone with your database, even if you did this say a week ago or two weeks ago It's gonna get it wrong.
Rym: So with Java it's the same thing.
Rym: So earlier this year North Korea and Morocco both decided Morocco.
Rym: Yeah Morocco both decided to change.
Rym: Morocco mole their time stone stuff for no reason.
Rym: Egypt also did earlier this year multiple times and Mongolia, yeah, so Mongolian when North Korea?
Rym: If you had to deal with it You better have Java 6 105 Java 791 or Java 865 Installed if you want to deal with the turkey thing that just happened.
Rym: Well, no, there isn't even a Java update for it yet.
Rym: Meaning you get a run the TZ update Application which is included in your JRE.
Scott: It's a good thing that almost nobody has to deal with this.
Scott: So almost everyone only deals with UTC and their local time.
Scott: However, this only what.
Scott: if you went on a vacation to Turkey right now and brought your phone with you And you got off the plane you looked at your phone and go fuck you get the time wrong.
Rym: Young people explain on the way home, you know, it was trending in Turkey.
Rym: What time is it?
Rym: People are making fun of this all day.
Rym: yeah, but So the this pretty much only happens in countries that have bad tech governance.
Rym: or on Governance, I mean look Turkey North Korea, Morocco.
Scott: Here's the great government that is busy spending time messing with its time is a government that is not really good.
Rym: an individual Mexican state made a change at one point.
Scott: that actually affected me I mean, but in the u.s.
Scott: I can't even happen.
Scott: the federal government controls times.
Rym: Yeah NIST and everything, right?
Rym: So I'm gonna read to you the okay in Mexico.
Scott: They don't have it that way.
Rym: I'm gonna read you the update from the Moroccan one from TZ data 2015 e Quote.
Rym: Morocco will suspend DST from 2015.
Rym: Oh 614 3 a.m.
Rym: Through 2015.
Rym: Oh 719 2 a.m Not 613 and 718 as Guest.
Rym: They don't even maintain it.
Rym: the person who maintains the zone files in Java had guessed at what they were going to do And then the government did something different.
Rym: So yeah, you guys the moral of this news Is that a lot of the stuff on the back end of computers?
Scott: Well, as long as you haven't reached that time yet as long as like you have it Nothing's held yet.
Scott: You can guess and change the zone files as long as you don't reach that time.
Scott: Yeah, while you're wrong and you'll be okay, but all these updates?
Rym: There's no programmatic feed of this crap at the end somewhere in your Linux distro or in Java or in my SQL.
Rym: There's some dude like me who sees a government news release and says I'd better type a bunch of XML somewhere So other people can get that up.
Scott: There is the website.
Scott: that is the time news.
Rym: Yeah, so someone's got to type that into all these different systems.
Rym: Yeah things of the day.
Rym: So you remember twitch plays Pokemon, which was a beautiful beautiful thing.
Rym: You should go put watch like five minutes of it just to understand the glory of this.
Rym: Don't watch the whole thing unless you're crazy.
Rym: but the idea was that twitch people could just type commands in and they collectively played Pokemon as though a million voices were Screaming at a screen and hitting buttons all at the same time and they did eventually beat the game.
Rym: It was kind of crazy.
Rym: this my thing of the day is twitch installs Arch Linux and the most.
Rym: the best part about this is that a bunch of people organized a botnet and they Basically took over the stream and partially installed Gentoo instead.
Rym: Sure.
Scott: Why not?
Rym: So I think this is wonderful.
Scott: Okay, do you know Todd Fry is Todd Fry?
Scott: No, Todd Fry is the person who made pac-man Oh for the Atari 2600.
Rym: Oh I saw a video.
Rym: Oh, I saw this video.
Scott: Yes So this guy Todd Fry, you know, everyone knows pac-man for the Atari 2600 is not a good pac-man.
Scott: it is the Atari 2600 was very limited in his technological capabilities and Could not produce the same pac-man that you played in the arcade.
Scott: Even the 7800 could only get close.
Scott: even the NES could only really get kind of close, you know for a lot of reasons I guess Super Nintendo could be perfect effectively mostly.
Scott: I'm sure some emulator nerds gonna be like no, it's off Bay You know, you got Mame.
Scott: it's fine close enough writing any s Galaga is an okay Galaga.
Scott: It's it's playable enough, right?
Rym: Atari pac-man was kind of infamous.
Scott: Sorry to Atari 2600 pac-man was bad, right?
Scott: You know, you don't want to play that It's not.
Scott: you know, it's not real pac-man.
Scott: Anyway, so somebody of course, you know years having it been since the 80s made a demo of Atari 2600 pac-man.
Scott: They just coded it themselves from scratch and it was vastly superior to the to the official Atari 2600 pac-man.
Scott: It had the right colored goes linked a lot less.
Scott: it flickered a lot less.
Rym: And when he's when the guys to have the right had the right made the anti flicker algorithm that he came up with, right?
Scott: So here at some convention or something, I don't know where this is Todd Fry the guy who made that old pac-man comes along and sees this demo of Somebody being like here's how you should have done it.
Scott: I'm better than you at programming.
Scott: take that Todd Fry and he's basically like wow Yeah, and he comments on it and he's like, holy shit.
Scott: That's this video.
Scott: So watch this.
Scott: This reminds me a lot by the way 8k.
Scott: Imagine you have 8k.
Scott: You got to make pac-man happen.
Scott: That ain't easy.
Rym: Yeah That used to be considered a lot of memory to think about that.
Rym: fuck Now that's that's smaller than like a page.
Rym: Yeah, like that's You can.
Scott: if you make a text file you can't address that little memory.
Scott: You just made 8k in like the space in the file system structure 8k.
Rym: you could type 8k of text and not that long.
Rym: Yeah, so this reminds me of that guy way back who took the code from ET and tweaked it to make ET Way better.
Rym: game too.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: But this is a brand is like a fresh game.
Scott: This isn't a remix in the meta moment.
Rym: The book of book was the wheel of time book one.
Rym: We're burning through those books tonight.
Scott: So I sort of slowed down a bunch cuz stuff.
Rym: Yeah, I think we both we should do a like special episode like beginning a book five and then you That's right around where I stopped.
Rym: So we should let's do a special episode at some point.
Rym: Yeah, just talk about those books like the continuing book club.
Rym: But yeah read the first book at least That's the last GeekNights book club book.
Rym: It's fantasy book the novel and We like fantasy novel.
Scott: you'll like this book.
Rym: Yeah Matt people learn to shut up by the fifth book mostly.
Rym: But uh, otherwise the next convention we've got is magfest.
Rym: We're definitely gonna be there.
Rym: I got my badge confirmed and my badge confirmed.
Rym: Did you fill out your business?
Scott: I filled out the form and I never heard anything since.
Rym: did you fill out the badge form?
Rym: That was like this is your badge.
Scott: I did not get one of those.
Rym: Yeah, you really need to respond to emails.
Scott: I didn't get any emails you.
Scott: well You've anyway just could probably filled out the form that you sent me a link to.
Rym: yeah Like two months after I sent it to you and then I have not.
Scott: and I you sent me an email and I have not Heard anything at all since then.
Scott: I have not received any email from anybody.
Rym: worst case I'll just do all the panels on my own if you can get a badge, but we'll be back.
Scott: So is out can I even get a badge?
Rym: Well, I promise.
Rym: well I promise we'll be at magfest doing a bunch of panels as part of the majors like we always do.
Scott: if I don't get bad Just won't go mag fit.
Rym: You wouldn't go I would go.
Rym: Anyway magfest is one of our favorite.
Scott: I'm saying it's so if it's sold out and they don't give me a badge You're not gonna hassle to go.
Scott: get one.
Rym: I'll bet you could scalp one for cheap.
Scott: I'm not scalping.
Scott: Well, that's pain in the ass anyway.
Rym: That aside we've got a patreon.
Rym: now as we talked about and if we hit our first stretch goal, I am re-releasing remastered all the original beta pre-release episodes of GeekNights for Everyone, but the two people who have found them because they are I mean I've told people it's just like.
Scott: it's seriously not hard to Find them if you just have common sense and whatever.
Scott: but Some people actually found them finally.
Rym: Yeah, eventually we get a like Like other people.
Rym: Yeah, but I'm gonna re-release them with some commentary.
Rym: if we hit our first stretch goal.
Scott: I guess how you commentate on a podcast of two audio tracks overlapping.
Rym: I'm gonna listen to it and before you listen to the thing I'm gonna talk for like five minutes about like how we made it and all the stuff.
Scott: So you're gonna alternate between talking.
Rym: you know, no, I'm not gonna alternate.
Rym: I'm gonna do a five minute thing and then you're gonna hear the episode.
Rym: I'm not putting that much effort Jesus you kidding.
Rym: But yeah.
Rym: and go to check out the patreon because we got a bunch of stretch goals One of which is we'll both literally we're not joking quit our jobs and make it nice full-time.
Rym: I don't think we'll hit that stretch goal.
Rym: But I'll beyond all that listen to GeekNights after the credits because now I have to do a stinger.
Rym: Every episode we do calling people out and doing something stupid and I have provided stupid things for every episode.
Rym: we've done okay, so a lot of people you know a lot of people we know a lot of people out there have smartphones with Shattered screens or other sorts of brokenness.
Rym: I mean you still use them.
Rym: They kind of work.
Rym: the batteries like dented the screen like there's an area on the touchscreen that doesn't work.
Rym: I know people have laptops were like half the screen literally doesn't display.
Scott: It's not just smartphones.
Scott: There's all kinds of stuff.
Scott: I mean you got people with like analog sticks and their controllers.
Rym: this snap Dude brought a laptop to ConnectiCon to do a panel good panel like smart, dude but he goes to plug in his laptop and he's like the VGA.
Rym: or can I look at it and the VGA port is Battered beyond recognition and I was like, there's no way you're plugging a VGA cable into that.
Scott: Yeah people like cables that are all frayed.
Rym: Yeah, I see USB cables that are just a bunch of like the four internal wires kind of on their own.
Scott: Yeah, people with really dirty mice and keyboards are discussed.
Rym: We're not talking about dirt though.
Scott: That's a whole Alright fine, they got one really cute.
Scott: some keys don't work.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know.
Rym: Yeah, I I've seen mice where a key doesn't work and people are totally okay with that.
Rym: Whoa So how does this happen?
Scott: people just don't take care of their shit, right?
Scott: It's like let's say I gave you Rym.
Scott: how much how much is your phone worth on the market?
Rym: my phone like a hundred and fifty Bucks, it's an old like nicely working Hundred fifty dollar phone.
Scott: What if I gave you a vase like a porcelain vase?
Scott: That was a hundred and fifty dollars worth.
Scott: How would you treat that vase?
Rym: I'd sell it immediately because vases are stupid.
Scott: You wanted a vase.
Scott: you had some flowers.
Scott: You actually needed to put in it.
Scott: It was a really awesome nerdy vase Alright, so there's a big difference there already.
Rym: that's gonna highlight the point of this thing you care about.
Rym: I know if I own a vase I don't put it in my pocket and carry it with me literally every hour of every day.
Rym: I put it in one place out of reach of bunnies and dogs and children and I never touch it except to dust it once A week.
Rym: the point is is that you don't blame your of a precarious shelf.
Scott: Yeah When you are handling it this valuable item that you care about you have a valuable thing that you care about When you handle it regardless of how often that is you handle it with some measure of carefulness and respect.
Rym: But there is already a difference in that.
Rym: the kind of most I mean a lot of people I know don't care.
Rym: Take care of their shit and that's a whole.
Scott: they don't take care of the shit in general.
Rym: Yeah, like it all like their lives.
Rym: Yeah, like Rick the party.
Rym: You need to get your shit.
Rym: get it all together.
Rym: I don't care if you put it in a bag or a backpack.
Rym: just get it all and put it all in one place.
Rym: See your shits together.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: But anyway Technology like smartphones you carry with you all the time you handle it like a hundred times more often than you handle it Still Extremely valuable it's you care about it a fuck ton and it worth hundreds of dollars probably.
Scott: So when you take it out of your pocket Don't just sort of like hold it between two fingers while you're holding an ice cream in the other hand.
Scott: Right, don't sort of you know do anything dumb with it, right?
Scott: Hold it carefully hold it close to you If you're in a crowded place, you just hold it far away from you.
Scott: So I'm just walk up snatch it run.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, you know be careful be mindful of this like.
Scott: imagine you're holding Like if you have a brand new iPhone 6s, right that's like hundreds of dollars.
Scott: six to eight hundred dollars probably right?
Scott: Let's say it's the top-of-the-line one.
Scott: Would you just hold six hundred dollar bills just like out there sort of in between two fingers in one hand, right?
Rym: It's like what is wrong?
Scott: But at the same time that's what I want to do with right if your hands are all dirty You're like maybe covered in like butter grease because you ate a big pretzel or something.
Scott: That was all buttery.
Scott: Don't reach and touch your phone until you wash your hands.
Rym: I guess the difference is with the phone.
Rym: I pull it out a lot and poke at it a lot because I'm doing stuff with it actively all the time.
Rym: Yes, I do as well, but I'm not gonna stop poking at it because I'm I mean I'll pull out biking and like fucks around with it.
Scott: But now I won't do it like for example biking if I need to.
Scott: if I my phone starts ringing while I'm biking I'll do a little pullover, you know stop and then take the phone out.
Rym: It depends already on where I am.
Scott: I don't have the phone in one hand Looking at it while I'm biking with like one hand on the handlebar paying attention to the phone.
Scott: That does never happens.
Scott: I've seen people do that.
Scott: No, I do that.
Scott: Don't do that.
Rym: But I do that when I'm on like the super wide empty bike lane that's separated from the road over on the west side.
Rym: I don't do that.
Scott: I see people doing that going over the bridge like uphill dude.
Rym: I saw a guy.
Rym: he was walking.
Rym: It wasn't even biking.
Rym: That was today.
Rym: on my way home I was standing in a light.
Rym: the light was red.
Rym: cars are just going by like you couldn't jaywalk like even though like Hardest core New Yorker would not jaywalk
Scott: cuz it's green light for the cars and this
Rym: dude in hipster glasses young, dude Literally is on his phone talking and just walks into traffic and a car almost hits him lays on the horn Swerves out of the way and he doesn't even look up.
Rym: He just keeps walking and talking on his phone.
Rym: It was amazing shit.
Rym: and then no so there's a lot of crowd of people cuz you know rush hour.
Rym: She hit him.
Rym: so he gets to the sidewalk and there's a wall of people who are all staring at him And there's no way through and he literally shoves his way through the crowd of people Mumbling and goes on his way.
Scott: dude if he shoved me I would like that would have been it.
Scott: once someone shoves you that's like like license I used to kill.
Rym: thing is I ride the seven to work so I get shoved enough and my I also shove.
Rym: in return I give him.
Scott: I would give him a little leg sweep Like sweet, but who would?
Scott: he would know who did it.
Rym: so Here's the thing I've realized.
Rym: there's a fundamental thing with phones that are sort of different from all the other tech Is that it's a giant screen, but you also carry with you all the time.
Rym: So here's my rules.
Rym: number one.
Rym: You need to take a real hard.
Rym: Look at yourself and decide something.
Rym: Are you capable of?
Rym: Exhibiting basic amounts of dexterity and not dropping your phone all the time?
Rym: You need to honestly answer that question.
Rym: if the answer is no you are not capable.
Rym: Put your phone in one of those stupid heavy-ass cases that makes it twice as big and pay for Apple care.
Rym: Like don't pretend that you're not gonna break your phone.
Rym: you broke the last four.
Rym: It's time to realize the thing is.
Scott: I see people getting cases.
Scott: It's like it's like no you shouldn't get a case.
Scott: You should change yourself and not be a clumsy oaf.
Rym: But the reality is there are people who cannot change themselves.
Scott: and my advice to you You don't deserve to have a phone if you're a clumsy oaf.
Rym: you shouldn't be carrying around $600 and there is a market for this.
Rym: you pay for Apple care.
Rym: They just don't care anymore.
Rym: Just drop your phone all the time.
Rym: You're just paying a lot more money than I am.
Scott: Yeah, that's bad, I mean if you saw someone being so wasteful like I don't give a shit.
Scott: I'll just break my car and buy a new one.
Scott: I'm so good so much monies then that's a bad person.
Rym: Yeah, what I find is that in general the people who who have I don't need to take care of my phone.
Scott: I'll just buy expensive case or buy a new phone and pay over Apple care.
Rym: Well the thing is I use my phone naked.
Rym: I decided a long time ago I want my phone to be small.
Scott: I got a case when I had the iPhone 3g originally cuz like.
Scott: I didn't think about it And then after a while I just kept take.
Scott: I took the case off and then I took the screen protector off and then I haven't put a protector on Since and the only time I had a problem was when my my phone was Assumedly safely like inside my bag and I fell off my bike like a dumbass not getting hit by anything Just falling like a stupid.
Scott: Yeah, the phone happened to be on the falling side.
Rym: I mean sometimes phones in a bag like sometimes phones just break like literally my old Nexus 4.
Scott: The screen shattered when nothing was happening there, you know, there's always an excusable situation for breaking right.
Scott: for example Maybe it exploded like there's a bad battery.
Scott: It happens.
Scott: It's happened more than once.
Scott: maybe It's just defective.
Scott: I mean I had the home button not working situation.
Scott: I had to get a recall, right?
Scott: That wasn't my bad.
Scott: That was you know, it's a recalled device.
Rym: They made it wrong, but like my Nexus 5 has a crack in the bottom.
Rym: You know why cuz it wouldn't fit?
Rym: because it was too big and it wouldn't fit in the case.
Rym: I put my Nexus 4 in when I used to run and I was in Hong Kong and I wasn't gonna not run.
Rym: So I went running in the mountains just holding my phone in my hand And of course, I fucking like fell down the mountain broke the bottom of my.
Scott: there are other weird situations, too.
Scott: like your phone is safely on a table and You know, it's it's perfectly safe in a safe place someone else knocks an expensive vase over and it Somebody just spills a soda from like a ridiculously long distance away and it gets your phone wet.
Scott: and that's the end, right?
Scott: It's kind of stuff can happen and even you know It's okay if that kind of thing happens that it happens all the time.
Scott: It's life.
Scott: accidents are not completely avoidable.
Scott: However, there are many situations for which there is no excuse.
Scott: For example, your screen is scratched the fuck up because you put your phone in the same pocket with your keys.
Rym: I don't understand that.
Scott: that is just like my boss did that and he just got a new phone.
Scott: He's like, I'm not putting it in the pocket with the keys anymore Like I would never use one because I just think they're silly.
Rym: but I can understand the rationale of someone using one of those like Thick cases that protects their phone, but the people who put those little like thin screen protectors.
Scott: I did that originally and then I took that off because I was like, wow, this is dumb.
Rym: I mean it is real hard to scratch that glass already like you got to work at it.
Scott: I've had an iPhone 3g and iPhone 4 and iPhone 5 and I'm an iPhone 6 and all of those phones.
Scott: The only time any of them was ever in a case was the original iPhone 3g for a few months and the only one that ever broke was the iPhone 5 when I fell off my bike and I was able to get it repaired because all that really happened was like the.
Scott: The screen wasn't even broken.
Scott: It was just like dented in the metal in the back and the van.
Scott: the cable connecting the screen to the you know board got Sort of pulled out.
Scott: So these are just reconnected it and put my phone back together and it was fine until the iPhone 6 came out and I replaced It.
Scott: so I've gone that long without ever and I know why you're conflating breaking and scratching.
Scott: I've dropped my phone many times.
Scott: like you get out of bed in the morning You reach over and try to get off the nightstand.
Scott: He's not get onto the floor.
Scott: You're like that kind of shit happens and my phone is still in perfect condition.
Scott: despite that Part of what kind of drop do you need to have?
Rym: well part of a break like.
Rym: I saw some things where someone took a Nexus 5 and they showed like if you drop it and It lands on like certain spots the screen just shatters But at one degree angle different and it's totally fine.
Scott: They measured it with like a Caliper.
Rym: they know they were doing that Consumer Reports style like they shot it out of this little like slingshot gun.
Scott: How do they know?
Scott: it wasn't just because that was the third or fourth drop?
Rym: No, they used a bunch of different phones like they were doing stuff But the I don't know that one wasn't a defective one the scratch phone.
Rym: There is no excuse for scratching The screen on a phone.
Rym: it can't happen unless you turn it face down on the cement and move it around Just like take it to the beach just like roll it around.
Scott: Why did you take your phone to the beach?
Rym: I do in a ziploc bag.
Scott: That's totally works I guess in a zip like bag, but you know what?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: You're gonna leave your really expensive phone just sitting by the chair where you go in the water.
Rym: I'll pick it in the water with you.
Scott: Uh No, don't do that.
Rym: The Nexus not the Nexus the Sony Xperia's 100% waterproof.
Scott: That's pretty good.
Rym: Yeah, like that's actually great.
Scott: Like you can just dunk it in an ocean.
Rym: Yeah 30 meters go.
Rym: Well, so the warranty.
Rym: they say no salt water because you know reasons but the reality is it's totally fine.
Scott: Yeah, I when we actually went to the wedding.
Scott: I had my phone in my pocket I forgot it was there and I started to walk into the water and then I said, oh no But you know what.
Scott: I've gotten my phone like wet on occasions Like I've been out in the rain with the phone and I got a whole bunch of drops of rain on like crazy heavy Like a few months ago.
Scott: never has it been wet enough to cause it to malfunction in any significant fashion whatsoever.
Scott: So a few months ago, you have to really get your phone about to make water hurt it.
Rym: I was feeling kind of shitty like like getting sick.
Rym: So I just took a long hot shower and while I was standing in there for like five minutes Just like I was holding my phone in my hand out of the water.
Rym: Just like reading Fark Mm-hmm, and then I sneezed.
Rym: I just dropped my phone just right into the stream of water whoosh submerged And I went out and I picked it up and I wiped it off.
Rym: totally fine.
Scott: So it's like to get to ruin your phone with water.
Scott: it's like whoa, what did you do?
Scott: Yeah, like did you just throw it in a swimming pool?
Scott: Did you just put it in the safe?
Rym: Well, I used to not understand the people who would drop their phones in the toilet But then I noticed something.
Rym: a lot of the old people I know they wear their smartphones and holsters on their belt.
Rym: That's like blackberry style and it'll just pop out of those holsters.
Scott: Yeah, like boop the blackberry holster actually lets the blackberry know when it's in the holster that does with a magnet.
Scott: Yeah, anyway, so it's not just.
Scott: it's not just phones even though it's the most broken thing, right?
Scott: It's all kinds of stuff.
Scott: I see people laptops that are beat the fuck up and it's like what the hell?
Rym: No, if you have a Toughbook and that's the point like you take it to the beach.
Rym: Okay, cool.
Scott: But like I see like I have my all my laptops forever.
Scott: The only damages have been done to them is stickers added.
Scott: Yeah, they've not been.
Scott: the army keys popping off the keyboard I don't have any you know like the back of the Plastic chipping off like nothing has ever happened to it to break it in any way.
Scott: and all I can think is number one.
Scott: Most of the times I see this it's people with like really fragile a crappy laptops from like aces.
Rym: Yeah, those things like you like.
Rym: I've dropped my Lenovo laptops Significant distances and they've been fine.
Rym: I've seen aces that broke because you put them in your Timbuktu bag next to a single book.
Scott: Yeah, don't buy pieces of junk, but I've seen Mac books that are basically like steel Our aluminum I guess and people are denting the hell out of them.
Rym: and it's like what did you do?
Scott: You put it in a bag nicely, you know, you don't have to.
Scott: you just toss it in the bag.
Scott: You don't have to like, you know, and then you know.
Rym: You do the same thing.
Rym: tight phone.
Scott: put it back in the bag.
Scott: They don't throw it in a lady slamming it down in the table.
Rym: I've seen this piece the same thing below the phones.
Rym: when they scratch them up They don't put the laptop in a case or something and slide it into their bag.
Rym: They toss it into a big open backpack next to a whole bunch of stuff like their phone and they're all banging into each other so To turn the show away from.
Rym: we're just superior to you.
Rym: and an actual advice.
Rym: But we are here are rims rules of not breaking your phone.
Rym: one get a smart watch.
Rym: You don't take it out of your pocket all the time.
Scott: That's a smartwatch does prevent reduce the amount of number of times you take the phone out of the pocket which thus Reduces the number of opportunities you have or breaking the phone by taking it out to.
Rym: if you're taking out of your pocket Hold on to it before you take it out.
Rym: Most people who like I see people drop their phones literally every day and all that happens.
Rym: They put their hand in their pocket They pull it out and then they immediately drop it as soon as it comes to their hand comes out of their pocket.
Rym: I don't know how that happens.
Rym: Just don't do that.
Scott: That's my advice Don't touch your phone if there's anything wrong with your hands, right?
Scott: Like if you just worth having a snow fight or if you just were covered in sand.
Rym: You're just eating.
Scott: if you're just needing some dough in the kitchen or you know any kind of thing on your hands.
Scott: Maybe you're like, you know rubbing some butter on them for some fun time.
Scott: Whipped cream action, right.
Scott: if your hands are messed up in any way Don't touch the phone.
Scott: wash them and get them nice and okay before you touch the phone.
Rym: Never put the phone in any compartment with anything else ever Mm-hmm, unless it's like paper.
Rym: Yeah, they even that like don't like I. Why do people put their phone in the same pockets their keys?
Rym: Like.
Rym: are you a moron?
Rym: You've got more than one pocket, what's it?
Rym: all those other pockets?
Scott: It's like I put my.
Rym: I've got at least three or four pockets on every pair of pants.
Rym: I own up But don't put your phone in your back pocket.
Scott: You're gonna sit on it.
Scott: Yeah, I don't put anything in my any back pocket ever.
Rym: I put my wallet back there.
Scott: I do not.
Scott: that causes weird sitting.
Scott: No, it doesn't even with a tiny wallet.
Scott: It causes a weird sitting one.
Scott: My wall is tiny and even if it doesn't cause weird sitting you don't have this thing shoved in Squeezing into your bow to buy nice pants.
Rym: The back pocket is shifted a little bit away from the pelvic bone and up So you're not actually sitting on it.
Rym: It's like to the side of the butt when you sit down.
Scott: So now if someone walks by they just take your wallet right now cuz they're fucking tight pants.
Rym: I didn't buy you to get your hand into my pants and get that.
Scott: That's going in the thread Plus.
Rym: honestly if I'm in a place where Pickpocketing is a real possibility, which is not common anymore in most places I shift it to the front pocket while I'm standing there.
Scott: everything I have is always in the front pocket always.
Scott: Why why not?
Rym: front left pocket keys.
Scott: front left pocket phone.
Scott: front right pocket wall.
Rym: back left pocket nothing.
Rym: Back right pocket nothing.
Rym: if I have a piece of paper like a boarding.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: Maybe yeah.
Rym: extra thing goes that maybe Occasionally, I'll shift the phone to the back pocket while I'm walking upstairs because phones are too big and I can't bend my leg that Much if with tight jeans, but it goes back into the front pocket immediately afterwards.
Scott: My keys I say a front right pocket wallet front left pocket phone keys Go into a different place.
Scott: Like if I have my messenger bag my keys are on the low.
Rym: Yeah, the dog did they?
Rym: we meet right?
Rym: He's go somewhere else if you got a.
Scott: but maybe I'm going somewhere wearing a coat.
Scott: I'll put the keys in the coat pocket or maybe I'm going somewhere on a bike.
Scott: Little thing on the bike Jersey.
Scott: It's like the keys always go in the extra place And if I have to I can stick them in with the wallet in the right pocket.
Rym: the phone goes by itself no matter what?
Rym: And you never put it in the back pocket and then sit on it.
Rym: Yes, like just don't do that.
Scott: Don't?
Scott: uh There's really no other rules like don't Be forceful with stuff treat it like that's a vase and be careful.
Rym: I mean, I see people holding their phones with death.
Scott: imagine I look at whatever device you have near you whatever kind of thing you have that you care about.
Scott: maybe your watch your phone You know your laptop, maybe your TV in your house, or you know any kind of electronic gadget you care about your camera Right with your expensive lenses on it, right?
Scott: Imagine right now you close your eyes.
Scott: imagine that thing like breaking like like so broken.
Scott: that is beyond repair Like got hit with a sledgehammer.
Scott: It's broken super broken now.
Scott: Imagine how upset you are that this thing is broken.
Scott: How upset are you?
Scott: Okay, if you want to avoid being that upset be fucking careful.
Rym: Of course, there's also another split here between devices that require maintenance and devices that do not.
Rym: there's no maintenance to do on your phone It's just a phone that's true.
Rym: But like my computer the other day I went to render GeekNights and it took way longer than usual took 10 minutes to render out the episode.
Rym: I was like, what?
Rym: What?
Rym: So I look and my processor was clocking it like 1.6 gigahertz.
Rym: Okay, that's a full gigahertz left less than what it is supposed to be running at.
Rym: Hmm.
Rym: So think then My computer just needs to be cleaned out.
Rym: One of the fans is not spending that.
Rym: well I just don't have efficient.
Rym: It's time to clean my computer.
Rym: Most people I know Not clean yeah, not gonna name any names but certain people who live in Pennsylvania that I know.
Rym: Your computers inside of them have entire civilizations brought from the dust of eras long past mites The might kingdom mighty Kingdom.
Rym: Yes So dude, if you have an electronic device Learn if it requires maintenance or not.
Scott: And this applies to even things that you like wouldn't think about like I have a Clippers to shave my head.
Scott: the same one Barbara has that little book that came with it probably said like put oil in this spot You gotta grease that shit up once in a while according to the instructions, right?
Scott: I mean like almost the digital camera.
Scott: the sensor like got to be clean once in a while if anything got in there.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, you know lenses.
Scott: You got to clean them at least a little bit.
Scott: You know the cleaning that much right?
Scott: But yeah, but you know, they almost everything that you have.
Scott: I mean I had cast iron pot that came with maintenance instructions.
Scott: follow those.
Rym: Yeah, but like phones don't like.
Rym: there's nothing to do except my old palm free.
Rym: I actually needed to be taken apart and dusted regularly because of poor design Like I opened it one day and it was full of dust like a computer.
Scott: I I was getting yourself a can of air.
Rym: Yep, I was dumbstruck by that.
Rym: I'm Seriously though most of you can't take our advice.
Rym: and if you're gonna keep breaking your stuff My advice to you is if the stuff that you keep breaking matters to you pay for the Apple care equivalent How many like 3ds is you see?
Scott: you like snap screens and shit?
Rym: Yeah, my 3ds lasted for a long time.
Rym: But finally the screen.
Scott: you broke it on purpose.
Rym: No, I'm not gonna replace it.
Scott: Oh you even broke another one.
Scott: You're the fear that clumsy?
Scott: Oh breaking new 3ds.
Rym: I've never broken a 3d.
Rym: I've never broken my my original fat DS.
Scott: I've never broken any Nintendo portable gaming platform.
Rym: my original fat DS broke.
Rym: my old regular DS made it until like about a year ago And it still mostly works fine.
Rym: But like one corner of the screen goes all flickery weirdly and I think like the LED is dying there like something weird is happening to it.
Rym: Not that I really need it anymore because I got my 3ds Which is fine working like a champ and I don't really use it because I've played every game I care about on it.
Rym: There aren't new games that matter.
Scott: Why don't they make Mario maker for assholes?
Rym: That would be great.
Rym: There's rumors of the next console being good, but I'm probably gonna get it if it's Wii U compared I might also get it.
Rym: It's looking.
Rym: that might be that that might be the return to the console lands vermin Scott.
Scott: No, I'll just play the few games on it.
Scott: Like I did with every Nintendo console and be done with you.
Rym: No, you return to the console and like on a vacation.
Rym: You're not gonna live there.
Rym: You live in PC land.
Rym: But stop breaking your shit.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Rym: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night and so the Odyssey into dumb things that I can think of putting at the end of episodes continues as Per our new patreon reward tiers quote.
Rym: This is super dumb But if you support us this much Rym We'll say your name at the end of each episode after the credits along with some ultra dumb stinger content.
Rym: We're talking rims.
Rym: YouTube likes dumb.
Rym: so without further ado in order of the money that you're giving us the People above the arbitrary line I set in the sand are Rebecca Dunn Nicholas Brando James David white Christian Koontz Jessica L Barlow mechanical mind Rym eats poop Edgar Mendez William Eisen rose Chris midkiff Chris Knox flame Darkfire Samuel Cordery Daniel Redman Chris Haddad Doug Snyder Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: and Now I present for your enjoyment something really dumb But.