Rym: It's Thursday, December 10th, 2015.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: jobs Every single one of them.
Rym: Let's do this Basically two movies we're gonna see in theaters in the near future because usually it kind of either pirate stuff or wait for it to Come home, or I watch movies on planes a lot.
Rym: I mean the last movie I saw in a theater that I was like Deeply invested in seeing in the theater was Fury Road.
Scott: It usually it takes a real lot to get me to go to a movie theater.
Rym: saw the Martian in the theater And I'm glad I did but seeing it at home would have been pretty much as good.
Rym: I just wanted to see it, but Fury Road was definitely worth seeing in the theater.
Rym: Yeah, so and if when it comes back to theaters for when you know as like the marathon before Fury Road 2 comes out in a few years I'll go see it in the theater again So I can go see.
Scott: there's gonna be Star Wars which is pretty much what it takes.
Scott: you get to me to go to.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I'm not gonna see Star Wars an opening night.
Scott: No, how would I do that?
Rym: I saw I went saw a fucking Phantom Menace opening night.
Scott: You know what I didn't do that either.
Scott: It's not like.
Rym: the day or two after might have been worth it if Phantom Menace hadn't been terrible Still cautiously optimistic about Star Wars.
Rym: But I'm gonna see it when I can just buy a ticket at the theater that has assigned seating like 84th Street.
Scott: Yeah, it's gonna be.
Scott: you can be able to see.
Scott: it's not going anywhere Right, it's like it's gonna be in that theater for a while.
Scott: You can just go see it If it's good, and you know what if it's bad you can maybe avoid it.
Rym: Yeah, cuz you know what if the like if the initial I don't I mean like.
Scott: I have hopes in meaning.
Scott: I want it to be good, but I don't have any expectations.
Rym: my expectation is Probably below average if people I trust see the Star Wars movie and say it's bad.
Rym: I'm not gonna go see it in the theater.
Scott: Uh You know it depends on people.
Rym: I trust Scott like it's certain of our friends.
Scott: I don't trust hardly anybody.
Rym: Yeah, what it?
Rym: what if?
Scott: oh wait?
Scott: Maybe I can trust my one snooty co-worker.
Scott: I can trust him.
Rym: No Would you trust me?
Rym: What if I was like it was a garbage movie?
Scott: Well?
Scott: I mean you know I don't know.
Rym: But the other movie that we got to get tickets to is the 70 millimeter three hour long.
Scott: Hateful eight right so normally.
Scott: I wouldn't go see a Quentin Tarantino movie in the theater.
Scott: I didn't see Inglorious Basterds in the theater.
Rym: well remember.
Rym: I saw Django.
Scott: I didn't see Django in the theater.
Rym: I saw Django in the theater, but I saw it in the shitty Jewish theater in the bad part of Queens.
Rym: So that's worse than your home, but no so because that theater is so shitty.
Rym: I Thought the movie was kind of out of focus and had this bad film grain on purpose.
Rym: And I did not know that was not true until I saw a YouTube clip of the movie, and I was like oh That was just authentic that wasn't?
Rym: that wasn't on purpose movie I see.
Scott: the only movie I saw in that theater the tiny theater and queen in Flushing Main Street is James Bond.
Scott: the world is not enough My grandma when it was near this.
Rym: the only other movie I saw at that theater was the Avatar movie the bad one not that not the blue people one.
Scott: Okay, the only reason I didn't walk out the blue people one is man.
Rym: I liked it was a good movie solid sci-fi ish movie.
Rym: Yeah But no that that avatar movie.
Rym: the only reason I didn't walk out is that I had no way to get home So I needed a ride so I'd wait for the movie to end.
Scott: I found out that one of my Newer co-workers is like a super fan of the blue people avatar like.
Scott: he's like man.
Scott: when that was out I thought it was the coolest thing.
Scott: I was buying stuff.
Scott: It was my wallpaper on my desktop.
Rym: Wow well You know I was kind of like.
Scott: I didn't realize anyone was that into that movie.
Scott: But I guess someone is.
Rym: it's weird to see someone who's very into like.
Rym: one movie like Mad Max is different Yeah, but like series of movie I guess there's a kind of person who like changes their desktop background ever like every time the newest.
Scott: I mean go see what you know this trailers for right now right pick one of those things this someone who's like.
Scott: I'm like a fan of whatever it is, but Eight I have to see in the theater because it's in 70 millimeter.
Scott: Otherwise I'd wait for it to.
Scott: you know it's like.
Scott: I fucking love Quentin Tarantino movies But I don't think I've ever seen any of them in the theater.
Rym: I think I saw Pulp Fiction in the theater, but I don't know if I might have seen Kill Bill in the theater.
Rym: I saw both Kill Bill movies in the theater.
Scott: I might have seen them both, but other than that It's like dude.
Scott: I you know.
Scott: they're just fine to watch at home even though Quentin Tarantino is like the biggest freakin You know like vinyl listening film using you know snob hipster Yeah,
Rym: but it's a bad format,
Scott: but the thing is if it's a 70 millimeter
Rym: Not
Scott: like this 70 millimeter, it's not like vinyl records where it's like.
Scott: oh I like that sort of thing.
Scott: right it is just better.
Scott: the film is so big Right and the it is.
Scott: so we aspect ratio is so wide.
Scott: if you watch that at home It's gonna be like this little sliver down the middle of your TV with like these two.
Rym: Yeah, you know what the aspect racing ratio is.
Scott: it's like one to three or so two point seven six to one.
Scott: So it's basically one to three yeah, which means you see my guy in order to watch this at home your teeth Imagine you have to have three TVs in a row And it would span it would take full height and it would go all across all three TV.
Scott: So if you put it on just one TV the top third and the bottom third of the TV screen are gonna be black.
Rym: Yeah, you're gonna have remember letterboxing.
Rym: well letterboxing in your yo dog.
Scott: This is why you have to see and you know I think he's gonna release a version that is like digital And isn't.
Scott: but why would you go see that?
Rym: yeah?
Scott: Yeah guys, there's not that many showing this To do what I always wanted, which is you know so many Hollywood movies.
Scott: It's like they all make them all 90 minutes because you know people have short attention spans especially adults.
Scott: these days It's fucking three hours motherfucker.
Rym: It's like There is an inner inner mission.
Rym: Thank God.
Scott: It's like dude.
Scott: You know it's like you.
Scott: look at all the great movies.
Scott: It's like most of them are fucking long even the old Star Wars movies like two hours.
Scott: right if I'm not mistaken Lawrence of Arabia like that's a fucking movie.
Scott: right.
Scott: bring it on.
Scott: I don't want to go to the movie theater and pay a fortune to sit there for 90 fucking minutes.
Scott: if I'm going there I want to sit there all.
Rym: goddamn day there might be an upper limit But I think that upper limit for me is got her damn wrong.
Scott: I mean yeah, okay There is definitely an upper limit, which is where if I have to leave to you know P or whatever.
Scott: But if you have two inner missions, I'm still good.
Scott: if you need a third then we have a problem.
Rym: I just realized I can't.
Scott: I think Lawrence of Arabia has two inner missions.
Rym: the thing is this movie because Tarantino is a fanboy of this stuff is going to use this.
Scott: The trailer already tells you it's gonna be just as good as his previous movies.
Scott: It had a little bit as you have to see this one in the theater because the trailer had a little bit of TV.
Rym: is Tiny that derp act like the certain kind of certain kind of acting that you'd see in like 90s westerns And I feel like it's going for that instead of for like older western style Just the way the actors talk to each other and the way they.
Rym: well.
Rym: We'll review the movie after it comes out.
Scott: I don't care.
Scott: I can read the cinematography well.
Rym: Yeah, because he's such a fanboy this movie You know is going to use every millimeter of that wide format to do Everything.
Scott: so imagine is three hours long and the film is gigantic right.
Scott: I heard that at the places that are actually you know Projecting the film they had to have like teams of people like carry it up the stairs because it weighs.
Rym: they deployed special Cameras.
Scott: well the projectors don't exist in a lot of places.
Scott: So they had to like get old projector parts from everywhere They could and like mangled projectors together, and you know if they're gonna go through the effort I'll go through the effort of watching it.
Rym: so if you don't live in a big city You just can't like.
Rym: it's not playing in that many places in that format.
Scott: Get in your car.
Scott: if you don't live in a big city you have a car and you can get to one.
Rym: There's like three or four places doing it in New York, so we're good.
Rym: We're good.
Rym: So in the news remember how yeah the last show we talked about how we saw two different people in cars Almost get hit by trains because people can't drive.
Rym: yeah got another train story Boston train on the t-line like.
Rym: it's just a little like local commuter train.
Rym: Yeah, well so passengers are on this train like this happened this morning.
Scott: So I mean the T is not as a subway But some of it is more commuter rally depending on the line you're on this.
Scott: this was this was a. some of the tees are Actually like buses that are underground, but this one's actually a train train.
Rym: Yeah, so it's like a big subway.
Rym: Okay, so people got on the train, and it takes off Skips its first stop.
Scott: is it going like no normal speed normal speed just.
Rym: Then it skips its second stop.
Scott: well I mean, that's a problem.
Scott: so people in the I mean if it skips what the regular subway skips one stop unannounced.
Scott: That's never happened to me and all the years that happened to me once I would push as soon as if that ever happened.
Scott: I would push the emergency talk to the engineer button immediately.
Rym: Yeah, so the only reason I didn't the one time it happened is because the whole crowd starts going rabble rabble rabble like immediately.
Rym: I push the button right away, and then an announcement comes on.
Rym: just like ladies and gentlemen due to Bubble bubble we're making stops.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, but that's that happens, but if they don't say anything it just skips a stop unannounced.
Scott: I'm pushing that red button immediately.
Rym: People who were in the car.
Rym: that is where the purse the engineer running the train is on car.
Rym: Yeah, I assume it's the front car.
Scott: I hope so.
Scott: otherwise how could they see?
Rym: They go and start like banging on the door to see what's up And then they realize there is no one in there.
Scott: there the emergency stop.
Scott: So if what?
Rym: the thing that everyone pulls for the wrong reason all the time like I got heartburn wait Are you telling me?
Scott: Are you telling me?
Scott: They didn't pull it?
Rym: No one pulled it.
Rym: the central office happened.
Rym: the central office cut power to the track and Stopped the train and then the train was stopped with no power.
Rym: So the people on the train started trying to break windows to get out of it.
Scott: No, aren't they emergency opening windows?
Scott: I just think the moral of the story instructions to how to open the door in an emergency think people in Boston Just might not be that bright Cuz.
Rym: if I were on this train one I would have pulled the emergency break as far as I know.
Scott: if I know there's no engineer I pulled the emergency brake and then I'd be like all right.
Scott: everyone in this car.
Scott: listen up.
Scott: Here's the instructions for getting the hell out of here, but I'm in New York.
Rym: I wouldn't need to because everyone in New York would react the exact same way.
Rym: We'd be fucking prying the door open with a little crank and we find me in the subway.
Scott: There's emergency exits that let you get back up to the street and they're well lit and then you can find where they are Pretty easily.
Scott: Yeah, especially if the electricity is off.
Rym: if I got trapped on a train I would risk it in the tunnels like I would not dude.
Scott: I'm like you.
Scott: when you're just in the train you can look out the window and say oh look There's a staircase that takes you up to 50 whatever Street.
Scott: Oh know that if I ever had to escape this train don't touch the third rail.
Scott: My biggest fear is that if you're in which is completely unrealistic is if you're in a tunnel and the tunnel just cracks open and All the river pours in nothing you knew about that.
Scott: No, but I mean that would be fucking scary as hell.
Scott: way to die.
Scott: who wouldn't want to go that way?
Rym: Yeah, I guess.
Rym: well, you'd probably just drown.
Scott: Yes, you would drown.
Scott: it would suck balls.
Rym: I'd rather drown than I don't know fire.
Rym: I think fire is worse than drowning.
Scott: I might try to kill myself before I drown.
Rym: How by drowning.
Scott: it's like smashing my head against the tree.
Rym: I don't think that would kill you before drowning.
Rym: did I?
Scott: Bad news?
Scott: Hope.
Scott: maybe they'd be like rocks caving in.
Scott: I can get crushed.
Rym: plus What if you get lucky and the water rushing in flushes the train car forward and that pocket of air holds out long enough For someone to come rescue you?
Scott: that would be so unlikely.
Rym: It's possible got a holdout.
Rym: Hope I Mean, what do you got to lose?
Scott: I guess I would be so.
Rym: yeah, there's debates of if this was Sabotage or if the operator might have.
Scott: could it be sabotaged?
Rym: So someone tampered with the dead man switch that's supposed to top that just stop the train if there's no one driving it.
Rym: Yeah, how did the trains drive because someone tampered with the thing that's supposed to stop the train if no one's driving it?
Rym: They said it was tampered with.
Rym: it was not an error.
Scott: Uh-huh, so who done it?
Rym: the operator who's supposed to be driving it is apparently out administrative leave and there's an investigation.
Rym: All right, my guess people are saying oh maybe terror or whatever.
Rym: now my guess is dude jury-rigged it so we didn't have to hold it the whole time while he drove it normally and Accidentally like let it go when he wasn't there the train just left.
Rym: that's gonna make you don't like the people who you know The thing on a lawnmower.
Rym: if you let go of it the blade stops.
Rym: Yeah, and you know everyone just wraps twine around that.
Rym: So it's always up.
Scott: No, we did not do that.
Rym: I did not either Scott, but you know what?
Rym: And most people Disable that as the first thing they do when they get a lawnmower.
Rym: Go to go to the Midwest pick any random garage You can walk right in.
Rym: everyone leaves their garage doors open and look at their lawnmower.
Rym: I practically guarantee they have jury rig something to prevent that safety mechanism from working.
Scott: Well, if you do that, you should go to a place that begins with a J or P Jeep.
Scott: no a J or a P jail or to prison Or The P pokey.
Rym: so an actual news L. I got an actual news - Scott had nothing I guess.
Rym: or the D dungeon Don't John?
Rym: About how about the lubliette?
Rym: That's Oh Or L.
Scott: Well, that that's it.
Scott: That'd be like saying T the jail.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So In other news cuz Scott decided that there is no news worth talking about I couldn't hire world.
Rym: So the other thing I got is a lot of people seem to be really invested in these quote-unquote hoverboards And I don't know why this is such a thing.
Rym: one.
Rym: These things are like two to six hundred dollars.
Scott: It's just like the new scooter.
Scott: as far as I'm concerned I don't give a fuck.
Rym: their cheap shitty pieces of plastic that putter along at about like four to six miles an hour Faster than walking.
Rym: No, it's not.
Scott: I saw a guy.
Scott: I mean I cried the One at full speed down the street.
Scott: I could have gone faster than him But only if I really so.
Rym: most of these things go four to six miles an hour.
Rym: My default walking pace as I confirmed one day on a treadmill by walking just at my normal speed and trying to see My default walking pace is five point one miles an hour.
Rym: These things go four to six.
Scott: So He was booking it.
Rym: the I'm saying most expensive of these can go up to 15 miles an hour Which is about like that's close to.
Scott: my buddy might have had that one because he was.
Scott: he was booking it.
Rym: Yeah, I would not move that in the street.
Scott: Not even the side.
Rym: I would not move that fast on a platform.
Rym: I'm standing on that.
Rym: I have very little control over dude.
Scott: I can't even stand on a skateboard.
Scott: So I'm definitely not standing one of these.
Rym: but the interesting thing is that these things like to just explode and catch fire and seriously Injure people because these aren't being manufactured by like, you know, someone who's like a high quality manufacturer of transportation equipment.
Scott: It's not like a bombardier.
Scott: Yeah It is a cheap Chinese knockoff, you know, it's what hoverboard.
Scott: Yeah, it's not Otis in order to have enough power to make something move, you know Like with a human being standing on it.
Scott: It can't be like weak in the battery department like a you know A knockoff third-party camera battery.
Scott: It's got to be like a serious fucking battery.
Scott: Like the thing is mostly battery.
Rym: Yeah, these things have batteries like those electric bikes have.
Scott: so you have a cheapo battery and a cheapo electric motor.
Scott: That is a recipe for the boom-boom.
Rym: so Yeah, these things just keep Exploding and seriously hurting people and cuz they're not being manufactured.
Scott: What high quality person is manufacturing.
Rym: So that's the interesting thing because I was poking around a little bit because a lot of people said oh don't buy a knockoff one Buy the real one.
Scott: What's the real one?
Scott: There is no real one.
Rym: They're all basically the same.
Rym: There's like four or five Chinese manufacturers who are making these things white and people are buying them white label and just selling them.
Rym: Yeah, there's zero quality control.
Scott: No, like, you know, at least with like say previous transportation devices.
Scott: It's like there's.
Scott: there's some brand that's like the real brand like, you know, there's the GoPro camera Yeah, there's the razor scooter and then there's the pro pro and the bazer right?
Scott: There's the segue.
Rym: segue Yeah, then there's the Sorni the magnet box, right?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: but for these there isn't a real brand Originated as a cheap knockoff and there's only knockoffs.
Scott: There's no real one.
Rym: They seem to have been embraced weirdly by the hip-hop community.
Scott: Alright, I thought it was in the same community of like using razor scooters like little teenagers and kids in the neighborhood.
Rym: I always I was doing a lot of research over lunch just cuz I was you know kind of cuz I found a Twitter feed that was just vines and videos of these things exploding.
Rym: but Basically as far as I can tell these are most popular among like Boring upper middle like the children of boring upper middle-class suburban people the razor scooter.
Rym: Yeah, okay and Hip-hop enthusiasts.
Rym: All right, like bunch of rappers are using for stuff.
Scott: That's totally cool.
Scott: You can rap while you're on this.
Scott: It's hard to rap on a bicycle.
Rym: you're huffing and puffing and you know and I can see that and I feel that style.
Scott: But you can.
Scott: you can zip on a stage of this thing and back.
Rym: Oh Be awesome, but why do we call them hover boards?
Rym: They're not boards.
Rym: They do not hover.
Scott: someone called it that.
Scott: I think I originally see what they are.
Rym: They're Handless segues.
Scott: I mean it the first time I saw one they actually called it by some other name dirt boards.
Scott: No, it's like.
Scott: I guess it might be the original name of it was like the something tech something I don't know.
Rym: Well, there's a few things like this is mono wheel thing Like?
Rym: this kind of thing has been around for a while and someone just decided to manufacture a bunch of super dangerous ones to start Selling them.
Rym: All right Yeah They're also technically illegal in New York.
Rym: I mean any kind of like.
Scott: the same is anything anything that is a powered transportation device That is not registered with the Department of Motor Vehicles like a car or a motorcycle or a truck is Illegal in New York, but some have a motor device that isn't registered with the Department of Motor Vehicles.
Rym: now simultaneously There are some exceptions for very specific classes of devices, but that excludes most things.
Scott: Exceptions are things like a power wheels for your kid as long as he stays in the driveway and the sidewalk.
Rym: I believe there's an exception for power assist bicycles as well, but I'm not a hundred percent sure.
Scott: I never heard of that one.
Scott: I found Conflicting reports of whether or not there's far as I know a powered by anything less than a moped can't be ready.
Rym: Oh, so there are rules around that.
Rym: Now where where bikes that have power assists are Okay, but bikes that just drive without any pedaling or not, okay I can't quite figure that out.
Scott: I mean just go to the DMV and get a little license.
Scott: the same one they can say it's a moped.
Scott: Just say that even if it's not and you'll be probably.
Rym: but that's the thing in New York City.
Rym: specifically if something Cannot is something is regulated and there's a thing that's like that thing But is not like that thing enough to be licensed the same way?
Rym: the answer isn't oh, it's okay.
Rym: Then the answer is it's illegal.
Rym: That's why airsoft guns are as illegal as real guns.
Scott: The thing that really bothers me is that people who want to use some weirdo transportation device on the road There's already a legal option and that is the three-wheeled motor vehicle.
Scott: Yeah As far as I know from everything I've seen in my life the truck in New York City and New York State if you have A three-wheeled vehicle.
Scott: There's pretty much almost no regulation and you can go to the DMV and get a license plate for it.
Scott: And like I've seen such a wide variety of three-wheeled vehicles It seems like there's basically almost no regulation on what it takes for that to be street-legal.
Scott: I've seen them without lights.
Scott: They have a license plate.
Scott: I've seen them like with the one wheel in the front the one wheel in the back all kind of wide real fucking wide like wider than one lane wide.
Scott: four wheels in the back two on each side with one big one in the front.
Scott: I've seen ridiculous shit and all of them have license plates and I've seen cops near a few of these.
Scott: not even give a shit Because apparently the law is such that if it's got three wheels you could do almost whatever the fuck you want.
Scott: So people put a third wheel on this fucking hoverboard.
Scott: Yeah, and we are good to go.
Rym: But I feel like this tech needs a little more iteration before it would be cooler for me to you.
Scott: I don't understand why there some company that's actually capable of manufacturing quality goods doesn't get in on this.
Scott: Yeah, I think part of the segue is too big.
Rym: this like segues are dumb even in conventions Like.
Rym: they just get in the way, but these would be great.
Rym: It's like an enforcer at PAX.
Scott: Well, I think part of the rule Is because if you made a good one like say be like a thousand dollars.
Scott: Let's say bombardier made one Yeah, or like who else could make one?
Scott: Suzuki could probably make one.
Scott: right people have the you know, the capacity Yeah thousand two thousand dollars.
Scott: that yeah It would cost so much money for the good one that everyone only the richest like, you know People would buy one and everyone in knowing normal people would buy what even couldn't sell enough.
Rym: They're selling these for four to six hundred bucks and that is not what they cost to make Especially cuz they clearly like.
Scott: I imagine you at the battery pack probably is Remember my my tablet video from before I imagined is just dogs breakfast I imagine is just a bunch of cheap lithium ion batteries all you know in a pack, right?
Scott: It's anything fancy tape together solder together.
Rym: Yeah anyway anyway things of the day Got a thing of the day.
Scott: I did remember one at the last second.
Scott: I already posted this in the forum, but if you're listening to the show you're probably not into the forum.
Scott: So yeah, you also probably don't go to packs apparently, but I digress anyway, so Way back in the 90s 1999 or 98 but actually no 99.
Scott: All right that phantom mean ass came out cuz it you know Star Wars time.
Scott: Let's talk about Star Wars.
Scott: Yeah, the Phantom Menace came out and you know, it was a big deal.
Scott: And at the time, you know There was people lining up outside movie theaters to get tickets or to see it including me and him and every other nerd who was alive then and conscious then and The news went to report on these long lines.
Scott: so somebody went and took News reports from those days and cut them up and made this little video here for you to watch.
Scott: And it shows Star Wars fans before going in being like oh, it's gonna be so good guys.
Scott: Oh good.
Scott: Oh, and then it shows what they said when they came out.
Scott: Oh and when they came out You'd be surprised pretty much all.
Scott: every single person was like, oh my god.
Scott: It was life-changing.
Scott: I'm gonna see it again.
Rym: Cuz I remember walking out of that movie.
Rym: it was me and a bunch of our friends.
Rym: we walk out.
Rym: No one was saying anything.
Scott: We were just at the end of this video.
Scott: There's one guy where They're like, how did you like it?
Scott: He's like not suck two thumbs down.
Scott: everyone had everyone else in the video.
Scott: Yeah This has resulted in people who like Phantom Menace saying look it's actually good all you people who don't like it are on the bandwagon.
Scott: You Would have liked it if it wasn't the situation where everyone else, you know didn't like it.
Rym: Yeah I can at least say cuz I.
Scott: and then the response to that is jar jar bangs.
Rym: I rest my case Because we were and we sat there silently.
Rym: the credits roll.
Rym: I think it was Greg.
Scott: I mean the movies not you.
Scott: mean if you want know the movie has good lightsaber battle good music That's a good lightsaber battle.
Scott: It also has a podrace.
Rym: the potteries was not great.
Rym: Yeah, I was not a fan.
Scott: This video is great.
Rym: So yeah, that video is great.
Rym: But I just remember Craig turned to us like everyone's in quiet.
Rym: He was like guys.
Rym: That wasn't that good was it?
Scott: Yeah, and we're all like nah, but what if Craig turned to you and said, oh man That was amazing.
Rym: Would you guys been like, yeah, I would have been like, who are you?
Rym: How did you?
Scott: Anyway, yeah, but they there's actually some articles going around lately which reminded me of something I knew and forgot which is that The current culture of movie trailers was started by the Phantom Menace.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: when the Phantom Menace had a movie trailer and you could only see it before a few different shitty movies like Waterboy and such and so I Pirated it from the internet cuz I knew the fuck.
Scott: I was like that trailer on the internet and the day after Lucasfilm put It on the internet and it was hard to get it But I knew what I was doing.
Scott: so I had it and that was like the first time anyone had ever watched a movie trailer Anything internet.
Scott: we downloaded this like, you know, it wasn't even an mp4 is an mpg file.
Scott: Yeah, I just an mpeg2 file, you know what that trailer?
Scott: it took a long time to download with our shitty 56k modems.
Scott: We watched it.
Scott: It was a big friggin deal I can you know, you had to have a good computer to be able to play the video file, you know.
Scott: And that was like a huge deal.
Scott: and ever and then ever since then You know that was when like the movie trailer thing Became a thing and you get apple.com slash trailers and I think you know According to some articles like by getting that the movie trailer thing going Apple got like 600,000 QuickTime downloads at once.
Scott: Yeah, it was a big deal.
Scott: so, you know nowadays you just watch movie trailers at apple.com trailers like it's nothing.
Scott: But Phantom Menace is the reason that that started.
Rym: so there this is a clip.
Rym: Emily found this and it's wonderful.
Rym: So, you know Margaret Atwood is right.
Scott: Yeah, I mean every friggin person in the world is like saying oh my god, Margaret I would read this book.
Scott: read that book.
Scott: Oh, she's making a comic about a bird man or what a bird cat boy.
Scott: And basically, I think she just got to be the next book club because it's just no one's shutting up about it.
Scott: So there's no avoiding it.
Rym: So there's this show that Emily found a clip from it and it's celebrity tips And this one is celebrity tip with Margaret Atwood.
Rym: So Margaret I would just like I'm a celebrity.
Scott: I'm gonna give you my tips on stuff that I know about but it's not tips on how to be a celebrity.
Scott: I know it's from a celebrity about whatever.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: So this is Margaret Atwood's celebrity tips on Being a hockey goalie.
Scott: Does she know about being a hockey goal?
Scott: Hey watch the video show.
Scott: Don't let the puck go in the net.
Rym: No, she talks about the five zones.
Rym: She talks about it's okay fucking people up She's big hockey fan.
Scott: Now she's definitely getting the next book club big for sure.
Scott: Sending your suggestions about which book of Margaret Atwood's is the most GeekNights.
Rym: Yeah, you know what.
Rym: tell us which one.
Scott: Don't.
Scott: tell us which one you like the most.
Scott: tell us which one the most popular.
Scott: Tell us which one is the most GeekNights.
Scott: I heard there's some that are cyberpunk ish.
Scott: So those are probably the ones.
Rym: Otherwise the meta moment the book club book was the wheel of time.
Rym: I'm still burning through those books but rims gonna pick some other book club book when you and then I'm gonna pick a Margaret Atwood book, yeah, and We're going to be live at Pac South with Atari game design and designing game rules.
Rym: Possibly a third panel gonna be a paxies MAGFest bunch of shit at MAGFest like so many convention Transportation and hotel things right now.
Scott: It's like super convention preparation season.
Rym: Yeah, Mike I it's gonna be conventions my Delta thing.
Scott: Really what it is is that for the first time nothing's overlapping.
Scott: right anime Boston PAX East aren't overlapping Magfest and PAX South aren't overlapping.
Scott: So it's gonna be huge.
Scott: It's gonna be mag fest PAX South PAX East anime Boston doom doom doom doom doom Yup, then Connecticut then and then PAX Australia, which is the.
Rym: the dates are out.
Rym: tickets are on sale.
Scott: We'll see about PAX Australia.
Scott: I might go to Essen.
Rym: I'm I'm pretty sure I'm going to PAX Australia one.
Scott: I can do an awesome thing Where I go to Europe look at the castles Then I go to Essen then I go to PAX Australia and then I go to California and then I go to New York.
Rym: You can pull that off.
Rym: I've circumnavigated.
Scott: I'll just be like work.
Rym: see ya I have twice in my life back like next month Scott.
Rym: I have twice in my life done a trip like that where I went all the way around the globe stopping on places along the Way, I got back to New York.
Scott: We can call it Scott Magellan.
Rym: Yeah Magellan 2016 I beat you.
Rym: you're gonna be the guy after Magellan that no one remembers.
Rym: That's fine.
Rym: Also Magellan didn't actually make it.
Rym: His crew killed him before they made it.
Rym: the rest of the way the boat made it.
Rym: the boat made it.
Rym: He did not.
Rym: you imagine.
Rym: they kill him like fuck this.
Rym: We're gonna go home stupid and then it get like a little bit further and they're like, oh, I guess we made it.
Scott: Well, Magellan is probably also a jerk.
Rym: I suspect Magellan was a dick.
Scott: I don't suspect.
Scott: I mean, did you ever get learned about a conquistador or an explorer in school?
Scott: That was like a super nice guy.
Rym: Awesome yeah, like Columbus makes a lot of them look like super nice guys by comparison.
Rym: and Finally the word the least worst one is I mean, I mean Cortez was the worst As far as we know.
Scott: the stories at least which are half fictional I guess dramatized.
Scott: Ponce de Leon was just a moron and not an evil.
Scott: Yeah, but I'm sure he was also a bad person.
Scott: Yeah Wasn't a good person with a hero.
Rym: and the patreon is ongoing.
Rym: We're getting really good questions for the December Q&A.
Rym: remember give any amount of money to our patreon.
Rym: You can listen to all these special episodes, but if you want to ask questions, you gotta pay.
Scott: I'm gonna start making a bunch of free content to compete with rims.
Scott: evil non free non open patreon content.
Rym: I'm bumping up the content.
Rym: rims rants is started.
Rym: Emily.
Scott: Are you creative Commons in this this pay content?
Rym: Uh Some of it.
Rym: Yes, because I put the closer on the end.
Rym: So I do by default but if the closer isn't there it's not technically Creative Commons.
Scott: Alright, well you just do whatever you're gonna do.
Scott: We keep doing it stuff that you're making.
Rym: she's gonna keep doing it.
Scott: But if I'm talk if I'm in it you have to create of Commons it because I said so, okay Yes, I am creative Commons lesson.
Rym: My tweets are not going to come.
Rym: if you treat me I will fucking sue you.
Scott: attribution only copy the Scott's all you want.
Scott: Yeah, I have my DNA as long as you just say it's got DNA.
Rym: But yeah, so keep submitting questions.
Rym: if I get enough questions I'm gonna shut the form down because I'm not gonna do.
Rym: we're not doing like a four hour Q&A episode.
Rym: There's like 11 in there right now already.
Rym: I opened it a few days ago.
Scott: You can just like when we do an episode if it gets too long.
Scott: We can just hold those questions off in the next month true.
Rym: Just start queuing them up on the list.
Scott: They'll be a queue.
Rym: Yeah a coup queue because no one understands the coup stuff.
Rym: Yeah, no one knows what the red envelope is.
Rym: Literally.
Scott: No one you can sort of guess just by One guy's.
Scott: I tell you that there are a box Questions and in some of the questions are in a red envelope and some are in a white.
Scott: but most of them are white.
Scott: You can surmise there is something special about the red one.
Scott: one person What could it be say?
Rym: cuz I scammed the question like skimmed him.
Rym: one person said their question was a red envelope question.
Scott: Was it actually?
Rym: they asked what we do on the holidays?
Rym: Oh, no red envelope Misinterpreting the red envelope.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: It's not because it belongs to Santa Claus.
Rym: So I never had a real job until after I graduated high school.
Scott: What counts as a real job?
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I think what I might say is part-time jobs.
Rym: I was a camp counselor a job where you file a w-4 every job.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: See I had real jobs in high school.
Rym: So I did not.
Rym: I never had a job that I paid taxes on Until after I graduated.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: I mean I only filled out an easy form, but I still filled it out.
Rym: Yeah Well, actually so before that I did have a job I didn't pay taxes on.
Scott: I gave and I guess I probably paid no taxes because I made so little money.
Rym: Yeah, I gave professional trumpet and French horn lessons to kids in like Sterling Heights.
Rym: Okay, cuz I was a really good trumpet player and I was actually apparently a really good trumpet teacher - you know much I charged for that in 1997.
Scott: dollars ten bucks an hour.
Rym: thirty bucks an hour.
Rym: and you know what.
Rym: you know who paid that Everyone.
Rym: I had as much work as I wanted all under the table.
Rym: statute of limitations is so far gone.
Scott: Oh, yeah, cuz someone's gonna really come out.
Scott: even if it would you did it yesterday.
Rym: come after my thousands.
Rym: Yeah, but my first actual legit real job right after I graduated high school I Realized this job.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I applied to work for the US government year 2000 census Counting.
Scott: such a great job.
Rym: Yeah, you know why cuz it paid like 15 bucks an hour job wasn't?
Scott: I don't think you had to go to Doors job.
Rym: That's the job I wanted.
Rym: Oh, really?
Rym: Yeah, but that's job everyone.
Rym: I don't think you want that job that pays 15 to 20 bucks an hour.
Scott: go to this.
Scott: go to Detroit In the neighborhood.
Rym: No, I would have been doing it.
Rym: you do it in the place you live So I would do it like in sterling heights.
Rym: Okay, that's how it works.
Rym: So but that was part-time.
Rym: It wouldn't have been enough money.
Rym: So I Took this government Functionary test.
Rym: you had to take a test to join the sense that you're gonna edit a plus on that test.
Rym: So I got a perfect score.
Rym: Yeah, the question the questions were like one plus one.
Rym: The questions were like here's a street address.
Rym: Can you read here is a simple map showing three houses?
Rym: Circle the house, which house does this address refer to?
Rym: and Apparently I got a perfect score like duh.
Rym: Apparently I was one of the only people who was above the line.
Scott: if you're allowed to hire this person I mean None of those people could like.
Scott: you know How many people play Zelda 1 and can't even find like the first Don Joan?
Rym: These these were questions like Johnny has seven apples and then gives four to Suzy.
Rym: How many does Suzy have?
Scott: Listen, you don't have a job and you're so desperate.
Scott: You're gonna try to work for the census.
Scott: You probably don't have a job for reasons.
Rym: So They called me and they're like, yeah we want how you run it the fuck away like before I was ready cuz high school was still going and I was like No, and my parents were like, uh, you should experience what work is like.
Rym: Also, you probably need some money.
Rym: So I was like, okay sure.
Rym: so I took the job.
Rym: So I went to high school 730 in the morning until 3 left.
Rym: high school went to work from 4 to midnight at the census.
Scott: I didn't realize it was that many hours.
Rym: It was a full-time job.
Rym: I did it for two weeks and then I said fuck this shit.
Scott: I'm out.
Scott: I quit.
Rym: And then they called me again after I graduated and said, uh You want to come back during the daylight.
Rym: and I said yes, and then I worked there until I quit.
Rym: I go to college.
Scott: And basically I guess they were still doing the census when we went to college.
Rym: So my job was basically to be an accounting and payroll clerk.
Rym: and let me tell you that Job is real hard for a lot of people to do like a lot of my co-workers.
Scott: Well, it's wouldn't you hire an accountant to do that job?
Rym: Uh So the census has to hire an entire.
Rym: so there was someone in charge who would like tell people what to do.
Rym: but the work was done by people who didn't need to know how it actually worked and Basically you were able to figure out how it worked.
Rym: I they ended up having keeping only me as the sole clerk for the entire office for the entire time because I could do in About 12 hours a week.
Rym: What took a team of people working for 40 hours a week to do previously?
Rym: and then I started also doing all their IT and basically everything in the office and It was really weird because it was all 40 to 50 year old like women who had husbands or were widows a few old people and This 18 year old punk kid nerd.
Rym: It was a weird experience working there.
Rym: What was your first job?
Scott: I worked at.
Scott: was I go to the dry cleaner for it?
Scott: No, I went to the summer camp first.
Scott: or did it summer camp first or dry cleaners first?
Rym: I don't remember.
Scott: and I was a summer camp counselor at two or three different places and then In high school, I worked at a dry cleaner.
Scott: after school I'd take the same bus that took me home would also if I just stayed on it go to the dry cleaner.
Scott: So I'd get off
Rym: like school bus sir
Scott: Yeah school bus and then I'd just go to the dry cleaner and I'd stay there until it closed like at 6 And then I just go home to my house and eat dinner and I do that like two or three days a week and then also like You know sometimes like Saturday like the be open like Saturday morning or something like until noon or whatever.
Scott: So I'd go in early on Saturday morning and then leave at noon, you know, then watch football or it's on whatever.
Rym: I guess there's always weird having those kinds of jobs like the not a career job For me because the jobs are always like really really easy and yet at the same time They pay almost enough to live.
Scott: it paid me enough that I bought a computer with that monies.
Rym: Yeah, I had some bonds my grandma T&T to video card when it was brand new.
Scott: I basically just saved all the money and bought a computer because I didn't have to buy food or rent or anything.
Scott: And summer camp was pretty much just like.
Scott: also money I didn't spend.
Scott: oh no, I think I used the summer camp money.
Scott: I bought a Gameboy color the day it came out and I bought you know And then I bought games for it a whole bunch all the games.
Scott: and then In college, I I think I did summer camp again in between freshman sophomore year Between freshman and sophomore year.
Rym: I went back home to Michigan.
Rym: I went home like they wouldn't let us live in the dorms over the summer and I worked Construction at a Kmart.
Scott: Oh, right that one because they were renovating Kmart's.
Rym: they hired construction workers to renovate the inside of this Kmart and That job paid way less than the census and summer camp counselor pays almost nothing.
Scott: you get one check at the end of the job and it's like for hunt.
Scott: it's like not a lot of money at all and The thing is all the money that you know, you you're not an hourly worker It's like being a waiter or waitress whatever but you what you get in return is basically free summer camp Which cost a fortune right?
Scott: You get all that food all that lodging all that You know all those trips that you go on.
Scott: you get to swim in the pool.
Scott: You get to play baseball To do all this shit, right?
Scott: So that's why that's a good job.
Scott: I lied and I would totally just be summer camp counselor forever if I could live like that.
Rym: I actually applied with my brother and we both worked at that place.
Rym: like at that came our doing construction that whole summer.
Rym: I lied and Basically said I wasn't going to college and I just graduated high school to get the job Because there's no way they would hire me if they knew I was going to college September you would leave.
Rym: Yeah, and that job was probably the worst experience of my life other than food poisoning.
Rym: Yeah, Lyme disease and food poisoning.
Rym: just because like it was soul-crushing to work So hard doing physical labor for 40 to 60 hours a week making 7 bucks an hour.
Rym: Yeah, but just it.
Scott: folding clothes and throwing a bag and the weirdest thing was like putting number two tags on shirts.
Scott: The people got the right shirt back.
Rym: people I had to work with.
Rym: like there was a break room and I go hang on the break room your 15-minute breaks and your 30 minute break.
Rym: and They were like I don't want it like they were just the worst people Like they all smoked everyone smoked so they'd all take smoke breaks all the time.
Rym: most of them had graduated from the same high school as me, but Had run up a bunch of credit card debt somehow and had the job to try to pay off all their thousands and thousands of dollars of credit card debt.
Rym: For I guess I don't know how they racked up all those credit.
Scott: We need to save money to eat also and they use some of the money to pay the payments on the credit card.
Rym: understand And I just like I literally there was.
Rym: no I I gave up trying to have conversations with anyone there and I Considered just quitting and not having money.
Rym: That's how soul crushing that experience was like.
Rym: I was very willing to not have money Rather than continue to do this work somewhere else.
Rym: I was in the suburbs in Michigan.
Rym: No one was hiring.
Rym: Okay, there was nowhere to work.
Rym: I also applied to work at that time at a Boston fucking market.
Rym: I had no trouble finding because that paid $12 an hour, but they wouldn't hire me because I was going to college.
Rym: So when I applied to the construction job, I lied different restaurant Scott.
Rym: no one was hiring because Most of the jobs were being taken by people who did not escape the orbit of that suburb Had just graduated high school and needed a job.
Rym: that was going to be their real job.
Scott: Anyway, I At college I worked in The crossroads.
Rym: Oh, yeah, you made me a sandwich.
Rym: I remember your opening night when you were working there like the first day like we all came over and we all heard of sandwiches.
Scott: I would make sandwiches that were way more meat than you were supposed to put on there
Rym: Yeah,
Scott: and I was the awesomest but then eventually after a long time of working there They're like, all right everyone actually used the fucking scales and then I switched over and worked in the grilling area instead and Then I stopped working there because I found I got an office II job.
Rym: Wow.
Rym: I'd pretty much the same thing.
Rym: I mean I worked at that the Ritz until I quit in disguise.
Scott: I didn't quit it Just sort of lapsed.
Scott: and in the summer, right?
Scott: Yeah, and then I got an office II job.
Rym: Yeah, I got the opposite job.
Scott: It was the office I was in was like the student services like students would come in and be like, oh I need help with this.
Scott: I'm like, alright, I'll help you.
Scott: and then in the summer What happened was obviously don't need as many people for that job in the summer because it's not a lot of students to service.
Scott: Yeah, so I was actually working in two different student service offices in the art school like switching between them.
Scott: So I only I was went down to just one of the two offices in the summer.
Scott: But then like this person who had been there for years was like actually I do I couldn't get a real job in the summer.
Scott: Let me come back.
Scott: So they kicked me out Which was actually a blessing in disguise because I got kicked out to go to the scheduling office instead Which was a much higher profile job and the actual scheduling officer was like super awesome And she brought a little doggy to her wiener doggy to work.
Scott: Nice and we just hang out in there.
Scott: and she kept like pushing with like the student employment office to like raise the category of That job constantly.
Scott: Whoa, I just kept getting paid and I was doing like, you know, like quality work.
Scott: It was like it's pretty much like the best job you could have on campus.
Scott: I think mine was and I kept that job like for three years.
Scott: I was almost equally good.
Rym: I worked at the GCC at the office of grants contracts intellectual.
Rym: I just kept that job as long as in school my only duties were the office.
Rym: ladies would need stuff like I do in her office mail, which is great because I get a bunch of envelopes and I just have to deliver them to wherever they had to go all over campus outside of the nice weather all day.
Scott: The scheduling office is super good because it wasn't like oh you're a student.
Scott: sometimes We'd help a student get their schedule in order But mostly it was schedule of like this class is going to be at one on Wednesday.
Rym: Oh, I never had that power.
Scott: It was that kind of scheduling right and I could see things like admissions and like I was.
Scott: you know I was in but it's all art school.
Scott: It wasn't the same school.
Rym: I don't think they would let you work in the scheduling office of your own department.
Scott: No, I mean that might be I don't know.
Scott: but like I was I had my hands on everything We're and we were getting shit done.
Rym: Yeah, but basically where I was I would mostly do data entry like they have these like multi-million dollar contracts to do research at the school and Like some company would basically pay the school and a grant to do the research and all this kind of stuff.
Rym: So I would Data enter from the contracts into the system that tracked all that and if I finished all that There was really nothing else to do.
Rym: So I just sat around Switch over to the IT department.
Rym: Oh way later.
Rym: That was way later.
Rym: That was like senior year.
Rym: Okay Yeah senior year I applied to work.
Scott: I stayed in the same place right up to the end.
Rym: I applied to work at the IT department and they didn't want to hire me at first Partly because I was gonna graduate at the end of the year partly because I never actually worked in IT before.
Rym: Apparently they wanted experience from students going to IT school in IT.
Rym: So yeah, that's great.
Rym: and They also I think my professor's Disrecommended me because I can't add reputation for being a shit who never came to class.
Rym: And I was that legal.
Scott: is that a Lieber violin?
Rym: I have no idea.
Rym: but no one no professor in the IT department liked me if they knew not even trumpet gang.
Rym: I only had one class with him and he loved me because it was the music class.
Rym: He actually taught the IT new media music composition and digital whatever class.
Rym: That was the audition and Pro Tools in recording studio class that I took with Katsu.
Rym: That was the only class was great.
Scott: What's that guy's name again?
Rym: Uh, I'll Biles.
Scott: Yeah, Google him.
Rym: See if he's around I'll look up what his business was.
Rym: but basically, they didn't want to hire me and then I went off and co-opted IBM and I came back as like a super IT professional and I interviewed them again and they were like you are way overqualified and I was like WTF
Scott: Yeah,
Rym: and then basically they
Scott: told me in person I was six months ago.
Rym: Yeah, except now I worked at IBM and now suddenly I'm too good for you.
Scott: Like I know just I didn't learn anything there.
Rym: I mean, I guess in a school we're like, I mean how many thousands of IT people are there?
Rym: There are more IT students than any other single major and every one of them wanted to work for the IT department of the campus For obvious reasons.
Rym: Yes, so they made me a Project manager and said that my expertise your job was upgrading the outlooks, right?
Rym: Yes, my job was managing the project of upgrading the outlooks.
Scott: But you went to a lot of teachers to upgrade those outlooks.
Scott: I did.
Scott: they were unhappy with you.
Rym: They were super fucking butter.
Rym: when I took away their giant giant archive files of like back in the day.
Rym: You know four gigabytes was a lot of space.
Rym: And actually that job was so trivial that most of my time they gave me off my own office Downstairs, I just sat there doing nothing playing my gameboy Poking around on the internet because there was literally no work to do because I did it all in like a couple hours.
Scott: It was awesome over cloth.
Rym: I paid a lot and I was supposed to mentor people but all the other kids they hired Were goody-two-shoes like teachers pets who knew a lot of like the textbook stuff of IT But didn't know how to actually do anything.
Rym: So none of them wanted to actually work with me because I'd make them work.
Rym: So I They'd be like, well, I guess I'm gonna go over there and copy the PST file over like no no, no, no, no, you're gonna sit here and learn out learn bash.
Rym: You're gonna write a script to do that shit from here.
Rym: That's right, and no one wanted to do that.
Rym: Okay, so, uh, what after that?
Rym: because you had co-op.
Scott: I had a co-op where I worked.
Scott: I got a cop because James worked there already is it was this place that James already worked and They were basically like they just did contract work of making hardware and software for people Mostly in like industrial places.
Rym: So oh, yeah the batteries.
Scott: Well, James was doing batteries.
Scott: He wrote software for battery chargers of the military, but at this place.
Scott: But then what we the project that we were hired to do was this place that had like a corn syrup Factory had like all these pumps and it was the place that managed the pumps I guess and they needed to monitor the pumps for like temperature vibration, etc.
Scott: It's like if something went wrong They could just think they could just be notified and go to the pump.
Scott: that was fucked up and deal with it.
Rym: I got bad.
Scott: So there were three things and we eat.
Scott: James made the smallest most embedded thing which was the sensor that goes on the pump.
Scott: I made this thing which was like a single board CPU and I had to had Linux and had 16 megabytes of flash storage.
Scott: And I basically had to write a program that would with a wireless like interface on the serial port Collect data from the sensors, right?
Scott: Sort of gather it into some sort of useful data structure then write it out as like, you know Some sort of normal protocol and send it over a cellular modem.
Scott: I had to like dial in the cellular modem to get to the internet 56k and Communicate with a web server.
Scott: using like soap is what we use then because I didn't even have JSON.
Scott: Oh,
Rym: yeah Wow Yeah I keep forgetting how long ago all this was
Scott: right and I would soap it over to the web server where the and then shitty Alex wrote software that would Take that put it into a MySQL database and had a web interface where you could look at graphs and all this stuff and semi real-ish time.
Scott: And we made that.
Rym: yeah, and that was what you also do a co-op for Rudy.
Scott: That was nice.
Scott: So I needed four co-ops.
Scott: I need four co-ops guys.
Rym: Remember RIT is a five-year program for IT and CS.
Rym: You've got to get a real job that pays real money four times.
Scott: Even if RIT hears this and takes away my degree, I don't give a shit.
Scott: It's not like I'll lose my job.
Scott: Yeah so I Had to do four co-ops.
Scott: the first two co-ops were ten weeks.
Scott: Well 20 weeks.
Scott: at making that real those are legit co-ops.
Scott: making this thing for the pump people, right?
Scott: Then I had to do a co-op.
Scott: So I managed to as a camp counselor at cyber camps.
Scott: now that should count as a co-op.
Scott: But actually that was only like a two three week camp not a ten week camp.
Scott: So whatevs deal with it?
Rym: co-ops had to be 10 to 20 weeks.
Scott: Anyway, I needed one more co-op.
Scott: I got someone who we knew to fill out the forms.
Scott: that said I did a co-op when I didn't do anything.
Rym: So so ever full disclosure I did something kind of similar in that I worked at IBM.
Rym: Like I got my basically I went from No experience in IT to at IBM as an intern and basically when I got there I realized that I wasn't learning much at RIT and I learned everything I needed to know that I didn't already know what I teach just by working in this IBM like Factory fab
Scott: the job I got after college.
Scott: I started working at before I Technically hit the graduation date at RIT, even though I had finished all my work at RIT.
Rym: Yep, so I co-op there after a week.
Rym: They were like, oh you're not an intern You're in charge of the data center now, and I just did a real work for them.
Rym: Like I was just IBM employee as far as they were concerned.
Rym: I had to leave to go back to school.
Rym: RIT.
Rym: I needed Two more.
Rym: I needed one more co-op.
Rym: You're not allowed to do all your co-ops at the same place and you're not allowed to end.
Scott: you're not allowed to end on a Co-op end at school.
Rym: So then I Didn't feel normal circumstance.
Rym: I didn't fill out the paperwork to get credit for the second part of that co-op at IBM.
Rym: So I technically failed the co-op.
Rym: Yeah, so it's not my try.
Rym: I failed it.
Rym: then I went back to IBM and just worked there After I was done with all my classes and should have graduated, but I didn't take senior seminar.
Rym: So technically I was not a graduate candidate yet.
Rym: Like I could not get my degree So I pushed it off as long as I could and then I went back to RIT went to the office.
Rym: I was like, look, I tried to get co-ops everywhere But I couldn't and I failed a co-op and I had all this kind of sob story.
Rym: So I got the exemption to have done all my co-ops at IBM and I couldn't end on the co-op.
Rym: So I stopped co-oping took one online class while I just continued to work at IBM Passed it and then I just went to next year's graduation.
Rym: In fact, I picked up your.
Scott: I never went to any graduation.
Rym: I picked up your robe hat and tassel.
Rym: I still have them.
Scott: My sister was complaining.
Scott: She's like, oh we didn't.
Scott: no one came to my graduation.
Scott: You made me go to Alex's graduation and I'm like, dude, I didn't go to my own.
Scott: I didn't go anyone's graduation for anything.
Rym: Hey Scott.
Rym: Do you want your robe and tassel?
Rym: I still have them.
Scott: What the fuck do I need it for?
Rym: I'll give you your tassel after the show.
Rym: I know where it is.
Rym: I don't need it.
Rym: It's two says 2005 on it cuz that's the year we both technically graduated can have it.
Scott: I got to Job, I got immediately after college.
Scott: I've said oh I got to find a job in New York City now Because I was living at my parents house for a few weeks and I could take the train in New York City And they're sure as hell weren't jobs in Connecticut?
Scott: So I found a job at this place called did business services Which is basically they had a website that let you fill out all at once these forms to get small business loans And then they would sell you services to help your small business like oh you need an accountant You need insurance.
Scott: You need all this stuff.
Scott: We'll just you know, we'll just give you all those things.
Scott: so to simplify your deal and They hired me to make you know web applications, which I'd never done before.
Scott: but I figured I'll figure it out I can program and I did.
Scott: it was no problem and I made some PHP web app that they really didn't give me a lot of instructions and had it what to do.
Scott: They were just like it needs to do this.
Scott: So I said and it was like the barest spec ever.
Scott: It was like a basically a vague description and I made it and I just did whatever I felt was best and they were satisfied.
Scott: I'm like, okay.
Scott: Then they opened up like this disaster recovery office in the middle of fuck nowhere And I was living.
Scott: I moved to beacon like a few weeks after starting this job.
Scott: So You know, I was.
Scott: then they're like.
Scott: we opened up this place.
Scott: It's close to you, right?
Scott: And I'm like, maybe I'm like Oh, right.
Rym: You had to drive all the way the fuck out to.
Scott: It was basically the border of Connecticut New York where the Connecticut is like a stick.
Scott: it was like, you know Almost an hour driving each way And I'm like, but if I'm gonna go all the way out there every day, you're gonna buy me a car.
Scott: they're like, okay, they raised my salary by the amount that the car payment was and They fixed back then.
Rym: we both thought was an amazing idea.
Scott: I mean it was effectively.
Scott: they bought me a car Yeah, which was fine.
Scott: Someone buys you a car.
Scott: You can't really complain.
Scott: They even paid for the tax and you know everything.
Scott: so whatever they bought me a car.
Scott: I drove the Mazda out there every day to go to this disaster recovery office.
Scott: They put me on another project and they gave me even less of a vague description like I couldn't even work on it because the description wasn't enough and I tried to talk to people to make meetings with the people actually use the existing thing.
Scott: cuz I was.
Scott: now I was replacing an Existing thing that was old.
Scott: was that when hopefully making something better, right?
Scott: But no one would meet with me.
Scott: I couldn't get requirements.
Scott: I tried to.
Scott: I was easy gather requirements.
Scott: I kept trying to gather them and they were ungatherable.
Scott: So I was driving to the middle of nowhere to do nothing every day.
Rym: now That's funny because that is the same time I had quit IBM because I didn't think there was a long-term career there just because IBM.
Scott: so I just Got tired of driving somewhere to do nothing every day.
Scott: So I quit and I got a job at this other place downtown Manhattan, which had cool people.
Scott: But we were doing shady business, right?
Scott: They were basically making forms online And you try to get people to fill out these forms.
Scott: and if you fill out the form we had your personal information including your social security number and We now knew who you were and the form was saying hey Do you need an auto loan?
Scott: fill out this form?
Scott: So we would then go to all these car dealers that were our customers who are paying us a lot of money.
Scott: And if you live near one of these car dealers, we would say hey car dealer We know someone who lives near you who needs an auto load.
Scott: We will tell you who they are if you give us monies.
Scott: And we would do this.
Scott: There was not only was there this retail market for this information There was a wholesale market for this information like leads.
Scott: so you basically their sales leads and there's like all this automatic buying and trading of personal information of Sales leads.
Scott: like god.
Rym: There's a gravel going on here, but there's a geek fable going on here.
Rym: So look you got a job After your like initial, you know, RIT job.
Rym: like I had my IBM.
Rym: We both had our initial jobs That we learned stuff in.
Rym: we both got a job that eventually had no work for us to do because remember I quit IBM And worked at that hospital.
Rym: Oh god where there was no work to do.
Rym: Like I went to my boss and my boss's boss and all their project manager.
Rym: I was like guys is there any project?
Rym: and they give me like nothing.
Rym: one day I didn't even fucking show up to work and no one noticed.
Scott: I could have not driven out to the middle of nowhere.
Scott: I probably shouldn't have.
Scott: yeah, I should have stayed in beacon.
Scott: I went to the middle of nowhere.
Scott: I started maybe going out there once a week to check on it.
Rym: I had to use the billing system.
Rym: So I'd like log my hours like my billable hours against different projects.
Rym: so I started billing 40 hours a week to nothing and No one cared.
Rym: and they were still shocked when I quit despite the fact that I was literally doing Zero work.
Rym: So we both had a job that paid well for.
Rym: Literally not.
Scott: I mean I was fresh out of college and I the first job made 40k Before and then they added on to that the cost of the car.
Scott: So hospital paid 50 and then that was in 2005 and then they opted to 60. a lot That's you know, that's not a lot of money, but it's a lot.
Scott: I mean, it's more than people I know make yo today, which is way fucked up Especially considering we didn't know how to do it is more than a lot of people make.
Rym: No when I first got my IBM offered me 40k without benefits.
Rym: I was like that is amazing.
Scott: I had benefit every job I've had even the co-op had like profit sharing 401k insurance.
Scott: Well, I didn't one of them.
Scott: originally it was a co-op and then I converted into like a full-on employee because every single job I've had to roll over 401k so many times because every single job I've had had one.
Rym: so then so we both were had jobs That did nothing.
Rym: that then turned into the shady era of working for people doing a shady stuff.
Scott: What did you do?
Rym: that was shady when I started getting into the other projects in the hospital that were all like weird?
Rym: Shady kickbacks and I think tax dodges and corruption.
Scott: but anyway they had the shady place went out of business because they got bought and then the 2009 happened and cars were hit pretty hard and it's not like they were doing a good business anyway.
Scott: Yeah, they went under and then I was unemployed for a little while and then I got the job I have now where I basically went on Craigslist like I always did.
Scott: I got every job from Craigslist pretty much yep, and I saw let's find some people making websites and there was some startup and the startup Was making a website that let rich parents Manage the money for their kids trust funds and I was like, okay But they wanted to pay me a lot of money.
Scott: and then the other job was Broadway.com where I work now And it was like, oh they're paying me less money But this is actually a totally real and legit business that isn't going anywhere.
Scott: and I was right.
Scott: and now I make way more money.
Scott: Yeah in there for like six seven I did the same thing.
Scott: I responded to an ad on Craigslist around the same time to work for a company that they didn't say what they did all these Recruiters be calling me but every job I've actually gotten is when I looked for one on Craigslist.
Rym: This Craigslist ad was like are you smart?
Rym: and it listed like a bunch of stuff that I could do around like database stuff and Shell scripting and Linux whatever and it but primarily was like you have to be smart.
Rym: and like Red Bull I was like, alright, whatever and I applied to it.
Rym: I do and it turned out.
Rym: it was a broker dealer and I got my job at pipeline and I don't.
Rym: they've offered me 65k and I was shocked at that raise.
Rym: It was amazing.
Rym: And then two months later.
Rym: They're like, uh, yeah you don't know how this works and they gave me a raise to 90 and then the next year to 130. and Then I got bored and quit.
Rym: and now I've worked at you know, where I work now as a product manager.
Rym: So like there's there's sort of interest.
Rym: I guess the the geek fable here.
Rym: people are asking to bring that back in the patreon.
Scott: Have skills get job.
Rym: No have skills I'm sorry, but notice like I couldn't get a job working at my own college's IT department because I didn't have experience.
Rym: But then I got a job at IBM, which you could get without experience.
Rym: Well, I I kind of scan my way into that job.
Rym: So you want to hear you want to learn like Rym?
Rym: Messing with people like here's a case.
Scott: I got my jobs like going into interviews and saying yeah Look, I actually know what the hell I'm talking about.
Scott: I obviously do.
Scott: I hope.
Scott: I hope people believe I know about.
Rym: I went right from listening to Monday episode to the career fair at RIT and Applied to an IBM co-op job that I was not qualified.
Scott: The only job I apply I talked to when I was at that RIT career fair was a computer associates And I don't think she wanted to talk to me.
Scott: But my RA was like, oh man, you should totally talk to this guy.
Scott: So she talked to me and I interviewed with her.
Scott: but she was like, why'd you fail calculus?
Scott: three like twice?
Scott: I'm like cuz it's really hard.
Scott: You can't pass calculus.
Scott: I'm like, I don't think so.
Scott: and just like hire me anyway, and they didn't so like alright, whatever.
Rym: So I only applied to jobs for the co-op because remember I needed a co-op like real bad to graduate.
Rym: You gotta get your first co-op in like your second year.
Rym: You're fucked at RIT.
Scott: Yeah, I think that's the thing with our.
Rym: it's so hard to get a co-op right.
Scott: getting the co-op is hard But once you get one, it's like there's a reason they have that program because it's like if you have a job.
Scott: it's like the rate of Graduated from RIT with a like a computer related degree to getting a job is like a super high rate.
Scott: It's like 90%.
Scott: also because the retention rate was so low.
Rym: Yeah So I applied to jobs that were kind of minimum GPA requirement cuz I had a really high GPA back then.
Rym: Yeah, it was so bad.
Rym: I was like 3.9 before I took over the anime club.
Scott: Yes I got a drop.
Scott: I didn't give a shit about grades But somehow my first quarter ever at RIT was like almost all A's and my last quarter at RIT I got like the Dean's list and in between it was like failed calculus 3.
Scott: Well, I had the same degree with a 2.0 that you get with a 3.0.
Rym: It doesn't matter I had to maintain a 3.4 minimum or I lost my full ride.
Rym: I lost my scholarship.
Scott: my scholarship slightly moved up and down a little bit over time, but they never completely removed it.
Scott: So well, they were like, alright, we're getting $100 less.
Scott: I'm like shit.
Rym: So I applied to an IBM co-op job to be a database administrator.
Rym: Now I point out I took the database class at RIT and decided that I fucking hated databases And I was not like.
Rym: I know SQL like you just know SQL.
Scott: I know SQL but I couldn't make my whole job databases and nothing but database.
Rym: Yeah, like I could not actually Normalize a database nor did I know anything about Oracle one class and that was like hell.
Scott: no.
Rym: So I applied to the job despite being abjectly Non-qualified for it.
Rym: and then when I went to the interview I wore a nice suit but it wasn't this like the like I wore like a Deep blue shirt and I had my basically made sure that I stood out like I kept my earrings in.
Rym: My resume was like four pages.
Rym: I'd like just I wanted to stand out and I figured out.
Rym: I remembered who the people who were behind the booth at IBM's booth at they like the thing looked like.
Rym: So I hung out in the area where the interview was happening.
Rym: There's like a little waiting area at RIT where they do the co-op interviews Like the companies come in and do the interviews the week after the job fair.
Rym: So I hung around there like an hour before my interview and I started making small talk with other people who were waiting in line for the same job interviews at IBM and I basically waited for someone I could talk kind of loudly to about like oh scholarships And what's it like at RIT and how's your GPA?
Rym: and I use this as an excuse to talk a lot about my full ride.
Rym: How I'm only here for the piece of paper because I already know everything and IT is so easy Like this stuff's baby stuff.
Rym: and the guy I was talking to Was like a mirror sort of reflecting the conversation back at me and I made sure those people I recognized before were within earshot.
Rym: then I go into the interview.
Rym: I Very I'm very like.
Rym: I don't lie and I basically when they ask about database stuff I admit I do not have any of that.
Rym: and the end of the interview.
Rym: I actually said, you know what I Would like to rescind my own application like as much as I need a co-op.
Rym: I'm not qualified for this particular job So I will apply to you like I'm backing out.
Rym: so Because I did all that IBM called me like they kept my resume around.
Rym: cuz the guy was like, oh well Keep your resume on file.
Rym: and they did.
Rym: and then they called me and offered me a completely different job within a couple weeks.
Rym: That was a lot of work.
Rym: to get that job because I wouldn't have got it Otherwise, I don't know what I would have done.
Rym: But once I got that job some other crappy idea.
Rym: Maybe it's hard to get it jobs A lot of people couldn't get co-ops and like had trouble could have gone straight to the hospital step one.
Rym: I don't know if I that might have.
Rym: just I might have just quit and become a lawyer if that happened.
Rym: But once I got that job and I went in it's like oh the real world IT is Super easy.
Scott: if you know anything about computers, this job is like I'm having to teach all my co-workers Unix because like nobody knows you Nick.
Scott: It's like nobody knows.
Scott: they all have Macs.
Scott: They all have Unix computers.
Scott: No one actually knows any Unix anything.
Scott: So it's like I think I might have to even make like Unix YouTube videos like learn Unix with Scott or some shit.
Rym: when I showed Someone the T command once it blew their mind like everything is a file.
Scott: That's all you need to know.
Scott: It's files like what my co-work today was like.
Scott: he actually knew stuff.
Scott: He was like, do I have to chamad?
Scott: I'm like, yes, he's like, yeah, it's like what it's like.
Scott: What do I have to chamad?
Scott: I'm like just make it 700.
Scott: He's like, alright, I'm like, do you know what the numbers mean?
Scott: He's like.
Scott: it's like RWX or something.
Scott: I'm like, oh my god, you know more than all the other coworkers.
Rym: Yeah, that guy is already On the road is to die.
Scott: But then I was like, do you know why?
Scott: it's the number seven and he's like no bitch if bitch shifter.
Scott: And I'm like, it's simultaneously really awesome and really stupid.
Rym: Yep And DP is the same thing.
Rym: There's there's one register that just has all these bits in a row and ever and it just shifts to the left and ones mean It's working.
Rym: Well sevens meet ones mean is working and zero means it's not working.
Rym: But the actual number you get will be like three seven seven, which means it's all ones.
Scott: So Because it's not as long as you think it oh, it's only yeah Yeah, anyway Eight instead of nine bytes or whatever.
Rym: people who know this bits.
Rym: Yeah It's people who know like like people who know what a subnet mask actually is Like why that is the way it is You're unicorns.
Rym: So I guess the moral is.
Scott: I think the IT guys at my place know what this subnet mask is.
Scott: I don't think the programmers know.
Rym: if you go to a real computer school and you already know about computers Like the classes are not teaching you the useful stuff unless you're a programmer they might be but an IT They're definitely not.
Rym: just get any IT job and you'll be badass at it probably and if you're not You'll learn because you already know a lot of this stuff.
Rym: if you know computers just get one job and notice.
Rym: as soon as I Had that one IBM job the people who previously wouldn't talk to me Fell over themselves offering me jobs and nothing had changed.
Scott: My advice is that most jobs out there if you need a job in technology Most of the jobs are looking for a specific technology for you to know right like where you want to hire someone who knows X. So what you need to do is just look at what's hot out there right and learn one hot thing Whatever it is.
Scott: Yep, and then Get a job doing that one hot thing, right?
Rym: You don't have to learn it to be an expert.
Rym: You have to learn enough to pass the interview and know what that like.
Rym: say someone needs a Windows admin Like you got to know kind of how.
Rym: Active Directory right?
Scott: So for example, the first job I got was PHP my SQL.
Scott: But it's like yeah, I had set up I you know I've done a little bit of that in college.
Scott: and then the second job I got was also PHP my SQL.
Scott: But towards the end of the job of the shady place We started messing around with git and Django and so when I got a job at Broadway calm I was like I've done the Django tutorial But now I'm a Django master.
Scott: you get all your skills at specific skills at your job.
Scott: You just need the general skills.
Scott: Yeah elsewhere What sucks to learn is what you need to learn like real talk.
Rym: RIT did not give me those base computer skills.
Rym: I always I hardly use any.
Scott: the only thing I learned at RIT was Unix, which I learned on my own.
Scott: They didn't teach it to me.
Scott: I just happened to learn it while I was there because I had to yep same deal, but Basically are like people.
Rym: graduating from RIT wasn't so much.
Rym: they learned a lot about IT.
Rym: It was they were smart enough to make it through IT to get the piece of paper.
Rym: So yeah, that's that's job.
Scott: Hope to get a piece of paper.
Scott: You need to have money to begin with.
Rym: Oh, and I worked at that temp agency, but I've talked about that on keep nice.
Rym: I'm just so.
Scott: if you're a privileged white dude who grows up in the suburbs and goes to a good high school and has a Computer when you're growing up in the 90s.
Scott: Yeah you too Get enough get a job good enough to live in New York City And get money and technology.
Scott: you miss the boat.
Scott: I'm sorry Millennials.
Scott: Yeah, I can't do anything about it.
Scott: What do you I mean like yeah, I admit that that's the situation But would you like me to like would you would not do any differently in my shoes?
Scott: I mean like I gotta eat.
Scott: What do you want me to do?
Scott: my advice to you give you my job.
Scott: I don't want to sit at the desk all day.
Scott: You can have it, but I don't know if you can do it.
Rym: My advice to you is like Scott said learn some of these things like learn the shit out of Linux and Then you just have to scan.
Scott: if you actually fucking know Unix like I will hire you.
Scott: I need you yeah.
Rym: And once you if you know Linux like or Unix real well Then even if you don't have the pieces of paper or anything You've just got to pull some like what I did an IBM.
Rym: pull some bullshit to just get in the door.
Rym: Impress the people who are interviewing because they're usually people like me.
Rym: and Scott once you get past that HR wall where I'm just like Do you know what the fixed protocol is?
Rym: do you know what regular expressions are?
Rym: Write down a regular expression for me.
Rym: anyone.
Rym: write down a regular expression.
Rym: I'll hire you right now.
Scott: So if your regular expression can actually match something like here make a regular expression that matches a file name and extracts the file extension.
Scott: You got your hired.
Rym: whoa capture group Scott.
Rym: That is where you do that one capture group.
Scott: You are immediately hired Scott.
Rym: I've explained capture groups to a dozen people in the last year being people who currently work for you and are being paid or people who work for other companies doing the same kind of and they Don't know how to do this and they don't understand it.
Rym: the other the other argument I've gotten from people in this industry in Wall Street finance is me blah blah blah blah.
Rym: Let's let people just set a regular expression for this thing.
Rym: counter argument No one knows regular expressions.
Scott: regular.
Scott: is it my rebuttal.
Rym: No you just don't know regular expressions.
Scott: But I mean it a. regular expressions are often are a tool that is often used for jobs that it should not be used for Hammer used to hit many screws, but you need to only bring it out when you know you've got nails.
Rym: if you know how to navigate a command line Like basic like babies first Linux, and you know how to use grep with regular expressions you can do 90% of all IT work.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: be sure to visit our website At front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: remember GeekNights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patrons this week are in order of the amount of money.
Rym: They give us Nicholas Brandau Rebecca Dunn James David white Christian coons Jess mechanical mind testing.
Rym: one two three Phil Ulrich Amanda Doucette Renee from New Zealand Robert Lee Ryan Perrin drew up and Lander rare Lavell Brian Cedroni Rochelle, Monta Nona Finn Eric silver odd Rym eats poop Kinetic man William Eisen rose Aaron Cerise Chris midkiff Chris Knox flame dark fire Samuel Cordery Daniel Redman Chris Haddad Doug Snyder Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: Also, I actually was finally called out on pronouncing someone's name wrong.
Rym: So it is Doucette's and you are the winner of the prize of being the first person to actually call me out and getting someone's name wrong.
Rym: and beyond that stay tuned.
Rym: Like I said, there's gonna be some more rooms ran some special episodes some things coming up, especially on the holidays we will be doing a normal episode of GeekNights on Christmas Eve and it's gonna be Christmas related.
Rym: and So I leave you with your moment of as always literally the opposite of that.
Scott: You can't shoot We'll just let it slip.
Scott: Yeah This pause.
Rym: spaghetti knees weak arms.
Rym: spaghetti is vomit on a sweater.
Rym: spaghetti mom's spaghetti.
Rym: He's nervous, but on a service He looks calm.
Scott: spaghetti to drop bombs, but he keeps on spaghetti what he wrote down.
Scott: the whole crowd goes spaghetti.
Rym: He opens his mouth, but spaghetti won't come out.
Rym: He's joking.
Rym: how everybody's joking now.
Scott: spaghetti's one now times Over last night back to spaghetti.
Rym: Oh, there goes spaghetti.
Rym: Wow He's so mad, but he won't give up spaghetti.
Scott: No, he won't have any notes.
Scott: He keeps on forgetting that.
Scott: mom's spaghetti's dope.
Scott: He knows that but he's pro.
Rym: He's so stacked that he knows when he goes back to his mom's spaghetti That's when it's back to the lab begin.
Scott: Yo, this old spaghetti better go catch the spaghetti and hope it don't.
Scott: Mom's spaghetti, it's ready.
Rym: Hey Sans can we listen to that song about M&Ms again, please?
Rym: Oh, come on, bro.
Rym: Really?
Rym: I know if we start you're not gonna want to stop.
Scott: Oh, please brother.
Scott: That's all I want.
Scott: Please please please please please please Fine, but only cuz.
Rym: I like seeing you happy.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Thank you, brother.
Scott: I don't really like this part this much but then Mom's forget.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: I love that part sons.
Scott: Can you restart the song please?
Scott: really bro?
Scott: Don't question me.
Scott: Just do it.