Rym: It's Thursday, May 14th, 2015.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I am Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: The fuck are we talking about tonight?
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So, uh, biking home today, I was gonna have a bunch of anecdotes about how for whatever reason today must have been, like, shithead biker day.
Rym: Like, I bumped into more people on bicycles.
Scott: Yesterday was bike to work day, that Wednesday, and I think it's bike to work month also?
Rym: Oh!
Rym: 'Cause yesterday a whole bunch of shitheads had set up these tents, like, blocking the bike lane, giving away free shit.
Rym: And it really got in my way.
Scott: That's transportation alternatives doing their thing.
Scott: They do that every year.
Scott: You haven't noticed?
Rym: You know what?
Scott: I think they do it multiple times a year.
Rym: Yeah, you know what I probably notice it as?
Rym: Some shitheads are blocking the bike lane.
Scott: They've actually upgraded.
Scott: Usually I just pass it by and ignore them.
Scott: But they upgraded, and instead of just having coffee that I don't drink, they had coffee and snacks.
Scott: So I actually slowed down for a second to peep the snack, and then saw it was a crappy snack and kept going.
Rym: But they had, like, the crowds they formed were blocking multiple bike lanes that I used to go to work.
Rym: So, guys, think this through a little bit better.
Rym: But no, so today, I've run into, like, I've never seen so many adults who clearly do not know how bicycles work attempting to ride them in New York.
Rym: And they're almost all on Citi Bikes.
Rym: So Scott just informed me right before we did the show that apparently today it was like, "You can ride Citi Bike for free
Rym: day!".
Scott: It was actually very interesting.
Scott: The reason you could ride Citi Bike for free today was because some Swiss company or whatever sponsored it.
Scott: They basically said, "We'll pick up the tab for everyone getting a free Citi Bike as a means of advertising
Scott: themselves.".
Scott: And I think that's actually cool as a revenue stream for Citi Bike.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But, you know, it's like...
Rym: If it's like the Empire State Building where every day is sponsored by...
Scott: Well, I guess sort of.
Scott: But think about it this way, right?
Scott: Let's say today they would have had 100 people buy day passes, right?
Scott: Okay, that costs X dollars.
Scott: That's how much revenue they bring in.
Scott: If day passes are free, because this company is paying for them, a lot more people are going to get day passes.
Rym: I'll just go get bikes and take them to other stations.
Scott: Right, just to ride bikes around.
Scott: But meanwhile, they're still getting paid probably pretty close.
Scott: You know, I can't imagine they would make a deal with too much of a discount, right?
Scott: You know, that company is paying for all these day passes.
Scott: They're not actually giving away for free.
Scott: They're just increasing sales.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: It's interesting, though, because I had no idea that this was going on.
Rym: All I knew was shitheads on Citi Bikes who don't know how to ride.
Rym: bikes were wobbling around all over the place, going the wrong way in the middle of the street.
Scott: I'm sure business people already knew this, but that's a great business idea I never heard of before.
Scott: Where it's like, let's say I sell apples in my fruit store.
Scott: And it's like, you know, apples, 10 cents.
Scott: I'm going to sell X apples.
Scott: If it's free apples, but I'm getting the 10 cents from Rym who said, "I'll pay for everyone's apples today.
Scott: I'm going to sell out of apples and make way more
Scott: money.".
Rym: Me paying for all those apples is way cheaper than me buying like an ad.
Scott: Well, because what you're doing is you're buying people liking Rym.
Scott: I'm the one profiting from that with my store and everyone else is profiting with the apples.
Scott: It's pretty much like just good all around.
Rym: We're onto something here today.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So we just need to find...
Rym: So here's the next thing.
Rym: If you want to advertise on the Internet, the way to do it is find a popular website that otherwise has ads.
Rym: And instead, buy the site's ads and put no ads up except a tiny banner that says, "No ads because of
Rym: us.".
Scott: Well, I think a better way to do it would be saying, "This game on Steam is free today.
Scott: I'm paying for every
Scott: copy.".
Scott: Anyone who downloads this game today on Steam, it's free.
Scott: or Humble Bundle.
Rym: One day only.
Rym: The fabulous Blues Brothers.
Scott: Anyone who gets Humble Bundle today pays $0 and you get the whole bundle, the max bundle.
Scott: And I will pay the max bundle price for every person that downloads.
Rym: Not the worst idea.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: So you're promoting those games because they're getting exposure.
Scott: People play them who wouldn't have.
Scott: I'm getting exposure because my name's on it.
Scott: People are getting free games.
Scott: And the people who make the games are getting money and I'm just spending money.
Scott: But I'm getting exposure that I was paying for in the first place.
Rym: Don't do it with City Bike because those people were in my way all day.
Rym: It was awful.
Scott: I didn't bike to work today only because I went to El Dentist.
Rym: I biked to work like 12 times this year so far.
Scott: The dentist said I was looking great.
Scott: No problems.
Scott: My teeth are awesome.
Rym: Not bad.
Scott: I bite you.
Rym: I don't really want you to bite me.
Scott: But they're so clean right now.
Scott: It's the best time for me to bite you.
Rym: No, I think I'll get them dirty right away.
Scott: Are you filthy?
Rym: I just biked here.
Rym: You're going to get a bunch of New York all over your teeth.
Rym: In the news, as I pointed out on Twitter, because we chose not to pay for upgraded infrastructure with money, we're now paying for our lack of upgrades with literal human lives because one of the biggest train disasters in recent history happened.
Rym: And an Amtrak train basically crashed and killed a ton of people.
Rym: I think they found the eighth dead person so far.
Rym: They're not sure how many people are dead necessarily.
Scott: Why is it so hard to find people?
Scott: Aren't they just all in the train?
Scott: Did you see pictures of the train?
Scott: Yeah, but aren't they just next to the train or under it?
Rym: No, they're like crushed inside of that.
Rym: They've got to cut this thing apart and get inside it.
Rym: Look at that.
Scott: Yeah, that took this many days?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Shit's not easy.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: So basically this should be a wake-up call, but the reality is already, one, it's a partisan issue, and two, almost no one actually cares.
Rym: The Republicans, funnily enough, they had basically, along with the Democrats, passed this thing a while ago that said, "Amtrak has to put in this fancy system that will prevent accidents exactly like this
Rym: one.".
Rym: But they didn't give Amtrak any money to do that, and simultaneously they had been cutting Amtrak's budget constantly.
Scott: Isn't there some train-making company that wants to lobby the government?
Rym: I don't think there's a lot of money in the train-making enough to be worth lobbying.
Scott: Trains are worth ... They're so expensive.
Scott: You've got to imagine a train business could profit heavily if they convinced the United States to spend tax dollars on trains.
Rym: The thing is- There's so much space here.
Rym: I think the cost of convincing the United States is so high that you could never make a profit.
Scott: What if I already have so much money because I'm Google, and then I buy a train company and then lobby?
Rym: That could happen.
Rym: We need a Rockefeller to come and say, "Look, fuckers," and just do it with money.
Rym: That is not going to happen.
Rym: I can't let Bill Gates and Sergey Brin and Musk all get together.
Scott: Because they're car people.
Scott: You know how many cars Bill Gates has?
Rym: Yeah, but how many of them does he drive?
Scott: He's always driving one Porsche or whatever.
Rym: The funniest thing about this, and also the saddest thing, basically the Republicans sense danger immediately.
Rym: They were like, "Don't make this an infrastructure issue.
Rym: Don't bring up the fact that we cut Amtrak's budget literally yesterday because no amount of infrastructure upgrades could have prevented this.
Rym: This is clearly human error.
Rym: That train was going too fast.
Rym: The speed is literally the only thing that
Rym: matters.".
Scott: Yes, but neglecting to mention the fact that the train was going 100 something miles an hour, right?
Scott: Don't bring up the fact that trains in other countries go 200, 300 miles an hour.
Scott: perfectly fine with no issues and no one would complain about that.
Rym: Or never mind the fact that it just so happens that that thing that the government said Amtrak has to deploy but also gave them no money to deploy and then cut their budget even further.
Scott: It would cost as much as getting better trains?
Rym: It wouldn't have cost that much at all.
Rym: In fact, it's pretty cheap.
Rym: Amtrak had deployed it in as many places as they could possibly afford with their pitiful budget.
Rym: But they couldn't deploy it everywhere because Congress and mostly the Republicans won't give them any money.
Rym: That thing a bunch of engineers came out and said would literally 100% have prevented this issue.
Rym: It is designed to prevent this issue.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: And it wasn't even that expensive.
Rym: It's just like Amtrak has no money.
Scott: If they would have given them money, it would have been deployed and these people wouldn't have died.
Rym: Yes, so the Republicans basically caused these people's deaths because it's a partisan issue whether or not to fund Amtrak.
Rym: Also, for people who don't live in America, you should probably realize that Amtrak is like our big train network.
Rym: The only profitable part of it is the area around New York and literally no other part of it matters and operates at a huge loss.
Scott: But you can ride this train everywhere.
Scott: It goes all the way to Seattle, to Chicago, to L.A.
Scott: You can ride this train across the whole goddamn country.
Rym: You can pay and attach your own train cars to these trains.
Rym: You can get little cabins in these trains.
Scott: You can take the, I don't know if you can still do it.
Scott: There used to be, we took it once, the auto train.
Scott: You would drive to Virginia.
Scott: You would put your car on the train in the back.
Scott: You would go sit in the front where there's all the dining car and all that kind of stuff.
Scott: And the train would take you basically overnight to Florida and then you would get off and then they'd bring your car around.
Scott: And you'd get in it and you'd be in Florida and you just didn't have to drive.
Scott: And you didn't have to rent a car.
Scott: You didn't have to fly.
Scott: And it took basically overnight.
Scott: You sleep on the train once.
Scott: You get there in the morning, get on the train, spend all day on the train, go to bed, wake up, get off the train sometime during the next day.
Rym: Well, that second Anime Central that I went to, I drove to Rochester from Beacon, well from Fishkill.
Rym: And then I got on an Amtrak with like Scojo and some friends.
Rym: Then I took the Amtrak to Chicago from there.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And that's the thing is all these fancy trains in other countries, much like the internet in other countries, it doesn't have to go very far.
Rym: But also it's subsidized by the government and there's a lot of investment in that infrastructure.
Rym: In the US, Congress gives Amtrak basically no money and they force them to run very, very unprofitable routes that a handful of people use.
Scott: Well, if you turn those routes off, those few people, what the fuck are they going to do?
Rym: You know what?
Rym: A bus.
Rym: Replace all the Amtrak in those dumpy little towns with a bus that goes to a bigger Amtrak station somewhere.
Rym: I think that's what we should do.
Rym: Or if Amtrak has this mandate to cover the whole country.
Rym: They, yeah.
Rym: I'm not saying Amtrak's that unsafe yet.
Rym: I'm just saying that they should either fund it enough to cover that mandate or drop the mandate.
Scott: Like I knew some people who wanted to go to Minnesota for the Netrunner World Championship, which I would never go to in Minnesota.
Rym: I would fly and rent a car.
Scott: Obviously.
Scott: That's what I would do too.
Scott: But they were the kind of people who were afraid of flying.
Scott: What?
Rym: Don't go to Minnesota.
Rym: There's no way to get there.
Scott: They took Amtrak to Minnesota and they made it.
Scott: How long did that take?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: They played Netrunner on the train the whole way there.
Scott: And I'm just like, all right.
Scott: But if they didn't have Amtrak, they would have had to deal with their fear of flying.
Scott: Or drive, which would have been way worse.
Scott: Or bus, which would have been way worse.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: Buses are pretty awful.
Scott: But Amtrak totally lost money bringing them there.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: How many people were on that train?
Scott: I can't imagine a lot.
Rym: And meanwhile, America has this weird obsession with making mass transit.
Rym: They treat it like a business.
Rym: It has to be profitable.
Rym: It has to make profits.
Rym: It has to self-fund.
Rym: But roads don't have to self-fund.
Rym: Roads get funded by the government.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: And somehow they don't see how utterly fucked up that is.
Scott: Well, because I think it's a matter of not understanding the cause and effect.
Scott: It's like, people drive, therefore we need to fund roads.
Scott: And it's like, actually, people are driving because you fund roads.
Scott: If you funded trains and stopped funding roads, people would stop driving and they would take the train more.
Rym: Or like Midwestern people, like, oh, buses are for poor people.
Rym: It's like, yeah, that's because buses are cheap and they suck.
Rym: That's why you would get this impression that only poor people ride them.
Scott: If you paid money to make fancy buses, poor people would stop using them and rich people would use them.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: Look at Google with their private buses.
Scott: Whatever you spend the money on, basically it's not give money to what people use.
Scott: It's give money and people will use the thing you give money to.
Rym: Or maybe, just maybe.
Scott: You tell the people where to go.
Scott: They don't tell you where.
Rym: Just maybe, connecting all the wide spaces in America with trains is stupid.
Rym: Maybe we should just use bullet trains to connect all the major cities on the two coasts.
Rym: I mean, flying to Boston is a ridiculous waste.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Because a bullet train would literally get you there faster than flying.
Rym: And in fact, if you account for the TSA security bullshit and getting to and from the airport, it's actually faster to take our existing shitty Amtrak Zelle to Boston than it is to fly there.
Scott: You don't think they would put the TSA security on the fancy bullet train?
Rym: They haven't so far.
Scott: On the fancy bullet train, though.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: At the same time, they also shouldn't...
Scott: They would be like, this is a target for terrorism.
Scott: We spent so much money on this.
Scott: This is so fancy.
Rym: I'm going to put it this way.
Rym: If America was smart enough to make a bullet train, by that point, they were already smart enough to get rid of the TSA.
Rym: Alright.
Rym: There is no world I can envision where bullet train happens and TSA still exists in the same political climate.
Scott: So, something good that is being built.
Scott: My news.
Scott: The most important thing.
Scott: The most important news of the entire week, month, year.
Rym: Oh, I know what you're talking about.
Scott: In Brooklyn, New York.
Scott: A place that we don't live.
Scott: It's actually slightly far away.
Rym: Well, I live on the border of Brooklyn.
Rym: Sure.
Scott: Whatever.
Rym: I live in Brooklyn.
Scott: They're going to build a Wegman.
Rym: Ah, yes.
Rym: Motherfucking Wegmans.
Scott: The most important thing.
Scott: The real deal.
Scott: The greatest grocery store to exist other than Stu Leonard's.
Rym: So, you listeners, you've known us long enough to know...
Scott: I mean, a lot of you people probably live in suburbs and just have big supermarkets.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: A lot of you people maybe live in cities and know what the deal is.
Scott: Maybe you live in other countries where groceries are totally different than they are here.
Rym: Yeah, like even here, like in New York, I get Fresh Direct.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I like Fresh Direct a lot.
Rym: I don't go grocery stores.
Scott: Yeah, maybe you get shit delivered.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Maybe you just eat out.
Scott: Maybe you eat from your own farm.
Scott: I don't fucking know.
Rym: But I can put this really succinctly.
Scott: Wegman is, other than Stu Leonard's, the grocery store of grocery stores.
Rym: You know us.
Rym: We are jaded as shit about everything.
Rym: When we leave New York City to go to a convention, it's nothing but Scott bitching about it.
Rym: Everything's not as good as New York.
Rym: Nothing impresses us.
Rym: Every time we go to, we're like, wow, there's nothing to do here.
Rym: We ate at all the restaurants.
Rym: We did a whole episode reviewing the city of San Antonio, one of the biggest cities in America, and how boring and tiny it is.
Rym: And yet, when we are near a Wegmans, like we travel somewhere, we'll go to it like we're going to an amusement park.
Scott: Most of the Wegmans are so big, and they have every food imaginable, and the food quality is so high, and the price is average.
Scott: But they're like, not only that, but not even for the customer, how amazing a place it is for the employees.
Scott: It's always number one place to work, Wegman.
Rym: Yeah, they're super ethical.
Rym: They pay their employees real living wages.
Rym: Everything about this place is great.
Scott: And they're going to finally build one in New York City.
Rym: Now, there's a real important question.
Scott: How much does it cost to rent an apartment near where this place is going to be?
Rym: About as much as it costs to rent right here.
Scott: Well, it's time to move then.
Scott: I've got to be within walking distance.
Rym: It's in that green pointy, that sort of rising area.
Rym: So it's in a hot area, but it's in a hot area that's furthest away from the hottest areas, and it has basically no subway access.
Scott: How do I get to work?
Rym: You could walk to the G, and then take that to further Brooklyn.
Scott: Is there a water taxi there?
Rym: I'll bet there will be.
Scott: I could take the water taxi over the East River in the winter, and then take across town something.
Rym: Well, in the summer, I would just bike over the Queensborough Bridge.
Scott: Obviously.
Scott: I'm talking about the winter.
Rym: Well, if you were living down there, you would want to bike up through Brooklyn and bike over the Queensborough Bridge.
Scott: Sure.
Rym: Anyway, so there's a big question that we didn't think about, because there's one thing left.
Scott: It's only going to be 25% smaller than a regular Wegman, so only 75% the size.
Scott: I'll take it.
Rym: There is one thing left now that New York City lacks, other than a rollercoaster park.
Rym: Dibella's?
Rym: Yeah, Dibella's.
Scott: But Wegman's has sort of a Dibella's in it.
Rym: So that's what I'm getting at.
Rym: Will the deli counter at this Wegman's have the 90% as good as Dibella's subs?
Scott: I can't see why it wouldn't.
Rym: If it does, I don't know what I'm going to do, other than eat there.
Scott: Bike down there and get a sandwich.
Rym: Stop there every day on my way home.
Scott: Bike over, grab a sandwich, go to the park.
Rym: Bike over there for lunch from my office.
Scott: Eat the sandwich, go back home with a backup sandwich.
Rym: We have detoured dozens of miles out of our way to go to Dibella's on trips to other places.
Scott: Why wouldn't you?
Rym: If you're stupid, if you're gluten intolerant, there's that.
Scott: I should buy a bodega around here.
Rym: And just copy the Wegman's formula?
Scott: No, and make it a Wawa.
Rym: While we lack Wawa, I think we make up for that with our combination of bodegas and street food.
Scott: But imagine if one of the bodegas was just a Wawa.
Scott: It had a Wawa brand on the outside.
Rym: You know what I just imagined?
Rym: If that weird gas station right next to our apartment, like the studio right here.
Scott: Yeah, that's a good example.
Rym: If that was a Wawa.
Scott: Right, there's no reason it can't be.
Scott: Why couldn't it be?
Rym: There's no reason it shouldn't be.
Rym: Right.
Rym: That place would have been a bank too.
Scott: Once those new buildings open up.
Rym: Now, even though that place, all the good restaurants are at least several blocks away.
Rym: That is the place.
Rym: You know what it would do?
Rym: It would kill the deli downstairs in my building.
Rym: So, tiny news.
Rym: I wouldn't have talked about this.
Rym: I wouldn't even be on our radar.
Rym: Most people I know saw like, oh, they're kind of like how when the government monitors terrorists, they're like, oh, there's chatter.
Rym: We don't know what they're talking about, but there's increased chatter.
Scott: Yeah, I saw a whole bunch of news on all my feeds talking about Jem and the Holograms.
Scott: And I said, oh, there must be some new Jem and the Holograms thing that people are excited about.
Scott: Okay, I don't really care about Jem and the Holograms.
Scott: I've seen maybe like two episodes and I don't care.
Scott: So, I will ignore this.
Rym: Now, one, that's how we stay abreast of stuff on the internet.
Rym: By paying, like we know if something's trending, even if we don't know why or care, you at least know like we had the pulse.
Scott: I'm tapped into the feeds.
Scott: Something's going on with Jem.
Scott: I know what's going on.
Scott: I know what I need to know.
Rym: So, I was in the same boat, but then I saw a tweet from Ben Kachara and he felt the need to have an article on Polygon about this trailer.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: So, I was like, all right, that's worth clicking on.
Scott: I guess if something's trending, you're going to write an article about it to try to get some hits, right?
Rym: So, I clicked on it and the story was kind of fascinating.
Rym: So, I watched the trailer and the first notable thing was that when I watched the trailer, it had like 60 likes and like 2,000 dislikes.
Scott: Well, that tells you something.
Scott: By the way, not only are they making Jem and the Holograms, right?
Scott: It's a live action Hollywood movie, Jem and the Holograms.
Rym: So, it is a live action Hollywood movie that is called Jem and the Holograms and they are all named after characters in Jem and the Holograms.
Rym: There appears to be no magic, no technology, no supercomputer.
Rym: I don't think there's even any misfits and it's basically... Remember that movie with Tom Hanks and younger actor who looks like Tom Hanks?
Scott: No.
Rym: Okay, anyway.
Rym: This is basically a tween version of that thing you do about a fake YouTube celebrity band becoming famous.
Scott: All right.
Rym: I am amazed and the cool thing is the entire internet realizes how bad this is going to be.
Rym: So, what do you do as a studio if you're making your movie and you release your big trailer, your big deal and it gets across the board universally panned even by the people you're trying to target?
Scott: You put it out and make your money anyway because even Garfield movies made money?
Rym: But Garfield movies, parents will take their kids to see that no matter what.
Scott: You think they won't go see this?
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: There are people who like this kind of movie, right?
Scott: Let's say you took the same movie and didn't call it Jem and the Holograms, called it something else.
Scott: I'm sure there's already 30 movies just like that.
Scott: but those people, they will see and like this movie as well.
Scott: They don't care that it's Jem and the Holograms or not.
Scott: and at least some Jem and the Holograms fans will also go see it.
Rym: You know who will go see it?
Rym: The people who liked Pitch Perfect.
Scott: I don't know what that is.
Scott: Is that basically the same kind of movie?
Rym: The Rockapella group.
Rym: Alright, it made like a hundred million.
Scott: That's money.
Scott: I'll take it.
Scott: You can give that to me.
Rym: So then the question is will this movie actually have enough bad momentum to fail?
Rym: Or is it getting all this really bad publicity because everyone outside of this very niche specific tween demographic noticed it?
Scott: The only bad publicity it's getting is internet.
Scott: bad publicity because those people who know what the fuck Jem and the Holograms is, other people don't know.
Rym: That's what I'm saying.
Scott: This will be Jem and the Holograms to them.
Scott: They don't know about the robot and anything.
Rym: Yeah, so it's interesting that it's sort of, it's being hated primarily because people who weren't supposed to see it noticed it.
Scott: I mean, did you see the video of the kid today at the pay phone who didn't know what the fuck it was?
Rym: Oh yeah.
Scott: Alright, that kid doesn't know what Jem and the Holograms is.
Scott: Maybe he likes this.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I get the impression.
Scott: If this is his first exposure, people will see this and not even know that it was based on something.
Rym: I'm confident this is aimed at 10 to 11 and a half year old girls.
Scott: Anyway, if you didn't know, there's a Jem and the Holograms comic.
Scott: There's a lot of comics now that are legit.
Scott: There are a lot of comics out now that are based on properties and unlike other mediums when they just base new material on old licensed properties, many, not all, but many of the comics based on properties are good.
Scott: Adventure Time comic is good.
Scott: Brave Azura's comic is good.
Scott: There's a lot of good comics based on the stuff that you like anyway.
Scott: So if you like Jem and the Holograms, it's a comic book.
Scott: You can go check that out.
Scott: It has all the magic and stuff.
Scott: It's not like this movie.
Rym: I mean really, Jem and the Holograms should have been remade a lot like that Equestria Girls thing.
Rym: That kind of media was how you remake that.
Scott: Oh yeah, because that's so great.
Rym: You know, it's not for us, but that is the way you do it because it's basically like it's music driven.
Rym: It's a cartoon.
Rym: It's got all that kind of fantasy stuff that like made Jem what it was.
Rym: Whatever.
Rym: This thing is literally, watch the trailer just so you, because you're thinking like how bad could it be?
Rym: It's pretty bad.
Rym: And ignore it after that and don't worry about anything else anyone says about it.
Rym: There's literally no reason to pay further attention.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: Our friend Judith showed me this.
Rym: It's kind of an amazing video.
Rym: Needs a little bit of discussion.
Rym: So this is a video from kind of like public access TV.
Rym: Like I don't know what network it was.
Rym: I'm trying to figure this shit out.
Rym: But basically, kind of like PBS, like other networks would do like telethons or fundraisers or auctions and things.
Scott: So public television and people are in the only in the United States might know this for old, like us who watch public television when it, you know, so we have a channel, it's PBS and it's public television.
Scott: So the government pays for it, but the government doesn't pay for it enough so that they won't survive with just the government's money alone.
Scott: But it also doesn't do commercials and the programs it puts on are usually things like Sesame Street and whatnot.
Scott: that, you know, don't, you know, other educational highbrow content that's not really going to rake in tons of viewers and tons of, you know, money from sponsors and whatnot.
Scott: So the money comes from these donation drives where basically they'll go on and they'll have programs.
Scott: But in between the programs, they'll stop and talk to people and be like, if you call us on the phone and give us money, we will send you this tote bag and this cookbook.
Scott: And there's all this, it's like, please send us money.
Rym: And when I was a kid, there was a big one that was auctions, like they auctioned stuff off that people had donated.
Scott: And we would watch it religiously every year because they would put on really good stuff during this thing.
Scott: Like, yeah, my mom, there's a lot of.
Scott: there were a lot of cooking programs on there.
Scott: And this is before the Food Network existed.
Scott: So like you would go see like Jacques Pepin cook something and like he would do the best cooking.
Rym: Oh, no, I'm sorry.
Rym: My mom was bitten up.
Rym: And because one time I wanted to buy something because someone put up just this legit, antique, like awesome phone booth.
Rym: And it wasn't that expensive.
Scott: Oh, wow.
Rym: We were trying to get it.
Rym: And then another time someone was auctioning off like a complete set of Dungeons and Dragons books.
Scott: Why do you have a shiv there?
Rym: This is my Google Glass screwdriver.
Rym: I used it for a task.
Scott: It looks like a shiv.
Rym: This is this is a shiv for like a rat.
Rym: Anyway, maybe a chinchilla could wield this.
Scott: So you'd call them up and give them money and they'd send you stuff and you become a member.
Scott: And then that money would keep the network going.
Rym: So this is that still works.
Scott: The network is still around.
Rym: This is that.
Rym: This is from 1992.
Rym: This was on television.
Rym: The Gallery 33, like art auction thing.
Rym: The video is great one, because if you've never seen this style of programing, it is gone.
Rym: This is a legacy.
Scott: This is like maybe PBS does still have it, but not like this.
Rym: The cadence, the words people say, the way they talk, their diction, the way they're dressed, their hair.
Rym: This is amazing.
Rym: When people think of the 90s, they're thinking of like the mid to late 90s.
Rym: The early 90s were like a bad version of the 80s.
Scott: Well, I think it's just, you know, you're thinking about young people 90s.
Scott: You're not thinking about what the old people are doing in the 90s, right?
Scott: People think about the 60s.
Scott: They think about what hippies.
Rym: This young guy's dressed in an 80s, like late 80s fashion.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I'm just saying like people think about the 60s of the 50s.
Scott: They always think about what young people are up to.
Scott: Right?
Scott: Elvis fans, Beatles fans, hippies, right?
Scott: Disco kids, right?
Scott: No one thinks defines a generation by what the old people were doing in that era.
Scott: Like, you know, 80 year old, 70 year old people in the 70s.
Scott: What were they into?
Scott: Still jazz music probably.
Rym: So anyway, not to get too down into this, watch this video because this is an art auction and this video is a super cut of one person who donated several pieces to this.
Rym: I think they all got bids.
Rym: Like people bid them up and bought them and it's all furry erotica.
Scott: Really?
Rym: Uh, yeah.
Rym: That one was I think called surfacing.
Rym: The funniest one at the end is called the smell of wet fur.
Rym: And the best part about this video is they're just straight faced.
Scott: They don't think there's a problem with it.
Rym: They are a hundred percent straight faced, but a few of them, like one guy starts to talk and he's like, those rats, they look like they're having a good time and let's move on.
Rym: This is amazing to behold.
Rym: All right.
Scott: Someone's bidding on the furry erotica.
Rym: It all got sold.
Scott: There you go.
Rym: So thank you, Judith.
Rym: The person who showed this to us.
Scott: So speaking of animals with fur in Hong Kong, a place Rym recently went, he apparently did not witness this event though while he was there.
Scott: That's a shame.
Scott: Uh, somehow a wild boar, I don't even know how wild boar lives on an island like that, uh, got into the store via the ceiling.
Scott: And here's a video of that incident.
Scott: It's hilarious.
Scott: The end.
Rym: There's this great moment where he's on the, uh, like on top of all these shelves and he's got this look of the fuck are you all looking at?
Rym: Like he's looking down at all these people and the cops are all just kind of hanging out watching him.
Scott: Like, I'm surprised they had someone who knew how to hug, tie it and take it away properly.
Rym: Well, I guess a hog tie is the correct way to deal with that situation.
Scott: Someone who had the proper training knew what to do, you know, just because I know to hog tie it.
Scott: I mean, did they go on YouTube and say how to hog tie wild boar?
Rym: You know who does that?
Rym: At least in the U S animal control.
Rym: My mom.
Rym: That was my mom's job.
Rym: She basically would work with like the police and the anti cruelty.
Rym: And like when they go to bust up a dog fighting ring or like deal with an abandoned pet shop or something, she was the one who would come in because she knew how to deal with all the different animals.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So in the meantime, the book, Hong Kong's going to call up your mom is still water ship down.
Rym: It's a story about rabbits on an adventure, fighting fascists and cultists and just trying to make a new home.
Rym: You read it yet?
Scott: I haven't read it in a few days.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Because I'm reading other novels now.
Rym: I've moved on to several other books since then.
Scott: If I just keep going on not reading it for longer, it will be a more hilarious and ongoing joke that way.
Rym: I really like that book.
Rym: I don't know why you're not reading it.
Rym: It takes like half a day to read that book.
Scott: I'm sure if I actually sat down and read it, it wouldn't take very long.
Scott: Let's do it two weeks.
Rym: I'll just say this.
Scott: On that Thursday episode, that'll be the end of it.
Rym: The longer this goes on, the longer the book I pick is going to be.
Scott: We got to pick.
Scott: We got to move on with the book club.
Scott: It's not much of a book club if we just keep talking about it and don't do it.
Scott: So I think it's been almost like a ridiculously long time, like perhaps even six months or so.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So two weeks from now, I'll finish it.
Rym: And kind of an aside, if you want to see us perform again at PAX Australia, our third PAX Australia in a row, email us or tweet or something and let us know.
Rym: I want to know how many people, for serious, actually really want us to be at PAX Australia.
Scott: Is it worth it for me to use my vacation and my monies to go to Australia again when I could just go to someplace with castles or a tropical island or et cetera?
Scott: Not that Australia isn't part tropical island.
Rym: It's tough because after I went to the second one, even without Scott, because I've gone to two and the second one was better than PAX South, for real PAX.
Rym: now in a real venue, it's real hard to imagine myself not being at it every year.
Rym: There's this momentum.
Rym: But at the same time, even I can't afford to drop like six grand a year.
Scott: Even you.
Scott: So wealth.
Scott: Wow.
Rym: Yeah, but that is not a trivial expense to fly yourself to Australia.
Scott: I mean, for a fraction of the cost, I can go to Europe, right?
Rym: Yeah, for the cost of going to PAX Australia and staying there for like the two weeks to make that flight worthwhile, I could spend like a month in Hong Kong.
Scott: What's the exchange rate in Hong Kong?
Scott: Don't they have Hong Kong dollars?
Rym: Yeah, it's like 12 Hong Kong dollars to one American dollar.
Rym: Oh, alright.
Scott: But are the prices 12 times higher?
Rym: Yeah, it's something like that.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I paid for everything in my credit card.
Rym: I don't really care.
Scott: Oh, so much money.
Scott: You can't afford to go to Australia, but in Hong Kong, I don't even care.
Scott: Well, no, my company card.
Rym: I was there on business.
Rym: I didn't spend any of my money.
Rym: Oh, okay.
Rym: Believe me, I would have known.
Scott: You didn't buy any wild boar?
Rym: Oh, shit.
Rym: Oh, yes.
Rym: The crazy thing happened in Hong Kong.
Rym: I forgot to tell you about this.
Rym: So I lost my wild boar.
Scott: Oh, how did you get it into customs?
Rym: So I guess we're doing this show about nuts because people didn't like the other crab people.
Scott: People love food shows and there are a lot of different nuts to talk about.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Macadamia.
Scott: Might as well start at the top.
Rym: Pistachio.
Scott: That's the top.
Rym: That's the money nut.
Scott: So the pistachio nut is the greatest nut that can possibly exist.
Scott: If anyone fucking calls, writes, or forums or anything to us talking about what is actually a nut and what is not a nut, you can go fuck yourself.
Scott: Yeah, we've been down that road.
Scott: A pistachio nut is called a pistachio nut colloquially.
Scott: Therefore, it's a nut.
Scott: If you try to tell me like a peanut's not a nut or I don't even know what's a nut and what's not, but I know.
Scott: Someone is going to come up to us and be like a cashew.
Scott: nut's not a nut.
Rym: Scott, sometimes you feel like a nut.
Scott: A pecan is not a nut.
Rym: Sometimes you don't.
Scott: They're all nuts.
Scott: If the word nut's in the name, it's a nut.
Scott: Go fuck yourself.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So pistachio nut is the greatest nut, which is why.
Rym: Oh, it is a nut.
Rym: It isn't for real.
Rym: This article is about the culinary nut and the tree that bears it.
Scott: All right, fine.
Scott: The pistachio nut has a protective shell.
Scott: The protective shell is the most important part of the pistachio nut.
Scott: That protective shell keeps you from dying.
Scott: If you get already shelled pistachios, a human being cannot physically prevent themselves from just eating all of them and then they're dead.
Rym: This happened to me.
Rym: I didn't die.
Rym: But the first time I went to Turkey, I went to like a bar.
Rym: I was having a drink and they brought out like a big tray with a bunch of nuts, like big bowls of nuts just for the bar thing.
Rym: So I'm sitting there.
Rym: I'm looking.
Rym: There's one nut I don't recognize.
Rym: Like, what's that?
Rym: And it was just a bunch of pistachios outside of their shells.
Rym: because I just, you don't see a bowl of shelled pistachios.
Scott: Well, you do if you pay a zillion dollars for them.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But meanwhile, in other countries where they actually have these things growing, they're cheap and plentiful.
Rym: The next thing I knew.
Scott: In the United States, they are expensive and rare.
Rym: I had eaten every single one of them.
Rym: And I had a stomach ache.
Scott: If I go to the grocery store and they have pistachio nuts, they're charging like eight bucks for a tiny bag.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: They are expensive and there is a reason.
Scott: It's because they come from far away.
Scott: That's why they're expensive.
Rym: So who do you think makes the most pistachios?
Rym: Which countries?
Scott: I mean, it's not Turkey?
Rym: Turkey is not number one.
Scott: All right.
Scott: It has to be in that same latitude generally.
Rym: You'd think that.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Maybe the same.
Scott: Yeah, that makes sense.
Scott: Number two is the US.
Scott: I mean, we're just big, right?
Scott: Number three is the most of a lot of things.
Rym: Number three is Turkey, then China, Syria, Greece, Italy, Afghanistan, Australia, and Tunisia.
Scott: Greece got a lot of pistachios for a tiny place.
Scott: They got like an island of pistachio or something?
Rym: Though what's interesting is you look at the yields and the United States has like three times the yields per hectare.
Rym: Like an equivalent sized pistachio farm in the US makes three times more pistachios than Iran does.
Scott: We have better farm technologies.
Rym: Harvesting.
Rym: Ooh, I'm learning about droops.
Scott: Uh-oh.
Rym: I guess they're droops and they're not nuts.
Scott: See, this is the shit I was saying we're not going to talk about.
Scott: Fuck that.
Rym: Hollom and dry.
Scott: It's called a nut.
Scott: It's a nut.
Scott: Anyone who says otherwise, I'm going to get Rym shiv and come after you.
Rym: So I learned something very important because I like pistachios.
Rym: Like we've gotten this out of the way.
Rym: But I also like Turkish Delight.
Scott: Turkish Delight has pistachios in it.
Rym: Yes, and all those like candies.
Scott: Pistachio flavored ice creams, pistachio flavored anything.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: So the thing about the pistachio nut is that you get the saltiness of say the baseball park peanut.
Scott: But you also get sort of like this oily fatty tissue part, sort of like an avocado.
Scott: It's almost like a peanut and an avocado got it on and then protected themselves in a shell because they were too delicious for the world.
Rym: So pistachio baklava was my favorite.
Scott: That's pretty great.
Rym: Until I went to Turkey where they have pistachios.
Rym: You can just get pistachios.
Scott: Were those pistachios better or different than the ones we had here?
Rym: Way better.
Rym: The cheap ones were just amazing.
Rym: Also, they just toast some of them like peanuts.
Rym: Those get toasted salted ones.
Scott: Yeah, see when you don't have a thing that's plentiful and it's too expensive, you often don't want to like, you know, variation on it too much, right?
Scott: So if you only got so many of these, don't fuck them up by roasting them or some shit.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: Right, but when you've got tons of them, it's like we got tons of apples, man.
Scott: We got apple pie, apple cake, apple fritter, apple everything because we got so many of the damn things.
Scott: We got a hundred varieties and whatever.
Rym: Thanks Johnny Appleseed.
Scott: You know, grapes, we got 10 billion wines, 10 billion grape varieties, but pistachios, all we got is pistachio nut in a bag.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: That's it.
Rym: And we don't think about like, "Ooh, does this come from the good trees with the thin shells or is the shitty trees with the thin
Rym: shells?"?
Rym: I got a Macoon pistachio.
Scott: I got a Honeycrisp pistachio.
Scott: It's like we don't do that shit.
Scott: All right.
Rym: So I'm at this dinner and I go to order some pistachio baklava and my business partner is like, "Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Rym: That's a...".
Scott: That is a tourist move.
Rym: He basically said the equivalent of, "That's a noob's
Rym: mistake.".
Scott: A noob's mistake?
Rym: Yes.
Rym: It's like, "You're a baklava amateur.
Rym: Get the walnut
Rym: baklava.".
Scott: I like walnuts.
Scott: Walnuts are nut number two.
Scott: There is no question.
Rym: So I asked him like, "Why?
Rym: Why the walnut?
Rym: Why does that make a better
Rym: baklava?".
Rym: And lo did he tell me over about 15 minutes why walnut is a superior nut for baklava.
Rym: And it comes down to that baklava is sweeter and lighter and you can eat more of it before you feel sick.
Scott: So the walnut, even though pistachio is the best nut, when I'm baking anything and perhaps I've never baked a baklava, but I'm sure that would be all right.
Scott: A walnut is always the go-to nut for baking anything.
Scott: It goes in the chocolate chip cookie.
Rym: A walnut is a nut.
Scott: It goes in the banana bread.
Scott: It goes in just a fucking salad.
Scott: Just take a salad, crunch up some walnuts and chuck it in there.
Rym: I put nuts in my salads.
Rym: Like almost every salad I make, I put nuts in.
Scott: A lot of times, like when I'll go buy salads for lunch, the salad is usually like some kind of lettuces, apples, walnuts, some kind of cheese, some kind of dressing, maybe some other junk thrown in there.
Rym: A walnut is the nut of any tree of the genus Juglans juglandusae.
Scott: Juglans juglandusae?
Rym: Particularly the Persian or English walnut, Juglans regia, is King Juglans.
Rym: Oh no, here's the funny part.
Rym: See if you can guess why I was giggling.
Scott: Juglans juglans?
Rym: It is used for food after being processed while green for pickling walnuts or after full ripening.
Scott: I've never had a pickled walnut.
Rym: For its nut meat.
Rym: Nut meat of the eastern black walnut is less commercially available, as are butternut nut meats.
Scott: So the walnut actually comes in a shell, but rarely do you see it with the shell in the store, right?
Rym: Unless you have one of those poisonous shit fake walnut trees.
Scott: Yeah, so the walnut usually comes out of its shell in a bag, but that's okay, because walnuts really, while being so great to be the number two nut, are not as delicious as pistachio if you're just eating them by the fistful.
Rym: Yes, a raw pistachio just dried without salt or anything on it is super delicious.
Scott: It's so delicious, with salt it just makes it better.
Scott: A walnut, salted or no, is not something you just want to eat.
Scott: I mean, it's okay.
Rym: I prefer them unsalted.
Scott: Sure, but I mean, it's not usually salted, right?
Rym: Well, if they're mixed in with other nuts.
Scott: Even if you roast it, which really brings out the flavor of a walnut more than any other nut, when I bake with a walnut, I will often toast them before putting them in for the baking.
Rym: Yeah, I learned how to toast different kinds of nuts in the Blue Apron.
Scott: Toasting the walnut really brings out the flavor more than any other nut I've ever used, which is part of why it's so good for baking.
Scott: But anyway, it's still, even toasted to perfection, eating a raw walnut isn't really amazing, right?
Scott: It's all about putting it in the baked good so that it combines with sugars and the butters and the flowers and the chocolates and whatever else is in there.
Scott: And usually you buy them in a sack chopped up and they are perhaps even more, if not as expensive, as the pistachio, which is why when you go to like a frozen yogurt place, where they're selling frozen yogurt for like 79 cents an ounce or 49 cents an ounce-
Rym: No walnuts?
Scott: And walnut is one of the available toppings.
Scott: Just scoop walnuts into a cup with no yogurt.
Scott: You are getting a mad deal on that shit, yo.
Rym: Now there's the mega form, the mega evolution of the walnut, the candied walnut.
Scott: Yes, often now I will notice I went to the frozen yogurt place to try to scoop some walnuts.
Scott: They didn't have the walnut just sitting there on its own.
Scott: I think they were onto me.
Scott: They had the walnut suspended in sugary syrup.
Scott: Perhaps it was maple-ish, perhaps it was caramel-ish, whatever.
Rym: That's no good.
Rym: But it was- I'm talking about the candied walnut.
Scott: That's a candied walnut.
Rym: No, but the ones that are like separate individual walnuts with a thin crusty layer.
Scott: Well, how do you think you make that?
Scott: You take it out of the syrup and you leave it out.
Rym: So they leave it just sitting there in the syrup.
Scott: Well, I mean, you know, they don't want it to go bad just sitting there.
Rym: I guess I only ever encountered candied walnuts in like expensive dishes I've ordered at restaurants, like ringed around a salad.
Rym: Like salt and fat and that one salad that we get every time we go there.
Scott: Well, there was that place we went to that had like the one night of, you know, what was it, what country was that?
Rym: Oh, the Finnish thing?
Scott: Yeah, they had some walnut action going on.
Rym: Oh yeah, that was super good.
Rym: Right, so- Was it Finnish, Swedish?
Rym: I already forgot Emily's gonna yell at us when she listens to this.
Scott: Sorry, Northern European country, your food was delicious.
Rym: That place was super good.
Scott: We can't remember you.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway- Well, because it's gone and also that was one of the more expensive dinners we've had in a long time.
Rym: Yeah, we couldn't eat there regularly.
Scott: Well, it was a one night deal, so it was a pop up.
Scott: Anyway, yeah, you're right, the candied walnut and salt and fat is so good, right?
Rym: But that's because it's paired very well with like this particular kind of salad.
Scott: Same thing, it's like.
Scott: the walnut is so powerful, but it only works in combos and you got to do something with it.
Scott: It's not like the pistachio where you can just eat it or combo it.
Scott: The walnut is very relatively weak on its own, but super powerful when comboed.
Scott: It's like a synergy nut.
Rym: So when I was young, like when I was really young, I pretty much considered the cashew to be the king of all nuts.
Scott: Cashew's okay.
Rym: Because I liked cashews a lot.
Scott: I mean, I like a cashew, but it's not like it's up there with the pistachio and the walnut.
Rym: Yeah, but they're one of the nuts that I can eat in bulk when I'm hungry and feel pretty good about it.
Scott: So I would often go to the Duane Reade and they had this magic mix and the magic mix used to be called Raisin Nut Mix before they changed the brand.
Scott: And basically what it is, is peanuts, cashews, M&Ms and some other junk mixed together in a bag.
Scott: So I realized they were charging a lot of money for that.
Scott: I realized that by weight, I could actually save money by making it myself.
Scott: So I go to the grocery store, I would buy a thing of peanuts, a thing of cashews, a thing of sunflower seeds, a thing of M&Ms or chocolate chips.
Scott: And sort of mix all that together in a bag and shake it up.
Scott: And that is a delicious magic mix of nutness that you can get.
Scott: You don't have to do the chocolate if you want.
Scott: You can put dried fruit in there, some raisin.
Scott: Raisin is good in there.
Scott: I was Raisin Nut Mix originally, right?
Scott: You can also put like some dried, any kind of fruit you want.
Scott: Apricot, pineapple, whatever, you know.
Scott: It's a really good nut usage where you can get the full power out of something like the peanut or the cashew by making a trail-ish mix out of it.
Rym: So, not that I'm not a fan of, actually.
Rym: I think my least favorite nut is the Brazil Nut.
Rym: I don't eat- That's the big motherfucker that's hanging out in the mixed nuts.
Rym: that kind of just tastes dry and bland and is just in the way.
Scott: I don't eat the Brazil Nut very often, but I think I might agree with you except for the fact that I specifically dislike the chestnut.
Rym: What?
Rym: The chestnut's one of my favorite nuts.
Scott: So the chestnut, I mean, maybe it's because you're a goyim, right?
Scott: But the Jews don't really eat the chestnut.
Rym: Why not?
Scott: It's like a holiday Christmas goyim thing.
Rym: Yeah, it's also just like a delicious thing.
Scott: I mean, I tried it once and it's sort of like I'll put it over there with the eggnog, right?
Rym: Wait, how did you try a chestnut?
Scott: You know how they have them, they're all heated up, right?
Scott: And they're in the shell, you open the shell, you take the nut out and you eat it.
Rym: See, the real secret is you get chestnut things.
Rym: Kind of like with walnuts and baking, get like a chestnut pastry.
Scott: I guess that could be okay.
Rym: You know who has these?
Scott: If you're ever downtown- Well, like when you're in New York City, right?
Rym: The hot dog vendors in the winter- No, no, fuck those guys.
Rym: Fuck the street nuts.
Scott: They always have the little- I never had eaten one of those.
Rym: Well, most of those guys are selling like other weird nuts or they're selling like just almonds.
Scott: Right, but I'm not talking about the nuts truck.
Scott: I'm talking about the guy who sells hot dogs, but in the winter he brings out the chestnut tray where he's got a little circle thing with tinfoil with chestnuts in it near this fire, right?
Scott: And he's heating them up.
Scott: And they're, you know, it's like.
Scott: I didn't have that from those guys, but I basically had that at like a friend's house who was roasting chestnuts and I'm not into it really.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: You run into them a lot in Turkey.
Rym: Like every street corner there's just chestnuts everywhere.
Rym: But I don't really like them that much in that form.
Rym: I actually like them in-.
Rym: If you go to Takahachi, that really good Japanese bakery downtown, kind of by City Hall, they have basically blueberry and chestnut pastries- Oh, that could be good.
Rym: That have like cheese.
Rym: They're so good.
Rym: I eat one like at least once a week.
Rym: One of the two.
Scott: I'll eat that.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Crazy, dangerously good.
Scott: But I mean, there's no way that that can approach anywhere near walnut, pistachio or even peanut level.
Rym: No, it's better than peanut.
Rym: Peanut's a different purpose because peanut is the default nut and it's the savory nut.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Well, in the United States peanut is the default nut and people like to look down on it the same way that like someone who eats fancy hamburgers might look down on a McDonald's.
Rym: Like they see the peanuts in the mixed nuts box as filler.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's like you should look down on the McDonald's, right?
Scott: But you should not look down on the peanut.
Scott: The peanut is the default nut, but it is so, you know, popular.
Scott: that doesn't mean that it's bad.
Scott: A peanut is super delicious.
Scott: Peanut butter.
Rym: I prefer actually peanuts.
Scott: I like- Going to the baseball game, buying a bag of peanuts, making a big mess, letting someone else sweep it up.
Rym: I like wasabi peanuts.
Scott: Honey roasted peanut.
Rym: I'm not a big fan of honey roasted-.
Scott: See, peanut is so common, right, that you can start to get these variations on it that you can't do with the other nut.
Scott: It's like, you know, pistachio and turkey, peanut in the U.S.
Scott: And it's still good.
Scott: If I lived in Turkey and I came to the
Scott: U.S.,
Scott: I'd be like, "Oh my God,
Scott: peanuts.".
Rym: See, my favorite kind of peanut, bar none, is the simple oil-roasted peanut with a little bit of salt.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: That is the best form of peanut in the world, in my opinion.
Rym: Because dry roasted gets kind of like dusty if you're eating a lot of them.
Rym: Like you can't eat a lot without feeling sick.
Scott: Do you still eat the shells like a nut job?
Rym: Well, so we're talking about now.
Rym: I'm only talking about peanuts that are not in their shells.
Scott: Oh, see, I was talking about the shell when I was talking about the baseball game.
Rym: Yeah, well, the baseball game peanut is a different kind of peanut experience.
Scott: It's all the same nut, yo.
Rym: Yeah, but those are brined and it's not like the salt or dry or roasted outside.
Scott: How do they get the salt in there?
Rym: To this day, I've occasionally run into people who exclaim something to that effect when I'm eating around us.
Scott: They have a tiny syringe and they squirt salt into everyone.
Scott: There's a hole, you just can't find it.
Rym: They're artisanal.
Rym: No, they actually bred them.
Rym: That salt's natural.
Scott: They put salt in the dirt.
Scott: It doesn't kill the peanut.
Rym: That's totally fine.
Rym: But I don't eat those kinds of peanuts that often.
Scott: I eat peanut butter more than I eat peanuts, but I will eat peanut rather often.
Scott: You know, usually in the bag of magic mix or something like that that I put together.
Rym: Wow, there is a question on the straight dope and someone is just like, "So, I've seen this happen in movies.
Rym: Do people actually eat the entire peanut, including the
Rym: shell?".
Scott: I do not.
Rym: The first post is my mom used to.
Scott: That is disgusting.
Rym: I do it sometimes.
Scott: The outside part is not food.
Scott: That is like eating the, I don't know, like the rind of an orange or the peel on a banana.
Rym: Oh, you know what I've never had?
Scott: You don't eat that.
Rym: Someone has suggested deep fry peanuts in the shells and then eat the whole thing.
Scott: I guess that could be better, but you could just deep fry peanuts.
Rym: Okay, I used to eat salted in the shell peanuts hole.
Rym: I grew up eating that way.
Rym: I discovered that if you eat too many of them, you experience a phenomenon that would be best described as anal splinters.
Scott: Yes, don't do that.
Rym: Usually what I do is I'd eat like every fifth or sixth one.
Rym: I just eat the whole thing.
Scott: Something else though about the peanut is that unlike other nuts, you know, I talked about the walnut needs like an upgrade.
Scott: The peanut, you can't upgrade it too much besides peanut butter, right?
Scott: Wasabi.
Scott: Sure, but you can downgrade it by making peanut brittle, which is disgusting old people candy.
Rym: What's wrong with you?
Scott: Peanut brittle is fine.
Scott: As disgusting old people candy that you should not eat.
Rym: I think you're just hung up on the name and the fact that it features in a lot of media involving old ladies.
Scott: No, I would eat it when it would come in Halloween.
Scott: Some old lady would give it to you and it was never good.
Scott: I've tried to eat it so many times.
Scott: Even go into places where it's like, you know, you go to like a tourist place and there'll be like a fudge and, you know, some butterscotch sticks and there'll be some peanut brittle.
Scott: And I would get like one everything and the peanut brittle was like, why did I get that?
Scott: I should have gotten just more fudge.
Rym: Yeah, I'm a fan of the peanut.
Rym: The problem is peanuts, like any other, but more so than any other nut.
Rym: If there's a bowl of peanuts and I'm near them pretty much, I'm going to eat them all.
Scott: Goodbye.
Scott: Yeah, that's why I put the peanut is even above the cashew.
Scott: If there's a bowl of cashews, I'm not just going to dig in like crazy.
Rym: Well, I'll kind of alternate between the two.
Scott: I mean, I will eat them, but I won't like.
Rym: If I was going to make my magic mix of like nuts to have out just for like casual consumption at a party, there'd be one bowl that was a mix of cashews and peanuts.
Rym: One bowl that was just pistachios and one bowl that was just toasted pistachios.
Scott: I usually take my magic mix and I put it in a. I'll put it all in one big giant Ziploc bag, the big kind and shake it up like crazy.
Scott: And then I'll go biking or something and I'll pour out a little bit from the big bag into a little bag and take that with me in a little jersey pocket thing.
Scott: And that's that's how you do.
Rym: I'm kind of done with pecans other than in pie.
Scott: Yeah, pecan is really like a pie only kind of deal.
Scott: I mean, I've never I think maybe a few times I've eaten them, not in a pie.
Scott: And it was like like while I was making a pie, maybe I don't know.
Scott: Or maybe while someone else is making a pie.
Scott: And it's not something I really want to eat too much.
Scott: It's not like ew, I don't want to eat this like the chestnut area.
Scott: But it's not like, you know, I mean, if if there was a bowl of them next to a bowl of cashews, I probably wouldn't even need one pecan.
Scott: But if there was a pie, I would cut off a nice slice.
Rym: But I think the nut I'm the most sick of, of all things, is actually the almond.
Rym: Like, I don't like most.
Rym: most forms that almond are presented to me in as nuts.
Rym: Well, they're not nuts.
Rym: They're droops.
Rym: The fruit of the almond is a droop.
Scott: So the almond, I actually like the almond a lot, especially when it's put in the chocolate bar.
Rym: Exactly.
Rym: I like that form of almond.
Scott: But I also like just an almond, a sack of almonds.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Sometimes they'll put the almonds in the magic mix.
Scott: The thing is, I think the almond is a lot like the cilantro.
Scott: I think there are some people who just they try to eat the almond, then it's no good for them.
Rym: See, it's not that though.
Rym: Like, I liked almond.
Rym: You see them a lot, but I'm kind of sick of them.
Rym: And they're usually like too dry or they don't fit the other things I've got around.
Scott: The other thing is that almond prices are going up and there's a lot of things people are doing with almonds, like almond milk.
Scott: Right.
Scott: People don't know this.
Scott: Well, some people know this.
Scott: You can use almond extract instead of vanilla extract.
Rym: And you probably won't even notice the difference.
Scott: Well, no, it's actually sometimes it could be way better.
Scott: Depends on what you're baking, which one you want to choose.
Scott: But they're both really expensive.
Scott: But almond extract is like that's hot stuff to have for like, you want to step up your baking like next level.
Scott: Instead of using vanilla for everything, figure out when to use the almond and when to use the vanilla.
Rym: I guess I only like almonds like with olives and in almost no other context as just a nut on its own.
Scott: I could eat a sack of almonds.
Rym: I wouldn't though.
Scott: More readily than cashews.
Rym: I would eat a sack of cashews.
Rym: In fact, I did eat a sack of cashews over the last two and a half days.
Rym: So I just bought a big sack of them.
Rym: I set them on my desk because I'm stupid.
Rym: Now they're gone.
Scott: All right.
Rym: Hence my tweet earlier.
Scott: The almonds are also good.
Scott: If you're going to make mixes with almonds, it's usually better with fruity mixes.
Scott: Almonds and dates, almonds and figs.
Rym: I like almond with something.
Rym: I don't like almond by itself.
Scott: By itself is good, but with the chocolate, with the fruit is better.
Rym: And it's got to be toasted.
Rym: I don't like raw almonds either.
Scott: I like the ones when they have the little skin on them still.
Scott: If the skin is gone, then it's not having a problem.
Scott: I need that little skin there.
Scott: I like the pistachio with a little skin way better also.
Rym: When I'm cooking, blanched olives and things are sometimes useful.
Scott: Actually, I think with every kind of nut, I like the little skin that's on there.
Rym: All right.
Rym: We have talked about nuts for 55 minutes.
Scott: Well, some of that was news time.
Rym: Some of it was.
Rym: I think we can stop talking about nuts.
Scott: See, I told you this is the right topic.
Rym: Yeah, it was a good show.
Scott: Send us your other nut varieties.
Scott: Do not tell us what is and is not a nut.
Scott: You can shove it.
Rym: That's a bannable offense.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Scott: The assigned value is $100, and I hold in my hand the last piece of art.
Rym: Item number 69, a watercolor titled Exchanging Fluids by Brian Swards of York.
Rym: The dimensions are 24 inches wide by 19 inches high.
Scott: And this is really, we were saying, kind of a companion piece to the Brian Swards piece that we had up on the table previously.
Rym: Actually, this one should have come up first, and that should have been the later piece.
Scott: A little bit on both, right?
Scott: And anyhow, it also is self-explanatory, certainly.
Rym: Once again, our final piece for the 1992 Gallery 33 is item number 69, a watercolor titled Exchanging Fluids by Brian Swards of York.