Rym: It's Monday, June 15th, 2015.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I am the sky and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: What are we talking about?
Rym: Tonight we're talking about sneaker net.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: So I was unduly productive over the weekend because I had a bunch of you know I had a panel from PAX South and then a bunch of other video from PAX South and a panel from PAX East Bunch of other video from PAX East and I had to like edit that shit together so I can put it on YouTube like we've been Kind of dormant on YouTube for a while.
Rym: We've just been really busy with other stuff.
Scott: I'm gonna be not dormant on.
Scott: Saturday is a big netrunner tournament.
Scott: live stream Live stream.
Scott: reach out if their internet works.
Scott: I'm watching and to get there.
Scott: bring all this shit.
Scott: their internet's not gonna work.
Rym: Well, then you just got to record it all and upload it or live stream over LTE Like one megabit per second or something.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Hey for that.
Rym: I don't know What?
Rym: don't you have free unlimited bandwidth or anything?
Scott: You don't have free unlimited LTE?
Rym: I could get away with a lot as Teemo.
Scott: Anyway, so live streaming from like 11 a.m.
Rym: To 2 in the morning Independently of that the you know Adobe.
Rym: We know a lot of people who are running like some crazy old ass version of like Premiere like they bought production premium or something like Four or five years ago.
Rym: Well, if you don't
Scott: have a lot of money and you did save up your money and spend thousands of dollars on that a long Time ago and it still gets the job done Why would you start paying 50 bucks a month to get creative cloud if the old one is still working for you?
Scott: And you don't aren't like getting files from people with creative cloud that you need to be compatible.
Rym: There is a case to be made there if you don't use the software that much and you already own one of those old versions Sure, but a lot of people say they don't want to upgrade Because like it's not better or they don't trust those.
Scott: those are the same people.
Scott: listen You should up.
Scott: I'm not talking that anybody Should be upgrading to like beta untested versions that you know pre releases.
Rym: But if you have like a production pipeline of creative stuff, you should just always be Use the.
Scott: no not just Adobe.
Scott: like everything.
Scott: Windows update if there's updates in Windows update install them and video driver if there's an update Install.
Rym: so did you see with Windows 10?
Rym: What are the great things they're doing?
Rym: if you have the home version you cannot defer or prevent updates?
Rym: They just happen.
Rym: Fuck you good.
Scott: I like that.
Rym: Yeah, I like that.
Scott: It's like if there's a new version of Chrome.
Scott: I mean, it's just updating without you doing anything, but you should just update.
Rym: I prefer Firebird version 3.1 If you know.
Scott: if you're using Linux just app.
Scott: get this to upgrade.
Scott: Get upgrade whenever right.
Scott: just if there's upgrades get them.
Scott: you should upgrade everything all the time constantly.
Scott: you know some person's gonna be like oh my Predictions.
Scott: it's like whatever.
Scott: Give a shit.
Scott: Well fine.
Scott: I've done this on every computer forever and I have less computer problems than everybody.
Rym: You know what I'd say if you're.
Scott: one of those reasons is because I update and patch everything.
Scott: I'm very.
Rym: if your pipeline is such that it's that prone to disruption and disruption is that bad.
Rym: You should have a UAT environment.
Scott: Anyway, obviously, so I Heavily update everything.
Scott: I'm super up-to-date on patches and that's one of the reasons my shit always works great But anyway, not enough to derail.
Rym: so especially with Premiere and like video editing workflows Premiere 4 is Kind of garbage.
Scott: Well, I had Premiere Elements before like when you're in beacon Wow, and that was Way garbage compared to the real Premiere But I've been so that's better that premiere elements was better than like premiere.
Rym: like guys if you edit video And you're not using like the most recent Adobe Creative Cloud premiere
Scott: or Final Cut
Rym: The Creative Cloud is like breaking away from the pack at least with premieres specifically Which
Scott: is a Mac only thing anyway,
Rym: yeah The only reason the thing I'm about to say happened is because I'm on the updated version.
Rym: So I found like oh, yeah, Dave Riley and AJ did this great panel at Connecticut like years ago Yeah, and I videoed it.
Rym: cuz I video like everything like.
Rym: I have like tons of old videos.
Scott: I got lots of video of stuff and lots of photos of stuff that it is not posted any.
Rym: Yeah, and in that same directory I also had a panel that Luke Crane did like at 2013 at a PAX and I was like, oh, right I had these things.
Rym: I had the audio and like everything into directory and I never done anything with him because it's a pain in The ass like sync everything up and you know, just do all the stuff but I don't.
Rym: there's a feature now where you can take a whole bunch of just clips just random crap and just say hey synchronize this via the audio and Premiere just figures that out.
Rym: Yep, so I did that and now I have this panel that Dave Riley did in 2012 at Connecticut This other panel Luke Crane did in 2013 at PAX and they're already on YouTube.
Rym: I'm just gonna make him go live like in a couple days.
Rym: The only reason I didn't do it today is because I just uploaded two other videos.
Scott: one of the other things the feature they added somewhat recently ish is in if you're doing speed grade or any kind of color grading instead of like sitting there twiddling with all the color grading settings because you Don't know anything about those.
Scott: cuz you're not you're me and you're not a professional.
Rym: Well, you're means you're me too.
Rym: You're all of us.
Rym: You can just.
Scott: you can just find a photo any photograph that's already graded like the way you want.
Scott: Drag that photo in and it will grade the video to match the color grading in that photo.
Rym: Whoa How well does that work?
Scott: It'll even do it across.
Scott: You can drag in a whole bunch of different video files into the sequence from different cameras and such and it will grade all of Them because
Rym: I just always started really playing around with Lumetri looks which are kind of like baby's first color grading And they already work like way Way better than what I used to do of like trying to set like a luminosity curve or whatever for a video.
Scott: Well, I mean they work better if you record the video Yeah, the great contrast is possible.
Scott: Yeah, so if you want if you want to color grade from now on I'll record the videos in the big grade.
Rym: No, I don't because that means that there's another step that I have to do or I otherwise the video will look gray.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, no I use color grading just to make my arb like pretty badly put together video look a little bit better.
Rym: Anyway, anyway, so yeah, I got a bunch of YouTube videos Thanks to the fact that I just upgrade my software and yeah, like new features come all the time All right.
Rym: Yeah, so it's Monday not the lounge.
Rym: It's tech day.
Scott: So those big Apple news and for once we didn't talk about it till way after just cuz of how scheduling work.
Scott: Usually Apple news seems to always come inside with Monday shows.
Scott: I guess this time it didn't.
Scott: so the WDC happened which is what they usually announce stuff developers care about.
Scott: Yeah, but really there were it was pretty minor.
Scott: It's just like yeah, we're making a new OS X. We're doing the same thing We always do which is take features that everyone else has had for a long long time and bring them over to our platforms Right.
Scott: There are really only a few things that were interesting at all.
Scott: the first one is That they have their language Swift.
Scott: that was the language they invented for writing iOS apps.
Scott: They're gonna just open source that whole language.
Scott: What does that mean?
Scott: Well, hopefully if they're being true to their word, they're actually gonna fully open source the language.
Scott: It means you'll be able to use the Swift programming language to program anything You could make a Windows game or an Android app or a website.
Rym: Oh Is actually pretty big news.
Rym: if it really happens like fully the way if you're a Swift developer You won't just be a useless.
Scott: if you learn Swift you won't just be Learning, you know how to make iOS apps.
Scott: It's like a language that you can use and use for everything.
Scott: So it.
Scott: I think the reason they're doing this is to encourage people to learn Swift right to increase the size of that community around their language because obviously Swift is gonna be best at writing iOS apps, which is what it was invented for Mac or Mac apps.
Scott: Yeah, so by making it open source, it means like they don't make any money selling it directly.
Rym: They can build this community and get more people to develop things for Macs and to buy Macs to use this language as opposed to say, you know Java is supposed to be the you know, use this code anywhere but Exists in a different ecosystem.
Rym: Oracle's kind of mismanaged it for a long time.
Scott: Son may also manage it right and also because the language is open-sourced, right?
Scott: That doesn't just mean that anyone can use it for anything and anyone can make libraries for it.
Scott: It means that someone can go out there can make a patch for Swift that changes the language and Send it to Apple and possibly have it be included in the official, you know, like in Xcode or whatever.
Scott: Yeah Anyway, that was interesting.
Scott: How far they actually take that right.
Rym: like if you're a kid in college Switch the language.
Scott: You should probably just learn it doesn't hurt.
Scott: Yeah, it's not bad.
Scott: Um Let's see any other.
Scott: they're making a music thing.
Scott: No one gives a shit.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Oh, here's an interesting one, right?
Scott: I remember they're making an app for Android that makes it easy to switch over to iOS.
Scott: You put this on your Android phone you you open it up you get your new iPhone You just bought and it'll copy over a whole bunch of stuff to ease your transition.
Rym: That's a really good idea.
Scott: Well, it's not like Android can possibly do this with iOS.
Scott: It's there right there blocking you from doing that.
Scott: Yeah, if you tried to submit a migrate to Android app for iOS into the App Store that shit ain't getting approved.
Rym: I said it's a really good idea.
Scott: That's a big guy.
Scott: You know, that could be a trust issue even right?
Rym: We'll see what happens with that, but I will admit, you know My phone exploded not that long ago, and I didn't want to buy a new phone yet.
Rym: Because even if I want to go iPhone, I mean September's coming like I'm not gonna buy a phone now.
Rym: Literally right now like this month Probably the worst possible time to buy an iPhone might as well just wait a little bit.
Scott: all the new Apple stuff happens in September October.
Scott: guys in this year since iPhone 6 came out last year it's gonna be iPhone 6s and It's gonna be a bad idea to buy it because it's only gonna be a little bit better than the iPhone 6 unless I have an iPhone.
Rym: if you're on like the five and you need a new one five is a great phone.
Scott: Well, you don't need a new one if you got a five.
Scott: Yeah, some people might maybe they broke theirs I don't know but next year September there's gonna be the iPhone 7 guaranteed 100%.
Scott: I can't wait till next year and then that is the phone you should buy.
Scott: I'll be buying it because I have iPhone 6 that I or anyway.
Scott: But this year is the year that there's gonna be a huge step up in iPads.
Scott: since last September There's only a little bit step up in iPads.
Scott: There's gonna be a big step up in iPads now and they just announced in the new iOS.
Scott: They're gonna support side-by-side Multitasking.
Scott: so like you can actually have two apps open actually fully open at once and see them both at one.
Rym: Oh, it's like a laptop computer.
Rym: It's like Windows 3.1 all over again.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: and then like this is really useful for copy and pasting from one to the other.
Rym: It's really useful for everything.
Scott: that's watching you watching a YouTube video in the corner while you write something in Google Drive or This is why The Windows interfaces.
Rym: people were going down that road of just have one big window like one big screen like full screen every app.
Scott: Well, they're still limiting it.
Scott: Your choices are basically split the screen in half Make one app sort of sneak in on the side or the app uses a special API like the YouTube one.
Scott: So I just play a video in the corner.
Rym: I'm just talking, forget technology, I'm talking purely from UX perspective.
Rym: Microsoft and Apple both had this road.
Scott: They were going down Apple much more so of Monolithic full-screen apps doing things on computers because most people the vast majority of people I think even using a you know multitask user interface Tend to just maximize one app that they're using except that you think that.
Rym: but I was thinking about this a lot because I do UX my day job.
Scott: Well, this is why see people do that on Windows.
Scott: I think the thing is on OS X. they reason they don't let you maximize things properly was to force people to Realize they could and multitask.
Scott: right if you look at Apple users they rarely full even like full screen was a recent feature.
Scott: People rarely full screen usually have a cluttered-ass screen full of windows open sort of like a Windows prison as a cluttered-ass screen icon.
Scott: yeah, right because Maximizing doesn't really fucking work properly the way it does in Windows.
Scott: So you're you know, you sort of forced into this multi window multitasking People who have to use computers to do boring crap at their jobs.
Rym: Pretty much everything they do involves having multiple windows of things open at the same time and looking at the same time Looking at a spreadsheet and typing something into something else.
Rym: Yeah, or right now what I got?
Rym: I got audition up and then next to that in the same monitor I got the next news thing.
Rym: We're gonna talk about and then on the second monitor.
Rym: I got a notepad or I'm taking show notes.
Scott: but anyway the You know, this is even good for just having a candy box next to a web browser.
Rym: that's no that's bad.
Scott: It's heavy candy box always open on the side while you get your real stuff going on the other side.
Scott: But anyway, this is apparently on the big iPad.
Scott: It's gonna work better than on the smaller iPad.
Scott: Maybe depending on what they announced in September I might get the full size iPad instead of the mini iPad that I have now.
Scott: Because the problem with the mini iPad I have now the only thing really wrong with it Is that it only has 16 gigs of storage and Apple fucking rips you off and they're not gonna stop ripping you off.
Scott: to get The 128 gig one you basically to pay two or three hundred extra dollars, dude I can get a 128 gig USB stick for like 30 bucks.
Scott: and you're telling me that to put 128 gigs inside the iPad instead of 16 I got to pay 300.
Scott: Oh my god go fuck yourself, but I sort of have no choice because It really doesn't work.
Scott: Well with 16 gigs you fill that shit up so fast.
Scott: I'd like delete apps like it's the DOS days because I'm running out of storage.
Scott: Yeah, I put photos on here.
Rym: you think now like what I have paid this much money amortized over the time I've owned this thing.
Scott: I think I think they should be legally required to have an open storage slot where you can put an SD card in and fuck You.
Rym: yeah, cuz SD cards are tiny.
Scott: I think it's price-fixing too.
Scott: I think right maybe FTC?
Scott: I would say it's price-fixing.
Scott: I say Apple.
Scott: Why is this one three hundred dollars more than that one when the only difference in parts whatsoever is this $30 chip?
Rym: Why you can unless they're a man, how is that not price-fixing?
Rym: That's not what price-fixing means.
Rym: Okay Price-fixing would be if they coordinated with other tablet manufacturers to make sure no one had expandable storage and they all agreed to do that.
Rym: Then you could go after.
Scott: we need a new term for whatever.
Scott: this is because it should be illegal.
Scott: if it's not You know what it is.
Rym: I'll tell you what the term is.
Rym: It's Apple gouging Apple.
Scott: Is that illegal?
Rym: You don't gouge an apple you take a bite out of it.
Rym: So fuckers there's a big initiative among the US government the British government and other governments in general to Basically either weaken encryption by making legal requirements to have backdoors.
Rym: Nope.
Rym: or to outlaw encryption.
Rym: Nope, this has been a thing since the 80s.
Rym: Yeah, I mean we've talked about this on GeekNights before but it's coming up.
Scott: You know the EFF that they exist because of this court case from a long time ago with PGP.
Rym: yep Was regular, you know pretty good encryption.
Rym: It was basically or pretty good privacy.
Rym: I guess it stood for us.
Rym: It wasn't about a Powerful encryption system.
Rym: that was very much Yeah Mathematically simple easy to use and it was classified by the US government and other shitty governments as a weapon and banned from exports and The only so you were.
Rym: technically it was illegal to explain to someone who was not an American citizen How to use it, but every American everyone knew this math.
Scott: It's not a real secret.
Rym: So there was this crazy shenanigans That's like Zimmerman.
Scott: Don't tell the Russians about multiplication.
Rym: They they can't know.
Rym: they published the source code as a printed book Exported the book and then someone typed it back in to get around the law, right?
Rym: So this bullshit is not new but it's escalating Partly because the snowed by the way, we won that case a long time ago.
Rym: we did but the governments of the world are frantically trying to put that genie back in the bottle.
Rym: and they could succeed because the one thing that Trump's encryption is Guns, basically, right?
Scott: So give me your private key or you will die to highlight in my opinion the necessity.
Scott: I've already destroyed my private key.
Scott: Yep, you're shooting me.
Scott: We'll get you nowhere.
Scott: That's that's the way to go.
Rym: But there's other ways to use that.
Rym: for example, I have incriminating information on the government basically Blackmail against some sort of corruption.
Rym: I put that data in an encrypted store publicly.
Rym: There's millions of copies of it.
Rym: It cannot be destroyed.
Rym: the key Some people have that key.
Rym: I Might not have that key.
Rym: someone has the key.
Rym: if Scott sets me on fire Someone who has the key finds out because I didn't check in and then that data magically gets revealed to the world.
Scott: So basically like oh if you destroy me the date the information that you were trying to keep secret will be revealed and right.
Scott: so You can't touch me Unless you're willing to you know, get the blackmail revealed on you.
Rym: another aspect of encryption is that it's actually a fundamental component of actually being able to put data in places Anonymously, it's a big part of that.
Rym: so to combine those two things There's a story here that apparently is not an uncommon story where a journalist in India used a Facebook page to publish information about some government corruption and He though he posted under pseudonym people figured out who he was tracked him down and the police burned him alive.
Scott: The police burned him alive.
Scott: That is what appears to have happened wouldn't I mean if in the United States?
Rym: Well, the police better get on arresting these people.
Scott: no I mean even I would you know, even if police burn someone alive, right?
Scott: In that case, right?
Scott: I mean if they shoot someone it's like there's a police protocol for that They burn someone alive.
Scott: the FBI would come happen.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So there are big investigations everything going on But isn't there an FBI of India there is but I have a it's also corrupt.
Rym: That's my suspicion.
Scott: see as you know, well, I'm sure every part of the US government is corrupt.
Scott: I sort of get a feeling that the FBI is slightly less corrupt.
Rym: if our government was that corrupt like a lot like Snowden wouldn't Be alive today.
Scott: It's like as much corruption as we have.
Scott: like the amount of corruption that goes on everywhere else in the world is actually way way Worse.
Scott: It's the point where like people are just used to it.
Rym: Yeah I mean a cop pulls you over in the US like you can't just slip him a $50 bill and expect that that's gonna make it be okay.
Scott: that will make it worse Right now many areas.
Scott: if you're in Italy, you're just expected to slip over.
Scott: Yeah a $50 bill.
Scott: That's so.
Rym: that's what you do Basically, I mean I urge you to read this because even if this isn't a concern in the US encryption and Anonymous speech on the internet like actually anonymous speech.
Rym: the same, you know system that allows 8chan gamergate bullshit to happen Could be used to prevent this journalist from being murdered.
Rym: So encryption and anonymous speech come with a whole bunch of bad consequences both society and technologically But the consequences of not having them are far worse and if governments start pushing to actually ban this stuff You really need to be mad enough about that to do something.
Scott: on a tangent if you're the one being black mailed for pretty much Anything ever there's only two possibilities.
Scott: one you did or are guilty of whatever someone's going blackmailing.
Rym: I already have my counterpoint ready for you or be you're not guilty.
Scott: All right, you're guilty Just admit it so they can't black now.
Rym: Here's the blackmail.
Rym: I'm a Russian politician where homosexuality is basically illegal.
Rym: Okay, blackmail is proof that I'm homosexual.
Scott: it just admit it.
Rym: and then what I get kicked out of office and possibly jailed.
Scott: That's tough shit.
Scott: You just got deal with it.
Rym: You what do you mean?
Rym: You just got to deal with it.
Scott: I mean, you know stand up for being gay and then you know.
Scott: Maybe you'll think that'll help fix things.
Rym: Don't you think you could do better by being in the government as an incognito gay and then working to undermine the system?
Rym: What if you're the right?
Scott: is that ever worked?
Rym: There were a lot of moderately high-profile Nazis who were actually agents who were working hard on stuff like that Like stuff.
Rym: that stuff happens.
Scott: Are you saying that?
Scott: The gay Russian politician is a spy.
Scott: All right, fine.
Rym: What if this journalist here who was murdered by the police in India?
Rym: Someone a third party broke his encryption and blackmailed him saying look Pay me money, or I'll reveal to the police that you're the one who exposes their corruption.
Scott: I'd be like leave the country.
Rym: All right, I reveal Yeah, that that that is an option.
Rym: but then again like Simon rosy like you got attacked way outside of his country of origin.
Rym: Multiple times people chased him.
Rym: how many people were murdered by the KGB outside of Russia?
Scott: Just saying well Letterman admitted to having sex with like his staff When someone tried to blackmail him.
Rym: if it's not a Scene to cause him if it's not a situation like that Like where the thing that you're guilty of is not and should not be a crime, but you'll be murdered or fucked for it.
Rym: Anyway, yeah post your like Sonic the Hedgehog furry porn and cosplay outfit and be like, yep.
Rym: That was me.
Rym: Yep, I'm still running for president.
Scott: bring it because the pain of that is not as bad as the pain of having to pay Some asshole a bunch of money or whatever they want.
Scott: Interestingly.
Scott: I've learned recently Blackmailing you for like a dollar, right?
Scott: I guess that's always possible.
Rym: I am not like Scott.
Scott: Give me a dollar or else I'll set your house on fire.
Scott: It's like here's a dollar.
Rym: All right, we're good.
Rym: Then I'm a racketeer, I guess I don't know but apparently it is.
Rym: it is illegal to blackmail someone.
Rym: Yeah, obviously Sort of but actually there's a lot of situations where depending on how it's framed It's not what.
Scott: give me one of those situations.
Scott: Oh, so I may execute upon it.
Scott: So here's why I know many things.
Rym: It is not illegal to pay Blackmail money.
Scott: No, of course not.
Rym: So if someone just says hey, I have all these really embarrassing photos of you I found isn't that funny?
Rym: and he doesn't directly threaten you and you separately say hey Here's the keys to my this condo that I own.
Rym: use it whenever you want to pay that blackmail.
Rym: You probably couldn't actually take any legal action against those people.
Rym: Nope so Really?
Rym: It appears that it's easy to blackmail people in such a way that it would be very hard to prosecute you for blackmailing them.
Rym: Mmm now I'm just thinking about that Monty Python skin the blackmail show.
Rym: I'll link to that as a secondary thing at the day, right?
Scott: But if you don't suggest like let's say I have a website I put it up with a bunch of embarrassing photos of Rym and It has a password so no one can get to it.
Scott: and I send Rym like hey check out this website And I send you the URL and the password.
Scott: Yeah, all I say is hey check out this website you check it out.
Scott: You go.
Scott: Oh, oh shit.
Scott: And but you see there's a password on it.
Scott: I haven't said anything else.
Scott: I can't say anything else.
Scott: I can't say pay me money or I can't write up.
Scott: How do you get the hint that you're gonna have to be?
Scott: you just don't realize.
Scott: you just think oh shit Scott's gonna reveal.
Rym: Well, see you think that it.
Rym: this comes down to.
Rym: how naive are you and how dumb is the blackmailer right?
Rym: This is like that burning wheel game where we failed our write test and then our cohort failed their read test.
Rym: So one other news.
Rym: I'm not gonna talk about the lot but this is so amazingly cool.
Rym: So there's in the culture books There's the neural net mesh Which is like this technology where you basically put this like net this mesh inside of your brain And then it's like an awesome machine interface.
Rym: It's like a cyber brain and ghost in the shell.
Rym: That technology is actually kind of real and there have been some big breakthroughs in it recently and they're injecting with needles Meshes into the brains of rats in a manner that not only does not kill them But allows the brain to be sort of analyzed on a level we've never been able to analyze a working brain before.
Rym: Okay, this stuff is so cool.
Scott: Just another step towards our ghost in the shell future.
Rym: Yes, and also the article is Terrifying to read just by the nature of what and how what they're doing and how they're doing it.
Rym: And it's phrased in this very sort of neutral language.
Rym: but reading between the lines Horrifying death is a common failure condition in this kind of research things of the day.
Rym: There's this thing.
Rym: I actually encountered a very similar thing way back when I worked at IBM because that IBM in This one facility at IBM and this one department at IBM this one part of IBM.
Rym: I won't say what part there.
Rym: Some DNS servers that are pretty important.
Rym: They're like the root DNS servers for this stuff.
Scott: I did the root DNS servers for IBM com.
Rym: No So they also post some other services Like.
Rym: I think there's some.
Scott: are these ancient IBM mainframes like with COBOL and shit.
Rym: No, no, nothing like that.
Rym: So I think there's some socks and spinning tape wheels God Do you even remember or know what socks is as an HTTP proxy kind of thing sort of yeah Yeah, so it's got some bunch of services running like old ass services.
Rym: It was some OS 2 warp machines.
Scott: Oh, yeah It's an IBM thing that hadn't been powered off since before.
Scott: I saw Warp was the weird one that you got on like your home system.
Scott: That also was Windows 3.1.
Scott: I thought that other the real servers used just like OS 2 not OS 2.
Rym: Well, this was always to warp and actually it had been updated periodically.
Rym: So it was a version of that that never made it outside of IBM.
Rym: It was like a real like they kept using it.
Scott: development Wonder if you can run it in VirtualBox.
Rym: I have it.
Rym: I have the full install and documentation for it.
Rym: It was a parting gift when I left IBM.
Scott: Nice.
Scott: Let's try to run it in VirtualBox We should.
Rym: I got it on a bunch of CDs and shit, huh?
Scott: I guess you probably have to run in box.
Rym: Yeah, you'd have to run it on like a hardware.
Rym: It's an x86 and that shit's not gonna just work in like VMware.
Rym: Bo CHS is an x86 emulator But anyway, so this thing was never really powered off or anything and just kept working.
Rym: Everyone's terrified of turning it off because they were afraid, you know, what would happen if it doesn't turn back?
Scott: Yeah, this thing had.
Scott: we haven't run the boot sequence on this in a long time.
Scott: We don't even know if it works.
Scott: like for all we know I worry about that on servers that have been running for like a year.
Scott: It's like wow this reboots.
Scott: Will it turn back on?
Rym: Or even like what if a hard drive failed in such a way that it just won't spin back up and in old Mechanically.
Rym: Yeah, or even like in old computers.
Rym: It could be running out of RAM That hard drive might be empty depending on how it's set up like old OSes.
Rym: You could run shit in weird ways that you wouldn't even dream of in the modern era.
Scott: Yeah, what if this has like a RAM disk?
Rym: Yeah, what if there's a RAM disk and like oops?
Rym: So this is a story that's public of a similar thing.
Rym: a computer from the 80s I think it's like a Commodore machine or something.
Rym: Yeah, I think it's an Amiga or something like that has been controlling all the HVAC So like the heating and cooling and boilers and everything as opposed to say a thermostat for 19 school buildings in this area Via this like crazy wireless network.
Scott: Yeah Basically, they all the like the temperature sensors and all the buildings will radio over to this computer with a radio right like Radio What the temperature is and then the computer will decide whether to turn the heat or air conditioning on or off And it will send a radio signal back to the school That's in a different building across town and tell it turn your heat on turn your air conditioning on quote.
Rym: Whenever the district has a problem with it, they go back to the original programmer who still lives in the area.
Rym: It's a very unique product.
Rym: It operates on a 1200 bit modem.
Rym: I guess I guess 1200 baud.
Scott: I'm pretty sure it's baud.
Rym: Well baud, you know what the difference is from a baud and a bit Bit and something something.
Rym: No, no, no, no, I'll save that I'm making.
Rym: I'm gonna make that a thing of the day separately.
Scott: what baud is?
Rym: Yeah, cuz baud stopped being relevant when we jumped from 90.
Rym: I think 9600 baud was the last time.
Scott: baud meant right but like a 9600 baud modem sent over 9.6 kilobits per second.
Rym: Was it bits or characters?
Scott: I Thought it was bits.
Rym: Yeah, I'll link to an article about it.
Scott: If it's characters.
Scott: That's way more bits.
Scott: It's eight times as many bits.
Rym: so, uh this thing Needs to be replaced obviously.
Rym: And this article kind of talks about why it's gonna cost a hundred one point five to two million dollars each Building control its own heating and cooling.
Scott: Yeah, they really that complicated.
Scott: You don't need new heating machines or new cooling machines.
Scott: They'll seem to be working.
Rym: It's not just turning on and off from what I can gather because it's controlling.
Rym: it's not kind of these asshole boilers and like all There's complicated stuff.
Scott: Oh And basically I think part of the cause my school student was able to write a program to control it.
Rym: I don't know over the high school soon, but part of the he was a high school student when he wrote it.
Rym: I think part of the cost is someone's got to go and like really figure out exactly what it's doing.
Rym: But I'll bet I could do this project For half that money where I could do this project in like a weekend.
Scott: Well, no I would give you sent me the source code just for that thing to study it for a little while and I'll run it in A little emulator.
Scott: I could replace that shit so fast.
Rym: I would go different.
Scott: tack You know, I'd put like one Raspberry Pi in each school connected to an Arduino that we're drilling the relays or whatever the physical.
Scott: You don't even need the Arduino.
Scott: You just put one Raspberry Pi in each school and like a one backup Raspberry Pi next to it.
Scott: cuz why the fuck not?
Scott: So it's like I'm into the wall with a battery back back up.
Scott: So he's got.
Rym: how does it like control the boiler then?
Scott: Whatever wires there's definitely a device.
Scott: Yeah connecting that radio to the boilers that exists.
Scott: Now I figure out what protocol is going on between the radio and the boilers and I implement that.
Rym: in the side might be a bunch of like high voltage relays.
Rym: It might be like some fucked up.
Scott: and those relays those relays are there at the connection point with the radio?
Scott: There is an analog signal going to the radio and I can connect to it the Raspberry Pi at that point with Worst case like an ADC or whatever.
Scott: Yeah, so you got a thing of the day.
Scott: Oh sure So the camera that I have is the very fancy Panasonic gh4.
Scott: it is a fancy camera.
Scott: It is Expensive as most people would see it at the price of seventeen hundred dollars.
Scott: You can get it for less like twelve hundred or used or refurbished or whatever.
Scott: Yeah, the magic of it is that it can take 4k video Which is insane for like a camera with interchangeable lenses and all right.
Scott: It is crazy good at video and also pretty great damn good at photo and whatnot.
Scott: So it is a very popular camera, but you know, you might think that's a lot of money But really it's not actually that much money.
Scott: as far as cameras are concerned the Canon 5d mark 3 which is like the standard For digital cameras that have a sensor the size of one You know size of 35 millimeter film full-frame is like almost three thousand dollars.
Scott: ridiculous, right?
Scott: It's and it's way big and it only takes 1080p video and whatever but it's still a very popular video camera regardless.
Scott: anyway some guy had that camera the same one as me and he attached it to the Fujinon X a 55 lens.
Scott: See the thing with a mirrorless camera.
Scott: See the Canon camera has a mirror in it Which means the distance between the sensor or the film the digital film and the lens is a big distance because you have to put A mirror.
Scott: in between that space the mirrorless camera There is less space Which means you can use a lens designed for a camera where there's more space just by basically sticking a tube on there.
Scott: Right because it's like oh this lens is designed to be two inches away from the film.
Scott: this camera The mount is like half an inch away from the film.
Scott: So we'll just put a one and a half inch disc in between and then we can attach this old-ass lens To this brand new camera.
Scott: And so that is the magic of the mirrorless gh4 and other mirrorless cameras.
Scott: So the Fujinon X a 55 lens is One of those lenses made for a TV camera.
Scott: like you ever watch sports and you see those guys in the sidelines Well, you think it's a giant can have this giant camera, right?
Scott: Like the guy at the football game on the sideline who's like in the little like the lift, right?
Scott: And he said this giant camera.
Scott: It looks like a big box basically, right?
Scott: You realize that the box is the lens Everything else.
Scott: the camera behind it is very very small.
Scott: The box is the lens and those lenses that are odd that they use for television live sports and things.
Scott: First of all, they're that big because they're amazing.
Scott: They're also I don't know at least Usually I've seen him go depending on which one you get like hundreds of thousands of dollars.
Scott: I've seen some for 300,000.
Scott: They're really really expensive Right, so this guy he takes my camera $1,700 and attaches it to this $60,000 lens by way of adapting as I just described.
Scott: and When you combine the fact that this lens is already insane to begin with, right?
Scott: It's a nine point five to five twenty five millimeter lens Which means it can zoom way in way way in more than pretty much any lens that you have at home Zoom way out probably farther out almost as far out as any lens I have.
Scott: actually I think you know It zooms farther out than any lens I have also and It's one point one sevens.
Scott: So we can let you.
Scott: basically you can open the aperture a ton and let tons of light in So you can shoot in way dark conditions.
Scott: He puts a 2x extender on it So that basically makes it zoom in twice as much and is also sort of necessary for attaching it to this tiny camera That wasn't designed for it.
Scott: and then in addition to that you have to realize the sensor on this camera is Like half the size of you know, a 35 millimeter sensor.
Scott: So when you're basically cropping into the middle of the picture, which is sort of the same thing as zooming in, right?
Scott: I mean if I take a picture and I just crop out the middle part and then I put that next to it It's like oh it looks like you zoomed in which sort of did.
Scott: Yeah, so it comes out to be a 45 to 2415 millimeter 415 millimeter equivalent.
Scott: now if that doesn't mean anything and that doesn't mean anything to you watch my thing of the day Which is a video and you can see the ridiculousness when he zoomed in on that lighthouse Wait to which he can zoom with this 60. that I mean you got what you pay for $60,000 lens, right?
Scott: But this is why they use these for television because basically you can any situation No matter what the light is no matter how much you had to zoom.
Scott: you can get the shot with these lenses.
Scott: Right, you need to get the whole football field or a player's close-up face.
Scott: You're gonna be able to get it done No problem In a moment.
Rym: the book club book is the wheel of time.
Rym: Eye of the world The first one.
Rym: I got to read it.
Rym: I'll start reading it.
Rym: I'm going to London this week So I'll read it on the plane.
Scott: I haven't.
Scott: I read it and then I stopped reading it for a little bit because I'm busy but every time I see it there I actually kind of want to read it.
Scott: Oh Interesting more so than the rabbit book at least.
Rym: I like the rabbit book a lot.
Scott: I don't hate the rabbit book.
Scott: I just didn't want to.
Rym: I just don't know if I'm feeling generic fantasy because I almost want to read.
Rym: Some of those forgot it at Elms books again instead.
Scott: So this is hopefully better than this.
Scott: We'll see.
Rym: I'm curious.
Scott: It's while it's generic fantasy.
Scott: I think it's slightly.
Scott: it's not highbrow.
Scott: I think it's mid brow.
Scott: So it's not lowbrow like your dragon lance.
Rym: We're like fuck dragon lance.
Scott: So say it's mid brow.
Rym: So we Were catching up with a video queue.
Rym: So upload it to our site on YouTube.
Rym: now our Two videos a short excerpt from our bad games lecture at Santa and at peck south in San Antonio where we shit all over race walking for the garbage.
Rym: bullshit not a sports sport that it is.
Rym: and Then the whole lecture.
Rym: because why not?
Scott: Also this Saturday I mentioned already but whatever I'm gonna lie attempt to live stream the Philadelphia regional 25th.
Scott: I don't know what order to put these words in the 2015 Philadelphia netrunner regional championship Philadelphia regional 2015 netrunner championship.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know How do you put those words in the right order?
Scott: Someone help me out with that?
Scott: But anyway, you can watch.
Scott: I'm gonna live stream that shit if I can.
Rym: and July 9th 10th 11th and 12th Connecticut on 2015 and the 9th is only like get your badge because they don't mail the badges.
Rym: yet The only bad thing about Connecticut and it's like there's.
Scott: there's a couple events at night that don't really count Repanels and the nerd prom and a bunch of people just hang out like a nerd prom requires separate tickets.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I think so.
Scott: I think it does.
Scott: I've never was different registration at least.
Rym: despite running the panels department for many many years.
Rym: I've never been there Thursday night - we're not really into the nerd.
Rym: find out I would have if I was 17.
Rym: I'd be so into that nerd prom.
Rym: Maybe yeah, I know I would have been anyway I know what I was like when I was 17.
Rym: So, uh, yeah Talking about the sneaker net.
Rym: so Cuba opening up and there's a fascinating article in the link to here.
Rym: But basically it's a report on El Paquette day or El Paquette.
Rym: Okay the package Mmm, it's just called the package.
Rym: I'll read this excerpt for you Cuba's answer.
Rym: I'm quoting Cuba's answer to the internet an informal but extraordinarily Lucrative distribution chain where anyone in Cuba who can who can pay can watch telenovelas first run Hollywood movies Search for romantic partners, etc.
Rym: The so-called weekly package distributed a house to house I guess on USB sticks contains a bunch of movies and TV shows and documentaries.
Scott: So there's one there's one person with internet who downloads all this shit onto USB like pirates a terabyte.
Scott: where the shit Where does this person get their internet from?
Scott: that fills up these USB sticks?
Rym: Uh, I don't know.
Rym: read the article.
Scott: Where did they get all these USB sticks from?
Rym: well Scott?
Rym: Wait, where did you get it?
Rym: I could if my job was hang out on Pirate Bay and assemble the package.
Rym: every week I can make one fucking amazing package.
Scott: I can make it amazing fucking package as well.
Scott: But how do I get that package on to so many USB sticks and up for all the nerds in Cuba?
Rym: So it's sort of this ad-hoc network.
Rym: We're like one gets made and I guess once you've got one and you can churn out a bunch of them just copy them Right, and how do I have?
Scott: one guy in the neighborhood gets El Paquette day and everyone else copies it and doesn't pay.
Rym: Yep, so read the article and it goes into the details of how this works.
Rym: But apparently it's you get a terabyte a week For ten bucks.
Scott: Oh, holy shit.
Scott: They're downloading a lot.
Rym: Yeah Wow There is there is everything here.
Rym: another quote the thumb drives make their way across the island from how are the hair bite?
Scott: Usb sticks what the fuck.
Rym: hand-to-hand?
Rym: Might be for smaller USB.
Scott: Are you sure it's not just like a hard drive a magnetic one?
Rym: that'd be fine just at this point like yeah, but this is Fascinating to say the least.
Rym: Yeah, it shows the power of human ingenuity.
Scott: Also, that's a lot faster download speeds than I got, you know, let me take to download a terabyte of movies.
Rym: So one this is amazing because what if subverts, you know the worldwide like copyright Can I pay ten bucks and get up a ketate delivered to me?
Scott: Oh my god.
Rym: I want El Paquette.
Scott: I'll take ten bucks for that.
Rym: yeah, but to like this was also subversive in Cuba because For all the stuff the NSA does This is the kind of network.
Rym: That is the hardest to bust up.
Rym: Oh, yeah way more useful than complicated encrypted mesh networks.
Scott: Nothing to spy on.
Scott: It's like imagine if people aren't using the post office and you know, there's no third party There's no central point where the communication passes through that you can sit and look at all the things that are happening.
Rym: It's just one guy hands a thing to another guy and then that guy copies and gives it to ten friends.
Scott: Are not you beside?
Scott: you can you?
Scott: it's like look out the window and see who's handing who what see?
Scott: Okay, I saw that those two people exchanged something.
Scott: You go down and find out I was letting him borrow my screwdriver.
Scott: It I've you know, hey, it's like you can't be doing every time people trade something It's like.
Scott: and how can you see every time people do anything in public?
Scott: All right, just more important changing goods and services like.
Rym: yeah We can use like waste to like networks and like really all the stuff.
Scott: Guy brings his car to the mechanic to get it fixed.
Scott: He leaves the mechanic.
Scott: Oh, the glove box is filled with USB sticks.
Rym: Yeah You had no idea but he's supposed to know all the complicated ways We've talked about to like really subvert governments and like so share information.
Rym: They all rely on a couple things.
Rym: they rely on you still having electricity The internet still being there and in terms of like even ad hoc encrypted mesh networks The EMP isn't things gonna stick that out.
Scott: But if you send data over anything that's wireless ever someone who's near enough can spy on that.
Scott: So I might be encrypted maybe.
Rym: But signal intelligence can figure out where the broadcasts are.
Rym: and even if they can't figure it out because it's a really complicated cool Or you have a really long wire between your home base and your antenna.
Rym: They can just jam it.
Rym: Any wireless signal can be jammed.
Scott: Yeah jamming is way easier than doing and any wired signal Can be cut obviously.
Scott: or hey, what's this passes?
Scott: Yeah, if it passes through any point that is not you and its destination.
Scott: It can be spied upon.
Rym: So the sneaker nets are like the sneaker net is the term for when you exchange information in Person or via physical artifacts as in you are using your sneakers your shoes as a network.
Rym: to
Scott: deliver the data I take a floppy disk I walk over to rims house and I give it to him
Rym: and this is like this is used for real Stuff like as I linked you in this article Sometimes mailing a truck like a truck full our drives is way faster than any other option.
Scott: Yeah, I mean think about how.
Scott: you know, you have gigabit connection to the internet 10 gigabit connection to the internet.
Scott: All right, how fast is that?
Scott: Can that beat me mailing a 4 terabyte hard drive in the mail?
Rym: What about me?
Scott: What if I do overnight Express Mail?
Scott: What if I do a bike courier across the city?
Rym: What if I get a u-haul and literally fill it to the brim with 4 terabyte disks?
Rym: Yep Wow, what if you made a truck that was dedicated like it's my skull the drivers mounted in it and just has like a port On the outside to connect and fill it with data like gas Mm-hmm.
Rym: So, uh this stuff this is an aspect of technology.
Rym: computing Anonymous speech data distribution sneaker nets touch on Way more parts of technology in the internet in the world than you'd think they're still useful even today.
Rym: and they are used today both by Shall we say illicit actors and just by like Google and the government?
Scott: Well, I mean in the olden days they were super popular because it was sort of your only method.
Scott: right a modem Was not good.
Rym: Yeah, like if I wanted to download where's from the local BBS one that took a while.
Scott: You didn't get doom pirated by downloading it You got doom because someone had the wad files put them on a floppy disk and gave them to you.
Rym: Yep, and you'd have.
Rym: I had this floppy disk that had scorched earth on it the unlocked version.
Rym: Good God, did that floppy disk get copied?
Rym: Basically around the world.
Scott: Yeah, everyone in school right keeps trading files between all their floppy disks, right?
Scott: That was sneaker net.
Rym: every I've got a copy of scorched earth and la la checks on a floppy disk once.
Rym: And we're like when I was in like high school and it had some of the shit from the same disk I'd seen in a different school district in middle school.
Rym: Yeah, like data just starts to accumulate on that rolling stone moss grows all over a rolling USB stick All right.
Scott: Well you is.
Scott: best thing is nowadays, you know, the floppy disk, you know It's not.
Scott: people aren't doing it as much because it's no longer necessary.
Scott: You can just download and trade over the net.
Scott: But the USB stick that is such high capacity in such small space makes it more powerful when you do use it Yep, and you can do crazy stuff.
Scott: You can leave a USB stick out in public somewhere and someone can pick it up because it's so small.
Scott: People are like sticking USB sticks in walls with the USB port sticking up and if you get a little cable or stub your laptop Up against the wall, you can get the data on there or leave data off.
Scott: So think about this.
Rym: Hey, what's this USB stick?
Rym: Oh, it's a whole bunch of government anti-corruption stuff, huh?
Scott: Oh, it's a bunch of viruses.
Scott: It just grew in my computer.
Rym: Yeah, that did you see the dude?
Rym: He made a proof of concept a USB stick that will physically destroy any computer.
Rym: you plug it into nice.
Rym: It's pretty complicated.
Rym: how it does it like.
Rym: it's way harder to do that than you'd think but any computer Mac PC doesn't matter.
Scott: Yeah, it hardware ruins it even if I use a hub Through a hub.
Rym: I might just destroy the hub maybe Mmm, it's interesting.
Rym: Yeah, it's it's a complicated thing.
Scott: I'll find Howard hub non-powered.
Rym: I'll find the article.
Rym: Let me make a note on this third monitor To remember to.
Rym: I'll link to this in the forum because I don't remember the detail.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: Yeah, the increased capacity makes it, you know so much more powerful.
Scott: The other things you can do is you can sort of have half sneaker net, right?
Scott: We talked about pirate box way back in the day.
Scott: You can make like a physical thing that you carry around.
Scott: that has Wi-Fi.
Scott: so you it's still wireless.
Scott: It's still sort of has that bit of insecurity, but you have to be pretty close to it to get it.
Scott: but then the power of it is so much greater.
Scott: imagine if I just had a bunch of hard drives and some access points in a truck and I drove around town and parked in a few places according to like a schedule and like I hid my SS IDs that you had to know and see.
Scott: the truck was there and be in the know.
Rym: and then you log into This thing and it tells you the flash mob Information where to go to do the whatever crazy poor.
Scott: you log in and access the terabytes and terabytes of data in el Paquette day that is in my truck.
Rym: Whoa, that gave me a great idea.
Rym: That's the new pirate radio.
Rym: That's the new party el paquette day.
Rym: You just got to know Stand in like Madison Square Park.
Scott: connect to this as his ID with this WPA password.
Rym: at this time It's there between 1 p.m.
Scott: And 2 p.m You have one hour a day.
Scott: you can access all this data.
Scott: that's just there at Wi-Fi speeds.
Rym: Oh my god, that's actually an amazing idea.
Scott: Then the security camera notices that this car shows up there every day.
Rym: Yeah, but you do it like those night markets.
Rym: Like you just have one.
Rym: you have an underground distribution network.
Scott: I think you're better off making it just put inside a lunchbox and you just physically go and sit in the park every day.
Scott: Yeah, it's you know, who's gonna?
Scott: Oh a guy has a routine of going to the park every day.
Rym: There's a lot of ways to do it.
Rym: you could use Directional antennas and do it like from a rooftop point it at an area.
Scott: Oh and turn it on and off.
Rym: Yeah, there's a lot of cool there.
Rym: There are ways to do this.
Scott: There's many ways.
Rym: do but the idea is that If you want there's a lot of things you might want to do where.
Rym: putting that information on the internet publicly ruins that because people you don't want to see it can have access to it and Reveal what it is you're doing.
Rym: sneaker net or I guess pirate Wi-Fi Localize the effect and it's like it's a security through obscurity like don't get me wrong But it's obscurity that's kind of hard to defeat.
Scott: and you know Even at the beginning of the matrix the dude comes up to his door and with like trading floppy this, right?
Rym: Well, I mean never forget in hackers the famous line.
Rym: Hey Remember that time that place I put that thing that one time.
Rym: Yeah, I Still have some old friends.
Rym: I still have some relationships like that.
Rym: There is in fact a place where I put that thing that one time and there's some people on this earth who know exactly Where that is probably in Michigan somewhere, maybe maybe not.
Scott: pretty sure it is maybe maybe not.
Rym: Okay, I can say anything about it because it's kind of important.
Rym: gives ever needed.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Rym: You never know.
Rym: gun There's a gun hanging out there a dollar A D20.
Rym: this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.