Rym: It's Tuesday April 14th 2015.
Rym: I'm Rym I am Scott and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We're talking about the sheriff of Nottingham Really slowly for some reason.
Rym: also.
Scott: mount your friends Let's do this.
Rym: So now we play a lot of games in our off and on game nights But lately we've been playing a lot of DDR again, and you know dance dance revolution for all you young Kids who just don't know things anymore the real revolution
Scott: in gaming
Rym: Mm-hmm, then you know it's.
Rym: it's sad because I realized years ago because I had a red octane ignition pad Which was the best soft pad money could buy a slab one.
Rym: Yeah, so I had one that had a ps1 like a PlayStation hookup and nothing else.
Scott: mine has all the hookups.
Rym: so PlayStation yeah, you can sell that for a decent amount of money because those haven't been manufactured in so long.
Rym: Yeah, you could use it, but I've bought some bootlegs.
Rym: at least you can still buy the bootlegs.
Rym: DDR is so dead except among ultra hardcore DDR people and the kinds of people who are like arcade machine enthusiasts in the u.s.
Rym: That I did never really expected to run into people younger than me who play DDR like more than a few years But just recently we've been having like some people over like doing some parties and things and DDR came up in casual conversation with strangers And I was like you DDR, and they're like you DDR and I was in DDR another room, and they're like bring to this room and some of these people have never heard of step mania and Long.
Rym: story short we've been playing a lot of fucking DDR again and good.
Rym: God is DDR the best dancing slash Bimani game ever made.
Scott: DDR is one of the best games ever made.
Rym: I mean pump it up not as good.
Rym: In terms of best video games ever DDR is way way up there like we did a pax lecture on why DDR is kind of notable and why other games have not really filled that niche.
Scott: It's also a summer thing for some reason.
Scott: even though it should be a winter thing it always ends up being a summer.
Rym: I know it's like the game I should play when I can't go outside But then gets warm out and suddenly the DDR pad is in the living room for the entire VR kicks in when the Sun comes out.
Scott: yeah No, but like if you made like a rubric of like what it takes to be a great video game I mean if you think about the greatest video games of which probably are things like Super Metroid or Super Mario 3.
Scott: Yeah, it's like but even though those are probably better than DDR if you it's like.
Rym: It's like saying is Star Wars better than like your mom's fancy recipe?
Rym: Like which one's better, but it's like DDR.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: probably if you had a scoring system would prob at least a good scoring system that I Scott approved DDR might be the highest or perhaps only perfect scoring game there is.
Rym: well I mean it's designed so well though actually a lot of the things that we praised it for having such great design for Didn't appear until fourth mix.
Scott: well fourth mix is when it Began right first second and third of AC beta.
Rym: third mix is fine.
Rym: third mix has it's playable But it's got problems, but man like when you accidentally like you start you hit a third mix song with third mix arrows You can feel Third mix arrows in your bones Like mixes after that.
Rym: where you feel fourth mix like DDR hips like Someone who's never played it before can play the same song next to someone who's played it for multiple Decades and they can both totally have fun unless it's like some ridiculous max 300.
Rym: Well unless it's something that doesn't have like beginner mode which aren't that many.
Scott: well No, the thing is even the hard songs if they do have a beginner mode, but you drop out beginner mode It's like I was coming up.
Scott: Yeah, gotcha.
Rym: But it's like the little like the fact that the arrows Oscillate and that you can like train your brain, and I remember explaining to someone who's visiting us once They're like there's no way you're reading all those arrows like you've had.
Rym: you have done this before and I'm like no But I mean it's patterns.
Rym: your brain just kind of gets hardwired like if you play DDR You'll start dreaming about DDR like you'll dream about Tetris when you play a lot of Tetris.
Rym: And then the next thing you know like you see arrows feet just move.
Rym: There is no conscious thought between those two input output.
Scott: Nope.
Rym: God damn DRS a good game.
Rym: So yeah I've been thinking about for a long time buying a DDR machine and the only reason I didn't just buy one like Literally before we did this show.
Scott: I don't have anywhere to put it.
Rym: I don't have anywhere to put it either.
Rym: so kind of thinking about seeing if the building would let me put it in the gym As an exercise machine like it'd be mine But if they let me put it there and plug it in and put it on free play and then
Scott: you move out because the new Buildings going up you can't see anything Then
Rym: I'll be if I wonder that's just the excuse to have the machine.
Rym: if I have to move and the other buildings like no You can't do that then I'll figure something out.
Rym: But oh man DDR machine.
Rym: what I kind of want to do really is buy an art like the replacement pad for a DDR machine and Then set up like a relay box to an Arduino or something like that and then just use that as a pad.
Scott: I don't know what the hookups are for that.
Scott: It is well documented by ultra nerds So you can basically make a converter for it for that goes down as being.
Rym: I mean It's like high voltage because there's like there's a lot.
Rym: It's not USB.
Rym: I'll put it that way But I'm confident I could plug that shit into an Arduino and make it happen.
Rym: Hmm part of it's like you got a power like all those lights and everything in there.
Rym: I feel like with my modern knowledge like I made a hard DDR pad a long time ago And I feel like I could make one again.
Rym: That would be way better because I have more knowledge in your workshop, but I don't have a workshop.
Rym: But the reason my old DDR pad failed is partly because while I had a workshop I didn't have a lot of money.
Rym: So I cut corners like I made this sort of like two metal plates separated by weather stripping contact.
Rym: nowadays I would just buy professional ribbon strips.
Rym: So anyway DDR I feel like there's gonna be.
Rym: I'm gonna be talking about DDR a lot as I play DDR again.
Rym: Mm-hmm That's all I got.
Rym: That's my Intro bit.
Rym: Do you have any news now that we're past that bit to the next bit of the show?
Scott: It's not really a lot of news going on in the gaming world.
Scott: I wanted to talk about Kojima being fired or not fired or whatever's going on there But the thing is whatever is going on.
Scott: There is so cryptic and so many conflicting in reports that I can't really talk about it with any Reliability or meaning.
Scott: Yeah, so I just think it's really interesting and I'm I want to wait for it to you know fully pan out so then we can get all the dirt and Scoop it.
Scott: Yeah So instead I'll just talk about hearthstone which is doing some pretty Big-time upgrades lately, right?
Scott: They can't with the new adventure Right, but the big deal is that in the latest update or whatever, you know Every time an update comes out basically people take apart the binary files to dig for assets and they found a bunch of you know Textures that are for use in the iPhone version of the game Which isn't out yet to prove.
Rym: this proves definitively that half-life 3 is coming.
Scott: Yeah summer No, I mean they're coming out with iPhone version.
Scott: they've said so right now We need to sort of know what it's gonna look like kinda now, right?
Scott: I don't know why game companies keep including future assets that aren't being used in the current version.
Scott: in the current version.
Rym: I know why.
Rym: whatever.
Rym: because the way the version control is it's just easier for everybody Usually because better version control like I am.
Rym: Yeah, I think it's the people.
Rym: Having seen that happen in every company I've ever worked for I see a lot of companies like using feature flags.
Scott: It's like so they release non production code to their production servers and just use different settings to keep those future Unfinished, you know features be disabled and I'm like fuck.
Scott: No, I'm not putting any code on the production server That isn't production ready.
Rym: We let that happen once with a product and then I was like, yeah We're not even though it might be disabled by a flag.
Scott: It's like hell no.
Scott: Yeah anyway.
Scott: so the reason that's notable is You know because there aren't really any other mobile games and this is why despite there being Some problems with hearthstone, right?
Scott: It's very luck based.
Scott: You know, you'd get to pay to win.
Scott: ish Right, despite having many many issues Which are sort of made up for by it's actually usable user interface, which no other car digital card game seems to have It's pretty much the only multiplayer strategy game of note That you can play on an iPhone or iPad or pretty much tablet or phone.
Scott: period.
Rym: I mean The only other game I can think of is neuroshima hex.
Scott: Yeah, the only other I mean the only other games that you can play that are even you know Worthwhile on tablets or phones that are real strategy games are pretty much all just board games Translated.
Scott: Yeah, whereas hearthstone is a card game, but it also takes advantage of the fact that it's only a video game.
Scott: It's like you can take magic or in turn it into a video game because anything you can do with cards you can do With pixels.
Rym: hearthstone does things that cannot be done with cards at all period which is the right way to go if you're making a game like that.
Rym: like I mean Netrunner is cool because of like it.
Rym: the cards are the interface.
Scott: It would be very hard to actually I mean if it's possible to do Netrunner a video game, but it's not possible to hearthstone card game.
Scott: Netrunner to the video game would be very very difficult because there's so many timing windows.
Scott: You know It's like basically constantly pause to give players the opportunity to do stuff.
Scott: a better
Rym: option is Whatever your medium is for a game like tabletop video like whatever your medium is for the game Do use the things that make that medium unique
Scott: sure, but it's like how come there aren't any other Tablet or phone games that at least on the same level.
Scott: It's hearthstone in terms of multiplayer Somewhat meaningful strategy Action, you know.
Rym: it's interesting because tons of games like that exist on mobile platforms.
Scott: They're all.
Rym: they're all in the gameboy advance and the gameboy gameboy color.
Scott: I mean there are turn-based strategy military games on the mobile device.
Scott: It's mostly but they're not advanced wars.
Scott: I've played like four or five of them and none of them are
Rym: like seriously unless you are Final fantasy tactics advanced wars or fire emblem like at least to that level like don't even bother talking to me There's no reason to play you yeah,
Scott: so I wish other companies would step in here.
Rym: But until then is it because the people who use you know gameboys like dedicated game counsel are more Gamery and thus are more willing to play game games?
Rym: I don't know as opposed to the wider market because I feel like most people making games for mobile are Really going after the like shitware model mm-hmm.
Scott: I Don't know, but meanwhile the shitware companies are not having a good time lately.
Rym: that is true.
Scott: You know Zinga's switched back to their original CEO recently.
Scott: Newer one wasn't doing a good job.
Scott: They're basically dead.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: yeah, whatever.
Rym: So we'll see.
Rym: so I have the tiniest little news here, and it's more relevant to Wednesdays, but whatever.
Rym: So there's this robot statue that people keep calling a transformer, but it's not.
Rym: it's obviously well.
Rym: It's obviously a non Gundam suit from a Gundam world with a weird mohawk helmet And it's in Turkey because some mayor was like this thing's going here and taxpayers are paying for it.
Scott: But if you're he's a mayor he can just say something.
Scott: there's no town council or anything.
Scott: He's a dictator of the town.
Scott: your lies.
Rym: mayor's in many places have Surprisingly wide latitude in terms of their powers.
Rym: hmm and in a lot of places a mayor Yeah of New York.
Rym: Yeah, of course, New York, New York's mayor basically been Leashed to the governor and the state legislature.
Scott: the state's afraid of us sure, but how do you?
Scott: How old you got to be?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I think I think we're old enough to be mayor.
Rym: Oh, I think we just can't be like senators or presidents.
Scott: still Why do we get like town council for LIC?
Rym: You want to you want to go for that?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: LSE isn't a town.
Rym: I guess we could join the.
Scott: there has to be a town council representative person for a town.
Rym: What town are we in?
Scott: a City council?
Rym: the city of New York.
Scott: There's a city council.
Scott: you can get on.
Scott: there's that.
Rym: yes, there is for the city of New York.
Rym: Yes, there's also the county government because we're in Queens County.
Scott: You don't want to do that.
Scott: I don't do shit.
Rym: Anyway, this is just funny from a lot of perspectives because basically he started getting a lot of shit about this from people who are like Why he's.
Scott: his comment was respect the robot.
Rym: Yeah, that's that was his response to all the criticism.
Rym: So just go look at this thing.
Rym: It's just kind of funny.
Scott: best response.
Scott: That's your news It's not.
Scott: it's a thing of the day not a news.
Rym: No, cuz I got a thing of the day.
Rym: So anyway things of the day.
Rym: So this is something related to my DDR stuff earlier.
Rym: So if you lived behind the Iron Curtain like in the Soviet Union during the Cold War it was hard enough to get computers.
Rym: So let's say you've somehow got a computer.
Rym: You think you're gonna fucking get a printer or a mouse or any peripheral.
Rym: and this is a collection of the?
Rym: hacked together homemade Peripherals that nerds in the Soviet Union made for their computers.
Rym: There's like mice that were made out of spice containers with ping-pong balls Like this.
Rym: shit is amazing.
Scott: Why don't we make some peripherals?
Rym: you want to just make some peripherals?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Check it out.
Rym: I just made a mouse.
Scott: You just bought that man.
Scott: I did.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, I'll mod it.
Rym: I'll hack it.
Rym: I wrote my name on.
Rym: it's mine.
Rym: I Don't know.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I don't think these people were making laser mice.
Rym: I think they were making.
Scott: no one had laser mice.
Rym: Yes, ping-pong ball mice that's a good mouse though the rollerball of a handmade mouse.
Rym: it is a ping-pong ball.
Rym: Thank you.
Scott: Just didn't even get a billiard ball like most people.
Rym: Ooh, whoa, whoa, whoa a housing for the mouse.
Rym: They used a plastic kitchen spice can inside.
Rym: They placed a circuit board where there were two mutually perpendicular metal rollers.
Rym: on both rollers.
Rym: There was a jagged Aperture made from thick paper.
Rym: its position was read using an LED in a pair of photo transistors.
Rym: It was a light made.
Rym: It was a light mouse Optical mouse.
Scott: Well, yes Was that the perhaps the first optical mouse the odd.
Rym: this nerds optical mouse?
Rym: That he made behind the Iron Curtain was better than any mouse.
Rym: I owned during that era.
Scott: Good job, dude.
Rym: Yeah, anyway, so this thing's amazing and you just check out.
Scott: I can say good job comrade.
Scott: Yeah Excellent work.
Rym: So What do you have for me?
Scott: So there's this village somewhere?
Scott: I don't even know the name of the village doesn't freaking matter.
Scott: It's a village and they have a tourist attraction in this village.
Scott: It's the thing that many places have.
Scott: It's a model of the village in the village, right?
Scott: Just like me your dog.
Scott: just like there's a model of New York City out in the Queen's Art Museum There's a model of this village in this village.
Scott: What's notable is that this model is pretty big pretty significant percentage of the village.
Scott: It's not a big village, right?
Scott: Model of itself.
Rym: Well kind of like how you know You had a lot of conventions where they account for like 10% of the population of the town.
Scott: Yep well this model of the village contains a Model of the village model.
Rym: Whoa That is so up my alley.
Rym: That is my kind of thing.
Scott: It is recursive a certain number of times.
Scott: that is excessive but not you know impossible.
Scott: So it's like you look at the model of the.
Scott: you're in the village You're looking at this model of the village and in that model is A model of the model and in that model is a model of the model and perhaps one or two or three more times It goes down
Rym: Scott the fact that you picked this because you know very well that one of my favorite things in the world is when someone Has a picture of their cubicle in their cubicle and in that picture is the picture of the cubicle.
Rym: That kind of thing the yo-dog is my favorite thing.
Scott: Yo-dog.
Scott: I put model village in your model village.
Rym: In the moment the book club book is still water ship down is the story of rats rats rabbits on an adventure Maybe next week.
Rym: You should do the secret of NIMH Mmm.
Rym: Yeah, I haven't read that in a long time.
Scott: Yeah, it's a kid's book.
Rym: Yeah, half the books.
Rym: We've done our kids books.
Scott: Do you keep picking kids books?
Scott: I pick adult books.
Rym: All right, what book you gonna pick next?
Rym: All right, just don't cross me or it's gonna be some LeCombe de Monte Cristo Perhaps the man in the mask made of iron.
Scott: I'm not sure if this is crossing you or not, but we're gonna find we're gonna find out.
Rym: indeed I hope it's just something I've already read and I'll just laugh.
Scott: that's possible.
Rym: It is possible, especially cuz you won't tell me.
Rym: Mm-hmm All right, so that aside We have no live shows like convention appearances.
Rym: Oh Connecticut until Connecticut July if you if you want to present something at Connecticut.
Rym: The panel submissions closed over half a month ago.
Rym: The form is still open.
Rym: you can still submit.
Rym: however I've been scheduling shit for a while Unless.
Rym: what you submit is so awesome that I cannot resist probably not getting into schedule at this point Mm-hmm.
Rym: So let this be a lesson to you send your stuff to conventions early not late.
Scott: Yeah Remember conventions have like a whole year of not doing anything.
Scott: You can probably start sending very shortly after the convention ends for the next year.
Rym: I mean packs.
Rym: Australia badges are already on sale guys.
Scott: That's in October.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah I don't know.
Rym: That's it.
Rym: Watch all our videos.
Rym: We got tons of videos of our stuff on YouTube.
Scott: come and check us out on the internet and all the other places besides the Ignites Apparently already found GeekNights.
Scott: So go to the other places.
Rym: Yeah, our forum is pretty rockin actually and it's mostly smart people.
Rym: We've been so few people over the years that it's kind of Unprecedented how good that community is.
Rym: You guys should join it.
Scott: Well, also we just don't let people in it's begin with who are shitty.
Rym: How do we not let people in?
Scott: because I look at their reason for applying.
Rym: Oh, yeah If we got about that you apply.
Scott: make sure you write something in the application.
Scott: that makes me like, you know I've seen people write things that are sort of like on the edge like I want to start a discussion or I would like to talk to like-minded people and it's like Nothing in that sentence while that sentence probably is maybe not robot.
Scott: ish You haven't indicated to me that like you're a listener or you didn't even mention GeekNights or anything.
Scott: So it's like that is not getting an accept, you know, you need to write something.
Rym: That's like prove you're a human.
Scott: Someone did one today.
Scott: that was like I've been a listener for a long time and have never joined the forums and it's like that's A good one, right?
Scott: You said you're a listener and you know robots not right.
Rym: just prove you're a human who isn't shitty.
Rym: That's all you need to do.
Rym: Yeah, write a sentence that proves both of those things.
Scott: It was a current.
Scott: I also wrote it properly like a complete sentence with grammar and spelling.
Rym: Yeah, pretty much.
Rym: grammar and spelling are the only real rules in our right.
Rym: like I am listener I don't know if someone said that I might maybe sure whatever especially if their account posted only in that language.
Scott: Alright, so, um, you know a while back we did an episode.
Scott: we talked about this game But we didn't talk too much about it, I think it was probably the Pac South review episode.
Scott: yep, but now it's time to talk about this game in depth because we have played it many times and I've indeed purchased it and We know all there is to know about it.
Rym: sheriff of Nottingham designed by Sergio Halavan Brian Pope Benjamin Pope and Andres that.
Scott: so these are I think the dice tower dudes.
Scott: Is that correct?
Rym: I am not a hundred percent sure.
Scott: actually, I think I was told that these are the dice tower people's.
Rym: I can figure that out while we're talking.
Scott: Yeah, but anyway, so sheriff of Nottingham is obviously has the theme of you Robin Hood Right kind of action.
Scott: The art is all awesome with all kinds of crazy characters really well-designed and what.
Rym: yeah I really like the art in this game.
Scott: It's very very professional arts And basically the game works like this Someone is the sheriff of Nottingham, you know King John is not in the picture apparently.
Scott: Well, he's sort of in the picture People merchants who have nothing to do with Robin Hood and his merry men.
Scott: We're a little John or Friar Tuck or Maid Mary or anything like that.
Scott: They are merchants and they need to bring things into Nottingham from the outside world in order to sell them in The market, you know bread cheese chickens things that people need.
Scott: right the sheriff He's at the gate of Nottingham and he doesn't want anyone bringing things into Nottingham That shouldn't be in Nottingham.
Scott: things that might help Robin Hood and his merry men like crossbows Rye bread Pepper Silk for Maid Marian, you know, nothing like that is allowed right.
Scott: only things that are allowed are apples Chickens cheese and bread.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: No other imports.
Rym: so every game all you do is go around and someone's the sheriff and Everyone puts between one and five goods in their bag and they look the sheriff in the eye.
Rym: You have it says you have an actual bag that you put actual cards in and snap shut a snap that it makes a loud Audible snap.
Scott: and when you give it you give this bag to the sheriff and look them in the eye and tell the sheriff What is in the bag?
Rym: There are four chickens in this bag, right?
Scott: There's really only 20 different things.
Scott: You can tell the sheriff you must pick one and only one of the legal good types.
Scott: So chicken bread cheese Apple and you give a number between one and five.
Scott: the number must be correct.
Scott: If you have three cards in the bag, you must say three.
Rym: Yeah, you can't lie about right?
Scott: So there's really only 20 possibilities of things that you could say one apple two apple three apple four apple five.
Scott: Oh one chicken two chicken three, right cetera.
Scott: and you hand him the bag.
Scott: now What's in the bag could be fucking anything?
Scott: Who knows what the hell's gonna be five crossbows Jesus Christ.
Scott: Yeah, give me five peppers.
Scott: It could be anything.
Scott: But what you tell him is something legal because obviously you're not gonna tell the sheriff something illegal.
Scott: Then the sheriff completely of their own will may open or not open any number of bags.
Rym: The sheriff's choices are hand the bag back to you.
Rym: And once they hit it back to you, they can't ask for it again.
Rym: You've got it back.
Rym: Those five crossbows are going right into your stall.
Rym: So crossbows here crossbows or you can open it as soon as he unsnaps it.
Rym: That's it.
Rym: He can't resnap it.
Rym: He's looking in that bag or he can engage with you.
Rym: So Scott, what would you pay me?
Rym: Would you pay me five doubloons to not open your bag?
Scott: I dare you to open my bag.
Rym: Sure What I dare you to open my this bag if my friend Muggsy were hiding if my friend crossbows hiding in there.
Scott: So here's the deal.
Scott: if you all if you have in your bag what you said was in there and the sheriff opens it the sheriff owes you money because He opened your totally legit goods and wasted your merchant time.
Rym: man If the TSA had to pay me every time there wasn't a bomb in my bag, that would be amazing.
Scott: Now if the sheriff opens the bag and he finds something in there, that's not supposed to be in there like my Scott.
Rym: That's a nice crossbow.
Rym: You got.
Scott: You said you had four chickens.
Scott: I see three chickens, but this chicken is the king's chicken.
Scott: How is the king's chicken in your chicken basket?
Rym: So the sheriff then throws away all the contraband if he catches it and you got to pay him based on there's.
Rym: there's of every card has a value.
Rym: that's points.
Rym: it's worth and Dollar, it's worth as contraband meaning if the sheriff finds it.
Scott: Yeah There's a basic an award value and a penalty value.
Rym: It's like something will be worth like seven victory points if it's in your stall at the end of the game and you can use That as part of a bribe or whatever like a deal or it's just victory points at the end and on the bottom It'll say like four in red meaning if the sheriff sees it in your bag you owe him four bucks if it's in there.
Rym: But if it's legal, it's always two.
Rym: so the chickens worth like three or four bucks or whatever.
Rym: But if the sheriff opens your bag and you've got five legit chickens the sheriff owes you ten bucks.
Scott: Yep So some of the goods that are contraband like, you know are just like crossbow or silk or whatever And they're just worth a lot of money if you can sneak them into town.
Scott: But there are certain other goods like the king's apples the king's You know chickens the king's rye bread.
Scott: if you get that stuff into town Not only is it worth a lot it also counts as cheese bread Chickens apples because the end of the game whoever has the most apples gets extra bonus points.
Scott: There is the most cheese gets bonus points.
Scott: I guess it's cuz you get a reputation for being the best cheese dealer.
Scott: I guess I don't know.
Scott: So the king's cheese counts is like three cheeses.
Scott: It's like a super cheese.
Scott: So if you get that into town It's gonna be really easy for you to win the cheese battle of who has the most cheese because you got three cheeses in one Card snuck through that
Rym: aspect actually kind of like a small world modified the feel of Vinci by hiding the victory points.
Rym: by doing that it sort of makes the game like.
Rym: it makes the game not just Calculated at the end.
Rym: it makes it hard for someone to say I'm winning by eight.
Rym: So I should do this because the if someone's got a bunch of normal contraband.
Rym: That's just a bunch of victory points, but you don't know if they've got like the chicken contraband.
Rym: You can't be.
Scott: you're not secure When you sneak stuff in the town or bring it into town.
Scott: legally.
Scott: It's publicly visible what you have brought into town except for contraband Which is face down.
Scott: so people know how many cards of contraband you snuck in but they don't know what is on those cards.
Rym: Nothing is better than when you convince the sheriff to not look in your bag and he hands it back and you pull five Motherfucking contraband.
Rym: just lay them all face down.
Rym: I Can't I cannot express to you how good that feels.
Scott: So here's the thing in this game Number one the way you draw the cards.
Scott: We're not gonna get into those rules because it's just sort of a little bit fiddly.
Rym: It's hard to teach this to people.
Scott: Yeah, but basically you draw cards in certain ways and it's also discard piles and sort of like a rummy situation.
Scott: It's easy for other players to know what you could have in your hand because some of the cards you draw are face-up when you Draw them and if anyone's paying attention, which the sheriff should be they can figure out what is in your hand.
Scott: So if you're like five chickens, someone would be like you just picked up like three peppers.
Scott: There's no way you could have five chickens in your hand.
Scott: It's not possible And then they'll just call you out.
Scott: another thing is that Even when it is possible People could look around and count the visible cards.
Scott: So later in the game.
Scott: They're like, huh?
Scott: There's already like 40 apples out.
Scott: There's no way that you can do four apples, right?
Rym: So unlikely what I found happens in practice is there are so many cards in that deck You can't count perfectly.
Scott: because there's so many freaking cards.
Rym: people fuck up the soft count.
Rym: That's all we play with like.
Rym: there was a game where I legit had four bread in my hand and I was like for motherfucking bread and the sheriff and other people also like one bread to bread whatever.
Rym: and the sheriff was like There's a lot of bread out.
Rym: There's no way you have bread and no one was lying because the soft count was really misleading.
Rym: because there's so many cards and people Overestimated what they've seen right.
Scott: also while sneaking contraband into town is such a hugely powerful play if you can pull it off It's actually kind of difficult and from what I've seen Except in cases where someone manages to to bring in a ton of contraband in the town.
Scott: Usually the person who wins this game is someone who is just able to really efficiently bring in the most legit goods in the well.
Rym: So it depends.
Rym: cuz I win a lot.
Rym: I seem to be really good at this game.
Rym: I'm also pretty good you are but you have not won it in a while.
Rym: You won the early games.
Rym: I won many times, but I think the problem is you play a very conservative strategy.
Rym: What Scott will do is be like so that I got four bags here.
Rym: I'm going to open two of them pay me $10 to not be in that lottery and he'll do it randomly.
Scott: Yep, it works.
Rym: It works.
Rym: Okay, but I've had better luck by and maybe it's just.
Rym: it depends on who you're playing with.
Rym: But if someone's just really obvious like I had this beautiful moment with a friend of ours when I looked at him I'm like you said.
Rym: you have five chickens in here.
Rym: What would you like to offer me?
Rym: a bribe to not open your bag and they're like I would like to offer you four.
Rym: and I immediately opened the bag because I knew there's a fucking contraband in there and I Knew they weren't clever enough right then to have been tricking me because I made him talk and make the decisions too quickly, right?
Scott: That's another thing is much like settlers.
Scott: I don't really see a reason to bargain with anyone.
Scott: if someone's bargaining with you That means they're going to pay you.
Scott: they want to pay you some amount less than what the penalty is going to be.
Scott: But if I just open the bag, I get the penalty money.
Rym: Yeah, you say what if I offer you look I'll give you.
Rym: I got five cards right in here.
Rym: I'm gonna tell you right now three of her contraband.
Rym: You'll make 12 bucks.
Rym: If you open my bag, I'll give you 15.
Scott: then I would do it.
Scott: No one has made those kind of offers.
Scott: Everyone is off always offers less than what the penalty is gonna be.
Scott: Yep, so there's no reason to take their deal.
Scott: Also Also, I would say have that much contraband.
Scott: Why would I offer that?
Scott: Why wouldn't I just right?
Scott: Well, do you never know basically giving me that person the game?
Rym: I might propose a deal like that to see if the sheriff is like, oh, I know there's contraband in there.
Rym: now Opens the bag anyway, oh it is actually just two chickens right now there is right.
Scott: So there are some strategies that are out there that I don't see and I haven't seen used enough Right.
Scott: One of them is I got fully legit goods but try to offer a bribe to get the sheriff to open the bag and thus pay you the penalty.
Rym: or I want to see the Strategy of no one's done this.
Rym: I've offered like what everyone's always like three cards, maybe four cards.
Rym: I would expect at least Occasionally someone to be like one card and it's just the most valuable contraband because the sheriff's like who would?
Rym: who would lie about One?
Scott: no But that's the thing is that you put your.
Scott: when you're trying to sneak contraband in you try to do it with just one.
Scott: Because yeah, that's the only way you're getting it through occasionally.
Rym: I've laid down five fucking contraband.
Scott: Yeah Well, yeah but I think one thing is that the rules of the game are such that all the goods you legally declared you get to keep Even if they opened it.
Scott: So if you want to sneak a contraband in you're better off because you only have Two.
Scott: basically one two times the number of players turns in the game.
Scott: So there's five players.
Scott: you have ten turns two of which are gonna be the sheriff.
Scott: So you only have eight turns in the game to get cards through.
Scott: you got to get as many cards through as possible.
Scott: So if you just spend a turn on one contraband, even if you get it in that's even though that card is real valuable.
Scott: That's not that great.
Scott: You were better off going with like three cheese and a contraband Declaring four cheese and if they open it while I still get my three cheese that turn wasn't a waste.
Rym: So you say that but you're playing the game.
Rym: I think your style and strategy Well, I'll get to this in a second.
Rym: the end game of all smart players works.
Rym: Um, if like everyone at the table is super fucking pro but In reality, it's like playing Bonanza If I get the one through the sheriff just because of the feel of the game and the way like you want to open bags.
Rym: It feels really good to open someone's back way.
Scott: more fun to open a bag than to give it back to him.
Rym: And I feel like if the sheriff doesn't open any of your playing TSA agent the game or right?
Scott: What is it more funny to say go on through come on through or is it more fun to like and look through everyone?
Scott: cases and see what they got.
Rym: So I feel like if me another player collude to like put small amounts of stuff through so the sheriff is like eh like he Doesn't bother opening our bags.
Rym: It's probably more likely to open other people's bags.
Scott: If you're a sheriff right someone putting through a small bag, you know, it's like if someone says one I'll open it no matter what because the penalty is gonna be small and it's likely that they're trying to sneak something through right.
Scott: and If they if it isn't something illegal and they only did one it's like fine.
Scott: I'll pay you the penalty of two dollars.
Scott: You're not winning this game.
Scott: Anyway, if you spent a whole turn just to get one cheese
Rym: But I've seen people who had a turn where they just put one fucking thing in there come within two or three points of winning Well,
Scott: they basically, you know It's as good
Rym: as
Scott: putting one thing in there and getting it opened.
Scott: that's legal is as good as putting two things in and getting Them through.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well what he comes down to is this game?
Rym: We haven't fully explored like.
Rym: it's okay.
Rym: It's the same brain feel as Bonanza.
Rym: this game serves the same niche of gaming.
Rym: It's a really really social game.
Rym: There's a lot of like.
Scott: what's in the bag?
Rym: What's in the bag?
Rym: Like you?
Rym: just you really like people slip barons into the bags like cards from other games Just to fuck with the sheriff and like fun stuff like that.
Rym: The game is super fun just like Bonanza.
Rym: super fun because it's really a vote.
Rym: who wins game?
Rym: in the end of everyone's super smart and it might just be Well, there is.
Scott: it's a very largely vote.
Scott: who wins?
Scott: but there's also a large element of luck believe it or not.
Scott: Oh, yeah, if you if you just get like telling if you let's say you just keep drawing tons of chickens It's just like well, I'm probably gonna win because I can get these all in legally.
Rym: I say five chickens Sheriff calls bullshit.
Rym: I get you know, ten extra dollars right my chicken.
Scott: It's like you saw.
Scott: if you can consistently put in your bag every turn a large number of legitimate goods of the same type Because your draw was so great.
Scott: It's like you don't need to even try for contraband because you're going to get the points for having most of legal good Whatever, but the same happens in bonanza.
Rym: I just happen to keep drawing red beans.
Rym: Well, fuck y'all I'm not trading for shit exactly.
Scott: the sheriff is gonna open your bag sometimes at least and you're gonna get extra points for that and You're gonna go these legal goods which are worth a ton of points.
Scott: So it's just like that's.
Scott: you know if you go for the high contraband strategy because that's all you get sure.
Scott: sometimes the sheriff won't open your bag and you'll get a million points and then sometimes they will and You'll have to pay a bunch of money and you'll get zero points that turn because he was all got your pay.
Rym: So, I think basically bonanza is probably one of our favorite most go-to like social games because it's it's a real game.
Rym: There is a pretty high luck factor, especially when everyone's good and the game comes down to.
Rym: you're playing it with a bunch of friends Who are?
Rym: Super super manipulative and the game is this really abstract social game.
Rym: Sheriff of Nottingham is the same brain feel and it breaks down at about the same point like Bonanza.
Rym: if you play it too much gets to this point where People toward the end of the game make very like well Scott's winning so I can't trade with him So I'll trade with you and that's very like.
Rym: how many victory points do you have?
Rym: they break down at the same level of analysis?
Scott: The thing is okay, let's say you're the sheriff.
Scott: at the end of the game You see who's winning right and you're in second place and it's like do I open their bag and perhaps end up giving them Money and they win?
Scott: or do I not open their bag and then they sneak a bunch of stuff through and they win?
Rym: so one thing sheriff has the bonanza doesn't.
Rym: is that the bonanza trading on lying about like what's actually in your hand and what's coming Up is more about convincing other people who's actually winning and convincing them to trade with you.
Rym: This is more about Distracting people getting them to forget to open your bag or like getting the focus on someone else.
Rym: it's this is a game of redirecting your friends attention and at that is actually a fun game, but I Among.
Rym: if five people who have complete poker faces and act like me and Scott play this game It's the same as bonanza.
Rym: Everyone's like I'll trade you this fuck you.
Scott: Yeah, I'm pretty much my only stress.
Scott: if anyone ever says hey Scott pay me to not open your bag I'm just like I dare you to open my bag.
Scott: I dare you go for it.
Scott: Yeah, what are you gonna do?
Scott: What do you do?
Scott: and it doesn't matter what I've got in there?
Scott: I say the same thing every time.
Scott: that way It's just like they don't know what to think.
Rym: see but I pay attention to things like when someone draws cards Do they reorder their hand and then where do they draw cards out afterwards?
Scott: If you watch if you actually look at other people you'll see like they just take the first three cards because everyone's gonna sort Their hand by good type, right?
Scott: So if someone takes the first three cards in their hand and puts them in the bag Okay, those three cards were next to each other They're probably not lying and someone else like well You know three different cards in their hand and puts those in the bag.
Scott: It's like or not even in that.
Rym: What I'll just see is someone will take like two cards out of their hand put them in the bag Then they take another card and put it in the bag.
Scott: Open in that shit.
Rym: Yeah, of course at the same time if they were clever and they did that it becomes a poison cup situation And that's where the game breaks down in the end.
Scott: Okay, but in the same or put stuff in your bag under the table.
Scott: So no one can see what the fuck you're doing.
Rym: Yeah But much like with games like mafia like yes and very pure analytical players Will take a lot of the fun out of the game, but in practice Despite attempting to play analytically people fuck up.
Rym: They lose attention for a minute.
Rym: They a lot of people forget what they put in their own bag.
Rym: Yeah and the rules are very clear.
Scott: one lot of times the sheriff forgets what people declared.
Scott: like the sheriff like people go to the Chef and like three cheese three apples four chickens one bread.
Scott: It's like what did you have again?
Scott: Three cheese?
Scott: was it three cheese.
Scott: I forget but what did you say?
Scott: Yeah, the sheriff doesn't remember what you declared.
Scott: That's a problem.
Rym: So it's a. I think it's a great game to buy.
Rym: it did this and bonanza.
Scott: if you own them both You don't really need anything else in this category.
Rym: if you have those two exactly I mean the only other game in this kind of category at the high level is just mafia.
Rym: You just need the deck of cards for that.
Scott: Yeah You know like we said the theme just goes so well with the mechanic of You're bringing goods into town and the sheriff is opening your bags or not?
Scott: It's so that's you know.
Scott: Not a lot of games can pull off the theme matching.
Rym: So well, the game is also ripe for a small number of very pointed expansions.
Rym: I mean what game isn't like Puerto Rico like.
Rym: expanding it just over complicates it.
Rym: Sure, I can try to imagine just quickly a good expansion to Puerto Rico.
Scott: There's some more buildings or something or tickets in your freddy's.
Rym: I'm not a big fan of the expanse.
Scott: You can't expand tickets in your freddy's.
Scott: really well.
Scott: It has an expansion.
Scott: That's not good.
Scott: Yeah, it's a monument.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Yeah, but you're from Nottingham.
Rym: like there's like.
Rym: there's some sort of like dangerous.
Rym: good Sure that.
Rym: yeah, like little it's like.
Rym: I don't think that you get like bombs.
Scott: like the sheriff opens it they get hurt.
Rym: If the sheriff opens it they get hurt.
Rym: if they don't open it and it goes into your stall you get negative points.
Scott: Yeah, it's good something like that.
Rym: You want to do things.
Rym: the problem is this game.
Rym: It can't be things that just change the analytical side of the game.
Rym: It has to be things that change the psychological side kind of like how in mafia the psycho killer like from a game Theory like game analysis standpoint.
Rym: It's pretty straightforward how to use the psycho killer in practice.
Rym: people Just wanted.
Rym: they want to be the psycho killer cuz it's cool.
Rym: Okay, I could kill you just you want.
Rym: you're just waiting to flip that psycho killer over even if it loses you the game.
Rym: So like if someone's got the bomb in their hand.
Rym: now There's this like they got to keep their cool even though they've got the rare cool thing and they get to do the cool thing with it.
Rym: mm-hmm like The bomb gets discarded and then someone picks the bomb up and then puts their bag with five down.
Scott: Proven to be a popular well-selling game.
Scott: I've seen it around a lot.
Scott: So I don't see why it wouldn't get expanded because every other board game that does well gets expanded.
Rym: and also honestly Groups of people playing this game are always having a loud good time.
Scott: Yeah, I've never seen anyone have a bad time playing this even if they lose.
Rym: yeah So seriously this and bonanza own them both and alternate which one you play and they both have infinite replayability together.
Scott: Yeah, I guess you know.
Scott: the only thing like I said that's negative about this game Is that there's just so many cards and the deck the drawing is and discarding is a bit fiddly.
Rym: Yeah, the the rule.
Rym: it's weird the rules.
Rym: if someone's a gamer you explain the rules once they're like, okay I get it, but someone who's not like really versed in like German board games and card games and everything.
Rym: They will have a lot of trouble with the drawing and discarding rules until you just demonstrate it in the course of play.
Rym: Yeah, luckily, it doesn't.
Rym: you can just.
Rym: you can just demonstrate it in the course of play.
Scott: It doesn't affect their decisions very much No, it's just two discard files and it's like they could have made this game with a lot less cards.
Rym: probably Yeah, but it doesn't.
Rym: well, I don't know.
Rym: having so many cards, you know It's interesting.
Rym: if the game were a little simpler card wise it would be more Analyzable and be less fun in the long run.
Rym: maybe the fact that there's so many cards it pushes the game more toward the psychology.
Scott: Bluffing fucking with your friends just annoying have to deal with all the cards.
Scott: Yeah shuffling them.
Rym: It's hard to rebox it cuz it's just a million fucking cards.
Scott: You can't shuffle them properly at all Yeah, and they always get sorted because like at the end with the game all everyone's You know tableaus or markets are full of legit goods and the discards are full of contrabands Way more contrabands than you can get into your.
Rym: what we do is like the people who know how to play the game Just shuffle the deck like crazy split up while someone else.
Rym: I think you gotta just take all the cards and do the big wash method for like a few minutes to really mix it up Or at least end of game wash just a little bit before you put it away.
Scott: That's also true.
Scott: All right, do you want to talk about mounting your friends?
Rym: So really briefly because it doesn't need a huge Mounting your friends is a game that our friend the hitman hard bought us as a gift and made us play sight unseen at a PAX.
Scott: I didn't play it until I got to rims house.
Rym: It is it's it's versus QWOP.
Scott: It's so good.
Rym: it is so simple and so good and so cheap that all I will say is you should just buy this game and Whip it out And then mount your friends, yes But it's basically.
Rym: you need an Xbox controller plugged into yours just one.
Scott: you pass it around only one person takes it.
Rym: It has all these other modes.
Rym: you can explore that but just there's a mode where it's just add all your name all your friends Into the game and you just take turns trying to climb on top of each other, right?
Scott: It's a QWOP controls at the start of the game.
Scott: What sort of QWOP ish controls right up and basically the controls are you press on what each one of the buttons the four face buttons a bxy Corresponds to a limb arm arm leg leg or hand hand foot foot actually.
Scott: and then when you press one of those buttons down use The analog stick to move that limb or appendage and you could only move one appendage at a time.
Scott: And you have sort of a weird goofy model dude Who's got some junk and stuff and you move them around and at the start of the game?
Scott: There's a goat and a goat just is just a thing.
Scott: It just sits there and you have basically to get onto the goat and get some part of your body above the white line.
Scott: And then once you're above the white line You can press start.
Scott: and if you press start while any part of you is above the white line or enough of you is above The white line you have succeeded in mounting and the next player now can begin and they have to get above the new white line Which is now higher and they have to mount not on top on you on top of you Right, and then the next person is to mount on top of them because the white line keeps getting higher So you can't just like sort of mount onto the side.
Scott: You got a climb on top of everyone that has climbed before and Successfully, press start while enough of you is above the ever rising line.
Scott: It's sort of like a reverse limbo in a way human pyramid situation.
Scott: But the thing is is a time limit.
Scott: So it's like it's not easy to control this person with these weird control scheme and you got to get them up there Which is easy enough, but not easy with this time limit.
Scott: the other thing is that some people spawn on the left and some people spawn on the right and Also, if there's an odd number of players someone's gonna alternate between left and right spawns When you mount.
Scott: you might like try to create a pyramid like leans to the right or leans to the left Making it much harder for people who spawn on that side to mount Because they have much much farther to travel to get above the line.
Rym: There are tons of other modes and the game is just it's.
Rym: it's another one of those things The games that are really break out in the last several years on.
Rym: Like like PC games and video games for me have been these very very simple Directly competitive games.
Rym: It's like this reimagining of Atari combat.
Rym: Every game that's just a reimagining of Atari combat that is well designed.
Rym: It's just like they're my favorite games lately and I feel like there's been a renaissance of this kind of game.
Rym: So it's a great game because it is skill based But it's also funny and fun enough to where no one's gonna feel super bad when they lose.
Scott: Yep It would be awesome If you had a bunch of people just play in it because it's so silly and they could.
Scott: you know Even people who are not very good could still mount a few times and have a good time.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: this is also great if you have a bunch of people who are really freaking good at it because it would be so epic in A reverse Jenga sort of way when everyone's mounting way high and it gets real tense the game.
Rym: So, oh my god, the coins have dicks on them too.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Yeah, there's dicks.
Rym: yeah, so but you can turn them into grapes if you don't want to see the the Poorly animated dick swinging around.
Rym: but this is the kind of game Like if you're having a party like at your place with a bunch of friends just have this on our TV With the controller laying there and just let people play it.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.