Rym: It's Tuesday July 19th 2016.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm coughing and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We're talking about Ekans.
Scott: We don't need it.
Rym: We're talking about Pokemon go.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: So yeah, we're finally back.
Rym: you guys know we were in ConnectiCon.
Rym: we're the heads of the panels department.
Rym: that all went fine and We all got sick.
Rym: Well at least me and Scott and Emily got sick, and you know some kinds of sicknesses like When I followed all the protocols of not shaking hands.
Rym: I fucking didn't touch anyone.
Scott: it hand wash.
Rym: I wash my hands every time I walk past that bathroom by panel ops, and I use the alcohol disinfectant.
Scott: I don't use the disinfectant, but I wash my hands like crazy.
Rym: Yep, but it didn't matter.
Rym: now it appears that we actually got different things.
Scott: I don't like the way that shit makes your hands feel.
Rym: yeah, no no cuz it's all like gooey and jelly.
Scott: yeah No, I don't like that shit.
Scott: Yeah, but at least it was.
Rym: at least it was the real shit.
Rym: It was alcohol.
Rym: It wasn't like trickles and just like came from operation Hammond.
Rym: Real guys term busters, but I guess Scott got strep throat And I just got this like ridiculous fucking cold that migrated into my eye at one point.
Scott: Oh, yeah Wait I didn't get the eye thing.
Rym: yeah I called my I called my insurance.
Rym: cuz they have this like nurse you can call and ask questions.
Rym: And I was like so I'm an adult and I think I just got pink eye from myself And she was like you have a cold and I'm like yep, and then she's like were you coughing violently?
Rym: I was like yep, and she was like you probably coughed it into your eye And I was like that's a thing and she's like that is most definitely a thing.
Rym: So yeah pink eye is super contagious if you get it like Eyeword like you get it in your eye from like some kid who didn't wash his hands after poke your eye out kid yep.
Rym: But if you have a cold you can cough so hard that you knock it into the back of your eye And you'll basically just get pink eye from yourself.
Rym: so uh Normally like when I get sick with like a flu or something like that one katsu kann long ago Like we'll power through and like do a show or like do a thing especially at a convention.
Rym: But both of we ended up having illnesses that caused Constant coughing.
Rym: so even if our mind was sound the body could not do GeekNights nor could I even do any patreon stuff?
Rym: So we're basically just dead in the water.
Scott: also I wasn't even here.
Scott: I stick because I woke up in Connecticut Monday morning planning to take the train to the city directly to work But I was sick, so I just stayed in Connecticut.
Scott: Yeah, can't do a podcast from a state away.
Rym: I'm at work on Monday and Scott messages me, and he's like you motherfucker I got me sick, and I was like wasn't me bro.
Rym: I got a different sick.
Scott: Well, we all got say whatever.
Rym: so we're finally back.
Rym: There's gonna be a lot of coughing in this episode probably and I'm not gonna edit that out cuz my cough is like 25% of what it was yesterday.
Rym: yeah, no you.
Rym: so Emily saw cuz.
Rym: well I thought I was feeling better like I didn't think I was sick anymore on Wednesday, so I'm playing some overwatch right and Suddenly like the game's getting intense and I start to say some stuff on the chat And then I just had this ridiculous coughing fit.
Rym: so bad That one of our friends on the voice chat in the game was like Rym you afk.
Rym: What's up?
Rym: Cuz I just wasn't moving.
Rym: I was like flailing and coughing coughing more now that I'm talking.
Rym: yep That's how that'll go.
Rym: you want to cough drop.
Rym: No now.
Rym: I think we have some Emily's coughing out there, too Offing on the dinner the only.
Rym: well, I don't think I can get what Emily has cuz I'm pretty sure it's what I had.
Rym: But at least the party we went to over the weekend was chill times in the summer outside, so I feel pretty good rejuvenated and healing wave unrelatedly But kind of related because it's kind of funny.
Rym: I promise we're not talking about American politics or any nonsense but the bad parties conventions going on right now in America.
Rym: and Something really funny happened.
Rym: the the attendees of the Republican convention, which is like Literally the opposite of the nerd convention that we just ran Might have a norovirus outbreak.
Rym: well.
Scott: They're all old people so their health is not the greatest.
Rym: now It's funny cuz on one hand is easy for disease to spread.
Rym: yep But nerd conventions are known for disease spreading because like a lot more people there And there's the churn like that's why Convention Center escalators always fail.
Rym: because nerds don't just walk into a room Sit there for four hours And then go out drinking in like shitty hotel bars.
Rym: nerds are going up and down and up and down walking around constantly.
Rym: tell the Conventions.
Scott: if you look at them on TV They don't look like tech conferences where it's like a bunch of chairs and people sitting quietly.
Scott: It's a bunch of people standing all crammed in next to each other tightly.
Scott: Yeah, right push it open and yelling and I realize this and coughing on each other.
Rym: It's a political convention, which means it's not just that they're full of flecks of spittle all over their faces.
Rym: What a politicians do?
Rym: kiss babies and shake hands.
Rym: They're walking around.
Rym: this thing touching so much is so much handshaking going on there I there's a rumor that I can't confirm yet that Maybe 100% of California's delegation has norovirus, and if you don't know what norovirus is Republicans in California, there's at least two or three I assume Someone else.
Rym: it was something funny because there was an uproar like there's some political nonsense going on.
Rym: so a whole bunch of delegates walked out of a vote like all this like drama happened and Someone pointed out that the tweet from the news that said the Colorado delegation has abandoned the convention Was that exactly 4 20 p.m Oh That is the extent of the politics we'll get tonight.
Rym: we're back we're bad we're doing GeekNights.
Rym: got any news?
Scott: I do have a news the long-awaited Radio ball and a grim dark future when all he was released to the world Like a week or two ago.
Rym: Have you played it yet?
Scott: I bought it immediately and have not even launched it or installed it because I have not been home and not sick and At a time when I'm gonna play some video ball.
Rym: even at a time like this We've been.
Scott: why don't you really game in the winter?
Scott: Why would you release your game in the warmest most beautiful time of the year?
Rym: I mean, we've been talking about this game for what?
Rym: almost three years every packs We go up to these guys and you were like just give me the game like.
Rym: I don't just forgive me the game I want the game also.
Scott: at a time It just so happens even though I'm ready to play video ball everyone that I would play video ball with is over Playing overwatch and Pokemon go and I even if I played video ball.
Scott: No one else is video balling now Luckily there.
Rym: It's not a fully transitive situation.
Rym: You can play Pokemon go and video ball at the same time.
Rym: you play Pokemon Pokemon goal and overwatch at the same time.
Rym: You cannot play overwatch and video ball at the same time especially because the competitive season started and The let's just say the level of overwatch play is rising rapidly.
Rym: I'm holding on to my 51 rank with grim determination.
Scott: I'll be started on video ball.
Rym: Soonish I will install video ball and play it before the end of this week.
Scott: I think at the very least right even if video ball doesn't take off to be internet competitive.
Scott: You know thing that it will at least become the best like everyone's in the same room at the party game.
Rym: Oh hell yeah, in fact, it's Scott.
Rym: It's kind of good.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: take that, you know It's like we'll have another option besides Bomberman.
Scott: Well Bomberman and video ball.
Rym: when rocket league came out Half of our friends played enough to get pretty good and the other half didn't.
Scott: but it sucks to play rocket league in the same Room.
Scott: Yeah, well, we had it also hard, you know, it's hard people to play.
Rym: We did it at the New Year's party But that's because we had like seven computers.
Scott: that also sucks to have like a split-screen time.
Rym: I didn't have that.
Rym: I was playing my laptop.
Scott: It's still.
Scott: it's not but it's not the best.
Rym: But the other problem was you know people got good at different rates and overwatch While it's fun to play with friends competitive kind of split off on its own both a video ball.
Rym: If our friends don't play it that much it means every time we're together We bust it out and much like star wall Nobody's good enough to where no one wants to play Street Fighter or Soul Calibur with Jess or Scott anymore.
Scott: Well, there are also times when even if everyone plays the game the same amount some people progress and skill more quickly than others.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, anyway, I am excited though I mean, I've been waiting for video ball for a long time and it's gonna scratch an itch.
Rym: I know it's gonna scratch an itch.
Scott: It's the other game We've been waiting for which we talked about.
Scott: last episode the Valhalla is out - we still haven't played that The cyberpunk bartending simulator.
Rym: I installed it on my laptop And I was gonna play it on the way to the party this weekend because I was still a little sick.
Rym: I just fell asleep instead and then the Prince of Nothing book came out.
Scott: So that's replacing all portable gaming.
Scott: is reading books instead?
Scott: Yeah, oh by the way, I finished reading the book club book.
Rym: I was about to finish reading the book club book.
Rym: Wait for some meta moment And then I read the first 60% of the Prince of Nothing book.
Rym: I feel like I'm gonna finish the Prince of Nothing book, but I'll probably finish Orcs and Craig this weekend.
Scott: Mmm, took me five or six hours to read it.
Rym: Not bad.
Rym: My Kindle says there's only two hours left in the Prince of Nothing book.
Scott: I was surprised at looking at the percentage at the bottom of the Prince of Nothing.
Scott: as I read it I'm like really 30% already.
Rym: we ready for this because I hit the whale mothers and then I looked at the percent and I was like Whoa, whoa, okay.
Rym: Well, I know about whale mothers.
Rym: There's not that much book left.
Scott: I think I'm in the whale mother chapter right now.
Rym: Yeah, but you don't know what the whale mothers are yet.
Rym: Oh if men bred themselves the way men breed cattle, yes, it's bad stuff.
Rym: This book is peak our Scott Packard.
Rym: Yeah, but why did everything we like come out literally like in the span of a few weeks?
Scott: Everyone got their shit done in August.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: No get your line in February That's right.
Rym: If we make a convention which we're talking about it's gonna be like middle of February on the worst.
Scott: It's gonna be sometime fucking cold.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: It's gonna be cold and miserable.
Rym: There'll be nothing going on that weekend to trust us.
Rym: so in my news.
Rym: Scott might make fun of me a little because my news is yet again overwatch, but the new patch came out.
Scott: You'll get over it soon enough.
Rym: Uh I'm still not over weapons factory.
Rym: you realize I'm still not over tribes Like if tribes were easy to play like like this game is.
Rym: I just play tribes every day Like I've been maybe even quick GeekNights.
Rym: to be a I'd wander the world's game of jet packs.
Scott: There's a character Farah, but not everyone not everyone and there's that spin fuse ores.
Scott: Uh doesn't have all that crazy shit.
Rym: You can set up in your base Symmetra kinda Not quite to that extent but symmetric and make teleporters You can get.
Scott: you can equip yourself every time you spawn with all And it's all the vehicles and everyone gets in the vehicle.
Rym: Can't do any of that.
Scott: The map is ginormous.
Rym: That's what I'm saying.
Rym: It doesn't fully scratch the tribes eating but holy hell Does it scratch the weapons factory?
Rym: old team fortress mega TF itch?
Rym: I play this game every goddamn day but a new patch just hit and The internet was going crazy about it and you might have seen me arguing with a lot of different people about the patch.
Rym: But the patch is interesting for a number of reasons.
Rym: so I'm gonna read the patch notes because one thing you should know Scott and I were talking before the show one thing blizzards real good about is There's like this twofold balance on the one hand.
Rym: They don't listen to you when you complain to them.
Scott: Actually a little bit.
Scott: Well the hearthstone people seem to be listening.
Scott: They listen somewhat.
Rym: they listen in the sense of they see people who are mad and they look at the game and say oh There's a problem there Let's fix it.
Rym: But they don't listen to you in their lot when you're like.
Rym: You should add another kind of card called this and let us make mods of the game.
Scott: No, and they're definitely not letting.
Scott: they never let anyone mod anything.
Scott: blizzard.
Scott: blizzard is the most anti mod, right?
Scott: They go after anyone who sets up their own server.
Rym: And I'm telling you I used to be super pro mod.
Rym: the only reason I am NOT anymore is because of tribes - But the other thing is that blizzard when they do make changes I'm pro.
Scott: I'm pro mod in terms of the kind of mod where it's like we made this brand new game using your engine Right without having to buy your stupid engine like counter-strike.
Scott: But I'm not pro mod Like.
Scott: we made a different counter-strike get zombie counter-strike and now half the people are playing zombie counter-strike.
Rym: The worst thing about your example, is that zombie counter-strike was almost fun like it was probably the best of those.
Rym: Did you ever play World of Warcraft counter-strike?
Scott: I'm also pro mod in terms of like.
Rym: hey, let me make a custom map for this game like FYI swirled Yep, or sieve five like let's just make the entire Prince of Nothing world into a scenario.
Rym: I was my.
Scott: that was my idea.
Rym: It was we.
Scott: uh, we're just as long as you admit that it was my idea.
Rym: I should just post that chat you had.
Rym: uh, was it your idea or did I incept it into you?
Rym: What came before?
Scott: I came before.
Rym: Well, actually we have a chat log and you'll see exactly what came before.
Scott: Yeah me.
Rym: But so the one thing is there here's.
Rym: I'm gonna read some of these change notes because blizzard goes into a lot of detail.
Rym: If a match goes into overtime for more than 20 seconds, the overtime fuse will now burn down much more quickly Mmm, so if a match doesn't end definitively at the end of its time it goes into overtime.
Rym: the way over time basically works is they'll be like an objective of some Kind.
Rym: so like one example is there's a payload that is to get to a destination by a time.
Rym: if the time runs out and the Payload is not yet at the destination the people pushing the payload lose, but the payload is still moving Because the the attackers are still on it.
Rym: then over time starts and as long as they stay on the payload The overtime goes on forever, but the moment they're off the payload.
Rym: There's this cow overtime fuse that just goes.
Scott: So it's 20 seconds, right.
Scott: so it basically allows you.
Rym: if like well, no, it's 20 seconds from the point you are not Advancing it any further.
Scott: Right, but I'm saying it's like it's basically allows for the buzzer beater situation.
Scott: We're like, we almost made it.
Scott: We don't want to just get cut off like you're one.
Rym: You could spend the whole match at the beginning of them of the thing Like you're like way away from the objective hit overtime And if you just never get knocked off of that thing, you'll eventually take it over the finish line in a win.
Rym: It works great But what they're doing is if they over time goes on for more than 20 seconds total The fuse that determines whether or not it can keep going will start burning down faster and faster and faster to force a conclusion which is good because The ice.
Rym: I saw some players and I did this a few times who had strategies that Involved getting into overtime and delaying the game for a very long time like six mays can't lose a Competitive play.
Rym: Oh, oh.
Rym: and also in overtime Respawn times are increased.
Scott: Yeah, that makes sense.
Rym: So think about this.
Rym: That means in overtime It kills someone.
Scott: you're gonna win like.
Rym: that's a big deal.
Rym: killing someone matters a lot surviving matters a lot.
Scott: Sure That's good.
Rym: The change that everyone's bitching about is and I was bitching too, and I'm very Conflicted and ambivalent on the change in competitive play Matches.
Rym: you can only have one of each hero per team.
Rym: So that would be like if in weapons factory you could only have on your team one sniper one engineer one arsonist one Whatever.
Rym: healer nurse nurse was the class.
Rym: and on one hand I don't like that because I do enjoy the strategies people came up with like in certain maps just have two sentry turrets fucking go Nuts, but on the other hand I can see that if you allow Heroes to be doubled up because every hero has like a crazy dune style power.
Rym: Then if you make one hero a little bit too strong in a certain situation You could theoretically have a degenerate strategy in certain maps of yeah Just fucking send six Winston's in and nothing beats that but six maze.
Scott: I mean limiting options is usually good, right?
Rym: It's like, you know Well, it's good for balance.
Scott: If you think of like the set of players you have on the set of classes you choose on an FPS team as Like the cards in a in a collectible card game.
Scott: It's like you can't just let someone make a deck of like eight lightning bolts and then turn it into a deck of eight.
Scott: You know restore health or whatever right when they need health.
Scott: It's like that's you know, it's bullshit, right?
Scott: It's like yeah choose one of everything, you know at any given time.
Scott: I'm surprised they didn't actually take it further and do the thing the mobas do or you deny.
Scott: And it's only.
Scott: it's like if someone when you pick something you're that for the whole game and Only one person and as soon as one team takes a class the other team can't pick it.
Scott: You know what?
Rym: They appear to have been floating some of those ideas, but honestly I don't ruin the game.
Scott: I think it works in mobas because they have so many classes that if someone like takes one support There's always another support you can get.
Scott: it's not like they can ever ban you from getting any healers whatsoever unless you really mess It up, but I don't think overwatch while it has a lot.
Scott: It doesn't have enough yet.
Rym: Also overwatch is more like make your team of six with your strategy for those six people Irrespective of the other side.
Rym: It's more like hockey and less like a MOBA in that regard.
Rym: Like this is my team as your team.
Scott: No, like counter picking like ah, they picked that person.
Scott: So we need to pick this.
Rym: in fact, you can't see who they pick until you see them in game.
Scott: Well, they could let you see right they can let you see, you know They could if they built the MOBA like character selection system They would like.
Rym: I'm saying right now you can't right but what it means is, you know to use the hockey analogy Because you can change characters during the match Like yeah, that's another thing as he can't do.
Rym: that is great because that is like a hockey line change Yeah, and it works really well.
Rym: So I'm really ambivalent on the change.
Rym: I Suspect in the end.
Rym: now they gave some additional notes as to why they made the change and the chain.
Scott: I'll just make the game more interesting.
Rym: Yeah It does so.
Rym: the here's the pros and cons.
Rym: the pros of the change seem to be one.
Rym: It's easier to balance heroes Like.
Rym: they can try crazy stuff with a hero and they can test it much more easily for balance, right?
Scott: If there's some ridiculously powerful hero That's like Opie.
Scott: each team will have one at most and that's it and you can balance around that and you won't have these boring games.
Scott: So it's like oh we made a hero Opie.
Scott: Both teams are six of the same here all the time.
Scott: Oops You know, you just save yourself from that.
Rym: Yep But the main complaint seemed to be that competitive players are whiny little babies who are complaining That it was really hard to counter certain strategies on certain maps.
Rym: they didn't appear to be completely degenerate.
Rym: It's just baby's got to get good.
Scott: Well also, yeah, it's hard to counter certain strategies in certain maps.
Scott: But now those other people can't use those strategies because they also have to have six unique heroes Yep, and they can't come at you with six of the same guy.
Scott: You don't need six of the other guy to stop them.
Scott: They only have.
Rym: you know, it's like come on But like there were some maps word, but then here's there's my counterpoint on the other side.
Rym: When this wasn't a thing especially in casual play you'd see these amazing spectator moments Where the crazy bullshit goes down like a team's losing and losing and suddenly they just kind of get desperate and six winstons just burst onto the scene and go crazy go literally apeshit and It was real fun.
Rym: It's like when the crazy crap like the onside kick nonsense happens.
Scott: Yeah, that's why this rules only in competitive mode.
Scott: Hearthstone did the same thing.
Scott: Hearthstone.
Scott: They have you know, they have competitive mode, which is like standard mode and they also have wild mode Which is like play all the crazy cards.
Rym: Whoo Now I do think I suspect.
Rym: now again, I do not know the math I don't have any of the stats that Blizzard has I Suspect they could have gotten away with doing actually the thing that weapons factory did back in the day Cuz weapons factory the most recent game.
Rym: that's like this game And what they did is all the people who ran servers sort of converged upon.
Rym: So certain classes were limited to a limited number and others weren't.
Scott: yeah another way of doing this.
Scott: That's just too complicated for real-time Switching is just use a points based system Like each class is worth X points and your team can only have X points on the field at a time.
Scott: But it's like imagine respawning.
Scott: I mean, I have to choose a class.
Scott: There's only 20 points available.
Scott: I want a class that cost 22. could someone else die and respond to something that cost to last so I can switch to the?
Scott: You know, it's like that.
Scott: it's like fuck that nonsense, right?
Scott: But yeah, but that's a good system other than that obvious problem.
Scott: If you were if you were like planning at the start of the game like building a miniature, you know, then it would be fine.
Rym: Yep, but I remember weapons back.
Rym: I remember the full details just been so long.
Rym: but like Gunner was like Bastion is an overwatch and most servers said only two Gunners Only two engineers because like six turrets in a room in a 10v10 was just unbeatable.
Rym: So they do that sort of thing.
Rym: I hope in the in the long run.
Rym: That's what ends up happening.
Rym: I'd like to see a little bit of hero stacking because it really adds to the strategic depth I think.
Scott: I think that all they really need to do to solve that is to just do like I said with the MOBAs.
Rym: Right, if you want it, for example, I do not want to see a lot of heroes in this game.
Rym: Like I don't want is I was gonna be a lot of heroes.
Rym: Hey, I don't think they'll be hundreds cuz they're going real.
Scott: I don't know if they'll be hundreds.
Scott: But for example, like you want more engineers right that because you want more than one turret, right?
Scott: So they'll just.
Rym: they already have two kinds of turrets.
Scott: I'm just saying they'll make a Yet another class that has some kind of engineer, you know, that's different than the other ones But still right.
Scott: and that's how you would get to stacking, right?
Rym: I just don't think they'll add too many heroes over time partly because the game in all games they've had so far they've kept adding heroes.
Rym: true, but this is a very different kind of game because of the player skill input and Unlike those MOBAs even the Pareto frontier in this game is fucking tight.
Scott: I sure but I'm saying expect new heroes.
Rym: Oh, yeah, but they're the rate of hero adding.
Scott: Expect multiple heroes multiple heroes per year.
Rym: Well, well, I don't know.
Rym: I don't think it'll be multiple per year.
Scott: It'll be multiple per year.
Rym: I may be at most two a year.
Scott: No, it's gonna be way more to be at least five.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: We'll see.
Scott: that's how they do.
Rym: in the very least They'll never charge you for heroes But if they do it if they do it a lot of charging 50 bucks for the game So they better fucking not charge it.
Rym: The problem will be if they had too many heroes the game will turn into a MOBA where that knowledge matrix starts to matter a lot.
Rym: and Also, it means that teams tactical composition changes are so much more subtle and less obvious to spectators that the game will basically turn into A MOBA and I'd quit playing it.
Scott: That's how they do.
Rym: Yeah, and if that happens, I'll quit.
Rym: but it's not doesn't appear to be happening Now.
Rym: the player the characters are all all true dick and super skill based.
Rym: There's a whole bunch of other changes
Scott: But I mean it'll be slower than adding heroes to their actual MOBA because it takes a lot more work to make one For an FPS, you know all you got to make all these weapons and models and animations and stuff that you know.
Scott: They're bigger and they're fancier.
Rym: I think they're gonna add more modes and more maps first.
Scott: They're definitely gonna do that for sure because also I noticed something the character they added unlike the MOBA's that I'll have like one map Right.
Rym: Yep Well, actually I'll get into that later because we got other stuff to talk about and this will be a real long news.
Rym: if I talk About everything else is going on here.
Rym: But the the most important change I play diva a lot Like I'm real good with diva and I stopped playing diva because it felt kind of overpowered to me And I wanted to get better at other classes.
Rym: They just made diva way more powerful because everyone else thought that character was underpowered.
Rym: So I'm already like real fucking dangerous with that character and now they just made her like twice as powerful.
Rym: I'm real curious.
Rym: What's gonna happen if I start using her again.
Rym: So anyway things Of the day got a thing of the day.
Scott: Yeah, some dude got some Legos and he made with those Legos a gentleman's club.
Scott: Yeah Ricks bricks bricks all shapes and sizes and while you know a gentleman's club is in itself rather distasteful This is funny.
Rym: It looks a lot like show palace.
Scott: Yeah Like specifically it's quite low brow, but it has all these Lego jokes and ah, but I'm quite low brow It's it's well constructed.
Rym: So so a multiple people sent this to me.
Rym: This is called hyper reality.
Rym: Uh presents a provocative and kaleidoscopic new vision of the future where physical and virtual rallies emerge in a city saturated in media.
Rym: This is basically now.
Rym: I couldn't find it because I forgot it was called.
Rym: I couldn't remember who showed it to me.
Rym: so eventually I just typed into Google and I was like Dystopian augmented reality and this is literally the first thing that came up, but it is a video that's like a first-person view of a human being living in a Pretty likely future of what augmented reality is actually gonna be like in the real world.
Scott: But I mean we've seen stuff like this a million times before.
Scott: what's different about this one?
Rym: I like what name one.
Scott: Well, there's like the dental coil anime.
Rym: No coil is a lot different from this.
Rym: Yes Superficially, here's a future where augmented reality exists.
Scott: Blade Runner every single cyberpunk thing ever.
Rym: So Blade Runner doesn't say any of the things really that this says.
Rym: Blade Runner also wasn't really focused on AR at all.
Rym: Mmm Blade Runner.
Rym: Yeah, all right Scott there are works of media that Superficially cover the same broad spectrum of just someone walking around is like ads in their face all the time.
Rym: That is one tiny aspect of this.
Rym: Also.
Rym: What is very different about this is that it is very well constructed and has a deep variety of very Specific and subtle details that really drive home the Terrifying reality of this sort of future.
Rym: the moral is always block ads.
Rym: Yeah, always always always block ads and every every aspect of your life block ads.
Rym: hundred years block ads.
Scott: calm You wanna play gods?
Rym: Yeah In the moment, the booklet book is Oryx and Crick by Margaret Atwood read the whole thing.
Scott: It took me like five six hours tops.
Rym: I'm gonna finish the Prince of Nothing book and then this weekend I'll probably read Oryx and Crick.
Scott: So I already picked like the next two book club books and Apparently Oryx and Crick has like two sequels and those are not the next book club picks even though it's apparently you're supposed to read Them.
Scott: Yep I didn't even realize that that was a trilogy.
Rym: until many of our friends when they're when they find out that we're reading this book For the book club are like, oh you got to read the other two.
Scott: I'm like other two.
Scott: What?
Scott: Even though I finished it at that point.
Scott: I was like, oh Okay that you just turn the ending from a non cliffhanger into a cliffhanger That there was more.
Rym: see remember the only reason I read all 14 of those Wheel of Time books plus new spring Was that I knew that series was already done.
Rym: There'd never be any more and the original author was dead.
Rym: I will.
Rym: I basically don't start things that I don't trust.
Rym: might that I do not trust you end reliably.
Scott: you're reading Prince of Nothing.
Rym: then Based on how those books are going He knows how it's going to end and he's likely to survive to finish them.
Rym: and there aren't that many more.
Rym: There's gonna be way less news tomorrow if our Scott Packard dies Before the book after the one I'm reading right now comes out.
Rym: I'm going to be distraught let us put it that way.
Rym: but I think the the Danger of that is much lower than with say the awful Game of Thrones books that I really have zero interest in reading.
Scott: Yeah, no fuck those.
Rym: Yep in other news now that Connecticut is done All that content that's been kind of on hold for a long time is coming back full force.
Rym: Scott's gonna make a bunch of videos.
Rym: I'm gonna make a bunch of videos.
Rym: got a ton of things for the patreon.
Rym: I got a bunch of panels from other conventions.
Rym: I got to upload to YouTube GeekNights presents who 10 of 15 is like 90% done.
Rym: all this shit is a creative explosion is gonna come out dependent only upon how nice it is outside Mm-hmm.
Rym: And also we are going to be officially Appearing live at PAX West not PAX prime West 2016 on a prime and a living in capstone at the end getting help from physical plant physical plant.
Rym: and I'm using my fire My Phoenix browser.
Scott: Yeah I'm gonna play some tennis on my Nintendo revolution.
Rym: But we are performing Saturday September 3rd at 5 p.m.
Rym: In the chicken theater the grind.
Rym: We're doing an hour-long lecture on the very concept of grinding in games.
Rym: at its core It's been you know, we do a lot of panels a lot of lectures of cons.
Rym: But I do want to say this because this one's gonna be More like panels we did many years ago in that We're excited like really excited about it.
Rym: as soon as Scott had the idea cuz he I was like, what about grinding?
Rym: and I was like Oh, oh and then we both had already like four hours worth of shit to talk.
Scott: So if anyone get out there, I want you to help us do some research.
Scott: I want you to find us the earliest examples of grinding that in gaming that you can follow.
Rym: in gaming I was about to say being a peasant right, but I mean like, you know, I found like.
Scott: there's some old-ass RPGs obviously But like is there anything older than the oldest RPGs?
Rym: We have to level up and yeah, there's no grinding in Kriegsfield.
Scott: I mean like.
Scott: grinding is old.
Scott: Final Fantasy 1 was not the first.
Rym: now you might be saying but Rym and Scott.
Rym: What do you mean by grinding?
Rym: There's some wonderful threads.
Scott: I think you can get an idea of what grinding means.
Rym: Yeah, you can figure it out But there are a lot like.
Rym: grinding serves purposes in games.
Rym: This is not gonna be a lecture of.
Rym: here's all the reasons why grinding is bad and why grinding sucks the end.
Scott: Let's go home.
Rym: Yeah, no grinding serves its purpose.
Rym: Grinding is a good thing.
Rym: in some games.
Rym: There's different kinds of grind.
Rym: this I'm just.
Rym: I'm feeling it.
Rym: This is gonna be more like that dude, bro Like those old lectures we used to do because I don't know that clocks ring and I feel good about this one Because I've noticed the lectures that we really really like.
Rym: we basically do like twice at conventions and The second time we do it.
Rym: that video is what we put on YouTube and it's just perfect and we never run it anywhere again Because the perfect versions on YouTube.
Rym: But then we got lazy for a while cuz we've been busy.
Rym: So we'll take like one panel and run it at like eight conventions.
Rym: I feel like this one might be a one and done on YouTube.
Rym: Hmm.
Rym: See I'm playing Babe Ruth in it Pointing.
Rym: I think this one's gonna be good.
Rym: Whatever also packs is five four days six.
Rym: if you go to dev I'm gonna be there for all six days and it's gonna be amazing.
Rym: I Don't think we have any conventions after that until mag fest good, which we'll be performing at.
Rym: and yeah.
Rym: So speaking of you know, those kinds of lectures there was a panel we did at a PAX a long goddamn time ago.
Rym: This was like PAX Prime 2010 or it might have been like East 2011.
Scott: the thing we said at this panel was we've been saying much longer.
Rym: well before we did that Yeah, but they culminated in this panel.
Rym: We called the panel egregiously unrealized potential and we were like Why doesn't someone remake tie fighter like we?
Rym: just all these things like why doesn't someone do this?
Rym: Why doesn't someone do that?
Rym: And then we talked about like why the remake of bionic commando From the NES was way better than the game that it was made to promote and all that nonsense.
Rym: But then at the very end our last slide was just Pokemon Pokemon MMO.
Rym: Let's fucking do it.
Rym: It'll end the world.
Rym: It'll be the most important thing ever like.
Rym: it'll change everything.
Scott: and we were right Yeah, they're also right when I said that Pokemon go is just gonna be ingress of the Pokemon skin on it.
Rym: So I'd listen to because we talked about ingress on GeekNights when it came out and we you know We played a whole bunch, which is why I feel no need to play Pokemon.
Rym: Yeah But we played ingress a lot because it was the first one that played it a moderate amount.
Rym: we played it a bunch for a short span of time to be able to Understand it because it was the first modern AR game.
Scott: No, the first modern AR game was that thing that EA did in 2001.
Scott: That was I don't argue No, I said you and called you on the phone.
Rym: I know what you're talking about.
Rym: I think that's a different class of air again.
Scott: I'm just saying it's that's that's even more AR than yeah.
Scott: But that's why I said modern AR also Pokemon go Only a little bit of AR going on.
Scott: It's mostly just Jeep.
Scott: It's mostly just a game that has GPS in.
Scott: that's the very definition of AR that it has a GPS.
Rym: It's overlaid on the real world in your real life.
Rym: There's there's physical things in your alter.
Scott: Your reality isn't altered by Scott and you're playing.
Rym: but AR AR game like version one would have been when people Told a story about a place in a novel and that Think about the things the novel said about that place.
Rym: Version two would have been like geocaching But whatever.
Rym: anyway, when you talked about ingress we both said Multiple times that this is the model.
Rym: This is the blueprint for a real AR game down the road.
Rym: Like this is clearly just a candy box.
Rym: This is Google through Niantic Experimenting with this concept.
Rym: It's like the beta test that they're gonna use this data to make a real game later.
Rym: and then a while ago years ago.
Rym: Was it years ago?
Rym: was a while ago at least a year ago.
Rym: but remember when one day Pokemon just appeared in Google Maps for a day and then they disappeared like just there were Pokemon in places around the world and you could Yeah, poke up.
Rym: Nintendo and Google have been pretty tight with Pokemon and stuff for quite a while They've been friendly to each other when that happened that one day I was like, there's a Pidgeotto just on Google Maps and I clicked on it and now I have a Pidgeotto.
Rym: and then like we talked about it.
Rym: but what one thing that I said in that GeekNights was It's interesting because that means that Google and Nintendo Talked to each other and made that happen like Roger Rabbit style including characters of multiple properties Which meant Google and Pokemon were talking or Google and Nintendo were talking and we basically predicted that this was gonna
Scott: happen.
Rym: Yeah physical plant Mm-hmm, and sure enough we were right 100% it happened.
Rym: and here it is.
Scott: Yeah, I mean we talked about it when it was announced and now it's here except the wristband thing isn't here yet.
Scott: Yep, the race is exactly what we said It would be.
Scott: yep, and it's interesting because it changed all those people who were like, oh man, you know, they kept saying stuff It wasn't gonna be and I told them they were wrong and they didn't believe me.
Scott: They're like, oh, yeah There's gonna be like battling and I'm like, no there isn't and we were right there isn't.
Rym: well There sort of is but not regular not really not the way that they were thinking.
Rym: now, it's interesting because Nintendo they've said Features will come and they have said specifically Trading and all those other things are going to come.
Scott: and the people are also like, oh, yeah You'll be able to get Pokemon and bring them into your Gameboy game and I'm like, nope That's never gonna happen.
Rym: I think some of those things might happen down the road, but not all of them.
Rym: Here's my prediction.
Rym: I think Pokemon go is going to be kept like Studiosly separate from the real Pokemon games for the foreseeable future in the sense that None of the companies involved will ever let Pokemon Bago Cannibalize even one sale of a regular Pokemon game.
Rym: Mm-hmm And that is that is not on the table.
Scott: All they want to do is use Pokemon go to boost the sales of regular Pokemon and vice versa Which I think they're going to very well.
Rym: Yeah, I also think When the inevitable happens and Nintendo is no longer a hardware company Maybe maybe not like well very likely someday that'll happen.
Rym: But when there's no hardware anymore or Nintendo the other option is Nintendo might go the oculus road and start making Increasingly specialized hardware, but like we you not the greatest thing in the world Like there's a reason we don't just want to play Mario maker.
Scott: I don't play anything else.
Rym: Yeah, and remember the big game I wanted to play on?
Rym: it was actually Splatoon.
Rym: No overwatch like Splatoon is dead.
Scott: I don't I never needed to place Look, it's a real good game.
Scott: I'm sure but it's better.
Scott: I don't need I don't need that in my life.
Rym: I did need it in my life but it wasn't worth owning a Wii U to have and the fact that it's basically dead now in light of overwatch means I was correct, but Pokemon go.
Rym: if Nintendo stops being a hardware company and goes the way of Sega and Start selling like regular Pokemon games like on Steam or on other consoles or just on phones Then the great singularity will happen with Pokemon go but only then.
Rym: It's unlikely.
Scott: don't hold your breath for that one.
Rym: Yeah, exactly That is a distant future that requires a lot of different dominoes to fall over.
Scott: So since I knew exactly what it was gonna be and it turned out to be right I never even bothered to play Pokemon go.
Scott: have you played Pokemon go?
Rym: I played it but I did play ingress all the way up to level 8 to really like.
Scott: see I played it.
Scott: I don't even know what level I'd have to log in and find out.
Rym: but I got to level 8 just because that was the highest level in the game when it came out.
Rym: and then they added 8 more levels.
Rym: and There's a fact and what I noticed this is the prayer.
Rym: the most interesting thing about Pokemon go that's happening right now.
Rym: social media People who are playing the game notice How much experience you need to get past?
Rym: Some level in the in the future.
Rym: like if you play it you get to like level 14 or whatever like to get to the next Level you need a lot of experience.
Rym: They realize that it's basically an exponential curve of the amount of experience you need to continue advancing The same way.
Rym: it was like to get to level 2. you need like one experience.
Rym: fucking just did happen.
Rym: You're already level 2.
Rym: Yeah to get to like level 4 It's like alright you need like a hundred to get to level 8.
Rym: It's like you need a thousand to get a level 9.
Rym: It's like you need a billion.
Rym: All candy box games must have Exponential progression or they will fail.
Scott: if you have linear progression people just keep progressing like whoop whoop Yep, and they don't feel and then you can't really get away from anyone.
Scott: So it doesn't really feel good to be high level because everyone's high level.
Rym: Yep, because you remember there is no cost to you to level up in Pokemon go except you keep clicking.
Rym: But if you just keep poking at the game, you'll just keep leveling up.
Rym: So the only way to make that Monetizable and to make sure that levels matter in some way is to make that leveling curve be to the point that even crazy Joey Jojo Shabadoo who plays this game 24 hours a day seven days a week Eventually Peters out and hits a vertical line.
Scott: Yeah, you need to separate Joey Jojo from the non Shabadoo version right at least by one level.
Scott: So you need to have that gap there.
Rym: But also the game is competitive, but it's competitive in the same way that ingress is.
Rym: in fact It's even.
Scott: I've spent more time on the game than you and there's more people who on my team color living in this area than I mean, basically the way it works is it.
Rym: they added a few things that make it objectively way better than ingress But they took some ingress concepts and super fucking dumbed him down.
Rym: So ingress has the portals and you like have to team up with people and like collaborate to connect them together.
Rym: All that teamwork is gone.
Rym: Like teamwork doesn't mean anything in this game.
Rym: Really like the team you're on fuck it.
Rym: It doesn't matter like who cares also everyone.
Scott: art is also no green team.
Rym: Everyone smarts on the blue team Because the blue team is like we're gonna learn about stuff and the red team is like we're gonna be strong and the yellow team Is.
Rym: don't trust science.
Rym: go with your gut.
Scott: fuck you yellow team.
Rym: Yeah, the yellow team is Hufflepuff.
Scott: Fuck you yellow team so much.
Rym: I mean, I really wanted to be Team Rocket.
Rym: I feel like I could still be Team Rocket.
Rym: All I have to do
Scott: green team or Team Rocket should be the teams but they're
Rym: not all you have to do to be Team Rocket is Place a Pokemon lure at night and then hide in that place and when kids show up playing Pokemon Literally run over punch them out steal their phones steal their Pokemon.
Scott: steal the fuck.
Rym: think about it.
Rym: Team Rocket could be real.
Rym: You can literally mug a kid and steal his real Team Rocket cosplay.
Scott: come out do the thing The kids be like, yeah, and then steal their Pokemon.
Rym: Yeah, then you're like, no really kid.
Rym: Give me your.
Rym: give me your fucking Pokemon.
Rym: I'm taking that Pikachu.
Rym: No, no, give me the phone.
Rym: I'm gonna Brian gonna break your phone and kill your Pikachu.
Rym: I Feel like this has got to happen.
Rym: But anyway, so instead of all that portals stuff with the connecting together and the shields and the stuff pokestops you basically go up to them and You have to literally like click on the screen.
Scott: one seriously in a pokestop in a gym.
Rym: So a pokestop is an ingress portal.
Rym: you walk up to it and you got to go into the screen and you see the circle That shows like what the thing is that you don't care about and then you've got to spin it.
Rym: You put your thumb on it and you spin it.
Rym: Whoa, and you know what, you know how fucking non-intuitive this is.
Rym: I didn't know how to interact with them until I looked it up.
Rym: Mmm, I know at no point did I think I should spin that thing.
Rym: So you go to the pokestop and you spin it a bunch and then a bunch of bubbles appear like four or five bubbles With like individual pokeballs in them and you click on them all to get them.
Rym: Okay, which is just real real Real like.
Scott: see you basically sit there tapping to collect pokeballs.
Rym: Yeah, but you know you got to physically walk to the thing and tap it.
Rym: Okay, and then you can go to a gym and if you have a really high level Pokemon you can attack the gym.
Rym: and Then you play this really bullshitty game where you jump your Pokemon left and right and like real-time battle the guy.
Rym: but level is the only thing that actually matters and level is the CP value and CP value basically just means you spent the most time playing game.
Rym: you level up like you want to level up your riddle.
Rym: You got to catch like a million wheedles.
Rym: Grind them all into wheedle candy feed wheedle candy to your wheedle to level them up.
Rym: So there's basically no way to level up your starter because you can't find Bulbasaurs out there to get Bulbasaur candy.
Rym: So your starter is just completely useless bullshit.
Scott: You can't feed a wheedle candy.
Rym: Nope.
Rym: You gotta feed them Bulbasaur candy Because I know you all caught a Bulbasaur in your bathroom.
Scott: No, basically, really you only have one of each Pokemon, but their level is equal to pretty much the number of that Pokemon that you've caught.
Rym: Yep, so you catch like a million wheedles.
Rym: then when you're bored what about evolution, right?
Scott: So if I catch a wheedle and it becomes a you know, be drill eventually, right?
Scott: Then I catch wheedles and I can't find any be drills in the wild.
Scott: Oh every can I feed the wheedle candy to the be Drill.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: All right, that's fine.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: That's fine.
Rym: You can also catch evolved Pokemon all the original all the original 150 or whatever in the game right now You and you two and Dragonite.
Rym: and supposedly you can't get like those.
Rym: you yet zapdos.
Rym: I think it zapdos already Legendary stuff.
Rym: There's I think you can't.
Rym: I'm not sure.
Rym: like I said, I haven't really played that much.
Rym: I got like you gone.
Rym: I got like 40 Pokemon, but I got omenite.
Rym: omenite I just caught the omenite like a ConnectiCon just like I'd say these teams raise helix.
Rym: But Some Pokemon are region exclusive.
Rym: I think Tara or whatever like one of the one of those Pokemon is like Australia only or Genghis Khan.
Rym: Genghis Khan is The kangaroo.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Yeah, and mr.
Rym: Mime is the Europe exclusive the mime Only.
Rym: yeah, the best way I saw it was like Europe.
Rym: We're so sorry.
Scott: I'm not sorry.
Scott: Fuck you.
Rym: Yeah And already all our friends were like Rym.
Rym: You've got to fucking get us Pokemon.
Rym: I'll be in Australia soon.
Scott: So you can get Pokemon for people.
Scott: There's no trading.
Rym: there will be trading.
Rym: They've officially said trading will come whatever.
Rym: but yeah, the gym is basically just be Ridiculous high-level because you wasted your life and then you can play this bullshitty game.
Rym: That really only level matters to take control of the gym and then your Pokemon stays in the gym Fighting off other people until someone else beats it.
Scott: So when your Pokemon is in the gym, can you use it say at another gym?
Scott: It's just stuck there It's just stuck there.
Scott: What happens if it gets beat?
Rym: it comes back to you I think I guess dead and then you gotta like revive it and then you can use it again.
Scott: Is it at the level it was or does it lose all its levels?
Rym: I think it stays at the level it was at but the gyms Suck.
Rym: like I I decided like this game I will play it because it is actually really fun.
Rym: The third piece of the game is the air part where you're walking down the street and it buzzes.
Rym: You're like, oh shit There's Pokemon and you pull your phone out and you look at your camera and then you find it and it's in a physical place Like a specific physical place and you see it on your screen overlaid over the real world and it like pegs.
Scott: Then you take a funny screenshot and tweet it.
Rym: Yep, because it yeah, you know how many Pokemon I have on people's dicks.
Scott: I'm enjoying the tweets without having to play the game.
Scott: I'm getting the full benefit without having to waste my life.
Rym: that part of the game is Super fun because like I was walking down the street the other day and my phone buzzes and I look I see a Pidgeotto and I'm like, ooh And I tried to catch it, but it kept flying away from me.
Rym: So I like fucking come back here and I'm like chasing this Pidgeotto.
Rym: I threw like 20 pokeballs at it before I got it.
Rym: Hmm, but that's the only part of the game.
Rym: That's fun.
Rym: So I am literally not going to try to level up Never gonna interact with the gyms because they're stupid and also the gym near my office.
Scott: He's gonna try to get funny screenshots.
Rym: If you live somewhere still like somewhere like Hicksville Like the local gym has like a CP 30 like you can just go put your Magikarp in there and you're good to go.
Rym: but in Manhattan The gym next to me changes hands like a hundred times a day.
Rym: Lie and add that the people who are attacking it are so high level that I don't even know how that happens.
Scott: They're not doing anything else with their lives.
Scott: They're not podcasting.
Scott: Yeah, I just play Pokemon.
Scott: go play it and while they're work play it on the subway play it on the way home.
Scott: Play play play play play.
Rym: So I guess don't get me wrong.
Rym: The game is fun, but it is Like the minimum effort.
Scott: it is the mindless candy box.
Rym: We thought it would be yep And the AR part is fun.
Rym: None of the other parts of it are fun.
Rym: If you think you're gonna play it at all It's probably worth it to play it now and put in the minimum effort Because this kind of game the other thing that's likely to happen strike
Scott: while the irons hot
Rym: When they add more stuff to make the game better You don't want to decide to start the game then because then you're that dude who's playing World of Warcraft Doing the beginning like terrible contents while everyone else is playing the new awesome thing that came out.
Scott: You're that dude who tries to start playing netrunner and everyone else's already has all these cards or playing You know Magic the Gathering and everyone else already has all these cards.
Rym: So and also usually these kinds of games There'll be ways to level up now to power level that will probably disappear in the future.
Scott: You show up at the Warhammer meetup and you got your brand new little tiny piece of Space Marine.
Scott: But everyone else and a man everyone longer than you are Already has a giant painted army and you got your little squad.
Rym: But the AR part is super fun.
Rym: So I do recommend it to play that part because the thing I say I'm saying that's amazing is Like.
Rym: so when we came home from Connecticut was like right after the game went live.
Rym: I got to the subway station in Long Island City pretty late at night like 11 o'clock and I come out of the subway station.
Rym: You know Queens Plaza like way over in the middle of nowhere and I'm walking back through that park.
Rym: There's a little park under the subway tracks.
Rym: That's empty like hobos live there.
Rym: Like there's never anyone there.
Rym: at night It was crowded.
Rym: there were like 40 people milling around and every one of them had Pokemon out.
Scott: There are a lot of people playing this game.
Scott: like no question.
Scott: I see.
Scott: I see this game being played on the street pretty much everywhere.
Rym: Yeah, like there's a giant crowd of people the funniest thing in the world.
Rym: There's a big crowd of people in City Hall Park and every day they're there like huge amounts of people.
Rym: They're all playing the game.
Rym: There's this one dude and he's there like multiple times a week when I'm out at lunch and he's like He's basically trying to be an evangelist for ingress to the Pokemon kids like oh kid I see you're playing Pokemon.
Rym: You want to play the real game the Pokemon is based on.
Rym: the kids are like, dude No that game sucks.
Scott: But why doesn't he just start playing Pokemon?
Rym: because he's real mad.
Rym: all the ingress people seem real mad that everyone's playing Pokemon.
Scott: because What is?
Scott: it is shut ingress down?
Scott: What's the point?
Rym: because the people who played are obsessed with it?
Scott: There's not that many people playing it.
Rym: There's a decent number of people playing it.
Scott: Money on it just cost money to run.
Scott: just shut it down.
Rym: Remember Pokemon also has microtransactions.
Rym: It's monetized.
Scott: Well, what can you buy?
Rym: you can buy in-game money that can be used to buy like pokeballs and upgrades and shit.
Scott: So basically spend money and you don't have to spin the hoop.
Scott: Yep So they see instead of spinning the hoop at the focus top You can just pay money and get pokeballs.
Rym: So all the people who said when Nintendo finally does mobile They'll do mobile right and mobile different.
Rym: No, they're doing mobile the same.
Rym: It's same mobile just with a Pokemon skin.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: But that's the thing that's interesting there with the ingress stuff is that ingress existed.
Rym: it was the beta test for Pokemon.
Rym: Pokemon comes out and now you have something that's never happened before.
Rym: there's two augmented reality games Which are overlays on the real world, right?
Rym: They use the same data.
Rym: So every pokestop is an ingress portal.
Rym: Okay, meaning the two games clash with each other in the real world.
Rym: It'd be like if you made a an MMO and then someone else made a different MMO But somehow like characters from the two MMOs could see each other because they're set in the same world of like a while or whatever.
Rym: Like.
Rym: that's the kind of thing that no one who designed video games ever had to worry about before.
Rym: but because the substrate for AR Games is reality if you decide to put a thing in your AR game in the real world It effectively conflicts with any other AR game that has the thing in that same place also conflicts with real life.
Rym: Yes, and No one's answered all those questions yet.
Rym: So just like when mobas started appearing or MMOs started appearing or video games started appearing Although there's a whole bunch of new questions No one's ever had to ask before and suddenly a whole bunch of people on Twitter are giving really bad answers to those questions.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brand ok for the logos be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.
Rym: The patrons for this episode of GeekNights now that we're finally back and mostly on sick in order of the amount of money They gave us on a continuing basis are Alan Joyce Rebecca Dunn Nicholas Brandau Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette James David White Christian coops construction noises mystady.com Sean Hayworth William Isen rose Jeremy Meyer Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn Brian Fisher sailor Vista Devin Goodman couldn't think of a funny name.
Rym: Iggy kid Matthew Smith char tavish and Joshua Joe star Tyler eller John Schleich Sean Yeager Clinton Walton run from New Zealand Ryan parent or open ladder rare Laval Brian Cedroni Rochelle, Montanota Finn Eric silver on Chris Reimer and Thomas on Aaron's Reese Chris midkiff Chris Knox You thought this was going to be Thomas Hahn, but it was me do.
Rym: Sam Cordery Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: We're finally on sick.
Rym: We were gonna record a Q&A and catch up on those today, but Scott was still coughing too much.
Rym: So we just ended the show when we ended it, but I think he'll be not coughing by next week.
Rym: We're gonna probably do the Q&A from the politics one on Thursday and all that content We've backed up is gonna start flooding out into your faces over the next few weeks.
Rym: And now I leave you with something strange look.
Rym: there's mr.
Rym: Bladder in the basement.
Rym: Now food comes in through the chimney mouth and goes from room to room Greeting the different organs.
Rym: Hello Now the good healthy food is very nice and polite to the organs and so is invited to stay for a party.
Rym: Yay, but the bad not healthy foods are very rude and must leave through the cat flap.
Rym: What's that?
Rym: a tasty snack.
Rym: you don't want to go and eat a snack like that Greedy.
Rym: to eat all that you'll end up with your gums all gray Exactly, how do we know?