Rym: It's Monday January 11th 2016.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: nuclear vessels Not to get into the details because it's more of a metamoment thing, but we got a lot of conventions coming up.
Scott: I know one convention per month for January February March April.
Rym: Yeah, and I've got more.
Rym: and south Yeah, egg fest egg fest.
Rym: then We've got a Zenkai con Pax East anime Boston, I forgot about Zenkai con.
Scott: Yeah, maybe five conventions.
Rym: Well, you said you might skip at a Zenkai con.
Scott: So I technically skipped a lot of Zenkai cons.
Scott: Why not skip some more?
Rym: I did tactically put in panels that I could do on my own.
Rym: Mm-hmm cuz I'm and also I'm only going Saturday and Sunday I'm not going Friday.
Rym: Mmm.
Rym: I'm praying to head out like Friday night like after work in the Amtrak cuz Bolt buses don't go to Lancaster.
Rym: No one goes and there is an Amtrak station actually near the convention center.
Scott: It's just down the street.
Scott: It's a straight shot.
Rym: So I could live with that.
Scott: I could live with that as long as it's not too cold.
Rym: So I bitch a lot on the show about how there's no phone for me And you know, I want to buy the experience.
Rym: the Sony Xperia z5 compact is probably the best cell phone hardware In the world.
Rym: if you want to run Android, it's waterproof like everything about.
Scott: does it run the newest Android without any bullshit?
Scott: 6.0.
Scott: Also, it's Sony.
Rym: Yeah, it's 6.0 troubling with some Sony bullshit in it, right?
Scott: A lot you don't trust Lenovo.
Scott: you're gonna trust Sony who is the first to put like, you know Evil spyware DRM on us on an audio CD.
Scott: You know what?
Rym: I do trust Sony more than I trust Lenovo.
Rym: Sony's malware is at least well constructed.
Scott: So yeah, Sony actually has like the best cameras right now.
Rym: Yeah, that's the problem.
Rym: So he has really good heart.
Rym: if Sony could be split into a hardware company and a bullshit company I feel like Sony do real well.
Scott: Yeah, just sell your hardware with no software on it whatsoever.
Scott: people will take the Sony a7s camera and it'll just run Android instead of Whatever that garbage it runs.
Rym: now, you don't understand how good that z5 compact is.
Rym: is a phone like it's so good?
Scott: Could it be?
Scott: it's also tiny Better than iPhone 5.
Rym: I say well the thing is I gets hard to compare Apples to androids because the OS like the experience is so different.
Rym: So in terms of hardware though I think it's better than the iPhone 5 better than the iPod mini the iPod nano.
Rym: That might actually be too small for a phone right now.
Rym: Well, I could have a separate screen like on my wrist like a big screen.
Scott: What's the problem?
Rym: that I could not play nourishing my hacks on a like 40 by 40 screen.
Scott: That's fine.
Rym: Anyway, and there's a rumor that's pretty substantiated that there's gonna be Another.
Rym: there's gonna be a third pillar of the iPhone land.
Rym: There's gonna be the iPhone C class devices.
Scott: Well, they already have that.
Rym: they had an iPhone 5c and then they got rid of it.
Scott: I think you can.
Scott: Can you still get it?
Rym: It's not they're not making them anymore.
Rym: And let me check the Apple store.
Rym: It was widely considered to be a failure.
Scott: Oh, we have a lot of them at work and a lot of my co-workers bought him and loved them.
Rym: Oh, yeah, so some of them still use them widely considered to be a failure, but Apparently they have a deep fandom among people who wanted a smaller phone.
Scott: so right now the iPhones you can get that are currently in production are the six six s and Five s which is just an iPhone 5 pretty much which is slightly better I guess.
Rym: so the the iPhone 6c or it might be a 7c.
Rym: We're not sure.
Scott: This is the year of iPhone 7.
Scott: So it's September.
Scott: They're gonna announce the iPhone 7.
Scott: I'll get it.
Rym: So the rumor is unless April or May they might announce the 6c.
Scott: That's a big deal.
Scott: and it makes this rumor less credible because the iPhones have been on a September schedule for years yes,
Rym: and the rumor is that the C devices are gonna be on their own separate schedule and Partly because of lackluster iPhone sales from the previous they
Scott: did decrease orders on iPhones to you know the manufacturers in China recently because basically we're at a point where everyone's just fucking got a phone and the phones are lasting longer.
Rym: if you've got like an iPhone 6s a lot of people have no reason to get the 7 when it comes out, right?
Scott: It's like well, I mean if you have iPhone 5 like you're still fucking good today And iPhone 5s iPhone 4 is even good today.
Scott: So it's okay.
Scott: people are good with phones for now Like they're not buying iPhone 6s and 6s is at the rate that they expected.
Scott: So like they got workers who are just like at home not working over in China not making iPhones because Apple's like we don't need Anymore only order this many and androids the same way.
Rym: I mean I'm using a Nexus 5 and you know what.
Rym: there is no better Android phone Like.
Rym: sure you could get a 5x But there is nothing better in the 5x as far as any user of a phone except Conrad would care about.
Rym: so The rumor is that they're gonna release this iPhone 6 ish hardware in a size.
Rym: the rumor ranges from iPod touch.
Rym: That's the perfect touch.
Scott: We have an iPod touch at work the newest one.
Scott: Yeah, it's incredible.
Scott: Yeah, so good.
Scott: So the size the shape the thin everything about it is a mirror is a miracle.
Rym: There's a credible rumor that it's gonna be that size.
Rym: give or take a millimeter.
Scott: I'll pay for that.
Scott: Okay, I'll pay more for the smaller one.
Rym: so the biggest that it would be appears to be an iPhone 4.
Scott: that's iPhone 4 was the perfect size.
Scott: iPhone 5 had a better screen.
Scott: It was a better device But compared to the iPhone 4 it was thinner, which is good.
Scott: The thinness is better, but it was it was too long.
Rym: Look at that comparison, that's the phone.
Scott: The iPhone 5 was too long.
Scott: the iPhone, you know It was like.
Scott: I want the iPhone 5 but just not as long as the iPhone 5.
Scott: I'm gonna be iPhone 4 height, but with all the stuff that was in the iPhone 5 only probably faster nowadays.
Scott: Yeah, that's also.
Rym: it looks like they're gonna ditch the plastic cuz they made him kind of like colorful.
Scott: I like the color of a plastic.
Rym: They're gonna have the same metal as every other iPhone.
Scott: I want colors though.
Rym: Yeah, well, they'll have the green color.
Rym: green me.
Rym: They probably won't have rose gold.
Rym: They'll probably keep that there.
Scott: I don't wanna bullshit rose gold.
Scott: I always get the boring gray one, but that's cuz there's no green.
Rym: Yeah, if there was a there was like a metal green.
Rym: green me up Scott the Xperia's have a green option.
Scott: big deal.
Scott: Hey, it doesn't help but everything behind the green is garbage.
Rym: He is the only reason I didn't get a z5c now because you can get a gray market one in the US even though it's not released in the US and confirmed Android 6.
Rym: The only reason I didn't get one is that because it's the international edition.
Rym: It's missing two or three LTE channels Which wouldn't matter that much?
Rym: Except most of the new coverage that t-mobile and other people are putting out is in those bands in the u.s.
Scott: Well, you can't be using t-mobile now that the CEO is like EFF.
Scott: Who the fuck is that?
Rym: Yeah, so we'll see what I do with phones.
Rym: You can read these rumors.
Rym: the iPhone 6c will probably come out ahead of the iPhone 7 to get a sales bump Because then they expect that a bunch of people will buy that who will otherwise wouldn't have upgraded during the seven cycle Because there's a bigger demand for a small phone than people realize.
Scott: I can't do anything until the iPhone 7 comes out in September October.
Rym: I the rumors also that it's gonna be cheaper like a lot cheaper, but not cheap.
Scott: Well, it doesn't matter Talking like 400 ish bucks That's a good deal, which is still like especially now since the subsidies and contracts are all gone now in the US.
Scott: Goodbye I mean, but I think that's also what's hurting new iPhone sales.
Scott: Is that?
Scott: is that as people need to buy iPhones now and they're like, oh $800 fuck that.
Rym: Yeah, I think what also is hurting?
Rym: that honestly the hardware on phones is good enough for 99.9% of what anyone does with them.
Rym: The only limiting factor that anyone gives a shit about is either the size or the battery life.
Rym: Yep Except for old people.
Scott: I don't know why people have such problems with battery life.
Scott: fucking charge your phone I mean, I've never had my phone die out.
Scott: I've had to come close at conventions But I always make it to the hotel room with like 5% and then I plug it in and go to bed.
Scott: I wake up.
Rym: It's 100 or if I'm really like not sure I'm gonna make it.
Rym: I do have in my bag that tiny battery.
Scott: Yeah, I only have to use that at conventions where I wake up way early and get back to the room at like 2 a.m.
Scott: So that's how long my phone battery lasts.
Scott: How could you possibly run out your battery?
Scott: What the hell are you watching movies on?
Scott: Are you watching Netflix?
Scott: that are like all day while you're at this?
Scott: Apparently to watch a lot of Netflix to kill that battery.
Rym: So, uh as much as I would like to stay on Android there is literally no Android phone to buy at all.
Rym: Like they're all garbage.
Rym: They're all giant pieces of garbage.
Scott: I hope you didn't spend a lot of money on Android apps cuz I spent a lot of my own iPhone app So I can't leave.
Rym: I spent about.
Rym: I'll lose all that.
Rym: I've spent about 40 bucks on Android apps so I'll probably lose about 40 bucks worth.
Rym: but As much as I know I'm gonna bitch about Andrew our iPhones OS and interface for a while just because it'll be different is nothing to bitch about.
Rym: Yeah, but I'm used to Android and I like Android.
Scott: but the Android ship sailed.
Scott: there aren't any good Android phone.
Rym: So if a small iPhone comes out, like I'll just jump ship without even looking back.
Rym: I'll put up with.
Rym: even if I hate the main complaint people have with iPhone They can't get rid of some of those icons.
Scott: He's hide him in a folder.
Scott: big fucking deal, right?
Scott: And then the other thing people come in.
Scott: I was like, how do you do this, right?
Scott: A lot of my co-workers like how do you do this?
Scott: I just want to.
Scott: I just don't have files.
Scott: It's like well dude my coworker today.
Rym: Oh, he like he uses a. he has an Android phone.
Rym: He's like, how do I get to the file Explorer on my phone?
Rym: I was like plug it into your computer.
Rym: and he was like no, but I want it on the phone.
Scott: and I was like Yeah, why it's like.
Scott: you just have to accept the fact that you're gonna do the same thing.
Scott: You can still do everything that you do by with your file Explorer finder, whatever.
Scott: You just got to do it differently, right?
Scott: For example, I got a movie and I want to watch it on my phone.
Scott: Right, so you could use iTunes.
Scott: people hate iTunes for no reason.
Scott: that I understand always works for me But everything works for me.
Scott: Apparently, I don't like iTunes something.
Rym: I have no use for I write.
Scott: But another thing you can do is you can get the VLC app for your iPhone or iPad.
Scott: You can then access your video files in like 20 different ways.
Rym: Scott I realize that most people like even relatively young people never heard of VLC.
Scott: Okay, you can get the Amazon.
Rym: look at all of our unnamed friends.
Rym: maybe icons who use like ghetto virus player, right?
Scott: And maybe it's.
Scott: maybe it's music you want to get on to there with your drag-and-drop.
Scott: well Just drag all your music into Amazon music player into the cloud and then install the Amazon music app and up Look, there's all your music.
Scott: same with the Amazon Kindle app, which is free.
Scott: Also, you can just drag PDFs and shit onto the internet in the cloud from your computer and then open up the app on Your phone and there they are.
Scott: So you don't need any file Explorer nonsense.
Rym: So anyway, I'm probably gonna jump ship if this comes out Like.
Rym: I'm just gonna pre-order day one like immediately and never look back.
Scott: Oh cuz you're like.
Scott: that's right cuz you're not on this two-year cycle that I'm on.
Scott: You're just like whatever there's a phone you can do because I I'm at the end of my cycle.
Rym: I'm at the point of I would upgrade my Android phone.
Rym: I'm on and there is literally no phone in the world that is better enough.
Rym: They make such.
Scott: I made such a good move by that iPhone 3g on day one waited in line for like a half hour.
Rym: Also, yeah, yeah, so I think Scott has some Apple iPhone news - well, this is news.
Scott: We've discussed this before because this is not the first time for this rumor But the rumors coming back so hard and strong this time that I feel like, you know It definitely has all the hallmarks of being even more true than the rumor you just had Yeah, which is that they're really gonna get rid of the headphone port on that iPhone and perhaps other I devices.
Scott: I would be moderately annoyed because the TRS the TRS and then they're just gonna make you either a use bluetooth headphones or B which a lot of people already do.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: or B Plug headphones that go into the lightning cable or get an adapter that goes from lightning to headphones.
Rym: So in my experience most bluetooth headphones, the sound quality is good But it's actually noticeably not as good as my like sure or etymotic TRS just regular.
Scott: I had bluetooth headphones at work.
Scott: I still have them.
Scott: They were really good.
Rym: The problem is they were cheap and the little head thing snapped and they won't stay on my ears Actually, so interestingly for the 5c or the 6c not the 5c 6c 7c the rumors Specifically show that they still have TRS.
Rym: Okay, cuz they're not thin.
Scott: Yeah The reason they're getting rid of is because it's like it's the thickest thing in there.
Rym: So get rid of the 5c that and the 5c that.
Scott: the headphone jack and the camera are pretty much the only things keeping them From making the phone like a lot smaller, but they can't make the phone that thin if they also make it small in the other dimensions.
Rym: So the 6c has to be fatter.
Rym: so there's no benefit to getting rid of TR.
Scott: This is why lightning is such a tiny thin connector, right?
Scott: It's anyway, but yeah I mean the thing is lightning.
Scott: as far as I know and I could be wrong the old dock connector You're the big wide one that was on iPods Yeah But they used for like the early iPhones the 3g and whatnot That dock connector had a ton of pins on it and some of those pins had analog audio output.
Scott: So you could actually get a really simple connector that would go into the dock connector and then headphones or cassette tape.
Scott: That's in your car or you know, all kinds of stuff.
Scott: and I had this right?
Scott: It was really simple cuz like the you know It had in there somewhere with some of those pins are for charging.
Scott: some of them were for firewires.
Rym: I remember I had a device that I basically plug cuz.
Rym: I had my iPod nano and it had a TRS in the bottom Yeah, and I plugged a device into that that Re-broadcasted my audio over local FM.
Scott: So I had one of those two.
Scott: But anyway, the lightning connector as far as I know is a hundred percent digital Which means if you want to get a headphone adapter that goes into the lightning hole that that has to have a digital to analog converter Right.
Scott: So the thing that you're gonna shove into the bottom of your iPhone to then put your headphones into is probably gonna Cost a lot of money if I know Apple 30 bucks or 50 bucks.
Rym: Yeah, which we talked about this on the episode I'm not gonna get into.
Scott: like YTR They already have a connector that goes from that to HDMI and I have that connector and it's like 50 bucks.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I suspect There's gonna be a lot of people complaining about this on the internet and freaking out but the reality is no one's gonna actually care.
Rym: No who had who uses iPhones?
Rym: No, no one's gonna not buy the next iPhone because of this.
Scott: And I think someone someone is You know that really obstinate person.
Rym: I don't know if that person yeah that person has never actually owned an iPhone.
Rym: That person is running GNU Linux in their basement on their desktop there.
Rym: No, they got Amiga.
Scott: Mmm, I did the what the only it's not.
Scott: it's fine if we get rid of this old connector, right?
Scott: It's not the you know, we can.
Scott: we have.
Scott: Bluetooth is fine.
Scott: It's also an open standard, right?
Scott: Lightning is sort of open ish, right?
Scott: even though no one else uses it but Apple.
Scott: but the problem is if you go to the store and Suddenly this, you know, you could buy any headphone in the store right now It would really suck if you went to the store.
Scott: It's like no you got to buy the right Headphone.
Scott: you can't just buy any headphone.
Scott: You got to buy the right one and you bought the wrong ones.
Scott: They don't work, you know, we need to make sure that every device in the whole earth You know from this point forward uses the same thing, right?
Rym: You don't have it because everything's gonna be you the USB right?
Scott: It's now we've done this plenty of times right USB then newer USB except, you know There's gonna be piece from.
Scott: you know, there's gonna be people who have our Side to HDMI.
Scott: We didn't have a problem.
Rym: A lot of people had problems along the way and we just let them perish.
Scott: Yeah, it's not really the biggest deal As the other thing is we can't once we pick something right?
Scott: We can't be changing it as frequently as we change USB.
Scott: We got to be changing it like once in a blue moon because you don't want to be buying headphones and then suddenly I buy Lightning headphones and then five years from now apples like yeah, no more lightning.
Scott: It's like fuck you.
Rym: Well, I remember I had you know, my old iPod was like you can get iPods used to use firewire Mm-hmm, and then I had a firewire port and I would use it.
Rym: and then I got a new iPod and it just didn't work With firewire anymore.
Scott: Yeah that USB only yeah.
Rym: So I have an anecdote that's relevant to that in terms of people Misunderstanding those things.
Rym: after we ran our freshman year in college at RIT.
Rym: So this is like 2001. we all went back home and I was back at home You know in Michigan hanging out and a lot of my high school friends were around.
Rym: I went to a party and they wanted to watch a movie and then they say how Rym You should help us set up the home stereo theater, whatever.
Scott: Oh, that's good.
Scott: They actually asked the person who knows best because a lot of times I go somewhere and it's like I see the TV.
Scott: It's clearly not in HD Even though it's in the HDTV.
Scott: I see that they're not using HDMI and it has nothing to do with me But they're like no one wants to hear my advice.
Rym: You're going to computer school.
Rym: So you know how to do this.
Scott: You do know how to do it.
Rym: Yeah, so I go back behind their TV and what I see is RCA cables plugged into component.
Rym: All right on the DVD player and plugged into the RCA inputs on The TV.
Rym: so that wasn't working clearly but there was also and as video cable plugged into the DVD player and That was plugged into the TV.
Rym: and their complaint was that the HD whatever has always worked fine.
Rym: But the sound never works unless video is video only.
Scott: So as video is video only.
Rym: so the fact that you could plug the same cable into an RC.
Rym: You know RCA connectors were used for both component and the old RCA analog stuff.
Rym: People just plug cables randomly into all that.
Scott: That's a mistake of the design of component cables actually was that they were the same.
Rym: You know big stick in the middle ring around the edge cables, yeah, I feel like I should have made them a slightly different size.
Scott: You know modern cable design.
Scott: they make sure that you know cables can only go in the right way.
Scott: You know, you can't possibly put them into something.
Scott: That's not where they belong.
Rym: Yeah, you can't.
Rym: if they're directional they make them a shape so that they only go in in the early days of building computers Like you plug a cable in the wrong way.
Rym: Everything's fried forever.
Scott: Yeah, now if you open up your computer, it's not possible to put something in the wrong spot.
Scott: It just won't fit.
Rym: Yep, I mean you'd be like a hard drive into the wrong half of a parallel cable.
Scott: It just wouldn't work and you wouldn't know why like I used to get IDE ribbon cables that didn't have that little notch in The middle.
Scott: Oh, and you'd have to know looking at the red stripe on the ribbon Which direction it went in.
Rym: on the mother the red stripe we had to be closest to the power on the drive.
Scott: I would look at the motherboard instruction manual to see the numbers on the pin out.
Scott: So I would put it towards the zero.
Rym: and but the worst one.
Scott: now you have an SATA cable.
Scott: You can't fuck it up unless you can't even if you can fuck you fuck up an SATA cable putting it the wrong place Or the wrong whatever.
Scott: you can't even build a Lego set.
Scott: You're so dumb, right?
Scott: Like a baby Lego like Duplo.
Rym: So I got one last little news here.
Rym: This is kind of fun.
Rym: I'm gonna read the anecdote from slash jock cuz.
Rym: it's just kind of funny.
Rym: An anonymous reader writes Nvidia GPUs don't clear out memory that was previously allocated and neither does Chrome.
Rym: When a user recently fired up Diablo 3 several hours after closing an incognito mode window that contained pornography The game launched with snapshots of that last private browsing session appearing on the screen.
Rym: So what I'm gonna actually link to instead of the slash dot.
Rym: I like how they're very open.
Rym: They're like, yeah, I was looking at porn and then I saw my porn in Diablo when I launched it.
Scott: Well, this is really interesting.
Scott: So what happens is when your computer is drawing to the screen, right?
Scott: There's a space in them in the video memory called the frame buffer and what it's doing is drawing literally your screen.
Scott: So let's say your screen is 800 by 600, which is a really old computer.
Scott: You've got basically like an array and each pixel on the screen is 32-bit color or 24-bit color.
Scott: So you have 24 bits times 800 times 600 that many bits in a space.
Scott: and the computer has to draw the screen.
Scott: so what it does is it arranges those bits.
Scott: it says aha the top left pixel is Pure green.
Scott: so in those, you know, 24 bits it puts zero zero FF zero zero All right, and there's your bits.
Scott: and then it says what's the next pixel?
Scott: and it does this ridiculously fast.
Scott: It does this so fast that it can draw all the pixels on the screen at 75 frames a second.
Scott: usually you're 60 or whatever your frame rate is, right?
Scott: Yeah So is a space in the memory where it fills up.
Scott: it writes down in memory what color every pixel is and then the video.
Scott: You know hardware Sends turns that space and memory into a signal that it sends to your monitor and the monitor takes that and draws the pixels On the screen and it keeps doing this over and over again.
Scott: Usually you'll do like double buffering or triple where you'll have like multiple buffers and it'll be drawing multiple screens at once Or it'll be just draw a screen and while that one's being displayed It starts drawing the next screen and then once it finishes drawing that screen and it starts being displayed It starts using the previous memory space and over and over.
Rym: Yeah Now it's a good security practice.
Rym: Applications or operating systems should theoretically wipe out or make an accessible memory that has been released by Theoretically.
Scott: if you could access someone's frame buffers or if the computer is storing up old frames and not using the same as X space in Memory, you could see what the person did on that computer going into the past regardless of what they were doing.
Scott: If you can access the video cards memory, you can access basically screenshots.
Rym: So this guy so however far horn guy he was like, huh?
Rym: I wonder if I can just get shit out of the frame buffer.
Rym: This is a big security hole.
Rym: Let me play around in the intro.
Rym: I'm quoting him, right?
Scott: So here's the thing is that the chrome and most modern browsers does not clear memory for you.
Scott: They're using the GPU to render right your browser, you know image, right?
Scott: So and your computer is generally using the GPU to render everything these days even 2d stuff.
Scott: So now the GPU is storing up all these things right with you know in its in its video ran.
Rym: So this guy wrote an application and you just across users just on the PC period.
Rym: no security at all.
Rym: That would scan GPU memory because you can just read it all apparently.
Scott: Yeah You know, I mean you can write a program and see that just tell sends commands to the GPU and it'll do so.
Rym: We wrote a program that just look for non zero pixels Get grabbed everything it could get and then did some algorithms to rearrange because it would get like Corners and parts of images.
Rym: and he recreated all these reddit pages.
Rym: He'd been reading previously pixel perfect and Yeah, you can just totally spy on people many hours after they looked at their porn just by scanning.
Scott: The real question is there's a bug in Diablo.
Scott: Why did Diablo upon and he's surrender some Diablo like crash.
Rym: He said it was just like Diablo freakishly crashed, you know video game.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Scott: So it wasn't.
Scott: it wasn't like a bug in Diablo.
Rym: He started Diablo cuz that'd be weird if it's normally was porn and then it crashed.
Scott: Normally when a video game loads, you know, it says loading for a long time.
Scott: Usually what it's doing is copying all of its textures from this the hard drive into the video memory And then when it starts rendering that allows the video card to quickly apply those textures To all the surfaces and whatever it is.
Scott: It needs to render.
Rym: So if you can replace crash, right?
Rym: So if is he goes to join me calm, right?
Scott: So if a picture, you know If his porn site was in that Space and memory it would get applied to something like as if it was a texture and be rendered.
Rym: Oh my god, he didn't.
Rym: he censored out the image, but he didn't censor out.
Rym: So he was looking at redhead teen Mary McCray fingered in the hallway.
Rym: All right, awesome.
Scott: That sounds hot.
Rym: So, yeah I guess if you look at things whatever they might be in your incognito windows and you share that computer with people or Anyone has malware cuz you know malware has probably been doing this for years.
Scott: It probably hasn't but I think it might start now cuz someone who writes malware will see this.
Rym: Yeah at the same time if I was gonna write malware and I was trying to steal passwords Oh, they're not gonna steal password.
Scott: some screenshots cuz you can't see him.
Rym: Yeah, but you could probably steal credit card numbers Mm-hmm.
Rym: Yeah anyway.
Rym: But anyway things of the day.
Rym: this blog.
Rym: I follow it because it's just about like war and peacekeeping and just sort of an interesting Look at that world from a hobbyist perspective.
Scott: Haha obvious of war.
Rym: Yeah, it is.
Rym: It's like if you're if you know about war and war nerds and stuff.
Rym: It's just a cool blog But basically and it's got irrelevant.
Scott: What we're not a good kind of nerd to be.
Rym: we did an episode in 2007 Scott that we just called weapons needed ideas.
Scott: We still need ideas.
Rym: 2007 running out of ideas sentiment and this is an article about a gentleman who?
Rym: Basically worked for the.
Rym: he had a. he had a gun shop in Manhattan But it didn't sell.
Rym: good.
Scott: You could still have a gun shop.
Rym: I know it didn't sell guns.
Rym: It sold custom holsters for concealed guns to hide them.
Scott: I guess that's like all the bong shops We have.
Scott: you can't sell.
Scott: we be you can sell bones.
Rym: But actually that was a front for the CIA and the FBI and in the back of the office He just fucking made crazy one-off custom guns for spies.
Scott: I'm sure you could tell by going to a shop like that I mean the stuff the place that sells bongs.
Scott: you can get weed there.
Scott: Yeah Everybody knows.
Scott: I actually don't know the place that sells gun holsters.
Scott: You can get guns there.
Rym: I don't know if I could get weed at the place downstairs because you see you know that bodega by us.
Rym: They the whole front of the building is nothing but bongs.
Scott: I'm sure you can get weed.
Rym: I don't know if I walk in there like hey, you can at least get weirdo tobacco to put in a hooker Yeah, but I don't know if I went to them and I was like, hey, can I buy weed from you?
Rym: if they'd be like Yes, how many weeds would?
Scott: well you they might discriminate against you being a white dude thinking you're a cop, right?
Scott: I might be the only reason they say no.
Rym: Yeah, but I'm also kind of a nerd hipster, dude.
Rym: So maybe that I mean no cop looks like me.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So, uh, yeah They talk about because a lot of this got declassified.
Rym: now the kinds of crazy weapons this dude made Because all this stuff was very recently declassified and a lot of what he did apparently is still classified.
Rym: But I think my favorite one and they made a lot of these is a 12 shot clipboard.
Rym: so Specifically for someone who's negotiating with a terrorist hostage taker to sit down with them to go over their demands and then Kill everyone in the room.
Rym: I Guess except the hostages.
Rym: Okay, I learned about.
Rym: so check this out.
Rym: This is a sight, you know guns have different kinds of sights apparently spies.
Rym: We're like we generally don't shoot people far away.
Rym: We need pistols that are good for like killing people in the room with us like pretty close range.
Rym: So they have this custom kind of sight that's designed for like quick hip shots Like whip a gun out and shoot someone like gangsters doing old movies and the whole gun is covered in teflon.
Rym: So you can draw it quickly and without a drop.
Scott: drop it quickly Yeah, well snag on anything just fall on the ground because you can't hold on to it might as well cover it in Greece.
Rym: woman Have you got any race?
Scott: Yes Okay, so I kick-started something a while ago Because it was nine dollars.
Scott: It was one of those tiny computers.
Scott: Now.
Scott: We got plenty of tiny computers.
Scott: You got the Arduinos of the world.
Scott: There's a Microsoft one.
Scott: This is Texas Instruments one, right?
Scott: There's the Raspberry Pi which is mad popular these days.
Rym: It's the kind of things that ideally reason I don't kick-start all these things that I never have a good reason to use them.
Scott: I don't have a good reason to use it either.
Scott: but this one is nine bucks.
Scott: So I'm like whatever who gives a shit right nine bucks.
Scott: I get a tiny computer.
Scott: I don't care, you know, it might be useful.
Scott: It's really tiny.
Scott: It's only nine dollars.
Scott: I won't miss the nine dollars if this computer sits in my you know with my Arduinos and whatnot.
Scott: No biggie what.
Scott: and I forgot about it.
Scott: cuz well, you know, I kick.
Scott: sometimes you kick-start something You just don't forget remember it and then one day it shows up.
Scott: so I opened it and this is the chip computer C dot H dot I dot P and I checked it out cuz I had it now for nine bucks.
Scott: And then I realized what the hell it was.
Scott: and oh my god Let me tell you a story.
Scott: So I used to work in college at this place and I was programming for you know This board.
Scott: it was a single board computer with an Intel x scale CPU And it had like 16 megabytes of storage or something like.
Scott: it was really really weak.
Scott: It was kind of big cuz.
Scott: he had a lot of serial ports and input outputs and things like that.
Scott: But it was really really weak and tiny and didn't have much storage at all.
Scott: And I had to program for this thing and one of them cost like 500 bucks.
Scott: This thing cost nine dollars.
Scott: It's really tiny.
Scott: the bottom of it has a plastic thing so you can just rest it on your desk.
Scott: No problem, it gets power from micro USB.
Scott: It has one actual USB port for plugging in a mouse keyboard whatevs.
Scott: It has a TRS connector, but is?
Scott: the TR is audio But then the second R is video so you can plug it into the RCA on a TV or whatever to see what you know.
Scott: the display It has a whole bunch of pins on the top just like an Arduino does for you know.
Scott: Controlling electronic devices or an LED readout or analog inputs and all that kind of stuff.
Scott: power you know.
Scott: But the specs on this thing for nine dollars for this ridiculously tiny computer.
Scott: The CPU is a 1 gigahertz CPU which is guess that can get stuff done as long as it's not games.
Scott: Yeah, I mean my CPU is only 2.6 ish 512 megabytes of RAM a Four gigabyte SSD just like built into this little book.
Scott: yeah, and it has Wi-Fi and Bluetooth.
Scott: the Wi-Fi is GN.
Scott: The Bluetooth is 4.0.
Scott: You can use it and it runs Debbie, and it's already runs Debbie and as soon as you get it.
Scott: That's ridiculous.
Scott: You can do it like more than the Raspberry Pi like Raspberry Pi is junk.
Scott: now basically because this exists.
Rym: You know what I would use those for if I had my druthers.
Rym: You could get let's see a gig of RAM $18 so $20 per gigabyte of RAM.
Scott: Right this thing is ridiculous.
Scott: I mean you could basically take a monitor and strap this to the back and boom you're done.
Rym: Yeah I would say you know conventions like ConnectiCon or whatever.
Rym: if we could get a bunch of TVs to stick like by panel ops just stick one of those things on The TV.
Rym: do.
Scott: this thing can run pretty much any emulator NES SNES, right?
Scott: It can.
Scott: you can run like all sorts of Linux.
Scott: you can run Chrome on here.
Scott: you could run audacity on here.
Scott: you could run.
Scott: You know the GIMP emails VLC Pretty much anything that runs on Linux will run on this thing and run a surprising number of games in that actually.
Scott: Yeah, I mean if you want it to be super portable you need to find a battery for it.
Scott: You know how much power does it draw.
Rym: I mean I could probably power for a while.
Scott: I mean if you get a giant battery that has micro USB output which every battery does Got that like 26,000.
Scott: Whatever milliamp hour battery like you're freaking good to go.
Scott: like this thing is redonk.
Scott: If you have any sort of project that needs any sort of you know CPU off to the side.
Scott: I think Arduino and also Raspberry Pi pretty much have to eat it because the chip is here In the meta moment.
Rym: the book club book was a long time ago the wheel of time.
Rym: I bring this up because I'm moving on to book 8 and what I can say is that my Favorite thing about the wheel of time.
Rym: or you know the ale like those guys yeah at them.
Rym: So there's a bunch of ale wannabe weeaboos that come up later.
Rym: So there are people who aren't ale people in like tier and all these places like whoa like the young nobles.
Rym: those ale are Super cool.
Scott: They just want to be like that.
Rym: They start acting like them wearing each other guys Shan or we start wearing ideal clothes Yeah, and half the ale like ideal food.
Rym: half of the ale are like wow We these we gotta keep spread the word of how to act like civilized human beings Because they're finally getting it and the other half are like what the fuck are these kids doing?
Rym: can we just kill them?
Scott: Seriously guys dat cultural appropriation.
Rym: I just go kill them, but there's a scene where one dude remarks like Iran.
Rym: Can I just go murder all those kids because they're really not offensive just personally annoying to me That appropriation.
Rym: we are going to be at Pac South.
Rym: our schedule is slightly updated.
Rym: As a favor we let them move Atari game design to the earlier slot because someone Needed that panel slot because they have to video a packs like penny arcade panel, and we don't really give a crap.
Rym: Yeah, so they email me.
Rym: They're like yeah, you guys have done like every like a billion packs panels.
Rym: You okay with this?
Scott: like?
Scott: I don't care.
Rym: Yeah, like maybe if they'd put it at like 8 a.m.
Rym: On Friday, I'd be like no, but I don't care.
Scott: do whatever you want.
Rym: Atari game design.
Rym: Saturday at 1130 a.m Scared yet a discussion of horror and games.
Rym: Saturday at 5 30 p.m Sunday January 31st at 1 p.m Designing game rules.
Scott: Also packs is now having a night runner tournament Pac South.
Scott: Oh, yeah, Sunday morning at 11 so I can play a little bit and then go to a panel.
Rym: Yeah, and then I get a fly immediately to Boston from San Antonio.
Rym: That has no direct flights anywhere.
Scott: as far as I can tell no one wants to fly directly to Santa.
Rym: No one wants to fly directly to New York from San Antonio like no one except us.
Scott: That's right is really interesting.
Rym: Yeah, like I expected to not get a direct flight to Boston from somewhere like San Antonio But can't even get one from New York Really, you should be able to get a flight from New York to anywhere on planet earth that has an airport directly, right?
Scott: Yeah, I mean there might be those flights that are like once a week, you know If you want to go to a certain country, there's not a flight every day Scott when I flew to Turkey, there's multiple flights every day to Istanbul.
Scott: No, but I'm saying like if you want to fly to say Luxembourg direct is there really a flight every day.
Rym: I think there's at least one every day.
Scott: There might be one a day, right?
Rym: It's not like you could go at the time you want, you know Let me put it this way New York spoils you so bad on flights and you want if you wanna die from London To somewhere else even London.
Rym: It's like oh, there's only like one flight to Paris left today.
Scott: You want to go to Buenos Aires, is there really a flight every day?
Scott: maybe one a day at most maybe one every other You know, yeah, it's like how many people are going to Argentina from?
Scott: right, New York every day.
Rym: But uh PAX East coming up.
Rym: we put our panels in for that.
Rym: So stay tuned.
Rym: What else we got?
Rym: We put in our panels.
Scott: magfest is coming before any of those magfest.
Rym: We got like seven fucking panels.
Rym: It's gonna be awesome.
Rym: But also magfest is four days long Oh my god, and it's too early to even book our travel for that, but we'll be there.
Rym: Also the patreon edging toward that first stretch goal surprisingly, so if we get not that many more patrons if Even a quarter of the people listening to these words right now gave us just one dollar Just one dollar you don't even have to commit to giving it to us forever.
Scott: Everyone listening probably did give you $1.
Scott: the people who you think are listening just downloaded without listening is no automatic podcast download.
Rym: We only have like 50 something patrons, but they're giving us like 250 bucks a month.
Scott: What the hell is wrong with you people stop giving her money.
Rym: all of you just gave us a dollar not pay.
Scott: It'd be better for you.
Scott: No, do not.
Scott: zero dollars You should give.
Rym: but guys you can hack patreon you almost dead.
Scott: Vast majority of people listening to this have less money than me or Rym for now.
Scott: Do not give us money Unless you have more money than both of us.
Scott: in which case give us money until we are even with you.
Rym: Well guys, there is a stretch goal.
Rym: if you can muster up 24 grand a month We will we're not lying quit our jobs and do this full-time.
Scott: Well, I'll do whatever you want me to do.
Scott: new employer person.
Rym: I'll also eat my hat and probably pass out.
Scott: Do not also if you are going to throw money away on The Powerball lottery give it to us instead.
Scott: Yes Do not think that you're taking money and you're setting it on fire.
Scott: if you give it to Rym You're not setting on a fire.
Scott: You're only putting in the toilet, which is less bad than setting it on fire.
Rym: But also, uh We you could give a dollar and then we'd hit the stretch goal.
Rym: So we'd have to release all the episodes.
Rym: You could just take the not give any more dollars just cancel it after the first month because the stretch goal is just the peak The high-water mark.
Scott: So if you guys what if it hits the goal for like one second and then goes under then well at least for one month.
Rym: If it hits it for one month, then I'm obligated.
Rym: I got a re-release.
Scott: the money has to come in.
Scott: Yeah once Once.
Scott: so someone just changes their there, you know They're giving it's like a thousand and then immediately five minutes later brings it down to zero.
Rym: now I'm not gonna do it back.
Scott: So you actually have to get the cash.
Rym: Yeah, but if we get the cash even once then we which means me give your money to a real charity instead.
Scott: some suggestions We'll see.
Rym: syringas patreon.
Rym: You should give the money to.
Scott: yeah, he needs money's more than we do.
Rym: He makes more swell.
Rym: We've made more.
Scott: He's also more talented than we are.
Rym: We've made more hours of content.
Scott: He's one minute of quality of content one minute of neil Cesar Ega content is worth more than all the GeekNights ever times a thousand.
Rym: So he's not getting that much more money than us on patreon.
Rym: He really deserves it.
Scott: Oh, I should give him some money.
Scott: I'm giving him money.
Scott: The Here are the suggested charities official charities of GeekNights already.
Scott: comic book legal defense fund.
Scott: Yeah Or said EFF, except I don't agree with them on privacy, but everything else is fine.
Scott: The Creative Commons is a good one.
Scott: All right, the ACLU is good.
Scott: ACLU is okay.
Rym: Yeah Well, they're good because at least they're pretty ideologically consistent.
Scott: Yeah, doctors that borders always good.
Rym: Yeah You know what Planned Parenthood.
Rym: they could actually use the money.
Scott: right now They just take donations straight up.
Rym: I'm pretty sure you can donate directly to Planned Parenthood.
Scott: Oh, I did not know that.
Scott: I thought it was not a. if you never thought of it as a charity That would be like.
Scott: well, it shouldn't be a charity Sure, but I didn't realize that it was like you could do that.
Rym: It needs money.
Scott: Sure.
Rym: Why not?
Scott: What are the other nerdy ones though?
Scott: archive org?
Scott: Yeah, the Wikimedia Foundation.
Rym: Yeah trying to think of nerdy ones, you know, uh There's a few other patrons of people we know you could give money to.
Rym: they make art.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, I'm sure there might be one I'm missing or whatever cuz I didn't think of this until just now I'll crash course.
Rym: you give money to any patreon give it to crash course.
Scott: Yeah, you don't need that.
Rym: They are the some of the that's some of the that one.
Rym: They're the reason can a patreon exists?
Rym: and two That's probably one of the more noble causes because they actually just create educational stuff for free forever Independent of if you give them money kind of like gig nights.
Rym: We'll keep doing gig nights even if you give no money to the patreon ever.
Rym: So, yeah, Oh child's play child's play there you go.
Rym: or uh, you know games done quick because they just turn the lights That's the see.
Scott: I'm not sure about the games done quick.
Rym: They turn that money right around in a cancer chair.
Scott: Well, they give it to the prevent cancer Foundation, which I'm not sure is about cancer prevention.
Scott: Yeah, and it's like awareness and those charities are usually is awareness.
Scott: It's not research I mean, I don't know but it's about preventing cancer.
Scott: They might do research to prevent cancer.
Rym: It's always tough for those cancer charities because we're gonna talk about a dour topic.
Scott: my summer games done quick does.
Rym: There was a big meta study.
Rym: I didn't read the fullness of it yet, but it's it's.
Rym: it's one of those.
Scott: like that sucks They take all the studies and combine them.
Rym: Yeah Yeah The study basically said that the death rate like n years out from cancer has not decreased at all In 30-ish years despite prevention despite screening.
Rym: and it basically said that screening for cancer and Detecting it early has no outcome on the actual death rate across the population.
Scott: Mm-hmm
Rym: that basically people who had like the few people who could be saved because they have the rare cancer That's actually that treatable and they catch it that early is mitigated by the people who get pre-screened and they aggressively treated cancer That either would have been deadly anyway, or wouldn't have been deadly But the treatment ended up being worse.
Scott: how often is treatment end up being worse?
Scott: you think that the oncologist editor should be able to?
Rym: Well, what it comes down to is a lot of cancers aren't actually treatable in any meaningful way, right?
Scott: So you just tell the person this isn't treatable.
Rym: deal with it, but the study's main point was that Vastly increased cancer screening has had zero impact on cancer deaths.
Rym: hmm, and then the rest of it which I haven't finished reading talks a lot about the ramifications of that and Follow-up studies to determine, you know, why the answer is currently still zero.
Scott: What if you have the rare preventable one and you don't get screening because it doesn't affect the statistics?
Rym: Apparently apparently all these people getting colonoscopies earlier has not significantly impacted the death rate of colon cancer.
Rym: Well, because if you get it, you're gonna die, you know, yeah, but what they're saying is that pre-screening It has not reduced the death rate.
Scott: Well, cuz it's not one of those rare preventable ones.
Rym: Yeah Theoretically can magically lips that would.
Rym: then you know, I mean, I'm gonna get my colonoscopy is when I'm 40.
Scott: So does that mean cleaning, you know getting your polyp scraped out doesn't help you live longer.
Scott: All the questions you're asking I have not finished reading it yet Are you saying my just death rate cuz it could be like, okay, you still gonna do everyone the death rates a hundred percent Right.
Scott: I gotta live ten years longer and then I died.
Rym: I read there's another article to talk about.
Rym: statistically the death rates not a hundred percent because so many people are alive today That there's a place like a ninety nine point nine nine eight percent chance that you'll actually die.
Rym: based on the evidence.
Rym: We have two dates.
Scott: Yeah, okay.
Scott: Yeah anyway.
Rym: So to get onto a much the one of the few things we could talk about that's worse than cancer Nuclear weapon.
Rym: This is rims favorite topic for some reason just lately because it's been in the news a lot.
Rym: So what's been bothering me?
Scott: Chomsky Rym over here Rym Chomsky.
Rym: No, I'm sure he's one of my favorite people.
Rym: Okay, so they're gonna nuke us all.
Rym: Basically, I know a lot about nukes partly because I had some high school teachers who like when we like when we learned about World War two I had a high school teacher like that, you know, like the sophomore year like well kids modern history coming
Scott: He
Rym: we spent like a month talking about nuclear weapons.
Rym: The dude just knew a lot about him and was real mad about him.
Rym: and fun fact He actually was a big gnome Chomsky fan.
Rym: Okay, and also a Lenin fan.
Rym: So your mileage may vary.
Rym: Okay, and so recently North Korea, you know Detonated a nuclear test which is problematic for a lot of reasons I mean when I don't want to talk about politics at all.
Rym: But the headline that CNN ran was North Korea detonates hydrogen bomb.
Rym: unlikely Definitely didn't happen and I realized already that most of the people I talked to.
Scott: if they did I'm gonna buy a lottery ticket.
Rym: Yeah Very few nations in history have ever developed or detonated a quote hydrogen bomb Which is misnomer calling it a hydrogen bomb and it's nothing to do with hydrogen.
Rym: Yeah, like it's kind of like a bomb H of all that nonsense.
Scott: I mean people.
Scott: they don't really teach you this in school, right?
Scott: They teach you about like Japan and dropping, you know, the little boy the fat man What at right and you know, you think atomic bomb.
Scott: and then you know about ICBMs.
Scott: It's like a big rocket.
Scott: They can go to the other side of the world and but people don't realize that the warhead they put on the ICBM is Not like the atomic bomb.
Rym: It was in Japan.
Rym: It's a completely different thing and in fact people talk about India and Pakistan being nuclear states.
Rym: They have a gun type wet.
Scott: They have.
Scott: they have the things that we dropped on Japan.
Rym: They have the thing that we dropped on Hiroshima at best right modified slightly to be a little more powerful.
Scott: We still have some of those because they're still useful.
Scott: like.
Rym: No, they're not.
Scott: no No, I thought that we use them in the tactical nukes and you want to blow up like a Navy.
Rym: We don't you know, the gun type bombs are not used by anyone anymore.
Rym: Okay
Scott: at least
Rym: as far as we can I mean as far as I can tell they might be used by that kind of Atomic artillery that
Scott: even
Rym: we decided it was a bad idea because the Davy Crockett The human who launched it couldn't be outside of its blast radius and that was like a hundredth of a kiloton.
Scott: No, I thought we had them and like we'd like, you know the bombers and just drop them.
Rym: I know bombers don't use gun type weapons.
Rym: Okay bombers don't use atomic bombs.
Rym: They use thermonuclear weapons.
Rym: I'm pretty sure that almost every weapon we don't have any more atomic bombs left atomic bombs.
Rym: Oh, so this is where I want to explain things and then I'll let Scott ask questions.
Scott: I'm the rims too nerdy about this.
Scott: He just wants to nuke everybody.
Rym: what happened with North Korea was not a Thermonuclear device.
Rym: when people say h-bomb what they mean is a thermonuclear weapon, which is not what the Manhattan Project invented.
Rym: Nope, specifically, they mean a two-stage Thermonuclear weapon or a teller ulam device.
Scott: So when was that invented?
Scott: If not, if if the Manhattan Project 50s like who did that?
Rym: us the u.s Made pretty much all the progress in nuclear weapons.
Scott: Okay, but I mean who specifically Tell her an?
Rym: ulam.
Scott: Okay How can no one knows about them?
Scott: they're not famous like.
Rym: they're famous if you know about physics, right?
Scott: But they're not famous like, you know Oppenheimer and fine Because people don't know things about nukes.
Rym: you can see you get the fur.
Rym: the easiest way to know that someone doesn't know anything about nukes Is if they even say hydrogen bomb or h-bomb because those terms were invented by the press.
Rym: But so what North Korea detonated was not a thermonuclear modern device.
Rym: What it was is a variant of the weapon that we dropped on Nagasaki in World War two.
Rym: So those weapons the first nuclear weapons that were ever developed were criticality weapons Meaning you've got some like uranium right and you get a lot of uranium.
Rym: Yep, if you get too much uranium too close to itself like in too small a space or plutonium either way Yeah, then they're giving off enough radiation enough neutrons and shit to start a self-sustaining Catastrophic react like what's in a nuclear power plant?
Rym: Uh, yeah, so those are also critical.
Rym: They're critical They're self-sustaining.
Rym: They just keep going, right?
Scott: So one radiation bat, you know shoots out of one molecule and hits another one and makes that one go crazy like You've got some uranium 235 and it's just popping neutrons out.
Rym: Some of those neutrons hit more uranium and they do some stuff and they're like radiations coming out all over the place.
Rym: This is baby's first like simple description 10th grade chemistry class.
Rym: if you get a bunch of it together It'll start reacting which causes more reactions to happen.
Scott: exponential increasing reaction.
Rym: Yeah, so you do that either by getting too much together or by surrounding it with something that's gonna reflect radiation.
Rym: It's making back at itself.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So there was a term for this in the old days of making nuclear weapons.
Rym: during the Manhattan Project They called it tickling the dragon's tail because while they had Physics, you know people with pieces of paper said this is the amount.
Rym: Someone had to test that shit and you know how dangerous that was.
Scott: they tested it from real far away.
Rym: No, a lot of fucking people died.
Rym: Yeah, so there's if you want to read a really depressing Wikipedia article read the article called the demon core because we had a core of Nuclear material that we called the demon core because it killed a lot of people in experimentation.
Scott: One don't work there.
Rym: one dude had just two halves of this thing apart and he was holding him apart with a screwdriver And he was just fucking with it and he I guess sneezed and knocked their screwdriver out and it closed and flashed And he was dead.
Rym: he died of radiation poisoning days later like he was done.
Scott: So if you get radiation poisoning like that, don't wait days.
Scott: It'll just be really bad and suffering.
Rym: Yeah, well, actually it'll be really bad and then it'll be really good and you'll feel great For like another couple days.
Scott: Oh, yeah, you'll feel like no, how does that work?
Rym: I don't want to.
Rym: so that's just real depressing.
Rym: But basically it fucks your body up.
Rym: So you feel bad, but then your body starts shutting down.
Rym: So your immune response and all the things that are making you actually feel bad They turn off they turn off.
Rym: So you feel great and then you die.
Rym: Well, you feel bad again and then you die, but we're not talking about we're just talking about nuclear bombs.
Rym: I want to keep this real constraint.
Rym: so the early like the first weapons we made were literally you just have a ring of uranium and I'm not like a rod of uranium and you would shoot the ring at the rod like a gun.
Rym: They'd overlap and that would be too much critical mass.
Rym: So they would have a catastrophic reaction and explode.
Rym: but The reactions happen so fast like on the order of nanoseconds That the reaction would start when only a little bit of it was overlapping.
Rym: So you'd only get a pretty minimal yield.
Rym: you get the reaction going but then the explosion of the reaction Would break the materially apart and the reaction would stop.
Rym: and most of that uranium just was dust and plasma and shit.
Scott: You need some way to like hold the explosion in until it's even crazier and then let it go and you want yep.
Rym: so we made those kinds of bombs if you're evil and We dropped it on her own Hiroshima we.
Rym: this design is so simple that we didn't even test it Like we.
Rym: just we just dropped it.
Scott: We just assumed it would work.
Scott: I mean, it doesn't.
Scott: it doesn't explode when it hits something.
Rym: So what loads when the gun goes off in the bomb?
Scott: So how does?
Scott: is it like a timer or something?
Rym: I actually don't know.
Rym: I don't know the details.
Scott: There's a remote control.
Scott: I actually do not know much about the like because I can you know You watch Looney Tunes and they're always like hitting bombs with hammers.
Rym: So it doesn't work like that our through more thermonuclear devices like the ones that are actually crazy dangerous.
Rym: A lot of them would have gone off if we drop them like for real Mm-hmm, like we are wet they work by get.
Scott: if I hit one with a hammer it would go on.
Rym: Oh, they were just fucking like poorly designed and not safe.
Rym: Oh great We designed the weapons first and the safety came way later.
Rym: Do you know how we made the first two bombs that we actually dropped safe?
Rym: the nuclear payload was just separate like in a box.
Rym: the plane took off and then a dude in the plane crawled down there and Activated it.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So if they dropped it, it might have just gone off.
Rym: It was some crazy crap.
Rym: in fact, the gun bombs were so reliable that Those are the weapons that most countries developed that weren't in the current nuclear powers.
Rym: So like South Africa with their nuclear weapons, they had a bunch of bombs like that.
Rym: I'm pretty sure Israel has bombs and a lot of their bombs are also like that at the time.
Rym: so the implosion bombs that we dropped in Nagasaki were much more advanced.
Rym: and So like the engineering challenge is night and day.
Rym: instead You have a ring of high explosives tons and tons of high explosives and then they're shaped and there's Lensing like regular explosives like TNT.
Rym: Yes, just like TNT stuff like that I think it was actually like the sort of primer cord like RDX before.
Rym: no, it was more like RDX.
Rym: I think again, I'm not too.
Rym: conventional bombs Yes conventional bombs tons of that shit, but you'd array it with like fast and slow propellants in different shapes.
Rym: So you have this lens.
Rym: so the explosion would happen with such precision that the core which was just a hollow sphere of like plutonium would be crushed Instantaneously from all directions at once and that would cause the reaction and it was significantly more powerful.
Rym: Mmm, what North Korea just did is one of two possible things because the yield was too low.
Rym: real thermonuclear devices have kind of a minimum yield like So high that there's no way.
Rym: what they did was actually a thermonuclear device.
Rym: So either they did something called boosted fission where you have a regular old Hiroshima style bomb but in that empty core you fill it with something like lithium and Basically, it'll compress in and do the normal atomic bomb thing.
Rym: But that middle part will fuse from the pressure.
Rym: that fusion reaction will make a ton of neutrons.
Rym: that then just do Crazy more fission.
Scott: So it's still mostly a little bit the lithiums who are in the middle of the explosion.
Scott: They fuse together and make who knows what?
Rym: fusion fission Like boom all at once and the yield of that Could be like ten to a hundred times more.
Rym: like you could make a bomb like that and get up to almost a megaton.
Rym: If you really tried.
Scott: That's just.
Scott: that's really yeah.
Scott: So a megaton that sounds great.
Rym: Yeah, so to give you a one.
Rym: so to give you a reference because I tweeted about this a while ago.
Rym: The weapons that the United States used in World War two were ten to twenty kiloton meaning 10,000 tons of TNT equivalent explosion.
Rym: the biggest nuclear weapons ever designed were on the order of 50 to 100 megatons a hundred million tons of TNT.
Rym: a Fusion boosted bomb could be ten to a hundred times more than the weapons that were the weapons that were actually used in the real World.
Rym: so that is the best case for North Korea of what they developed.
Rym: They figured out how to make the the output of their regular crappy old-school atomic bombs be where they even get any radioactive stuff from.
Rym: That's an interesting question.
Scott: I mean is it is it?
Scott: can they mine it in North Korea?
Rym: That I actually don't know.
Scott: can they refine it in North Korea?
Rym: Apparently they did or someone gave it to them.
Rym: So we'll see.
Rym: I mean, it's kind of a secretive state.
Rym: China sort of just tells everyone to stay away.
Scott: I mean, it's like that's.
Scott: it's hard to get.
Rym: In fact, one of the reasons that the u.s Had so many atomic weapons after World War two is that we had uranium in our country.
Rym: We could just dig it up and Russia for a long time had no known source of uranium.
Rym: They found Russia.
Scott: They found some.
Rym: they found some later.
Rym: There's a lot of Russia to find it Yeah, but early on they didn't have it sure.
Rym: So and the difference.
Rym: so the other thing that North Korea could have done is doing that civilization, right?
Scott: It's like I got horses you don't.
Scott: so the other Horses.
Rym: because one thing that they might have done it might have been a boosted fission weapon Which was what the u.s Made.
Rym: we made a huge stockpile of those things in the Cold War ready to just lob with conventional bombers.
Rym: the other thing they might have done is they might have made a sloica style device.
Rym: sloica is like a. it's a pastry cake in Russia.
Rym: It's like a layer cake and a sloica device is layers and layers of like that fission fission fission fission fission.
Rym: So it's more like an advanced version of a boosted fission weapon and those things are a dead end.
Rym: We learned from physics later.
Rym: Like that theory Peters out at about a megaton and isn't really viable as a weapon.
Scott: like they're okay But a megaton bomb isn't viable as a weapon.
Scott: if I drop that on you, you'll be fine.
Rym: Well, it's a megaton, but it's also kind of big and unwieldy and there's problems with that sort of design.
Scott: I'll put in my giant plane and drop it on you.
Scott: what you do about it.
Rym: So North Korea has either one of those two things.
Rym: The ramifications however are not what a lot of people are like.
Rym: Oh now they can make real nuclear weapons.
Rym: Not really the ramifications are still bad though.
Rym: Don't get me wrong if they made a boosted fission weapon the former type That doesn't mean they're gonna be making like more powerful weapons.
Rym: That means they can take their existing style weapons and put them on missiles Which they their enemy.
Scott: their enemy is not far away, that's the real.
Scott: see if their enemy was us.
Scott: We don't really have much to worry about.
Scott: no matter what they have Yeah There's.
Scott: no matter how much atomic technology they have they don't have Something that can fly halfway around the world and land in New York.
Rym: Best weapon they have the best missile at least could theoretically hit the west coast at its extreme range, right and accurately.
Scott: No, it would probably land in like the forest or on some hippies, dude Accurately the.
Rym: there's a. there's a term called the CEP 50 Circular error probable which is the percentage.
Rym: basically it's the radius.
Rym: if you launch a nuke Where there is a 50/50 shot it'll land within that radius.
Rym: Think about that.
Rym: So some CEPs were in the miles.
Rym: So here's a circle of like five miles in diameter.
Rym: There's a 50/50.
Rym: There's a 50% chance.
Rym: It'll land Somewhere in that area.
Scott: So from here to work is about five miles.
Scott: So 50/50 it'll land between here and work or somewhere else.
Rym: Yeah, so somewhere else bomb the wrong place, Vermont That's part of the horror of nuclear weapons.
Rym: The the things that we had after World War two were not only terrifying in their power But they were inaccurate as shit, right?
Scott: So now we just send them into space and they land in exactly the right spot.
Rym: So North Korea might have Developed boosted fission weapons meaning they could take nuclear weapons that they can already make today and Deliver them somewhere nearby like Japan or South Korea.
Rym: That's not anything to sneeze at.
Rym: the other thing They could have done is developed a sloica style device meaning they could make a megaton weapon, but probably couldn't deliver it anywhere.
Rym: Neither one of these while they have sociopolitical ramifications is a modern nuclear weapon.
Scott: the engineering Challenge and by modern you mean how old yeah, so the 50s.
Scott: Yeah Okay, so there has development since then are probably a non-existent or be secret.
Rym: Oh the teller ulam design is secret.
Rym: like you can go look up Scott you and I together Anyone who knows even basic physics and engineering could make a gun type uranium nuclear weapon if they had if we had uranium Which we don't if you had the materials.
Scott: the engineering challenge You can't get it at the chemistry lab because they don't have enough.
Rym: The implosion type weapons the engineering challenge is a like an order of magnitude more.
Rym: It's very difficult to make that lensing and they're huge.
Rym: The fission boosted weapons or the fusion boosted fission weapons boosted fission Sloica all those things.
Rym: the engineering challenge is substantial but I cannot express to you the gulf in Engineering challenge between even the most advanced like a weapon that could ever be conceived and a modern thermonuclear device The fact that only five countries in the world.
Rym: arguably four have ever developed that technology And some of them were just gifted.
Scott: they didn't figure it out on their own.
Rym: Yeah, I mean the Soviets were kind of on the right track, but there was a lot of espionage going on.
Rym: We shared a lot of secrets with Britain France.
Rym: There was a lot of sharing going on and apparently a lot of espionage.
Rym: This stuff is not easy to develop like people talk about India and Pakistan.
Rym: Nope.
Rym: They don't have those weapons.
Rym: They do not have thermonuclear weapons.
Scott: I think about calculus, right?
Scott: There's always some story about someone who lives in the sticks somewhere who never took math class who figures out calculus on their own And has just different terms for everything and different symbols or who knows what but it is calculus.
Scott: They figured out independently Pretty much only once in the history of the entire world Despite half a century of trying plus Only one people's ever were able to figure out as far as we know how to make this thing.
Rym: Maybe two and it took a huge percentage of the GDP of the most powerful and economically viable country in the world decades to design that.
Rym: it also required Constant testing by blowing up nukes Mm-hmm, so because we have the nuclear non-proliferation treaty and because no one's allowed to test new.
Scott: and if you Even if you wanted to test nukes and you didn't care about the treaty everyone else will know immediately.
Scott: Yes I mean the whole unless you just keep failing.
Rym: the world knew within which case keep going that North Korea tried this bullshit.
Scott: And we knew within hours that either they develop you can't do it secret Even if you did at the core of the earth or in space everyone can see or find you with their Richter scale Seismograph, whatever.
Rym: It is such a secret that actually no one knows for real how to make them Like.
Rym: we know the theory you can look up.
Rym: you'll see these diagrams like everyone see the diagrams of what a modern nuke looks like But the actual engineering even if I had a whole pile of plutonium in the closet and I was totally Radiation-proof like Superman or something.
Scott: I still couldn't do it, right?
Scott: I couldn't get it to blow up that way because it's that hard to figure out how to make that happen.
Rym: And that is a good thing because the true horror of thermonuclear weapons and I can't do trial and error because everyone will see me Trying is that their yield is literally unlimited.
Rym: There is nothing Limiting the power of a nuclear weapon.
Scott: You can make one that just blows up the solar system like boop.
Rym: Yeah Modern nuclear weapons where there's a term dial a yield or a variable yield where you just pick what yield you want from the weapon And it has an upper limit because it does have a lower limit.
Scott: Can I be like I'd just be like one ton?
Rym: So that's where things get kind of complicated.
Rym: So this is where I want to ask you questions Scott.
Rym: Have you ever heard of a neutron bomb?
Rym: Yeah, I mean, what do you think a neutron bomb is?
Scott: I don't.
Scott: I'm pretty sure that this is complete bullshit because it's just sort of that, you know I don't follow you.
Scott: It's one of those stories that people tell that's complete bullshit.
Scott: Like hey, there's a secret in more.
Scott: You know Mario you can go to this right up and down 65,535 times right exactly.
Scott: So the story the kids tell about the neutron bomb in school, right?
Scott: Cuz like I'm not as morbid as Rym where I actually want to research such horrible things other than make them no longer exist.
Scott: the story kids tell about the neutron bomb is that it goes off and Shit doesn't blow up like all the buildings in the in everywhere will just be perfectly intact.
Scott: It doesn't blow up everything but it shoots neutrons everywhere really fast and it kills everybody.
Scott: and but it doesn't destroy anything.
Rym: So they're not actually a special bomb.
Scott: all it is sort of like cosmic rays hitting your computer, right?
Scott: You don't see them hitting your computer, but they still flip a bit.
Scott: You know the neutrons would come and like destroy your body because your body is and kill yourself.
Scott: So but it wouldn't kill.
Scott: a building is just concrete.
Rym: So actually the effective radius of the neutrons is about the same as the explosion radius.
Rym: Yeah, the only reason neutron bombs existed was to take out tanks.
Rym: Mm-hmm Because if you blow them up, it'll kill all the unprotected people because the explosion.
Rym: but the people in the tanks would be fine.
Rym: The neutrons make the tanks so radioactive that the tanks then kill everyone inside the tanks immediately From the from the nuclear radiation, but it's true that it doesn't blow everything up.
Rym: No, it blows everything up within its radius.
Rym: It's just the radius isn't that big but it's not a special bomb.
Rym: Neutron bombs are just thermonuclear weapons with the yield dialed all the way down.
Rym: Uh-huh So actually dialing the yield down makes them more horrifying in a different way.
Scott: So you couldn't dial the yield down say to make really efficient say Useful.
Scott: in modern-day construction bombs like I want to make a big tunnel under the river to put a train through.
Scott: Let me use this in a practical and non evil mechanism by turning the yield down.
Scott: So it just makes a ton.
Rym: Oh, you have to have the high after the yield pretty high up but with a thermonuclear device There's a sweet spot where.
Rym: so you have the nuclear weapon that goes off and has its yield of like a megaton or ten Megatons or whatever, but like Tsar Bomba is an example because that's the most horrific thing humans ever made.
Rym: That was a fifth.
Rym: Well, that was a hundred megaton weapon.
Rym: The Soviets detonated it at half power.
Rym: They dialed the yield of 50% Mm-hmm, and the.
Rym: the results of that test were catastrophic, but The difference between the 50 and the hundred megaton version is that the 50 megaton version you have a nuclear device and it's wrapped in Inert material like lead.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: So a lot doesn't let radiation get out.
Rym: Well, no, it's more that it.
Rym: that's just to hold it together.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So a lot of the actual explosion is fusion Which means that the energy yield is primarily from that and not that much fallout is generated.
Scott: Well, that's good at least better than you know, I mean you still.
Scott: it's still horrible.
Rym: so if you were doing peaceful nuclear weapons like excavation or whatever theoretically to use that kind of weapon because the Actual fallout is relatively low like reasonably acceptable for some use cases.
Rym: However to make an efficient weapon if you replace that lead with say uranium Then the 50 megatons goes off and that causes all that uranium to do fission and you double your yield with a minimal increase in weight and The radiation is uranium really heavy though.
Scott: I guess lead is heavy.
Rym: Uranium is open From from that kind of weapon is horrific.
Scott: Well, I mean, it's all horrific.
Scott: Yeah Even more horrific than regular horrific on the scale of nuclear weapons.
Rym: But I guess my only last question for you Scott is how do you think a thermonuclear device works?
Rym: No one seen diagrams.
Scott: Nobody knows.
Rym: Yeah, no one knows.
Scott: There's some isn't there like some mysterious code name like fog bank?
Rym: No, thanks is something probably an aerogel of some kind that's used to hold everything together an arrow.
Scott: You know about aerogels, yeah, but why an aerogel is gonna hold in that?
Rym: no So the area.
Rym: so the best theory we've got and this is why it's such a challenge.
Rym: This is the best we know.
Rym: basically a Boosted fission bomb goes off first.
Rym: Mm-hmm, but that's just a little baby bomb.
Rym: It's not the explosion or anything else that causes the fusion reaction.
Rym: that bomb generates x-rays.
Rym: So many x-rays.
Rym: the x-rays are Channeled via basically a big lens and a containment system into the second stage of the weapon.
Rym: You can have any number of stages They're just fusion all the way down.
Rym: the x-rays themselves are so much that they compress the secondary Mm-hmm, so light photons are compressing the secondary.
Scott: So the dialing is adjusting the how much x-rays.
Rym: maybe It's not it's.
Rym: that's where we don't know a lot about that's.
Scott: that's the trick.
Scott: Is that you know, it's not just something that you set off, right?
Scott: There's a way.
Scott: we know that there's a way to dial it.
Scott: So there's something that you can adjust how much at some point.
Rym: so think of it this way.
Rym: What do you think the engineering challenge is of all the timing?
Rym: Necessary to have a burst of x-rays such that they physically compress something to the point that it fuses, right?
Scott: Because you can make a bunch of x-rays, but you don't make them all at once.
Scott: They don't get to the destination all at once.
Rym: it ain't gonna happen and it's not a physics problem.
Rym: A lot of people can come up with a lot of ideas as to how that would work.
Scott: But yeah, I mean you could think you mean like you could just make a Sun right?
Scott: It's like we know how the Sun works.
Scott: We know the chemistry of how the Sun works.
Scott: It's like well get us, you know, I can write down on paper.
Scott: Well, it's helium fuses together and then it makes you know, you get enough of it and you're good.
Scott: But how do you actually make that happen in a space?
Scott: You have I give you tanks of helium as much as you want.
Scott: You have your own space lab.
Scott: It's in outer space.
Scott: you can have any Elements for the periodic table that you want in any quantity and you won't die and you can have any machine you want.
Scott: How are you gonna make a star?
Scott: you get to make a nebula first, right?
Scott: It takes too long It's not gonna work.
Rym: the engineering channel the the engineering to make a thermonuclear device from what North Korea did a few days ago would be like Your your warrior in Civ 5 Trying to make the spaceships.
Scott: at the end of the game It'd be like, you know, if at home you just started making i7s in your closet.
Scott: Yeah, it's like you can't do.
Rym: actually It'd be easier to make It would be easier for a country like North Korea to make a chip as fast as the i7 that it would be for them To engineer.
Scott: No, but I'm saying you in your closet making an i7.
Scott: It's like yeah You couldn't you know, even if I gave you the plans for it It's like and I gave you silicon you couldn't.
Scott: you couldn't print on that silicon.
Scott: What are you gonna do?
Scott: get a laser and start drawing on it and you're not clean room?
Scott: So I got nothing to end this.
Rym: on a kind of a positive note two atomic weapons were used in human history And we're not gonna debate about by luck And many near misses.
Scott: we have thankfully not used any since.
Rym: but yeah Except for testing.
Scott: For on people.
Rym: The power of those weapons pales so powerfully small Before the power of actual thermonuclear devices.
Scott: and the fact that and people don't really realize that that's you know.
Scott: They just think atomic bomb and they think of Japan and that's all they think about.
Scott: they don't realize that this much more horrific bomb has been made and is the only thing that we have and
Rym: the fact that in the So many generations of humans decades and decades and decades and decades, I mean from the 50s until We have no human has ever used one of these weapons Says I hope it says a lot about us.
Scott: Well used them on people.
Rym: Uh, well, yeah Well, we used them on people by accident.
Rym: We used them on trees and rocks a lot and water because the US military after World War two Basically treated those weapons just like a natural extension of bomber technology.
Rym: It wasn't until Castle Bravo when they developed an eight megaton weapon that was accidentally 15 megatons.
Rym: That was when the general started saying whoa Maybe we go too far You and play gods?
Rym: yeah, like that was when they started treating them like something fundamentally unique.
Rym: and It's also a testament that humans have never been able to develop these again And that somehow despite the fact that Russia the US China If playing gods was easy we wouldn't be here.
Rym: five countries in the world have developed this technology.
Rym: two of them hate each other and most of the rest of us at least in terms of geopolitics at different stages through history.
Rym: and yet No one's ever shared the secret.
Rym: No one else has ever figured out the secret and no one's ever used This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott special Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.
Rym: The patrons in order of the amount of money they give us are Nicholas Brando Rebecca Dunn Amanda Duchette James David white Christian coons Jess mechanical mind William Eisen rose.
Rym: the donation is coming from inside the house.
Rym: Clinton Walton my state e.com.
Rym: Phil Ulrich Renee from New Zealand Robert Lee Ryan Perrin drew open Lander rare Lavelle Brian Sidroni Rochelle, Mantanona Finn Eric Solver Rym eats poop kinetic man Aaron Cerise Chris midkiff Chris Knox flame darkfire Samuel Cordery Daniel Redmond Chris Haddad Doug Schneider Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: We finished shooting of episodes 14 and 15 of GeekNights presents utenna on Sunday.
Rym: So I'm actually in the middle of editing now and I'm gonna try to get at least one of those fully together with the new process and everything Before I go away for a long ski trip at the beginning of February.
Rym: So I'll keep this one short because we just also recorded the December Q&A which will be out this week.
Rym: There's a little bit of trouble and I lost Scott's audio for the first half of it but I had the backup running but the backup was not calibrated great because I rarely have to go to the backup and I Realized that our process has post hoc post record Compression so I don't have compression in line on the pre-record like I did with the old rig.
Rym: So as a result Scott's voice clips a bit But that gets cleared up about halfway through because I only lost the first half of Scott's audio.
Rym: So it's all in there.
Rym: All patrons will get the GeekNights December 2015 Q&A Very soon and I will now open up the question submission for GeekNights 2016 patreon Q&A.
Rym: and now I leave you with something really really A nine-tailed fox suddenly appeared if you believe it My ninja clan ninja clan.
Scott: here we stand Naruto.
Rym: I'm on my way Naruto.
Rym: I'll be okay getting ready to fight on set.
Scott: Come on best friends by my side.
Rym: That's okay.
Scott: He's really cool Sakura the beautiful Oh.