Rym: It's Tuesday September 13th 2016.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight captain sonar One ping only.
Scott: I use two things that you can do about it.
Scott: I said one thing we think like three times And then we found you and blow you.
Rym: Oh, what was it?
Rym: There was this game that I used to play on the Intellivision where you were a sub captain.
Rym: I'm trying to look it up when we get to the main bit of the show But I played this game on the Intellivision.
Rym: you're like a sub captain and you've got a harbor you've got to defend and enemy submarines are coming in to nuke it and you're like sneaking around and finding them and pinging them and Then torpedoing them.
Rym: and I remember as a dumb kid not really understanding that game and playing it a lot But not quite getting it.
Rym: All right.
Rym: I should emulate it and see what the deal was if that game was actually good or not Good for you.
Rym: Yeah, it was a good submarine game.
Rym: There's a lot of good submarine game.
Rym: Actually, you know, what's pretty good is the Game the original Game Boy Red October game because it was a two-player.
Rym: last time you played it Uh, it was unique in that it was a two-player Real-time asymmetric game that used the link cable.
Rym: Mm-hmm The original link cable.
Rym: one of you was the Red October and the other one of you was the entire Russian Navy.
Rym: And you'd like put assets around and go after the sub and it was it was I'm not saying was necessarily a good game by Like objective standard but for the time there was nothing else like that.
Scott: All right, try to play it and see how much if it's like what you remember.
Rym: I mean, it's a real simple game.
Rym: I remember it real well.
Rym: In fact, I played it a few years ago in an emulator to see what the deal was because as a kid while I was obsessed With it.
Rym: I only knew one person who had a Game Boy and a link cable and was willing to play it with me.
Scott: Do the emulator support opening up to emulators and having a virtual link cable between them?
Rym: Uh, I don't know.
Rym: I just played it.
Scott: like you can play it single-player or like using the internet using the network as a Link cable.
Rym: so I don't know a lot about the state of non NES SNES Mame emulators.
Rym: I should look into that.
Rym: I did find a game boy a 3ds emulator that worked Okay, and I used that to do some advanced war streams, but holy shit doesn't need a lot of CPU.
Scott: I think what people mostly do to stream 3ds stuff is they send their 3ds to this guy who installs a video out?
Scott: Yeah, I've seen that and apparently it's a reliable.
Scott: But there's like a wait period.
Scott: so generally you get a buy 3ds send it and then just wait.
Rym: I've seen kits.
Rym: you can do it yourself, but I'm not a good solder anymore.
Scott: I mean, I happen I am but are you?
Rym: what was the last thing you soldered?
Scott: The clock nice to my bed.
Rym: All right, how long ago was that 2006?
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: I mean in my apartment.
Scott: I was living in New York.
Scott: Yeah, I have all kinds of soldering shit.
Scott: I can sign.
Rym: So I was in Utah.
Rym: That's why GeekNights was delayed even longer.
Scott: Why would you go there?
Rym: It was a work thing.
Rym: I'd go for this hackathon or whatever and a hackathon in Utah.
Scott: the people there like our computers.
Rym: No, well, actually there's a huge tech it business like industry there.
Rym: like if you want to if you want to live somewhere cheap and Get a tech job.
Scott: There's a reason it's cheap.
Rym: You get what you pay if you're not gonna live in a tier one city like New York or Chicago or whatever Salt Lake City like that level of city not the worst place like living in Omaha, Nebraska Like.
Rym: you'll get a job.
Rym: You'll get a job.
Rym: There's more than two restaurants Three.
Rym: a lot of people don't live in New York, and that's fine.
Rym: But also the deal is this is a super here in Park City, which is like for 23.
Rym: It's like 40 miles east way up in the mountains like so high that when I went mountain biking I had some trouble with the altitude.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Yeah, but I did go for real mountain biking Which I haven't done that often recently and this was the most intense I've done yet because you know I didn't.
Rym: Sydney every time I go in the Blue Mountains and I do it in Singapore every time I go and Singapore is like a technical track and Sydney is just like down a mountain on a fire trail and then like one single track technical Course at the end after the 40 kilometers or whatever.
Rym: But this was go up a couple thousand feet and then ride on crazy steep like super technical courses all the way down the mountain all over the place I Strava did or whatever and I'm pretty proud how I did like I only flipped over my handlebars once Mm-hmm.
Rym: It was good.
Rym: I got a pretty serious bruise on my thigh though It hurts real bad if it does.
Rym: if it keeps growing I might go to a doctor and get it checked out but otherwise do dangerous shit, but it was fun and I'm proud to say that my belief in my skills as a mountain biker Were fine.
Rym: I chose to go with the pro group So I followed the two guys.
Scott: Your belief in your skills regarding everything are inflated, but that's who you are.
Rym: I never.
Rym: I followed the pro guys down the technical black diamond trail and I had a pretty good time compared.
Rym: I was only like two minutes behind them.
Scott: Are you sure they were actually pro guys or were they guys who just had fancy equipment and looked like pro guys?
Rym: No, they knew their stuff.
Rym: They were.
Rym: they were.
Rym: one of them was like our guide and everything.
Rym: Yeah, okay Yeah, the bike I had though was great.
Rym: It was this like all carbon fiber mountain bike and had this crazy Gearing made for mountain biking my lowest gear.
Rym: The front gear was way smaller than the rear gear and had all Hydraulic brakes and everything.
Scott: I don't like the hydraulic disc brakes, but I guess we're at a mountain.
Scott: You don't have a choice.
Rym: Yeah, because the thing is you can't have Rym brakes on a mountain bike cuz I get some mud in there and you did Yep.
Rym: Also, you got to be able to coast on them a lot because some of the slopes are so steep.
Rym: You're going down in a grade that's almost straight down.
Rym: You've got to ride the brake And the suspension was way way beyond anything I'd ever used in a mountain bike for real before.
Rym: Which man?
Rym: if I didn't lock it out It was like doo doo doo doo when I actually tried to pedal anywhere.
Rym: But going down the mountain I could slam into like a four-foot high tree stump wouldn't even feel it Just like put him right over it.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: It's good times.
Rym: Yeah, that was that was my open event.
Rym: you got any news.
Rym: we got anything to talk about other than the Really disappointing omega-thon finale.
Scott: We could talk about the disappointing omega-thon Not a repeat.
Rym: for the second time in a row the omega-thon finale was on Mario game.
Scott: Yeah for the PAX Prime omega-thon for the second time in a row was Mario last year.
Scott: It was Mario maker with a pretty easy level that used the Super Mario World bits.
Rym: And yet was clearly the fight the omega-thon finale.
Rym: people last year were both people who appeared to have never played a Mario game before Yet somehow made it to your mega-thon finale.
Rym: Well the curve well because the omega-thon up until the last round is mostly kind of easy in this year It wasn't.
Scott: it was actually games of somewhat skill.
Rym: Sure was like super skill a lot of tabletop.
Scott: There weren't random games really.
Scott: and then So this year it was just Mario 3. play for 10 minutes over as the higher score and you have infinite lives.
Scott: We put game genies just in case you suck now.
Scott: This is notable.
Scott: that was necessary.
Scott: cuz boy Did they suck?
Rym: it would have been game over immediately for both of them?
Rym: Yeah, but it was notable for two reasons.
Rym: one the the new challenger had clearly never played Mario 3 before and probably never Played a Mario game before because the way they were like they didn't seem to realize they didn't.
Scott: they didn't hold D to run.
Scott: But the other guy on the right he was the guy who was in there last year and lost.
Rym: I would never played Mario last year.
Scott: He clearly yeah, and he's still.
Scott: he didn't appear to improve at all.
Rym: He got to the omega-thon again.
Rym: It was a Mario game again, and he still didn't hold B to run in the entire like.
Rym: sorry, dude Sorry to trash a semi-anonymous stranger on the internet on our show But you don't deserve to be a lot.
Scott: you shouldn't be allowed into packs with those kind of Mario skills.
Rym: See now it's.
Rym: we're getting to the point where those Mario games are so old that I'm not gonna say I'm not gonna try to Be some sort of gatekeeper for packs like.
Rym: that's actually kind of stupid.
Scott: I'm a gatekeeper for.
Scott: I mean you shouldn't even be allowed to like play other games.
Rym: What so 20 years from now kids have to play Mario 1 yeah?
Scott: It's like you know.
Scott: you can't drive until you get a driver's license.
Scott: You can't play games until you can play a Mario.
Rym: the only I mean in all seriousness the only reason.
Rym: I would say anyone really has to play those games as if they're Serious about gaming as a hobby or game design.
Scott: so you're someone is in coming to packs And they're not serious about gaming.
Rym: most people who go to most conventions aren't serious about the thing they go for.
Rym: that's always been.
Scott: You shouldn't be coming because it's someone else who is serious who wants to come and can't come because you're there so get out all right.
Rym: You're exactly the stereotype of what's wrong with most fandom community.
Rym: serious only except That's not what packs is even about.
Rym: Packses you know get people to see all the different sides of gaming.
Rym: maybe they come just for the expo hall But then they see a tabletop game.
Rym: they get interested.
Scott: Yeah, maybe you should play Mario.
Rym: Disgrace it was.
Rym: it was just very interesting because I noticed something.
Rym: This is totally an aside, but I met just because I was traveling a lot around packs and after packs in Seattle I met a ton of people who are kind of serious gamers like they play games a lot like obscure German tabletop games like obsessed with Overwatch like PC gamers like these people aren't.
Rym: gamers like these are the people where you would even say yeah They should go to packs mm-hmm.
Rym: I get the impression that the vast majority of those people in the US have never heard of packs or penny arcade mm-hmm.
Rym: I think the vast majority of gamers have never heard of the idea of a gaming convention.
Scott: Yeah, why would they?
Rym: well?
Rym: Do you think it's not.
Scott: it's not advertised to the general public it's in the internet.
Scott: And if you don't live in the internet like I do or we do then you don't know what's going on.
Scott: There's a whole.
Scott: it's basically another world all these.
Rym: but these are people who read read it regularly They're on the internet.
Rym: They like use Twitter all the time.
Rym: They do all the stuff We do like everything.
Rym: they read Kotaku.
Rym: they read all the shit We read.
Scott: they just don't know packs exists, but this Kotaku has like a big section every time.
Scott: They just don't notice like.
Rym: they don't like gaming convention.
Rym: What do you mean?
Scott: They just don't read it?
Scott: I guess they just don't get those articles that are Covering the whole front of the.
Rym: these are people who are like oh, yeah Like I'm ready that really the German games and the Catan is too easy, but Puerto Rico is pretty good.
Rym: or like yeah I've been playing overwatch a lot.
Rym: It finally gave me that like old quake to feel.
Rym: and yet they don't know gaming conventions exist.
Scott: They didn't and then must not be reading.
Scott: I mean basically if something happens on the internet.
Scott: It's in like its own dimension.
Scott: It doesn't like advertise.
Scott: you have to know.
Scott: if you have to go into that you have to know the zone exists.
Scott: You have to find the door on your own and walk into it of your own volition.
Scott: It's not the door doesn't have like a sign on it.
Scott: There's no one outside the door saying come inside guys You know, this thing is here.
Scott: Whoo.
Scott: This thing is here.
Scott: Whoo It's like you have to know it's a stumble upon it or search or know someone or be told or something Right in order to find places on the internet and know things exist.
Rym: Yeah, though the one ray of hope one person I met in all my travels had heard of not only packs but penny arcade and knew who gave in taiko were Because her child is really interested in game design and watches video of the panels from paxes Cuz.
Rym: the child doesn't go to paxes.
Rym: Mmm.
Rym: So there is one ray of hope there.
Rym: But that aside people don't know about packs and they definitely don't know how to play Mario games.
Rym: So to the credit of the guy on the left at pack, he seemed to learn how to play Mario slowly.
Rym: I mean it is fun.
Scott: Mario 3 is one of the best games of all time and it teaches you how to play it.
Rym: So it's fine.
Rym: If you get to the America if you go to packs and you haven't played Mario, it's fine.
Rym: I mean what if you're only a tabletop gamer and why you can just go to Gen Con?
Rym: Even if you're only a tabletop game.
Rym: also don't go to jail.
Scott: if you're a tabletop gamer you still.
Scott: I mean Mario.
Scott: It's like it's like if you're only a video gamer and you haven't played settlers.
Rym: So I've been watching a lot of Industry.
Rym: people talk about anime.
Rym: we're at a point now where there is literally no show That you could even say a third of American anime fans are familiar with deeply.
Rym: Yeah, there's no touchstone show nothing, right?
Rym: And the one complete bifurcation not even a bifurcation just a long tail spread across all genres.
Scott: It's the same thing with right and the and the two thirds who haven't seen cowboy bebop and evangelical.
Scott: You know the ones who are wrong and aren't real fans.
Scott: They can just go You know not be allowed at the anime convention anyway.
Rym: Well, I mean most people go to anime cons haven't seen anime.
Rym: at least most people go to packs Actually, I would say that but I get the impression this year a lot of people who went to packs only went to see PewDiePie Maybe but I don't have any data on that yet.
Rym: I'm actually trying to figure out why packs felt so light even though it was clearly sold out.
Rym: It was clearly the biggest packs ever and it was quiet.
Rym: Yeah, like it was Weirdly quiet like tabletop felt like packs circa 2008 or not.
Rym: You could get seats Yeah, like trivially middle of the day on Saturday.
Rym: Just go to the convention center pick any tabletop room get a whole table Mm-hmm.
Rym: It was weird.
Rym: Anyway, so you got any news?
Scott: Yeah, so speaking of Mario's You know Apple dead Apple Day since we last did a show.
Scott: Yeah, it was a pretty boring Apple Day because they didn't really add anything to the iPhone.
Rym: They took shit away.
Scott: What did they take away?
Rym: headphone jack?
Scott: All right, yeah, whatever.
Scott: but I think the I think the fear over the loss of the Headphone jack is greatly exaggerated.
Scott: Not that it's you know, not that I don't want a headphone jack.
Rym: well a lot of people have pointed out that all the devices that use that hole to plug in like temperature sensors and Scientific equipment and mostly payment processors.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: It appears that they will not work with the dongles.
Scott: I Don't know about that.
Rym: I mean that that is the report that I read this morning when I was looking into it.
Rym: I've not followed up too much because that's my topic for Monday.
Scott: That's a good question.
Scott: I mean as far as I believe is basically on the lightning connector.
Scott: It like it just converts all the analog to digital and vice versa.
Scott: So what like your square reader?
Scott: Why wouldn't it work?
Scott: It would just.
Scott: you know, you're reading from the analog input.
Rym: This is the were so the the.
Scott: I'd have to look I'd have to look at the documentation for like the API For the analog and input/output on the phone But I did.
Rym: I read an article that was basically by this dude who were like blogs apparently on payment processing Specifically and he was talking about how the apps can automatically read the headphone jack Like without like special permissions or anything and it appears that they can't do the same thing through the lightning connector.
Rym: Apple could just say, you know that you might have to go through an Apple process to be able to get that data.
Scott: I think the API you use is use the microphone API, right?
Scott: because yeah you're basically like trying to record audio as if you were making like an audio recording app and then you just examine the data that Came in as not as audio but as bits, right?
Scott: Yeah so I and so if you have right an app that uses say the say you say you made a Microphone recording app just a voice recorder.
Scott: Yep, and you know somebody installs that app on an iPhone 6 which has a microphone hole and iPhone 7 which won't You and the person plugs the microphone into the adapter into the lightning.
Scott: that the same app with the same code won't record anything On the iPhone 7 and that's the question that does not sound right to me.
Scott: I have to believe that the app will still record the audio on the iPhone 7 Using the dongle if you're wearing one of those headsets with the microphone.
Rym: Well, anyway, that is what I'm going to figure out for Monday.
Scott: Yeah, I find it hard to believe anyway.
Scott: So nothing there was a surprise or exciting.
Scott: I'm gonna wait and get the tiny iPhone which according to schedule should be out early next year.
Scott: Yeah, because the iPhone 7 isn't significantly better enough than my iPhone 6.
Scott: There's no reason to rush out and get one.
Scott: Yeah anyway, but They did do something that was surprising which is they were like, hey Me and moto's here and we got some Nintendo games.
Rym: That's the thing that many people have told us when we said hey someday Nintendo might just be a software company Just like Sega.
Scott: that's not gonna happen.
Scott: Making the NX they're making hardware.
Scott: the 3ds is going strong.
Scott: They just made more 3ds stuff for now.
Rym: We'll see anyway.
Scott: but they're making a Somewhat more real Mario game for the iPhone for iOS.
Scott: that will come out on Android way later because they got an exclusive deal With Apple.
Scott: so it seems like all the Nintendo games are gonna come out on iOS and then come out an Android way later.
Rym: I do think that is a Resistant to mobile like deeply resistant and I think they were very afraid that if they embrace mobile gaming It would kill their portable console like a hundred percent.
Scott: I think it's too late.
Scott: It's regardless, right?
Scott: I think it's more that everyone's playing games on their phones and not killing playing on the portable console anyway.
Scott: Yeah, so you might as well put a Nintendo there and hopefully maybe you put some games that are mobile type games on there And you'll get people to like and realize that Nintendo shit is so much better than crappy iPhone shit.
Rym: But will that convert people then buying a regular Nintendo portable console?
Scott: I don't know if it'll convert enough people to move the needle and like the stock market But I think it only will definitely get some people.
Rym: I think it only will if there are still exclusive first-class games only on the console They're getting.
Rym: those games are Pokemon games.
Scott: There's no sign of that stopping.
Scott: Yeah But I mean the game that they're coming out with is basically Mario runner Which is like the simplest Mario game.
Scott: All you do is he if there's a little jump like if Mario runs up to a goomba He's gonna jump on it automatically.
Scott: You only basically tap your phone to make Mario jump and you tap more to make him jump higher and he runs to the right Without stopping and you pretty much only have to handle the big jumps.
Scott: He's gonna handle little jumps.
Scott: Yeah, but if you watch video footage of the game They've actually taken this runner concept which has been done before right?
Rym: Yeah, those games are all mostly the same.
Scott: I remember really I remember really old games.
Scott: I mean, it's basically the same thing as uh, dude There was a game Adventure Island right with the kid on this the cave kid on the skateboard.
Rym: It wasn't always on the skateboard.
Scott: No, but he basically just runs to the right and jumps right?
Rym: Well forget that on my ti-85 I had a game where you had a boulder a ball and it went forward and you had to jump obstacles.
Scott: and I had that game.
Scott: I also had one that it was the same thing a guy on a skateboard.
Scott: Yeah, I mean this bit trip runner.
Scott: There's so many this.
Scott: basically there's a games.
Scott: There's a lot of games on the phone that are like this.
Scott: There's like I think temple run.
Rym: But there's also runs the one that you see like kind of basic people playing camera.
Scott: The camera is behind the guy running forward.
Rym: There's also a temple run equivalence with like Sonic the Hedgehog branding and so is this Nintendo just doing that the best that can be Done.
Scott: right, but if you look at the video footage of this This is way better than those other runners.
Scott: cuz you know, it's got the Nintendo action, right?
Scott: It's like they put enough stuff into it that it's like oh, that's a level above.
Scott: Those are the crappy run games.
Scott: Yeah, and also it's gonna be pay once get the game.
Scott: It's not gonna be.
Scott: no if that's interesting because there was a lot of play It's not gonna be micro transaction.
Rym: way back when Nintendo amounts fuck announced Pokemon go like when that was happening a lot of people were saying that this will be great because Nintendo will do micro transactions differently and they're gonna do it right.
Rym: and then so far Pokemon go is basically just been the same old Bullshit because it's not made by Nintendo.
Rym: Yeah, so we'll.
Rym: it'll be curious to see if these games are Basically just Nintendo variants of the existing ecosystem or if they actually do something different in the long run.
Scott: No, I mean, they're just selling this game like you pay a few dollars or however We don't.
Scott: they didn't say how many dollars yet, but you pay.
Rym: that'll be interesting because I think $1.99 is already considered premium.
Scott: I mean this can probably be sold for five bucks, but people would be like and Ten bucks would be way too much right.
Scott: more than five would be too much.
Scott: five would be like Alright fuck you less than that unless this game was somehow legit amazing.
Scott: I mean, it's it's probably the best sideways running game There's gonna be ever.
Scott: That I mean that depends what you think of sideways.
Scott: just run.
Rym: I mean run.
Rym: yes guys This is the best Seattle downtown pizza ever exactly.
Rym: people are giving me shit people out.
Rym: I was like a pax.
Rym: I was like never delivered.
Rym: delivered pizza in Seattle because holy shit.
Scott: Well never ordered pizza anywhere.
Scott: That's not New York City.
Rym: So I'm gonna qualify that because if you were mad at me one.
Rym: Yes, there is good pizza in Seattle.
Rym: I've had it.
Rym: never delivery.
Rym: It's only sit down in real restaurants.
Scott: I've never seen any good pizza anywhere.
Scott: That's not New York City.
Scott: I got good pizza Or close to New York.
Rym: I got a really good pizza advance.
Scott: It's not real pizza.
Rym: Yeah, was it?
Rym: was it you and your fucking real pizza?
Rym: It was a fine real pizza.
Rym: It was that thin crust like the stuff you get at a fancy Italian restaurant.
Rym: That was good.
Rym: problem is can't get that delivered.
Rym: and one of you was like oh But there's good pizza if you order it from.
Rym: and they named places that do not deliver downtown.
Rym: And even better some of you were like, oh what about this place?
Rym: they're legit good.
Rym: I Researched all the places that people thought.
Rym: well the three places that people told me were legit good.
Rym: Over the years that packs we have ordered from all of those places.
Rym: And if you think that's good pizza, I will never eat food that is in your proximity again.
Scott: I think the thing is is just people who don't live in New York.
Scott: They haven't had real pizza, dude I grew up in Michigan.
Rym: I knew a good pizza was like when I got to New York.
Scott: I thought in Michigan all you had was Pizza Hut.
Rym: if you want to chain you could.
Rym: there were fancy places.
Rym: You could sit down but they didn't deliver.
Rym: But the point is delivery pizza.
Scott: you haven't had the good stuff.
Scott: because like people like don't like.
Rym: they think five guys is a good Burger.
Scott: well, people don't even know what a bagel is, right?
Scott: I mean it's recently is the 70s or even 80s.
Scott: There just weren't bagels anywhere.
Scott: That wasn't like Brooklyn, New York You know, you just if you were in like, I don't know, Florida.
Scott: There wasn't a bagel like.
Scott: you couldn't get one.
Scott: you have to make it yourself.
Scott: They weren't available.
Scott: and now bagels are everywhere, but you still can't.
Scott: you can only get real bagels in very few places.
Scott: It's very likely that most most people on earth do not live near a place that bakes real bagels.
Scott: They probably never tasted a real bagel.
Scott: Do not realize their bagel that they have had is shitty Because they haven't had a real one.
Scott: and in fact when they encounter a real one They might mistakenly say it's shitty because they like the thing they're used to because they're a typical human who doesn't like change.
Rym: Nobody actually likes like.
Rym: they choke it down.
Scott: They enjoy familiarity over quality.
Rym: Nobody likes that that mid-america bagel.
Rym: They say they like it because they resent your New York attitude and they choke it down crying inside the whole time.
Rym: They know But listen, I'm gonna put it this way this the pizza that is able to be ordered in downtown Seattle is shit here even by Albany or Detroit standards.
Scott: I mean the pizza we had.
Rym: I'm not comparing it to New York City I'm comparing it to like taste buds.
Scott: the pizza that we ordered and delivered and that was like the line of edible at this most Recent bags.
Rym: that was the best we've ordered yet and I was like at the bottom line.
Scott: It was an edible pizza Barely, it would.
Rym: it was not like ew gross I'm not eating this but it was like like there's the line below which not eating this.
Rym: It was like a little bit above that line, but it's not not much room to fall, you know, it's like I'm hungry.
Scott: I need something.
Scott: here is a pizza.
Scott: I will eat some of it and fill my stomach.
Rym: had I not been hungry I would not have eaten it.
Scott: No, I mean if I'm not hungry, I don't eat anything.
Scott: Wouldn't even eat the world's most delicious pizza if I wasn't hungry.
Rym: if I'd been only a little hungry I wouldn't have eaten it.
Rym: I only ate it because I was desperately hungry.
Scott: I wasn't desperately hungry.
Rym: I was because I ate a light lunch.
Rym: Anyway, yeah, but I just said so.
Rym: in terms of Nintendo Pokemon go still going.
Scott: I guess why would it not be going?
Scott: it's not Pokemon stop.
Rym: Well According to Bloomberg and a few other people Engagement in the Pokemon app has fallen off precipitously as All the people who are actual gamers who like for whatever reason expected this game to be made way more than it was Hit the wall of.
Rym: well I can't really level up much more unless I grind and they all stop playing it.
Scott: I mean, that's every single thing.
Scott: every single game that has just grinding is mechanic.
Scott: Yeah gets a ton of players because at the early part, it's super funny.
Rym: Like yeah, I got a level.
Rym: Yeah, ten levels loop by loop.
Scott: There's so much low-hanging fruits together.
Scott: It's like we for your brain and then Eventually, just like I. that's enough of that.
Scott: if you look at like all those Facebook games like the Mafia whatever is in the Farmville Yeah, they were actually dying before Facebook sort of cut off their sharing mechanism.
Scott: He hit that upper limit all those zinga games like.
Scott: they got crushed zinga Right because people played all those games like crazy and then they were done with them.
Scott: They they don't have staying power.
Scott: if you want a game to have staying power You want people to keep playing it?
Scott: It has to have substance that keeps you know brains interested for a long time.
Rym: I guess what's interesting with Pokemon go is that just because it wasn't it was a it was Pokemon that IP a Lot of people who would otherwise never even look at a game like this Double down on it and for whatever reason they.
Rym: it's almost like in VR.
Rym: Like there's a concept in VR where if you make an object too realistic, then the player Expects it to behave more realistically and when it doesn't it messes them up.
Rym: So if you want if you're not gonna make something complex, you can't make it look complex.
Rym: So people just looked at this and said oh Pokemon Pokemon's got a lot going on and started trying to IV train their Pokemon and Pokemon go because that's gonna matter ever.
Rym: No, so one by one those people are realizing.
Rym: Oh, there isn't anything like nothing.
Rym: Nothing's gonna be different.
Rym: It's just see more Pokemon and take more funny pictures.
Scott: It's exactly what we said.
Scott: It was go back and listen to old GeekNights.
Scott: I'm sure you'll find a me saying before the release of Pokemon go.
Scott: this will be Ingress with Pokemon skin.
Scott: Yeah, that's exactly what it is.
Scott: I was 100% right.
Scott: Yep, cuz I'm smart.
Rym: So they added a new feature the Pokemon go buddy system.
Rym: and you know We call these games like we did.
Scott: our lecture is just share with people to level up faster.
Rym: No, you know how we call these games candy box games, right?
Rym: Well in Pokemon go the only way to evolve or level up Pokemon is to get candy.
Rym: Okay, just like a candy box.
Rym: Literally you get candy.
Rym: So if you want to level up like if you want to evolve a man handy now just candy.
Rym: But the candy is tied to each species line.
Rym: So if you want to level up a Bulbasaur Bulbasaur candy if you Can you can use these.
Rym: you can.
Rym: it's all.
Rym: bubbles are candy.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: So if you don't know you want to level up your Venusaur you got to give it Bulbasaur candy.
Rym: or you can grind up Bulbasaurs or Venusaurs or Ivysaur so you can't give it dragon eyes.
Rym: Nope.
Rym: But for example to evolve a Magikarp you need 400 Magikarp candies.
Scott: That's a lot.
Rym: you get candies every time you catch a Pokemon of that type.
Scott: You got to catch 400 Magikarp.
Rym: So now they've added buddies when you pick one of your Pokemon and they're gonna appear on the map walking around.
Rym: and what they do is You get a certain number of candies per kilometer that you walk of that type.
Rym: It's literally just CPS.
Rym: it's just candies per second or in this case candies per kilometer.
Rym: It's just candy box.
Rym: Pokemon goes buddy system is the lollipop farm in candy box.
Rym: Yeah And That's it.
Rym: That's the new feature that everyone's excited about.
Rym: you can everyone.
Rym: you can turn on Another grind machine that grinds by itself.
Rym: So you have to click less to grind.
Rym: that is literally the feature They added and this article I found one one step further and they actually calculated You have to walk 400 kilometers to evolve a Gyarados from a Magikarp, yes 400 kilometers.
Rym: and remember Pokemon go if you run it decides you're not walking and that shit doesn't count.
Rym: What?
Rym: yeah, I thought when the game first started like oh, whatever.
Rym: I'll just fill all those incubators with eggs.
Rym: And you know, I run like every day I'll have every goddamn Pokemon in the world.
Rym: and no it doesn't count my running unless I run less than like three and a half Miles an hour, which that's a New York walk.
Rym: speed is faster than that.
Scott: biking doesn't work.
Rym: No Only walking.
Rym: Okay, you go too fast.
Rym: It doesn't count.
Scott: All right Maybe they should increase that speeds like 20.
Rym: No Cuz then people would just put it on like a bike and ride around all day and get everything.
Rym: remember you got.
Rym: you got to Keep that grind slow.
Scott: You shouldn't give the points per kilometer.
Scott: You should get the points per time spent moving.
Rym: Yeah, and you know what?
Rym: The answer to that is you put your poker you put your cell phone or in your dongle on your Roomba but anyway things of the day.
Rym: So this is a bunch of tweets and it's basically a bunch of tweets as you think of the day.
Rym: Well, what it is is you remember way back?
Rym: they were talking about how Lego universe had their problem with penises and how they had their penis detector to detect if people made Penises to remove them.
Rym: Well, it appears to be a little bit of an expose of some people talking about how this actually worked and Apparently making the software detect dongs was actually impossible.
Rym: Of course it is and they actually just had Whitelists and humans literally looking at everything and one by one approving Everything.
Scott: this is how you saw the recent news at the Facebook and the Norwegian person posting the Vietnam photo.
Scott: Yeah, and the Prime Minister of Norway being pissed and whatnot.
Scott: it's because Facebook does the same thing.
Scott: Facebook has an army of very lowly paid people who look at all the Facebook posts and Choose to report or filter or escalate them based on like some content guidelines given by Facebook.
Scott: The mod the human modern a computer does not do this work.
Rym: They actually had a huge moderation team.
Rym: They got a bunch of screenshots of every model every property entirely whitelist based building.
Rym: You could build whatever you wanted, but strangers could never see your builds until we'd had a team to a penis sweep on it.
Rym: It was all automated.
Rym: Here's the interesting part.
Rym: But the human moderators were I are see the single biggest cost center for Lego universes operational costs That cost more than anything and the only reason this is the case is because of the the child online Protection Act.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Copa is the reason why so many things that are good online Technically say you can't use this if you're a kid Fuck you, and frankly the advice in this tweets at the end is like guys if you want to make a game Never let kids play it.
Rym: you're fuck.
Rym: You can't make something fun period.
Rym: you cannot have anything online if kids would play it at all And they tell this story even about how one of the developers made a dick in a sandbox to test the moderation system.
Rym: But then someone else actually took a bunch of kids while they were doing a kid's day Into that property and they saw the dick and apparently that was a four alarm.
Rym: Somebody's getting fired.
Rym: incident Mm-hmm.
Rym: I'm curious what that dick looked like because that's one of the people who's like a developer on Lego universe.
Rym: They had to have some really high quality dick building capabilities.
Rym: this is all just fascinating and I guess the moral is if you ever make an online game like if I ever make one I'm just gonna say if you're under 13 You're not allowed to play and I'm sure that you're actually born on January 1st 1901 and everything will be
Scott: fine.
Scott: I'm just gonna put my servers in some other country.
Scott: Oh, yeah, that's oh and then not get bother getting it rated by the ESRB.
Scott: You just have a game.
Rym: Yeah But seriously Copa is one of the most.
Rym: like we talked about laws that affect people a lot more and a lot more dangerous Copa is just a bad law.
Scott: I mean you can just go to a porn site.
Scott: This is are you 18?
Scott: you say yes, and then you see porn.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So really everyone under the age of 13 Go actually go on January 1st, 1901.
Scott: you go on Steam and there's a game rated You know a oh and this scene doesn't have a OA games, but game rated M and they're like, what's your birthday?
Scott: My birthday is 1934.
Scott: Well, you can see this game now.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: All right I do but at first I'm gonna ask you some questions.
Scott: All right Rym.
Scott: Oh, here's a quiz.
Scott: Oh, can you sing for me a Song or hum or whistle or whatever a song from the soundtrack of Star Wars?
Rym: Okay, good, you got it for all you.
Rym: I didn't finish anything.
Scott: it's alright you're good enough, right?
Scott: Can you do the same?
Scott: For a song from the soundtrack of any James Bond movie ever?
Rym: Dude, dude.
Rym: Okay good.
Rym: All right.
Scott: Can you do the same for any?
Scott: Any song from the soundtrack of the good the bad and the ugly?
Scott: Oh you just suck.
Rym: yeah, I just think Well, that's easy.
Rym: I'm thinking more like I imagine a sweeping instrumental spread in the background, but I don't have that At any point do.
Scott: Anyway, that's easy.
Rym: one is the point also, I can't whistle the And you didn't want to hear my voice make that sounds.
Scott: Well, anyway, that's really all right you ready?
Scott: here's the one that I do not think you will get.
Scott: okay.
Scott: Sing a song from the soundtrack of any Marvel Universe movie Ironman spider-man's Avengers Captain America's anything I'm doors hulks.
Rym: I Just imagined generic.
Rym: I can't I cannot I can't even think of like a light motif.
Rym: Nope.
Scott: No, you can't.
Scott: and do you know why?
Rym: because they don't use like motifs.
Rym: is that?
Rym: is that what's going on here?
Scott: No But here's a video those posted today from every frame of painting that explains how shit their music is.
Scott: every frame of painting and he Says exactly they go into.
Scott: they start off the video by interviewing people on the street saying can you sing a Star Wars?
Scott: Can you sit and then can you do him?
Scott: Hey, and there's one.
Scott: I actually thought of a Marvel song despite not having seen any of those movies And I was like, oh I thought of one.
Scott: I know it and a guy sings it at the end of the video.
Rym: But Yeah, when I think about it like when I want a lot of movies like I can remember like like Princess Leia has her theme and like all like the Imperial stormtroopers have their theme like things have themes and movies.
Rym: I don't know what Iron Man's theme is.
Scott: He doesn't have.
Rym: but I think the same song the plays when he's fighting.
Scott: this video is fascinating.
Scott: Also, I somewhat disagree with the video.
Scott: I think there's a point that he just doesn't.
Scott: he gets close to making but doesn't make.
Scott: but regardless, you know the video is really interesting and He really shits on.
Scott: you know, modern movies and their soundtracks.
Rym: Yeah Well, you know what?
Rym: The problem is I think a lot of more recent movies often have larger larger soundtracks smaller scores.
Rym: Nope, or no, they have scores that are basically the same as other scores.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Yes But another thing is that I was think for a long time I was like man, they just don't make like symphonic, you know soundtracks or movies.
Scott: these days Every fucking movie has one.
Scott: They're just such garbage that you don't you don't even realize that they're there.
Scott: There's a fantastic unless it's like a Lord of the Rings situation.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Rym: So, there you go watch this that that actually sounds really good.
Rym: I know.
Scott: also it's like, you know, I haven't seen these movies but you know and I don't know if they're good or bad even because I haven't seen them and I don't really want to.
Scott: but if someone's gonna Shit on something.
Scott: I haven't seen that everyone else seems to like that's.
Rym: that's up your alley.
Scott: Yeah, why not?
Rym: Yeah Well think actually think back.
Rym: Final Fantasy 4 & 6 had very good scores Like motifs all you know, the.
Scott: every Final Fantasy has a good score.
Scott: every Final Fantasy Sure every Final Fantasy, yeah, even the shitty ones have good music.
Rym: Well, do you can't do you count American games that had the Final Fantasy brand or only actual Final Fantasy games?
Scott: I mean even Final Fantasy Legend 3 has good music.
Rym: What about Final Fantasy mystic quests?
Scott: I don't remember.
Rym: You don't remember that game because I don't remember the music.
Rym: Yeah that game not good, but I remember they're like.
Rym: You know, it probably is.
Rym: the best soundtrack in modern gaming though is actually undertale.
Rym: Mm-hmm is a full score with It's.
Rym: it's one of my favorite game soundtracks of all time.
Scott: like not portals or portals.
Rym: soundtrack is actually kind of forgettable.
Rym: How many thing from it?
Rym: The voice acting is memorable, but the music is.
Rym: No, yeah that song the theme of the entire series that song Yeah, the one that plays on the radio in the beginning and then you hear at the end with the yeah that song.
Rym: Seriously even if you don't play under tails listen to the soundtrack y'all.
Rym: do the score the score.
Rym: It's not a soundtrack.
Rym: It's a score.
Scott: Yeah, the point is if I'm making a movie You know or anything that has music I'm making the music not suck.
Rym: What was there was that there was a I think it was a college humor video a long time ago where they were like we're gonna make another movie and They get the soundtrack guy in and it's just him like miming what the soundtrack is gonna be like.
Rym: and they go through making like Tenton Burton movies in a row and they all have the exact same soundtrack.
Rym: So in the moment, the book club book was works and great.
Rym: We did the episode It's done.
Rym: the book club now, which Scott is not posted yet is Rebecca.
Rym: Our last panel of the grind at PAX West was successful.
Rym: Hopefully it'll be on YouTube whenever I get a chance to actually edit that together.
Rym: We don't have any conventions until magfest.
Rym: Finally a break.
Rym: That means we're gonna be up in all our other content cuz.
Rym: finally I don't have all these like big things hanging over my head.
Rym: No more ConnectiCon no more packs for a while.
Scott: All right, we're gonna make our own convention.
Rym: Uh, yeah, we're gonna do that, but that's not gonna be till 2018.
Rym: Mm-hmm 2017 is the planning year.
Rym: Mm-hmm Yeah, what else?
Rym: I don't think we have anything else going on.
Rym: It's just watch all our internet stuff because Scott's YouTube channel my YouTube channel All our stuff is gonna have a lot more stuff in the coming months.
Rym: So I saw a bunch of people on Twitter just you know for a week or so like saying something something Captain sonar and they post a picture and the picture they always posted was the one.
Rym: I just pulled it right here And it shows like these little charge-up dials and a picture of a submarine.
Scott: Well, my friend my friend Chris who plays netrunner is moving to Seattle But is moving like on Wednesday and wasn't able to move before packs.
Scott: He told me about captain sonar and I said that game sounds amazing.
Scott: and then we got to packs there.
Scott: It was so he played it at packs and then just yesterday I was in the game store for a netrunner tournament and I was telling you know We're just chatting it up before the tournament.
Scott: I said, yeah, this is great game.
Scott: I played a packs captain sonar and everyone was like, oh that sounds awesome.
Scott: And then I lost.
Scott: so I had to buy in the round two.
Scott: And then I walked around the store just looking around and there captain sonar was for 50 bucks and I said Well, I could buy this and we can play it like right the fuck.
Scott: after this netrunner tournament everybody.
Scott: Yeah, as long as they get Rym to pay for it Which I did because Scott said hey they got it and I went on Amazon and it was $104 on Amazon is 50 bucks at the store and I had store credit.
Scott: So I'll charge you slightly less because it's a used once copy of that on Amazon.
Rym: Well, I didn't buy the captain sonar.
Rym: I saw fresh fish for $38 and I saw deep-sea adventure for like 11.
Rym: So I bought both of those.
Scott: But yeah, so captain sonar this game.
Scott: So in the world of games that are co-op, right?
Scott: We have a lot of problems.
Scott: For example, we got pandemic.
Scott: where the pandemic problem is is just basically backing.
Scott: Yeah It's a solitaire game and you just happen to unofficially divide the work between four people and there isn't really any Actual separation because you can share all the information.
Scott: Yeah, and the rules are bullshit, whatever.
Rym: I think we're fine.
Rym: Yeah, we've talked about this.
Scott: You've got the traitor kind where it's bullshit because obviously the traitor isn't.
Scott: it then becomes pandemic.
Scott: You've got the pandemic legacy, I guess slightly better than regular pandemic.
Rym: I played more a role-playing game slash experience, which is fine.
Scott: Yeah game puzzle solving part is not really the problem with those games.
Rym: They don't have a lot of replay value by design.
Rym: Yeah So got the beautiful Hanabi style where you're forced not to share information and it or there are strict rules around sharing information Which itself is the core of the game.
Scott: Yes You've got the real-time kind the space alert in the x-com where the real-time nature of it forces you to co-op because no one Can do all that work in such a short amount of time.
Rym: But that real time has to be facilitated by a third party be it an app a recording or a human.
Scott: Yeah, you got the versus kind where there's a Dracula right fury Dracula where there's a person you're up against.
Scott: So four people are co-oping against one person on teams, but furry of Dracula has problems with the combat parts.
Rym: Part is good Yeah No and also that genre of like a bunch of people versus one person.
Rym: that's basically just Facilitated gaming and it's actually that's really the same as hero quest in some ways and that genre is fine.
Rym: It's just any individual implementation of it might be good or bad
Scott: but captain sonar brings to the table something that is very rare even with all the board games in the world and that is Team versus team two teams going against each other just like football or any other sport.
Rym: on for real time and the real For and it's real time, but the thing is I heard that and I thought that's cool.
Rym: But then when I was told that not only is it foreign for real time You do not need a facilitator.
Rym: The game is self facilitating and there is no app or anything.
Scott: Yep It's just four on four and that's it.
Rym: And then I said what the fuck?
Rym: How do you do that?
Rym: And that's because the people who made this game are brilliant.
Scott: Let me tell you how this shit works.
Scott: So first of all, you're paying 50 bucks and there's not a lot of stuff in the box.
Scott: You can make this game.
Scott: You don't need to buy it.
Rym: Yes I'd say buy it because like this game design is legit.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, yeah, the game design is legit.
Scott: Also, you really want to make like some sort of shield wall to separate four people from four other people.
Rym: We're on all the boards and all that stuff comes with dry erase markers.
Scott: They're nice, even though they're shitty by replacements on Amazon.
Scott: Figure out which ones are best on Amazon or probably the ones you would use in an overhead Projector those guys.
Rym: Yeah, that kind exactly.
Rym: Yeah, you're writing on that transparency if you're there exactly.
Scott: So here's how this works.
Scott: each team of four is on a submarine in the water.
Rym: There's some backstory whatever.
Rym: you don't like you don't care about that and you don't like each other.
Scott: you have the same map and You say the captain's on each team say dive And you die and then the game begins.
Scott: once everyone dives and here's how it works.
Scott: The captain chooses any starting location on the map.
Scott: That's not on land because you're a fucking submarine.
Rym: Yeah, so both sides you're looking at this just map.
Scott: then You have on each team.
Scott: You have the captain.
Scott: the captain says head North or head east or head south or head west because the grid and the captain said when you move you have to say it Loud.
Scott: so everyone hears right your team and the other team.
Scott: So the person on the other team They don't know where you started, but they know you just headed north.
Scott: So on there There's a radio operator and the radio operator.
Scott: This is that.
Rym: this is what really makes the game.
Scott: this is really the radio operators only job is to listen to the opponent's captain and Draw a line north because he headed north and then draw a line east when they head east so they know the path you took.
Rym: So the radio operator is trying to figure out where the other sub is.
Rym: based on all this information they're overhearing right and they're on.
Rym: all they do is solve the puzzle or figure it out and Give the basically consult with the captain and be like captain.
Rym: They're either here or here captain.
Rym: I think they're going this way and the captain is Synthesizing their information like Scott.
Rym: Where do you think they are?
Rym: I'm gonna start heading north.
Rym: Cool Yeah, and you're also working with engineering and all the other people talk about those people in a second.
Scott: But the radio operator has a transparency and a map.
Scott: the captain has a map that there's a drawing on where they really literally are.
Rym: You can play as fast as you want.
Rym: I could be like head north head north head north head north head north.
Rym: That's okay.
Scott: Well, you can't necessarily do that either because you can until no you can't.
Scott: so anyway the Radio opera.
Scott: I played this game recently.
Scott: Let me explain it cuz you don't know.
Scott: you don't know.
Scott: I read the rules.
Scott: You didn't read the rule book actually did read the rules.
Scott: Okay, anyway the radio operator has a transparency and a map that it moved the transparency around.
Scott: you also can't move and bump Into your own trail.
Scott: It's like Tron.
Scott: You can't hear your motor.
Scott: So your submarine has a laser coming out the back.
Scott: That's creating a wall.
Scott: Yeah cannot bump into your own wall.
Scott: You can bump into the other team's wall Yeah, because you don't even know.
Scott: you don't even know where it is.
Rym: Yeah bump into the wall can't bump in the land.
Scott: You can't go like you can't go east southwest north.
Scott: That's an illegal move because you just bumped into yourself right your trail and you can surface and make it go away.
Scott: But whatever that's not important.
Rym: servicing is super fun.
Rym: We'll talk about that a bit.
Scott: So then you've got the first mate.
Scott: now if you only have three on three the captain is also the first mate.
Scott: and what the first mate does?
Scott: every time they move they Charge a system and a little bit and they can charge all these different systems that do different things.
Scott: There's the sonar and drone systems which you can use to help find the opponent sub.
Scott: Yep There's the silent running system the silent system which lets you move secretly As a number of spaces for in any of the four directions except for backwards because you that you'll bump into your own trail.
Scott: Yeah, and there's the weapon systems the mine and the torpedo which you can charge up and there's an optional six thing for like.
Rym: That's only.
Scott: no that's only on map five.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: That's the hardest map.
Scott: There's the scenario.
Scott: thing that you charge up and use it does something special, but what we didn't enter played with it.
Rym: So I already read online a lot of people once they played the game a lot They make up their own thing.
Rym: You have to make up your own map because but basically you that's the spot where you can charge up something weird If you made a custom scenario.
Scott: also the map one is the only map I've played on and it's a baby map.
Scott: We gotta gotta go to map B real quick.
Scott: Yeah Once you once you know how to play anyway the the final person is the engineer and the engineer has this picture of the submarine kind of.
Scott: and There's a main circuit and there's a nuclear reactor and every time you move There's they have to cross off something on this sheet.
Rym: Yeah shit breaks every time you move.
Scott: So if you move north they have to pick something in the north Rectangle and remove it either something in the reactor or something in the main circuit.
Scott: And now let's say they remove like the weapon system in the North's area.
Rym: Well, you can't use your weapon systems Yep, so you get into situations where if the captain's not paying attention I'll be like halt fire torpedo and they're like, nope Not some of the things in the main circuit are connected to each other.
Scott: So if you hit all four things that are connected to each other by a line They all clear.
Scott: so you can go north north northeast and those are all connected to each other.
Scott: So if you do north north northeast those all then get erased and now you're good to use some sort of equipment.
Scott: All right, one of the things that the first mate is charging up.
Scott: You can also clear off your reactor things, but those are permanently removed Until you surface.
Scott: so good luck with that.
Scott: And if you fuck up your sub if you exam if you cross off every less your north area on your little sheet only has So many circle bits.
Scott: if you cross all of them off a hundred percent you take damage and your submarine only has four hit points And can ever be healed.
Rym: and the best part is the captain just gives orders.
Rym: so if the captain says go north like once you say it and The second is yeah.
Scott: After the captain says north southeast or west both of the people next to him the engineer and the first mate have to say, okay Yeah, if they don't say, okay, you didn't move yet.
Scott: Really?
Scott: Yep, and If they don't say, okay, you can't move again yet, right?
Scott: So you feel like head north and you don't hear two okays then you didn't really move north and you'd not have to discuss with Them.
Scott: Why didn't we move north engineer?
Scott: Yeah engines busted.
Scott: We can't move noise Here.
Rym: she blew us up.
Scott: Yeah We got it.
Scott: We can only move this direction.
Rym: Oh, so you get a lot of chatter Like I was the captain in the one game I played and I kept yelling engineering like hey How much leeway do I have in the east?
Rym: and they'd be like not a lot.
Rym: captain What do you need me to do to heal stuff to go like this?
Rym: I'm looking at where Scott's telling me to go and I'm looking at where engineering is telling me to go The opposite directions.
Scott: so every time I played I mean I'm gonna go through all the rules of exactly how everything works.
Scott: But the every time I played this so far were just three times.
Scott: It's everyone sort of used the same strategy, which I now only at the end of the third game I realized might not be the best strategy.
Rym: I'm curious what you're gonna say there because I came up with what I think is a decent strategy.
Scott: But also your strategies are different because on map a it's really easy to figure out where people are because there's so many islands.
Scott: Yeah on the harder maps is a lot less islands.
Scott: It's a lot harder to.
Scott: they could be anywhere, right?
Scott: But basically we were playing such that we're moving fast as fast as we could because moving is the only way to charge stuff.
Scott: Uh, right charging all kinds of stuff up and then trying to use the sonar and drone systems to find the opponent.
Scott: We found them easily because the map has a lot of islands on it.
Scott: Yep, and they were moving a lot.
Scott: when someone moves a lot It's easy to find them because they have a big old trail that only fits in certain places on the map.
Scott: They had a little trail.
Scott: It's hard.
Scott: It could be anywhere.
Rym: Well, it's funny.
Rym: we both in the first game both subs kind of went near each other and try to put mines and basically the Same place.
Scott: Yeah, but mines don't set off when someone goes near them.
Scott: They set off remote their remote triggered mines.
Rym: the heck have to raise his hand.
Rym: is like we're detonating the mine at this location.
Scott: Are you?
Scott: are you near it?
Scott: Yeah, we're near it shit or oh, no, we're nowhere near there.
Rym: Yeah, and if you detonate it near yourself, well, yeah, you can hurt yourself anyway.
Scott: So yeah, so we everyone moved fast found each other quickly and then it was free was just a race to see who could shoot the other Submarine with torpedoes first.
Scott: and I've won all three games I played.
Scott: but I think a better move is to move a little bit charge up some stuff and then just silent to sit there.
Rym: Yeah, put
Scott: mines out, you know Make sure these move slowly so they can't find you, you know use silence a lot like drop a mine silence drop a mine Silence and move a little bit and be really mysterious and stealthy and then like surface because they have no clue where you are.
Scott: So you can surface safely.
Scott: when you surface they know what sector you're in.
Scott: And then right after you're done surfacing silence move, right?
Scott: They can't you know and leave so many mines around right and then the radio operator will be like captain.
Scott: I think they're near one of our mines and set it off and this way you can't really get torpedoed.
Scott: It's hard for them to find you Right and you just make yours your sub harder to find than their sub.
Scott: But then even if they do the same thing as you you just had to do it better.
Rym: But then you do run the risk because if you're moving more slowly Meaning you have more time to consult and like come up with the strategy.
Rym: The other sub has the exact same opportunity now.
Rym: Yeah If you suddenly start moving fast They got to keep up.
Rym: like if you're the radio operator and you like you flub it or you fuck it up Your subs in a lot of trouble.
Scott: now, maybe maybe not, you know Even if you fuck up a little bit Usually you can get still really figure out where they are.
Rym: There's one mechanic that I think is super fun.
Rym: where if you surface the there's a task you have to do the rule for yourself.
Rym: Alright, this is cool.
Rym: pencils down.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So if Scott's the radio operator and I surface is the captain The other subs moving and Scott's not allowed to write anything down.
Scott: I thought you are allowed to keep tracking.
Rym: you can listen to it, but his pencils down.
Scott: I didn't read that in the rule book.
Rym: That's how the Facilitator who taught us the game was very specific.
Rym: Everyone has to put their pencil down until everyone completes their task.
Scott: I don't remember.
Scott: I've never put my pencil down while the except for while doing the thing anyway.
Scott: so when you surface the engineer takes on their sheet.
Scott: at the top is a picture of a submarine with four sections and That each section has a white outline and you have to draw in that white outline without touching the edges without touching the edges.
Scott: sort of like You know one of those games where you have like a metal ring on a stick and you're trying to move it around the wire Without touching the wire.
Scott: Yeah And then you initial it and your whole team has to initial a section each.
Scott: if you have three players Someone does two sections then you show this to the enemy engineer.
Scott: They look at it and verify it that you did it properly without messing up.
Scott: And if they say you did a good job Because they shouldn't be assholes and say you did a bad job when you didn't actually mess up Then they say okay, and now you can say dive and play again
Rym: Yep, but the other sub can keep doing stuff while you finish unless
Scott: they're also trying to surface.
Scott: But yeah, and they know it's second announce what sector you're servicing in but you don't announce your exact location.
Scott: So it's not like you're just dead.
Scott: Plus you hopefully do this when they're far away and can't really do anything to you.
Rym: Observe it.
Rym: like in the first game we played the other sub was forced to surface because they had a bunch of breakdowns.
Scott: Well, it's like they can't.
Scott: you can't go back on your snake, right?
Scott: So let's say for example you go like south east south west.
Scott: Now you can't go north and you can't go east and maybe there's an island to your south.
Scott: You can only go west again, but maybe you're out of West's.
Scott: So your choice is to go west and damage yourself or Surface.
Scott: all right, and maybe you already have three damage.
Scott: You can't go west and damage yourself.
Rym: You have to serve Cannot use their pens for anything.
Scott: That's new.
Rym: Okay, so So when I played it the first time what cuz?
Rym: yeah, you were doing the radio operators cuz I kept it.
Scott: I kept radio operating when we were certain.
Scott: Oh, you're cheating then.
Scott: Oh, no, wait, we didn't surface ever.
Rym: Yeah, we never surface or fine.
Rym: But yesterday when we played yeah So they surface and I looked at my engineer because they played the game a bunch already And I was like should we go for it?
Rym: and they were like go and I was like North North East.
Scott: We're just like moved as fast to charge it to our Peter.
Scott: You only needed three movements.
Scott: So we went move move move.
Scott: Shoot move move.
Scott: Shoot done.
Scott: If you knew the whole it only hurt them because we knew exactly the spot they were on.
Scott: we had shot them.
Scott: Then they started servicing.
Scott: then we just went move move move shoot and they were dead.
Rym: Yeah, we moved as fast as we could.
Scott: they didn't want to serve us.
Scott: He just had no choice.
Scott: you want to serve us when no one can know where you are.
Rym: Yep Exactly, so if the other ones also surfaced then I guess you can get away with it for a little while.
Scott: I think they really.
Scott: the only flaw in this game is that I think it can be fucked up.
Scott: You can get it messed up if like you can't you know, there's some sort of miscommunications or right?
Scott: Because no one's like watching you and verifying you only charge the right number.
Rym: It's like you could just cheat But a clever person would notice right and the game really requires everyone to be in the spirit of let's not cheat.
Scott: guys You know, you can't like just saying no when they drew the outline properly, yeah stuff like that, you know.
Scott: But it's like if you're going fast, there's a lot of opportunity for mistakes.
Rym: You'd need a lot of discipline and I think the way I would get around that is irrespective of how the rules are actually written.
Rym: When I teach it to people I'm gonna come I'm gonna use a very specific lexicon and require it of everyone Just to make it clear.
Rym: and I think it's something like when the cabin wants to move they have to say like set a course North.
Scott: no, it actually says in the rule book.
Scott: You have to say head north head north.
Scott: That's what it says in the rule book.
Rym: Yeah, I'm saying you must say it.
Rym: I think head is enough.
Scott: You just don't say it more than once and the other people have to see.
Scott: the rule book is very explicit about this.
Scott: We just weren't told that the one time we played at PAX.
Scott: I read the rule book yesterday.
Scott: It's very explicit.
Scott: You must say head north if you just say north then it doesn't mean shit.
Scott: You have to say head north and your engineer and first mate have to say, okay Otherwise, you didn't move anywhere.
Scott: All right, that's super explicit.
Scott: You don't need to know what.
Rym: he also said To me after we were talking about the game because actually I told him my idea of say set a course instead and he said That's way better.
Rym: because he said that they ran into that problem a lot.
Scott: Yeah, because they didn't tell people to say head They said well now we were just playing like North North East.
Rym: No, he said it was any problem with that partly because a lot of the people who played were kind of mumbling nerds.
Scott: That's also a problem.
Scott: You have to be loud and clear.
Rym: but the other suggestion that he had that he said worked really well.
Rym: If you didn't want to make it a longer phrase to make it very explicit was have a rule.
Rym: Does that tell the group?
Rym: the captain has to look at the radio operator and like point at them or make some gesture when they?
Rym: Say it.
Scott: Yeah, you know something whatever you can do, right?
Rym: It doesn't really matter.
Rym: and just be as long as you're a hundred percent consistent Then the other team has no excuse.
Scott: it effectively doesn't matter but the rule book isn't flawed.
Scott: The rule book is not enough list.
Scott: so the rule book is fine and you know just had to be absolutely clear when you move and Versus when someone is just like saying the word north for some other reason because they're discussing where should we?
Scott: Like should we move west?
Scott: Yeah, I think we should move west if the other team accidentally thinks you moved west.
Rym: No, another guy I was talking to in the room after we played the first time.
Rym: they were at packs.
Rym: they were.
Rym: they were talking to how in a previous game the other sub stop moving and The captain started talking to the radio operator about a plan.
Rym: So he just jotted down their plan because he was listening as the radio operator.
Rym: I know.
Scott: see I mean so that's when you play the game the first few times, right?
Scott: You're playing a busy baby mode, but you're not actually playing baby mode.
Scott: rules other than the other than the math.
Rym: Yeah, don't play the baby actual baby mode.
Rym: Everyone says it's the turn-based mode doesn't exist.
Scott: Yeah, don't look on the other side of your map.
Scott: It's like that CD in D&D third edition when it came out when we played Basically, if the radio operators like got something wrong on the path We would stop and like have the captain like reiterate the path they took so that they could correct the radio operators map.
Scott: But in reality when you play this game for serious with eight people who know what they're doing you don't do that shit Right.
Scott: The radio operator is your role-playing the existence of like a real radio.
Scott: You're under stress.
Rym: if the other team's moving fast and the captain's yelling at you You're like miss an order and well that sucks right.
Scott: like so, you know a radio isn't always loud and clear, right?
Scott: You might not know, you know get everything coming in clearly right when you put your pencil down to surface You might not remember everything.
Scott: So you're you know, you have to find them despite the radio not being perfect Yeah, and that aspect of it actually the radio operator.
Scott: we have to find a balance between it's bullshit.
Scott: You were being quiet.
Scott: We couldn't hear you.
Scott: You're just trying to scam the radio operator.
Scott: and no We actually don't want this to absolutely be perfect.
Scott: Which is there should be some noise on and interference on the radio jamming and whatnot.
Rym: but it's easily solved by just following the rules explicitly and you know loud and clear voice and use the Specific terminology that is required of you for your role.
Scott: The flaw in this game is it's hard to get eight competent people in one place who are dedicated.
Scott: and well if you get those Eight people.
Scott: Why are you playing a tabletop RPG?
Rym: You can get away with well one.
Rym: this takes way less time than tabletop It does and it takes less preparation.
Scott: But and you still need eight quality the four rolls, right?
Rym: The radio operator is the hardest and the most stressful.
Scott: They can't do anything else.
Rym: Yeah, the captain is the second hardest because you might just kill everybody like.
Rym: it's your fault if you mess up.
Rym: the other two roles Are way easier.
Rym: They're still fun.
Rym: They're like.
Rym: they're not like the game is set up to where.
Scott: let's say you played a bunch of first mate is definitely the easiest job Because all the first mate does is basically charge up systems.
Scott: But the first mate.
Scott: I think the reason that the first mate exists and has such a simple job Is that they can do a lot of the thinking right?
Scott: It's part of the role-playing part.
Rym: is you know of actually being in a submarine Captain where mines are charged to place them somewhere, right?
Scott: The first mate advises the captain and like thinks, you know Cuz you need the captain is so harried dealing with all this shit coming right at them that you need that one job That's light so that that person can sort of you know help with.
Scott: you know, what's going on?
Rym: fact in our game our my first mate was actually Consulting with engineering and then he was actually talking to me.
Rym: So engineering didn't talk to me except when I gave all you know, go ahead north.
Rym: Okay?
Rym: Yeah, because otherwise he was dealing with his own shit of trying to figure out a course.
Rym: So they would like they worked out a system with it, but since this game is real time.
Scott: There is no Requirement whatsoever for the pace at which you move.
Scott: you could just not move and just like get up get with your team and put Your heads together and huddle and discuss things for like minutes if you
Rym: want and then suddenly the like you see both subs are quietly I
Scott: mean your
Rym: mid one subs like head north and then all shit breaks out,
Scott: right?
Scott: It's like suddenly you have to pay attention to them.
Scott: Yeah Like you might just be quietly discussing things and not even moving and then the other team is like stop Because whenever you use an ability you have to stop the game.
Rym: I think you say halt.
Scott: Yeah, you say stop halt whatever.
Scott: and then they're like stop.
Scott: We're firing a torpedo at i9 and it's like oh Shit, how did you know?
Scott: How did you know?
Rym: But because there's there's sort of four levels of roles two stressful ones and two much less stress like way less stressful.
Scott: The engineering one is slightly stressful.
Rym: Yeah Well, especially because the captain might not listen to you.
Rym: if you're like captain We can't go east anymore.
Rym: Yeah, the captain is like head east again.
Scott: You're like, well, the first mate is the easy job.
Rym: Yeah, but it's good because say you play the game three times in a row Like you're out of your like hanging out.
Scott: change change up the roles change.
Rym: Yeah, cuz after if you do the captain and then the radio operator your brain needs a break.
Rym: Game is like I'm not kidding.
Scott: You don't want to be a radio operator again.
Scott: You know want to go be the first mate.
Rym: I would not want to be the captain two times in a row.
Rym: That shit is real hard.
Scott: Yep yeah, if you got if you're the kind of person who plays tabletop games has a big enough table and Has eight people this is a must-buy game even at the retail price of $50.
Scott: If you are a gaming tabletop gaming convention, you are a convention or a library of games.
Scott: This is a must-get game in your library.
Scott: If you're if you go to meetups, right, you know, it must get games.
Rym: This is a game where I think most people will only experience it at conventions.
Rym: Like you go to PAX someone comes over to the table and says hey, we're playing this.
Rym: I got it from the library.
Scott: Yep, I'd like to play it like, you know and more harder maps and you know what I like to see this time on it.
Rym: This should be the first round of the megathon finale of packs or the megathon at PAX East.
Scott: Yeah you could have a bunch of games and just all the winning teams continue all the losing because you can divide any multiple of people in half by using this game
Rym: and because the game mechanics are so streamlined and simple the game is right for modding like if you Play this game to the point that like
Scott: you've
Rym: all memorized the engineering So, you know movement patterns to clear stuff and you're like super a game.
Rym: just modify it because it doesn't matter It's not like it's secret.
Rym: You just both teams agree like let's make up a mod.
Rym: you make a mod you do something with the scenario and then you just Play that man.
Scott: I mean you just make new maps.
Scott: really in that.
Scott: Yeah, that makes it exciting enough just changing the map like make a map where there's a nuke or something.
Scott: You can make a bigger map.
Scott: you could make a smaller map.
Scott: you could make you know Something else.
Rym: you can even use.
Rym: this say you're if you were playing like a naval RPG or some nonsense.
Scott: There's a map.
Scott: There's a map that comes with it that where all the water is ice and you can only surface in certain parts And if you surface under the ice and smash into it you take damage.
Scott: Yeah, right It's like you just come up with something like that Like oh there's a you know, everyone has a boat.
Scott: that also.
Scott: but you can just go crazy.
Rym: or you've both got intelligence.
Rym: You've got to get to a port on the opposite side.
Scott: Yeah, sure, whatever.
Scott: Yeah, but that would be you can't?
Scott: I don't think you have a victory condition besides finding the other sub.
Scott: Yeah, I think you could and you just go to the other side and wind like our game over now.
Rym: But maybe yeah, so I know they're doing that.
Rym: So I go over to the other side like there's one port on the square and I put a mine.
Scott: How do you know?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, how do you know when they're there?
Scott: It's like, you know, well, I hear I'm moving.
Scott: One mine doesn't kill him either.
Rym: Yeah, I'm there too.
Rym: Well, I'm gonna wait.
Scott: I think you have to always.
Scott: the objective always has to be.
Rym: There are ways to play this game.
Rym: once you've played it out you can just mod it forever because it's gonna have expansions for sure.
Scott: Yeah, the expansion is gonna come with like more boards.
Scott: Yeah, like replacement boards and all sorts of stuff.
Scott: It's definitely coming.
Rym: This was probably the most surprising game to me at all effects.
Rym: The
Scott: thing is you're spending 50 bucks though for a bunch of cardboard boards that are really thin and you can dry erase on them to transparency sheets Some thick boards that just have sort of artwork on them that used to separate your team from the other team Yep, and a pile of crappy dry erase markers that the racers built in.
Scott: that are really shitty, but they get the job done.
Scott: That's all you're getting in and the rule book.
Scott: That's all you're getting.
Rym: You're not getting anything else in this box Which like I said, I'm fine with in this case.
Scott: It's a really big box to rebox this shit.
Rym: Yeah, well the funny thing is this packs for whatever reason it PAX West.
Rym: We played a lot of co-op II games and a lot of shared space games like way more than ever.
Rym: This was one of many and we'll be talking about him.
Rym: But this one this was my favorite game I had not yet played at PAX and the thing is my second favorite one is deep-sea adventure Which is also about a submarine, but it's not co-op II know it.
Scott: Well, it's it's.
Scott: It's.
Rym: it's like yeah, it's the opposite of co-op competitive.
Rym: No, but you share a space and you're just fucking each other in that space.
Scott: I mean you share a space in T&E and you're fucking each other in that space.
Rym: Yeah You're sharing oxygen and if you go deep That game we'll talk about in a future show.
Rym: It's super good.
Rym: It's super cheap.
Scott: So everyone with friends get captain sonar.
Scott: everyone without friends who can't play captain sonar cry.
Rym: I am definitely bringing captain sonar to magfest.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It might be the only captain sonar at magfest.
Rym: Yeah that magfest especially because we have the suite we're gonna play a lot of captain sonar.
Rym: I think at magfest once people know how to play it like I can walk away and they'll just play it.
Scott: I don't want to walk away.
Scott: I want people to play it so I can play it.
Rym: I think we're gonna have more than eight people who want to play it.
Scott: Well, that's their problem.
Rym: We go Scott.
Rym: We got to form the all-pro team at magfest.
Scott: Oh, you want to make a submarine?
Rym: That's like a civil submarine.
Scott: It's like me you two smart people.
Rym: Yeah, like you me you Alex Pete like that's unbeatable.
Rym: Scott Johnson could be good too.
Rym: Maybe I think it'd be good.
Rym: You're about to disparage Scott Johnson.
Scott: I mean the thing is while Scott Johnson might be okay this game, especially if this team Scott How fun would it be to blow up the submarine with captain Scott Johnson on it?
Rym: Yeah You know what he does in overwatch.
Rym: So if someone's in a group like you can join like we can group up and join games together.
Rym: But say someone else is already in a group or already in a game You can just join that game as a spectator and in the next game or when someone quits it puts you on the opposite side.
Rym: So you can see Scott Johnson playing and join his game and kill him.
Rym: Uh-huh, it's.
Rym: he's been doing that a lot and it's really funny like I'll be playing and suddenly I get killed by Scott.
Rym: I'm like Scott's in this game.
Rym: You son of a bitch.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott special Thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night.
Scott: the patrons
Rym: for this episode of GeekNights in order of the amount of money They give us on a continuing basis above $5 are Alan Joyce, Rebecca Dunn, Nicholas Brando, Logan Stafford, Heidi McNichol, Amanda Duchette, James David White, Christian Koops, Construction Noises, MyStady.com, William Isenrose, Jeremy Miner, Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn Rochelle Montanona, TheRainbowInTheDark, Aaron Cerise, Brian Fisher, Sailor Vista, JailFriedPork, Iggy Kid, Matthew Smith, Don Schleich, Jar Toffish, and Joe Shiro, Joe Star, Tyler Eller, Sean Yeager, Sam Cordray, Clinton Walton, Ren from New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, Drew Openlander, RareLaval, Brian Cidroni, Finn Eric Silveraude, The Rural Juror, Chris Midkiff, Chris Knox, Daniel Redman, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: Like I said, I was delayed by Utah.
Rym: We were delayed by PAX.
Rym: We're finally back.
Rym: Recorded this episode on Monday a little bit early.
Rym: I think I gave it to you patrons a little bit early just as a thank you and we are now as of this week Resuming our normal course of operations more content more streaming all that stuff.
Rym: So stay tuned for us catching up on everything.
Rym: and now I leave you with one ping only.
Scott: Re-verify our range to target one ping only.
Scott: Captain I just Give me a ping Vasily One ping only place I kept.