Rym: So, quite some time ago, I was biking home from work and I stopped and actually took a picture of it on my cell phone because there was a gigantic horse-headed man painted on a wall in Williamsburg.
Emily: And he was like sexy pose, right?
Emily: It was like he was mostly nude and it looked like an underwear ad but with this cartoon horse and we're almost like, "I remember you tweeted about
Emily: it.".
Rym: Well, first I messaged it directly at Adam and I was like, "Hey
Rym: there.".
Rym: Because it said, "Hey there," like, "Hey," like, "Horses eat
Rym: hay.".
Emily: Yeah, and so you were just like, and you know, it's the kind of thing that's basically like weird shit that's Rims aesthetic, just like bizarre furry stuff.
Rym: I mean, I like bizarre furry stuff, skeletons.
Emily: Bojack doesn't have any skeletons, but it does have a lot of bizarre furry stuff.
Rym: Sort of though, because it's basically, so if I had to describe, so Bojack...
Emily: Anthropomorphic animals, you know, like we said during the Zootopia review.
Rym: It's more like Californication, but half the people are animals.
Emily: Have you watched Californication?
Emily: I was like, "How do you know what it's like if you haven't seen the
Emily: show?".
Rym: I saw some bits of it just because you see things, but eh.
Rym: It was not the kind of show I expected I would care about.
Emily: It's the quintessential, you know, the tainted life of Hollywood celebrities down and out.
Rym: But I don't, because we started watching Bojack like pretty early after it actually came out and I don't remember who recommended it to us.
Emily: Cat and Carl.
Emily: I know for a fact it was our friends Cat and Carl, because Carl, he likes a lot of comedy stuff.
Emily: He's a comedian, so he's always recommending comedy shows and stuff like that.
Emily: And so I was over at their house and they're like, "Let's put on that Netflix
Emily: show.".
Emily: And I watch a few episodes, and they were early episodes, right?
Emily: And I was like, "Haha, this is actually pretty funny.
Emily: This is better than I expected it to
Emily: be.".
Rym: Honestly, it was funny, but it was also kind of like it's a typical four adults American cartoon where everything's kind of vulgar and gross and a little bit weird.
Emily: Yeah, it was kind of like, "Oh wow, it's a cartoon, but they're talking about sex.
Emily: Oh, let's be
Emily: edgy.".
Emily: And I was like, "Oh, this is
Emily: good.".
Rym: And that was juxtaposed with just really obvious and really low-hanging fruit animal puns everywhere and animal jokes.
Emily: But even early episodes, I was like, "This is
Emily: watchable.".
Emily: And I actually got you to watch it.
Emily: I was like, "Hey, we don't have anything to watch tonight.
Emily: Let's just put on this show I saw over at
Emily: Cat's.".
Rym: Yeah, we watched an episode, it was okay, and then we watched another episode a few days later and it was okay.
Rym: And it really quickly happened.
Emily: It changes.
Emily: Halfway through the first season, it really takes a turn and you're like,
Emily: "Whoa.".
Emily: A few episodes will end and it kind of creeps up on you, and you're like, "I didn't expect it to go there and get quite that
Emily: dark.".
Rym: The first season was a bunch of, "Wow, I didn't think it would get that dark.
Rym: Whoa, what's the show really
Rym: about?".
Rym: And then season two was just this steam train to hell.
Emily: It is a hard show to watch.
Emily: I would not recommend this show to anybody who is... Yeah, exactly.
Rym: This show, really, it's about a depressed, rich celebrity who's not really a celebrity anymore, who is kind of a toxic person, and one by one he just poisons and ruins everyone around him who doesn't abandon him.
Emily: I would say it's a show about failure.
Emily: That's really what it's about.
Emily: It's like people failing to communicate, people failing in their careers, people failing in their relationships, all different ways in which people fail and...
Rym: But they're all rolled up into basically one person failing.
Rym: Everyone else fails and also succeeds and lives a more reasonable life, and he just either always fails or fails and causes other people around him to fail, and when he does succeed, he treats it like a failure.
Emily: Yeah, he can't be happy at his successes.
Emily: He has this kind of toxic thinking that doesn't allow him to... Princess Carolyn says at one time, "I could say ten nice things about you and one bad thing, and you would always focus on that one bad
Emily: thing.".
Rym: I think what Todd said in season three was a little more on the nose, though.
Emily: Oh, my God.
Emily: I don't even want to go into his monologue, because his monologue is like... A lot of times, the end of the show, it's kind of like Rick and Morty.
Emily: Rick and Morty was another show where it started out, and I was like, "Haha.
Emily: Oh, okay.
Emily: This is edgy adult
Emily: animation.".
Rym: And then they'll play the sad song.
Emily: The sad song at the credits, and the part right before the credits just hits you really hard, and you're like, "That's where they're ending it?
Emily: Oh, my God.
Emily: Fuck.
Emily: That's pretty
Emily: harsh.".
Rym: Of course, at least they set a precedent, because even an episode that didn't have that serious plot would still end kind of suddenly like, "Yay!
Emily: Roll the
Emily: credits!".
Emily: The end.
Rym: Yeah, but... But this show is more... The episodes pretty much always end on either a kind of pointed joke or a very pregnant moment in Bojack ruining everything around him.
Rym: Well, sometimes they... One episode, literally.
Rym: Motherfucker.
Emily: Well, they end very melancholy in a lot of cases.
Emily: Sometimes the plot threads have been wrapped up, but not necessarily in a happy ending sort of way.
Emily: Or they're left hanging.
Emily: It's almost like a cliffhanger, but not a high-intensity cliffhanger.
Emily: A kind of like, "Oh, what's going to happen
Emily: now?".
Emily: kind of cliffhanger.
Emily: Like, "Oh, it's just going to get worse from here, isn't
Emily: it?".
Rym: I think almost every episode in season three ends with both of us saying,
Rym: "Yeesh.".
Emily: It's not rock bottom yet.
Rym: So, I'm glad we waited until we're pretty much almost all the way through the third season.
Rym: In fact, the episode we just watched, I think it ended on the lowest point.
Rym: the show has ended yet.
Emily: But it was a really good scene, too.
Rym: It was a really good episode, and in fact, season three has been hitting it out of the park.
Rym: It's like they're going for an Emmy.
Emily: Yeah, high-concept episodes.
Emily: There was one where he's at a film festival.
Emily: So, you know, it's about an actor.
Emily: And so, a lot of the humor stems from all the Hollywood jokes and the film industry.
Emily: Yeah, Hollywood.
Emily: That's another thing I like about it, is that there's a continuity in it.
Emily: They'll have a throwaway joke, but then that joke will come back later.
Emily: There will be a brand name or something, some character is representing.
Emily: And then that brand name will be used for a joke half a season down the line.
Emily: But yeah, Hollywoo, and the high-paced life of agents, and the stupid personal politics that are involved in the film business.
Emily: But yeah, so he's at a festival underwater.
Emily: And so he's unable to talk to anyone throughout the whole episode.
Emily: And it's actually one of my favorite episodes.
Emily: It's very beautiful.
Emily: It's got good music and stuff.
Emily: But I feel like Season 3 plays a lot more with the form of the episodes and does a lot more stuff, kind of experiments with the format.
Emily: Well, that's it.
Rym: Season 1 was the show sort of finding its feet.
Rym: And if you look at the Rotten Tomatoes or Metacritic stuff, it's 56% for Season 1.
Rym: And it's actually 100% for both 2 and 3.
Emily: Well, it's funny because the AV Club, they reviewed it based on the first few seasons.
Emily: And like I said, the first few -- or not the first few -- Well, originally, didn't they do the first six episodes, I think?
Emily: Yeah, they did the first few episodes.
Emily: Oh, IndieWire.
Rym: IndieWire changed their policy because they realized that they can't review a show just based on -- let's see.
Rym: And they used to always watch the first six episodes.
Rym: They shifted to watching an entire season before they said anything.
Emily: That seems good because, like I said, if you review it based on the merit of the first half of Season 1, you'll be like, "Yeah, this is funny.
Emily: This is
Emily: okay.".
Rym: It's about as funny as the first few episodes of Venture Brothers if I had to compare it to something.
Emily: But Venture Brothers is another one.
Emily: I almost feel like a lot of these animated shows that are targeted at adults, they tend to have the problem where they start out and they go for the low-hanging fruit of shock value because Americans -- Ah, that horse had sex.
Emily: Well, you know, it's like -- or Adventure Brothers.
Rym: Oh, haha, it's -- Brock totally murdered that guy.
Emily: Yeah, it's the sex and violence.
Emily: It's the crude humor.
Emily: And part of it is because it's the taboo of using what is viewed as a children's medium for these adult jokes.
Rym: But both those shows -- and the reason I keep comparing it to Venture Brothers, too, is that Venture Brothers is specifically stated by the creators as being a show about failure.
Emily: Maybe that's where I got that from, and I was thinking, "Yeah, BoJack is a show about
Emily: failure.".
Emily: And then I'm like, "You said the same exact thing about the Venture Brothers, didn't
Emily: you?".
Rym: Yeah, but the creators of the Venture Brothers themselves said that was the overarching milieu of the show, is that these people are failures.
Emily: You know, in some ways, I kind of feel like there are certain parallels between them.
Emily: It's like, you know, washed-up has-been kind of thing.
Emily: And I mean, they're using very different genres.
Emily: One is like, you know, the behind-the-scenes of a celebrity, and the other one is like parroting superhero genre.
Emily: But at the same time, Dr.
Rym: Venture is the washed-up remains of basically a child actor.
Emily: That's what I'm saying.
Emily: The Rusty Venture stuff is actually kind of similar to BoJack, in that they both are constantly referring to this, you know, this golden age.
Emily: These, you know, "Those were my halcyon
Emily: days."
Emily: You know, "I miss my glory days," that kind of thing.
Rym: But then season two of BoJack in particular really took off.
Rym: Season two, the show just found its stride and just was perfect.
Rym: Season two was a very complete and very compelling arc.
Rym: And there's one episode where he just gets on a boat and takes it all the way home.
Rym: Oh, I love that.
Rym: That was the hardest thing to watch in that entire series up to that point.
Rym: No words.
Rym: It was just him on the boat and some music playing, as you sort of processed what just happened in the show.
Emily: So hard with BoJack, because on one hand, you're granted access to kind of how he feels.
Emily: You know, you can see his fantasies sometimes.
Emily: You actually can, to some extent, sympathize with his depression and his sadness and his self-loathing.
Emily: And so, on one hand, you know, you feel bad for BoJack.
Emily: The show is very good.
Emily: It's almost like, you know, when you feel bad for a villain.
Emily: Because in some cases, BoJack does play the villain.
Rym: He fucks people up.
Rym: He's charming enough both to you, the viewer, who's sort of enjoying his escapades.
Emily: And he has pathos.
Emily: He's pathetic.
Rym: But to the characters around him, too, he's charming enough to where people overlook it.
Rym: What does Wanda say?
Rym: "If you're wearing rose-colored glasses, red flags just look like
Rym: flags.".
Rym: But, so, you see, like, you kind of enjoy watching this.
Rym: And at the same time, you kind of forget that he's gonna ruin it.
Rym: He's gonna draw you in, and then he's gonna disappoint you.
Rym: And this happens over and over and over again.
Rym: To the point to where you almost dread watching him interact with anyone by the third season.
Emily: Well, like, you look at Princess Carolyn, right?
Emily: And this is really emblematic of their relationship.
Emily: In that, she's somebody, she's very capable, and she likes to fix problems.
Emily: She views herself as a problem solver.
Emily: And here's Bojack, who, you know, is very appealing to her and seems to need her.
Emily: And yet, you know, despite all her sympathies, time and time again, he just takes and takes and takes.
Emily: And, you know, it gets to the point where it's just like, you can understand why these characters keep giving him the benefit of the doubt and keep helping him.
Emily: But there comes a point where it's like, you know, he's just gonna do it again.
Emily: He's gonna break your heart.
Emily: He's gonna screw you over, you know?
Rym: And I'm gonna be real, like, watching this show.
Emily: And he does it for selfish reasons.
Emily: He's not malicious.
Emily: He's just incredibly, incredibly selfish and damaged.
Rym: It would be difficult to watch this show, and I don't even know if I'd enjoy it that much, if it were just human actors doing this.
Rym: Sort of the fact that it's these animals and people in this sort of weird contrived world with its own rules that are very self-consistent, but the rules are there.
Emily: Like that chicken episode?
Rym: That was so fucked up.
Rym: Yeah, the show goes into dark places with everyone.
Emily: How do people eat meat in this world where there are animals and...
Rym: And the answer in that episode is they eat meat, and that's a big problem.
Emily: And we leave it at that.
Emily: The chickens run in the chicken farms, and so it's like, what?
Rym: Sea World's not a great place either.
Emily: Oh, is Sea World with the stripper orcas and stuff?
Emily: Oh yeah, it's educational for the kids.
Rym: But this show, it's almost like how soda, like soda pop, pop in the Midwest, it's extremely acidic to counterbalance the sugar, and both that acidity or sugar by themselves would be off-putting.
Rym: This show, without that sort of punny, wink-and-a-nod backdrop to everything, would just be too depressing to watch.
Rym: But it's even more insidious than that.
Rym: I think because the show has the animal people and the light-hearted and weird stuff going on in the background, just random things about the...
Emily: Like, "Haha, he's a mouse, he's a
Emily: cat.".
Rym: Or like the dog who keeps trying to fetch the keys, or Mr.
Rym: Peanut Butter just going to the Labrador Peninsula.
Emily: Well, Mr.
Emily: Peanut Butter, I love him.
Emily: He's the cinnamon roll of the show.
Emily: He's dumb as a brick.
Rym: Just when he runs around in the circle before he gets in his bed.
Emily: He goes, he circles, and it's basically like, because there's the animal puns, it gives it a lot of slight comic relief.
Rym: But if it didn't have that constant low-level humor and absurdity, this would be way too hard to watch.
Rym: It draws you in, and it makes you almost forget what kind of show it is, and then something horrible happens in the last minute of an episode.
Emily: And it's kind of weird because I feel like you're able to sympathize with Bojack more because he's a horse than if he was a live-action 50-year-old man.
Emily: You just look at that 50-year-old man and be like, "Ugh, I hate you.
Emily: You're so
Emily: awful.".
Emily: And you do that for Bojack a little bit, but you're like, "But he's a
Emily: horse.".
Emily: You know, a horsey.
Emily: And then you're thinking, "Oh, pathetic horsey, and I feel bad for-- Oh, that pathetic horsey just--".
Emily: Aww.
Emily: But I think some of it is very inside jokey about, like I said, the politics of film and stuff and goes into a lot of agencies and that puff, puff, puff, go, go, go aspect.
Rym: And the third season sort of spreads beyond just mostly lampooning celebrity and Hollywood and also just lampooning stuff in the news, or also just being very kind of social commentary series.
Rym: Yeah, I was surprised.
Rym: There's an episode in season three where a character gets an abortion, and it's probably the first time I've seen a mainstream television show in American history where the topic comes up, and not really spoilers, but the person who wanted an abortion just gets one and it just happens right away.
Rym: She goes to the clinic and it happens, and that's it.
Rym: And she's back home watching TV, and they treat it a lot more sort of normally, as opposed to making it a gigantic plot point.
Emily: Yeah, it wasn't like this huge-- I mean, there was angst surrounding it, but it was more like personal relationship angst, the kind that had been back and forth throughout the entire show.
Emily: And it was a very meta episode, too, because it was like there was this whole subplot about this pop star who was faking-- Awkwafina.
Emily: Yeah, 16 Awkwafina.
Emily: And so it was very like, "Ugh, this is so tasteless.
Emily: This is hum--".
Emily: And then they actually kind of were like, "Sometimes we use humor to help us deal with these things,".
Emily: and then it's kind of like making commentary on the episode itself.
Rym: So it was like-- Well, they bring it back around to that.
Emily: It was like the subplot within the episode was kind of like a parallel to the episode.
Rym: Well, it's also just the fact that that particular thing-- Abortions are almost always used in media, if they're even used at all, either to have a big conflict where someone wants to keep the baby and the other partner doesn't, and that's the big drama, or the person deciding not to do it, or this giant story of someone deciding to do it, but then consequences, and it'll always be an arc.
Rym: It'll never be a beat in an episode.
Emily: There was one episode, and I'm pretty sure based on the content of the episode, that was exactly their intent, is they wanted to take some of the stigma away, partly through humor, but also partly just to be very realistic about it.
Rym: I guess that's the strength of season two.
Rym: Season two has several long arcs that come to a conclusion.
Rym: Season three is actually almost like a-- It's more like the episodic nature of older shows or sitcoms that it might be lampooning, in that the plot and the story moves very quickly, like this Oscars thing comes up, and before you know it, it's over.
Rym: It's dealt with, and that pushes other things on.
Rym: Every story that a normal show would draw out a lot longer gets resolved, or at least ends, way quicker than you expect.
Rym: Always sad.
Emily: Is this show going to have another season?
Rym: I'm not sure.
Rym: On Polkadot and Wikipedia, there are three seasons and 37 episodes to date.
Rym: Yep, fourth season is coming next summer.
Rym: Bojack's probably not dead at the end of season three.
Emily: I hope that the fourth season is the last season, because I don't know how long this could go on.
Rym: This can't go on without either him killing himself or someone else killing him.
Emily: It either has to have some sort of redemption aspect to it, or it just like--.
Emily: I don't know if he could do that, though, because he's had a few chances.
Rym: A few?
Rym: He's had nothing but chances in this show.
Emily: He has chances, but he doesn't recognize them as much.
Rym: I remember season two with the jogger who runs by when he's trying to jog, and he has life together, and the guy's like, "It's hard, but you just got to keep doing it every
Rym: day.".
Emily: I love that scene.
Emily: That's the kind of scene that I like about this show, where it will be crass one moment, and then the next moment, this kind of dark humor, crassness, and then it will have something very poignant.
Emily: I always like when shows do that.
Emily: It's like the one-two punch of they smack you upside the head with something pretty sick, and then they give you a little tear in your eye.
Rym: And season three in general, because these episodes are a little more self-contained, they're all very different, like the one where you have the two competing agencies together, and it's almost like showing the story in a typical inspirational movie, where everything works out, and we saved Christmas.
Emily: Everybody loves a happy ending.
Rym: But it sort of shows it to you from the perspective of the villains who lose in a movie like that.
Emily: Well, it's the antagonists win, but at the same time, the antagonists are equally as morally bankrupt as the main characters.
Emily: They're no better or worse than the people you're usually working with.
Rym: They are at that point actually a lot better.
Emily: They're kind of the good guys.
Emily: They're getting their lives together.
Emily: They're just trying to do their jobs and make movies and stuff.
Emily: So a little bit of a tangent.
Emily: Who's your favorite character, do you think?
Rym: Well, Wanda's kind of a minor character.
Rym: Wanda was perfectly likable, and that's why she got the hell out of that.
Emily: She was a bit character, and she was a sweet person.
Rym: But I guess she's very emblematic of the character.
Rym: It seems like her character was there almost to make you fully understand how corrupting Bojack is.
Emily: Yeah, to kind of provide a contrast and to be like, "Okay, here's your...".
Emily: Again, with the chances.
Emily: He had this chance.
Emily: This is somebody who lived in the past, basically, and thought he was great and perfect, and it was like he could forget his slump ever happened, but he still managed to squander this opportunity.
Emily: But I think Princess Carolyn is my favorite character.
Rym: She's definitely the strongest of the characters, in terms of she's actually a strong person as a character.
Emily: She's good because she's not perfect.
Emily: It's not like, "Oh, this one's a cinnamon roll.
Emily: This one's
Emily: terrible.".
Emily: Princess Carolyn does a lot of bad stuff.
Emily: She's like the fast-talking hustling agent.
Emily: But I really like her because she's one of those people who's... She's good at her job, and she's trying to do the right thing, and you're like, "Yeah, Princess Carolyn's pretty
Emily: cool.".
Rym: Yup.
Rym: In terms of, I don't know, I enjoy whenever Mr.
Rym: Peanutbutter's on screen.
Emily: It's just so... You love Mr.
Emily: Peanutbutter.
Emily: You're like,
Emily: "Oh.".
Emily: But he's perfect golden retriever.
Emily: He's dumb.
Emily: He's so dumb and so good.
Rym: Yup, he's a good boy.
Emily: He's like everything.
Emily: His initial purpose in the show, even from the get-go, it's obvious that he's good version Bojack.
Emily: It's like another sitcom actor who's just like...
Rym: He's not as rich, he's not as famous, but he sort of just keeps living his life.
Emily: He's pure as the driven snow, and always wants to help people, and when he screws up, it's with the best intentions.
Emily: And with Mr.
Emily: Peanutbutter, it's basically like he doesn't even want these opportunities, and they just kind of come to him, and then he'll fail, and then he'll just let it roll right off his back, whereas if Bojack succeeds, he manages to treat it like failure.
Emily: Mr.
Emily: Peanutbutter treats failure like, "Oh, well, I guess my house is full of spaghetti strainers
Emily: now.".
Rym: But he has issues, too, and I like how they put him and Diane together and make just a very complex relationship story.
Rym: that sort of breaks outside of almost all of these stereotypes of those kinds of arcs in television.
Emily: It's nice, because as of season three, they haven't broken up.
Emily: You know, they're still together.
Emily: I mean, that's not a major spoiler, though.
Emily: It's like they have a long-term relationship, and it's not perfect, and it has a lot of conflict.
Rym: But it's a very strong contrast to all the other characters around them in that while their relationship is often very dysfunctional...
Emily: It's very flawed.
Rym: ...they both work toward it, and that's shown very directly while all the other characters work actively against or work very differently.
Emily: Yeah.
Emily: So I think a lot of the characters in that show are about providing contrast.
Emily: And I kind of feel like Diane hasn't been around as much as she was in the first season.
Emily: I feel like the first season really focused on her and Bojack.
Emily: Those were the two main characters, and it was the contrast between Bojack and his ghost writer.
Emily: And I feel like Diane's kind of taken a little bit of the backseat while Bojack interacts with all these other people in his life, or animals, as it were.
Emily: I still don't understand why Princess Carolyn is pink.
Emily: Of all the things to be hung up on, I'm like, "Why is she
Emily: pink?".
Emily: I don't know.
Rym: I guess it just works, because her name's Princess.
Rym: I mean, Mr.
Rym: Peanutbutter's first name is Mister.
Emily: And Captain Peanutbutter is his brother in the Labrador Peninsula.
Rym: But just this show is super good, and especially after the first six or seven episodes, super nuanced, just really well constructed.
Rym: Everything about television and the production and the voice acting and everything is just basically great.
Rym: I can't make any complaints about the show other than that it's really depressing.
Emily: The voice talent's pretty good.
Emily: I mean, Amy Sedaris is Princess Carolyn, right?
Emily: And the voice acting, like a lot of these shows targeted at adults, I think the animation's not all that great.
Emily: It serves its purpose.
Emily: And you can kind of see it's an animated show.
Emily: that's not about the animation.
Emily: It's animated so it can have that animal aspect to it and kind of distance you from the characters a little bit.
Emily: But usually with this kind of show, it's the acting that really shines, and I feel like it's that case in this show, too.
Rym: But yeah, I hope season four, maybe they could stretch it to five, but the show can't go on forever.
Rym: It has to end.
Emily: I wouldn't want it to go on forever.
Emily: And it doesn't have to end necessarily with anything super dramatic, but I don't know how long I can watch a show with this much sadness in it.
Emily: It's not like I cry out loud sobbing kind of sadness.
Emily: It's just like this is kind of soul destroying.
Rym: Yeah, because it's just very real, and it's almost, like I said, because of the animal people and those other things, it pulls you lower before you really realize how bad it is or what's actually going on in a lot of these episodes.
Emily: So who would you recommend BoJack to?
Rym: Anyone who likes dramatic television, honestly.
Rym: Pretty much anyone who likes good television.
Rym: This show is like A-game television.
Emily: I feel like you've got to have a certain amount of appreciation for black comedy, and you've got to be in a certain kind of mood.
Emily: If you're feeling crummy about your day, just watch My Little Pony or something like that.
Rym: Yeah, but if you watched Rick and Morty and you liked it when it was funny, but didn't like it when it was serious, BoJack is nothing but that serious part.
Emily: Yeah, that's a good way to put it.
Emily: It's like the serious parts of Rick and Morty.
Emily: And actually it's weird because I'm feeling a lot of parallels there too.
Emily: Think about Rick.
Emily: He's this fucked up person who kind of messes with other people's life, and you're like, "What is your deal,
Emily: man?".
Rym: Except he hides everything inside.
Rym: Bottles of Love never shows vulnerability, except when he's alone, ever.
Emily: Whereas BoJack's just bleeding his vulnerability and his tragedy all over everything.
Rym: But I guess the end of season three hits this rock bottom, which is definitely the theme of season three is where is rock bottom?
Emily: This was even brought up in the script.
Emily: There's a slug at an AA meeting talking about being under a rock.
Rym: Oh, you know who voiced Captain Peanutbutter?
Rym: Who?
Rym: That was Weird Al.
Rym: No shit.
Emily: That's funny because it was a serious thing.
Emily: Weird Al, I feel like lately he's been doing a lot of cameos and animated stuff.
Emily: Yeah.
Rym: That's cool.
Rym: But I guess season four is either going to be the rebound in the redemption story, or it's just going to be the end.
Rym: I don't expect this show to have a happy ending.
Rym: I don't know if it can.
Rym: I don't know if it would work if it had a happy ending.
Rym: I don't know if that typical story of, but then they realize they hit rock bottom, and they clean up, and they fix themselves, and they want to change.
Emily: You know what I want out of the show?
Emily: What I want out of the show is a bittersweet ending.
Emily: I want things to get better, but I don't want them to be fixed.
Emily: My favorite thing in fiction is when a bad guy realizes that they are a bad guy, and they have a certain amount of self-awareness.
Emily: I think that's what it is.
Emily: It's like if there's some sort of breakthrough, but it doesn't magically fix everything, just a little bit better, like livable better.
Rym: I guess I still expect every other character to have dealt with their issues and basically be on this trajectory away from him.
Emily: Yeah.
Rym: And I just don't know if he's going to be dead or alone or what at the end of all that.
Emily: Who knows?
Emily: Well, I like the show anyway.
Rym: I like the show a lot.
Rym: It's not like House of Cards, where I pretty much, as soon as I finish an episode, I have to watch the next one immediately, because I've just got to follow this plot thread.
Rym: These episodes, as much as I would if I had free time, marathon the show faster, every episode actually ends on a really good dramatic stopping point.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So I'm pretty comfortable just watching one episode every night or so.
Emily: Like I said, the episodes end very well, but sometimes they're a little cliffhanger-y, but not intense cliffhanger-y.
Emily: They're kind of like, "And then
Emily: what?"
Emily: kind of feeling.
Emily: But usually, they hit a good emotional note to end with.
Rym: And I guess don't take it from us, too.
Rym: The critics pretty much overwhelmingly have high praise for this show.
Rym: If you have complaints about the low brownness or bad quality of television, this is near the top of what you're going to get these days.
Emily: The dream is not written to be completely biased against the suicide squad, and they like the Ghostbusters.
Rym: What about Scott?
Rym: Scott won't watch anything lately, except anime.
Emily: Well, that's why we're doing Rimmelhauge reviews, because we tend to watch things together because we live together.
Emily: And back at The Geek House, you guys live together, so there was a lot more to choose from in terms of things you both have seen.
Rym: So if you subscribe to the Patreon, we do a bunch of these Rimmelhauge reviews of just little ones, of shows that Scott just didn't watch.
Emily: Little 20-minute bits.
Rym: We'll be doing more of those in the near future.
Rym: But that anime erased.
Rym: We did a full review and a full final thoughts.
Rym: We'll probably do a full final thoughts of BoJack once season 4 ends, assuming that's the end.
Emily: That's going to be a while, though.
Rym: Next summer, about a year from now.
Emily: But very good.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rimmelhauge and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Rym: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Rym: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Rym: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Rym: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: The Patrons for this episode, in order of the amount of money they give us on a continuing basis, the numbers they give us at least $5 a month are... I am actively editing the video of Atari Game Design.
Rym: I'll try to have that up soon.
Rym: We also will probably have some tidbits of what's going to be in our panel at PAX West.
Rym: We've been working on that.
Rym: The slides are looking pretty good.
Rym: We've got to cut two hours worth of lecture down to one hour, so maybe I'll share some of the slides and some of the things we're going to talk about after I make some of the charts and graphs that we're using.
Rym: And yeah, now I'll leave you with something strange.
Emily: No dragons.