Rym: It's Monday, May 2nd, 2016.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight building your own PC in.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: Yeah, sorry for the lack of GeekNights.
Rym: right after PAX which suck is actually we had a lot of stuff to talk about Like we had a good Tuesday show coming up, but I got the flu.
Rym: I'm just now almost.
Scott: I will come back and make you get a second flu.
Rym: It was a pretty bad flu But it the badness really only lasted one day and then there's just like two week Convalescence afterward and then when you get over the flu, I'm gonna come back with something I stole from CDC.
Scott: Yeah, you know put in your food though.
Rym: The more annoying thing was because I was sick.
Rym: I basically just stayed home and worked on GeekNights stuff.
Rym: So I did upload a bunch of videos like that how to run an anime club panel and all that crap.
Rym: But I also tried to upload a patreon thing and I was unable to and I have an open ticket with them and I'm really curious to see where this goes.
Rym: I think they're gonna need my help because I tried to upload an mp3 file as an attachment or For the embedded player.
Rym: both options fail, but it only fails with one particular mp3 file.
Rym: that is not particularly different from any other mp3 file I've uploaded and it Specifically fails in a very specific 100% repeatable way.
Rym: yet other similar files do not fail and They seem to be stumped.
Rym: So I have an open ticket with them and it's interesting.
Scott: Oh, I'm surprised that they actually like care and are looking at it.
Rym: Oh, no I've gotten more tech support from patreon than I've gotten ever from I don't know.
Scott: Google Apple Intel combined It must be one of those stardom be places where like the people are working too hard.
Rym: What's weird is I tweeted at them because I figured that's the kind of place where you know The only place to get a human is to tweet at them.
Rym: I didn't get a response there.
Rym: So I was like, huh?
Rym: That's weird.
Rym: This seems like a kind of company where someone's job is just like read Twitter all day.
Rym: So I go to the website like how do I actually get support?
Rym: because you know, it's interesting in the modern era You don't expect there to be a way to get support for most things.
Rym: So like I go to the website and sure enough I could just open a ticket So I opened a ticket and it totally worked.
Rym: I'm kind of shocked by that.
Scott: I'm trying to see if Spotify actually contacted Spotify support today and I'm curious if it works Right, because if you go on Spotify and you search for Captain Jack, there's actually two different Captain Jack's and one of them's fake.
Scott: Well, it's not fake.
Scott: He's just some rapper who calls himself Captain Jack and there but he's mixed in with the good Captain Jack, right?
Rym: You can't click on like the Creator.
Scott: I mean it is but that says it and the artist page is like there's two sets of albums and two different artists mixed together Name.
Scott: and then today I would search for BTS because they have a new album That's not on Spotify yet.
Scott: And the first album wasn't their album.
Scott: It was some chiptunes album by a group.
Scott: I suppose is named BTS But I would assume then these all the regular BTS album.
Scott: So I went and I was like, how do you fix this?
Scott: So they're like fill out this the support form on Spotify.
Scott: So I did.
Scott: I filled it out twice being like these are mixed together.
Scott: These are mixed together So we'll see if they get unfixed.
Rym: I wonder if there are musical artists who make names of songs and names of bands that are Designed to get confused with things where likely that won't be fixed trying to funnel people toward their crap.
Scott: Well, no the Captain Jack guy seems like he's an actual like musician, you know.
Scott: And then BTS seems like an actual chiptunes album, it doesn't seem like some fake Oh album, but I'm glad you're defending Captain Jack cuz.
Rym: I feel like no one else will.
Rym: Captain Jack is finally remembered at least by me.
Scott: You know many people remember Not as many as should not as many as should indeed but enough.
Rym: So do you have any news or do I need to provide you some news to talk about?
Scott: I don't think there's any news really there's a lot.
Scott: There's not any technology news.
Scott: I mean, there's a lot of technology news.
Scott: It's all garbage.
Rym: All right, so I got some news then.
Rym: so This is an interesting article.
Rym: It's one of those like UX teardowns.
Rym: It's a long long article with lots of screenshots and examples comparing Google Maps in 2010 to Google Maps in 2016 and what it's specifically comparing is what data and what density of data are shown at different zoom levels and the conclusion is Actually something that I've noticed but I really think about and as I was reading this I started thinking about this a lot.
Rym: The conclusion is that in 2010 Google showed City names all over the place.
Rym: towns and cities were like like they were labeled all over the maps more like a traditional map But nowadays basically doesn't fucking show you any names of cities.
Rym: It just shows the interstates and important roads and that's pretty much it unless you search for the name of a town.
Rym: now as I scrolled through this article I was thinking about it and I realized that this that One.
Rym: but the article is good But the conclusion that the person who wrote the article makes is basically old man yelling at cloud like just doesn't get it.
Rym: I'm sorry person who wrote this article and everyone who might be mad about this.
Rym: once you notice it The reason your town's name is not on Google Maps anymore is because no one cares about your town.
Rym: Like the names of towns are never useful.
Rym: when you're looking at Google Maps You need to see the roads because people really only use Google Maps at that zoom level When they're driving and looking at directions to get somewhere.
Rym: Google is primarily a navigational thing or a find a restaurant in the town.
Rym: I'm in thing at this point and Google's UX is basically moved toward that end and it's actually a much cleaner better design.
Rym: I pretty much disagree with every conclusion this article makes but The article is a really good place to see side by side the changes in Google's UI and it's actually a really really detailed article.
Rym: I Was not just that.
Rym: it's that in the old days if you just like say you just look at a town in Google or look at an area in Google You'd see like some of the interstates and you'd see like 10 or 15 towns like with little dots and their names next to them.
Rym: Now you see almost no text at all.
Rym: It's just Interstates and a handful of cities like in New York don't I know but I don't care what.
Rym: we don't care about UX at all.
Scott: I don't really give a shit information.
Rym: You don't care at all about aesthetics or any of that stuff.
Scott: I do not care about this in any way.
Rym: You don't care if interfaces ever change or get better.
Scott: I didn't even notice which is the best kind.
Rym: Alright, well, I guess that's why you're not a UX designer.
Rym: so I had noticed this.
Rym: I noticed a lot of changes like this over the years and I know I found too that a lot of people seemed to be really mad about this and Most is one guy.
Rym: no So it's mostly the people who are mad about these changes seem to follow.
Scott: the people are mad about change of every anything.
Rym: They fall into a particular group.
Rym: They're the same people who would for example rather than using their smartphone To just get directions when they go somewhere they print maps or directions from their desktop and then they take that into their car.
Rym: and most of these people seem to prefer Physical maps to Google Maps and are just dumb old people.
Scott: that I did that back in the day when there were no phones.
Scott: Yeah, I did that.
Rym: Well, this also it's interesting because these this change coincides pretty heavily with the fact that in the early days the vast majority of clients hitting Google Maps were desktop computers and Nowadays the far majority of the things ever hitting Google Maps are smartphones.
Rym: so it's basically the design catering toward the need.
Rym: and The problem is Google Maps is called Google Maps and it analogizes what we would think of as a map.
Rym: but yet most of the things that humans have used maps for up until recently are better served by things that don't really look recognizably like the maps that we used in the old days like Extra detail in a map is almost useless 99% of the time when you're using the map because you're almost always using the map only to Get to a specific point somewhere on that map And you're not particularly interested in like what the town next to the point you're getting to is named after.
Rym: So all this means is that someone at Google has been consistently for years like Refining the interface of Google Maps and they've actually done a really good job of it and a lot of people like Scott just never Noticed how much better this interface has gotten over the years.
Rym: All right, whatever all right, I guess you don't care about stuff.
Rym: Here's another one.
Rym: Intel has decided that they're all but abandoning the PC business.
Rym: They're they're gonna sideline their PC business not too far to say that they might give up on the PC business down the road and they're basically saying that mobile chips cloud server type stuff is all they care about.
Rym: that PCs Desktops that sort of thing is just not a market worth considering anymore.
Scott: I haven't read this news, but it feels like you're.
Scott: they also just feels like one of this news that you are greatly exaggerating.
Rym: Oh, well, they also just cut 12,000 jobs.
Scott: Well, that doesn't sound exaggerated at all.
Scott: Yeah, that sounds 100% correct.
Rym: The article here is actually on Intel's website.
Rym: This isn't just like some speculator.
Scott: No, I'm not saying it's speculatory.
Scott: I'm saying you were exaggerating the words that are on that page.
Scott: most likely just but no just based on how much I know you.
Rym: Well, you can read the article, but they are sidelining their PC business and Lining their CPU cooler business.
Rym: Yeah Sort of relevant because if you notice, you know I was thinking about buying a PC last year because I'm getting mines getting near the end.
Rym: that's kind of the point of the show tonight.
Rym: and The components I would put in that PC between a year ago and today like nothing better has come out Like there aren't better chips for PCs.
Rym: Intel's not releasing PC chips on nearly the scale that they used to Because they're not that much better than the previous ones.
Scott: Yeah since Moore's law died some years back It's pretty much just like your CPUs just as good as the previous one.
Scott: Only the GPUs keep sort of bumping and even then they're not bumping, you know as crazily as they used to right I mean the different used to be.
Scott: there was a huge gap between one GPU and the next.
Scott: now There's still a good good gap yeah, but it's not enormous like it was before and CPUs.
Scott: the gap between like one CPU generation in the next in terms of Price performance whatever is not really that much.
Scott: Yeah, I'm gonna notice when you're using your computer now.
Rym: All they said was they're basically sidelining the PC business.
Rym: My speculation is that they're going to down the road back away from the PC business.
Rym: I don't know what that'll necessarily mean, but Increasingly people don't seem to use desktop computers unless they are like super professionals or gamers with VR.
Scott: I mean when the lat, you know, Apple's making their own CPU so they can they're okay if Intel goes away, right?
Scott: You know, they make that they're all for all their you know, iPods, iPhones They make the a7s whatever so they could easily just you know Use those fabs and their designers to make stuff to put in MacBooks.
Scott: if Intel bits, you know stops doing.
Scott: yeah PCs I mean AMD, I don't know if they'll stop or not, but they suck.
Scott: So, I mean if this doomsday that I think is still weighs off at you know, if it's even coming What's the ways off?
Rym: and we've been we've been.
Scott: if there's doomsday comes we can just go on new egg and buy like five Of the last generation of chips or whatever and right and that way if you know, we things get too serious.
Scott: We're just one chip doesn't cut it.
Scott: We can just go to two chip three chip four chip.
Scott: Yeah get better motherboards.
Rym: well, I guess that the.
Rym: the interesting problem is just that the PC market shrunk and Meanwhile separately.
Rym: there was a very narrow window at the end of the k6 era and the k7 era and then that window disappeared.
Rym: Where AMD was making chips that had comparable performance to Intel chips at a lower price there was competition for the desktop computing market.
Rym: then AMD just shit the bed and Intel.
Scott: Intel cheated.
Scott: basically.
Rym: Well Intel cheated by having R&D.
Scott: well No, if there's a lawsuit that Intel lost that was very much just like yeah, they cheated but yeah But they also just.
Rym: they could continuously done R&D and they were able to continue moving forward.
Rym: it almost appears like just speculation that Intel wasn't pushing too hard until AMD competed with them and then they had to do something.
Rym: but now there's no competition.
Scott: No, it's making desktop PC chips anymore like who's gonna compete with Intel because it tossed so much money to get into the business and to make the chips?
Scott: and then How many of them are you gonna sell really to gamers?
Rym: yep, and maybe someone with a server farm and even gamers like a VR ready rig.
Rym: if you built a reasonably fast PC in the last year or two All you need to do is upgrade the video card.
Rym: Like you don't need to buy anything else.
Rym: Not much has changed Things of the day.
Rym: So I don't have you watch this.
Rym: Do you know about Abu Hajar?
Scott: I have no clue what you're talking about.
Rym: So this was a YouTube video vice news thing that went viral, but basically Isis - soldiers.
Rym: they often wear gopros and things to get all this video and that's how they make their ads like come join the Fight or whatever.
Scott: Yeah that because when you see a video of that that makes me want to go.
Scott: Well, they make it look all those and cool Those videos just gonna make everyone want to stay the fuck away.
Rym: No, those videos make really impressionable people who think that they can be a badass.
Rym: They feel like who I could be.
Scott: that isn't the world a better place if those people go there and the smart people leave there?
Rym: maybe but that's not the argument I want to have now.
Rym: so A unit of Isis.
Rym: they died like they were defeated.
Scott: That's how they do.
Rym: the footage from someone's GoPro was recovered and There's one Isis soldier in this unit Abu Hajar.
Rym: and Abu Hajar is that guy.
Rym: Abu Hajar is a fuck-up.
Scott: So even among Isis people Among them he is that guy.
Rym: if you don't want to watch like for real video of these guys fighting someone made a compilation of.
Rym: Just every time someone's screaming at him and it's like he starts firing the machine gun and they're like Abu Hajar What the fuck.
Rym: you're hitting us with the shell casings.
Rym: move it over to the other side and Abu Hajar you're doing it again.
Rym: Stop it at one point.
Rym: He tries to shoot the machine gun because everyone's yelling at him.
Scott: why did it make him the machine gun guy?
Rym: so then he moves over and he's resting the machine gun a different way and he starts to fire it and then the front of it falls into the cabin and Starts ricocheting bullets all over inside.
Rym: and once again, the guy's like Abu Hajar WTF?
Rym: Then later, they're like give me and they give him a rocket launcher instead.
Scott: What why would you give the rocket launcher to?
Scott: Give Abu Hajar the knife.
Scott: So that is what you give him when a boo give him the pointy stick.
Rym: at best when Abu Hajar has the RPG He not once but twice fires it but he aims it up and just before he fires it you see the guy go.
Rym: No, Abu Hajar and the exhaust blast comes into the cabin and burns them all.
Rym: so This article the reason I'm making it my thing of the day is that that kind of made the rounds and you know It's a thing.
Rym: I saw someone already selling Abu Hajar t-shirts.
Scott: Yeah, and this is you know, this is why military training is a thing.
Rym: Yeah Like zones of fire and like like.
Rym: at one point the guy who's yelling at him was like Abu Hajar cover me And the particular jar doesn't know what cover means.
Scott: No, he's our probably murdered him.
Rym: So he did know.
Rym: but the guy who told him to cover him probably didn't know because the guy says Abu Hajar cover me Abu Hajar starts firing the shell casings start hitting that guy again.
Rym: Cuz he probably didn't realize cover me means fire.
Rym: So what I'm linking to my actual thing of the day is a pretty interesting technical takedown of a military person explaining all the things Abu Hajar does wrong and like what specifically he was doing wrong and it's just a Everything really fascinating article.
Rym: It also shows you kind of like what like from a military only perspective Like how Isis fights how jokey they are.
Rym: Oh, look, here's the movies.
Rym: see be careful of.
Rym: and then he's got the RPG and then see that that exhaust.
Rym: but do Good job, but you roasted us, too.
Rym: What's wrong with you Abu Hajar?
Rym: Okay So you got a thing of the day.
Scott: I do it's much better than your thing of the day.
Scott: So, you know pop-up books are good.
Scott: I have I have my Odyssey pop-up book, which is like the bell You throw the spike into the Cyclops.
Rym: I.
Scott: it's such a good one.
Scott: That's the best part.
Rym: It's got moving spike action.
Scott: Yeah, it's great.
Scott: I see here in this YouTube video a pop-up book.
Scott: That is maybe even better it Even though it's new style transformers.
Scott: It's still a transformers pop-up book and as you can imagine There's transforming action in this pop-up book and it is like holy shit level of popping up and booking.
Scott: So you don't need to buy this probably expensive pop-up book that will take up a lot of room in your place of living and not provide as much entertainment value because you can just watch this YouTube video and get the full experience.
Scott: I feel like everyone go to like the Barnes & Noble near you and play with it and Then put it back on the shelf and go home.
Rym: pop-up books are like wall Scrolls Like you're gonna have one.
Rym: just have one and have the best one and don't have any more.
Scott: Should I sell my Odyssey one and get a transformers one?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: that Odyssey one is pretty good.
Scott: And the Odyssey one is so much more rare, right?
Scott: Yeah, you can't find that shit.
Rym: That was from that like artisanal pop-up book Mocha years ago years ago.
Rym: So in the meta moment, the booklet book will be Oryx and Crake by Margaret Atwood.
Scott: I meant to start reading it and I didn't.
Rym: I meant to start reading it.
Rym: But now I'm halfway through the 12th book of the wheel.
Scott: it is sitting is sitting there on my little nightstand getting ready to get read and then a One-punch man fell on top and then master Keaton found of it and then asteroid omnibus fell on top.
Scott: It's just like no help.
Rym: I'm fine.
Scott: I'm just words.
Scott: I cannot beat these mangas.
Rym: It's fine because I made an accidental commitment and now I'm sticking to it.
Rym: Me and Keheil are gonna do a wheel of time podcast at PAX Prime.
Scott: You're gonna spend PAX Prime time on it.
Scott: podcasting about wheel of time.
Rym: It won't take us more than an hour But we're just gonna talk about what happened to ran out or over these last Into the fantasy novels.
Scott: Well, you know what it is.
Scott: have a nice fantasy novel.
Rym: Here's what I realized the because I've noticed whenever I tweet about the real time.
Rym: There's a few people who like respond.
Rym: It's like us with the prince of nothing.
Scott: Like if someone if I saw a tweet about prince of nothing, I would have to say something.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: So about the gnosis.
Rym: if you're thirsty for talking about your like long-running dense fantasy series That many people you can talk about it with who you haven't already talked about everything as heels red.
Scott: a prince of nothing I don't know.
Rym: So I'm gonna find out if he's thirsty for that.
Rym: as much as wheel it a burner burning wheel with My brain's getting messed up as much as the prince of nothing is very sort of Tolkien s deconstruction.
Rym: It is also really wheel.
Rym: a time II deconstruction wheel of time is closer to those books than you think Mmm, especially once you get into the weird stuff with the forsaken and compulsion and all that creepy stuff down the road.
Scott: Yeah, those guys are aliens who landed in a rocket.
Rym: Yeah So, uh, yeah, otherwise we have no conventions Until Connecticut Connecticut in July panel submissions are open the form kind of sucks.
Scott: If you're on our staff, you have to fill out this form on the website.
Scott: Otherwise, it's gonna be yes It's got.
Rym: I filled it out like four times.
Rym: I can't tell if it works cuz it just like you got the error.
Scott: It worked.
Rym: I get nothing If I hit submit it just goes back to itself again empty.
Scott: Did you fill out every single field on the form?
Scott: I did Even the ones you think you don't to fill out.
Scott: I filled out every single field cuz there's a message that will tell you What like you messed up, but it's a hard to see message because the bad UI.
Rym: Yeah, I'll just keep filling it out.
Rym: I'll just try a couple different ways.
Rym: I'll try a different browser.
Scott: I'm gonna ask the guy to give me a list of everyone who filled it out.
Rym: Yeah, so stay tuned.
Rym: Connecticut We'll be there as always.
Rym: but the website seven some trouble lately and I'd have no comment on that.
Rym: Next after that, of course is PAX Prime.
Rym: Don't worry packs tip badges supposedly will not go on sale for like another week or two.
Rym: So you got some time to relax.
Scott: PAX West it's changed his name.
Scott: They're going on sale after the PAX South badges And so the PAX South badges.
Scott: the problem is I guess South and us, you know, they weren't selling.
Scott: They're still selling out right, but they're not selling out in advance.
Scott: like Robert Coon For example, there were no hoodies at PAX South right and why was that?
Scott: Well, cuz Robert Coo says, you know, I don't know how many people are actually coming to this PAX South But I know I'm gonna sell this many hoodies per person.
Scott: But you know, am I really?
Scott: how many hoodies should I make?
Scott: is it gonna be worth it to make hoodies for PAX South?
Scott: And if you noticed PAX South didn't have any hoodies and that's because there weren't yes to do the hoodies Far enough in advance of the packs.
Scott: So he has to write So if everyone would have pre registered for the PAX South he might have made some yellow hoodies to everybody.
Scott: Meanwhile, despite the ridiculous That's just one example of that right the more people pre-order in advance the better they can plan the convention in the better.
Rym: Well paxies, I mean it sells out immediately no matter what they know the crowd.
Rym: and despite that those hoodies sold out like Friday morning.
Scott: No, they sold out.
Scott: I'm like Sunday or Saturday.
Rym: Yeah, they sold out of men's medium right away, and then you're fucked?
Scott: Oh, maybe.
Scott: but anyway.
Scott: So, you know, he's basically said look we need people to pre-order the South badges far in advance Even though the demand is lower than for the other one.
Scott: But the problem is he's offering big incentives for people who pre-order.
Scott: So if you're thinking about going to PAX South next year And you're gonna pay for it and do it the normal way by buying a badge Buy your badge as soon as they go on sale and you're gonna get all these goodies.
Scott: So why if you're gonna go why not buy the badge now and get the goodies?
Rym: Well, a lot of people don't know if they're gonna go and they decide later.
Scott: But have you buy now and get the goodies?
Scott: you can just you know, not go later.
Rym: And the other thing is I as you know, I don't want goodies.
Rym: I got enough things in my house.
Scott: One of the goodies is a. I don't want the goodies either but one of them is a custom Lanyard that you can't get any other way.
Scott: I've already got a nice fancy custom land I know but I'm just saying there's someone out there who wants that.
Rym: true true but there is the fundamental problem that not that this is the topic of the show or anything.
Rym: but Pax East will sell out.
Rym: they could probably sell up like a couple hundred thousand badges just because so many millions of people live within A drive.
Scott: I think there's an interview once where he said he could sell 5x.
Scott: I don't know about that, but you could definitely think he could could definitely sell 3x no matter what.
Scott: I think you could sell 5x or more or else I think is the borderline.
Rym: how many people are within a day's drive of Boston?
Scott: it's I don't know how many of you know More than 20 million.
Scott: I don't know how.
Scott: if that percentage would really hundreds of thousands of people come to the packs I think.
Rym: so what percentage of people would like to go to a PAX?
Rym: put that against the number of people within a day's drive of Boston.
Rym: But Pax Prime while it's smaller has the.
Rym: it's the first one has the sort of international appeal.
Rym: like all the people who fly Long-distances.
Rym: they're gonna go to that one obviously So that one sells out no matter what.
Rym: but who lives close to San Antonio?
Rym: everyone who lives nearby Desert people.
Rym: Yeah, they all already go.
Scott: I think there's people who don't know about it or don't go who probably should right?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: I know this gamer isn't like Oklahoma cuz like a netrunner is seen there, and they don't go to PAX.
Rym: Oklahoma.
Scott: to San Antonio is quite a trip though It's not any more of a trip than like to Boston.
Rym: But if you're gonna do a big trip you might as well go to the way bigger packs.
Scott: It's cheaper to go to San Antonio.
Scott: It is cheaper to go to especially if you live in Tulsa, Oklahoma.
Rym: It was cheaper to go to San Antonio for us, and we live in New York.
Scott: That's what I'm saying.
Scott: so the Tulsa, Oklahoma people.
Scott: if you're a gamer in Tulsa, Oklahoma Shouldn't you be going to PAX out?
Rym: ah but most gamers care about the expo hall nonsense And they can't that packs house doesn't have a lot of that going on.
Scott: You know the expo hall at PAX South must be way cheap.
Scott: We should get in on that.
Scott: yeah I don't know what we'll do in there, but we should do it.
Rym: We would just we would go in with a bunch of people and make the luxury box We just set in it like a table top.
Scott: We could do like the twitch booth where it says the luxury box for twitch.
Rym: we could do that.
Rym: We'd have to get some people in because I don't want to hire one of those companies that makes booths Scott the patreon money.
Scott: Yeah, go use it for that everyone.
Scott: It wouldn't be enough.
Rym: everyone who's about?
Rym: I had the price sheet from the first two paxis.
Rym: We could have bought a booth at those first two sure now.
Scott: We can't no kidding The price for the space at PAX South we could probably afford.
Scott: it's probably thousands of dollars right especially for the small booth We're gonna get.
Scott: but the price to make a booth like the twitch booth would be expensive.
Rym: What how much it would cost to pay twitch just to put us in their lineup?
Rym: That's how everyone else does it.
Scott: is that how?
Scott: You pay for time on that twitch couch.
Rym: I mean, I bet they just give it to like their creators.
Rym: But I'm sure if we went that to them with like ten grand and we're like look Schedule us on this thing.
Rym: Here's ten grand.
Scott: I wonder if you got ten grand don't use it on that.
Scott: and if you try to use it on that just let me know So I can murder you first.
Scott: Well, here's the problem doing that for us.
Rym: Yeah ten grand.
Rym: We could do a lot better things with ten grand but in the advertising like eyeballs space ten grand for that It would be way cheap compared to other forms of that that would give you.
Scott: So it's such a bad return on eyeballs per dollar.
Rym: Could I give you less of a return than the people who pay for those panels at New York Comic Con that literally no one?
Rym: goes to?
Scott: No, but it would still be.
Scott: you could get a ton of eyeballs for ten grand if we just bought like Google ads or something Project we could hire someone to design really nice ads and put them on project.
Rym: Wonderful Well, I did because I got a bunch of free money.
Rym: I did run a Google ad campaign once for one of our YouTube videos and It actually like drove a lot of eyeballs and a lot of ad revenue.
Scott: Yeah, we could make YouTube pre-roll ads and put them on YouTube.
Rym: Yeah Anyway, so I've talked about this off and on but I'm pretty much I've got my rig together.
Rym: and you know typically like in the old days We talked about building computers a lot more often than we do now because computers changed a lot more.
Scott: Well, that's true.
Rym: But also Well think about like to the year 98 through 2005 I pretty much always stayed abreast of like what was going on in computers because she was changing all the time.
Scott: Well, it's also a timing thing, right?
Scott: So because of the time of when we started GeekNights I think it's like there was a time early on.
Scott: we're like I got a new computer then you got a new one.
Scott: then five Years passed then we both got new computers again, and there was also a period.
Scott: we were like we moved and got HDPC.
Scott: so he bought extra computers.
Scott: true, right.
Scott: and then you actually bought two computers because you bought the Mac Mini and then you said And then you bought another computer.
Scott: so there was like a bunch of extra computer buying.
Scott: but even though you know still It feel it feels like oh did we used to buy the computers more often?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: no, I've consistently bought a new desktop computer pretty much every five four to six years.
Rym: I was about to say every year since 1998 99.
Rym: It's four to six years except except for the one time when it broke Yep, when my case seven eight hundred.
Scott: Yeah, those AMD's broke.
Scott: So we bought more computers then but I bought another AMD about a Thunderbird gigahertz Mm-hmm, and that one broke actually later - yeah, but other you know, it's just like we bought computer, you know.
Scott: So my computer is like only like three years old.
Scott: I think I'm not.
Rym: also in that era we bought.
Rym: we both bought our first like for real laptops and upgraded them like once each and Now like I'm still using that same laptop.
Scott: I'm using that.
Scott: I actually upgraded from the laptop to the iPad Pro.
Rym: Yep, I'm gonna get the I haven't.
Scott: I haven't used the laptop.
Scott: it's into the closet.
Rym: the problem is the iPad Pro can not replace my laptop because One I still haven't fully figured out.
Rym: if there is a clicker situation to use the iPad Pro to present panels of pax's.
Scott: Yes, there is.
Scott: you can use keynote.
Rym: Yeah, I'm not using keynote.
Scott: Well, then I Want to.
Rym: I want to use the kind of clicker I use now.
Rym: I don't know if there's a good way to plug something like that.
Scott: or if you have if you have a clicker that is Effectively a Bluetooth keyboard then you could connect to it.
Scott: The iPad would think it is a Bluetooth keyboard and then you could use Google Drive and Google Drive would say oh you're pressing page Down next page problem - I can't run like audition and shit on iPad Pro like I can on my laptop.
Scott: You can use Premiere clip.
Rym: That's not useful at all for me.
Scott: It's actually pretty good, but it's yeah, it's not real for me.
Rym: Yeah, like it's so and there's no audition But there are audio recording type programs those they're like prelude and like all those things that lets you like Have to your workflow.
Scott: I found that For the workflows, you can do a full workflow on these things If you just don't care like.
Scott: I used the lightroom one Yeah, and it's like yeah this stuff you can't do in the mobile lightroom as easily or as good But it's like if you really wanted to you could use lightroom mobile.
Rym: Yeah, but lightroom is good example.
Rym: If we had a if we had a more robust or less robust workflow for video then yeah, that stuff will work fine.
Rym: But our workflow is pretty much as professional as it can be without over investment.
Rym: and Those tools just would add time to know.
Scott: real, you know, you haven't used them.
Rym: I've tried them out.
Scott: Where you when did you try Premiere clip?
Rym: Oh, no, I tried prelude.
Scott: Oh, no, no, I'm talking about like, you know the mobile versions of the Adobe.
Rym: Yeah, I read what clip does because I was thinking I'm gonna buy that iPad Pro.
Rym: So I was like, huh?
Rym: Maybe I'll use this.
Rym: my general feeling was I probably won't use it But also I can't place it five on my iPad Pro.
Rym: So don't play war bits no, but I place it five.
Rym: when I travel I play rocket League.
Rym: when I travel for work I like.
Scott: when I try I just don't.
Rym: next week I'm flying to Hong Kong and I'm gonna be in Australia for like a week.
Rym: So in the evening if I'm in my hotel room for a few hours for go to bed I just want to play some rocket League.
Scott: You gotta tell me what days.
Scott: so I know what days not to come here.
Rym: Oh, yeah, I'm gone the next two weeks.
Scott: Okay, so When are you leaving?
Rym: Tuesday, I'm flying - so I guess Monday if we wanted to we could do like one more show for like the next Tuesday Or over the weekend.
Rym: We could do a bunch of shows and then you have two weeks off.
Scott: We'll see.
Rym: Tuesday I'm flying to Hong Kong Saturday.
Rym: after that I'm flying to Sydney and I'll be in Sydney until Thursday and then Friday morning.
Rym: Then I'm flying back here.
Rym: So I'll be home here Friday afternoon.
Scott: It's gonna be great.
Rym: Yeah It'll be a little too cold for like beach time.
Rym: So I'm gonna go mountain biking instead.
Scott: Hopefully it'll be warm here.
Rym: Well now that I've done.
Rym: now that I've like done some serious mountain biking in Australia I'm gonna do those courses again, and I'm gonna like try to beat times and like get some lap records and shit.
Scott: So good luck with that.
Rym: I forgot how much I love mountain biking But I digress not talking about a laptop because I'm not gonna buy a new laptop ever.
Rym: and if maybe the surface pro 6 That's when I feel like it'll be time to buy a new laptop.
Rym: But I'm gonna go through my full rig of what I would buy if I was building a computer literally today.
Rym: I might change it a little bit before I actually buy it because I don't need to buy it I'm.
Rym: it's not like times in the past where my computer is dying.
Rym: Like the USBs failed I need to do computer quick to do GeekNights.
Rym: Everything's fine.
Rym: So I'm actually in no rush so I can tweak this a little bit.
Rym: But it basically gives me a chance to sort of go over all the things that actually have changed.
Scott: What has changed?
Rym: so the first the biggest things that changed is that like when you look at the motherboards one There's USB 3 and USB 3.1 and all that kind of new stuff that just isn't on my motherboard as USB 3 and it's like Years old.
Rym: Yeah, my motherboard does not have USB 3 because USB 3 did not exist when I built this computer.
Scott: That's sort of necessary Us 3b.
Scott: USB 3 is actually kind of a big deal Like if I put my USB stick in the not USB 3 hole.
Scott: Yeah, it's very sad.
Rym: DDR4 is a lot faster.
Scott: Can you even notice though?
Rym: Uh for certain kinds of things?
Scott: I mean, I have 32 gigs of RAM.
Scott: It's like RAM is not an issue.
Rym: amount of RAM doesn't matter.
Rym: But RAM speed can matter especially things like rendering Whatever because there's.
Rym: there's a lot of effects in Premiere that Will calculate some massive stupid data set and they do it in your RAM.
Rym: So you need to have enough RAM to hold the whole thing until it finishes the calculation.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: But there's SATA 6 instead of SATA 3 and I've talked about before.
Scott: I'm not sure which SATA I have but I'm pretty sure it's Probably three.
Rym: it doesn't really matter because only recent drives can actually use that stuff.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: I mean the speed of my SATA drives never been a problem.
Scott: They're already so fast.
Rym: mine are not fast enough to do 4k video stuff as real-time as I'd like to.
Rym: Especially you're doing the multi camera view in Premiere.
Rym: Like I cannot.
Rym: I do not have enough bandwidth Power supplies and stuff is actually not changed that much which was interesting.
Rym: firewires dead Of course.
Scott: Yeah, my motherboards all actually still have firewire on them.
Scott: Yeah, there's no more my desktop both have one firewire each.
Rym: You EFI but that's been around for a while.
Rym: My computer has that m.2 is probably the one you'll have to think about the most because now Basically when you build a computer Well, isn't the main advantage of it just space savings like now?
Scott: you can just put a hard drive on a tiny stick onto your Motherboard so m.2 in a way tiny computer also supports.
Scott: Instead of having like now you don't need like a power cable and a data cable and all this garbage to plug in.
Rym: Also, there's different kinds of SSDs now and basically you can and this used to only be the realm of like ultra servers.
Rym: but SSDs can connect via say two three or say two six or PCI Express bus, why would you put a whole SSD into your PCI Express slot?
Rym: So people are doing high-end video workflows often do because they have plenty of PCI Express slots.
Scott: is but I mean, is it really faster?
Rym: Yes, 32 gigabit per second If you get a high-end SSD which we'll talk about SSDs in a minute because one of the side things has changed is that Not all SSDs are made like.
Rym: they're not all the same guys.
Scott: Yeah, there's cheap ones now, but this they're not as good.
Rym: Yeah, like you're in fact the lower-end SSDs you're almost better off getting a high-end spinning disk for how badly they perform.
Rym: but So you don't put these things unless like you're crazy in like your x16 slots or your video cards.
Scott: go No, cuz we're you gonna put your video card.
Scott: Yeah, actually, can you put your video if you're not doing the SLI?
Scott: Can you actually use that second slot of PCI x16 for a hard drive or you have to put it in the regular PCI Express slot?
Scott: There's a normal sky.
Rym: So it's just using the protocol.
Rym: so basically like the motherboard I got if you look at it the m.2 slot is Technically an x4 PCI Express.
Scott: Oh, really?
Rym: So if you put an m2 drive that supports SATA or not say that supports PCI Express access because it's high-performance drive It'll be wicked fast
Scott: Mmm,
Rym: so basically now if you're not gonna put like if you're building a relatively small computer if
Scott: you're building a pewter That doesn't need a giant video card in it.
Scott: Yeah get m2 and they'll be the tiniest computer in the universe and a crazy fast even it.
Rym: m2 goes into the m2 slot It doesn't take up and your PCI Express.
Rym: You can still put a giant video card in there.
Scott: Yeah, no, but I'm saying like you get your computer could just be so small though.
Rym: Oh, yeah, you can make the tiniest of computer.
Rym: So what I'm pairing this with and that's where it gets interesting is because a lot of people asked why I'm getting two SSDs.
Scott: I have two SSDs.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I've.
Rym: right now I have three.
Scott: I could probably do three But so I'm.
Rym: my main hard drive now is this Samsung SSD and it's so is mine 350 bucks.
Scott: I don't know if mine was 350, but it was.
Scott: it was hundreds cuz it was really big.
Scott: at the time It was like one of the biggest ones you could get.
Rym: Oh Scott my 30 gigabyte SSD that I bought in 2009 was like 400 bucks.
Scott: Yeah, mine was like I think it's a 256 and it was less than that.
Scott: But still it was.
Scott: yeah.
Scott: So I think at the time I bought it you could only get a 512 and if that was a fortune.
Rym: So so I got two SSDs here and then the thing with the SSDs?
Scott: is that the good name brand that looks like the one I have?
Rym: yeah that cost more like benchmarks show they perform so much better.
Rym: Don't even bother with those cheap SSDs like they're not great.
Scott: Yeah I mean You know there's a lot of Advertising there that like seems fake because it looks like the same kind of marketing you would see for something like monster cable Which is just bullshit.
Scott: right where people are like, oh, these are so much faster than those, you know It's the same garbage you see on all the packaging for these things.
Scott: But like for example, I have these Patriot USB sticks.
Scott: It's just a USB stick and they're like on the advertising like so much faster than your other USB sticks.
Scott: and you think really?
Scott: USB stick speed that's what we're getting into now.
Scott: But no This USB sticks the Patriot ones like the USB 3 blue ones that I have.
Scott: They are so much faster than every other USB stick I have.
Rym: Well this array of cards that I've got like these all perform differently Like I have a new the newer SATA drive.
Scott: the newer SSD I have compared to the older one.
Scott: I have is so much faster.
Rym: So, but anyway, so I'm getting the Samsung 850 Evo which is like a state of three like standard SSD.
Rym: It's 500 gigs, which is plenty.
Scott: That's plenty for your pure OS and your apps.
Rym: No, that's not for OS and apps.
Rym: So that is my backup SSD.
Rym: The only thing that's going there is when Scott gives me all the video and all the stuff from panels.
Rym: Everything I'm working on goes on that drive.
Scott: Yeah, that's what I put on my secondary drive.
Scott: So that's your secondary drive, but that's good enough to be a primary drive.
Scott: What's the primary?
Rym: Yeah, so that's the secondary drive.
Rym: It's right now.
Rym: It's like 175 bucks.
Rym: Oh, man, that's hella cheap.
Rym: Yeah, it is because now you can get a 500 gig SSD for like 70 bucks.
Scott: That's probably garbage.
Scott: It's definitely garbage, but what specifically about it is garbage?
Scott: besides just being slower?
Rym: It's just that it's slower and theoretically less reliable, but I based that solely on new egg reviews.
Scott: There are a lot of reliability issues, right people don't understand how SSDs work and how flash flash works But the thing is like name brands like.
Rym: I actually trust Samsung a lot.
Scott: Samsung has one of like the best flash factories like on earth.
Scott: Yeah And it's telling surprised like how much flash stuff in general.
Scott: like you what do you think your iPhone has a flat has flash storage?
Scott: And who do you think makes that?
Scott: it ain't Apple.
Rym: So The part of the reason why I chose this particular one is my backup SSD is one It's the right size like the one terabyte one is just way too expensive.
Rym: 250 gigs isn't big enough, but it's got a 5 a full 5-bag review still despite almost 600 reviews.
Rym: That says a lot because new egg people are not kind.
Scott: no when this is a bad product in new egg You'll see it has like no eggs.
Rym: Yep Now sometimes you buy the no egg product anyway But you know what you're getting into like when you buy those Rosewill firewire chips or whatever.
Scott: Rosewill is new egg brand.
Scott: It's actually pretty good.
Rym: It's pretty good.
Rym: Except their firewire chips are some of the worst firewire chips in the world.
Scott: I've never tried a Rosewill firewire chip, but I Rosewill keyboard.
Scott: That's really good.
Scott: Oh, yeah, they're fine cherry chips.
Rym: Yeah, so my main drive is a Samsung 950 Pro m.2 512 gigabyte PCI Express card To or PCI Express em - well, it's m2 form factor PCI Express protocol.
Rym: Okay, m2 is just the form factor that you plug into the motherboard with it.
Scott: Stick it like I thought it goes horizontal.
Scott: Do you put it in a PCI Express lot sticking straight up?
Rym: No, no, it goes flat like like.
Rym: basically there's a slot on the side.
Scott: Is it good?
Scott: It's just a PCI Express lot.
Rym: No, they don't m2 slot.
Rym: Okay, yeah, express is just a bus protocol.
Rym: All right, so it just uses that protocol.
Rym: It's on that bus, but you literally for m.2.
Rym: You just slide it in sideways Parallel to the plane of the motherboard itself.
Rym: It's like a RAM stick except the bits are on the end and the OS just sees.
Scott: this is just like any other hard drive.
Rym: Yes, so pretty much if you're building a super fast computer these days you get a super fast awesome m.2 Hard drive that looks like a RAM stick and just stick it into the motherboard and install windows on that.
Scott: Okay, holy shit.
Rym: Does this thing look fast from the benchmarks and everything?
Rym: I've looked there.
Scott: It's like it looks fast.
Scott: this piece of this piece of silica.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: No, but I mean circuit board looks real fast.
Scott: It's just sitting there on the table.
Rym: Wow, that's actually does like looking at pictures of it compared to pictures of like similar drives.
Rym: Now some motherboards got some lightning bolts on it some LEDs blinking some motherboards Daddy to m.2 slops, but I felt like that was overboard.
Rym: I am not.
Rym: I'm not doing any raid or any crap like that.
Rym: I've got one 512 SS.
Scott: Oh, what's the price of this compared to the one you just said?
Rym: three hundred and fifty?
Scott: and what's the sizes?
Rym: five hundred and twelve?
Rym: Gig both of them.
Scott: Oh, so it cost twice as much because twice as much it appears to be more than twice as fast I wouldn't get with that pricing.
Scott: I wouldn't get two of the m2 ones unless I was hella rich.
Rym: exactly see cuz even though I've got money.
Rym: I'm not gonna waste money I don't need that.
Scott: Yeah, dude, if I won the lottery and had hundreds of million dollars and lived on the beach I would still frugally buy a PC.
Rym: Yeah, if I had millions of dollars the only difference between the computer I'm showing I would drive a GTR though and the computer of about I would actually buy.
Rym: then If I had millions of dollars, I would buy like some ridiculous oxygen card for my video editing.
Scott: But I'm not an oxygen card early, you know, what are the?
Rym: what are those like fancy render cards like quadros?
Scott: I guess I would just get the Nvidia Titan.
Rym: Yeah But I would get a render specific amazing card and I'd have a separate gaming PC But that's if I had ridiculous stupid money, which video?
Scott: titans?
Rym: titans two of them but yeah, so I The gist of all this is that you can now build a computer where disk I/O is basically not a bottleneck anymore Which is kind of amazing.
Scott: This hasn't been a bottleneck for me since you know, sa ta SSDs not sa?
Rym: ta But it's a bottleneck.
Rym: if you've got multiple 4k and 1080p videos You're trying to watch them all at the same time in a multi-camera monitor.
Scott: Actually, you know Even though my computer is like way way fast The thing that really kills me the 4k video is just playing it like VLC.
Scott: just playing it like it'll be fully loaded But if you'll see is just like, uh, there's so many pixels to draw every frame.
Rym: What do you got?
Rym: a 780?
Scott: The GPU is a 680.
Scott: Oh and the CPU is like i7.
Scott: That's really fast.
Rym: So it's interesting.
Rym: I have a 770.
Rym: I can play 4k video just fine in VLC, but I cannot play it fine in Premiere.
Scott: Oh premieres actually better at it than I found then.
Scott: But that's I think what it is in VLC.
Scott: The problem is when I try to full-screen it and premiere I'm never full screening the 4k video.
Rym: Yeah, but in Premiere.
Rym: I can only play it if I down res.
Rym: it's like, you know The 4x or the 8x like the bad view?
Scott: I never.
Rym: I don't do that But I was literally my disk IO maxes out when I hit play.
Rym: That's just cuz my computer's so old.
Rym: So I bet you can tell that I whenever I buy a new computer The things I spend the most money on are the things that are like a current plateau of amazing performance while simultaneously Are hitting my biggest pain point with my current PC.
Rym: I'm willing to spend a lot to avoid the problems I have today and I'm not gonna spend money on stuff that I already like if I don't like.
Rym: I don't notice a problem With my CPU speed so I'm not gonna spend a ton of money to try to get more like.
Rym: I'm not gonna overclock Because my CPU is not significantly limiting me.
Rym: So, let's see the problem with CPUs.
Rym: So I'm gonna get the core i7 6700 K Skylake whatever for core for it doesn't come with a cooling.
Rym: It does not come with the cooler.
Rym: I had to do the most research to figure out like what coolers are good.
Rym: I've never bought an aftermarket cooler in my life because they were always stupid.
Rym: But now you pretty much have to and I think the best one to get for me is the NZXT kraken.
Scott: What the hell is that?
Rym: So remember it's.
Rym: it's kind of like what we're looking at at PAX.
Scott: This is the same thing that that advertisement worked on you at PAX.
Rym: Yeah, so yeah kind of I Advertised.
Scott: next time you say advertising doesn't work on people.
Scott: I'll just be like well that booth on PAX worked at you.
Rym: Ah, but I'll tell I'll explain at least why it was.
Rym: it's not just like oh I saw it and it's good.
Rym: I actually have some reasons why.
Rym: because I did.
Scott: Everyone justifies things after the fact.
Scott: that's how thing humans work.
Rym: now because I actually went and looked at a lot of other cases.
Rym: I went to the dealers room a couple times and That was actually the best case at PAX.
Rym: everything else either had things that you would complain about You know stupid fancy crap or whatever or they were just like weird foreign factors.
Scott: The only cases I saw at PAX I liked for the small ones for like those that tiny computer we saw.
Rym: Oh, yeah, but that's different.
Scott: Yeah, but what it mean?
Scott: every which every case that was on display was a gamery, you know You know like You know the kind of you know looked of like spinning rims kind of stuff Yeah, which doesn't bother me, but this was probably the most tasteful case there.
Scott: I mean, it wasn't the worst I've seen but it was bad.
Rym: I don't know why you think it was bad.
Rym: I think it actually is elegant.
Rym: It has a like 60s kitchen aesthetic that I kind of like.
Scott: Yeah, okay.
Scott: Sure if you think so, it definitely has a Teenager with too much money's bedroom aesthetic.
Rym: I think how is like an off-white?
Rym: enamel looking thing with a single red stripe.
Scott: I had like a window on the side.
Rym: every case has a window on the side and a cyber shape to it.
Rym: What do you think?
Rym: cyber shape what the?
Rym: I can show you a case where I'd say?
Rym: Yeah, that has a cyber shape.
Rym: this case has like 60 Kitchen.
Scott: just because you're spinning rims are less spinning doesn't mean they're not spinning.
Rym: But I looked at a lot of cases at PAX and I feel like that one was the best one I saw.
Rym: that was that was actually a mid tower.
Rym: It wasn't the worst I gotta say didn't have like weird crap Like it didn't have any stuff built into it for like ridiculous liquid cooling nonsense that I don't want.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: And I went back over there and I put dry put drives into it and took drives out of it.
Rym: It was the best putting drives in and taking drives out experience I've ever had.
Scott: I love how you take that in consideration.
Scott: a thing that you're gonna do like twice.
Rym: Yeah Cuz you know what every has to be.
Rym: this thing I do twice has to be a great Experience because I'll do it a third time toward the end of the computer's life.
Rym: when I go Ah, this m.2 is really cutting it anymore I'm gonna open it up and add some say to 50 drives to it And then I remember how much of pain in the ass it is.
Rym: But the drives just not really well is really nice.
Rym: But more importantly remember that TED talk about if you have a lot of options and they're all mostly the same The best thing is to go with whatever you just touched or like.
Rym: just pick one randomly doesn't matter.
Scott: case I mean, you know the case matters and you're building it and it matters for cooling and keeping dust out.
Scott: But after that if you don't look at it and it's you know Yeah, Rym, I guess is gonna look at his a lot cuz he likes his spinner.
Rym: My case is like buried inside.
Rym: It's only sticking out now because it overheats a little bit.
Scott: Yeah, it has a bunch of LEDs in it that are all blazing.
Rym: That's because those are the cheapest fans.
Rym: Also, I don't know why the LEDs bother you.
Rym: I don't know why you care so much about what someone else is wearing.
Rym: I'm just saying like I Just seems over this fashion.
Scott: I'm not getting any dumb LEDs in my computer.
Rym: Hey, I'll get back to the case.
Rym: so the other thing I realized part of the reason I picked this case is that the way to put a CPU cooler on today is Do it like most people do just fucking randomly buy one and it doesn't fit in your case and you have problems Buy one that's like this giant piece of ridiculous metal that fills the entire inside of your case.
Rym: what that's what most CPU coolers look like.
Rym: or Get a liquid pump where there's just one little contact on the CPU and then you put this big radiator like on the a like.
Rym: You know where your fans go in the front of your case.
Rym: you put a radiator there behind the fans instead.
Rym: So the CPU is radiating to this giant thin radiator Right where your fans are far away from the actual CPU and just pumping liquid back and forth between it.
Scott: Do you need a pump for that?
Rym: They.
Rym: so you buy these self-enclosed things.
Scott: What if the liquid comes out?
Scott: What if it breaks what it you know, then your CPU over there's like hoses or like yeah It's all a built-in unit.
Rym: the failure rate on these things is actually really really low.
Scott: I know I feel like it's gonna spill everywhere and ruin everything.
Rym: one if it spills everywhere.
Rym: It's not gonna break anything.
Rym: It's just a moderate like oil whatever mess.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: it's not water.
Rym: It's not water.
Rym: No, you don't put water in something like this.
Rym: but basically this that's the best way to do it that I can see and after reading a bunch of guys a lot of people do crazy crap that I'm not gonna do where they'll basically buy like a water reservoir and Instead of having this self-contained unit that someone else put together that you just buy and install They'll buy a pump they'll buy all the different pipes.
Rym: They'll have this connected to Another system that's also cooling the inside of their motherboard and all their other bits.
Rym: this ridiculous nonsense.
Rym: So instead I'm just getting this one cracking thing that cools the CPU and because that is made by the same company that makes that Case.
Rym: it's guaranteed to fit perfectly.
Scott: the case doesn't come with it.
Rym: No case doesn't come with that.
Scott: Well, they got you.
Rym: It doesn't know what.
Rym: how much is?
Scott: how much is this thing?
Rym: hundred bucks?
Scott: Oh If I'm paying zero, but you pretty.
Scott: instead of getting that you could have gotten two m2s, right pretty much God.
Rym: What CPU are you gonna buy if you buy a new computer?
Rym: Are you gonna get the fastest Intel chip?
Rym: Cuz there's no cooler.
Scott: I'll just get like a cheapo cooler for 20 bucks.
Rym: What cheapo cooler?
Scott: or I'll buy an Intel cooler from someone.
Rym: the stock Intel cooler cannot clock.
Rym: cool that chip effectively.
Rym: It'll run at about three point four gigahertz.
Scott: If you put that I'm sure there is a normal cooler.
Scott: I can find a new egg if I looked.
Rym: yeah.
Rym: So what you can get if you for about 40 bucks?
Rym: Let me check new eggs.
Rym: for 40 or 50 bucks You can get one of the giant ones that fills the whole inside of your case with metal.
Rym: No, I don't want that For 80 bucks you can get a smaller radiator But reports seem to indicate that the clock the chip tends to only run at like 3.8 gigahertz if you get that one Mm-hmm.
Rym: I did a lot of research on these.
Rym: I might be able to get away with one smaller cooler and save a little bit of money and I actually haven't finished that research Yet, but this seemed this is the guaranteed safe cooler.
Rym: because another thing I went guaranteed safe on was the power supply.
Rym: so I did a lot of research as to how much power modern computers need and Every and all the calculations I could do said that I need about a 550 to 650 watt power supply.
Rym: So I'm getting a 760 watt one and I'm getting a really high quality one because that guarantees 100% will not have a power supply problem because I just never want to deal with a power supply problem again on a computer ever.
Rym: This one's super highly rated.
Rym: It's some Corsair whatever.
Rym: It's platinum certified.
Rym: So it'll actually save me a moderate amount of money and The reviews again seem pretty good.
Rym: What else did I get in here?
Rym: so the case yeah, it's that NXT.
Rym: whatever case I'll just link to it.
Rym: Seriously, I think it's a really good case.
Rym: There's probably a better case out there.
Rym: I am NOT willing to spend the effort to find it because this case is really good and it's only and it's only 100 bucks.
Scott: So here is a cooler master.
Scott: hyper 212 Evo CPU cooler with 120 millimeter PWM fan 120.
Rym: All right, so that'll be a little loud.
Scott: It's the highest Rated cooler on Newegg.
Scott: It's $30.
Scott: You can even it's 25 after a fine.
Scott: Is that for LGA 1151?
Scott: it is LGA 1151 and it says in CPU support core i7 extreme All right, and it looks it looks pretty small.
Scott: It's just you know, it looks like a normal cooler.
Scott: It's got some pipe thingy sticking out the side of it and it's you know, so it does.
Rym: so it doesn't have a radiator.
Rym: It's just like.
Scott: it's like it looks like a radiator But yeah, it's.
Scott: it's pretty much just looks like that, you know an alternative to the Intel normal cooler.
Scott: But it doesn't look ridiculous or large or anything.
Scott: It's perfectly serviceable for 30 bucks.
Rym: a little bit of follow-up research before I've read those kinds of coolers won't fully cool this chip.
Scott: Well, it has five eggs and four thousand and nineteen reviews.
Scott: So that sounds promising to me.
Rym: the other thing that worries me is you said 120 millimeter fan.
Rym: that implies that it's a lot louder than the one I'm getting.
Scott: the Main selling point of the way, I guess if you have the liquid going to a radio, there's no fan, right?
Rym: Well, there's.
Rym: you have your case fans in the front.
Rym: Like there are still those are those are there.
Scott: Anyway, and also that one less you have one less fan.
Rym: Yeah, but here's also that annex that case I'm getting the NX zxt or whatever.
Scott: The first review says quieter than stock fans Both AMD and Intel.
Rym: the review of this crowd this cracking thing in this case basically says it is fucking silence Mm-hmm, but this case is only a hundred bucks.
Rym: I paid more than that for the case I got now and I do not like the case I got now.
Scott: This says provides really good temperature control to an i7 6700 K.
Rym: All right, maybe I'll do a little more research on the cooler 30 bucks for just a normal old cooler.
Scott: I don't know why it says Intel.
Scott: they could have just charged $30 more included one of these.
Rym: That's what it is interesting.
Rym: It still bothers me because I didn't notice until a couple months ago that Intel does.
Scott: I don't know how much research you did because this is just like the top of new egg the number one rated cooler.
Rym: Yeah, I can go back and see because Multiple of the like cooler master whatever's the reviews I was reading said that the chip only ran at like three point six three point seven like it wouldn't say you think right there.
Rym: Yeah, and I'll look at it.
Scott: It was on the front page of new egg cooler section.
Rym: Oh What else did I get in this case?
Rym: So the other thing I'm getting Ram, whatever.
Rym: just 32 gigs of RAM like Rams.
Scott: Ram the different memory brand brand isn't superior.
Rym: I just got the Corsair.
Rym: whatever is a good price point.
Rym: I'm getting 2x16 because eventually I'll probably upgrade and That seems like the best.
Scott: I have 32 and it's more RAM than I've ever used ever I've never.
Scott: I don't think I'm gonna need more than 32 unless there's like Someone starts writing some really bad software.
Rym: my current computers, but I work at work.
Scott: well at work I have eight and it's definitely not enough.
Scott: I run out of RAM at work like chrome unloads tabs that are in the background because it's out of RAM.
Scott: Oh, I have to you know, so I got to get a new computer at work.
Rym: I got 32 gig at work and 12 of that is running a really powerful VM.
Rym: that I do a whole bunch of crap.
Scott: Yeah, VMS are killing me at work.
Rym: I Got a crappy firewire card, whatever.
Rym: But one more thing that I got is I did buy some spinning discs because I was you don't have existing spin and is Yeah, I'm not gonna use them.
Rym: I'm not taking anything out of this old computer except the video card.
Scott: Are the spinning just perfectly good?
Rym: They're ancient.
Scott: These there that are perfectly good.
Rym: Yeah, I'm gonna keep this computer.
Rym: I'm gonna use it for something.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: My HD PC is on its last legs.
Rym: I might just make this the HD PC The same one as I do.
Scott: mine's great.
Rym: It's overheating for one.
Rym: I got to clean it out.
Scott: She doesn't have any problem.
Rym: hard drive has some bad sectors.
Rym: There's only one hard drive in it.
Scott: This mine has one hard drive.
Scott: That's perfectly fine.
Rym: Well, mine's got some bad sectors.
Rym: Yeah, also it stutters sometimes when it's playing video.
Rym: I got it.
Rym: I got a futz with a little bit.
Scott: mine doesn't do that.
Rym: It's got an old GTX 460 in it.
Scott: Mine has like a low-profile and ATI AMD card.
Scott: that never had a problem.
Rym: Yeah, but also maybe I'll just sell this computer because it's perfectly good.
Rym: But most of the drives in it are ancient.
Rym: like I haven't said I have SSDs.
Rym: Only one of those SSDs is a modern reasonably performing one.
Rym: The other ones are old as shit and slow as shit.
Rym: by modern standards There's no point in keeping them.
Rym: Mm-hmm and the spinning discs.
Rym: They're old and low-capacity.
Rym: Like why would I even care?
Rym: I could stick them in the new computer just to have access to that old data that I don't need.
Rym: so But I was thinking about buying a new NAS and it's actually much more cost effective to just buy two four terabyte 5400 rpm discs for cheap and Just stick them in there and do a mirror and that'll just be my raid effectively.
Rym: I'll just back everything up there.
Scott: I just use my NAS.
Rym: My NAS is only two terabytes.
Scott: Mine is like six because I have four two terabyte drives in it.
Rym: Yeah, I bought my NAS is old.
Rym: It's only takes two disks.
Scott: It's almost full though.
Scott: I'm gonna have to clean out some stuff.
Rym: Yeah, mine is also always teetering on full.
Rym: I just recently dumped the whole thing up to Amazon cloud drive and I started deleting stuff.
Scott: I might do something like that cuz yeah.
Rym: But basically I've got so much like b-roll and all these things and for a long time I would back him up to the NAS and Eventually, I'd take stuff that I wasn't accessing and I stuck it on two redundant external drives and just like file them away.
Rym: but I realized it'd be much more convenient if I just kept everything local and Four terabytes I can keep like all the video will gather from GeekNights the next five years Just local and not even think about it.
Rym: It'll be just as redundant and it'll still be backed up to the cloud.
Rym: and It's way cheaper just to buy two for four terabyte like slow efficient drives.
Rym: I just throw them in there.
Rym: then it is to upgrade my NAS like so much cheaper.
Rym: That's not even a question.
Rym: So yeah, that's pretty much the computer that I'm probably gonna buy other than some tweaks.
Rym: I don't know when I'll actually pull the trigger.
Rym: cuz like I said, there's no Limitations.
Rym: there's nowhere near failing Like I'm using it now.
Scott: We just like buying stuff.
Rym: Not really it's just.
Rym: I can't easily edit 4k video and the lack of USB 3 and the lack of like modern SATA and the fact that even My 770 is running slower because I don't even have modern PCI Express.
Rym: It's all starting to add up.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.
Rym: Any patrons for this episode of GeekNights in the amount of money that they give us on a continuing basis are Alan Joyce Rebecca Dunn Nicholas Brando Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette James David White.
Rym: Christian people ask me for related a lot.
Rym: coons Jess my state e.com.
Rym: Sean Hayworth.
Rym: mechanical mind.
Rym: William Eisen rose Jeremy minor Spartacus Spartacus Spartacus Matthew Smith Kimberly bachelor Kajar Tava shin Joshiro Joe star Tyler Eller Don Schleich Sean Yeager Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand.
Rym: Robert Lee Ryan parent drew open lander.
Rym: Rara Laval Brian said Roni Rochelle, Montana Finn Eric solver on and the infinite sadness.
Rym: kinetic man Aaron Cerise Chris midkiff Chris Knox John snow Sam Cordery Daniel Redmond Krista Dodd Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: still really hard to do that without having a coughing fit since I'm still recovering from some illness and As you saw I finally got a ribs ran up on the patreon.
Rym: I would put that up many days ago but there was a oddly specific patreon problem that I have a ticket open with them and Basically, I can upload 160 kilobit per second mp3s of any length up to 100 megabytes but 192 kilobit per second mp3.
Rym: it just hangs forever and They can reproduce it but they can't explain it.
Rym: and now I leave you with something kind of weird Shit Sir you're being stopped by an officer of the New York City Police Department Manhattan district.
Rym: We're doing a hundred miles per hour in the 35 mile per hour zone.
Rym: I see your driver's license and registration, please.
Scott: Here you are.
Rym: Thank you.
Rym: Wait.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: You're Captain Jack.
Rym: Oh, yeah I'm so happy to see you my god.
Rym: Thank you I'm happy to see you.
Rym: Okay, my friends.
Rym: Listen to you.
Scott: Hey, listen, listen to.
Rym: you have to autograph cards for your friends.