Rym: It's Wednesday, March 23rd, 2016.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, we fully review Gravity Falls now that it's fully done.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So one of the reasons way back when Emily and I moved into the building where the GeekNights studio is and everything, we picked it because it had a good view, and a nice roof, and the apartment was nice, and it had bike parking in the building, which in New York City is a really, really important thing.
Scott: I have bike parking in my building.
Rym: Well, you put it out on your balcony.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Eh.
Scott: What do you mean eh?
Rym: Eh, it's moisture and it's outside and I gotta carry it up the elevator every day.
Scott: You don't carry it in an elevator.
Scott: The elevator does the carrying.
Scott: That's what an elevator is.
Scott: Also, if it's rainy or wet, I just bring it inside.
Rym: Yeah, but that's a pain.
Rym: I like to reduce clutter.
Scott: Oh, such a pain.
Rym: It's more of a pain than just having a bike parking room, but we were some of the first people to move into this building, and as time went on, the bike room got more and more crowded to the point that it is filled with bikes, like all tangled with each other, and as far as I can tell, there's only like four people in the building who actually fucking ride their bikes, and the rest of them just sit there unmoving forever, in the way, being a pain, and there's some racks you can hang the bikes from on hooks.
Scott: No one does it.
Rym: No, they're all full with people who staked out a spot by writing their apartment number in Sharpie on the thing, and if anyone else puts their bike up there, they take it down with a passive-aggressive angry note.
Rym: Even though the people who hang their bikes on that thing, I don't think have ever ridden them.
Scott: But this is another good reason.
Scott: Just keep it in your apartment, because then you have to deal with the shared space drama.
Rym: See, I didn't have to, because so few people rode their bikes that I basically just put my bike and Emily's bike right in the front of the room, in the middle of the room, blocking everything, because it didn't get in anyone's way.
Rym: The other few people who rode their bikes also just put them in the front, and basically everyone else was completely screwed if they wanted to ride their bikes, which I don't think they've ever tried to do.
Scott: If they didn't try to ride their bikes, wouldn't you steal their bikes or destroy them?
Rym: I'm pretty sure I could steal most of the bikes in there, and no one would have noticed.
Rym: I probably could have made a lot of money selling all those bikes.
Scott: Just sell all the bikes that you don't see get used ever.
Scott: So anyway, my building- And they'll be like, "Why did these bikes not get
Scott: stolen?".
Rym: I imagine someone complained, because now we have real bike parking.
Rym: They took a giant room in the basement.
Scott: That used to be an illegal apartment.
Rym: It used to be an illegal apartment.
Rym: Those people got kicked out, and now it is a giant- There's still an illegal apartment on the roof.
Rym: I'm not sure.
Rym: I haven't been up there to check.
Rym: It has a big- I mean, it was an illegal apartment.
Scott: Okay, it has a sign on the front that says, like, "Storage Room" or something, but you can clearly see that there's an air conditioner.
Scott: Why would you have an air conditioner storage room?
Scott: And why would there be a kitchen sink behind the air conditioner in a storage room?
Rym: So, I am saying I have not peeked in that window to confirm if it is still an illegal apartment in the last few months.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: I'm willing to bet it's still an illegal apartment.
Rym: And actually, they do usually, in buildings like this, put air conditioners and heating in the weird storage rooms that are outside of the normal space of the building.
Rym: Yeah, well, that was a utility sink.
Scott: With Dawn soap?
Scott: With dishes?
Rym: But no, yeah, someone was definitely living in there.
Rym: But since I last confirmed that someone's probably living in there, I have not gone back to reconfirm.
Rym: So, it's possible.
Rym: in the last few months it is no longer an illegal apartment.
Scott: It's possible.
Scott: I'm not betting on it.
Scott: It's an illegal apartment.
Scott: I think it's actually two illegal apartments, one on top of the other.
Rym: Well, the runner on the back, I wish I could move into that thing.
Rym: That weird, like, top house.
Scott: Go to the illegal apartment in a different building.
Rym: I just go knock on the door and be like, "Hey, what are you paying in
Rym: rent?".
Rym: "I'll sublet it from you for 100 bucks more a month and just get extra rooms in our apartment up
Rym: there.".
Scott: But they're not going to be able to find a cheaper place than an illegal apartment.
Rym: I'm sure that the - I mean, how do you even go about getting the illegal apartment?
Scott: You find some commercial space and live in it.
Rym: Yeah, but that's not what they did here.
Rym: This is just a residential luxury building.
Scott: They knew somebody.
Rym: How do you - yeah, so I gotta know somebody.
Rym: I'll just ask the landlord - no, I'll ask the handyman, the super.
Rym: I'll be like, "Yo, you got any illegal rooms I can rent for, like, a
Rym: friend?".
Rym: Just straight up.
Rym: So anyway, we got a new room in the basement and they put - you know those nice, like, wall mounts?
Rym: You put your bike up, there's, like, a lock built into it.
Rym: They put a bunch of them down there.
Scott: I wonder where the money for that came from.
Rym: I guess people complained.
Rym: Like, a while ago, there was no hot water in the morning if you got up after, like, 8 o'clock for a couple weeks.
Rym: Really?
Scott: And then, I guess - Whoa, I've never seen a large building run out of hot water.
Rym: I guess people bitched because - Even hotels don't run out.
Scott: Because I've been in hotels that ran out.
Scott: In the United States.
Rym: I've been in hotels in the United States that were not quality inns where it ran out.
Scott: What?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Like a Marriott or something?
Rym: Uh, the Zenkai Khan Hotel last year.
Scott: The Marriott one or the Jank one that we were in?
Rym: I think the Jank one.
Scott: The Jank one is, you know, it wasn't the one that the Khan is in.
Rym: But anyway, so they have this new thing down there, and I see they put a sign in both elevators and in the stairways that said, "Hey, move your bikes to the new bike
Rym: room.".
Scott: Yeah, I saw that sign.
Rym: So I saw that sign, and I thought, "Oh,
Rym: fuck.".
Rym: So immediately, I went down there with our bikes.
Rym: And of course, no one had put their bikes down there yet.
Rym: So I took two of those nice bike parking spaces, and I wrote our apartment number on them.
Rym: in a way it cannot be removed.
Rym: And I locked our bikes to them, and they're ours.
Rym: Because if other people are going to play that game, I'm going to play that game.
Scott: See, I just avoid the games.
Rym: Tragedy of the commons, I will always win.
Scott: I just avoid the games entirely.
Rym: But no, it's convenient.
Rym: It's a nice room, and it's giant.
Rym: Like, bigger than our living room.
Rym: So there's plenty of space for bikes down there.
Scott: Which is living it then.
Scott: Yeah, it used to be an illegal apartment.
Rym: Yeah, with weird steps.
Rym: It actually has a stepped area with carpet, a lot like the thing in that lounge we used to play D&D in in Peterson 3.
Scott: So the bikes and buildings lie, I found something out.
Rym: The fact that it's actually completely toothless?
Scott: No, it's way more, for real, toothy than I ever imagined.
Rym: Really?
Rym: Because I know of some loopholes that are guaranteed.
Scott: No, so apparently, here's a true story.
Scott: You ready for this true story?
Scott: I'm ready.
Scott: Somebody was working in a midtown, large office building.
Rym: Wow, you're starting like a horror story.
Rym: Someone was working in a large midtown office building.
Scott: Okay, they tried to do some bike action, and the building was like, "Mm-mm, we're gonna be jerks and not make this
Scott: happen.".
Scott: Right?
Scott: So they were parking their bikes outside and tying them up.
Scott: And one of them got stole.
Scott: They went to the small claims court against the building.
Rym: That's the way to do it.
Scott: And they won, like, boop, you win.
Scott: Here's enough money for your bike.
Rym: Now that's not, the law doesn't help with that, because the loophole, how they get out of the law, is actually real easy.
Rym: The building has to say, "Yes, we recognize your
Rym: request.".
Rym: And then they say, "You have to use the service
Rym: elevator.".
Rym: And then they make the service elevator hours be slightly after when everyone has to get to work, and slightly before everyone has to leave work.
Scott: Apparently, you can avoid that bullshit also.
Rym: Oh?
Rym: 'Cause I actually called the city way back with my old company asking about that, and the clerk lady I talked to said, "Yeah, that's how everyone gets around the law.
Rym: There's really no way to fix it unless you sue
Rym: 'em.".
Scott: Well, apparently, the thing is, I think if you sue 'em, you can win on that.
Rym: I think they're not- No, I would sue.
Rym: Don't you?
Scott: Right?
Scott: So, yeah, we'll see what happens at my current building.
Scott: Me and Jose, we're gonna push.
Scott: He's tying his bike up outside every day.
Scott: I'm not doing that.
Rym: I would, but I'd get my boss to give me in writing that if my bike gets stolen, they'll buy me a brand new bike of equivalent quality.
Scott: No, my bikes ... My, I guess, I don't know, two bosses up was like, "Yeah, I'm gonna work on this like a
Scott: project.".
Scott: So, I emailed him the story that I saw, and all the infos, 'cause apparently it's much stronger than I suspected.
Scott: No.
Scott: Apparently, not only can tenants ask for it, but also subtenants.
Scott: Subtenant doesn't mean employee of a company.
Scott: Subtenant means one person's renting out the whole floor, and you're renting a piece from them.
Scott: That's a subtenant.
Scott: If you're a subtenant, you can do it.
Rym: See, I'd go further.
Rym: I say the law should stipulate that buildings that have elevators have to let you use bikes in them.
Rym: full stop, no exceptions.
Rym: Fuck you.
Scott: I agree.
Scott: That's what I would do if I have this law also.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: But anyway, so the bike room's there.
Scott: I got my bike in, and over the next week, pretty much all the bike parking spots- Stolen bike part is found in your bike shop?
Rym: They shoot you.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Also, if you're caught stealing a bike, death.
Rym: We should just make death bikes.
Scott: Oh, also, before death, we have a bunch of cyclists who just volunteer every day, and we put you in a room with them for like 10 minutes.
Rym: We could just have death bikes.
Scott: And then if cyclists are bored one day, they can bike over and volunteer.
Rym: You just put bikes around the city randomly.
Rym: that, if taken and ridden more than 20 feet- The seat explodes with spikes.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Anyway, so- What if someone takes- It's an emergency, and everyone's trying to escape the city, and someone just grabs one and goes- Well, you know what?
Rym: That sucks, Mad Max.
Rym: That's how Mad Max goes.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: So, like 12 people put their bikes down there, and the bike room that we're supposed to leave is still completely full of all the bikes that no one rides, and the deadline is basically within a week- Are there any way?
Scott: nice bikes in there?
Rym: Way nice.
Rym: There's a lot of really expensive bikes, but they're not really good bikes.
Rym: All the good bikes are the people who ride them, and they're downstairs.
Scott: Okay, so there's no real nice ones that you would want.
Rym: No, but there's bikes you could sell for like 700, 800 bucks.
Scott: I'm sure the building is going to take care of that.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: The same way they take care of stuff when you leave your apartment and leave all your stuff in it and don't come back.
Rym: It's just interesting to me how many people own bikes in New York, who went through the effort to put them in the bike room in the building that has a bike room, and then have a slightly further away room.
Rym: I wonder what's going to happen when that deadline comes and goes and none of those people have moved their bikes.
Scott: I wonder what they're going to do with the room they're moving the bikes out of.
Rym: Probably just make it storage.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I mean downstairs, nothing but storage and boilers and stuff down there.
Scott: There used to be someone living down there.
Rym: There's also a whole bunch of scary industrial shit down there because it's a big building.
Scott: Dude, the downstairs in my elementary school, it's like whenever I think of a downstairs that's scary- You want to compare downstairs scary elementary schools?
Rym: I went to an ancient elementary school with a Catholic church, like an old one, like one of the older ones in the US attached to it, with tunnels connecting them to each other and all this crazy shit.
Scott: There was a giant super bank safe in the bottom.
Rym: Ooh, that's where all the dead kids are.
Scott: I went in it once or twice, I forget why.
Rym: I remember once I was breaking into, I was bored at RIT and I was busting into the tunnels and then the sub tunnels and all the places you're not supposed to go.
Rym: Because RIT has tunnels everywhere, but there were tunnels under those tunnels.
Rym: So I found a stairway that was always locked that went down from one of the sub tunnels and there was a tiny window and I could see that it went way down and it's already a full floor below the tunnel, which itself is like a floor and a half below ground.
Scott: So it was at the bottom.
Rym: So I opened the thing because it was just unlocked one day and I start creeping down and I get about halfway down and the doors kind of prop behind me and there's a little bit of light coming in and I realized I couldn't find any way to turn on any lights down there and there were scary noises coming from the bottom.
Rym: So I went back up and I resolved to come back with a flashlight and it was locked.
Rym: every time I checked again for the rest of my time at RIT.
Scott: Why don't you just unlock it?
Rym: How?
Rym: I'm not a lock pick.
Scott: You could YouTube that shit.
Rym: Yeah, I guess I could have made a bump key, but I didn't care that much.
Scott: But actually, did YouTube exist?
Rym: No, YouTube appeared while we were at RIT.
Scott: You still could have gotten eLockPicking things from the library.
Rym: In fact, the first videos we uploaded to YouTube, you can only upload 10 minutes at a time.
Rym: So a lot of our early panels are in 10 minute chunks.
Rym: That's how old we are.
Scott: But you could still go to the school library and get info.
Rym: Oh yeah, go to the special collection?
Scott: I'm just any library.
Scott: Even a public library has a book on lock picking.
Scott: And if you don't have a book on lock picking, they have a book on locksmithing because you want to be a locksmith.
Scott: And I'm sure at RIT, there are many kids who have practiced lock picking.
Scott: You could find one.
Rym: Anyway, it's anime day, and Monica in comics day, and we got to talk about that kind of stuff.
Rym: Do you got any news?
Scott: I do have a news.
Scott: So we're doing at Anime Boston, one of the panels we do there is the judge book anime by its cover, and we review one of the upcoming anime seasons, and the spring season is literally like about to start, and it had more interesting stuff, so I chose that one instead of the summer one for our panel.
Rym: I haven't looked at this at all.
Scott: Right, so one of the things on the list was, normally we're supposed to judge by the cover and not know anything about any of these shows, but there was one that I had seen the trailer for because someone posted it in our forum, and this show looks like it's going to be a great, terrific, amazing show that everyone should see.
Scott: So I can't judge it by its cover because I've seen this trailer.
Rym: Well that trailer is part of the cover, you know, because we talk about it in the panel.
Rym: Sometimes you do the Google image search.
Scott: But anyway, this show is called Sakamoto Desuka.
Scott: It's about this kid named Sakamoto, and he is like Mr.
Scott: Perfect of school, basically, right?
Scott: Like everything he does is perfect.
Scott: If you try to prank him, you can't.
Scott: He like gets good grades and he's super athletic and just like he's perfect at everything.
Scott: He cannot be fucked with at all.
Scott: Right, but he's also like so nice and it's just like he's like infuriatingly good at everything, but also awesomely good at everything.
Scott: The way that like One Punch Man or Go Go 13 or any of those people are just so good and being badass and always winning.
Rym: I'm always a fan of the infuriatingly good protagonist genre.
Scott: Yeah, so it's also well animated, so it's, you know, it's like, well, you know, it's not super well animated like Ghibli level, but it's like better animated than the closest equivalent we can think of.
Scott: It's not a modern animation.
Scott: It is modern animation.
Scott: It's not some garbage.
Scott: So this show is the show to watch in the spring season.
Scott: We'll see what happens in the summer season.
Rym: So Escaflowne now, so many people emailed me about this.
Scott: That's your show.
Rym: Read it at me about this.
Scott: That's your thing.
Rym: I haven't talked to in four or five years.
Scott: I mean, your Twitter handle is Shazar.
Rym: That is true.
Rym: Named after Cliff Shazar from Trigon.
Scott: No, not named after Cliff Shazar from Trigon.
Rym: That is the other anime Shazar though.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: You had that name, though, before Trigon was even a thing.
Rym: That is, in fact, true.
Rym: But because of Alan Shazar, who is in Escaflowne and also kind of a not great person.
Scott: If you watch the show is exactly like Rym, but Escaflowne was intentionally made his own life and he manually crafted his own personality to be a combination of Captain Tyler and Shazar on purpose.
Rym: It's more like 90 percent.
Rym: Tyler is mostly Tyler.
Scott: That's what you like to think.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know.
Rym: I never really learned how to use swords.
Rym: that well.
Scott: You had more.
Scott: You're lucky that you didn't have money.
Scott: But that is the right time.
Rym: I would have Alex's fucking sword hanging around somewhere.
Rym: It's real good.
Rym: I never got into the wheel of time when I was young and had money because there's a lot of replicas of all the things in that.
Scott: Well, no, that would have been good.
Scott: You would have spent your money on books and not on some garbage for like 300 bucks.
Rym: You get the Heron blade.
Scott: Yeah, sure.
Rym: It was always in the museum replicas catalog.
Rym: And I always look at it and be like, whoa, that's a really cool.
Scott: So you can have all the Heron.
Rym: But it's got a full tang, Scott, a full tang.
Rym: It's battle worthy.
Scott: Rym, you can have the Heron blade if I have Kalindar Heron spear.
Rym: All right.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: You have the Heron spear.
Rym: I'll take oh, what is it?
Rym: The song real nonsense that they use those giant statues.
Scott: You're not beating my Heron spear.
Rym: I think those statues beat the Heron spear.
Scott: Heron spear is just some like Heron spear can destroy the no god.
Scott: Not you know what I can't.
Rym: It's so powerful.
Scott: Not only can destroy God, just like whatever.
Scott: It can destroy the absence of gods.
Rym: That book's coming.
Scott: But giant tornado with a scary coffin in the middle.
Rym: Escaflowne was one of the anime that I like, you know, I was in high school.
Rym: I was really into anime since I was like eight years old.
Rym: But Escaflowne was an anime that I was aware of when it was in Japan and was desperately trying to see for a long time.
Rym: And then when it got released in the U.S.
Rym: on VHS, I basically watched it as fast as I possibly could.
Rym: I tried to get fansubs and actually failed because the people who were fansubbing it wouldn't distribute it to me because I didn't run an anime club.
Rym: And they didn't believe me when I lied and said that I did run an anime.
Scott: But you did eventually run an anime club.
Rym: Yeah, fuck you guys who fansub Escaflowne.
Scott: But anyway, it I didn't realize until just now.
Scott: Escaflowne had never been dubbed.
Scott: We had a VHS set that was all subs.
Scott: I thought that there was a set you could have gotten with dubs and we were just smart enough not to buy that.
Rym: But no, there was also subtitles.
Scott: There was also a DVD box set that I believed had dub on it and it did not.
Scott: And there was a dub on Fox.
Scott: But that's not Escaflowne.
Rym: The dub and that's not even complete.
Rym: The Fox box or whatever dub basically cut the show up and kind of gave it the Warriors of the Wind treatment.
Rym: I'm not even sure if they finished dubbing the entire show.
Rym: But that dub was a disaster.
Scott: It's also not Escaflowne basically.
Rym: Yeah, it's Warriors of the Wind 2.
Scott: It's like it's.
Scott: I mean, people want to talk about Macross.
Scott: I mean, Robotech isn't Macross, which it isn't.
Scott: But really, the Escaflowne on Fox is even worse than that.
Rym: But Escaflowne is actually one of my favorite anime.
Rym: And it is a really good show.
Rym: There aren't shows like it.
Rym: Partly because there's a lot of reasons.
Scott: Isaac Newton spoilers.
Rym: I feel like I should watch it again because I don't know if it warrants its high placement on my list of my favorite anime ever.
Scott: It's no Evangelion.
Rym: No, it's not.
Rym: Of course, it's not an Evangelion, but it's a good show.
Scott: Why not watch it?
Scott: It's better than like almost all the shows coming out right now.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, if it came out today, it's got new.
Rym: It would do really well.
Rym: I think it's got those musics.
Rym: It moves real fast.
Scott: It's got good characters.
Scott: It's got cliffhangers.
Rym: This is where I think Maya Sakamoto basically got her start.
Rym: This is where this is where a lot of people got like their sort of starts in anime.
Rym: So the dubs coming on Kickstarter there.
Scott: So why would you kickstart a dub?
Scott: You could just buy the DVD box set that's legally available with subs.
Scott: Why would you pay more money than that to help them make a dub that we don't?
Scott: World does not.
Rym: That is, in fact, what I don't get.
Rym: Now, I could see them making a dub if they were going to try to do what I always say they should do and give you might.
Scott: you might be a blind person who does not know Japanese, in which case this dub would be very good for you.
Rym: That is true.
Scott: But other than that, why do you want this?
Rym: Yeah, because if I were like if I had the rights to the show, you'd only dub it if you were going to put it on like Crunchyroll or Hulu or whatever and then promote it and try to get Normies to watch it like or you're going to put it on TV.
Rym: You're going to do something with it for a like not insider anime audience.
Rym: But the people who are going to preorder this are almost entirely people who know the show exists and have already seen it probably several times.
Scott: Why do they want to see it again with English language?
Rym: There's no evidence that it's going to be a better dub than any average anime dub is.
Rym: And I feel like this is just a preorder for it.
Rym: I don't need to feel like because they say straight up.
Rym: This is just a preorder because obviously one hundred and fifty grand is not enough to dub a show, right?
Rym: I mean, one hundred fifty grand is maybe enough to dub one episode of a show if you do it low rent.
Rym: But that's not.
Scott: they seem to be doing it at the usual rent level.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So they pretty much straight up are like, yeah, this is just a pre preorder for all of you who want this and that'll make.
Rym: we'll only do the dub if we know there's enough interest because this is a preorder.
Rym: So they're basically saying we're going to pay to dub it, but only if a bunch of you actually commit with money to buy it once we release it.
Rym: But I think the actual reason people are excited about this, they don't.
Rym: I don't think any of these people care about the dub because the five thousand dollar tier is gone, the four hundred dollar tier is gone.
Scott: What do you get?
Scott: Is five thousand the highest tier?
Rym: Oh, yes.
Rym: What do you get?
Rym: OK, the star.
Rym: They're all named after tarot cards.
Rym: Yeah, a one of a kind Escaflowne experience will fly you out to the Funimation office where you'll get a tour.
Scott: No one wants to do that.
Rym: A bag of Funimation goodies, garbage, and you'll get to do voice work that will appear in the dub.
Rym: So you're going to do some random background.
Rym: You're going to be that guy in that awful Gasaraki dub who says, what's wrong, you sure?
Scott: Oh, you're going to be like some knight that gets stabbed and goes, oh, I'll bet you'll get to say a word.
Rym: And it's going to because you remember that guy in Gasaraki, right?
Scott: It's going to be some guy gets cut down by fun or something.
Rym: You remember that guy in Gasaraki?
Scott: Yeah, I remember that guy.
Rym: That guy stands out like a wound to this day in my soul.
Rym: We want to go get everything in the lower tiers.
Rym: So the four hundred, three hundred, two hundred dollar tiers, which are pretty much like all crazy subscribed, are basically just giant boxes of nonsense for the show.
Rym: Nothing about the dub.
Scott: Who needs any of this garbage?
Rym: Collectors, people who want the perfect edition of Escaflowne.
Scott: I didn't think there were this many collectors.
Rym: These are the people who are who, like me, were obsessed with Escaflowne.
Rym: But unlike me, still want to spend a lot of money on getting things like a poster signed.
Scott: The existing DVD box here for four hundred bucks.
Rym: You get the box set with all the fancy art and stuff and you get a poster signed by the director, the original creator and the character designer.
Rym: Nobutaru Yuki.
Scott: OK, but I mean, I saw Nobutaru Yuki at Otakon.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So you basically.
Scott: So why do I need a thing that he wrote on to get their signatures?
Rym: And it's that kind of crap.
Rym: It's the dub doesn't even need to be a part of this.
Rym: I'll bet if they just said Escaflowne re-released without a dub, they would have raised almost the exact same amount of money.
Rym: So maybe they're going to.
Rym: they're doing the dub just because they're going to get the interest from this and it'll sort of break even.
Rym: And then they're going to try to push Escaflowne to the mainstream audience.
Scott: Maybe it's just the anime voice actors like kind of upset because there's less dubs lately because everything is going pretty much straight to the Internet streaming with subtitles.
Scott: And they're like, let's you know, we want to make money doing this again.
Rym: Except most anime voice actors who are good also just do voiceover work and they're great.
Rym: And that other work, they're only bad in anime dubs.
Rym: I mean, they're not.
Rym: they're not hurting for though.
Rym: Actually, I've seen a few voice actors we know who are friends with me on LinkedIn in the last year updating their statuses to things to the effect of, yeah, I really would like some work.
Rym: So we'll see.
Rym: I don't think there's any reason to back this unless I mean, if I was going to.
Scott: We should find something that like no one will ever dub ever and dub it.
Scott: Just like as best we actually try as best as we can ourselves, which is to offend us, saying it's got to offend us, people we know, right?
Scott: Just do the best that we can do, which is not that great.
Scott: But just do the best we can do honestly and see what happens.
Scott: Yes, I'm like Zazen Jotaro.
Scott: It's not bad.
Rym: Well, wait.
Rym: Most of these low tiers don't even get you Escaflowne.
Scott: How much do you have to pay to actually get the DVD box set of the full series?
Rym: Fifteen bucks just gets you a certificate.
Rym: Thirty bucks gets you a preorder of the movie.
Scott: Oh, I was about to ask if you get the movie and any of these tiers.
Rym: Thirty five.
Scott: Are they dubbing the movie too?
Rym: I assume so.
Scott: So they're going to dub the movie and the TV show.
Scott: That makes me kind of okay.
Rym: For sixty five dollars, you get all that nonsense above.
Rym: You get a preorder of the Escaflowne TV series, part one featuring episodes one through thirteen.
Rym: Fuck you.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: This Kickstarter, that's the biggest rip off I ever heard.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The whole box.
Scott: How much is the whole box set on Amazon, the one that we already have?
Rym: I don't even know.
Scott: I'm going to go look right now.
Rym: But so it's interesting.
Rym: Well, Scott's looking that up because I had to make a new version of foreign anime openers because, you know, I want to have two hours of material so I can do the panel with different audiences, even though you people keep coming to it and watching the same Captain Harlock thing over and over and over again.
Rym: It's real hard to find foreign anime openers because even pretty much everywhere in the world, except for Russia and Korea, they just use the Japanese songs and they just subtitled stuff because no one cares anymore.
Scott: Oh, look at that.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: So, Rym, do you still have that Escaflowne DVD box?
Rym: Actually, for various reasons, I have two of them.
Scott: All right.
Scott: But so on Amazon, it's one of the.
Scott: it turns out it's one of those things that they didn't make that many.
Rym: And now it's rare that.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So they're selling.
Scott: I mean, they're being priced on Amazon at one fifty.
Scott: But no one seems to be buying at one fifty.
Scott: But I'm sure if you put it up at one hundred, maybe someone would buy or even seventy five.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Thing is for one hundred and twenty five.
Rym: Oh, no.
Rym: One hundred twenty five.
Rym: You still only get part one and part two.
Rym: OK, so you have to pay one hundred and twenty five bucks to actually get Escaflowne in this preorder.
Rym: And that is a limited tier.
Rym: There's only five hundred of those.
Scott: But I have a feeling we go to anime Boston.
Scott: We'll be able to find this box that cheap if we see it here on eBay.
Scott: It looks like a legit ones on eBay.
Scott: You know, it could be bootleg ones that just stole the art from the legit ones.
Scott: But these look like legit ones to me selling for twenty on eBay.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So there's no reason to buy it at anime Boston.
Scott: This is Escaflowne a complete collection, eight, this set brand new.
Scott: The image in the picture here looks like it's the image from the real thing.
Scott: It could be so bootleg, though.
Rym: So I did a control F on the Kickstarter.
Rym: The word remaster doesn't appear anywhere.
Rym: So I don't think you get any thing beyond that.
Rym: I mean, they're saying HD.
Rym: Pretty sure it's just DVDs.
Scott: Here's one that's definitely legit because it's the box with the lid that comes with the robot and stuff and either even showing the DVD cases spread out.
Scott: And it's definitely been watched and they're selling it for seventy five.
Scott: So whatever.
Rym: Yeah, no, I'm so I'm excited that this might cause a renaissance of Escaflowne watching because I think a lot of kids who watch anime today, their minds would be blown by this show because there aren't a lot of shows like it.
Scott: Well, there's not a lot of fantasy adventure.
Scott: that's somewhat serious, but there's plenty of main character.
Scott: magical girl goes to another the universe.
Rym: Yeah, but like full on high fantasy, like all the slayers kind of stuff, but actually serious and not just no comedy.
Scott: Escaflowne exit the cat girl for like five minutes.
Rym: There's comedy at times.
Rym: Yeah, it's just it.
Rym: definitely not like the comedy gets shed away.
Rym: Yeah, El Hazzard is about 40 percent comedy overall.
Scott: El Hazzard is Escaflowne plus a lot more lols.
Rym: Yeah, and a lot more weird fan service.
Rym: Cat armor.
Rym: Cat armor is great.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So, Scott, have you ever wondered why we have butt hair?
Scott: You mean hair on your butt or hair in the crack?
Rym: In the crack.
Rym: Like you ever wonder why there's hair in there?
Scott: Because there's more hair there than everywhere else.
Scott: I've heard stories of people removing that hair and then having a butt that gets sealed shut and is a disgusting result.
Rym: Ah, you were thinking of the story that I remember that we learned about at RIT, the pass out and vomit story from the yes.
Rym: So someone apparently in the Crash Course videos and SciShow and all that has when they have a they have a one punch man avatar and they ask anyone of the one punch man avatar they posted legit.
Scott: So someone today with a one with a Saitama avatar posted the images of what's almost definitely pretty legit.
Scott: The Nintendo NX controller.
Scott: You can always trust Saitama avatar.
Scott: So that is the only anime anime.
Scott: It's like the exception to anime avatars, not all anime avatars.
Scott: Saitama avatars are like the exact opposite of all anime avatars.
Scott: If someone has one, they're basically just follow them because whatever they say is great.
Rym: Lido Johnny with the Saitama avatar has posted a comment that gets upvoted a lot on every single video they have ever uploaded asking quotes in all caps.
Rym: Why is there hair on my anus?
Rym: So they decided to do a special and they answered that question.
Rym: So the do you want to know the answer?
Rym: Scientists don't know.
Rym: It's actually a mystery.
Rym: What?
Rym: No, for real.
Rym: There are some theories.
Scott: I mean, it's just right now.
Scott: Yeah, it is just not to be a reason.
Scott: Well, yeah, but the reason because people kept screwing people who had butt hair.
Rym: No.
Rym: So they're the butt hair.
Scott: Maybe you had butt hair or not didn't affect whether people made babies with you.
Scott: So some people, you know, it might have.
Rym: So actually what they come up with in the videos, one, they talk about all the theories and also didn't affect whether you lived or died.
Rym: So one that I could add long, long enough to screw and actually may have.
Rym: So one of the theories has to do with there was no evolutionary pressure for hair there to go away.
Scott: That's what I'm saying.
Rym: But hair went away everywhere else.
Rym: So why not there?
Rym: It's not tied to pubic hair, secondary sex or anything.
Rym: It's completely independent.
Scott: Hair didn't necessarily go everywhere else.
Rym: Well, man.
Scott: Exhibit A, Scott Johnson.
Rym: Did you see the font someone made that is pictures of their shoulder hairs?
Scott: I got shoulder hairs.
Rym: It's pictures of individual shoulder hairs on their body that form the shapes of letters.
Rym: It's a font you can use.
Rym: It's horrific.
Scott: Oh, I don't have that.
Rym: You don't have words up there?
Rym: No.
Rym: One of the theories involves that without hair there, you'll have warm, moist skin rubbing against warm, moist skin.
Rym: And it implies that that story we read at RIT might be a legitimate concern.
Scott: Yeah, I totally believe that.
Rym: But there's no evidence of that.
Scott: Well, at Rym you're just going to self-experiment.
Rym: So he proposes at the end of the video an experiment that would determine.
Rym: And apparently getting rid of the hair down there and forcing someone to see is not a valid experiment because the shaving or, quote, whatever method you use to remove the hair is equally likely to be the source of irritation.
Scott: So this video, if you wax your butt, that's going to be pretty irritating.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So this video goes into the science of why we don't actually know why there's hair in our butt.
Scott: You can also put Nair in your butt.
Rym: No, I will never let Nair touch my body in my entire life.
Scott: I'm going to take some Nair and throw it at you.
Rym: No, you're not.
Scott: Fun fact, I'll just slip some onto your keyboard and be like typing and be like, there is a I have my fingers.
Rym: A lot of men in America at least get injured by Nair.
Scott: What?
Scott: And it's because why are they touching it?
Rym: They use it for, you know, balls or whatever.
Rym: No, but they being stupid assume that man branded Nair is stronger than woman branded Nair.
Scott: It's the same shit in a different bottle.
Rym: No, it's not.
Rym: So they buy female branded Nair and use that.
Rym: But on average, Nair that is made for a woman to use for the kinds of places that women use it is actually way stronger than what they make for men.
Rym: I mean, I know that men are little babies.
Scott: In high school, I knew kids who put like Icy Hot on their nuts.
Scott: Right.
Rym: So that's that's a yeah, whatever.
Rym: I'm not touching Nair.
Scott: That's high school level material.
Rym: Actually, I wonder if we'll find out more about Nair's child in the upcoming Nair.
Scott: Anyway, so for anyone who doesn't know, Nair is like this hair removal cream that burns your hairs off, basically.
Scott: Anyway, so you've heard the phrase like milk toast, right?
Scott: It's like milk toast is like usually an insult to someone because they're so boring and plain.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, if you think and basic, if I imagine the word milk toast, I imagine a perfect picture of Milhouse Van Houten.
Scott: Yeah, but milk bread, milk toast is actually a real thing.
Scott: that is delicious.
Scott: You'll often buy it at the Japanese bakery or whatever.
Scott: Yeah, but how do you make that?
Scott: How do they make that?
Scott: Apparently, in order to make that and the reason it's not really a thing in most countries is because you need an ingredient that I don't even know the real name of.
Scott: It's known as bread improver.
Rym: Bread improver.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: So you can get...
Rym: That sounds ominous.
Scott: If I would say in Japan, I could just go to the grocery store and buy some bread improver.
Scott: But in the United States, it's not so easy to get bread improver.
Rym: Whole grain bread improver from King Arthur Flour.
Scott: Oh, how about that?
Scott: There you go.
Rym: It looks like it's just flour.
Scott: Yeah, who knows?
Scott: But anyway, if you can't get the bread improver, because it's not like the grocery store.
Scott: Find me a grocery store that actually has that, right?
Scott: They don't have it a stop and shop.
Rym: I'm going to check my fresh direct.
Scott: OK, but anyway, if you can't get the bread improver, which you probably can't unless you buy it on the Internet or something, right?
Scott: What do you do if you want to make some some milk bread?
Scott: So there's this Chinese lady and she has a website, Christine's Recipes.
Scott: And here's this other website, Kirby's Cravings, who made Christine's recipe for the milk bread.
Scott: And apparently the secret thing that they do is they use something known as the Tang Zong method, which I probably pronounced wrong because it's a Chinese word.
Scott: And in this method, you basically sort of take some flour and some water and like you warm it up and like you cook it like sixty five Celsius to basically make this other stuff, this Tang Zong, this like flour paste, huh?
Scott: And then you use that instead of using bread improver or any kind of preservatives or fluffing agents or anything like that.
Rym: It's got to get on it.
Scott: Maybe it's it's work, but you can make what looks appears visually in these photographs to be delicious milk bread.
Rym: Watch it's a trap.
Rym: It's like the anarchist cookbook, fake recipes for bombs.
Rym: It just makes like terrible bread.
Scott: If warming up flour in a pot is going to make a bomb.
Scott: Oh, that's a problem in the moment.
Rym: The next book club book will be Margaret Edwards, Oryx and Crake, because I'm going to pause the Wheel of Time books at the end.
Scott: You can't pause the Wheel of Time.
Scott: It's never ending because it's in the third age.
Rym: So it's a Wheel of Time.
Scott: It's a Wheel of Time.
Scott: Not easy.
Scott: It's not the line of time that has a beginning and an end.
Scott: It's not the line segment of time.
Rym: Yeah, the wheel.
Rym: There are so many characters that hit a point where there is a name of one of the And then that as to die ended up in a conversation that involved another.
Rym: as to die that I thought for most of the previous four books were the same person because their names are.
Rym: they differ by one letter and they just never been in the same area before.
Rym: And they're very different.
Rym: And I didn't realize that.
Rym: I just thought I just thought this one wizard was really erratic in her behavior.
Rym: OK, so we're going to be at Anime Boston this weekend.
Rym: On Friday, role playing anime.
Rym: We're going to talk about what role playing systems to use if you want to role play anime, because I'll tell you what, the anime branded role playing systems are hot garbage.
Rym: Judge anime by its covers Friday night.
Rym: That's the main event.
Rym: That's our like big ass anime Boston tradition.
Rym: We do this every year and it will not disappoint.
Scott: Is this the third or fourth time we've done this?
Rym: Yeah, we do it every year since that first year in 2013.
Rym: And we're going to keep doing it every year.
Rym: Saturday, how to run an anime club more for an anime openers, which is almost all new content and a motivational anime.
Rym: We're talking about like, you know, a pedal and why it pumps you up to bike the weekend right after that at Zank icon.
Rym: I will be there.
Rym: Scott will not.
Rym: And on Saturday, I'm doing how to run an anime club with the other Scotts.
Rym: I'm doing analyzing anime utenna because that's a good crowd for that kind of panel.
Rym: And I'm doing practical game theory.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Got anything else?
Rym: We'd talk about not really ourselves on the Internet.
Scott: Go go on the Internet and look at our things that we make besides this.
Rym: Like we have YouTube channels and Twitter's and Patreon's going strong and real close to that goal.
Rym: Five people have revealed that they found several of the beta episodes of GeekNights.
Rym: It's not hard.
Scott: People are just trying harder recently.
Rym: So it was explaining to me how the most recent person found it.
Rym: And basically it was typing too fast.
Rym: Hit enter before they finished typing something in a in a browser bar and it hit one.
Rym: He was like, what?
Scott: Oh, it's not hard.
Scott: It's just guessing URLs with.
Scott: they're not like obfuscated in any way.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But that no one appears to have found all of them.
Scott: But I'm actually not sure if all of them are actually still on the Internet because all the ones that we shared with our friends only in that PHP back in 2005 are on the Internet.
Rym: I might have direct shared.
Scott: And if you type if you type the correct URL in your browser, the Web server that they are on will send the MP3s to you free of charge.
Rym: I can't tell or remember if the episodes from before that point, we just never shared with anyone because we thought they were bad, maybe.
Scott: But if I direct shared them with people, the reason they are hard to find is because there are no HTML or otherwise other documents on the Internet with a links pointing at these URLs.
Scott: You know what I want to figure them out is to just type them in.
Scott: And I'm curious how much content is available on the Internet only in this form that you can't Google search for because it's not indexed.
Scott: But if you type in the right URL, imagine what kind of wonderful things are out there.
Scott: Like, are there?
Scott: like entire movies that like no one's ever seen?
Scott: But there's an MP4 like hosted somewhere.
Scott: And if you guessed it right, you could get it.
Rym: I'll bet the A people Gaga is out there somewhere in some directory on a Unix server.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, you know, how do you even search for that?
Rym: Gaga.
Scott: You can't even search for that, right?
Rym: You know how you search for it?
Rym: The way you search for stuff in the 90s, you search to find like places that reference something that doesn't appear to exist anymore.
Rym: And then you start poking around with URLs and directory explorers.
Scott: Maybe we should make a search engine specifically for this kind of search.
Rym: Oh, lost Web or something.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: It only indexes like Apache index pages.
Scott: Actually, you know, you search by file name.
Rym: That's something we could make.
Scott: I don't think you can search by like domain and file name and extension type and file size and things and date date because the dates are on there.
Scott: So you can be like old stuff only.
Scott: So I want to find MP3 before the year 2010.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, you have to uncook them when you download them.
Scott: That'll be an option.
Rym: Yeah, I read the other day, I randomly found a script that I used to use to uncook MP3s, but I download.
Scott: someone brought up some other stuff that they found while searching.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: That we played a forum, Forgotten Realms, Dungeons and Dragons game on a PHP BB a long time ago.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And there is some amazing descriptive text in there.
Scott: I was a mind player.
Rym: I was the typical.
Rym: Alish is our looking elf dude.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: You should have been a skeleton.
Rym: I like my elf dude.
Scott: Mind Flayer.
Rym: So Scott finally watched the end of Gravity Falls.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: And we can now review it fully.
Rym: I assume you've all seen it.
Rym: If you haven't, I guess you should.
Scott: I realized, though, when like, you know, watching all the remaining episodes I hadn't seen yet, which is right, which was a lot because you had left off before Mad Max.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: That I don't remember a lot of stuff from earlier because this was a show that I didn't like.
Scott: marathon all at once.
Scott: It's a show that, like, I watched over a long period of time.
Scott: Like, I watched it in chunks, like maybe four or five chunks.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: And so within each chunk, I remembered everything.
Scott: But like, you know, from one chunk to the next is hard to remember everything from the previous chunk.
Rym: Well, it's interesting because I watched like we were both watching it about the same time and then remember it like in season one, it stopped and then it started again.
Scott: Yeah, it did that a few times.
Scott: There's a time where it stopped after that Halloween episode at the convenience store.
Rym: After the Halloween episode, I didn't like.
Rym: I like the show, OK, but I didn't like it that much.
Rym: It wasn't.
Scott: it wasn't one of those shows at any point where I was like, oh, my God, got to watch an exhibit them again.
Rym: So I didn't pay attention to it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So even when new episodes came out again, I didn't rush out to get them.
Scott: I sort of waited and then eventually saw them.
Rym: But then there was a point that inspired me and Emily to start watching it again was you started watching it again for some reason.
Rym: And you got through the end of season one with Bill and like that stuff started to happen.
Rym: And you were like, oh, Bill Triangle Guy and I saw Triangle Guy around.
Rym: And I was like, oh, I guess Gravity Falls went somewhere.
Rym: So I went back and started watching it and now we're done with it.
Rym: So I guess we'll try to save spoilers for the end.
Rym: But if I had to fully review this show, it is a perfectly adequate kids cartoon.
Rym: It's good.
Rym: It's not the greatest show in the world.
Scott: The thing is, yeah, it's definitely not the greatest show in the world.
Scott: But I think it's it's one of those things where, you know, it doesn't really have too many flaws in itself.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Just looking at it on its own.
Rym: It had potential flaws that it actually addressed satisfactorily.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But it also didn't have anything that like made it incredible.
Scott: There wasn't like some masterful thing that it did.
Scott: that was like, oh, look at this amazing thing.
Scott: It's just like, you know, really good, really well done, you know, unique in a lot of ways.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, it did things that other things didn't do.
Scott: It was a kid's story wise, character wise, art wise, pretty unique.
Scott: Right.
Rym: It's a kid's show that set up some kinds of relationships and then had them not work out.
Rym: It's also a kid's show that got real scary.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: And also, it's better than a lot of its, you know, contemporary works.
Scott: It's not the best.
Scott: It's not Adventure Time good.
Scott: Right.
Rym: It's not even Avatar good.
Rym: Avatar is still like a full tier above.
Rym: I haven't seen that, but you should watch.
Scott: It's better than like a lot of the garbage you watch, like the kid who's a fish or whatever.
Scott: It's better than that.
Rym: The Amazing World of Gumball is an amazing kid's show.
Scott: And it's better than Teen Titans.
Rym: Go is also an amazing kid's show.
Scott: I haven't seen that.
Rym: Actually, it's an amazing adult show.
Rym: You should watch the hell out of it.
Scott: But, you know, it's better.
Rym: Do you hate all the DC stuff that's dumb?
Scott: Mostly, yeah.
Rym: Then you'll like Teen Titans because it's nothing but making fun of that crap.
Scott: Yeah, but it's still dumb DC stuff.
Rym: Yeah, but I'll put it this way.
Rym: People who actually like DC really don't like Teen Titans and everyone else likes it.
Scott: Anyway, but yeah, it's there's a lot of things that Gravity Falls is better than.
Scott: And that's why, even though it's not like, oh, my God, the greatest thing ever, you have.
Scott: you're done watching like Adventure Time and a few other things.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: this is the.
Scott: this is the next thing on list.
Rym: It's a good show to watch, like while you're eating dinner, like watch an episode while you're doing stuff when you get home.
Scott: Like, well, I think I'll sort of write because it's it's got so much going on.
Scott: I think you really got to pay attention to it closely.
Rym: I mean, like eating dinner, not like playing a game or doing something else, like distracting.
Scott: I mean, I'm one of those weirdos who always gives everything I'm watching full attention if I'm actually going to watch something.
Rym: I the only splitting attention I'll do these days is I will watch some things while I'm eating dinner.
Rym: But those are things like Last Week Tonight or The Daily Show.
Scott: Pretty much running, man.
Scott: That's about it.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Or like a Simpsons episode, which Simpsons is pretty good lately.
Scott: I haven't watched the Simpsons episode.
Rym: I've been watching a lot of old Simpsons.
Scott: I can't even remember the last time I watched the Simpsons.
Rym: Some recent ones.
Rym: Pretty good, actually.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: Anyway.
Rym: But Gravity Falls is I don't want to even compare it because there's some kid shows like The Amazing World of Gumball that are mostly comedy and they're kind of a separate space.
Rym: Gravity Falls is in that space of.
Rym: it's a kid show that has a plot and continuity and has serious moments and a serious story that resolves itself in a serious way.
Scott: You know what I think?
Scott: I think it's at the same level as Bravest Warriors.
Scott: That's a level.
Rym: Hmm.
Rym: So I like Bravest Warriors.
Scott: And it's real similar to Bravest Warriors in a lot of ways, too.
Rym: A lot more than I like Gravity Falls.
Rym: But I don't think I can disagree with you saying that they're similar, like average quality.
Scott: But I mean, even the plots of similar kind of things going on, right?
Scott: Even though Gravity Falls is more of a present day and deals more fantasy aesthetic and Bravest Warriors as a future space aesthetic, it's more unicorns and shit.
Rym: Yeah, magical realism is like the real world.
Rym: And then wait, wait, wait.
Scott: I mean, there are aliens and stuff in Bigfoot.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But well, that's still a situation of in Bravest Warriors.
Scott: It's this mystery of like, oh, what's going on?
Scott: There's this emotion lord guy and weird shit.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And Gravity Falls like, oh, this town.
Scott: Weird shit.
Scott: Right.
Rym: What's interesting is if you watch season one until like they have the mystery of the book, but they don't really push it like it's like X-Files, like it starts with like there's a mystery.
Scott: And then for most of the Gravity Falls has a I think a too high proportion of a Nami episodes that don't deal with the plot of the book.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Most of season one is entirely forgettable, like they're OK episodes.
Scott: But like if you even want even late near the end of the show, there was one episode that was oh, which one was the one?
Scott: Yeah, the DMD one.
Scott: Oh, screw that.
Rym: DMD episode was really.
Scott: that was a bad episode.
Rym: You can tell when a show that might be the worst episode in the show, the DMD one, because it does that thing of, hey, let's spoof a genre.
Rym: And clearly did not know anything about that genre at all.
Scott: Well, no, I mean, clearly the people who, you know, had played D&D.
Scott: But the point is that Dexter's Lab already did the D&D episode.
Scott: So there's no reason for anyone else to ever attempt to do that again.
Scott: You're only going to do worse than that, because that is like one of the best episodes of Dexter's Lab.
Scott: That says a lot about Dexter's Lab versus Gravity Falls.
Scott: Not that those are related to each other.
Rym: Dexter's Lab is more against.
Scott: the D&D episode of Dexter's Lab is one of the best episodes of Dexter's Lab, except for maybe like Action Hank and Omelette du Fromage and yeah, the high concept one.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But the D&D episode of Gravity Falls is like the worst episode of Gravity Falls.
Rym: But if like when season one, until Bill showed up, I was getting a little bored.
Rym: And I was like, if I missed an episode, I wouldn't have noticed.
Scott: I think, well, because the the one thing in Gravity Falls is they have many plot lines.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Every character has like a plot that's got to resolve.
Rym: Well, every character has their arc.
Rym: That's obviously going forward.
Rym: That got incrementally pushed in some episodes, but not others.
Rym: Right.
Rym: There was the overall plot of the book and what's going on with that.
Rym: And then there was the local mystery of that episode.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: But the thing is, it's some of these plot lines are really interesting and cool.
Scott: And some of the characters and some are not.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So the whole like Wendy Dipper thing is like it's there for the whole fucking show.
Scott: And it gets way more attention than it deserves because it's one of the plot lines that are like the not good one.
Rym: Yeah, I am so uninterested.
Rym: And I think the audience of the show is, too, in that typical trope of the protagonist guy really likes this girl and a bunch of teen bullshit happens.
Scott: Yeah, there should have been way more Stan, replace all that with more Stan stuff.
Rym: But to their credit, they took that.
Rym: And then when they started getting serious, they basically just stabbed that relationship to death and had a.
Scott: But they still kept, you know, the existence of that plot line didn't leave.
Scott: Even in the final episode, they kept, you know, giving it some that.
Rym: No, they resolved it.
Rym: It was friendship.
Scott: Sure.
Rym: But they still kept, you know, it was more that there were too many episodes that had a primary driver of Dipper wants to get with this girl and does stupid crap because of it.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: And actually, no, if I was to say the worst episode of the show, it's the one where Dipper tries to pick up girls.
Scott: That's a bad one.
Scott: That's probably the worst one, because the problem is that episode is saved by all the other stuff that goes on and all the day where they're pranking all the different.
Scott: Yeah, that is that concept is great.
Scott: And I wish they would have given that more screen time.
Rym: I like how the pranks were all just crimes.
Scott: Well, like, yeah, well, like he said he was basically going to turn the mountain upside down.
Scott: I was like, oh, man, let's see.
Scott: And he didn't really, you know, do much.
Scott: It's like, oh, come on.
Rym: But in that episode, the moral of it was basically if you're a guy and you ever talk to a girl in any friendly way, you're clearly trying to date her and she'll give you her phone number if you're confident.
Rym: But then if you talk to a second girl ever, you're cheating.
Rym: Yeah, that episode just was not missed the mark.
Rym: It's like the.
Rym: it's like the episode of My Little Pony in season one where the moral was basically a leap of faith.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: Gravity Falls is not as good as My Little Pony.
Scott: And actually, I get there's a parallel between these two shows.
Scott: And that parallel is the parallel between Diamond Tiara and Principia, whatever her name is, lives in the castle.
Rym: Both had plots that resolved similarly.
Rym: Right.
Scott: The same exact character.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Basically.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Pretty sure her and Dipper eventually date.
Rym: That's my guess.
Rym: They set that up nicely.
Scott: You know, if you're wondering about the show, the point the point I wanted to make about that, though, is that the girl in Gravity Falls, whatever her name is.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: it seems like when she resolves you, she actually like goes from like, you know, the start, which is I hate you die to.
Scott: Are you actually like you now?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: You're awesome character.
Scott: Diamond Tiara resolves.
Scott: And it's like you're still a bitch.
Scott: I hate you.
Rym: Diamond Tiara did OK, though.
Scott: I still hate Diamond Tiara.
Rym: Her parents made her that way.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Also, she can still dine to fire.
Rym: Her fucking cutie mark made her the way she is.
Rym: Can't escape that.
Scott: She can still dine to fire.
Scott: Get her out of here.
Scott: If she's she's on screen, I don't want her to be on screen.
Scott: If the other girl's on screen, I'm like, yeah, all right.
Rym: We got to wear that llama sweater.
Rym: I'd rather have had an episode where maybe her toadies should have betrayed her in some epic Nanami style fashion.
Scott: Maybe.
Rym: But anyway, so.
Rym: but Gravity Falls just was OK until Bill came and they started following the plot.
Rym: It's like the opposite of the X-Files.
Rym: The X-Files was only good when it was Monster of the Week.
Rym: And then when they started actually following the plot, it was stupid.
Scott: Well, the other problem with X-Files is that they didn't.
Scott: they kept when they followed the plot, they didn't really follow it.
Scott: They just said, oh, remember, there's a plot that's.
Scott: that's not stopping.
Scott: And we're never actually going to reveal that moment where anything about it, when Scully just finds a UFO, that's the last episode of X-Files I ever watched.
Scott: The second last episode X-Files ever watched because I was like, oh, my God, they found a UFO just like on the beach.
Scott: It's got like runes on it or something.
Rym: Part of it like flies across the room and hits the Bible and points at something.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: it's like literally like you found the shit like.
Scott: here it is.
Scott: I'm standing next to it.
Scott: And the next episode was like something completely unrelated.
Rym: And she's like, I don't think anything supernatural is going on here, Mulder.
Scott: And then they never go back to that ever.
Scott: And I don't think it like I didn't watch all X-Files, but it's like Gravity Falls takes the plot to the end.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: It's like imagine if X-Files finds the UFO and then they go in it and Gravity Falls, they find the UFO and they go in it literally.
Rym: Only warning, guys.
Rym: I'm just going to spoil the shit out of the show because it's also final thoughts.
Rym: We're going to talk about what actually happened.
Scott: There's not that much to spoil.
Rym: But I'm assuming you have seen the entire show at this point.
Rym: If you haven't, stop or we're just going to ruin everything.
Scott: It's not going to be ruined if you actually enjoy it more.
Scott: If you believe what I say and that spoilers don't spoil things.
Rym: I'll do it.
Rym: I'll do a counterpoint to that on the Patreon.
Rym: All right.
Scott: Yeah, go ahead.
Rym: So the I actually was wrong about the six finger thing for most of the show.
Rym: I thought they were setting up that it was like aliens or wizards or something like like.
Rym: it was something more supernatural.
Rym: And the fact that it literally just was his brother next to her finger was really cool.
Rym: Actually, I like that.
Rym: That's OK.
Rym: I like that.
Scott: it ended up that I thought the author was just like some long dead person related to the town or something.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't really think too hard about it.
Rym: And I also kind of enjoyed how the like the story ended up being simpler than I'd expected in a lot of ways, like what he was trying to do to get his brother back.
Rym: Like it was all actually pretty straightforward.
Rym: Yeah, until the until the only thing that was a mystery then was what does Bill want?
Rym: Like what's his actual motivation?
Rym: And I like how his motivation was, let's just be like all those background ghosts in the Ghostbusters, pretty much like he was dangerous and scary.
Rym: And I really like that.
Rym: And I was also I did not expect them to in a show where the second season at the same opener is the first season.
Rym: I enjoyed how suddenly the opener is different and the whole show is just 100 percent different all the way to the end.
Rym: Not many kids shows, not many shows do that.
Rym: many episodes.
Scott: They could put in the extra effort.
Scott: Remember, they put the extra effort to put like the secret codes at the end of all the episodes and even in the episodes.
Scott: And you can read it.
Scott: Don't bother trying to decode them.
Scott: You can just read them all on the wiki.
Scott: I was looking at about five minutes.
Rym: I was looking around.
Scott: There's nothing really interesting in there.
Rym: Yeah, it's just drink your Ovaltine.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But when I was looking for that, I did find something interesting.
Rym: The fandom of the show, surprisingly, like it's not surprisingly heavily.
Rym: ships, Princess, Princess, what's-her-face and Mabel, not Dipper.
Scott: Wait, Princess.
Scott: Oh, really?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: That's like the number one ship.
Scott: Are you going to ship Applejack and Diamond Tiara, too?
Scott: No, because Applejack.
Rym: I was about to say, Scott, one of them is an adult.
Rym: That's fucked up.
Scott: Apple Bloom.
Scott: I haven't watched the show in a while.
Scott: That is- It's not pony season.
Scott: Apple Bloom, right?
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You're not doing that.
Scott: No, but actually- That's the same thing.
Rym: Ah, but I think that's a little- That could be more rationalizing Gravity Falls than your synthetic example from My Little Pony.
Rym: Because the Princess, Princess girl is kind of weirdly obsessed with Mabel in a way that none of those ponies are really in Pony.
Rym: Anyway.
Rym: So, the end was kind of a cop out.
Rym: I mean, it was a kid's show, so I guess, sure, you got to have the happy ending, but even in a kid's show, I feel like it's not the greatest idea to have a sacrifice that resolves the plot.
Rym: And then, within five minutes, undo that sacrifice.
Scott: That's what bothered me about it the most, was not that it did it, because it's sort of obvious, like, oh yeah, you know, they're just, right?
Scott: It was that they basically got his memory back within like a minute.
Scott: It's like, it's like, uh, shouldn't that take more time?
Rym: If I were them, I would have done the show slightly differently.
Rym: The entire show would be 100% the same, except the two episodes they get rid of that we talked about, but in that moment, like, he'd wake up and there's a scene where, like, they're trying to make him remember and he doesn't.
Rym: I would have then cut to, like, the forward flashbacks or whatever, and the last scene of the show would have just been, like, forwarding him off on the boat doing their thing, and he's suddenly like, "Something, something,
Rym: Seuss!".
Rym: And then, he's like, "Wait, who's
Rym: Seuss?".
Rym: And he's like, it's like, hint that he's starting to remember and leave it at that.
Rym: But no, they literally had the, "Come on,
Rym: remember!".
Rym: He's like, "Okay, I remember everything.
Rym: It's
Rym: over.".
Scott: Yeah, and it only took a minute.
Scott: It would have been cool, though, maybe, like, if you want to do the memory-losing thing, you could have done it earlier and then had some episodes, you know, in between, like, dark times where he doesn't remember and they're dealing with that, and then it comes back later.
Scott: That would have been okay.
Scott: Or you could have just had him beat the bad guy without making a sacrifice, just like, "Aha, we got
Scott: you!".
Scott: Just make something up, and then that's fine.
Rym: Yeah, but victory without sacrifice is often also a boring story.
Scott: You could have made a different sacrifice that you wouldn't have had to undo.
Rym: They could have killed, like, Mabel or something, just let the internet go crazy.
Scott: No, you don't have to do something like that, but you could have, you know, I mean, you could have killed a less important character, but you also could have just, like, lose an arm, lose a leg.
Rym: You know what I expected?
Scott: You could have also lost a non-person, right?
Scott: You could have lost the shack.
Rym: I expected...
Scott: Right, the shack explodes, even though I really like the Seuss Gets the Shack, I like that part.
Rym: I expected that maybe if they'd fixed everything, the sacrifice would have been, "None of them would remember all the weird
Rym: stuff.".
Scott: Maybe, they could have lost the whole town.
Rym: Yeah, but instead, notice how the end was basically, "This town is now literally Springfield,".
Rym: because they're like, "Let us all never talk about it again.
Rym: Let's just not talk about
Rym: it.".
Scott: So there's one plot hole in the show that I'm trying to figure out, right?
Rym: What's your plot hole?
Scott: So it's not the biggest plot hole in the world, but it is slightly questionable, right?
Scott: So their parents send them to this town to live with their uncle, right?
Scott: But if you notice, when he leaves home, presumably, I guess it's the kids' grandparents, because he's great Uncle Stan.
Scott: He's not regular Uncle Stan.
Scott: So his sister, who's only shown in the show as a tiny baby for a frame or two, is Mabel and Dipper's grandma, right?
Rym: I guess.
Scott: So her children are Dipper and Mabel's parents, right?
Scott: You never see their parents.
Scott: But Stan left home and never went back home, so he didn't even know Mabel and Dipper's grandma, his sister.
Scott: He didn't even know her.
Scott: He never met her his whole life.
Rym: I guess they must have just un-estranged at some point.
Scott: They didn't show it in the show.
Scott: In fact, it's highly suggested.
Scott: he never went home ever, right?
Scott: So he was estranged from that person.
Scott: How did he even know Mabel and Dipper's parents, right?
Scott: And how did Mabel and Dipper's parents know to send him there?
Rym: Maybe Dipper and Mabel's parents died in a horrific accident.
Rym: The kids are, like, in denial, like they can't believe it.
Rym: And the state tracked down their nearest living relative and just fucking shipped him there.
Scott: But they had to go back home to California when the summer's over.
Rym: Rarely until they got a foster home because he was clearly unfit to raise them.
Scott: Anyway, you're really going on a limb.
Rym: I don't think that's that much of a limb.
Scott: So anyway, especially since they say in the show, "Oh yeah, there's so much and such as kids," right?
Scott: It's like, right?
Scott: Anyway, and they mention their parents.
Rym: Maybe they're going through a messy divorce.
Rym: They tracked him down, like, "Look, take care of the kids.
Rym: We gotta sort our shit
Rym: out.".
Scott: They're on summer break.
Scott: Okay, so then here's the other less-but-still-existing plot hole, right?
Scott: So their parents send them to live with their great-uncle, who they thought was the different great-uncle, but that doesn't really matter that much, right?
Scott: For the summer, and they would come back home when the summer was over.
Scott: It's at the end of the show.
Scott: It's highly assumed next summer they're gonna go back to Gravity Falls, like it's their summer camp.
Scott: But their uncle don't live there no more.
Scott: Are they gonna send them to live with Seuss, this guy their parents don't even know, to live for the summer, right?
Scott: That doesn't make any fucking sense at all.
Scott: They're not gonna go on the boat in the summer, right?
Scott: So if they go back to Gravity Falls in the summer, sure, they have a ton of friends there and people they could live with.
Scott: But are our parents really gonna send them to live with these complete strangers?
Scott: Some people they knew.
Scott: When you go somewhere for the summer, you're only there for eight to twelve weeks.
Scott: Tops, right?
Scott: That's how long they know these people.
Scott: Eight to twelve weeks.
Rym: They're smart enough to just lie and be like, "Yeah, we're gonna go back to Grunkle Stan's
Rym: house.".
Scott: And their parents are gonna call Grunkle Stan.
Scott: He's not gonna be there.
Rym: Their parents did not call at any point in the entire show to find out.
Scott: That's also fucked up.
Scott: That is also something that was on my mind the whole time, is they have telephones.
Rym: That's why I think there's some merit.
Rym: It's not that much of a limb.
Scott: There is something, that is the strange thing that is going on, is like, not the fact that like they don't, the parents are out of the picture, you know, which happens in a lot of shows, but like, what, how was this arranged to begin with?
Rym: So that's why I'm suspecting, like them being dead is a stretch.
Scott: Your explanation is really off on a limb.
Scott: There's gotta be a more reasonable explanation.
Rym: Yeah, them being dead is a stretch.
Rym: Home problems, or them not being great people, much more reasonable.
Scott: How do they even know Grunkle Stan, this person who's estranged from their family and never met their grandma, the only person who they would have met in their family?
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: It makes no sense.
Rym: Gotta think about this.
Scott: That's the part that makes no sense.
Rym: Meanwhile, the show brought back the giant Time Baby, and then that Time Baby got wrecked.
Scott: I know, the Time Baby came back, so first of all, in one of the codes, it says Time Baby's like, gonna reconstitute himself, it's gonna take a long time, so he's not dead.
Scott: And he's gonna be pissed when he comes back.
Scott: Also, when the Time Guy came back, and the Time Baby came back, I remembered, oh right, they existed, I knew those characters, I recognized them.
Scott: I didn't remember any of the episodes they were in, so I looked on the wiki, Time Guy, who's named, his name is like, I forget what his- Jason Alexander?
Scott: No, the Time Guy, his name is basically like, it suggests that he's a background, like, not noticed person or something.
Scott: And Time Baby, like, they were in a bunch of episodes, not just like one, they were in a few, and I totally forgot anything that happened in those episodes.
Rym: You know, you really don't, oh well, Blendin Blandin.
Scott: Yeah, Blendin, that's his name, he blends in.
Rym: He just, he reminded me of a George Costanza.
Scott: Yeah, kinda.
Rym: He's kinda just a shitty, vindictive person.
Rym: Though, to be fair, he was right, Dipper and Mabel were just little shits, they got him in trouble, and that Time Baby future is not a great future.
Scott: Nope.
Rym: That's a terrible future.
Rym: The world ends in a terrible future, regardless of what they did.
Scott: The town ends, the world doesn't end.
Rym: Time Baby shit happens in the future.
Scott: Oh right, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Rym: Time Baby happens, the world is fucked, nothing they did matters, because the Time Baby future is terrible.
Rym: That's right.
Rym: So yeah, I guess if they do another show, they could be like the War Against Time Baby.
Scott: So what episodes did you like the most?
Rym: Honestly, I really enjoyed the episodes inside Mabel's head, like that whole crazy side story of them trying to assemble the team, and I enjoyed the first couple episodes of When Mad Max Happened, because it's rare that a show will take such a hard swerve in tone.
Scott: See, it was the swerve where it comes to the portal, I actually liked more the swerve where they were dealing with the stone cutters in the town, and McGucket, that earlier part there.
Rym: The mystery had so much potential, you're like, "Whoa, what's going on?
Scott: What's the
Scott: story?".
Scott: It was almost like a hot fuzz with the people in the town, no.
Scott: And that part was way more interesting than the other, right?
Scott: And there were some of the side episodes that didn't have plot, I still liked.
Scott: So I liked the one with the Love God.
Scott: for some reason, Love God character was just really...
Rym: I also enjoyed the Love God, I liked the Multi-Bear.
Scott: Multi-Bear was okay.
Rym: I think someone is obsessed with the Multi-Bear.
Scott: The Unicorn episode, which actually was a plot episode, I liked the unicorns.
Rym: I thought that episode was going a certain way until the reveal of, "No, that unicorn's just an asshole, for
Rym: real.".
Scott: I liked the unicorns.
Scott: The Street Fighter one, not so much.
Scott: I mean, it sort of felt pandery, but maybe that's just because I'm a nerd.
Rym: The one where Mabel has the boy band.
Scott: That's a good one.
Rym: That might be my favorite regular episode of the show.
Scott: Oh, and I can't be neglected to mention one of the biggest characters in the show, which is the stupid kid who's all southern cowboy hick, whatever his name is.
Scott: The bad guy.
Scott: Yeah, Gideon.
Scott: He's just mad annoying.
Rym: That's the point.
Rym: He's basically... There's some Eric Hartman buried inside of his genteel.
Scott: Yeah, that's exactly what it is.
Scott: He's Eric Hartman, for sure.
Scott: He's Eric Hartman plus the KKK.
Scott: Not that Eric Hartman isn't in the KKK, because he totally is, complaining about Jews all the time.
Rym: But if I had to name my favorite weird character side thing, other than Giffany, which was pretty good, that whole bit, I enjoyed the demon that's just a head with an arm that's walking around trying to eat people.
Scott: Yeah, that's a funny side bit.
Rym: Because that's a very Rick and Morty kind of monster.
Rym: And that also signifies the tone shift where the show really avoided talking about killing or death and was always very kid show friendly.
Scott: People got turned to stone.
Rym: Yup, but then at the end of the show, when the final swerve happened...
Scott: They killed the mayor.
Rym: Yeah, but remember that scene where Bill is like, "I think I'm just gonna kill one of
Rym: them.".
Rym: And I think that might be the first point anyone referenced actual killing in the entire show.
Rym: That scene was really well done, because it shifted from kid show to, "Oh shit, now it's
Rym: serious.".
Rym: Eeny, meeny, miny, and that.
Scott: Yeah, it does feel a bit at times, even though it's obviously loaded with fantasy and magic, and your suspension of disbelief is in full effect when you see gnomes peeking rainbows.
Rym: Yeah, they make a lot of noise in places where they're trying to be quiet, and somehow no one notices.
Scott: Right, but stuff like, even towards the very end, they're shot out of the cannon of the robot arm, and then parachute into the thing, and it's like they're falling great distances off the bridge and then land.
Scott: It's hard to believe when they use a non-magical thing.
Scott: that's ridiculous, right?
Rym: Well, especially because that did not happen in the earlier episodes of the show, and it happened more and more as the show went on.
Scott: Right, if you're using shrink rays and stuff, it's kind of like, "I can deal with
Scott: that.".
Scott: Then it really stands out when you use something non-magical, and it's still ridiculous.
Scott: You should have just used magic for the whole thing.
Rym: Some of those bits did bother me, but the only excuse I have is, Gravity Falls is in that weird bubble, so it just made the world more cartoony there.
Scott: Sure, maybe.
Rym: Or it could be like that crack show where they talk about the Simpsons, and they have a theory as to why the Simpsons town is the way it is.
Rym: It's a pretty good theory, but it could be a situation like that.
Scott: This could be how Springfield was actually- I gotta do some laundry before Anime Boston.
Rym: Yep, Gravity Falls is totally worth watching, but- It's not a waste of your time at all.
Rym: It's a kid's show, and it's good for a kid's show.
Scott: It's not world-changing, right?
Scott: It's like 20 years from now.
Scott: It's like right now, it's probably near the top of your list, but 20 years from now, it'll just be like, "One of those shows you can watch,
Scott: whatev.".
Rym: Yep, I think things like Ponies, Adventure Time, Avatar, actually.
Rym: If you want to watch something next, that's a show to watch.
Rym: We could review each of the four seasons of it, even.
Scott: That's too many seasons.
Rym: It's worth it, Scott.
Rym: I'm going to say that Avatar as a whole is as good as Escaflowne.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Straight up.
Scott: I just watched Evangelion again.
Scott: Watch that again.
Rym: Neither one's as good as Evangelion.
Scott: Evangelion is- Just watch it again.
Scott: We could talk about it a whole bunch more.
Scott: There's very little- We've talked about it, but why not talk about it some more?
Rym: I'll just do what we should do.
Rym: I'll watch it again.
Scott: Well, finish some with Tena.
Scott: We can do.
Scott: Geek Dance Presents Evangelion.
Rym: Let's just do it.
Rym: Let's review.
Rym: Let's talk about Evangelion again, and then go back and listen to the last time we talked about Evangelion and see if anything's changed.
Scott: Well, I mean, there has been things that have changed in that there were still things in Evangelion.
Scott: I still didn't understand, but now after my ex watching, there's nothing in that show.
Scott: I don't understand.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: It's like, "Why did Kaji have that
Rym: thing?".
Scott: Well, duh, because- I know exactly what everything is at every moment in the show.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: The Patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are, in order of the amount of money they give us, assuming they give us at least $5, Rebecca Dunn, Nicholas Brandau, Heidi McNichol, Amanda Duchette, James David White, Christian Koontz, Jess, MyStady.com, Mechanical Mind, William Isenrose, Jeremy Miner, How Much Mud Could a Mudkip Kip If a Mudkip Would Kip Mud, Scott John Harrison, Sean Yeager, Clinton Walton, Ren from New Zealand, Robert Lee, Ryan Perrin, Drew Openlander, Rare Lavelle, Brian Sidroni, Rochelle Montanona, Finn Eric Silveraude, Can't Melt Steel Beams, Kinetic Man, Aaron Cerise, Chris Midkiff, Chris Knox, Sorry, Flame Dark Fire, I'm not going to read that one.
Rym: While it's moderately funny, it's over the line.
Rym: Sam Cordery, Daniel Redman, Chris Haddad, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer, and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: So as many of you are wondering, we love Anime Boston.
Rym: It is our favorite anime convention, both to attend and to perform at, but basically this year, they didn't just automatically comp our badges, and we ended up buying badges just because we didn't want to deal with a hassle at the con, and they are going to reimburse us, but basically we don't attend any conventions that make us buy badges and then get reimbursed.
Rym: It's just partly a hassle thing, like we go to enough conventions already, and basically no conventions we've ever performed at have asked us ever to buy a badge, and then get reimbursed, but Anime Boston had never done that until this year, and it appears it was in fact just a clerical error, and everything's fine for next year, so have no fear.
Rym: We will, assuming no date conflicts or anything weird happening, we will be returning to Anime Boston next year in 2017, and actually I'm kind of glad because we have a lot of anime content, and we really only go to one anime convention, so I guess the one interesting thing is that MAGFest sort of invited us to do our anime content there, so maybe
Scott: we'll make even
Rym: more anime content now.
Rym: But anyway, I leave you now with something kind of weird.
Media: German chemists created it in 2010 with the help of the US Army in an effort to develop more energetic compounds, and their first report on the discovery.
Media: they said, and I quote, "The sensitivity of C2N14 is beyond our capabilities of measurement.
Media: Even the smallest possible loadings in shock and friction tests led to explosive
Media: decomposition.".
Media: To give you a list of how touchy this stuff is, here's a list of things that make ZYTOazide explode.
Media: Moving it, touching it, dispersing it in solution, leaving it undisturbed on a glass plate, exposing it to bright light, exposing it to x-rays, putting it in a spectrometer, turning on the spectrometer, and my favorite, absolutely nothing.
Media: They had it in a shockproof explosive case in a dark climate control room, and it blew up.
Media: I think somebody said something mean about it somewhere, and it was like, the lead scientist on the team that synthesized it called it a very exciting discovery.