Rym: It's Thursday May 26th 2016.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: Jurassic Park.
Rym: from memory mostly bad memory Let's do this.
Rym: So yesterday someone straight-up threatened to kill me all right.
Scott: Did they succeed?
Scott: ah?
Rym: Don't think so.
Rym: And the way I normally go to get to Broadway like after I come over the Williamsburg bridge is Just like the road is closed and There's construction or some nonsense.
Rym: I have to turn left, so I turn left And then I gotta go up a bit And then there's a side street, and there is a bike lane on that side street.
Rym: that bike lane is 100% full of construction equipment, so I rode in the regular lane And I come up to a stop sign and I stop and then a car behind me stops and the guy Literally like leans out his window and yells what the fuck you stopping for?
Rym: So I ignore him, and he's like don't you ignore me I'll fucking kill you.
Rym: and then he revs his engine and then his car stalled mm-hmm, and I just bucked away.
Rym: It was just like really shabby looking angry, dude And his really shabby angry looking friends that next to him smoking a cigar and the guy next to him Had that look you know you see sometimes were like like there's a there's someone who's stupid Causing a situation and there's their slightly less stupid friend who realizes that what the person's doing Could get them in trouble and is really trying to like back them out of it without getting involved.
Rym: Hmm, so yeah, that was that was my experience.
Scott: I was biking yesterday because I wisely unlike some people who are not wise Checked the weather and saw that yesterday was gonna be 80 and sunny and today it didn't happen.
Scott: But there was chance of rain.
Scott: today the weather change got.
Rym: chance of rain means I bike to work unless it's actually Raining when I leave for work.
Rym: I'm gonna go to.
Scott: the point is yesterday was the first day Finally guaranteed 80 degrees and sunny, so I just didn't go to work.
Rym: I know what.
Rym: I'm glad I went to work because for various reasons you don't write lunch yesterday Nobu that like super famous sushi place downtown Mmm.
Rym: I like a $200 lunch.
Rym: It was great.
Scott: There was a free lunch at my work yesterday, too.
Rym: Was it like ultra fancy sushi?
Scott: It was ultra fancy Italian.
Scott: I guess our Mexican or something I don't fucking know.
Scott: I don't care anyway anyway.
Scott: It was catering from this place.
Scott: Whatever And I was making a left to go to Astoria Park, and I'm stopped.
Scott: There's a green light But I'm waiting to go left and this car is just coming non-stop.
Scott: so I can't go left and just waiting up as a car Behind me and they honk at me.
Scott: It's like what do you want me to do so?
Scott: I ignore them and they honk again, so I ignored them.
Rym: see it's it's and then I turned left.
Rym: It's this thing that I try to suppress.
Rym: But if someone honks at me more than passingly my brain says just you know you know that bike Finger The finger is making a move and I was like finger.
Rym: there's no reason to move.
Rym: Yeah, I try to not do it because pretty much.
Rym: It's unit satisfying because you're like all right.
Rym: I told that I expressed to this person who's obviously too dumb to realize it that yes I hear you and no I don't care that you're honking.
Rym: That's right, but at the same time sometimes It's I will fucking kill you shabby man.
Rym: That's right.
Scott: Don't get yourself involved with that first.
Scott: yep.
Rym: So usually I only do the finger if I'm already moving But not if I'm stopped in a place where I can't just keep going.
Scott: listen in New York There's.
Scott: you know that.
Scott: you know there's that spirit that travels around the city.
Scott: that just makes everyone's finger like real easy to move.
Rym: Oh my god is than usual my that thing like it is like it.
Rym: I don't even think about like.
Rym: literally when I flip someone off like when I'm biking finger just came out just now Even thinking about the.
Rym: you know I'll kill you guy cuz I'm pretty sure I flipped him off as I biked away But I don't really remember.
Rym: I just assume I did cuz I feel like I did.
Rym: It's an end.
Rym: It's like a reflex.
Rym: It's like if you get hit in the knee and your foot goes up someone honks finger comes out.
Scott: Yeah, but that the new bike path on that bridge.
Rym: Oh my god the Pulaski.
Scott: Yeah, so I go and I'm like oh, I'm biking that way and I'm like I'm so excited I'm gonna use this new path and I cheated.
Rym: I wrote on it before it was done.
Scott: I see I saw two people and they they got off their bikes were walking on the pedestrian path.
Scott: I'm like what the fuck is wrong with those people.
Rym: Yeah, I saw I saw a woman fucking Biking in the pedestrian path and everyone was yelling at her and she was like getting really flustered.
Rym: good I like.
Rym: I don't know if she just was too dumb to realize there's a tool as I start biking up the hill Right on the nice path.
Scott: Ah, yeah, I see the two people who are walking like throwing their bikes over the barrier.
Rym: So I've noticed that because people coming from Brooklyn if cuz if you come in that way if you bike that way a lot like Commuting the way to get on the bike path coming back into Queens is Actually like in a weird place and if you don't know it kind of looks like if you go that way You're just gonna be on the road going the wrong direction.
Rym: So I can see why someone would miss it the first bike in the city.
Scott: Why are you not paying attention to biking news?
Rym: You know what much like how.
Rym: you know, if you're playing a video game, how can we not pay attention video game news?
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Why aren't you?
Rym: I knew that overwatch was coming just because that's a video game.
Scott: It's been at PAX for like two years.
Rym: Yeah, I know that PAX exists.
Rym: I know that Otakon exists, but you know what most anime fans who live in Baltimore have never heard of Otakon.
Rym: So that's the same thing most bikers in New York.
Rym: They've not heard of gears Scott?
Rym: if they haven't heard of gears Do you think they're gonna know about the Pulaski bike path plans?
Scott: I'm saying is if you're not paying attention to the things in life that matter to you then you're basic And we're gonna do a show on that.
Rym: but then you didn't want to because it was gonna be condescending Because you're the one who condescends me.
Rym: So you do not feel you did not feel Somewhat condescending toward the people who are walking their bikes on the pedestrian path and then threw them over the barrier Because you know everything we just talked about.
Rym: no, you don't feel any amount of that like really no - I feel Pity.
Rym: All right, so pity.
Rym: pity could be argued to be somewhat condescending because Things pity only comes in two situations one eat you're in an equal situation to someone else, but they suffer Unrelated tragedy or two.
Rym: someone is slightly less able than you to live their life a normal way.
Scott: No They've suffered.
Scott: they've suffered a tragedy and that their upbringing did not turn them into a person who pays attention to things.
Rym: So you don't?
Rym: you don't feel that there is any amount of condescension whatsoever.
Scott: I'm sorry that these and sad that these people grew up in a way That they don't know how to Google.
Rym: so at work actually funnily enough We're sitting around and I was like something something something.
Rym: the W train because I was you know Because I know and nobody knew and everyone's like W is the one guy's like is there a W train?
Scott: And the other guys are not even knowing there was a W train.
Rym: Yeah So then I live in here.
Rym: so I started explaining like yeah You know the second Avenue subway and they're like second Avenue subway and I'm like, uh, the giant digga digga digga digga What are they gonna call it like?
Rym: what what a number is left.
Rym: I was like it's easy and they're like, how do you know that?
Rym: and I was like the internet.
Rym: not even I was like Cuz.
Rym: I know thing cuz.
Rym: I've been to Second Avenue at some point in the past X years Even though for me, the reason is I've actually been following the progress.
Scott: But I read the new.
Scott: you could read even even if you read the New York fucking post Right the raggiest of rags not even fit for toilet paper.
Scott: You would know this information.
Rym: you would know that a second Avenue subway is coming.
Rym: You would not know like the color the details.
Scott: You would know that it was probably the t-train and you'd probably also know the W train was coming back.
Rym: It's gonna use BMT cars and like.
Rym: I know but crazy stuff, but sure.
Scott: Well, I mean if the Q train is going on it has to use BMT cars.
Rym: Yep, but so then You called the queue because it goes to Queens and I was like, well no I guess I seven goes to Queens.
Scott: What is that?
Scott: Is it because there's seven somethings in Queens?
Rym: Oh So I saw a guy today.
Rym: This is totally unrelated, right?
Rym: So, you know how there's Mets themed city bikes around.
Rym: now like some city bikes are Mets named.
Scott: Yeah, cuz the city is Citi Field.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, so there was a. there was.
Rym: I could see a guy go over to get a city Bike.
Rym: there's a. there's two Mets ones and one non Mets one and he goes and tries to take the non Mets one But then it's broken and he looked at the Mets ones and then he just walked away.
Scott: Is he Yankees fan?
Rym: I assume so.
Rym: Yeah See you got any news on this news day.
Scott: Yeah, let's go ski go with our New York news here.
Scott: So the police department and the fire department have charity.
Rym: Oh, I know what you're talking about.
Scott: They often have charity sporting events where they compete against you.
Scott: You were you were.
Rym: you were suspecting that this is the kind of story room wouldn't know about.
Rym: this was far front page FARC.
Scott: It does seem like a FARC story And far it does seem like a FARC story.
Scott: So they've have charity sporting events.
Scott: very very often They'll even play ice hockey against each other.
Scott: Yeah, right and for charity, right you buy tickets You cheer for the fire department and they lose usually, right?
Scott: So they had a football game recently, which is weird because it's way not football season.
Scott: But I guess this is the time of the year that you can find a football field That's not being used to like at a college or something right in the city because there aren't that many in New York City think Like Columbia has one.
Scott: maybe I don't even know where this took place.
Rym: Yeah, the thing is though, you can't use high school fields cuz MCU Park in Coney Island is where they had.
Scott: I think that's where the minor league baseball team play, whatever.
Rym: Anyway, the Midwest right around now is when the football fields are all taken over by the marching bands for the next year's programs.
Scott: so they had the charity football game and As I as I said before most people cheer for the fire department and the cops win And the cops are running up the score or something.
Scott: and then like you do yep And the police were deleting 29 to 13, which actually isn't running off score.
Rym: That's that's a winnable game.
Rym: if there's more than like well, it's left on the clock.
Scott: I don't think there was that much time left But the game ended in some kind of crazy brawl.
Scott: that of course the cops started.
Rym: Yeah, but like the pictures I saw the cops start a brawl when they were winning.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: It's just that.
Scott: And that's how cops do?
Scott: I think also the Police are generally just like upset.
Scott: the people root for the fire department and hate them.
Scott: and it's like well This is this is fucking why I mean.
Rym: part of it is that I mean I grew up.
Rym: You know, my dad was a fireman.
Rym: His dad was a fireman.
Rym: I grew up around a lot of firemen and also some cops but the perception because remember this is Detroit like shitty parts of town When the cops show up Usually there's trouble for some of the people who are involved but when the firemen show up, they don't give a shit about the drugs or The fight or whatever happened up to the point where the fire started.
Rym: They only care about stopping the fire.
Scott: I think what is is a fire if firemen show up, right?
Scott: They're only there to help you.
Scott: Yeah, regardless of who you are.
Rym: There's no possibility.
Rym: The fireman is gonna show up and like set another house on right.
Scott: They don't care if you're black or you're old or you're white.
Scott: I mean there might be some problems like getting to your house if you live in a shitty area has bad fire service because Society.
Scott: Yeah, but the firemen want to get the fire, you know people themselves once they're there, right?
Scott: They only help people wherever they go.
Scott: They don't do it.
Scott: They don't hurt people.
Rym: come on a cop.
Rym: It's 50/50.
Scott: Sometimes they hurt people and sometimes they help people.
Rym: I called the cop because there's that homeless guy.
Scott: There's a lot of times when you ask him to help you and they fucking won't like hey my bike is stolen.
Scott: Here's where it is.
Scott: Come and take it back from this thief for me.
Scott: I don't even need you to arrest them and they just say no.
Scott: Yeah, I'm not gonna Happen to a friend of ours literally here and then when there's a football game They start a fight with the fire department that you like so fuck you cops there You know what?
Rym: The only thing that would make this great is there's no song.
Scott: fuck the fire department.
Scott: No one ever sang that.
Scott: You ever hear such a song?
Rym: I haven't.
Scott: I don't foresee anyone writing it or rapping it anytime in the near future either.
Rym: So I had a news but Scott stole it to be his thing of the day.
Scott: Why was your?
Scott: why was your news thing of the day worthy?
Rym: Because I had a lot more Semi-series talk about it, but it is also funny.
Rym: So instead I'll also go with the New York news.
Rym: so New York City, like all cities has a typical problem of people piss everywhere and They drink in public.
Scott: that is not a problem of all cities.
Rym: Well, no, it's not.
Rym: it's a because for example Well, yeah, but also Australia like it's not illegal to have alcohol outside.
Rym: In fact in most of the world Like especially in Europe Like if you're somewhere you're gonna
Scott: have alcohol outside in New York as long as you're in like the seating area of a place of The license,
Rym: uh, yeah but you can't just like drink a beer walking down the street.
Rym: or if you're black drink a beer in Central Park.
Rym: or Do you see that study where they?
Rym: Well, but like if white people drink wine in Central Park cops will there.
Rym: I don't think there's ever been a citation for a white person drinking in Central Park.
Rym: I was watching homeless.
Scott: I was watching some Korean TV and some Korean celebrities had a picnic in Central Park as they're visiting, New York Yeah, and they busted out the wine.
Scott: and I'm like, whoa, they're just showing this on TV.
Scott: They don't know do they?
Scott: and nothing happened to them?
Rym: Yeah, because there was Mr.
Rym: Walig.
Scott: they were very white colored.
Rym: Yeah No, the car it's not even minor It's just black people or homeless people get written up for it and no one else does.
Rym: pretty much.
Rym: That's how it goes.
Scott: I mean the law was created as you know, because you can't make a law that says arrest anyone who's homeless or blacks.
Scott: You make a law that says arrest anyone who does this thing and then you just only enforce it against people who are black or homeless.
Rym: but this is an interesting thing here because it it's a uniquely American problem of stopping people from drinking in public and I kind of Wish we just you know act like the rest of the world and grow up a little bit on it.
Scott: Well, I mean, but you know alcohol is becoming a bigger problem every year.
Scott: So I feel like it is but we need to do many things, too.
Rym: but at the same time the problem that it is is Correlated very tightly except for a few exceptions except for a few exceptions except for a few special cases.
Rym: It's mostly poorer people like.
Rym: there's deeper societal problems.
Rym: Alcohol is the one of the symptoms.
Rym: It's not its own cause.
Scott: I think you know, we already discussed on the on the forum the solution of banning alcohol advertising which is a great idea, but I actually thought of another great idea and we should cuz.
Scott: you know, there's the The.
Scott: you know, what's it?
Scott: tobacco and fire alcohol firearms, what's the name of the stupid?
Rym: ATF right all tobacco firearms, right?
Scott: They they say, you know, these cigarettes are okay These ones aren't these guns are okay.
Scott: These ones aren't.
Scott: these alcohols are okay These ones aren't.
Scott: they could if they wanted to much like the FCC does right say These beers and wines are okay, and those ones aren't and effectively outlaw all the cheap alcohol.
Scott: So they would basically only no more 40s no more Budweiser no more cores, right?
Scott: It's pretty much gonna be hipster beers only No more no more.
Rym: Hope one could make an argument that that basically saying only yuppie white people get to drink out.
Scott: No, cuz the yuppie white people are gonna lose their PBR to fuck them.
Rym: Yeah, you know what the PBR thing is like a very specific cultural touchstone.
Rym: But most of those places people are drinking like Bellini's in the middle of the day.
Scott: Sure, I'm saying we could outlaw all of the cheap alcohols Or just charge more for everything.
Scott: Yeah, cuz that totally stopped which effectively does no it effectively does the same thing.
Scott: Nobody's going to drink the hobo wine if they have to pay 20 bucks.
Rym: It's got.
Rym: Australia did it much better with cigarettes like no cigarette brands exist.
Rym: Every cigarette pack looks the same which is the name of the company that made it.
Scott: and how do you when you want to order?
Scott: When you want to buy some how do you choose which ones?
Rym: you say the name of the brand you want?
Rym: And there's a listing black and white that says all the names of the brands and how many dollars it costs for a pack.
Rym: And you know what happened people only buy the cheapest one when there's no more branding.
Scott: And I thought that they you know, not that I've ever smoked but I was under the impression that they actually no They don't had different tastes.
Rym: Yeah, they do but smokers are just addicted.
Rym: They'll use whatever the cheapest one is.
Rym: like all studies show that they don't give a shit.
Rym: in practice At least people who are like that like people who go to a 7-eleven and buy a pack of cigarettes one at a time.
Rym: Those people don't care.
Scott: Let's go and make the cheapest cigarettes we can and sell them in Australia.
Scott: So I'm in Australia and then After like we become the most popular poison the mall and kill every smoker in Australia.
Rym: I Generally feel like murder is like there are some murder.
Scott: They're killing themselves.
Scott: We're just speeding it up.
Rym: It's still murder if you light it up.
Scott: They're the ones doing it.
Scott: We're not forcing them with.
Rym: Moses name jumped out of the skyscraper To commit suicide and gogo 13 shot him on the way down.
Rym: that was still murder.
Scott: No shouldn't be.
Rym: Well Scott you're slowly dying just by existing in fact by living in New York right now with the air at the elevated air pollution Today, so I'll just speed it along.
Scott: Listen, if I could file a lawsuit against everyone making air pollution in the city, I would If I could have comedically farted right there, that would have been.
Rym: but anyway To get back to my news public drinking and urination are no longer are going to be no longer Criminal offenses in New York City.
Rym: They're gonna go into the civil courts.
Rym: It's part of a collective set of bills called the next time I really got to go and there's no public bathroom.
Rym: I'm going so you can still get a ticket.
Rym: but it's Criminal Justice Reform Act and It's already used for things.
Rym: Like if you ride a bike on the sidewalk or jump over a turnstile.
Rym: It shifts.
Rym: it shifts all these crimes to the civil court system and I would have actually kind of been against this because I'm really sick of like drunk people vomiting and pissing everywhere.
Scott: I think vomiting the street should be unless you're unless you have a sickness.
Scott: if you vomit because of alcohol on the street Right, then you should be in big trouble.
Rym: Yeah, and they're very clear this is just to undermine those broken windows laws because Specifically while broken windows might have been a noble idea in a perspective or a theory in practice It was only used to harass black people.
Scott: the broken windows.
Scott: I thought was meant see originally the first time I ever heard about it I thought it meant Oh will power wash and paint all the houses on your street to psychologically and fix all the broken windows.
Scott: Psychologically the neighborhood will feel better and people will stop committing crimes.
Rym: One minor component the general idea behind the broken windows laws was have very strict laws for behaviors that Correlate to crime like like if you like, you know minor crime, that's a bad part.
Scott: Don't do that part Just do the first part.
Rym: It was minor crimes like jaywalking Getting in public.
Rym: do the part gun.
Scott: just do the part that I talked about and not that other part.
Rym: So just make the city nicer.
Rym: But anyway, regardless of intent regardless of you know, any reason why these laws were made in reality They were just used to harass black people in the Bronx and upper Manhattan.
Rym: So this set of laws is saying because the criminal job and the analogy they use in here is pretty great.
Rym: The criminal justice system is a giant hammer and a giant hammer is the worst possible tool to deal with nuisance crimes Because a giant hammer brings with it a lot of consequences and the outcomes tend to be a lot worse if you use a hammer And a giant hammer instead of a ball peen hammer.
Rym: Sure So they're basically going to shuffle more things into the civil court system so that the civil court system Has a lot more discretion to deal with the people that are caught with these crimes on a case-by-case basis.
Rym: they tried this before with turnstile jumping because turnstile jumping the Demographic of people who jump turnstiles in New York is pretty much poor minority kids and rather than like messing up their lives With the criminal justice system they get a ticket that if you go to a civil court and a civil judge can just talk to them and come to some Sort of accommodation and it basically Really really reduces the ability for police to use broken windows bullshit to harass minorities.
Rym: So it's actually a pretty cool thing.
Scott: that's happening on a tangent.
Scott: Have you ever seen anyone use a ball peen hammer for a legitimate task?
Scott: I Don't know what.
Scott: I've only ever used a regular hammer.
Scott: I've never needed a ball peen hammer when a regular hammer wouldn't get the job done.
Scott: I don't understand what the situation is where you need one and a regular hammer is not gonna get it.
Rym: So I'm about to look up what you're supposed to use the ball before but I had ball peen hammer.
Rym: I'd one ball peen hammer that my dad gave me when I was a kid But it was made out of a metal such that it would not spark.
Rym: So I used it in situations where I was hitting metal and I did not want to create.
Scott: But isn't a ball peen hammer like a ball at one end and not a flat surface?
Rym: Yeah, I never used the ball for anything.
Scott: Yeah, what's the ball part for?
Rym: I only use the peen.
Scott: That's why it's a ball peen.
Scott: A peen is just a regular fucking hammer.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: The ball is the part that I don't know.
Rym: Ball peen, straight peen, cross peen.
Scott: Let's see What's the ball part for?
Rym: A ball peen hammer also spelled ball pine apparently.
Scott: Whatever.
Rym: Also known as the machinist hammer is a type of peening hammer.
Scott: What's peening?
Rym: Used in metalworking.
Scott: Sure.
Rym: I'm gonna look up peening.
Rym: What's peening?
Rym: Peening is the process.
Scott: The thing that you can do on the street without going to criminal court.
Rym: Working a metal surface to improve its material properties by mechanical means such as hammer blows or blasting it with shots shot peening.
Rym: Shot peening is fucking shooting metal To like sandblasting.
Scott: I've never seen a guy at like a forge use a ball peen hammer.
Scott: They usually use a big ass flat thing.
Rym: Well, there's different processes.
Rym: So yeah, there you go.
Scott: Whatever.
Rym: Metalworking.
Scott: I learned nothing.
Rym: You don't metalwork.
Rym: So the only time I ever did metalworking, I was metalworking I was working sheet metal over wood backing and I used a rubber mallet to do that.
Rym: But anyway things of the day.
Rym: So while vaporwave is not a thing like that is not actually a genre of music You don't think so?
Rym: No, I don't think so.
Scott: It seems like one of those situations where like, you know When you combine genres of music into a new combination That's never been combined before.
Rym: Like for example bad music and metal becomes new metal.
Scott: Sure Right.
Scott: Does that actually count as a new genre or is it simply a combination of its parts?
Scott: And if that's the case Shouldn't we just define all music based on like oh, that's you know, a cannon right use the original Right the oldest possible right because it's like.
Scott: oh, that's just.
Scott: you know, that metal song is just a cannon plus distortion We can't.
Scott: it's not a new thing.
Rym: Yeah, right, but there's two different kinds.
Rym: Some things are just this plus this and some things do synthesize in their own thing.
Rym: But anyway, I decided and I'd fuck, you know, anyone else who has had an opinion on this in terms of like Wikipedia or academia or whatever I Decided that it makes more sense if you think of vaporwave as an aesthetic genre Like it's not a music genre But it's like someone took a bunch of aesthetic elements Combine them together and said if you make something that combines all of these elements in any way You're part of this like weird aesthetic genre or aesthetic movement and it's linked together solely by the components that were used to make it Which means chiptunes are basically that as well just broader.
Rym: I Decided this because I found something fascinating The other day a while ago.
Rym: So and I legit like this music and I legit like this artistic movement, even though it's oddly specific But it's the same kind of thing as vaporwave.
Rym: So I was watching a YouTube playlist that was just.
Rym: it was like auto-generated.
Rym: It was just clips from the Simpsons like two to five minute clips, and I was just watching this thing.
Rym: Well, I was working on something.
Rym: so basically I was just like mainlining Simpsons like good Simpsons like seasons 5 through 11 and Suddenly one of them looks really distorted in VHS.
Rym: I'm like, oh this is probably shitty and then it distorts a bunch and then I'm about to like just hit dislike and skip to The next video.
Rym: and I rarely pushed his leg yeah, but I thought this was like bad like it looked almost like someone who's taken an old VHS tape like with tracking issues and Just put it on YouTube.
Rym: but then some music starts and The video was edited cleverly to match the music.
Rym: and then I realized that the VHS stuff was added in post on purpose and It was basically a music video and as I watch him like it was pretty cool.
Rym: So I liked it and then I noticed that all the recommendations after that Had the same title type thing.
Rym: This one was called feeling fine, you know vaporwave shit.
Rym: They had like all the letters are capitalized and like spaced out.
Rym: Every one of these videos was like that.
Rym: they all had Simpsons thumbnails and I start clicking on them and it was Simpson wave Mmm, and it was pretty good.
Rym: But that wouldn't have been a thing.
Rym: It's like okay.
Rym: someone was making fun of vaporwave and they made a bunch of videos and they called it Simpson wave and high production Value, but that's all they did.
Rym: But then I noticed that these videos were all uploaded by different YouTube accounts.
Rym: a ton of people were making Simpson wave like Two months ago this happened.
Rym: These are all like from like March April May 2016. so I present to you the best of these.
Rym: if you like this video or this music.
Rym: Then you will actually legit like Simpson wave.
Rym: Simpson wave is no less legit than vaporwave And I legit like this stuff.
Scott: Like I'm not even like all sorts of weird internet shit like potato conditions.
Rym: potato conditions I like because it's really kind of fucked up and dumb.
Rym: But I like.
Rym: I like this feeling fine and vaporwave for the same reasons.
Rym: I like Neil Cisarenga's music.
Scott: That's what I'm saying.
Scott: But Neil Cisarenga is like the borderline.
Scott: anything that goes beyond him is like nope too much internet.
Rym: This is at that level.
Rym: I think it's good.
Scott: Anyway, so there's this old TV show from back in the day called street sharks.
Scott: It was a cartoon for kids in the 90s that was trying to capitalize on Ninja Turtles.
Rym: the right it was like.
Rym: there was like.
Scott: there were a bunch of shows like this like swat cats and stuff Which is pretty much is like.
Rym: so I guess is legit.
Scott: good though They're just like.
Scott: basically let's make animal people on a team Who fight in all sorts of action and getting weird scenarios against crazy bad guys that are weird.
Scott: And it was all just pretty much Ninja Turtle clones of different animals.
Rym: They were trying to trick grandma who knows you're into turtles that someone could be like, oh Or trick you into watching it, right?
Scott: so all these Ninja Turtle ripoff things basically from the 90s.
Scott: street sharks is one of them and It was I guess slightly more popular than the others cuz like.
Scott: I remember seeing these toys at at least one kid's house Yeah, and I vaguely remember the TV commercial.
Rym: I might have watched the show, but I don't know.
Scott: I've definitely never watched an episode.
Rym: I've definitely seen episodes of street sharks On the network I was watching.
Rym: it was on in the middle of the block of like all the other cartoons I was watching.
Scott: it was one of those shows I definitely remember specifically seeing commercials for and knowing and seeing toys but not ever actually watching cuz man.
Scott: that doesn't look good.
Scott: Anyway, so there was a website called TV tome calm that I think no longer exists.
Rym: But this dude when I got bought by CBS or CBS bought it.
Scott: Anyway, this guy went to that website back in the day when it existed and for shits and giggles.
Scott: It's like a wiki.
Scott: he edited all the information about street sharks with fake nonsense and No one was paying attention to that.
Scott: right three sharks, right?
Scott: No one's paying attention to this obscure ass show and he wrote things that sounded authoritative didn't sound unbelievable Right, it's around that.
Rym: and like they're they shout.
Scott: they sounded true.
Scott: they just weren't true.
Rym: They're like they edge a little bit like they're just a tiny bit weird But they're not in like you.
Rym: like one flag might go up like really.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: All right, I guess I guess this makes sense.
Scott: I guess that was an episode and I guess if you've actually seen the show and knew about it You would know that this stuff wasn't true.
Rym: But but most people didn't watch the whole show.
Rym: That's interesting even though the shows on Netflix now It's people like me who saw like some of it as a kid and they're like there was a character rocks and one of his Characters was Roxy and he'd be like rocks.
Rym: Yeah, I guess there was a character like that.
Rym: I gotta remember that.
Scott: so people basically he's created all this stuff.
Scott: this like false history where people believe The things that he wrote are true because it was copied to so many other websites.
Scott: this information right ended up as being like the source for so many other places and Apparently Wikipedia is correct.
Scott: But all these other places just used his in for his fake nonsense as a source for information and people believe this story He wrote like is the truth about this show and they don't realize that it's not.
Rym: now think about this.
Rym: Like if you like randomly start googling after street sharks for some reason like say you have to write an article you work for some Like low-rent news organization.
Rym: They're like give me an article on crappy cartoons in the 90s and you're like looking up street sharks.
Rym: You'll find a page somewhere that talks about like the cool episodes or the lost episodes.
Rym: It seems like these episodes nowadays mostly show up on websites where someone's saying hey I found this list of episodes that I can't find copies of But I know they happen because and he links to data from hit that
Scott: There are people who will say things like they remember watching them when they're a kid and remember
Rym: that
Scott: false memories.
Scott: now There's people who are like I have a VHS tape of these and it's like no you don't.
Rym: Yep No, you don't.
Rym: there was a study a long time ago.
Rym: I referenced this a lot.
Rym: I gotta find a link to it again because it was a great study but a company that they made up a fake brand of root beer that never existed and they would insert it into this long very detailed survey of like.
Rym: what brands like what sodas did you drink as a kid?
Rym: and a lot of people Remember drinking this soda that was literally made up at various eras.
Rym: They would remember very specific details about this thing that never existed.
Rym: Mm-hmm It's very easy to make this happen.
Rym: And this article is just sort of like a fascinating look at someone who did it.
Scott: Yeah for all the more details read this article.
Scott: it's pretty interesting.
Scott: and also don't watch street sharks.
Rym: Yeah, you know what.
Rym: watch one episode of street sharks.
Scott: watch a clip of street sharks on YouTube if you must.
Rym: I'd watch one whole episode.
Rym: get the experience.
Rym: That's all you in the moment.
Rym: The book club book was the wheel of time.
Rym: It is now going to be Oryx and Craig by Margaret Atwood.
Rym: we're not will tell you when we start reading it because the weather's nice and I'll read it in the park and Thor's hammer just got forged.
Rym: in book 13 of the wheel of time Like straight up power forged weapon happens and some characters like I gotta give this thing a name and this character I'm trying to avoid some spoilers ask some other character in the old tongue What's a word for like soaring or flying and the guys like
Scott: this mule?
Rym: No, basically says me owner and he's like, alright, I'll name it that which.
Scott: it's a super old GeekNights.
Scott: Callback to the jolner.
Scott: Yeah, like goes back ten years and look for us arguing about how to pronounce that word.
Rym: jolner.
Rym: jolner That was I think Timo Recorded himself saying it and uploaded it was like guys.
Scott: You can also heat.
Scott: Yeah, there's pronunciations of it.
Scott: You can hear online.
Scott: Anyway, y'all know.
Rym: Anyway, anyway, so yeah, I'm gonna.
Rym: I'll be done with the real time real soon.
Rym: Keel white and I are going to do a podcast special on the wheel of time the entire scope of it at PAX Prime.
Rym: This is probably going to be an off-the-record event.
Rym: So stay tuned.
Rym: It's gonna be fun.
Rym: Con.
Rym: I'm literally scheduling like now.
Rym: so if you think you're going to do a panel at Connecticut and you have not made a grow ticks account and Actually submitted it You are very close to not doing a panel at Connecticut because I am just filling the schedule as fast as I can.
Scott: There is oh I forgot to say I didn't forget actually I remember to send the ignites newsletter in what was last month April and then I just didn't because I couldn't think of anything to Write.
Scott: but I haven't forgotten it so you can sign up for it at our website for newsletters.
Rym: legit?
Rym: good I don't know why.
Rym: anyway also I do a patreon to back the newsletter.
Scott: No, cuz I don't need money.
Scott: It's free free stuff from skies more free stuff from Scott.
Scott: I spent a bunch of money.
Scott: That wasn't patreon money.
Rym: Did you want patreon money for that stuff?
Scott: No, why not?
Rym: because we're gonna use it to make GeekNights content.
Scott: I bought some extra equipment and now I think the last of it just showed up at my house.
Scott: So I'm gonna test it when I get home so I can do amazing streaming videos from my house And I since I spent money on it.
Scott: I'm gonna use it a lot even if I make crappy videos.
Scott: Well, like we said we want to see me doing random nonsense in my apartment when I have nothing better to do.
Rym: The internet responds way better to people who are more prolific regardless of quality.
Rym: We're not gonna lower our quality of like our main stuff like GeekNights.
Rym: It's not gonna get crappier our panel videos and like all that stuff.
Rym: We're not gonna get crappier, but we're gonna upload the stuff that we all the be.
Rym: in the past We would have said nah, this wasn't good enough.
Scott: So you should check my youtube and it'll be.
Scott: you know, if you subscribe to it, it'll be streaming often.
Scott: ish You'll know when I have nothing better to do.
Rym: Yep and Pax prime badges PAX West now could go on sale any second.
Scott: My watch could buzz fucking right now It could happen and good luck.
Rym: Have fun.
Scott: also, I'll see you there.
Rym: Scott isn't but I'm playing overwatch now and Almost all played.
Scott: it wasn't $40.
Rym: So many people in the forum are playing it now too that You will be able to find good groups of people to play this game with.
Rym: not gonna review it now But I will say this it is Like it's team as far as I've heard is Team Fortress 2 with more skills to twice as good less hats with a MOBA Aesthetic and with a lot of MOBA elements to it.
Rym: But the skill cap of the FPS thing is three or four times higher than tf2 Like you but still way less than quick.
Rym: It's like yeah, it's.
Rym: it's like 20% as skill cappy as Weapons factory was for quick - and maybe 30 but it's still hard.
Scott: It's still more skills than tf2 way more skills than right, you know, so it's pretty fun and there's no pay to win.
Scott: I mean I as far as I can tell it's it's a fine game.
Scott: I'm just not paying 40 bucks when I have more games.
Rym: I know what to do with Yeah, but I'm gonna play it because the getting is good down and I'm never gonna.
Scott: there's so many other games with the getting's good.
Rym: Yeah, like sit five right now.
Scott: There's so many games with the getting's good.
Scott: I'll just play those.
Scott: the Philadelphia netrunner regionals are on Saturday.
Scott: I'm gonna go there and then come right home.
Rym: So a long time ago.
Rym: I was a kid.
Rym: I saw Jurassic Park in the theater 1993 me too and I've like my 1993 brain like this was one of the greatest movies I had ever seen.
Rym: No, not for me like it was up there.
Rym: I mean it was With Indiana Jones.
Scott: I mean, it wasn't like I hated Jurassic Park.
Scott: I liked it.
Scott: I enjoyed it, right?
Scott: It was fine.
Scott: I even had a VHS tape of it.
Scott: I believe I watched it quite a few times But it wasn't like I was.
Scott: I even read the first and second books.
Rym: I read the first book like Real hardcore and thought a lot about the differences between the two.
Scott: but like when I read that first book It was already the edition that was like, you know the movie but it was the real book But it had advertising on the cover that was like, you know based on the movie.
Scott: You know the movie was based on this whatever but it's like.
Scott: I liked it, but I wasn't like so into it.
Scott: It definitely was not at Star Wars level not easy.
Scott: So what I read the book first I'm pretty sure I actually did read the book before seeing the movie.
Scott: Yeah Right because that's that's the thing people don't realize because this doesn't happen anymore.
Scott: That movie was in the theaters, right?
Scott: But not the dollar theater.
Scott: it was in the main movie theater on at least one screen For perhaps at least a year since I saw it in the theater like three times during the original run, right?
Scott: It's like the original run of that in movie theaters lasted so long.
Scott: only that movie and Titanic were in movie theaters for such a long period of time.
Scott: like even like.
Scott: is Star Wars Episode 7 still in the theater now?
Scott: even I Fuck if I know like it maybe still is but it's like it's only been a couple months.
Scott: Imagine if that was still in the movie theater like next like like this holiday season.
Scott: It won't be right, but imagine it.
Scott: that's Jurassic Park was in the theater for so long I saw it not when it just came out like I saw it months after it came out Like I had time to get the book read it.
Scott: go see it.
Rym: Yep, see my mom gave me the book way before.
Rym: cuz I you know, we're really in a Michael Crichton.
Rym: Anyway, so I'd read a lot of Michael Crichton books.
Rym: I wasn't actually you know what he wrote the Andromeda strain, right?
Scott: I didn't read that one.
Scott: Uh, you know what I got to say.
Scott: there wasn't you know Because he was way popular then right because of Jurassic Park.
Scott: Yeah, he sort of had a surge in popularity.
Scott: They made movies based on his other books.
Scott: I really like the movie sphere a lot.
Scott: Ah I don't people don't like that movie so much.
Scott: it, you know, they'll probably just say it's okay.
Rym: Most people I know who really hate the movie.
Rym: It's because they read the book.
Scott: I don't think I read the book but really that that movie on its own is a thing that I like.
Scott: See, I remember I read the book like it more than I like Jurassic Park the movie.
Rym: when I saw the movie I remember being really disappointed by it because the bullshit ending and because it really skipped a lot of the themes of the book maybe but I just like You know, it's mostly the thing I like most about.
Scott: oh shit.
Rym: I forgot about Congo.
Rym: I read that and then I saw in the theater the thing I like most about Congo's got a real stupid end.
Scott: the thing I like the most about spear.
Scott: the movies like the atmosphere like they're in the bottom of The ocean and there's all the weird shit Scott.
Scott: It feels a lot like Stargate in some ways.
Rym: you read the book then I haven't read the book.
Rym: Maybe it's into a lot of things that the movie does not get into.
Scott: maybe I should.
Rym: yeah You should.
Scott: it's also got sort of an alien feel because they're like it's almost instead of being trapped in a ship They're trapped in this metal thing in the bottom of the seat, right?
Rym: Oh, you know what?
Rym: actually if all his books the one that I never read that I probably should is eaters of the dead because It's 13th warrior Never heard of it never seen the 13th warrior.
Scott: No, what were the 12 other warriors?
Rym: the 13th warriors?
Scott: It's all about.
Scott: it were the 12 warriors the 12 monkeys and the 13th warriors.
Rym: The 13th warrior is a movie that we're gonna talk about another day.
Rym: Okay, it is not a great movie, but it is a great movie.
Rym: Okay, like you can enjoy the same.
Scott: it tastes good, but it tastes bad.
Rym: It's like Commando.
Rym: I love commando like in terms of the commandos at both a great movie and also a really kind of terrible movie.
Scott: How is it terrible?
Scott: in what way?
Rym: it's pretty cheesy How it's all like how the plot kind of comes not Stan Lee cheesy.
Rym: No, that is a different kind of cheese.
Rym: It's like it's like a fine aged foot cheese as opposed to I like a fine aged foot cheese.
Scott: That's delicious.
Rym: Yeah in gourmet Yeah, so 13th warrior is a movie that you and I can appreciate and enjoy.
Rym: But a movie critic would say yes, this is a badly made movie.
Scott: Well, I mean initial D is bad, too.
Rym: Yeah, anyway, anyway, but we're here As a kid, I guess it was partly that Jurassic Park became one of those franchises like the Indiana Jones franchise back to the future.
Scott: It was the biggest deal.
Scott: They were they were 90 merchandise.
Scott: Like you could basically live a Jurassic Park life in terms of like you could buy all Jurassic Park merch.
Scott: You could eat Jurassic Park food See Jurassic Park Jurassic Park cereal.
Scott: I bet there was.
Rym: I went to see Jurassic Park at the drive-in like years later in a double feature With I don't remember what the other sure as hell Jurassic Park crunch.
Rym: And since you just look it up.
Scott: Yeah, it exists.
Rym: Good God See I ate the Nintendo cereal and then I realized to never eat another branded cereal ever again the rest of my life.
Scott: I never ate.
Scott: I didn't eat cereals that much and when I did it was always just Rice Krispies.
Rym: But anyway, I was.
Rym: I was a Frosted Flakes Cinnamon Toast Crunch cuz I just I didn't eat sugar cereals.
Scott: I said maybe corn pop but and it was also that honey nut cheerio.
Rym: There are movies.
Rym: You know in over the years that set on new bar for special effects in terms of like just how good they were.
Rym: like Star Wars changed the game.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: The matrix changed the game.
Scott: matrix didn't really change the game.
Scott: matrix took someone else's game and brought it to America.
Rym: But at the same time the way some of those scenes were shot and done had never been done with that level of technical ability Maybe like it after that.
Rym: I mean every movie did slow toy story change the game Yep, and Jurassic Park in some ways also changed the game.
Scott: Well, yeah kind of mean the dinosaurs look like dinosaurs.
Scott: They didn't look like guy in a zip pursuit.
Rym: Yep, and you know what the effects in Jurassic Park the original movie hold up pretty well.
Scott: Yeah, no, because it looks like real dinosaurs.
Scott: Yeah, it looks.
Scott: it doesn't look like some CG garbage.
Rym: and I remember when I saw the movie in the theater Like we were there like big screening like opening night when the first big dinosaurs on the screen I remember the entire audience was like Like people really reacted.
Scott: dinosaurs are a big deal.
Rym: that now people don't care about dinosaurs as much because I found out It's just we're older than the people who care like.
Scott: I remember being a second grade and dinosaurs were like that.
Rym: Graders are still like that.
Scott: I think but now dinosaurs have feathers on them.
Scott: They're not as cool.
Rym: I think they're cooler cuz.
Rym: now they're like dragons.
Rym: Yeah Yeah but I I'm pretty sure it's also that remember the only people are really into dinosaurs are kids chase and people with kids People who work at the museum and our friend chase.
Rym: chase is so into Jurassic Park like a friend of ours on his birthday Made him a Jurassic Park themed cake But and had like dinosaur bones on it.
Rym: But what we knew that he didn't know is that as you start excavating the cake to eat it.
Rym: the DVD of Jurassic Park Was inside the cake?
Rym: So, uh, I super into Jurassic Park and I remember as a kid being Really bothered by the tiny differences between the book and the movie and I was one of those people who would go on at length About like.
Rym: well the movie was great except the end was sort of a feel-good.
Rym: But really in the book like the Raptors were breeding and like there's something going on.
Scott: I do remember.
Scott: I don't remember what the details were but I do remember there were significant differences between the book and the movie.
Scott: like remember they go back to like As a kid that have set me greatly and I thought the book was better and there was.
Scott: the only thing I remember clearly detail wise was that there was a scene in the book where they were like trapped behind a waterfall or something and I was Like the most suspenseful.
Scott: Oh, yeah Book and that scene was not in the movie at all.
Scott: And I felt like that was like a really critical scene in the book and I was like if anything Why isn't this?
Scott: at least this one scene should have been in the movie and then someone told me I've never seen any movie other Than the first one.
Scott: someone told me that scene is actually in the second movie.
Scott: Fuck the second movie, which makes no sense to me, but I've never seen the second movies.
Rym: I'm the second book.
Scott: Yes, second movie is but I don't write hardly room.
Scott: I like I barely remember the first book I really don't remember.
Rym: the second second book was actually really bad I really don't remember and it had weird callbacks to the first book now.
Rym: I might be to remember.
Rym: this is from memory.
Rym: I haven't thought about Jurassic Park in like 15 years Jurassic world.
Rym: I thought about it at Chase's birthday.
Scott: How many tries to park movies are there now?
Scott: five?
Scott: I've seen one of the first one.
Scott: I've never seen the other one.
Scott: Let's see.
Scott: I heard from other people that six.
Rym: there is a sixth one coming.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: So I've heard from other people that in one of these movies a dinosaur like stomps over a city like it's fucking.
Rym: Yeah, I think and I'm pretty sure that was Jurassic Park 2 or throughout Dave.
Rym: Let's see bla bla bla bla.
Scott: That's bullshit.
Rym: The Sun Goes Missing.
Scott: just watch Godzilla.
Rym: instead Trying to figure out what happens in which of these movies Worked the other way.
Rym: the predator creature survived the second.
Rym: I Can't tell without reading this in more detail.
Scott: So let's talk about the good parts, right?
Scott: So first of all that first movie regardless of his differences from the book has one of the greatest soundtracks Has an amazing sound.
Rym: I will find myself humming the Jurassic Park, you know Like to this day that song just pops into my head.
Scott: it's a very high quality movie.
Scott: It's not like some legendary movie, but it's really good.
Rym: It has a really.
Scott: it wasn't in the theater.
Scott: It's for a whole year for no reason.
Rym: like good strong characters.
Rym: You know how the matrix set this sort of actually Newman.
Scott: Newman did a great job in that.
Rym: Edgeri nerdy Nedry really Michael Crichton Nedry.
Rym: Yeah, you didn't think we'd see through that the fat shitty guy who dies.
Scott: Yeah, but he deserves to die.
Scott: But yeah, I don't like that.
Scott: They made the nerd the villain.
Scott: They should have made someone else.
Scott: Yeah, they also made him so shitty and well, but that's the kind of character He plays.
Scott: he played it.
Scott: Well good job acting.
Rym: Yeah, no Nedry was like that was you.
Rym: the movie was perfectly cast because that was back when I mean that like So, you know how in the matrix they give you a lot of pseudo philosophy.
Rym: and yes You saw the matrix.
Scott: That's what the matrix is about.
Rym: got really into philosophy, but only this like pop minimal version Jurassic Park was that for the concept of chaos theory.
Rym: every 13-year-old kid was like well chaos theory and then they quote Malcolm in the movie.
Scott: Oh, it's not just teenagers.
Scott: I remember specifically when I was a kid around the same age, right?
Scott: I would go to the bookstore and I bought a collection of Dilbert comics in a book and crazy nut job Scott Adams who writes Dilbert who's even crazier nut job now.
Rym: Yeah, he's not only a nut job, but he's a shithead.
Scott: Yeah, he's not a good person.
Scott: But anyway, if you read like the old Dilbert books like I was expecting when I bought them I thought that they would be like Calvin and Hobbes book where it's like Oh a collection of all these comics in a book.
Rym: How can we afford by someone else?
Scott: right and I didn't read all these in the newspaper.
Scott: How nice is this right to have all these?
Scott: but he doesn't do it like that.
Scott: He would put writing in there, especially in the back.
Scott: He would just write stuff the kind of stuff he writes on the internet now and in the first or second over book I don't know which one it was is a whole nutty thing about chaos theory Which I presumed was because he had read Jurassic Park.
Rym: So this was also the era where I still thought that Jeff Goldblum was a good actor And I remember as a kid looking into that character.
Rym: not a bad actor, but he's I don't know He's not.
Scott: he's not fucking great actor, but I see Jeff Gold.
Rym: He's not bad.
Rym: I just shake my head a little bit and it's hard.
Scott: I think he's a bit typecast for sure.
Scott: Yeah, you know, I mean look in Jurassic Park and in Independence Day, which are pretty much the movies he did back-to-back Right plays basically the same character I was remembering mad as a kid.
Rym: that like I think what is the the old guy Hammond?
Rym: I'm pretty sure he dies just like a chump way earlier in the book.
Scott: He survives in the movie.
Scott: I think right.
Rym: Yep Yeah, cuz he's not like.
Rym: they keep giving him morphine in the book and there's this whole thing with the morphine And I remember the one like I think a little dinosaur Great if we're wrong because our memory from the 90s Yeah, but I'm pretty sure he dies cuz like.
Rym: I am also pretty sure no But I'm pretty sure the kids this.
Rym: this is gonna be the test of my memory because I remember the scene for some reason.
Rym: I remember the kids are in a control room somewhere and they find they can hit a button and it like makes Sounds out in the park.
Rym: and what if it makes a t-rex sound?
Rym: and I think it was used to like scare other dinosaurs away?
Rym: So they hit it and it happens and then the book cuts to.
Rym: He's fucking walking around in like a morphine stupor and it scares him because he thinks the t-rex is there.
Rym: so he runs away and he runs into a pack a little dinosaurs and the little dinosaurs have a bite that causes you to not feel pain and he gets bitten by one of them and he falls over and then he just goes down like A chump and they eat him and he kind of thinks that he doesn't feel them biting him.
Rym: and how odd that is.
Rym: That's a very specific memory I have.
Scott: I do not have the memory of how he died.
Scott: I just remember that.
Scott: my vague memory is the old guy dies in the book.
Scott: Yeah, the old guy was like a bad guy.
Scott: He was irresponsible and he's the one who made this stupid park, right?
Scott: And he did, you know, so he was a bad person who had played gods.
Scott: Yeah play gods.
Scott: Therefore he died.
Rym: So I also remember a scene in the first one.
Rym: remember where they're.
Rym: they're using the computer and she's like And then like she saves the day.
Scott: No, I don't remember.
Rym: they like types and commands and like open doors.
Rym: don't remember.
Rym: in this I think it's the second book.
Rym: the same fucking scene happens where the two same kids I think find a computer but it's like a more powerful Unix and it's got 3d graphics and there's this rotating cube of menus and they can't figure it out and It's getting more and more complicated.
Rym: and then the girls like wait a minute You couldn't drive that powerful of a graphic system without a fiber optic cable.
Rym: And then she goes behind the computer and finds a fiber optic cable and then they find like a pathway that cable went and they crawl through a hole.
Rym: Okay, that's all I remember.
Scott: I don't remember that either.
Rym: I remember those things.
Scott: So let's talk about some other Jurassic Park things, right?
Rym: So the SNES game was kind of legit.
Rym: good, right?
Scott: There was a. there was an SNES Genesis game Which is a platformer and this is one of those cases where SNES one was of FPS.
Scott: Oh Really?
Scott: I thought the SNES one was the same as Genesis one.
Rym: No, it was an FPS.
Scott: Oh, well, the Genesis isn't one of those cases where and it was a top-down walk-around.
Scott: This is one of those cases where the Genesis game was way better, right?
Scott: The Genesis X-Men game was better the Genesis Aladdin game was better and the Genesis Jurassic Park game was better.
Rym: The Genesis X-Men game was the best X-Men game to come out up to that point except for the arcade one.
Scott: Yeah, right But the Genesis Jurassic Park game was like a legit good platformer where you could be the velociraptor or the dude Right and you could do all you could like.
Scott: it was a really good sign.
Scott: a kind of good Platforming.
Scott: action game is really hard and totally worth playing.
Scott: I want to see someone speedrun it.
Scott: Maybe someone has So go back and check that out.
Scott: Also the Jurassic Park for the Sega CD was not good But it was legendary.
Rym: It was definitely.
Scott: It was all about like like you would literally like Walker.
Scott: It was like mist in a way.
Scott: right was like a first person but it was using cutscenes that were pre-rendered.
Scott: So it was.
Scott: it was a lot of loading time from the CD and you couldn't move around and you could certainly look around and Poke and point-and-click.
Scott: but then there was some action parts You had to shoot and they basically were trying to steal dinosaurs eggs from around the island without getting murdered.
Scott: and it was weird.
Rym: So Scott, you didn't.
Rym: I guess you didn't play it then.
Rym: So the Jurassic Park game on the SNES one it was one of the like ten games that used the mouse.
Scott: Whoa, what?
Rym: Yeah, it was an FPS with a mouse.
Rym: Okay, or you walked around.
Scott: I think the Sega CD one like like The Sega CD one probably should have had a mouse.
Scott: I don't think there was a mouse for the Sega.
Rym: so you had a top-down like secret of evermore secret amana kind of game where you walk around and like have a little gun and Like shoot like solve puzzles and pick shit up and you know what it was.
Rym: looked a lot like zombies.
Rym: ate my neighbors.
Rym: But then if you went into a building It was an FPS with the mouse and there's Raptors and dark rooms and it was real scary like real scary Like when a rafter came after me like I would flip out and like my brother would scream.
Rym: and those are good times as a Kid.
Rym: Hmm.
Rym: What other games like King Arthur the King Arthur game used the mouse.
Rym: Sim City didn't even though it should have Sim City came.
Scott: it was a launch game for the Super Nintendo.
Scott: the mouse came way way later.
Rym: That's why the mouse came with Mario Paint.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: You couldn't even get the mouse on its own.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Oh my god I was so obsessed with getting that mouse because I was already a PC gamer.
Scott: No, we should make a thing where you plug in a normal optical mouse with USB and then it converts it into you know Super Nintendo Mouse and you could plug your regular mouse into a Super Nintendo Except you can just use an emulator and say mouse.
Scott: But I mean if you have a Super Nintendo, but you don't have a mouse those are hard Nintendo.
Rym: I have two of them.
Rym: you want one.
Scott: No, I'm just saying there are people out there.
Rym: I'll bet I can find one for less than 10 bucks.
Scott: You think the mice is less than 10 bucks?
Scott: I think it's rare and expensive.
Rym: I cuz I if it's rare expensive.
Rym: I have two and I'm gonna sell them.
Scott: Good idea.
Rym: All right now a brand new unopened one is $295.
Rym: you don't have that Mario Paint with the mouse 20 bucks.
Rym: buy it now.
Rym: Oh, that's pretty good Mario Paint with the mouse.
Rym: good good quality 30 bucks.
Scott: All right.
Scott: All right, it's not worth that.
Scott: You can get one Yeah, but the problem is that is another thing though You might not want to use that mouse because it's a shitty ball mouse and it'd be much nicer to use a modern optical mouse.
Rym: Oh my god a whole generation of kids don't know what it was like to have a physical mouse with a ball.
Rym: anyway Do a show on mice the evolution of mice over the years?
Scott: Kids these days don't need to have mice.
Scott: They got touch screens and touch pads.
Rym: Yeah, and those kids can't play games.
Rym: as a result It's got the tutorial and overwatch is literally like I'm gonna run back and forth across the stream.
Rym: Watch me do it and it makes you like watch like left right.
Scott: Oh Have you ever done the half-life 1 tutorial?
Rym: nope, because I would.
Rym: by the time I played half-life 1 I was already like a pro FPS.
Scott: It's like walk forward jump over this pit.
Rym: Yeah, it's.
Scott: it's basically the same thing.
Rym: so I never saw Jurassic World and it's interesting because Half the people I know who've seen it said that it is an amazing movie and there's a Jurassic Park movie.
Scott: That's not the first one.
Scott: That's amazing.
Scott: That's what I have to be black.
Scott: I was under the impression that they were all garbage knowing almost nothing about them.
Rym: Well, the new one apparently is just like really well done.
Rym: But a bunch of people who have seen the movie said that it's hot garbage and it'll just kind of diminish your memory of you.
Scott: I mean, he only wrote two books.
Scott: So what did they write for the these future movies?
Scott: So I'm pretty sure do all the movies follow from each other?
Scott: if you watch only movies Are they all in the same universe?
Rym: So the second movie I don't think is based on anything.
Rym: Okay, cuz it's not the second book as far as I could tell.
Rym: it was just this garbage Follow from the first movie.
Rym: I don't remember because the second the first book already deviates so far from where the first movie ends that They're really couldn't.
Rym: if there was any continuity between the two sets I actually don't know because I never kept up on the franchise Jurassic Park as prevalent and Pervasive as it was in pop culture throughout my entire childhood all the way up through high school and I was really into the first movie and the book and the SNES game and Just pop culture like everyone had seen it.
Rym: Everyone knew about it.
Rym: I just stopped paying attention after I saw the second movie and it was bad.
Rym: I just ignored it forever more.
Scott: Well, I mean there are these certain franchises that from the 80s and 90s that center on movies, right?
Scott: Ghostbusters back to the future Robo cop Terminator 2 Indiana Jones and Star Wars again.
Rym: even that Robo cop the TV show is bad.
Rym: the Animated TV show is bad.
Rym: The second movie is bad.
Rym: The third movie is the worst thing you'll ever see.
Scott: I think that's all of them that I've got right.
Scott: Did I cover all of them?
Scott: That's just about all of them, right?
Scott: Yeah, the thing is Jurassic Park was actually at its peak other than Star Wars.
Scott: right at its peak time Was the biggest one.
Scott: it was in the movie theater for a year and the most money had the most shit everywhere, right?
Scott: It was way bigger than back to the future wasn't back.
Scott: The future was a new movie.
Rym: There was a big gap between Jurassic.
Rym: What was the next thing?
Rym: after like Jurassic Park that became a new franchise like that like a movie franchise?
Scott: I don't even know.
Rym: I think Lord of the Rings Maybe but there's gotta be some matrix.
Scott: Yeah, kinda anyway.
Scott: But the point is is that despite being just as big or bigger than most of those at its you know peak time It is faded more.
Scott: It's still around obviously, right?
Scott: Cuz something's.
Scott: you know inertia looks like all this but if you look if you were of course, it made a ton of money.
Scott: But if you look at say a graph of like where they stand today Like back to the future is way above where you know, Jurassic Park is today, right?
Scott: Just like they're how big they are right at this very moment You know, yeah, it's like so Jurassic Park like good because it was the highest and it fell the furthest It doesn't?
Scott: it's not in the gutter.
Scott: They're still.
Scott: you said they're just making another movie, right?
Scott: It's not gone.
Rym: Here's the box office.
Scott: Is it adjusted for inflation now?
Rym: Okay, but Jurassic Park won about half a mil 400 grand in North America and a billion worldwide.
Rym: Yeah, uh Lost world the second movie garbage like 200 and some Jurassic Park 3 way less hundred and eighty thousand hundred eighty million.
Scott: and I think that's the reason that Jurassic Park fell farther than those other ones.
Scott: because Even back to the future where the first one was way better than the second and the third right?
Rym: We're still pretty good.
Scott: They were still bringing, you know, those second and third aren't remembered as like vile.
Scott: right.
Scott: Star Wars is like boom Boom boom great.
Scott: Great.
Scott: Great, right?
Scott: It's like these other things that happened all matrix here.
Rym: Look, here's the One movie here the run tomatoes ratings Jurassic Park 93%.
Rym: Jurassic Park to 51%.
Rym: Jurassic Park 3 50%.
Scott: all right compare that to back to the future.
Scott: I'll.
Scott: even Ghostbusters 2 was better than Jurassic Park.
Rym: - yeah Ghostbusters 2 is actually pretty good movie.
Scott: It's okay.
Scott: Yeah All right, I think nostalgia boosted a lot.
Scott: I think it's also that those characters even Ghostbusters 1 New York boosted a lot.
Rym: The characters are so strong that they kind of carry Ghostbusters - like yeah If that same story wasn't those characters that movie would have been forgotten.
Scott: Terminator Terminator 1. and then Terminator 2 went up.
Rym: Yeah, well cuz Terminator 1 was a horror movie.
Rym: Yeah Terminator 2 was like a legit for real awesome sci-fi like science fiction Speculative fiction story I think independently was an amazing amazing action movie of Jurassic Park.
Scott: the point is if Jurassic Park - Had been like Terminator - like even better than Jurassic Park Jurassic Park would have been one of the biggest friends with current Jurassic Park would currently be like the king of all.
Rym: so of these things Jurassic Park 193 - 97 3 2001. so 14 years later in 2015 They made Jurassic World and it made way more money than the original Jurassic Park.
Rym: all the inflation with inflation It's probably about the same amount of money.
Scott: Maybe.
Scott: well movies, you know The size of the movie pie is larger.
Scott: right now the budget actually comparable which is not not the budgets.
Scott: I'm talking about the pie of how much money goes into how much money people are spending on movies.
Rym: Rotten Tomatoes rating 72. so the franchise kind of bounced off the bottom of the Jurassic Park 3 and Maybe it's gonna get revitalized Because I feel like Jurassic World.
Scott: they would have to make something like that.
Scott: Just be like such a legendary movie that even people who don't remember or care about Jurassic Park would go see it.
Scott: Yeah, that's how.
Scott: that's how much you would good you would need to do to bring it back.
Rym: The reason it's so tough I think is that one the one of the other huge franchises like Lord of the Rings The Hobbit just like fell through the trapdoor and disappeared into.
Rym: yeah, I didn't even see Hobbit - I didn't Did I see Hobbit - and not you saw - and not three, okay, I saw two and it was so bad I thought about walking out.
Rym: It was awful.
Scott: I didn't see it in a theater.
Scott: I saw - I saw the theater.
Scott: I saw one in a theater.
Scott: I saw two elsewhere and I haven't seen three.
Rym: actually kind of an aside You know what?
Scott: I'm just gonna watch Lord of the Rings.
Rym: Mad Max Was such a good movie that I've cuz madman's weird.
Rym: Like.
Rym: a lot of people know what Mad Max is but hadn't actually ever seen a Mad Max movie.
Scott: That's actually an example of you know, even though I still haven't seen it, right?
Scott: It shows that it is possible to revive some old dead franchise.
Rym: Scott I'm like, like I know you you have to see it at some point because I'm not even exaggerating Mad Max was the best movie of that year hands down but Jurassic World was about.
Rym: probably it looks like it's a being treated about as good as the new Star Wars.
Rym: Both of them are like this level of movie.
Rym: The problem is they have to compete in a world where the Marvel Cinematic Universe.
Scott: I think that's basically like.
Scott: there's like this level now of like how big your movie can be and that's how big your movie can Be these days unless you're the Marvel Cinematic Universe.
Scott: I think that's the level though.
Rym: It's yeah.
Rym: Well, yeah, that's the top, right?
Rym: But look at that That's a new kind of franchise.
Rym: every one of these things we talked about from the 90s and the 2000s was Make a movie part two part three part four Marvel Cinematic Universe was movie movie movie movie movie.
Rym: Let's mash them all together into another movie Movie movie movie.
Rym: mash those into a movie mash them all into a movie.
Rym: Like all these parallel threads like this totally different way of going about making a movie franchise.
Rym: That's all I got on Star Wars Jurassic Park.
Scott: I don't remember anymore.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night.
Rym: the patreon for this episode of GeekNights in the amount of money.
Rym: They give us on a continuing basis are Alan Joyce Rebecca Dunn Nicholas Brando Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette James David White Christian.
Rym: I heard a genealogist and we aren't pending blood test cuts.
Rym: my stady comm.
Rym: Sean Hayworth William ice and Rose Jeremy.
Rym: minor Spartacus.
Rym: Spartacus.
Rym: Spartacus Matthew Smith Kimberly bachelor kajar tavish and Joe Shiro Joe star Tyler Eller Don Schleich Sean Yeager Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Robert Lee Ryan parent drew open.
Rym: Lander Ryla Val Brian said Roni Rochelle, Monta Nona Finn Eric silver on and the infinite sadness kinetic, man Aaron Cerise Chris midkiff Chris Knox a red lion Sam Cordray Daniel Redmond Chris a dot Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: Yes, we know the forum is down.
Rym: There is an outage at rack space and that is affecting us.
Rym: And as much as I love you guys, we're not paying enough money to have multi data center.
Rym: aware Fully ha dr forums.
Rym: I could put the patreon money toward that and a better forum.
Rym: You probably expect me to put the major and money towards something much larger like a Convention or a bunch of video equipment because we're gonna accelerate some of our video content.
Rym: But I tried to use the money to give to let Scott pay for a bunch of wireless equipment that he bought.
Rym: But he doesn't want the patreon money.
Rym: So he bought that on his own.
Rym: but nonetheless, we'll get to use that stuff to make a bunch of video.
Rym: So the patreon money is still safe and sound and ready for some gigantic project that we will start using in the near future.
Rym: I actually haven't even claimed it all yet.
Rym: But anyway without further ado.
Rym: I leave you with some Simpson wave Oh.