Rym: It's Tuesday, February 16th, 2016.
Rym: I'm Rym, and this is GeekNights Tonight.
Scott: Helldivers.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So we mentioned a bunch of times that we've been playing a giant multiplayer robot game of Civ 5.
Rym: We're what, like 70 turns in now?
Scott: I don't know how many turns it is, but I need some fucking money.
Scott: My caravan was doing great, and then a barbarian just went
Scott: "boop!".
Rym: You gotta protect that shit.
Rym: You've got caravans going off into unprotected barbarian lands.
Scott: It was not unprotected barbarian lands.
Scott: It was lands that I presumed were perfectly safe, and then a barbarian just went
Scott: "whoop!".
Rym: Here I am.
Rym: I got scouts patrolling my trade routes to make sure barbarians don't get out of there.
Scott: I don't have enough shit for that.
Scott: Also, I don't necessarily trust- Because there's so many fucking barbarians in the way.
Scott: All my guys were on the barbarians behind my territory, but my caravan went in the other direction.
Rym: Well, that's your problem.
Scott: But the city that I was sending it to was right there.
Rym: Send it to a different city!
Scott: There was no other city to send it to because there's no one fucking near me.
Rym: Then send it to your own city and you get a huge boost instead of money.
Scott: It was.
Scott: I needed more monies than that to make up for my debts because I built so many good buildings at high maintenance.
Rym: I thought you built too much shit.
Rym: You know what you should do?
Scott: But I had good shit!
Rym: Good shit!
Rym: If you can send a guy near me, I will gladly pay you money for a luxury resource.
Scott: I'm on a worthless island.
Scott: Am I gonna send a guy to you?
Rym: Completely on an island?
Rym: Is there shallows they get across?
Rym: Is your science so pathetic that you can't go into the shallows yet?
Rym: Can you embark?
Scott: I would need to build something.
Rym: Just a scout!
Rym: Just send a scout down.
Scott: Meanwhile, by the time I build the thing, you know, what's gonna happen to my monies?
Scott: My coffers are gonna be empty.
Rym: Well, don't you trade with Lisa.
Scott: She's on the other side of the barbarians.
Rym: Do you have diplomatic relations?
Scott: Uh, no.
Rym: You never bumped into her so you can see her in the diplomatic thing?
Scott: Uh, maybe I can, but she's not gonna just give me fucking money.
Rym: Well, trade her something.
Rym: That's how diplomacy works.
Rym: Like, "Yo, I'll give you this
Rym: city.".
Scott: I'm gonna trade with someone who's like right there.
Rym: Why not?
Scott: Who's like the most powerful person in the game?
Scott: and I'm like the last most powerful.
Rym: If you're the last most powerful, you should ally with the first most powerful for a little while to suck resources out of her.
Scott: Why would she do that?
Rym: 'Cause she'll treat you like a toady.
Rym: Or she'll give you, she's probably gonna, you know what, also.
Scott: Then how come, how does she have money?
Scott: That's not interesting.
Scott: You're in the same situation.
Rym: I got a shit ton of money.
Scott: How did you get all the money from?
Rym: I got spices all over, up ends.
Scott: How did you get, how did you turn them into money?
Rym: Uh, spices, if you work them, give you like three gold.
Rym: Just on the land.
Scott: Yeah, I have some spaces like that, but it still doesn't add up to as much money as it costs me every turn.
Scott: How many militaries do you have?
Rym: Uh, pretty large military, actually.
Scott: Yeah, I had to disband a military 'cause I couldn't afford it.
Rym: I may have a trade agreement where I'm giving someone a luxury resource in return for like seven gold a turn.
Scott: Oh, well that matters a lot.
Rym: Yeah, so.
Scott: But I'm not near anyone to make a trade agreement.
Rym: In fact, I'm gonna build my fourth city real soon, I think.
Scott: I don't even have a third city 'cause I can't make a settler.
Scott: 'cause I'm too busy trying to build a replacement caravan.
Rym: Uh, sounds like civilization, tell you what, Scott, if you reach me and make diplomatic relations.
Scott: I wanna see like exactly what you had each city building each turn that allowed you to be more productive.
Rym: I'll tell you what, one thing that I did different, probably, is that I placed my cities real well.
Scott: I placed my cities real well.
Rym: And I rushed culture so I could max out liberty.
Scott: I mean, I got as much culture as I could.
Rym: Yeah, you traditioned.
Rym: Tradition sucks.
Scott: Alright.
Rym: That's part of it.
Rym: What did you get?
Rym: Liberty, all liberty.
Scott: I also got liberty.
Rym: In fact, I'm almost done with liberty.
Scott: I only have like one liberty.
Rym: What?
Rym: Did you build like monuments or amphitheaters?
Scott: I built, I can't build an amphitheater yet, I built monuments.
Rym: In every city as soon as you started the city?
Scott: Uh, yeah.
Rym: Alright.
Rym: So you built a monument, every city you founded, the first thing you built was a monument.
Scott: Yes, all two of them.
Rym: And you built a monument both immediately.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And, well liberty gives you, makes monuments give you more liberty, or give you more culture among other things.
Scott: Well, I mean, I spent all my time fighting barbaros.
Scott: How many barbaros did you have to fight?
Rym: Uh, I've destroyed like nine encampments.
Scott: I've only seen like three encampments.
Scott: If I could, I actually have a military now.
Scott: If another encampment appeared, I could kill it and get money.
Rym: Yeah, encampments keep spawning because there's this, me and Alex have this truce.
Rym: So there's an area between us where there's no settlements.
Scott: There is no encampments spawning.
Rym: And the problem is fucking barbarians keep spawning in this area.
Scott: I kill, I invested in this military to kill barbarians.
Scott: I killed them all and no new ones are showing up except for the one that popped out of nowhere to kill my caravan.
Rym: So take over like a city-state or the rest of the area.
Rym: Just conquer it?
Rym: Yeah, just fucking go.
Scott: But that's gonna hurt me if I conquer it.
Scott: It's gonna bring me all kinds of unhappiness and troubles.
Rym: Not that much.
Rym: Plus, puppeted cities give you their science and their production and everything.
Scott: Aren't they gonna cost me a whole bunch?
Scott: Every time I conquer something when I play Civ, it just hurts me.
Rym: It's always good for you unless you really overstep yourself.
Scott: Every time in the history of Civ I've conquered something, it's been like, "Oh, you conquered
Scott: something.".
Scott: Alright, yeah, now there's a bunch of people who hate you and your happiness is negative ten and it costs you a million dollars to maintain their shit and they suck.
Rym: Yeah, and that goes down rapidly and then after a few turns it's making money again.
Scott: I've never had that happen.
Rym: Also, puppet them and they don't increase the cost of the next social policy.
Scott: Never had this happen.
Rym: The social policies only get more expensive if you found or take cities and make them legit cities.
Scott: Maybe I'll just give all my stuff to Lisa so she wins and be a troll.
Scott: if I can't win.
Rym: Why don't you give it to me?
Scott: Because you're on the other side of the map.
Scott: Fuck you.
Rym: Why don't you give it to Scott Johnson?
Scott: Also, if it's a vote who wins game, I'm not voting for you.
Rym: Why not vote for me?
Rym: Because right now Lisa's winning.
Scott: Uh, okay.
Scott: She can win.
Scott: It'll be done even faster.
Rym: The thing is, you being done doesn't matter.
Rym: Why don't you just give each of your cities to a different person?
Scott: My lands are real valuable.
Rym: No, they're not.
Scott: They are.
Rym: Apparently they don't make any money.
Scott: I have mad sugars and shit.
Scott: It just doesn't make enough money for some reason.
Scott: I don't know where you got those extra monies from.
Rym: So, Scott, how many buildings are in your capital?
Scott: Buildings?
Scott: I don't even know.
Rym: Oh, okay.
Rym: Because I have like two buildings.
Scott: I have way more than two buildings.
Rym: Yeah, buildings cost a lot of money to maintain.
Scott: I got a library and all kinds of good stuff.
Scott: I had to get rid of my, I built a religious building just to get the pantheon, but then I had to sell it off to get the monies back, you know.
Rym: Ah, I've never sold a building.
Rym: Selling a building is like, you've already lost.
Scott: I had no monies.
Rym: How'd you run out of money?
Scott: Did you?
Scott: Because I had a caravan to keep my coffers in the plus, and then the caravan got killed and it became minus.
Rym: How much minus?
Rym: It still used to have like 80 or 90 gold back up just hanging out.
Scott: I killed a barbarian camp and that gave me enough money, but then after five turns that money was gone because it was negative every single turn.
Rym: Alright, did you build- It was like negative five.
Rym: Did you build a whole bunch of like roads and improvements and shit everywhere?
Rym: Because each one of those costs a gold to maintain.
Scott: Yeah, I have a whole bunch of them.
Rym: Do you have more than you're using?
Scott: Uh, no.
Scott: I'm using every single one.
Rym: You're literally using every one of those improvements.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Scott: Like a mad population.
Scott: I'm using every improvement.
Scott: In fact, I'm building an improvement so I can use it because I've got more alive populations on unimproved hexes.
Rym: Uh, did you rejigger your cities to produce gold instead of production?
Rym: Yes, they've been producing maximum gold since they've been, you know- I, if you log into your game and let me look at your cities, I will consult for you.
Scott: I mean, I'm going to quit the game anyways.
Scott: It probably doesn't matter.
Rym: I can show you what you did right now.
Rym: I'll show you my cities.
Rym: Except I don't want to show you where my military is because I might be doing something with it soon.
Scott: You're going to attack me across the water?
Rym: No, I'm not attacking you, but I still like keep my secrets close.
Rym: Someone's fucked in the nearing like 10 or 20 turns.
Scott: Well, people near Rym.
Scott: Go watch out.
Rym: So anyway, in the news, Street Fighter 5 came out and it's shocking how little I cared after I realized that it was out.
Scott: Well, I mean, I saw it.
Scott: It packs a few times and I'm like, oh, it's more Street Fighter.
Scott: I play Street Fighter 4 a bunch.
Scott: That'll hold me over to like Street Fighter 6 or something.
Scott: Yeah, I guess I just- Seven, maybe seven will be a probably exciting one.
Rym: I enjoy fighting games.
Rym: I even have like a Mad Catz, like awesome fighting stick.
Rym: I just, I don't have time for that anymore in my old age.
Rym: Like I don't play Street Fighter-ish games enough to be good at them.
Rym: And the only fighting games I'm good at that exist still are like Soul Calibur style.
Scott: So- I don't want to play those other high skill cap games.
Scott: We want to play low skill cap RTSs in fighting games and high skill cap RTSs in fighting games.
Rym: Which is interesting because remember most people who are very good at very high skill cap games specialize in those games and do not play many other games.
Rym: Which is true for us too in that realm.
Rym: But it's like in Omegathon, if there was both an RTS and DDR in the same Omegathon, the Venn diagram of people who are very skilled at both is probably close to zero.
Scott: Yeah, probably.
Rym: But there's a problem with Street Fighter 5 and it seems weird.
Rym: I didn't dig into this too deeply.
Scott: Yeah, this sounds suspicious.
Scott: I think it's overblown.
Scott: Whatever you're saying is probably inaccurate in many ways.
Rym: Not really.
Rym: Because we ran into this and we complained about it in a previous Tuesday show.
Rym: Where we were at a party and there were two PS4s in two different rooms at the party and a bunch of controllers.
Rym: And every time we wanted to play like Towerfall or something, you had to fucking sit there and log every controller in as a guest one by one.
Rym: And if someone was logged in with a game and they played the game and then they started playing a game on a different PS4, it would just kick the game out and crash it.
Rym: All these weird problems because it sort of assumes that everyone just has their own controller all the time forever.
Rym: And I guess brings the controller with them and always has an account and logs in even for local throwaway multiplayer.
Rym: But, all that aside, that was a problem that existed, we were annoyed by, but it wasn't a deal breaker.
Rym: That seems to be what's causing the first of the controller problems with Street Fighter 5.
Rym: Because apparently you need a modern controller or it won't work.
Scott: Is that to prevent cheating because people like making their own controllers?
Rym: It appears that if you have a controller, which I checked, it looks like my fighting stick would not work.
Rym: And you want to use it in the PS4, you have to log in with the DualShock 4 controller shit, which isn't in the old fight sticks.
Rym: So to make that controller work, you have to go through all these menus and go to legacy controller authentication.
Rym: And then you have to set up your legacy controller and then you have to plug in a regular controller, like a regular DualShock 4, Playstation, whatever controller.
Rym: And use that to log in and all this nonsense.
Scott: So just play on Xbone or PC?
Rym: So if you play on an Xbone, I believe it's fine because Xbox doesn't have as much of this nonsense.
Scott: Well I guess they're not using the controller for the nonsense, right?
Rym: Yeah, but if you're on the PC, it's also a problem.
Scott: What do you mean?
Rym: So quote, "As for PC, Street Fighter 5 natively supports a number of devices, but those without X input functionality will not work until a promised future
Rym: patch.".
Rym: Oh, okay.
Scott: So they pretty much only coded in support for certain controllers and they didn't support, you know, they only basically worked with the X input API for DirectX.
Scott: So if your controller is like using the old, I mean that's almost any controller you're going to use is going to use X input, right?
Scott: You'd have to get like some old busted like, you know, Thrustmaster flight stick thing, you know, that uses like the windows, like set up your analog controller thing to not work with that.
Scott: That's not a real issue.
Scott: No one's using a non-X input controller.
Rym: So from what I can gather, more people are than you'd think because a lot of people have custom or old fighting sticks that are super awesome that might have art or whatever on them.
Rym: And those don't work anymore.
Scott: I mean, it had to be a pretty old fight because they are...
Rym: It was widespread enough of a problem.
Scott: The fighting stick we have is an Xbox 360 controller.
Scott: It's using X input.
Scott: So it has to be even older than that.
Rym: And I'm saying that while I agree with you, there's enough people bitching on the internet that I guess there must be a community of people who have older controllers that don't do this.
Scott: I guess if you made your own controller, right, and you got the circuit board in your controller, it was not just an Xbox 360 controller that you opened up.
Rym: Well, like, so me and Scott back in the day, when we played Dance Dance Revolution, we'd buy these bootleg like dance mats.
Rym: And when they finally died, it was always because the dance mats...
Scott: Those are just PlayStation controllers.
Rym: Yeah, the dance mat was shitty.
Rym: So when I made a hard DDR pad, I just took the circuit board out of the front of one of those things and wired it up to my hard pad.
Scott: Which is PS1 controller.
Rym: And it totally worked.
Scott: Of course.
Scott: Why not?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So, yeah, people are complaining about this.
Rym: So apparently there's a workaround, but the workaround adds so much input lag that you can't actually play Street Fighter.
Rym: Some people were saying use joy to key and...
Scott: Fuck you, joy to key.
Rym: Joy to key is like the last ditch effort of Mad Men.
Rym: Like, that is, like, joy to key is one step before sniffing cocaine out of a gutter.
Scott: I never use joy to key.
Scott: I never will.
Scott: Anyone who uses it...
Rym: If the solution to your problem is joy to key, your problem is not worth solving.
Rym: That's right.
Rym: And the game was badly written, binding of Isaac.
Scott: I've played a lot of games that I've never needed to use joy to key.
Rym: I've played a lot of games that would have needed it, and I decided just to not use a controller.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: Just use the key.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Does he got any news?
Scott: It's only... I couldn't find a lot of gaming news, so I found this tiny news.
Scott: So today there's a big Steam sale.
Scott: It's not really a big Steam sale like all of Steam.
Scott: It's a Steam sale on this one bundle of games, the Make War Not Love 3 prize one no cost from Sega.
Scott: So you get, for zero dollars, Golden Axe, the original, the good one.
Rym: Whoa!
Rym: It's not a great game, but I'd play it for zero dollars.
Scott: Well, I mean, it's a game you can just emulate, but it's three dollars, Golden Axe.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But it's zero dollars, because, you know, this bundle.
Scott: A bunch of, like, hell yeah, rabbit something game that I never heard of.
Rym: Hell yeah, rabbit.
Scott: Yeah, the big deal, Jet Set Radio is in this, and you get it for zero dollars.
Rym: Wow, I forgot Jet Set Radio existed.
Scott: And then a Sega Classics thing.
Scott: So you get all these things together for zero dollars.
Scott: So if you have a Steam account, just make sure you click on this to get the games for zero dollars.
Scott: But the question is why this Make War Not Love prize bundle one number three thing?
Rym: So do you know why, or are you asking?
Scott: Everyone's presuming that Sega is doing this for some sort of promotion of something coming soon that we're not sure of.
Scott: So, like, there's going to be some sort of something from Sega coming soon.
Scott: that will be hot.
Rym: Sounds about right.
Rym: I mean, like, if I was going to make a modern Rampart, I would definitely re-release the old Rampart for free on PCs.
Rym: So I got one tiny news, too.
Rym: Because, as you know, full disclosure, I'm associated with Date Naito.
Rym: They make visual novels, so, you know, ethics in game journalism or whatever.
Rym: But one of our games, We Know the Devil is a pretty cool game.
Rym: And one of the shiks is that it was going to be for sale for six dollars and sixty-six cents.
Scott: Haha, Satan.
Rym: And because of reasons, this was literally impossible to do on Steam.
Scott: Well, I mean, you can make it six-six everywhere else.
Rym: Yeah, but on Steam, you could not make it six dollars and sixty-three.
Rym: It ended up being six-sixty-three, and that was as close as they could get it.
Scott: Okay, so wait a second.
Scott: So Steam is putting restrictions on the price you can set for a game.
Rym: There are prices you can set, like, at tiers, and you can't go between those.
Scott: Okay, so here's the question.
Scott: If you're going to make tiers, why wouldn't they be something logical, like, every fifty cent, or every twenty-five cent, or, you know, something like that?
Scott: Why would you even allow six-sixty-two?
Scott: Would you just only allow six-fifty, six-ninety-nine, seven-fifty, seven-ninety-nine?
Rym: So it was going to be sold for six-sixty-six.
Scott: Maybe throw in seven-twenty-five and seven-four.
Rym: When it went live on Steam, it ended up being seven-ninety-nine, because that was the only price they could set.
Rym: So a seventeen percent discount was used to get it as close to six-sixty-six as possible.
Scott: Oh, you can set percent discounts to adjust the price.
Rym: Yeah, so seven-ninety-nine, with a seventeen percent discount, got it to six-sixty-three, which is real close to the number that was actually the number of the beast in old documents, and also kind of close to six-sixty-six.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Scott: So, uh, I was gonna- Why not just set it to nine-ninety-nine, so that you can be an upside-down Mark of the Beast?
Rym: 'Cause then it costs a lot more money.
Scott: Well, I mean, you know, steam premium price.
Rym: So, uh, I was gonna talk about this in more detail, but literally between when I realized what was going on and when we came home to do the show, there's an article on Kotaku from three-ten p.m.
Rym: today talking about this, so...
Scott: There has to be maybe some other way, right?
Scott: Like, if you gave it, what if the price is, like, twelve, whatever, you set it at a fifty percent discount, right?
Scott: I feel like if you increased the percent discount, you could make a really high price and get it to six-sixty-six.
Rym: Well, so I'm pretty sure the reasons steam does this kind of thing, there's a bunch of, like, back-end business reasons.
Rym: Like, for example, one of the really annoying things with, like, the Google Play Store or, I don't know, Amazon, is that you'll see things for sale for, like, five dollars and one cent, four dollars and ninety-six cents.
Rym: Because they're trying to, like, game each other and appear at different parts in the listings and, you know, show, like, shave a penny off the price, but then add a penny to the shipping and all sorts of, like, weird arbitrage engineering nonsense.
Rym: Also, it's probably more efficient to have pricing tiers and, like, standard discounts and standard stuff.
Rym: And pretty sure this is the only game in history where someone noticed and cared.
Rym: I think that's the end of it.
Rym: Someone noticed and cared.
Scott: If I was selling Doom, I would sell it for six-six.
Rym: Yeah, so we need John Carmack and John Romero.
Scott: They're not working on the new Doom.
Rym: I'm not saying they are, but I'm saying we need their voices to advocate that six-sixty-six needs to be an available tier.
Scott: But I think Doom will cost you sixty-six-sixty-six.
Rym: Or sixty-six-sixty, actually, would be better, I think.
Scott: Sixty-nine-sixty-nine.
Rym: That's real close to our old Wi-Fi password.
Scott: You could have also given them a discount and made it cost four-twenty.
Rym: And also, one of the other games, Hustlecat, where you can date cats that turn into cute people, is on Steam Greenlight, but hasn't made it over the line yet.
Rym: So, go click on it.
Scott: What happens if it makes it over the line?
Rym: Then you can buy it on Steam.
Scott: Oh, so it's already done?
Scott: You just can't buy it until it's...
Rym: It's not done, but it's going to be for sale soon, but it can't be for sale on Steam.
Scott: Then how come you can sell the Devil Game on Steam?
Rym: Because it got over the line.
Rym: So, the Devil Game had a demographic that was very into it and got it greenlit.
Rym: Way early.
Rym: Also, that game is just out.
Rym: You can just buy it.
Scott: Ah, but the cat game needs help to get over the line.
Rym: The cat game, I don't think enough people realize.
Scott: You'll be able to pay six-sixty-two for the cat game.
Scott: You'll only be able to pay six-sixty-two for the Devil Game.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: You'll have to buy the cat game from somewhere else.
Scott: It's not Steam.
Rym: Yes, unless more people click yes on this thing.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: And that's why... Oh, there are, however, right now, on it, sixty-nine comments.
Scott: Alright.
Rym: Sounds good.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day!
Rym: If you know me at all, in fact, I see that bustin' thing just looking at me as the first recommended video.
Scott: Bustin', bustin', bustin'.
Rym: Makes me feel good.
Rym: Neil Cicierega is the avatar of all the good parts of internet culture.
Rym: Like, you know, in fantasy worlds, the god of whatever...
Scott: We have sung his praises enough times.
Scott: All you need to know is that there is a person named Neil Cicierega, and they are the person who has made all the things.
Rym: Yeah, like, name ten weird internet things.
Scott: The creative genius of, perhaps, the half a generation younger than us.
Rym: Yeah, I'll put it this way.
Scott: Yeah, he's younger than us.
Rym: Name, like, ten popular, well-known weird internet meme things.
Scott: He's made half of them, probably.
Rym: Yeah, like, for real.
Rym: And he made an opus.
Rym: So, this is twenty-one minutes long.
Rym: It is basically an entire TV episode titled "Computer
Rym: Fighters."
Rym: Just watch it.
Rym: Like, don't.
Scott: Just watch it.
Scott: You stole my thing of the day.
Rym: Hey, who backs his Patreon?
Scott: This is the best thing that I've seen on the internet in weeks.
Rym: It is the best thing I've seen on the internet, other than that suicide shower head that I'm gonna talk about next week.
Rym: But, the production values on this thing are pretty off the hook and independently.
Rym: If you are around...
Scott: There's, like, this set of all-star people helping out, and it's like, "Oh, just he needed the
Scott: help.".
Scott: Yeah, okay, yeah.
Scott: If you're between twenty- That's the person who needs the help from all these geniuses.
Scott: The genius himself, sure.
Rym: If you're between twenty-eight and thirty-eight years old, this is gonna hit real close to home in a lot of ways.
Scott: Alright, so I had to go to a backup thing of the day.
Scott: So, there's a YouTube video called "Bolt for
Scott: Brilliance."
Scott: And in this video, a man bolts for brilliance.
Scott: I don't know how much more I should talk about it, but I guess I will.
Scott: So, you know how at sporting events, there's the old, especially soccer, especially in Europe, there's the streaker?
Rym: They take it off, they run across the field, they get- I'm pulling up the video, I'm just gonna watch it while you're talking.
Scott: This is the full day in the life of the man who bolts for brilliance.
Scott: It begins with, you know, before even going to the stadium, you know, the preparations inside.
Rym: Oh, this already looks real good.
Scott: And then, you know, climax with, you know, the event.
Scott: Alright, so now you know what it's like to be a day in the life of a person with this occupation.
Scott: What goes through their minds, why they're doing this, how they get it done.
Rym: This is- I don't even have the sound on.
Rym: This actually looks really great.
Scott: Proper techniques.
Rym: He's like, he's ready.
Rym: Like, he's got this really determined look on his face.
Scott: Alright, you're almost at the really- the best part.
Rym: When he actually does it?
Rym: Yeah, just- I see him queuing up.
Scott: This is the best part, here it comes.
Rym: Okay, so he's queuing up his thing.
Rym: Oh, there he goes!
Rym: The best part is the guy in yellow who goes like that.
Rym: Is he flicking everybody?
Rym: Oh, he's waving.
Rym: The run.
Rym: I feel like if I watch the beginning of the video more, he practiced that run.
Rym: The floppy arm thing he's doing.
Rym: This is a pretty good thing of the day.
Scott: Alright, there you go.
Rym: In the meta moment, we're gonna do a new book club soon because nine books into the Wheel of Time.
Rym: Whoa!
Rym: I'm getting a little bored with it.
Scott: I made it to five- oh, I guess four and a quarter.
Rym: I am almost done with book nine.
Rym: I gotta tell ya.
Rym: I started skimming.
Rym: Because- but then I thought, you know what?
Rym: Maybe I'll just read the spoilers.
Rym: 'Cause I kinda wanna know, like, what the deal is with everything.
Scott: Oh, tell me.
Rym: Yeah, I started trying to read some spoilers.
Rym: The spoilers are so dense that I might as well just fucking read the book.
Rym: Here's the cliff note.
Scott: It's bigger than the book.
Scott: It's like our Utena video.
Scott: It's longer than the Utena episode.
Rym: Remember the oath rod thing?
Rym: So, now there's like four oath rods all over the place.
Rym: People are fucking using them for everything.
Rym: Like, all the time.
Rym: And apparently they learned that the oath rod has side effects.
Rym: And I tried to learn what the deal was with that.
Scott: Why would you want to make so many oaths?
Rym: Maybe to find the black aja.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Yeah, maybe to be like, "Yo, swear that you're not black
Rym: aja.".
Rym: Oh, you won't?
Rym: Also, the oath rods are real bad news.
Rym: Like, real bad news.
Scott: Did you find anything about the snake people?
Rym: No.
Rym: So, here's what I got.
Rym: In the beginning of, I think, book eight, or it might have been book nine, there's a scene way in the mountains with a bunch of people you've never heard of who are all like kings of whatever.
Scott: Ooh, my kind of scene.
Rym: One of them has a logo on his thing.
Scott: Of the snake people?
Rym: No, of the fox head.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: And then it cut away from them.
Rym: And now it's been like two books.
Rym: And they haven't come back.
Scott: Those are my people.
Rym: That is literally as close as I've gotten to them.
Rym: So, I might pick a different book club book.
Rym: Partly because I got some travel to London and Paris coming up in a few months.
Rym: So, I'll have an airplane ride or four to read some books.
Rym: But, most important, this weekend.
Rym: This weekend.
Scott: Well, this week.
Scott: Thursday, Friday, Saturday, Sunday.
Rym: We're going to be at MagFest.
Rym: I'm real excited about this.
Scott: I mean, this is serious business.
Scott: Like, everyone is going to be there.
Rym: Yeah, one, we skipped the last MagFest.
Scott: Well, because PacSouth is the same time.
Rym: Yeah, and so as a result, I just realized that it's been a long time since I've been to a MagFest.
Rym: And I remembered how much I love MagFest.
Scott: This MagFest, everyone is going.
Scott: Our Google Hangout already has like 30 people.
Rym: Yeah, we're going to need multiple separate Google Hangouts to manage these people.
Scott: Yeah, this shit is going down hard, right?
Rym: We've already planned a 4 a.m.
Rym: DDR party.
Rym: that I was kind of jokingly proposing.
Rym: And a bunch of people were like,
Rym: "Yes.".
Scott: You just keep saying it over and over again.
Rym: Because people keep responding to me like, "Yes.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Let's do
Rym: it.".
Scott: Alright, so what panels are we doing at this MagFest?
Rym: So, we have six panels at this MagFest.
Scott: That's too many panels.
Scott: I want to spend more time at MagFest, less time panel.
Rym: You're only on five of them, though.
Rym: No, you're on four of them, I think.
Scott: Okay, that's better.
Rym: So, Thursday, 5.30 p.m.
Rym: Esports.
Rym: It's a panel about Esports.
Scott: Am I on that one?
Rym: Yes.
Rym: Thursday, whatever.
Rym: Friday is our big day.
Rym: We front-loaded.
Rym: So, Friday, we got Designing Game Rules, Atari Game Design.
Rym: If you saw us do those at PacSouth, basically the same.
Rym: You don't need to go.
Rym: And The Far Future of Gaming, which Scott does not have to be on.
Scott: Alright, yeah.
Scott: Saturday.
Scott: Gonna party it up.
Rym: All Things is CCG, LCG, TCG.
Scott: I guess I gotta be on that because it was my idea.
Scott: Even though I contributed nothing to it, other than saying, "Hey, does anyone want to talk about
Scott: this?".
Scott: That's literally all I said.
Scott: Literally.
Rym: I think someone's got some slides.
Scott: I said, "Hey, does anyone...".
Scott: I play Netrunner a lot.
Scott: "Does anyone want to do a panel about card games and
Scott: shit?".
Scott: And that's paraphrasing, but that's all I said.
Scott: And then now the panel's on the schedule.
Rym: It's gonna happen.
Scott: I guess my name is on it.
Rym: And then Overly Complicated Board Games Phase 1, which Scott does not have to be on.
Scott: Okay, good.
Scott: I don't want to play any ASL.
Scott: I was only joking about that.
Rym: Six panels.
Rym: Thursday, Friday, Saturday.
Rym: And other than that, we're pretty much gonna be in the arcade or in tabletop or in a private room playing Eclipse.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: So come say hi.
Rym: This is one of the few cons where you can easily find us and hang out for a while.
Scott: Yeah, there isn't a super big concert I want to go to, but there were some concerts I kind of want to go to, right?
Scott: There was this video game.
Scott: DJ battle is always good.
Rym: I think I'm gonna wander into concerts.
Scott: Mighty No.
Scott: 9 tribute something.
Scott: There's some stuff on there, but it wasn't like two times ago that I went to MAGFest where Streets of Rage guy was there.
Scott: Or when Machine Supremacy was there the time we went and then the time we didn't go.
Rym: I think I Fight Dragons is doing some stuff.
Scott: That's not bad.
Rym: So MAGFest.
Rym: Well, if you're not going, I mean, I don't know if it's sold out.
Scott: It's not sold out, but it's gonna be hard to get a hotel.
Scott: that's close.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: In fact, I don't know.
Rym: I guess you could get a hotel far away and drive in.
Rym: A lot of people are driving in like our friend George.
Scott: It also might be close to sold out, right?
Scott: So you might have issues if you try to like show up and buy a ticket.
Scott: It could be sold out by the time you get there.
Rym: Yeah, but for real, the clock is ringing.
Rym: It's MAGFest time.
Rym: And then we got pretty much nothing until like zinc icon in PAX East.
Rym: So yesterday, actually, we were gonna do a game day and I had a little bit of alien that I was fighting off.
Rym: So Scott was like, well, here, why don't we play online games?
Scott: Well, me and Chris are going to come over here and play some serious tabletops.
Scott: But then, you know, you didn't commit.
Scott: And then it's like, well, you know, it's really snowy and shitty.
Scott: No one wants to leave their apartment.
Rym: I would have been totally up for it, except I was, you know, that feeling where you're almost sick.
Rym: And one, if I was going to get sick, I couldn't risk getting other people sick before MAGFest.
Rym: Two, I needed to make sure I recovered, which I appear to have.
Scott: So I'm like, hey, let's play a vidya game.
Scott: So actually we found this site that's like still working on some like online thing where you can play board games.
Scott: And we played some Reiner Knizia Samurai, which I remember how to play now.
Scott: That game's OK.
Rym: Oh, that's the one with the high hats.
Scott: They changed it to Buddha's helmets or Gates helmets and rice bowls.
Rym: No more Buddhas?
Scott: Well, I mean, the gate is up to a Buddhist temple.
Rym: That's the second best game named Shogun.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, we played Samurai.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Whatever.
Rym: No, it was Shogun.
Rym: It got renamed Samurai swords.
Scott: And then anyway, so, you know, we're just looking for a game to play online.
Scott: And we're sort of it's hard to actually find games that are a good good enough.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And that you can play online on a PC with some sort of co-op situation.
Scott: There's a lot of local co-op, a lot of local multiplayer, a lot of more than two people games.
Scott: But it's hard to find two people games.
Scott: They're just going through steam looking for them.
Scott: And it's like we already played like Portal two co-op.
Scott: And it's not like.
Scott: how many FPS are there that we can find that are co-op.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That would be fun.
Scott: But there's not a lot of them.
Scott: So we come across this one called Helldivers and I'm like, oh, this looks interesting.
Scott: You know, it's a. it's sort of like a robotron shooter.
Scott: That's always good for some co-op action.
Rym: That's all Scott told me about it.
Rym: So I just joined it.
Scott: I didn't know anything about it.
Scott: I just thought, oh, it's a robotron game.
Scott: It costs 20 bucks, which I'd rather wait for a steam sale.
Scott: But you know what?
Scott: Fuck it.
Scott: It's really cold out and I got nothing to do.
Scott: Let's just do this.
Scott: We'll do an episode on it, even if it sucks.
Scott: It'll you know, we'll get our 20 bucks worth.
Scott: Plus there's that steam refund policy.
Scott: I can always return it real quick if it's really bad.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So you and Chris played for a little while.
Scott: Played for a little while while Rym got his shit together.
Rym: Well, because I was in the middle of uploading actually the archival footage from Pac South to Amazon Cloud Drive.
Scott: I'll get my SD card back.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: So the card anyway.
Scott: So we get this game.
Scott: So here's what I learned about this game.
Scott: First of all, it's made by the people in Magica.
Scott: So they have experience with the sort of twin stick action, you know, of that.
Scott: Magica was right.
Scott: So they're good at this, too.
Scott: I learned from Wikipedia.
Scott: this game was actually a PlayStation game that was released in March of 2015.
Scott: So it's like it's a year old, but it wasn't put on steam until December 2015.
Scott: So it's actually a really new steam game and you could only play it on steam.
Scott: You don't play with the PlayStation people.
Rym: Thank God.
Rym: Right.
Scott: So you're all you know, it's only steam people when you play with steam.
Scott: So it's a robotron shooter.
Scott: And the story is there's this super Starship Troopers.
Rym: The story is Starship Troopers.
Scott: It's Super Earth.
Rym: You're on super democracy.
Scott: You're from Super Earth and you're basically evil.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And the game doesn't even like.
Rym: the propaganda video that plays.
Rym: in the beginning is like, hey, we're evil.
Scott: Join the Helldivers.
Scott: Go to some other planet and fuck it up and bring them managed democracy.
Rym: The new when you first start the game after you do the tutorial.
Rym: I love how the tutorial is like like it's like take pick up your gun and shoot that target.
Rym: You shoot it once and it's like you are now a firearms expert.
Rym: Move on to the next training.
Rym: You are now a grenade expert.
Rym: Right.
Rym: And then it gets you into the first NPC.
Rym: I talked to the whole game.
Rym: The guy who salutes you in the bottom right just said, why is our logo a skull?
Scott: Good question.
Scott: So, yeah.
Scott: So there's three different evil alien races.
Scott: There's the aliens, the cyborgs and the one I forget.
Scott: I forget bugs.
Scott: No bugs, cyborgs and I don't know.
Scott: I've only ever seen bugs because we only chose bug levels.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So you go and choose, you know, some mission based on his difficulty.
Scott: And you have to do certain objectives and then, you know, evac the planet, you know, after you do whatever missions there are and then you succeed in a certain number of missions per planet.
Scott: And once you do all the missions on the planet, you succeeded at that planet.
Scott: And now you can go do another planet somewhere and you bring with you one to four Helldivers.
Scott: You and up to three other people could be random Internet people.
Scott: Could be your friends, could be you alone, you know, whatever.
Scott: And you do these missions.
Scott: And at first you start playing the game and it seems like way too easy.
Scott: Like the easiest missions are baby missions.
Scott: Like you shoot one thing and you just do it.
Scott: It's done right.
Scott: But the difficulty gets up pretty high.
Rym: And then I knew it was good because I was yelling so much that Emily was like, simmer down.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it seemed, you know, I started playing the game a bunch and it really felt like there wasn't a lot of variation.
Scott: Like I was getting a little bored.
Scott: I was like, hey, we've been shooting the same bugs and doing the same objectives.
Scott: This is getting kind of old fast.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Can we.
Scott: Is there any variation here?
Scott: What's going on?
Scott: So the thing is, yeah, there's actually a shit ton of variation that it just you don't see it until you like get deep into it.
Scott: Like the depth is like way deep, but you can't like see the bottom of the pool.
Scott: You just got to keep swimming slower, like inch by inch.
Rym: Like at first we thought, like, let's just drop right on the objectives.
Rym: And then that started to not work.
Rym: So we had to like plan our routes.
Scott: And it's like with such small amounts of stuff, like so few weapons and so few different enemies, like the amount of thinking that had to go into everything and like, you know, the gameplay variation we had to get into was actually like, whoa.
Rym: So the way it actually plays the game that it is closest to and this might sound strange, but I'm going to stick by this is the original Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles.
Rym: Yeah, it definitely closes today because that game started out like, all right, just hit the bad guys, whatever.
Rym: But as you got deep and toward the end of the original Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles, you started figuring out how to do those like really complicated spell combos.
Rym: Suddenly, the game was like a squad of like Scott doing stuff while me and Katsu are literally like coordinating with each other, with code words to figure out like what attacks to do to make sure we time everything, coordinate everything right.
Rym: And we started having to act like a really pro unit.
Rym: And this game is the same way.
Rym: Like we sort of had this roll out phase where like we get our shit together and I'd roll out a turret and you guys would do whatever you were doing and then we go.
Scott: The key is there's three keys that make this happen.
Scott: Key number one is they don't let you go off the screen from the other people.
Scott: So if one person is going up and I was going down, you just get killed doing that because that person on top will get killed by something that's off screen to the top that you can't see.
Scott: And then the person at the bottom will get killed by something off the bottom of the screen that you can't see because you were trying to split up.
Scott: And the camera won't zoom out after a certain point and you'll just be screwed.
Scott: So that makes like Crystal Chronicles with a bucket where you have to stay together.
Scott: Number two, friendly fire is serious shit.
Scott: Like if you even shoot your teammate once, they dead.
Rym: Like you know most games like this, like you can throw down a turret and it shoots the bad guys automatically.
Rym: The turret in this game is utterly ridiculously powerful.
Scott: It's also really stupid and will shoot you if you were between it and the bad guy.
Rym: There was a moment where I literally threw, I had two turrets on either side of me and then a bug, like a camouflage bug jumped on top of me.
Rym: And the two turrets, I see them spinning around and I'm like,
Rym: "Welp.".
Scott: So yeah, the turrets will, you know, there are many, many things.
Scott: For example, there are mechs.
Scott: You didn't see the mechs.
Scott: I haven't seen any mechs.
Scott: I played online.
Scott: Yeah, there's a lot of stuff you didn't see.
Scott: And it's like, yeah, if you're piloting the mech, you can just step on people by accident who aren't in the mech.
Rym: Well, you can call down, I remember there was Scott, so Chris and I died and Scott was running away and he like threw down the thing to call in reinforcements, basically to respawn us.
Scott: Yeah, you can respawn your friends just by throwing this object, but you have to like get to a place to do it safely.
Rym: So then you got like attacked by some other guy and he pushed you back and then the respawn thing fell from the sky on top of you, killing you.
Scott: Yup, exactly.
Rym: Or like the chopper, like at the end you have to get to the chopper.
Scott: There's all these things that you can call for to come help you.
Scott: Stratagems, and you basically throw an object as a stratagem and then, you know, the helldivers in the sky drop something and it lands in the spot that you threw the stratagem.
Rym: Now there's two great aspects there.
Rym: One, the stratagems and the weapons and everything have an upgrade tech tree, which is fun.
Rym: And two, to actually deploy them, it's Sabin style Final Fantasy VI, like left, left, right, left, up, up, down, left, right.
Scott: Yup, it's like doing a blitz.
Rym: Yeah, so like some of the objectives are like that too, so like to arm the nuke you got to go over and be like bup, bup, bup, bup, bup, bup, bup, bup while everyone else is doing their shit.
Scott: So actually we were using the hellbombs to do that mission where you blow up the nests.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: People I played with just had actual nukes and just called them in and blew up the nests immediately without having to activate some stupid thing.
Scott: Oh.
Scott: Yeah, so there is just better stuff, right, that you can get.
Rym: Would the air strike do it?
Scott: I mean there's certain things that can damage the nests because they're strong enough and certain things that can't.
Scott: I think they have tank level armors.
Scott: Actually, my recoilless rifle could have destroyed them if we shot them enough times.
Rym: And then yeah, like talking about the depth, so Scott had the recoilless rifle.
Scott: Which is a really fun weapon.
Scott: Once I figured out how to use it, I was way into it.
Scott: Because basically any time a really big bad guy appears, it really sucks to kill it.
Scott: Especially because ammo is so limited.
Scott: But if the recoilless rifle is like this special thing, it's actually a stratagem that you call down and then pick up.
Scott: You shoot it once and if you hit them dead on, they dead.
Scott: And I got really good at that.
Rym: And it felt really good because we'd be like fighting and suddenly Chris would yell "Big one coming
Rym: in!"
Rym: and then you see it coming in.
Scott: So I just switch to that weapon, I aim and I fire my one rocket and boom, it's dead.
Rym: While the two of us fall back and cover Scott while he's aiming from all the little bugs that are coming in.
Scott: Right, if I hit something, and a lot of times I would shoot it and hit something too close to myself and kill myself.
Scott: Or something would get in the way and it wouldn't work.
Scott: But mostly I hit the bad guys with it.
Rym: A lot of stuff too, like the medevac copter coming down.
Scott: So reloading the recoilless rifle is really slow, but I found out when playing with people online that there's actually this supply pack that goes with it.
Scott: So Rym picked up my supply pack once and I was like "Rym, you took my stupid supply pack, how can I reload this stupid rifle now?
Scott: Fuck
Scott: you.".
Scott: Apparently, if Rym has the supply pack, there's a reason it's separate.
Scott: He can help me reload the thing and it would take much less time.
Rym: That's real important.
Scott: Yeah, we didn't know that.
Scott: So now that we know that, that's great.
Rym: So take all the gameplay feels of Crystal Chronicles, coupled with an upgrade tree that's more like a Deus Ex, like there's legit upgrade tree in there.
Scott: Yeah, but it's all co-op, there's no PVP at all.
Scott: It's always you and up to three other people fighting against the AI.
Rym: Oh, I figured out what the SOS does too.
Scott: Oh, it calls people from the internet to come help you.
Rym: It calls a rando into your game.
Scott: Yeah, it's like "Internet, come help
Scott: us.".
Rym: So there's theoretically a persistent meta, where as you level up, you just get better.
Rym: This is not a game that you would play forever, because once you've upgraded everything, I'm pretty sure...
Scott: Yeah, you're playing the same missions, and eventually when you do the hell dive level missions, those are the hardest possible missions.
Scott: If you've done enough of those and you've leveled up all the stuff, there's really not a reason to keep playing.
Rym: And that is when you stop playing the game, because it was only 20 bucks and you put like 60 hours into this thing.
Scott: But whenever you complete a mission, you actually have community influence, so this actually boosts the war effort in general with these points.
Scott: So as the war effort progresses, eventually there's like a final mission, and then I think the game ends as a whole, and then there's another war.
Scott: that happens.
Rym: So they're like events, like it can go the other way.
Rym: If the bugs start winning or whatever, like if one of the bad guys wins, then there's emergency missions that pop up.
Rym: Like, right now, whoever's online, fucking get in here, and you have to defend a city.
Rym: But those are like, it starts at two o'clock, like right the fuck now, if you don't join, you miss out.
Scott: Yeah, the stuff like that.
Scott: So the only negative in this game that I found is that there's a lot of DLCs that cost money, and those DLCs are not trivial.
Scott: For example, there are all-terrain boots that you can buy as a perk, and with real money you can get these.
Scott: You can't get them any other way, as far as I know.
Scott: The all-terrain boots, they make it so you just walk in snow and water no problem.
Rym: Oh, that's some bullshit.
Scott: Right, but obviously there's still a perk, so you'd have to get rid of your laser sight, because you only carry one perk on you.
Rym: I would give up my laser sight for that.
Scott: I'm just saying, for example, so there's certain things that cost money and are just better, but it's all co-op, and you can get really... I mean, I'm perfectly happy with the game.
Scott: It's not like I'm competing, so I don't care if someone's better at shit than me.
Rym: Well, that's the thing.
Rym: This is a game.
Rym: If you want to enjoy it...
Scott: It's like this pay-to-win game, and it's like, there is pay-to-win, but it's like, you know, remember when... I always remember Tycho wrote this thing when they talked about Diablo 3, having pay-to-get stuff, and it's like, who are you cheating?
Scott: Satan himself?
Scott: Right?
Scott: Who is the cheated party here?
Scott: The fucking bugs, right?
Rym: But for real, I wouldn't recommend playing this game with a bunch of randos, though Scott did, and we'll talk about that.
Scott: So after we played, you know, with Just Us 3 and had a good time, even with our very little... You know, we didn't even scratch the surface and had a great time.
Rym: Yeah, the amount of yelling was like, there was a lot of like, "Go, go, go, Scott,
Rym: recover!".
Scott: I'm gonna play this when I get home after I eat, so I played some single player, and the single player was lame, because if you get the difficulty to any reasonable level, you can't do it on your own.
Scott: It's too hard.
Scott: I mean, I'm sure you could get good enough to where you can do it on your own, but godspeed to you if you want to do these things on your own.
Scott: So I said, "Alright, fine, I'll play with random internet
Scott: people.".
Scott: So, this is only a sample size of two, but I played two games with random internet people.
Scott: So the first one, it was the stereotypical people who are speaking in Chinese and have way higher level than me, but they also spoke English.
Scott: So I'm playing with these people, and they were really good at the game.
Scott: They knew what to do, right?
Scott: You know, and I sort of was able to follow along and contribute and help without really bringing anyone down or anything, right?
Scott: And everyone, they were trying to help.
Scott: Everyone was just positive.
Scott: There was not one shitcock at all, right?
Scott: Everything was just A+, let's go.
Scott: The guy has mechs, he brought four mechs with him, and was like, "Four mech stratagems all at once, everyone get a mech, let's
Scott: go.".
Scott: Kind of situation, right?
Scott: And I picked up the recoilless rifle, the guy took the pack, and he's like, "Yeah, I can reload this for you
Scott: here.".
Scott: And then he was so good at reloading it for me, I would shoot a big bad guy with it.
Scott: They all knew that I was doing it and got out of the way.
Scott: I didn't have to say, "Hey, get out of the way,
Scott: guys.".
Scott: They were always out of the way any time a big bad guy showed up.
Scott: And then, every time I fired it, the next time I pulled it out to reload it in a quiet time, it would already be reloaded.
Scott: I'm like, "When did he reload this
Scott: thing?".
Scott: Right?
Scott: He just reloaded it without me even knowing because he's paying attention.
Scott: So I'm like, "Wow, these guys are really
Scott: good.".
Scott: That game eventually ended, played another game with some other people.
Scott: So he was a small bit of trolling.
Scott: One guy, all four of his stratagems were mines.
Rym: Oh, mine, mine, mine, mines are dangerous.
Scott: He put the mines everywhere and we kept dying on them.
Scott: But, we kept reviving ourselves.
Scott: Anytime anyone died, everyone, even the mine guy, would throw the reinforcement thing immediately.
Scott: Anytime I would throw the reinforcement thing and I wasn't the last person alive, all the other remaining living players would also throw their reinforcement thing the same time that I threw it.
Scott: So if anyone died, it'd be like, "Reinforce it, reinforce it, reinforce
Scott: it.".
Rym: That's actually kind of bad news because then you can't reinforce again for 30, 60, or 90 seconds.
Scott: Well, if you're going to play online with people, you need to upgrade your reinforcement thing to the maximum.
Rym: Oh yeah, because you've read that Etiquette Guide.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I'm not going to bow before I kill someone with a lightsaber either.
Scott: Yeah, well, the other thing is once I got to the point where I was able to upgrade my Recoilers Rival to have its own laser sight, I didn't need to use the laser sight perk anymore.
Scott: So I was able to instead switch to the priority stratagem perk which makes all my cooldowns faster.
Scott: So that's way good.
Rym: But, the game shines most if you find some friends and just play with them.
Rym: Play with your actual friends and ignore all the other people on the internet.
Scott: But I'm telling you, I played with two random internet groups and they were both excellent.
Scott: And in that second group, I already knew at this point how the Recoilers Rival worked with the friend helping you reload.
Scott: I didn't even say anything.
Scott: I just picked up the gun.
Scott: Someone else without me saying anything picked up the supply pack.
Scott: And in that second game with completely different people, same situation.
Scott: It was just always reloaded whenever I looked at it.
Scott: One guy, you can only reload it if I have it out.
Scott: One time I put it away too quickly to get the shotgun out.
Scott: And the guy started stabbing me with his bayonet and I knew what he meant and I pulled the gun out and immediately reloaded it.
Scott: And I was like, alright, these people are like...
Rym: It is interesting how little trolling there is and I think it's because...
Scott: Well, this is only a sample size of two games and there was a guy dropping mines on everyone.
Scott: There's also a system of commendations and reporting and someone commended me.
Scott: I was like, oh, okay.
Rym: But I did know, I read around like in Reddit and forums.
Rym: I was reading the meta, the people talking about this game.
Rym: And it seems like there is very little trolling in general.
Scott: I think it's because it's 100% co-op.
Rym: You gain nothing by trolling people and they can all just quit and form a new game without you.
Scott: And they can also just report you and not commend you and make a new game.
Scott: The guy who dropped mines everywhere, after the fourth time he did it in a silly way.
Scott: that wasn't helpful, he got kicked.
Scott: And it was like, alright.
Rym: But seriously, buy this game if you want a game like this.
Scott: Or wait for a Steam sale.
Scott: I don't think it's going anywhere.
Scott: Magic is still around.
Rym: But because of the nature of it, it is kind of repetitive.
Rym: You're going to play it out.
Scott: I'm telling you, it's repetitive because it's deep and there's a lot of stuff to see.
Scott: But you see very little new stuff over time so you have to keep playing.
Scott: And every mission you'll see a little bit of new stuff.
Rym: But eventually you're going to see most of the stuff?
Scott: It's a lot of stuff that comes in in a trickle.
Rym: People are saying 40 to 60 hours is about all it's worth if you play hard.
Scott: Yeah, that's about right.
Scott: And 20 bucks for that?
Scott: You don't need to wait for the Steam sale.
Rym: That's why I say it might be worth buying because we're in it right now.
Rym: And if you all get into it at the same time, it's going to be way more fun.
Rym: Because I'll totally play it with you guys because it is super fun.
Rym: And I can name many of our personal friends who will be specifically into this game.
Scott: And if there is a Steam sale for this, oh man, that is totally worth it.
Scott: So yeah, there's DLCs which is bullshit, but it's pay to win.
Scott: But who are you cheating?
Scott: The bugs?
Rym: However, if you join my game and you bought some of that DLC, not going to be a fan.
Scott: Why not?
Rym: I feel like those missions with the water would have been a little bit easy if I could just walk over the water.
Scott: That's just one example of a DLC, right?
Rym: If they're all that equivalent power, that's a little bit much.
Scott: I don't know, but let's say I bought a stratagem.
Scott: I could drop it and you can use it even though I bought it.
Scott: Yeah, right?
Scott: There's also a lot of the DLCs are cosmetic, right?
Scott: But I mean, yeah, it's bullshit because it's $40 to get the mega DLC pack plus the game.
Scott: It's $20 to get the game with no DLCs.
Scott: If there is, however, one day, if they had a deal like $10 to get every DLC to finish off, I'd be like, "Oh, maybe.
Scott: See how much I'm still playing
Scott: it.".
Scott: Because it would just add so much more freshness to the game.
Scott: Every time you mix up, you can get more gameplay out of it.
Scott: if you mix up which things you're using.
Scott: If I move away from my recoilless rifle strategy and decide I'm going to play more jump boots and laser cannon strategy, suddenly it's like a different game because you play so differently.
Scott: Play this game with us.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patrons for this episode of GeekNights in order of the amount of money they give us are Nicholas Brando, Rebecca Dunn, John R. Knobs II, Amanda Duchette, James David White, Christian Koontz, Jess, Sam Cordery, Mechanical Mind, William Eisenrose, You expected the next name to be yours, but it was me, Dio, Clinton Walton, MyStady.com, Phil Ulrich, Renee from New Zealand, Robert Lee, Ryan Perrin, Drew Openlander, Rare Lavelle, Brian Cedroni, Rochelle Montanona, Finn Eric Solvarod, Rochelle Montanona again, Kinetic Man, Aaron Cerise, Chris Midkiff, Chris Knox, he was a dark and stormy night, Daniel Redman, Chris Haddad, Doug Schneider, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer, and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: I was tripped up by the two Rochelle Montanonas in there.
Rym: That caused me a moment of delay.
Rym: Also, I'm speaking to you very close to the microphone in a perhaps smooth radio voice.
Rym: As you probably saw, the Utena episode is finally up, and we actually have two recorded, so I'm working on the editing of the second one already.
Rym: But that won't go up until I get the two panels we have left, possibly three from PAX South that have to get on the channel.
Rym: However, everything will be on hold until next week, because we are leaving for MAGFest early Thursday morning, where as you saw, we have six panels.
Rym: So, if you are listening to this still, the post-credits stinger, the Patreon extra content, then be sure to come by and say hi at MAGFest.
Rym: We're not joking, we're going to be playing DDR at like three or four in the morning at least one night, and it's going to be amazing.
Rym: And now I leave you with something kinda weird.
Scott: Good shit, good shit, that's some good shit right there, right there, if I do say so myself, I say so, that's what I'm talking about, right there, right there, right there.
Rym: Woo!
Rym: Good shit!