Rym: It's Monday December 12th 2016.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: instant messaging in 2016. cuz last time we talked about this was And it was way better back then.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So I did buy that computer that I've been talking about constantly and there's a bunch of forum threads about it.
Rym: I'll make the like Definitive Newegg playlist of exactly what I bought because I tweaked a few things.
Rym: playlist.
Rym: But you're like the.
Rym: the Samsung 960 just came out and it was actually cheaper than the 950 and better.
Rym: So there's no reason to buy a 950 Pro and do that m2 SSD unless you find it like less than 280 bucks.
Rym: What you might they might get cheap soon.
Rym: If you're not building computer right now, though the Samsung 950 or 960 will have an evo version which is like the more discounted version and they'll be pretty cheap.
Rym: You'll be able to get out like one terabyte one of those for not that much money like five or six hundred bucks in January Mm-hmm, so it'll be good times.
Rym: But I was not gonna buy a video card.
Rym: I had sort of planned Originally to take the 770 out of my current computer and stick it in the new computer and buy a 1080 later Because right now actually the 770 is not the primary bottleneck on this computer I'm using now.
Rym: all the other things are the bottleneck.
Rym: But then I was looking at the computer and I imagine taking my slightly dusty oldest shit 770 putting it in this nice new computer and then five minutes later.
Rym: I just bought a 1080 after doing some research Mm-hmm, and it'll come.
Rym: if not today definitely tomorrow's.
Rym: I'm gonna finish the computer probably tomorrow Mm-hmm.
Rym: Yeah So what's going on in the life of Scott?
Scott: Wake up go to work Make a podcast go home.
Scott: Wash your hands wash your hands page Go to bed.
Rym: That was some.
Rym: some football and hockey last night though.
Scott: New York is very winning right now.
Scott: everyone else very losing.
Scott: I mean losing more than normal, right?
Scott: Cuz I mean if you're not in New York, you're already losing just by not being New York.
Scott: Yeah, but we're winning Real good right now.
Scott: Oh, man, we put the beat we got a shit kicked out of us We got mad injuries.
Scott: We put the B team out there like to one or two lines of AHL dudes Yeah, and yet the B team shutting them out.
Rym: Yeah, and then Rhonda two nights in a row Giants, right?
Scott: So in the frozen tundra?
Scott: No, the frozen tundras in Green Bay where there was a much more thrilling game.
Scott: You know Giants coming out got these Cowboys and the Cowboys all season only lost one game to the Giants.
Scott: They beat everybody else and that the number one had the number one record in the whole Football League, but then Giants again.
Scott: Giants beat him again.
Scott: So it's like what does that mean?
Scott: We're like we lost other games, you know We're not like the greatest.
Scott: We won six in a row before but we're not like, you know, like the world.
Scott: we're not looking super amazing.
Scott: We got problems But hey, we beat the best team of the year twice.
Rym: So the crazy thing about that's how we do was that Rangers were scoring on power plays.
Scott: I know they didn't do that last.
Rym: that's that's kind of frightening new territory for last year.
Scott: They didn't know how to do that.
Rym: That was like the one Counterbalancing factors that made them not like the best team.
Scott: Well, they learned in the offseason.
Scott: We have an extra guy so it's easy to see.
Rym: I thought we should just like really turtle and just sort of pass it around the goal and not actually do anything with it.
Rym: So yeah, the biggest news is probably that.
Rym: So for a while people who backed all the new pebble devices.
Rym: We're kind of rumbling on Kickstarter like how come no updates hearing rumors things aren't good.
Scott: Yeah I didn't know it was up with that because like pebble was one of those things when the very first pebble was Kickstarted and I was like, you know If I it's not too much money if I kickstart that and I never get it.
Scott: I'm okay with that because if I do get it, whoa, cuz that was before smartwatches.
Scott: Yeah, I mean there wasn't no Apple watch.
Scott: there was no, you know Android wear Right, and it looked like pretty much exactly what I wanted in a smartwatch, which is not what Android wear Apple watch does But it's just.
Scott: I just want something that will have a very long battery life.
Scott: So I don't have to deal with it.
Scott: It'll just always work and just show me the time and show me notifications.
Scott: I don't take my phone out of my pocket.
Scott: Just bonus feature.
Scott: I don't even use right.
Rym: I yourself them like if I'm biking.
Scott: or the only other feature I use Navigation.
Scott: I don't use that.
Scott: The only other feature I use is could make my music go forward and back and also Remembering things.
Scott: No, it's like someone calls me on the phone.
Scott: I look and see who it is and I can hang up on them without Right, that's that's all I use it for us anyway.
Scott: So I kick-started and it came and I was like, wow, they done it.
Scott: And then those.
Scott: it was.
Scott: the first one though was not a perfect watch by any means Actually, my first one was like messed up and I had to send.
Scott: they sent me an RMA new one But they actually sent it and then pebble time came out and it was just so drastically better and perfect.
Scott: It was smaller and had a better screen.
Scott: It was just better in every way.
Rym: So and the pebble time steel was just like the power watch and I was happy with the pebble time.
Scott: So I got one and then I'm like those pebble time two and stuff and I'm like man.
Scott: I got pebble time.
Scott: pebble time two is not the significant upgrade.
Rym: I kick-started the pebble time to my Interesting.
Rym: So my rationale was one.
Rym: the pebble time one was just like spending money.
Rym: was it was real cheap?
Rym: That's the thing.
Rym: the problem with smartwatches in general is that they're really expensive devices Yet they don't actually provide that level of it like benefit to your life.
Scott: I think that they're ridiculously inexpensive.
Scott: regular watches are freaking expensive as hell.
Scott: if you want one that does You know, it's not just a Casio or whatever, but the Casio will tell the time right?
Rym: It's like 50% of your use case.
Scott: like you go you go to the you go to a watch store and it's like I Got watches.
Rym: thousand dollars two thousand dollars ten thousand dollars Dollars add zero additional functionality except they tell you like the moon phase or something.
Scott: They're gold gold Jerry.
Rym: Yeah, it's gold.
Rym: But the new one Emily didn't have a smartwatch and I was like, oh well I'll get the new one and I'll just give you my old one because it's still in like perfect condition.
Scott: I have a pebble one that still works I assume Yeah So and also have a one that's mad broken.
Rym: and also the screen on the time too was just way bigger Which was interesting.
Rym: because your thing because the pebble time the one thing about actually like smaller.
Scott: I don't like those giant.
Rym: Well, so it says the watch is now bigger the screen just goes all the way to the edge.
Scott: That's the difference because right now there's like Bigger though, but yeah, there is almost a centimeter of not.
Rym: Yeah, there's like a little space six millimeters on each side.
Rym: So you're getting like 12 millimeters of more screen total.
Rym: Yeah, maybe a whole centimeter.
Rym: That's kind of a big deal for a tiny device and the.
Scott: I don't need more screen.
Scott: That's enough screen like a little.
Scott: I wish they would just shrink the bezel down.
Scott: That would be better.
Rym: Yeah, well it was color as opposed to the original one, which was nice and it's ink.
Rym: So the screen is always on and not using battery.
Scott: I mean the pebble time is color.
Rym: Yeah, all the pebbles are as opposed to every other smartwatch, which is an actual screen burning through your one-day battery Like I see people talk about.
Rym: all those watches run out of battery in the middle of the day.
Scott: No, but you're acting like the pebble time - is color the pebble time?
Scott: one wasn't the pebble.
Rym: I kind of just digressed into like what I like.
Scott: Pebble is not color.
Rym: Now.
Rym: They did make a pebble like the when the pebble time came out.
Rym: They had like updated regular pebbles as well.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Rym: So anyway that kick I kick-started a thing and whatever it'll come because I kind of had faith.
Scott: It's like this company was already at a point where they went from kick-starting to actually making stuff to actually having a community of Developers to actually have it, you know, like it was a real thing.
Scott: They were in stores.
Scott: You could buy them.
Scott: It's like oh they made it into a real thing.
Scott: Good job.
Rym: So when I saw people rumbling in the early days like hey, what's going on with pebble?
Rym: I Mostly ignored it.
Rym: but then I noticed something because I had like.
Rym: there's three watch faces I use on this thing like three of the apps that I installed the minimalist weather one The weather land one.
Scott: I kept getting firmware updates too.
Scott: So I assumed that pebble was just rolling right along.
Rym: Yeah, and they kept adding features like they added stuff.
Rym: I don't use but they were adding like stuff to the pebble.
Rym: Yeah, but the apps like other than pebble themselves The list of apps and watch faces that the community created for the pebble a long time ago Basically went unchanged.
Scott: Well, I think when everyone gets a watch face, they like finally and then they don't look again.
Scott: It's like none of them.
Scott: I got a perfect one.
Scott: Which one?
Rym: minimalist weather?
Scott: No, I got this one that cost a dollar.
Scott: Ah It's perfect.
Scott: But Ben anyway.
Scott: But yeah it's like when you set up a brand new pebble.
Scott: you go searching through the watch faces and the apps and you set them all and You pretty much never look at that again ever but I just noticed cuz I thought oh I wonder if anything updated.
Rym: I went in there.
Rym: I was looking through like every app just to see like what had happened.
Scott: like imagine if like that's your thing like Making and changing watch faces all the time.
Scott: That's a weird thing.
Rym: Well, I could.
Rym: it's not a good use of your life But I could think of like cool like there were things I would like to do with the smartwatch that it didn't do that.
Scott: Well, I could make a watch face really easily.
Scott: Just make one.
Rym: Yeah, not just watching.
Rym: this is but other things like for example, I use Strava a lot for running and by the Strava Yeah, but I went and got the app.
Rym: I think I paid a dollar for it so I can start and start a Strava just on the watch without having to pull My phone out and we're great.
Rym: But that app has not been updated since it was written and there's no other app that does that.
Rym: Mm-hmm And that ecosystem seemed to have already dried up quite some time ago.
Rym: Like no one was buying apps for the pebble.
Scott: No, why would you buy apps for your pebble watch?
Scott: It's silly.
Scott: It does everything you need to do right out of the box.
Rym: Well, it didn't do the Strava thing.
Rym: I had to pay a dollar for that.
Scott: I paid a dollar for a watch face.
Scott: Yeah
Rym: But it was the fact that the ecosystem was Pretty much immediately stagnant was a minor warning sign Because that is the exact same thing that happened when the palm when I had the palm pre and that palm OS like there was bunch like it had the same number of apps as like Android and iPhones pretty much like early on and Then like no one ever wrote anymore and then the platform got discontinued like months later.
Rym: So, I don't know what smartwatch I'll get when this thing finally dies because I really like this thing.
Rym: But the story behind why pebble went down is actually kind of interesting.
Rym: because think about this They had a very popular hardware product that works and a very and they were actually able to manufacture it and sell it To lots and lots of people.
Rym: Yeah, cuz I kick-started hardware before.
Rym: millions of people have pebble watches most Kick-started like design projects like hardware Kind of garbage.
Rym: Yeah, and yet the pebble watch is like super well engineered like the things pretty much invincibles waterproof Like it was great.
Rym: Hmm.
Rym: And yeah, they went out of business and did not have a viable business.
Scott: Nope, and it seems like they actually sold the watch for not enough money for it.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: They also probably Didn't like.
Rym: the ecosystem was weird because there's this like upper-end ecosystem of people who thought they wanted like I watches.
Rym: But that market seems to have dried up too.
Rym: Once people realize watches don't do the magic things They expected them to do.
Scott: I think the problem with the watches is simply that You know, you look at something like iPhone has this upgrade cycle, right?
Scott: So it's like you buy iPhone and then two years later you buy iPhone.
Scott: years later you buy iPhone you buy a watch.
Scott: That's your watch forever.
Scott: Congratulations, you're not buying another one.
Scott: So it's like you make pebbles and everyone buys one and wants one and then you're done.
Scott: Well, thus when I kick started Apple watch and everyone buys one who wants one and then you're done.
Scott: You don't make.
Scott: you can't keep making money by making more.
Scott: It's like you keep making more of them.
Scott: I mean You can't get new people to buy them because everyone who wants one already has one and if you make a new one People are way pissed because they expect to watch to last like their whole lives not a year.
Rym: I don't think the smartwatch industry as a whole is really Thought all of that.
Rym: through just that you see the whole market like really cooling off rapidly Which is a shame because having a screen that shows you notifications on your wrist is a super big killer app.
Scott: It's pretty good.
Scott: You don't take your phone in your pocket.
Scott: Yeah
Rym: but the articles that are coming out about what happened to pebble because they're about my Fitbit who make devices that I See very little value in even
Scott: as well you whatsoever
Rym: even despite being An athlete who doesn't spends a lot of time running and tracking stats and all these things.
Rym: My smartwatch and smartphone by themselves already do all that stuff really well.
Rym: Fitbit would just be like one more device to buy.
Rym: that doesn't give me a lot of value add.
Scott: It's like part of a pebble.
Rym: Yeah, so Fitbit didn't buy the pebble company as best I can tell.
Rym: pebble basically is gone.
Rym: Yeah, they bought the pebble staff and not all the staff just like 40% of the staff Apparently the old one.
Rym: they only got the software and like app ecosystem people and they ignored all the hardware and UX people.
Scott: They have their own hardware UX people.
Rym: They don't need the pebble people Even though I actually think that the hardware and UX was the only unique and good aspect of pebble.
Scott: Sure like if it's not bad Yeah.
Rym: but I feel like Fitbit by my guess just my gut because when this sort of acquisition happens people really only buy a Receivership or they're like buying it because it's they're like they can buy it for nothing just for the hell of it to get the IP.
Rym: You buy it for the customers Which they're definitely not doing because they basically already pissed off all the pebble customers by shutting it all down Like that like people who like pebbles hate Fitbit.
Rym: now Or three.
Rym: you buy them because it's really hard to hire good tech people.
Rym: It's way easier to just buy out a company that has a bunch of people and now you've got those and if you see anyone Then, you know after you hire all these people you see anyone unproductive you can fire them later.
Rym: But especially if you knew how much recruiters get like say like in IT a recruiter picks you up and yeah Let's say recruiter calls me and I actually go to apply for the job and get the job.
Scott: that recruiter will get Thousands and thousands of dollars.
Rym: I've seen as high as like 50% of my annual salary.
Scott: I haven't seen that much but I've seen a large percentages.
Scott: But anyway, like 10% so 20% I've seen way higher.
Scott: the point is the point is that is thousands of dollars, right?
Scott: So you're if you're a recruiter if you get like two people hired like you're you're set for quite a while.
Scott: So imagine, you know pebble had like what you're getting tens of employees all at once and they paid you know Like 40 million for the company.
Rym: It's like you already know their value because they contributed to a Extremely viable platform.
Scott: It's like whoa that was that was totally saved us all this money on like and time not having to like get recruiters and read resumes and All this kind of nonsense.
Scott: It's like oh, we just hired a whole bunch of developers real cheap.
Rym: So, I don't know what the future is gonna be for this stuff.
Scott: now I think what's gonna happen is like, you know, people are amazing miss reading and misunderstanding where they're like We don't you know that when in the writing they're like a pebble may see degraded You know like use in the future like it may degrade service may degrade.
Scott: It's like yeah, that means that what's gonna happen is Android's gonna update iPhones gonna update and that Apple break.
Scott: They're not gonna update the pebble software ever again.
Scott: So your pebble watch might keep working But it might stop working because you're never getting another update ever.
Rym: Yep You might be able to do what I did with Google Glass where you can connect like if you connect to somebody.
Scott: I still won't work as well as it does like right now Won't work anymore.
Scott: right now is as good as ever gonna work and it's only gonna work less as time goes on.
Scott: Yeah, so I'm actually see.
Scott: what I was hoping was that you know because with Apple whenever they do the second version of something That's always the best version right?
Scott: It's like they had that.
Scott: What's a good?
Scott: like the iPhone the original iPhone not so good.
Scott: the iPhone 3g so good Right, like the Apple the first Apple no good Apple - so good.
Rym: The iWatch and iWatch - Not that special have some problems, right?
Scott: I watch was kind of big and fat and with battery life problems and whatever.
Scott: and the Apple watch - is I guess the new Apple Watch is just a slight update.
Scott: It's it's still fat.
Scott: It's still the same shape.
Scott: Mostly.
Rym: It's you know I think the real problem is we're not.
Scott: it said it solves some of the problems, but it's still a significant problems And I'm like, wow, that's not really fixing it.
Rym: if they other than for fashion There's almost no way to have a premium sale of a smartwatch Because for the all the use cases that require like complex design or difficult hardware Are things that a tiny minority of people care about.
Rym: I would like to have NFC support in it directly so I can not have to pull my phone out to do like Android pay and Apple pay and all that.
Rym: I guess the iWatch might do that I watch.
Scott: does I wish does that will pay?
Rym: yeah, this this pebble does not do.
Rym: that I don't know if any Android where does Android pay?
Scott: Mmm, but anyways, yeah.
Scott: So I mean if Apple were to make now because by pebbles dying I guess slowly if Apple were to make an Apple watch that was significantly better and thinner and whatever I'd probably get one.
Scott: But then unlike my iPhone that I replace every two years and they think of it like a computer that I carry around Yeah, I would never replace that Apple watch ever.
Scott: and if they made it stop working or stop supporting it I would be pissed and I would just stop wearing watches I like fuck.
Rym: this thing is.
Rym: I know I am so used to having that second screen.
Rym: I would go back to wearing my Google Glass if I didn't have a good smartwatch but actually Google Glass still works fine if you use it directly with Android wear.
Scott: one good thing though Is that Apple tends to actually be good about allowing old devices to keep working like when they put out a new version of iOS.
Scott: It works with surprisingly old iPhones and works well, right?
Scott: It's like, oh, okay.
Scott: Wow, I didn't realize that old an iPhone.
Scott: Yeah, it's still run the newest iOS and run all the newest apps.
Scott: That's pretty nice.
Scott: You didn't have to do that considering how much you're trying to get people to upgrade.
Scott: So I assume that even if you buy the old the original Apple watch today That it will serve you well for at least five years.
Rym: It's also so the article will link to is.
Rym: you can look at it.
Scott: I'll serve you as well as it can.
Rym: sort of goes through some of the details of what happened to pebble and We could talk about that, but that's more of a Thursday topic.
Scott: Silicon Valley bullshit.
Scott: yeah, because
Rym: that is that is the typical story of When and how these kinds of companies can't raise money and what kinds of people are the CEOs of these kinds of companies
Scott: heads
Rym: Or at least people well
Scott: People who do not share our values for whom
Rym: their professional life is the is the height of their ambition.
Rym: Who have trouble?
Rym: Existing in a world where they do not have to do that job.
Rym: Yeah the person with career goals Yeah, my career goal is to retire to the beach.
Scott: Yeah, my boss My boss is like trying to you know, do more I guess bossy stuff, I guess.
Scott: Ah So he's like.
Scott: he's like, alright, we're gonna have a little meetings with everyone and answer these questions.
Scott: So he's like here Let's try to.
Scott: he's like, alright, what are your goals?
Scott: And I'm like, do you mean outside of work?
Scott: He's like no at work and I'm like not be fired Keep my job.
Scott: I'm like, what do you want me to say?
Scott: take your job?
Scott: I don't want that.
Rym: Yep, not poop myself.
Scott: He the CEO don't want that don't?
Rym: we're sold your eye.
Scott: It's like it's like what's my career goal?
Scott: Nothing Not have to work less work less not get fired.
Rym: I mean any career goal I could give anyone get the most money for the least effort Boils down to.
Rym: I either want a job that's super fun and amazing or I want to not ever have to work again.
Scott: Yeah, what's my job?
Scott: rollercoaster rider?
Scott: Yes.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Now we're talking.
Scott: now we're talking.
Scott: I got career goals.
Scott: now Survive ten rides and without stopping.
Scott: so tomorrow my goal be twelve.
Rym: I got a little side news.
Rym: It's kind of fun.
Rym: This is a ransomware and it's amazing.
Rym: This is something I never even thought of.
Rym: I'm super proud of the whatever shithead made this malware.
Rym: It's a typical, you know crypto locker.
Scott: We're in your entire hard drive.
Scott: If you don't give us bitcoins, we gonna delete your data Yeah, or we just will never give you the key.
Scott: So your data will just be encrypted forever.
Rym: There are with this one Once it gets your data There are two ways to get your data back.
Scott: is it is one of them?
Scott: still give them bitcoins.
Rym: So with the it actually gives you two options one Restoring your files the fast easy way to get your files fast.
Rym: Please transfer one Bitcoin to this address.
Scott: How much is one Bitcoin these days?
Rym: Off hand, I don't know but I'm gonna guess 280 bucks.
Scott: That's a lot of fucking money.
Rym: one Bitcoin.
Scott: Oh 778 that's a lot.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I am so well bitcoins way up since the election.
Rym: actually Yeah, okay people are using it to launder money Because no one's gonna stop you?
Rym: Yeah, it was.
Rym: it was okay.
Rym: Yeah, it's.
Rym: it's gone up dramatically since the election.
Rym: That's interesting.
Scott: Is this safer than US dollars?
Rym: Oh, I don't know.
Rym: I guess you use it to transfer money.
Rym: But anyway.
Rym: so yeah pay the money.
Rym: typical or Restoring your files the nasty way.
Rym: Send the link below to other people.
Rym: if two or more people Install this malware and pay the ransom.
Rym: We will decrypt your files for free.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So basically give us 700 bucks or fuck two of your friends.
Scott: Yeah Anyone who sends this out?
Scott: I Kill you and I don't feel bad about no jury would convict.
Scott: No, they would be nullification all the way.
Rym: You know people talk about monetization.
Rym: This is a brilliant monetization model.
Rym: I Am proud of you, even though I would probably punch you in the face if I met you in person.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: But anyway things of the day.
Rym: so funnily enough Scott was telling me he had a thing of the day and I had my thing of the day and He was looking for the video of his thing of the day.
Rym: I went and clicked on the video of my thing of the day and The first recommended video for my thing of the day was Scott's thing of the day, I guess they're somewhat related.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, my video my thing of the day somehow has like a million views already.
Scott: So I guess it you might have you might have seen it already.
Scott: It's pretty good.
Scott: Yeah, it's good It's great.
Rym: so we can do yours first.
Scott: Okay, so imagine you're in like a mine or you like the kind where you dig stuff up right or Some other very large construction project like the big-time ones like the biggest big-time and you got some big-time equipment Like Tonka truck equipment Tonka
Rym: trucks
Scott: big time like, you know where the tire is bigger than you that kind.
Scott: It's so enormous, right?
Scott: Whatever this vehicle is.
Scott: Yeah Now imagine that tire on that enormous vehicle Goes flat because you ran over some giant nail.
Scott: cuz you're on a giant construction project.
Scott: You think I was gonna tire like that.
Scott: go flat.
Scott: Yeah, it's like forward six eight inches thick.
Scott: But yeah, no, you can run over something like, you know, a giant rock or something really nasty a night with a lance.
Scott: Yeah, anything can happen.
Scott: So they do go flat.
Scott: It's still made of rubber.
Scott: No matter how thick it is.
Scott: It's not invincible.
Scott: So what the hell do you do?
Scott: It's like well you think oh you just you know Throw the tire out and put on a flat tire spare tire and open on a flat tire.
Scott: You can put in a spare tire just like you would with your car.
Scott: And the answer is are you insane?
Scott: because on your car like car tires for your a normal car are not cheap.
Scott: But you know, they're cheap enough.
Scott: We're like you couldn't get and just buy a new one right if you have to.
Scott: it's sort of the cost of owning a car.
Scott: Right, if you can afford to own a car you can afford to buy a tire once in a while, right?
Scott: A tire for one of these vehicles is like $30,000.
Scott: It's like two daddy two cars that to get one tire for the construction vehicle.
Rym: that is about double The value of any car I have ever owned in my life.
Scott: That's not just that's not even counting the wheel That's just the tire rubber part.
Scott: So if one goes flat I'm sure at a big enough construction site you're prepared and you can.
Scott: you have a spare or you can get a spare from somewhere You know.
Scott: so you can keep working without you know having to delay your whole construction project because of one tire.
Scott: but you aren't throwing that shit out.
Scott: you're fixing that fucking tire right, but how do you fix a ginormous piece of rubber that is taller than a human being and Make it like sturdy enough that like someone can actually put an enormous Vehicles weight on that tire and drive around safely?
Scott: in this video He shows you the entire process of repairing the tire on an from an enormous construction vehicle And it is quite fascinating actually looks kind of fun except for the part where it looks like they're breathing in little bits of rubber Which I don't want to
Rym: do.
Scott: yeah All the rest of its looks real fun and way awesome and sort of like sculpting and artwork.
Scott: in a way, it's real good.
Rym: So what I got for you is The wobble dado blade the what the fuck what all right, so you know what a blade is like a knife.
Rym: Yeah, so imagine like a blade on a circular saw.
Rym: okay, all right, so do you know what a dado is?
Scott: an artist from you know like the.
Rym: so Like my grandpa was a cabinet maker so I learned a lot of carpentry and stuff as a kid.
Rym: But dados are when.
Rym: so you know what like say you've got like a piece of wood And you want to cut a groove in it to slide another piece of wood in like for a shelf or something.
Rym: That trench that you cut is called a dado Mm-hmm the kind that's like a trapezoid kind of shape or or yeah like it like there We've got a picture of on like that.
Rym: just cut a trench.
Rym: There's some wood.
Rym: Yeah, how do you think you make those in a piece of wood?
Scott: So if I remember my memory is not good I remember Norm Abrams the new Yankee workshop used to watch on PBS.
Scott: Yeah, the new Yankee workshop He would make shaker furniture, and I'm pretty sure what he would do is that there are two things I remember him doing right.
Scott: he always used like his router around the edge or Norm Abram and his dados, okay?
Rym: Oh, man, I just oh crap look at this.
Scott: Yes anyway.
Rym: This whole article is about Norm Making dados right.
Scott: so if I remember what he would do is he would had the table saw and he'd put something in the Table saw and just set it low.
Scott: and then when he put the wood over the table saw it wouldn't cut all the way through The wood it would just cut you know a groove in the wood without cutting out.
Scott: So you wouldn't split the wood in half.
Scott: you're getting real close.
Scott: It's got this groove in it what?
Rym: so if a dados say like an inch thick Mmm.
Rym: What are you gonna put there?
Rym: There's no such thing as an inch thick blade.
Rym: it can't be sure.
Rym: no you can.
Scott: when you have a table saw you can raise And lower the blades all right Is barely sticking out of the table.
Rym: no no I'm talking about Depth.
Rym: though the width of your blade the how wide is the blade you just get a thick ass one a thick blade.
Rym: What's that look like?
Rym: what are the teeth look like on a blade?
Scott: That's an inch thick the same as on a regular blade.
Scott: Just thick like that would chip the wood me.
Scott: I don't know I would.
Rym: so You can do this with routers, but that's really yeah.
Scott: I think I've seen him do it with a router a few times where instead of putting the router around the edge of the wood To make a nice shape you just
Rym: kind of you just
Scott: drive the writer the router right down the middle of the wood in a Straight line and you know just make it with put the right bit on there.
Scott: So it just that's tough to do.
Rym: in my experience people you use a router if you're doing like fancy work like kind of scroll Work or something, but I remember.
Scott: all I remember is he used the router all the fucking time.
Scott: That's like his favorite thing.
Rym: so there's a thing called a dado blade And it's basically you stack all these blades that have like these blunt gears together And you make a stack until it's as wide as the dado you want to cut.
Scott: and oh so only one blade hits at a time.
Scott: Yeah, but the blades are.
Scott: it's spinning fast and the blades are.
Scott: you know it ends up being wide enough?
Scott: So you're hitting all the.
Scott: I can already imagine exactly what that looks.
Rym: so dado blades are pretty expensive.
Scott: And yeah, I mean it's X times the cost of one blade.
Scott: or you're buying multiple blades.
Rym: they might be illegal in the EU as well.
Scott: Interesting don't make.
Scott: for.
Rym: oh yeah, I type dado blade Europe and the first result is illegal, okay Why is it illegal?
Rym: because they're dangerous?
Scott: Why is it dangerous?
Scott: more dangerous than just a single table saw blade so?
Rym: The reasons for that are kind of complicated, but basically It looks like in Europe It's illegal for because the way they the way they get prevent you from using them.
Rym: The thing you mount your blades on in a table saw in Europe is so narrow that you could never put dados on there Mm-hmm.
Scott: so if I tried to import a US table saw to Europe they'd be like no No, I find all that's what customs would see.
Scott: they'd be like Ah you know you get to customs and like table saws a and they go to their customs guide And it's got this list of things to check on a table.
Rym: so all these forms.
Rym: I'm finding our woodworkers who are like Really in the US like everyone dados everywhere ever a dado blade dado blade dado heaven.
Scott: yeah Yeah, we also got cameras that can record for more than 30 minutes.
Scott: Yeah, take that Europe.
Rym: We'll see how well we do in the near future, but they actually do also.
Scott: They just have to pay video recording tax on those cameras.
Rym: There is another way to cut a dado.
Rym: They.
Rym: apparently no one makes these blades anymore, but people find him like garage sales, okay I did not know this was the thing all right.
Rym: This is a blade That is a normal blade.
Rym: like.
Rym: it looks like normal table saw blade.
Rym: Is it like an angle at an angle so it wobbles?
Scott: Oh wobbling?
Scott: Oh, I thought it would just be like at a slant so as no fun It would be you know sort of going back and forth.
Scott: It's what not Physically wobbling at the axis that danger physically wobbles at the axis.
Scott: Oh, that's dangerous.
Rym: That's way safer than a dado stack as far as I can tell.
Scott: I thought it would just sort of be like this way So that as it spins.
Rym: It's you know it's got this whole mechanism inside to control the angle.
Rym: These are actually pretty sophisticated.
Scott: That's fancy.
Rym: Yeah, so I stumble out of this video.
Rym: I'm not really sure how and it was just really interesting.
Rym: and If you follow the recommended videos from this you think we talk our nerd crap about like what video card to buy.
Rym: Watch some woodworkers talking their nerd crap about what data blade to buy.
Scott: I wonder what.
Scott: cuz you know there's that stuff that other people are into the the Japanese woodworking where you don't use glue or nails you just Japanese joy.
Scott: There's a joinery.
Scott: Yeah, the joinery.
Scott: We're like you enter everything interlock.
Rym: Oh, soo.
Scott: Yeah, I forget what the word is, but it's like.
Scott: There's like a Twitter account.
Scott: I think that posts gifts of.
Scott: you know the interlocking Joinery, thank you Wikipedia.
Rym: You are very helpful.
Scott: Japanese carpentry is carpentry in Japan period yeah, but anyway I wonder how like these dados and stuff a lot.
Scott: I wonder how they did it by hand all those days.
Rym: Oh you want to know by hand.
Rym: I got videos of doing that by hand.
Rym: guess what it's a pain in the ass.
Rym: It takes forever.
Rym: You look you basically sit there with like these implements.
Scott: Just hitting and shaving with just like a chisel or whatever.
Rym: It is awful, okay.
Rym: In the moment the booklet book is Rebecca To start reading it yeah again, yeah, okay, I want you to think you've been done with it Weeks all right, I'll start reading it in earnest today cuz I just days days weeks It depends.
Rym: I finished Black Mirror on Netflix on my phone, so now I'm gonna read Rebecca as fast as possible.
Rym: Otherwise we're gonna be magfest Between Scott's on two panels.
Rym: I am on six panels and joy, and we're always gonna be a peck Or more hours of games than you.
Rym: one of those panels is anime openers from around the world.
Scott: It's a whole game of Eclipse.
Scott: you ain't playing?
Rym: yeah I don't think any of my panels start at midnight, so I think my clips game will be fine.
Scott: You're gonna miss daytime.
Rym: We're playing.
Rym: we got to play some battle tech.
Scott: You know you want to play battle.
Scott: take it mag fest.
Scott: I think we can do that.
Rym: We can get the band together and make this happen.
Scott: I can bring battle tech stuffs to mag fest.
Rym: I wonder if I guess I could run mech maker in an emulator.
Scott: We could just make mechs at home bring them.
Rym: Yeah, we don't know we're making the max ahead of time.
Rym: That is not.
Rym: we're not gonna make max.
Scott: They're gonna begin to get a printer at mag fest.
Scott: good luck.
Scott: Yeah, I guess I use my tablet.
Scott: I wonder if there's a Mac app.
Scott: I can get my.
Rym: I wonder how well supported modern battle tech is.
Scott: it's very well supported.
Scott: We go to packs.
Scott: we could buy it from.
Scott: the people are always there.
Scott: so yeah, but in terms of Technological support you want to upgrade our battle tech to the new.
Scott: you know the new updated rules.
Rym: It depends is the targeting computer is still cheap.
Scott: I'm pretty.
Rym: No one's allowed to have a targeting But my old neck is based on having nothing but rail guns in a targeting computer and armor only in the front.
Rym: Yeah, backed up against a wall with a tripod and no piloting skill and no jump jets.
Rym: But yeah, we'll be a PAX South doing at least one panel a bunch of stuffs coming up and Stay tuned as GeekNights will continue its regular schedule even through the holidays, so we've done the show before.
Scott: Yeah, so usually when we come up with a show idea for Monday then the number one reason We don't do it is we've done this before.
Rym: it's not even Simpsons.
Rym: Did it.
Rym: It's ribbon Scott.
Scott: You literally did this one in 2006 though in the first year of GeekNights about a decade ago a decade ago And usually I'd be like well.
Scott: Nope.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: We can't do the show again.
Scott: But so much has changed in ten years that we can safely do this show again.
Rym: in fact it's things that it's kind of like with monitors.
Rym: how like monitors and displays for computers were actually very high resolution until Relatively recently in the history when 1080p Became some sort of like.
Scott: oh I get an HD now.
Scott: We're 4k.
Scott: We're good.
Scott: We're high-resolution again.
Rym: Yeah but for a long time that basically monitor technology went from an elegant weapon from a more civilized age to this sort of dark era of.
Rym: Really, you're giving me 1080 pixels vertically.
Rym: that's worse than the CRT I had in high school.
Rym: Yep But I am instant messaging Kind of had a similar problem like the war the landscape of.
Rym: I am today in the era of modern smartphones and like way advanced web technology.
Rym: I mean 2006 was web 2.0 stuff going on I don't know like early days of like pre-modern internet stuff Mmm, and I am was in a lot of ways better back then than it is now mm-hmm.
Scott: so back Then we were talking about you know aim ICQ and mostly XMPP.
Scott: right and at the time XMPP jabber was this interoperable thing.
Scott: you could use Google Hangout Or you could use your own jabber server, and it's like all these things could talk to each other.
Scott: Yeah, and that was a feature that we actually used and was actually great That you could just sort of chat between these different chat systems.
Scott: They all work together and because they used XMPP you could get any client you wanted.
Scott: so you could use like you know Just any.
Scott: you could just pigeon I think that's what we were using bad vision at home, and there's pigeons trillium adium all these you know programs And you could use whichever one you wanted.
Scott: that was best for you, and they would all you could work with whatever aim.
Scott: You know instant messaging Protocol.
Scott: you wanted to use multiples together.
Scott: Yeah, and you know it was a little bit Cumbersome to you know.
Scott: sort all that out, but but it was like email.
Rym: Anyone could message anyone.
Scott: yeah the end result was actually pretty great.
Scott: anyone could message almost anybody and You could send you could.
Scott: there's even times you could send files to people directly over these networks.
Scott: And you know there are all sorts of features, and it was really kind of nice.
Rym: yep, and what's really interesting And we're not.
Rym: it was not a thing that we complained about really where we were mostly just Wondering about the future and like adding functionality and making it easier and encryption and all that kind of like file sending stopped working because of routers and things.
Scott: right you know.
Rym: and yet somehow and you know the year 2016 things like what's app exists and What's that basically has a limited subset of what I see Q provided in?
Scott: 1996 right.
Scott: so on the one hand things have gotten a little bit better in some areas.
Scott: right user interface is much better.
Scott: Right support for Unicode and things like that.
Scott: much better emojis and stickers and those sorts of fun things.
Scott: Those are those aren't night.
Scott: They're nice.
Scott: I like to use them sometimes, right You know.
Scott: so those are in mobile support.
Scott: obviously having mobile apps that are kind of slick is really nice because they can.
Rym: 1996 there was.
Rym: smartphones didn't exist.
Rym: cell phones were barely available.
Scott: the other thing that we have that we also had back then but is now easier.
Scott: as long as you choose the right app is Encryption.
Scott: that we didn't have.
Scott: you know.
Scott: end-to-end encryption it depending on what you choose If you signal or what's app you get the end-to-end encryption gonna.
Rym: it had encryption to a degree.
Rym: But also, I'm not necessarily trusting of the actually.
Scott: yeah I'm not I'm not sure quite yet sure which ones that claim to be end-to-end encrypted are actually really truly encrypted.
Rym: so for Lee in 1996 when I wanted to send encrypted I am's I use the PGP clipboard crypto to do it by hand.
Scott: yeah But it worked.
Scott: there's no way ends are gonna get through that.
Rym: Yeah, that shit was secure.
Scott: I was guaranteed secure.
Scott: cuz you do you can still do that today.
Scott: You could encrypt something by hand copy and paste it into Google Hangout and as long as no one's messed your computer up Yep, no one in between is getting the MTM to M MIM.
Rym: but the the biggest problem today is that there's been this huge fracturing of IM services and They've taken away Interoperability.
Scott: Google Hangout got rid of XM PPS only works with itself And then all these walled garden apps for communicating with people appeared.
Rym: What's app is just the most egregious way?
Scott: Google made like aloe and they made this other one.
Scott: That's like four groups spaces.
Scott: It's like four groups only.
Scott: It's like I guess supposed to do a beluga.
Scott: did you got Facebook Messenger, which is really the worst one?
Rym: Yep, beluga was gonna see.
Rym: there were all these.
Rym: like there was this explosion of good ideas like beluga.
Scott: Well, yes, we can use Google Spaces instead of beluga, but you can also just make a Google Hangout with multiple people in it.
Scott: Yeah, why do you need Google Spaces?
Rym: So I guess what happened was Google for a long time since 2006 like the Hangouts platform emerged as even though it was no longer interoperable It was the most reliable had the best feature set the best UX.
Rym: every feature of this thing was great.
Rym: So, of course, they're basically trying to kill it and replace it with aloe which kind of sucks.
Scott: Yeah, I don't aloe.
Scott: the problem aloe is no desktop client, right?
Scott: That's.
Scott: the other thing is that these, you know, the I am apps.
Scott: they worked on every device.
Scott: You could be the same identity and chat with the same people no matter where you are.
Scott: Now you got people using like iMessage and iMessage is actually really great feature wise.
Rym: Yeah, the problem is better than Google Hangouts in a lot of ways.
Scott: Oh, yeah But the problem with iMessage is that a you can only use it on a desktop.
Scott: if you got a Mac with iChat you can't use iMessage on a Windows desktop or Linux desktop and If your friend doesn't have an iPhone, they're not iMessaging.
Rym: So if you got Android friends get rekt, but my Android friends most of them have a gmail address.
Rym: Thank God at least so everyone.
Scott: Yeah everyone.
Scott: I know who I want to chat with uses Gmail.
Rym: Ah, you know who doesn't chase.
Scott: even if I said I chase I hang on him.
Rym: Yeah, even though I hang out him when I was out he hang us me too.
Rym: Yeah, if I I am him he will.
Rym: I am me back but his default way to communicate with me is they always sends me a Text.
Scott: Yeah, he does.
Scott: He does default to SMS, but he will use hang out And I think that's because his wider social circle is all SMS base.
Rym: Yeah, they pretty much only use SMS.
Scott: The people are using SMS which sucks by the way, but they're using it because 100% interoperable with everyone.
Rym: everyone has a phone except if I'm at home.
Rym: and I'm not using my phone because I'm home You can't SMS me.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Your SMS will only show up on your phone and not on your computer or anywhere I got around that is I use Google Voice.
Rym: So actually I do get like you can.
Rym: if you call my phone number It'll actually ring my computer if I'm home and you know what?
Rym: That's amazing.
Rym: Yeah It's like we advance to this point to where your identity and communication capabilities follow you to whatever device you're at.
Rym: And then we said fuck that and we're going back to these walled gardens and these phone only systems.
Scott: Yeah, I mean it people are not as upset with it as we are because they're phone only people.
Rym: Yeah right and I spend even eight hours a day sitting at work in front of a computer and you know what I do at home for at These four hours it in front of a computer.
Scott: But even if you have phone and tablet, let's say right or phone and Mac, you know If you're Apple person all this stuff works together.
Scott: If you call me on my phone and my iPad has Wi-Fi or it's near my phone My iPad starts ringing even though it's Wi-Fi only.
Scott: Yeah, it knows.
Scott: it knows it's like, you know.
Scott: So a lot of people are set up in this sort of integrated way.
Scott: We're like their shit works and they don't realize like, you know, they're not using a desktop computer So much, they don't have a real computer connected to their TV They have.
Scott: so they're doing it in such a way there.
Scott: for like normal people things are just fine But they're ruining it for advanced people.
Rym: So another example I've seen is that I know some people who will not be named on this episode.
Scott: who?
Rym: They have gmail accounts But they don't like pay attention to it or have like the messaging like notifications set up because they primarily use Facebook Messenger or something.
Scott: Yeah No bueno.
Rym: Yeah Beluga was great because in the old days you would use that at an event like a convention like we need an I am Group just for this convention.
Scott: You can do that today with Google Spaces.
Scott: But like I said, Google Hangout lets you make a hangout with multiple people and it's basically perfect Yeah, and it works on your phone and your computer.
Scott: But Google seems to be not.
Scott: first they got rid of the XM PP part and now they seem to be slowly killing it in Which is weird because they made aloe.
Rym: Why?
Rym: basically the same but only on phones but slightly different user interface like the ux.
Rym: The ux is a little better, but it doesn't have any like additional capabilities.
Scott: It's just separate for no reason.
Rym: It's more like it's aimed around Communicating with your friends, right?
Scott: I don't understand how you lot like if you launch a new network and it's how do you get people if everyone's already has a Hey friend, oh, yeah, there are holy shit Scott.
Rym: So people I interact with a lot of people in like the finance world and people who are our age are reasonably educated Don't they use SMS if they don't use anything else?
Rym: So they primarily so normal people like that Seem to just not know about this stuff like they don't really understand the difference between hangouts and SMS and all these things.
Scott: But I mean they're just using SMS.
Scott: So why?
Scott: how could you sell them on switching from that to?
Rym: So some of these people came to me when what's that was first announced and they were like, holy shit Check this out.
Rym: If you install this app and I'm like what app he's like, yeah, what's that?
Rym: And I did.
Rym: I've grown at him and then he was like it totally lets you chat with people on your phone Uh-huh.
Scott: They mean the thing we did.
Scott: since they don't know like they don't do that Do they not have people they chat with they don't.
Rym: they like SMS people like an.
Scott: I am client Marketed so why does that make?
Scott: why are they happy to use whatsapp as opposed to they didn't conceive I am before that.
Scott: Okay They didn't use I am but how if you're already if everyone you know is already SMSing right and some of those people all have iPhones and are therefore using iMessage in the same exact app?
Scott: that does SMS, right?
Scott: Why would you then that's doing what you need to do?
Scott: Why would you switch to alo or whatsapp or whatever?
Rym: So I feel like the people who switched to watch that.
Scott: and how do you convince I all of your friends to switch?
Rym: they switched From nothing or from just SMS, which was actually pretty unreliable, especially if it's international.
Scott: I've never under national.
Scott: Yeah as a problem Yeah.
Rym: So I feel I feel like a lot of the people are using things like whatsapp Basically didn't use anything before that like they might individually send an SMS occasionally, but they never chatted via SMS.
Scott: I feel like a lot of people.
Rym: it's like this messengers like built into everything Like you can eat like everything has messaging built in like yeah, like you can send me these blizzard messages I'm like, what the fuck is there any I wish I could turn it off.
Scott: You can use steam you can use reddit You can use What else.
Scott: can you draw Twitter on direct messages Skype you can use sky.
Rym: There are people I know who have gmails who use hangouts who send me Twitter DMS.
Rym: It's like.
Rym: you have my email you have my phone number you know where I live you have every means in the world to communicate With me and yet you send me a fucking Twitter DM.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: It's like everything that takes like 10 minutes to arrive.
Scott: Why does everything have messaging built in?
Scott: it's like, you know a Twitter DM makes sense for Someone in the public who's like a Twitter follower to message me?
Rym: Yeah, but it doesn't make sense for anyone right or like blizzard like inside of the battle net stuff.
Rym: It makes sense like the steam messaging because the messages exist for one purpose to try to invite someone into a game that you're playing Right now.
Rym: Mmm, but people just like I am me via it.
Rym: people We know have just tried to chat with me and had conversations with me in steam Instead of a hangout Mmm, and it's super weird.
Rym: Like I got home from work one day There's a couple months ago and there's all these messages from someone we know just in steam on my desktop Mmm, so of course, I guess think about the old days.
Rym: there was you know ICQ and there's I and there was aim and there was MSN.
Rym: if you were dumb or lived in one of the countries that was popular and then everyone got on right here and Everyone like.
Rym: there was the battle of half of us used ICQ and half is used aim.
Rym: Half of you were about to get fucked and gonna have to switch and that's what we did.
Rym: I switched from the far superior ICQ to the far inferior aim because that is what my new social circle use.
Scott: just fine aim.
Rym: It was just way.
Scott: that also supported XM PP.
Scott: Yeah, it was totally nice.
Rym: In fact, I remember I had a client client.
Rym: I used my.
Rym: I had my aim ID and my ICQ ID both working in Trillium.
Scott: I used pigeon.
Scott: Well at the time it wasn't known as pigeon.
Scott: It was known as GM yep.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I used to use the game pretty extensively.
Rym: Those are dark days.
Scott: thinking back became pigeon.
Rym: Anyway, the big difference is ICQ at offline messaging.
Scott: But yeah, instant messaging is fucked up these days.
Scott: It's all these separate, you know, totally walled off things and everyone's using like ten of them at once.
Rym: So I literally have to think whenever I want to met whenever I want to communicate with a human who is not like super savvy Well, sometimes there's a contextual reason to use a specific thing, right.
Rym: so like inside of a map, right?
Scott: Like if I'm gonna talk to someone cuz I'm gonna play a game with them right now We'll use the steam chat because we both have steam open and it's convenient.
Rym: But at the same time if if I want to play a mess like I want to play overwatch with someone I can't use blizzard first unless they're already logged in and playing overwatch.
Rym: if I want to say hey Scott You want to play overwatch?
Rym: I'm gonna.
Rym: I am them on something else because I don't look at the blizzard thing unless I'm actively playing the game.
Scott: It's for the people you're already playing a game with.
Rym: so you still need to use a different service.
Rym: with Like it old walkie-talkies you make the bleeper tone to tell people.
Rym: Hey, I'm about to message you, right?
Scott: So another example is like sometimes I have slack.
Scott: everyone uses slack.
Scott: Yeah, but slack is for like a group a permanent group kind of thing, right?
Scott: But it can also be used for a private thing if say someone in that group wants to contact you specifically but you're not super close with them, right?
Scott: so there's like a netrunner slack and It's for the whole netrunner world.
Scott: But we made a channel NYC on there for only netrunner and NYC people and there's people in there.
Scott: You can't hang out me really.
Scott: I guess I could if they wanted to that's fine.
Scott: But they don't.
Scott: but if they want to message me then they send me a direct message on that particular slack And it's like okay, I guess that works, right?
Scott: But this is yet another like.
Scott: how many different ways are there to contact me?
Scott: Why do we need so many?
Scott: It makes sense sometimes but really I wish there was just one and I could funnel everything together.
Rym: Yep, there was that like.
Rym: remember when Twitter was and it's everyone used xmpp.
Scott: we could write I could get a message from someone at steam and then I would get another message from someone at Netrunner dot slack comm and I get a message from my work at Broadway.
Scott: does like calm.
Scott: I get a message from Rym Just Rym at front recruit calm just like email.
Scott: Xmpp works is everyone could use all these networks and we could tie them all together.
Scott: and you could you know I'd have one app on my phone and every message for every different service would go into the one app all in one place.
Rym: Now the way that world did not happen Even though it should have another way around that would be to have clients that can connect to all the networks and aggregate for You.
Rym: but now because of smartphones that's infinitely more complicated.
Scott: all the networks also are like proprietary protocols.
Rym: Your own client for aloe I dare you.
Scott: yeah Can you make an app that like does steam chat like but also think of this the app?
Rym: Would now have to sync itself because you have all these different devices that are all connecting to all these things.
Scott: That's why you need your.
Scott: we had our own jabber server that did all the xmpp in for us Yeah And then would you just?
Scott: we connected to the one server ourselves and that server had bridges to all the other.
Scott: I have networks Right and work that way.
Rym: now remember Twitter was the same way.
Rym: in the early days of Twitter There was that Laconica thing that we used.
Rym: that was like federated.
Scott: That was run your own Twitter, right?
Scott: Yeah Yeah, that was we should do.
Scott: that should have been the way it went but they had that software failed.
Rym: So well, you know what?
Rym: I think it is written.
Rym: all the software All these networks are funded by companies that have to monetize or companies.
Scott: How does having a messenger network help you monetize?
Scott: I don't understand.
Rym: or why even make one or Companies that have a vested interest in getting you into the ecosystem of their shit and keeping you there, right?
Scott: I assume there must be some groups of people out there Right who like steam chat is their chat like their group of teenagers who play steam games.
Scott: That's their thing.
Scott: and up and steam chat like is their chat.
Scott: They don't make it easy.
Scott: They don't use the other stuff at all.
Scott: They live in steam.
Scott: That's where their life is.
Rym: or you know
Scott: by adding a messaging component to your app You're basically allowing people to make it their home
Rym: And even if you don't live there, it's just a way to keep you there Like you're done playing a game you quit but before you quit you look in the friends list and you say hey Joey Jojo's online.
Rym: then you mess up saying hey, you want to play some more games?
Rym: Mm-hmm and and cuz.
Rym: every every website every service is obsessed with getting people to stay.
Rym: That's why Twitter like the default app if you click on a link, it doesn't just open Chrome It opens its own browser to keep you in Twitter.
Scott: Yeah, it's annoying.
Rym: Yeah Everybody's obsessed with that.
Rym: Uh So and also like Google, I don't know what the hell they're doing.
Rym: I really don't understand Allah like.
Rym: I cannot Understand why it exists because it's just a shitty version of I mess.
Scott: I think the explanation for why Allah exists is that you'll you it's some internal thing at Google, right?
Scott: we're gonna hear a story one day about like.
Scott: This is why they got some team.
Scott: Google did this and that's why they made alo and they were fighting with the hangout team or someone on the hangout team got Fired and there was a political thing and they didn't like that person and they the other people They you know liked and they made alo instead.
Scott: It's like the same, you know I always bring up this story where like when we were kids you watch Disney afternoon the good shows Ducktales the tailspins, right and then suddenly one year.
Scott: It's like alright good shows gone.
Scott: Now we're doing Aladdin and Timon and Pumbaa and shows based on our movies Characters and not original shows.
Scott: and these shows aren't as good as the old shows.
Scott: and why did they do that?
Scott: It wasn't cuz the old shows weren't successful or anything Because there's an executive shakeup at Disney and the new executive wanted to do something different and the old executive did and that's what happened.
Scott: So there's a story like that that will explain alo hangout, etc.
Rym: so in terms of monetization to like look at Twitter is a big example of that and a bunch of the I am things over the Years and all these little social media networks or social networks.
Rym: They would be funded by VCS who wanted a big payout at some point.
Rym: So they had to monetize in particular ways.
Rym: But they also had a whole bunch of capital to sort of push themselves out there and get adopted Widely before they had a monetization model.
Rym: Meanwhile a federated model sort of kicks monetization Into the ground, right?
Scott: It's like oh if you because if you're federated then to most of your users You actually end up just being infrastructure, right?
Scott: Because they're not seeing any of your stuff.
Scott: They're not using your client that could have ads in it.
Scott: They're not looking at your brand.
Scott: They're just using their own stuff.
Scott: in a case, you know, you become just.
Scott: you know a dumb pipe your messages and some people will be using your client because they prefer it over others, but Most people will be other people talking to your users and it's not to say there aren't ways to monetize that sort of thing.
Rym: I actually came up with a bunch of them, but I'm not as easy.
Scott: I think a good way to If you have big networks federating with each other just charge each other money.
Scott: Yeah, just be like, all right, we're Google.
Scott: Oh you want to federate, you know, the steam messages and the Google messages All right valve.
Scott: and Google exchange money with each other and now all the users can chat with each other for free.
Rym: Well, like say I was making say Twitter if I in the earliest days if I wanted to federate it instead of running it 100% myself or be like Laconica or monetize Laconica you run the main service free to get people use it or whatever but Maybe you are the server to run.
Rym: the federated thing is not open source or free Mm-hmm, but you can just buy it and run it and the pricing is tiered based on your usage Like two schmucks with a podcast want to run their federated server.
Rym: Yeah, like hundred bucks a year go nuts, right?
Rym: I mean, you know, it's like but Microsoft wants to run their own And maybe have some enterprise features like an internal only version or encryption or like data tracking stuff.
Rym: I ain't gonna pay yeah, but that's a much more complicated monetization model.
Rym: then take VC money and then figure out a way to profit from a service that You literally hold by the throat.
Scott: I just don't know why anyone's making a new a new thing.
Scott: That's only messaging, right?
Scott: It's like if you you might be making a new product that should include messaging.
Scott: But why make a new messaging only serve?
Rym: So what's the difference between messaging and like Twitter?
Scott: Because Twitter is not just direct messaging, right?
Rym: Broadcasting to the whole world Twitter's like having a public conversation in a big like.
Scott: feel no Twitter.
Scott: the way I see Twitter Twitter is really closer to IRC right?
Scott: Imagine IRC chat room But you obviously you can only chat 140 characters at a time, right?
Scott: Yeah, it just.
Scott: it just stops letting you type when you hit 140, right?
Scott: But otherwise IRC and now everyone in the whole world that matters is in the same IRC channel and it's just a flood like oh shit Right, but that's okay because when you join it when you join this channel by default Everyone is on mute and it's absolutely quiet
Rym: and your own man you
Scott: Unmute specific people in this and this IRC channel that has everyone in the world and that's Twitter, right?
Scott: It's not you know, Google Hangout, which is I Specifically message one person or a specific handcraft, you know Hand grab two group of people each time Right.
Scott: Yeah, which is totally it's.
Scott: you know, you wouldn't use Twitter to be like, hey, you know, what do you check out?
Scott: You know, what are you doing?
Scott: Specifically, right you'd only use it for like hey entire world Yeah, well in the look at snapchat the idea of the ephemeral chat Like right, yeah you chatting it goes.
Rym: that's actually surprisingly popular and a lot of people even people We know use it as their main.
Rym: I am client.
Rym: Yeah, they don't care about the archive Sure, but I guess for me like my use case is this the good I am.
Rym: Network has secure for real fucking encryption Capabilities.
Rym: Mm-hmm is actually secure and private.
Rym: Mm-hmm has a good UX and works in all my devices Yeah, and has full archives forever.
Rym: Yep, like I want archives of everything I've ever said.
Rym: Yep granted There was just one of the black mirror episodes.
Rym: That's really good.
Rym: is everyone has implants in their eyes that record everything forever You mean goes in the show?
Rym: Yeah, and it just shows like interesting situations that arise like arguments between spouses when there is a record of what you actually said eight years ago on one night Which I think is great.
Rym: Yeah, I enjoy that as I enjoy the fact I have every I am I've ever sent or received since 1997.
Scott: Yeah, it's I mean, you know you argue with someone You're like.
Scott: I never said that you play a video of them saying it's like Daily Show instant.
Scott: Let's go.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: Let's bring it.
Scott: Imagine if they had that like, you know political debates like.
Scott: more importantly put the video up immediately Like while the person is talking of them saying the exact opposite like.
Scott: hmm Yeah I also use it more for right now the Daily Show can only get you like the day after.
Scott: imagine if I could Daily Show Rym like During the podcast if I could Daily Show Rym, that would be so good I could.
Rym: actually I can route the audio from old GeekNights.
Scott: I could daily show you when I can't quit I can't query it up and start playing it as you're talking like.
Scott: yeah The level of speed with which I can be like you said blood.
Scott: No, I didn't.
Scott: and then you immediately start saying Hangouts, that's the way hangouts got worse.
Rym: the the access to your archives of hangouts are way less like functionally searchable than they used Twitter.
Scott: lets you download a zip file.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Good job Twitter.
Rym: Yeah Twitter good on that front.
Rym: Actually.
Rym: Yeah, there's really nothing replaces Twitter right now.
Rym: It's kind of a problem for me, but that's a separate show topic.
Rym: Hmm Twitter Twitter increasingly is the platform That is like pretty cool with Nazis.
Scott: Can I go home now?
Rym: You want to go home?
Rym: You smell that food cooking out there?
Rym: No, cuz I smell it I'm real hungry.
Scott: I'm way full.
Rym: Yeah, you're full from the cookies.
Rym: Okay, too many cookies to make.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: Heat nights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons in order the minor money.
Rym: They give us on a continuing basis are Alan Joyce Rebecca Dunn Nicholas Brando Heidi McNichol Amanda to shit.
Rym: construction noises Ivy fame.
Rym: I stated calm William I see Rose Jeremy minor Chris Reimer and Thomas.
Rym: on Christian Koontz.
Rym: You can use reg ex to parse HTML.
Rym: It's true.
Rym: shirvin von Horrell Iggy kid rare Laval James David white Rochelle, Montana Superboy.
Rym: Don't look at me.
Rym: I voted for the goat.
Rym: Aaron Cerise Brian Fisher sailor Vista the amazing $5 Rym remote registered trademark exclamation point.
Rym: Matthew Smith Don Schleich chart a vision.
Rym: Jojo Joestar Tyler Eller Sean Yeager Sam Cordray Clinton Walton run from New Zealand.
Rym: Ryan parent drew open Lander Brian Cedroni do rev los kirei niff fight Finn Eric silver on Redacted Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas on and a Huge list of people who either don't want their names read or are giving us a dollar or so Which is fine.
Rym: You only need to give a dollar.
Rym: you get access to pretty much Everything these days as you know, we're gonna be with GeekNights all through December.
Rym: I will hopefully post our actual schedules for both mag fest and PAX South soon And I'll keep you guys appraised.
Rym: ski season starting.
Rym: So if you're in the New York area and you ever want to be at hunter mountain when I'm there I'll be there pretty often soon as my skis come back from the shop.
Rym: But anyway as of now The biggest change living on for GeekNights is as soon as I finish the computer.
Rym: I've ordered equipment To semi permanently set up the rig to live stream GeekNights.
Rym: I'm also gonna start live streaming a lot more games now that I'll have a computer capable of doing that without significant performance degradation.
Rym: and I'm using the old computer to set up a semi permanent streaming and video recording rig In the living room where we do things like it.
Rym: nice presents utensils.
Rym: So I'm gonna greatly simplify the pipeline of production for video Which you will see rapid benefits of in the coming months.
Rym: And I'm doing all this without using any of your patreon money.
Rym: yet that money is still in the pile of holy shit.
Rym: now I have enough money to do something crazy awesome with it.
Rym: So like I said not using that money for anything and someday You'll know because I'll use it for something cool.
Rym: and now I leave you.
Scott: I Can America's to be a great nation.
Scott: this must become true.
Rym: So that's freedom ring from the book.
Rym: it is hilltops in New Hampshire.
Scott: Let's freedom rain from the mighty mountains in New York.
Scott: that freedom rain from the heightening alligators of Pennsylvania.
Scott: Let freedom ring from the snow-capped rockings of Colorado.
Scott: that freedom ring from the cretaceous slopes of California.
Scott: That freedom ring that.
Scott: Not only that.
Scott: let freedom ring from snow on mountain of joy.
Scott: Let freedom rain from the mountain of Tennessee.
Scott: that freedom ring from every hill and molehill of Mississippi.
Scott: Let freedom ring.
Scott: and when it happens when we have our freedom ring When we let it ring from every village in every hamlet every state We will be able to speed up that day when all New men black men and white men Jews and Gentiles Will be able
Rym: to join hands and sing in the words of the only grow.
Rym: spiritual.
Rym: free at last free at last.
Rym: Thanks.
Rym: My children will not be judged by the color of their skin.