Rym: It's Tuesday, September 27th, 2016.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights Tonight.
Rym: Press your luck in a deep sea adventure.
Rym: Let's do this.
Scott: So, it got cold.
Scott: Which is also a problem.
Scott: that's not really a first world problem.
Rym: So today- Hey, cuz man I got some second world problems.
Rym: That Soviet block, ugh.
Scott: Anyway, so I go today cuz it's cold.
Scott: Put on pants instead of shorts.
Rym: I've been wearing pants lately.
Rym: You know why?
Rym: The air conditioning's still on in my building.
Rym: It's like 60 degrees in there.
Scott: Oh, anyway, so I go to put on pants and you know what?
Rym: Pants are awful.
Scott: Too big.
Rym: Too big?
Rym: You know why?
Rym: Cuz, well, I guess you haven't been biking as much, but you still bike.
Rym: You'll lose some weight if you bike.
Scott: I mean, the thing is I've always weighed less at the end of summer than at the beginning.
Scott: That's just how bears work, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, I gained about five pounds like pretty much right after magfest is when that weight starts going away.
Rym: But like magfest time?
Rym: That's like the death knell of my stomach cuz that is Thanksgiving, bonus Thanksgivings, of which there are several, Christmas.
Scott: And it's not like, but it's like I bike less this year than any year, right?
Scott: I mean, I didn't bike to work cuz, you know, they wouldn't let me bring my bike inside and such.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: So obviously I'm not exercising or dieting because I don't do that.
Rym: Well, you bike.
Scott: I bike less than any previous year yet for some reason.
Scott: This never happened before.
Scott: I went to put my pants on.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: And it's not just like, oh, you know, they're a little.
Scott: it's like, no, I need to go buy pants that are one or two sizes smaller.
Scott: I might have to like because I had the belt where you cut the.
Scott: I might have to like cut the belt.
Scott: But then what if I do and I get fat later?
Rym: Wait, you got the fancy track line belt?
Rym: What kind of belt is this?
Scott: Yeah, it's with the thingy.
Rym: Yeah, I got four of them.
Rym: I got like one of every combination to the best.
Scott: But it's like now I have to cut it.
Scott: But if I have to uncut it, I can't do that.
Scott: I can only go in one direction.
Rym: See, I've always had this rule that and this was a rule when I was a little kid that I would never, ever, ever buy pants with a bigger waist than the pants I currently wear.
Scott: You're wearing the pants that are the same size when you were a three year old?
Scott: Well, once I became a teenager/a little kid, though.
Rym: Well, yeah.
Rym: So like 18.
Scott: Sure.
Rym: Once I hit my like, you know, in high school, I wore a 32 inch waist.
Rym: That was like my waist.
Rym: And then after when I went to RIT, it went down to about 30 because I started like really exercising.
Rym: And it's pretty much stayed around 30.
Rym: So I just only ever buy pants that are 30 or 31 tops.
Rym: And if I ever like can't put those pants on, I just won't wear pants.
Rym: Like I got that weight.
Rym: That weight's got to go away.
Scott: But what do I do?
Scott: Do I have plenty of perfectly good pants?
Scott: and I was not planning to buy new pants.
Scott: Should I just eat a bunch of barbecue instead of buying?
Scott: Because I could spend my money on barbecue instead of pants.
Scott: And that might be a better deal.
Scott: Right?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: You could just...
Scott: Because pants are expensive and I had to buy all new pants.
Rym: Maybe it's time.
Rym: Maybe it's time to do a pants audit.
Scott: But I bought new pants even last year.
Scott: I have pants that are like a year old, perfectly good.
Scott: Nothing wrong with them, except they're no longer my size.
Rym: You could donate them to charity.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: That's a lot of pants money that could have been barbecue money.
Rym: The thing is, I'd say that it might extend your life.
Rym: So if you buy new pants because you're in better shape and you stay smaller.
Scott: But I didn't even do anything.
Scott: Everyone else is like, people are trying crazy shit to lose weight and I didn't do shit.
Scott: I just live as I normally live.
Scott: And I'm not sick.
Scott: It's not like I'm losing weight because I'm diseased in the hospital.
Rym: Maybe you do the thing that apparently, according to that TED talk, most Americans can't do, of you only eat when you're hungry?
Scott: I've done that my entire life.
Scott: It's not any different in the year 2016 than 2015.
Rym: Are you hungry less?
Rym: Or maybe with Blue Apron you're eating better and cooking more and going out less?
Scott: I only get Blue Apron not that frequently.
Rym: Because we make three Blue Aprons a week and we eat out a lot less.
Rym: Because I was looking through finance stuff, we eat out about half as often as we used to.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I mean, I could check my Grubhub order frequency, but I doubt that really makes that big a difference.
Scott: I just ate like a giant slice of cake at work yesterday and didn't give a fuck, as usual.
Scott: There's actually been lots of cakes at work lately.
Rym: Well, I mean, the thing is, you eat reasonably healthily, but it is known that for most of my life, I've eaten nothing but garbage.
Scott: Cookies.
Scott: You eat a whole package of cookies.
Rym: At RIT, too.
Scott: When it's cookies, I eat one serving of cookies at a time.
Rym: Scott would get things at Vienna Fingers and there were times when I would eat an entire row of them.
Scott: Yeah, I would eat two or three at a time.
Rym: How could you eat that few cookies?
Rym: When you eat one cookie, it's like cookie fugue.
Rym: You just eat them all.
Rym: You keep eating until there's no more cookies.
Scott: I eat, you know, one serving of cookie or maybe two serving and then I have a bunch of cookie for later and I can eat servings of cookie every day.
Rym: So for the first time...
Scott: So even though, I mean, you eat a whole row at once, but I probably eat two rows over the course of a month.
Rym: But I just buy another thing of cookies for the next day to ensure...
Scott: Yeah, you're eating a whole, you know, store's worth in a month, but I'm eating a whole package in a month.
Rym: I actually exercised some self-restraint the other day.
Rym: So basically...
Scott: You're capable of that?
Rym: So yeah, this was kind of crazy.
Rym: So the shnippers open next to my office, right?
Rym: Real hard to not just go there every day.
Scott: I mean, there's a shnippers near me, but I go there pretty rarely.
Rym: Well, it is like right there.
Scott: How close could it be?
Rym: Like literally one block.
Scott: Mine's like five, six, seven blocks.
Rym: One tiny downtown block.
Scott: But they're all small blocks.
Rym: You know those blocks that are like not even a block?
Rym: Yeah, it's one block like that.
Rym: I can almost see it from the window in our office.
Rym: So I have not yet eaten a burger there because, you know, I eat burgers here.
Scott: Actually, I think I've only gotten a burger at shnippers once.
Scott: I usually get the chicken sandwich with the good stuff.
Rym: I got their sloppy joe last time.
Rym: That's not something I'm making anymore at home.
Scott: I made a sloppy joe from Blue Apron.
Scott: It was great.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So I go over there at like three o'clock because I walked downstairs and I'm like gonna get some coffee and I walk and I remember the shnippers there.
Rym: So what I did is I went over there and just got a milkshake instead.
Scott: All right.
Rym: I was like, just give me a shake.
Rym: And she was like, what kind of burger do you want?
Rym: I was like, no, I just want to shake.
Rym: And she was like, that's a good idea.
Rym: And I took the shake up to the office.
Rym: And the crazy thing is I go upstairs.
Rym: Literally every single person who works in our office because it's an open floor plan walks over like as I walk by, they're like, what's that?
Rym: And I'm like, milkshake.
Rym: And they're like, milkshake?
Rym: Where did you get a milkshake?
Rym: And I was like, well, one, there's a Shake Shack across the street and two, shnippers.
Rym: So now my entire office.
Scott: Also, you could just there's a blender in our office.
Scott: I could get ice cream and milk and just make them.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So my office, I one day like I wanted some coffee and I showed up early, like before the ops team and everyone shows up.
Rym: So I go over to that coffee maker that they make coffee in and I opened it to make coffee.
Rym: And the coffee from the previous Friday was still in there, all moldy.
Rym: And then I realized that they never clean that thing ever.
Scott: Oh, we have the pod thingy, which I've never used in my life because I don't drink poison.
Rym: It makes coffee the opposite of poison.
Rym: Coffee is good for you.
Rym: There's serious evidence that it's mostly good for you.
Scott: I think the problem with coffee is whether it's good for your health.
Rym: Probably it's like spice once you start.
Scott: The problem with coffee is I have a hypothesis.
Scott: Obviously, I don't have any evidence of this.
Rym: I'll hear you out.
Scott: I think that the people with the attitudes of workaholism who like working are people who drink.
Scott: I think if we got if we eliminated coffee from Earth, everyone would be like me and just want to go to the beach.
Rym: So it's got two counterpoints.
Rym: during the rise of the Nazis, like during the war.
Rym: A good chunk of German society was high on meth all the time.
Rym: And I thought something like Adderall and all the like they were.
Rym: that was like.
Rym: that was the let's be productive.
Rym: Fuck it mentality.
Rym: Sure.
Rym: I drink a lot of coffee.
Rym: I do not want to work hard.
Scott: You work harder than me.
Rym: I would be on the beach.
Rym: The thing is, I would form a game studio on the beach, but I wouldn't do a lot of work at the game studio.
Rym: Say, you know, I do a little work is I'd make stuff happen.
Scott: You're working harder than me.
Scott: You're trying to do.
Scott: You're putting effort towards working.
Rym: Well, I guess I have goals.
Rym: My goal is to get to the beach.
Rym: You have no path to the beach from where you are right now.
Rym: I have a path to the beach that does not significantly impact my day to day life.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, I think I think if you eliminated coffee, you would not be able to go down that path.
Scott: If I eliminated coffee is powering your path vehicle.
Rym: It's powering my life vehicle.
Scott: That's what I'm saying.
Rym: It's like I said, it's like spice.
Rym: Coffee gives you a minor superpower, but once you start using it, you pretty much have to keep using it for your entire life.
Scott: I think it's bad.
Scott: Don't do it.
Rym: It also tastes really good.
Scott: It tastes like disgusting.
Scott: Just eat hot chocolate.
Rym: You think a lot of things taste disgusting.
Scott: It just like tastes like hot chocolate, but it's been like poisoned.
Rym: Hot chocolate.
Scott: Diluted.
Rym: It tastes really good, but they're two very different things.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: One of them is good.
Scott: One of them is not good.
Scott: If they were similar, if coffee tasted like hot chocolate, I would fucking drink it.
Rym: So I don't have any gaming news today because Scott has the gaming news I was going to do and my geek bite is part of the main bit.
Rym: But I do have a story.
Scott: Oh boy.
Rym: So I play a lot of Overwatch as you guys know.
Scott: And nobody cares.
Rym: All the Overwatch people will.
Rym: So last night, because the debate was on, we actually did an Overwatch and debate where we all watched the debate on one screen and played Overwatch.
Rym: Wow.
Scott: It's like, oh, this one bad thing wasn't enough.
Scott: Let me do two bad things at once.
Rym: Overwatch is literally the game you've been waiting for.
Rym: You just won't play it for some reason.
Rym: So anyway, that's not the story.
Rym: The story is the other day.
Rym: we're playing Overwatch.
Rym: We're playing it pretty seriously.
Rym: And we're playing casual mode, meaning you can all double up.
Rym: Like everyone could pick the same hero if they wanted to.
Rym: It doesn't count for your ranking.
Rym: It's just fun, but still playing to win.
Rym: Like we're playing, trying to win.
Rym: Occasionally we'll double up on heroes or whatever.
Rym: And we had a really good game with this group of people.
Rym: They were really good.
Rym: So like we play a game or two with them and then the next map starts.
Rym: And I'm like, what if we all, like I go Bastion and someone else also goes Bastion.
Rym: That's the turret guy.
Scott: And then someone's like, hey, Rym, let me tell you about an RPG character.
Scott: So we went into the dungeon.
Rym: I don't know why you don't find Overwatch a wonderful game.
Rym: Like I still don't understand why you refuse to play it.
Scott: Even if, even if you were talking about the most wonderful game on earth right now, you're still telling me about your RPG character.
Rym: Nah, so this is good.
Rym: So I choose Bastion and then someone else also picked Bastion.
Rym: So I go to switch and then I'm like, wait a minute.
Rym: What if we all go Bastion?
Rym: Which is usually kind of a weird Dick move.
Scott: Oh my God.
Scott: What if you did?
Scott: Oh, oh, I don't.
Scott: Oh my God.
Scott: That's too crazy.
Scott: That's crazy.
Rym: It's pretty funny.
Scott: So it's secret.
Rym: The other team doesn't know what you've picked until they see you.
Rym: So we all go Bastion and we like set up and we're laughing to ourselves and being dumb and like, yeah, this is going to be fucking great.
Scott: And then the other team all goes something else.
Scott: Oh my God.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So the way it happened was we're sitting there Bastioned up and no one attacks us.
Rym: And we're like, what's going on?
Rym: Where are they?
Rym: Why?
Rym: Why aren't they?
Rym: Cause they were super serious.
Scott: Oh it's legendary hall of fame material.
Rym: So then someone's like, okay, I see a Reinhardt.
Rym: I see, I think there's six Reinharts.
Rym: They had independently, we both played a bunch of games in the room.
Scott: I was playing a game and this guy, he picked rock three times in a row.
Scott: And then I picked paper three times in a row.
Scott: Oh my God.
Scott: It was crazy.
Rym: It's a dumb baby game.
Rym: And this is a real game.
Rym: So they, but the fact that they chose to do the dumb thing, literally independently of us, the same round that we chose to do the dumb thing.
Rym: And they happen to be a counter of each other.
Rym: And that match was one of the best matches of Overwatch I have had in a long time.
Rym: All right.
Rym: I guess you can continue by cause.
Rym: what are you playing still?
Rym: Hearthstone?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Hearthstone and Pac-Man.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Real games.
Rym: New Pac-Man.
Rym: Single player games.
Scott: Game of skill.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Cause Overwatch is entirely a game of luck.
Scott: It's more, it's less skilled than Pac-Man, which is 100%.
Rym: I would disagree with that significantly.
Scott: Pac-Man is 100% pure skill.
Rym: Now Pac-Man is just a memorized game.
Rym: There's nothing going on there.
Rym: Just memorize.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Let's see you do it.
Scott: Cause the new one is definitely not a memorized game.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: The new one I'm not even going to play.
Rym: I didn't even buy it.
Scott: It's not a memorized game.
Rym: Cause I didn't even finish getting super good at Pac-Man CEDX.
Rym: I don't need more Pac-Man.
Scott: Well, the new one is completely different.
Scott: I could, I only got two S ranks at the new one cause it's so balls hard and completely different in every way.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So if it's not memorized, then what is it?
Rym: Just random?
Scott: Skills.
Rym: Well, like what?
Rym: What kind of skills?
Scott: Uh, twitching skills, quick pattern recognizing skills.
Rym: All right.
Scott: Uh, keeping from, uh.
Rym: So it's like a baby version of an FPS that tests a very limited skill set.
Scott: Oh, you should play it and see.
Scott: Let's see.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: If it's such a baby game, let's see you play it and get some S ranks.
Rym: And then you play some Overwatch.
Scott: Let's see you even get some A ranks.
Rym: Let's see you even get into the golds in Overwatch.
Scott: Let's see you, you know, get even an A rank at Pac-Man.
Rym: You want to play some Doom Deathmatch?
Rym: We'll see how that goes.
Scott: Yeah, let's not.
Scott: No?
Rym: How about some Quake 1 Deathmatch?
Rym: Quake 2?
Scott: Uh, Quake 1, you can't even aim up and down.
Rym: Uh, yeah, you can.
Scott: No.
Rym: Uh, yeah.
Rym: Did you not play Quake 1?
Scott: I played plenty of Quake 1.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Rym: I think you, anyway, you got any gaming news?
Scott: Dude, there's enormous gaming news, so.
Scott: *yawns* Enormous real gaming news, so.
Scott: The Philadelphia 76ers.
Rym: Why do we even care about, what, are they a baseball team?
Scott: They're the worst basketball team in the entire NBA.
Scott: It's actually sad, because even though they're Philadelphia, and I would normally hate them, like the hated Phillies, the hated Eagles, I pretty much hate the worst.
Scott: Every professional sports team in Philadelphia is the most hated, except for the 76ers, who are so bad.
Scott: Well, first of all, I don't like basketball, so I don't really care, which also, which helps me hate them less.
Scott: And also, they're so bad, it's like, why would you hate them?
Scott: They're so bad.
Rym: It's like when you see a puppy who's got a peanut butter jar stuck on his head, you're like, "Oh, poor
Rym: dog.".
Scott: But they actually, the history of the Philadelphia 76ers is actually a, you know, unlike, say, the history of the Eagles, a team that has never won the Super Bowl and is full of shitheads, or, you know, the Flyers, a team that has historically been full of shitheads, the Philadelphia 76ers have a great history, full of players that are legendary and respected, like Wilt and Dr.
Scott: J. So, it's hard to hate on them.
Scott: But anyway, for every year recently, they have intentionally lost, or been accused, or they're intentionally losing, it's not even an accusation, everyone knows it.
Rym: In order to win, the NBA- It's the opposite of Herm Edwards, it's play to win next year.
Scott: Right, but the thing is, they keep losing, and they keep going to the NBA draft to try to get the better draft picks, and they keep losing.
Scott: It hasn't helped them enough to where they've been able to become a winning team.
Scott: So anyway, they have purchased, I don't even know the names or care, but they purchased some major esports teams, major ones.
Rym: Let's see, so they bought Team Dignitas- I've heard of them, actually.
Rym: And Team Apex.
Scott: I've not heard of them.
Rym: I don't know if I've heard of either one of them.
Scott: I've heard of- if you said Team Dignitas, I would say that is an esports team, I've heard of them.
Rym: Yeah, I think that you think that, but if someone said a similar name, would you have this vague memory?
Rym: Yeah, I think I've heard of that.
Scott: I have no memory of Team Apex.
Rym: I might have heard of them, I don't know.
Rym: I've never felt a compelling reason to actually follow any particular esports team.
Scott: I basically just pick teams when I watch a particular esports- I think one of them could be a New York team.
Rym: Here's my heuristic.
Rym: I choose the team that acts like the evil team in the Mighty Ducks.
Rym: Whoever play- or the Yankees.
Rym: Whoever's the most evil and trying to win, pushing the rules to their limit.
Scott: So you're a fan of the New England Patriots.
Rym: Yeah, fucking win the game.
Scott: That's what I want out of my esports.
Scott: The New York Yankees.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: Where's your Yankees hat?
Rym: Because baseball's boring.
Scott: Where's your Patriots?
Scott: anything?
Scott: How many players on the Patriots can you even name?
Scott: None.
Scott: Can you even know the name of the coach of the Patriots?
Rym: Why would I even know?
Scott: Because he is the greatest player of games alive.
Scott: And whether you're a fan of them or not, you must respect that.
Scott: if he played settlers, we would be in such trouble.
Scott: And we would be so fucked.
Scott: We are lucky that man plays football.
Scott: A game that we do not have to compete with him at.
Rym: So this is actually kind of big news because it's not the only esports team that was bought.
Scott: A day later, a group of people, including Magic Johnson and also the company that owns the Washington Capitals and a bunch of other Washington sports, bought other esports teams.
Scott: So it's like- Team Liquid.
Scott: I've heard of them.
Rym: Sold a controlling interest of the team to a group of major investors under the ownership group Axiomatic, which itself, I think, let's see, blah, blah, blah.
Rym: So Magic Johnson, I think they just have a stake in it?
Scott: Yeah, because the way in professional sports, for example, sometimes you have a person who just owns a team completely.
Scott: It's just one person.
Scott: But sometimes, for example, Magic Johnson, he doesn't own the LA Dodgers.
Scott: He owns a large portion of a company that owns the LA Dodgers, among other things.
Scott: Right?
Scott: So he's like, you know, he can act like he's the owner and just go to the stadium and, you know, do owner things.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: But he's not the sole owner.
Scott: the way that, say, you know, Robert Kraft completely 100% owns the New England Patriots on his own.
Scott: No.
Rym: But anyway- So this is a big deal, but it depends on how they handle it.
Rym: because are they buying these teams just to explore the space and figure out, like, what esports are?
Rym: Are they buying these teams to brand them with other teams that they own or interact with?
Rym: Like, will they rename one of these teams to the 76ers or the Philadelphia Somethings?
Scott: I don't think that is likely.
Scott: But I think what's going on here is, number one, it's clear that they don't actually understand the space they're getting into because, like, you know, some of these leagues, like League of Legends, you know, there's like relegation.
Scott: You could be buying a team and it's like that team could then become garbage.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: It's like- It's not like buying an NHL team where they're guaranteed to at least play the regular season.
Scott: It's pretty high risk to buy an esports team if they're not like that because it's such an, you know, a nascent, you know, sort of league.
Scott: It's like you're not- it's not like you're buying the Yankees or it's like a safe bet, you know, that this is an established franchise.
Scott: You could be buying a team that will be worthless if, you know, one of those players get old and the good new players join some other team and then now this team is garbage, right?
Rym: There also isn't like the existing structure of how to handle, like, player contracts, free agency.
Scott: Well, you don't have these, like, established fan bases that are all stuck on one team no matter how good or bad that team is.
Scott: the way that, say, someone who lives in New York will be a fan of the Mets no matter how bad they are or how few weird series they win, you know.
Scott: And the Mets will always play in the major league no matter how bad they are.
Rym: Most esports players, like people who follow esports- And always sell a certain number of tickets no matter how bad they are.
Rym: Almost no one I know who follows esports really talks about teams.
Rym: They talk about individual people on those teams or they just talk about particular games they watched in the game, like this esport that they care about.
Scott: Yeah, they're like, "Oh, that was an exciting match between Team A and Team B. I rarely see people have such-".
Scott: There are people who have this, but I think it's pretty rare that there are people who have such a strong allegiance to being a fan of one team no matter what.
Scott: Like, they're gonna- their children will inherit fandom of that team.
Rym: Now, for an organization like the 76ers, they could try to apply those techniques.
Scott: I would buy the league and not the teams.
Scott: But anyway, the thing is that's, you know, interesting though is that despite their lack of sort of knowledge of esports, they've clearly recognized the viewership numbers.
Scott: And that is why they feel this is a good investment and it's hard to argue against that.
Rym: And I think this is gonna suddenly accelerate.
Scott: The viewership numbers are huge.
Scott: It's like millions and millions of people watch these things more than are watching some of their sports and they recognize this and realize that at this time- Dude, I already think esports are bigger than baseball.
Scott: The price of an esports team is lower than its value, so it's a good investment even if those other risks come into play because it's way bigger than people realize it is.
Rym: Well, there's so little money involved.
Rym: Say you buy a team and you just say, "Alright, I'll pay all the players a salary to be on the
Rym: team.".
Rym: That's still less money than you would realize.
Rym: Like, that is small change to an organization like this.
Scott: Yeah, you can pay them less than you have to pay a basketball player.
Scott: And meanwhile, they'll still be mad rich and the number of people watching it is gonna be more than some of your basketball games or many of your basketball games.
Scott: I mean, do more people watch League of Legends final world championship than watch NBA finals?
Scott: I bet maybe they did.
Scott: I haven't looked at the numbers, but I wouldn't bet either way because it's probably close.
Rym: There's also a lot of ways this could go and I don't know what's gonna happen other than I think there's gonna be a sudden weird gold rush for teams.
Rym: I think that's gonna happen.
Scott: I think another major risk in esports in general is which game is hot, right?
Scott: Because Starcraft was the hottest.
Scott: and now League of Legends is where all the action is.
Scott: And League of Legends has been around a long time and it doesn't seem to be fading, but it's gonna fade at some point and another game is gonna take over.
Scott: It's not going to always be that game.
Rym: Also, because those games don't get necessarily the constant updates.
Scott: It could be five years, it could be ten years, it could be twenty years.
Scott: In my lifetime, it will fade and another game will become the major esports game.
Rym: As soon as someone has a bigger interest in these esports than has come up the other two, the meta will collapse pretty rapidly.
Rym: Even in Overwatch right now, the meta collapsed.
Rym: There's only a few heroes that people actually play in the big times.
Rym: Imagine if they're playing like some MOBA.
Rym: The meta will just collapse immediately on one set of heroes, one set of strategies and the game won't be able to adapt.
Rym: None of these games have the kind of depth that you can get from traditional sports because they rely still so much on physicality.
Rym: So, I don't know what their long-term goal is.
Scott: Well, it's a hedge against the decline as old people die of the old sports dying and losing viewership.
Scott: And when the young punk kids are the only viewership left, ESPN doesn't want to die because all the old people who watch real sports are dead.
Scott: So, ESPN already has an esports podcast.
Scott: They're showing esports stuff on their network and on their stream.
Scott: It's like they need some kind of content when people aren't watching baseball and whatnot anymore.
Scott: So, they're like, "Well, we can get that esports
Scott: content.".
Rym: See, if I were ESPN, I would be buying leagues now.
Rym: Buy entire leagues.
Scott: Buy fucking games.
Rym: Yeah, buy games, buy leagues.
Scott: Guys, nobody's bought like Riot, the company that owns League of Legends.
Scott: I mean, it's a big company that's going to be expensive to buy.
Rym: Are they public?
Rym: I don't know much about Riot.
Scott: It doesn't matter because there are still companies bigger than them who could buy them, right?
Scott: I'm sure Disney could buy Riot if it wanted to.
Rym: If I were the VC guy or worked at ESPN or something and had any say in this, what I would do is buy leagues wholesale, buy game companies that make these kinds of games, and make bespoke games just for esports.
Rym: I would make a vertical monopoly.
Scott: I'd start making teams associated with geographic areas.
Rym: Yeah, that's all fiddly-tackly.
Scott: People have already started making college teams and it's happening, but it's not getting that much excitement yet.
Rym: Well, the NCAA has to get involved there, I think.
Scott: They're not yet involved.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: What do you got for me?
Scott: So there's this guy.
Scott: What's his name?
Scott: I don't have my thing open right now.
Scott: But anyway, it doesn't matter.
Scott: This guy's amazing.
Scott: He's been around for a year and I'm shocked.
Rym: Greg Cornell.
Rym: He does not have more- Oh, no, that's the name of the-.
Rym: Oh, yeah, Greg Cornell.
Scott: Yeah, his name is Gregory Cornell.
Scott: I don't know why he doesn't have more views and more subscribers.
Scott: It's shocking to me.
Scott: It's unbelievable what this guy's doing.
Scott: It's like top-tier shit.
Scott: So what he's doing is reviewing board games.
Scott: The good kind of board games that we play, right?
Scott: And his reviews are okay reviews.
Scott: He's mostly showing you how the game works, which is actually really useful if you want to decide whether to buy the game or not.
Scott: The one that I watched, was it called Above and Below?
Scott: That looks like a pretty good game.
Scott: Oh, if I wanted to have a nice little action-taking competitive game, that seems like a cute one and has a nice theme.
Rym: Well, actually, some of the videos that get a lot of views on our channel are the two.
Rym: The one we did where we teach Zendo and then we just play it for a while, and the one where we teach T&E and then we play it for a while.
Scott: This is an above-average game and is definitely an above-average game review analysis demonstration thing.
Scott: So the thing is, his video is not his face talking and it's not just bad shots of the game.
Rym: Like I do.
Scott: It is an extremely, extremely well-done stop-motion animation using only action figures that he then voices over.
Scott: They don't have mouths, so it's pretty easy, but I mean, as easy as stop-motion is, which is not easy at all, a huge pain in the ass.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: I went from "Hey, I could do this" to "Fuck.
Rym: no, am I never doing this" in about two seconds.
Scott: And he's also done stop-motions of the pieces moving around to demonstrate how they move in the game and it makes it- That is the best part.
Scott: It makes it so easy to understand how the game works when you have stop-motion of the pieces moving around and it's well shot and it's so good.
Scott: The tragedy is that- Why does he only have, like, no subscribers?
Rym: He has, like, 800 subscribers.
Scott: That is not, that is like, he needs, like, three more zeroes on there.
Rym: Like, remember how Scott was like, "Don't back us on Patreon, back Neil
Rym: Cicierega.".
Rym: Well, you know what?
Scott: Follow this guy.
Scott: Yeah, if you listen to a GeekNights board game episode, like this podcast, and you're not watching everything on this guy's YouTube channel, what the fuck?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Seriously?
Rym: Like, these videos are great.
Scott: Also, dammit, I can't steal that idea, but also, yeah, I would never would have stole that idea.
Rym: We could steal that idea.
Rym: Do you want to?
Scott: No.
Scott: Fuck no.
Scott: You want to sit there moving a piece around?
Scott: Take a picture.
Rym: I mean, I've- If a person has moved a piece, they can take a picture.
Scott: We have all the necessary equipment to do what this guy does, perhaps even better, only we don't have the effort.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: What were you saying about coffee?
Rym: Scott, if you drank some coffee, we could make this happen.
Scott: If I drank coffee, yes, I would eat this guy's lunch.
Rym: So, you might have noticed, but I guess you wouldn't have.
Rym: I stuck it at the end of the show a while ago, but I've been re-watching The Simpsons with Emily, so I've been off and on tweeting because we're watching season six, like really- The good shit.
Rym: It is- Yeah.
Scott: The other day, I was getting the surround sound to work in VLC, and I pressed a play out of Star Wars.
Rym: That's a real dangerous idea, Scott.
Scott: Oops.
Scott: I Star War.
Scott: Two hours gone.
Rym: I remember that time at RIT, we showed someone was visiting.
Rym: I think it was Pete was over or something.
Rym: We're like, "Blah, blah, blah.
Rym: Cowboy
Rym: Bebop.".
Rym: He was like, "I've never seen Cowboy
Rym: I'm like, "All right.
Rym: God damn it.
Rym: I'll watch the first episode right now, just so you know what the deal is,".
Rym: and then we watch the entire show.
Rym: Oops.
Scott: Cowboy Bebop.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: Just happens.
Scott: Luckily, I only Empire'd, and I didn't return, but maybe.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I got nothing to do.
Scott: when I get home.
Rym: See, at least- The thing is, Empire's my favorite one.
Scott: Is it so good?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: It's the best one, I think.
Rym: I think it's still- I like all three.
Rym: Empire's the best one.
Scott: That Hoffio.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: As a kid, I was real obsessed with Hoff for whatever reason.
Rym: I couldn't tell you why.
Scott: Good.
Scott: You can go there.
Scott: I'm going to the beach.
Scott: It's the exact opposite of Hoff.
Rym: But unlike the daykillers we had at RIT, which were VHS tapes with episodes of The Simpsons with no commercials, openers, or closers, just rapid fire for eight hours, those would kill a day.
Rym: We're watching individual episodes, so the episode ends, and then I can continue with my life, but I watched the episode again where it's a parody of Cape Fear, which if you've never seen, that's a fantastic movie.
Scott: The Sideshow Bob episode.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: But the episode is like a one-to-one parody of Cape Fear.
Rym: It's one of the funniest episodes of The Simpsons ever for a lot of reasons.
Scott: It's even funny if you haven't seen Cape Fear, because while I knew it was a parody of Cape Fear, I still haven't seen Cape Fear ever.
Scott: All I know is that Cape Fear is some kind of action movie that is a lot like that Simpsons episode.
Rym: It's more of a thriller than an action movie, but it's like- The Simpsons.
Rym: parodies are often like just a couple of references here and there.
Rym: This one is like a one-to-one.
Rym: It's kind of crazy.
Rym: But anyway.
Rym: So at the end, Bart asks Sideshow Bob to sing the entire libretto of the HMS Pinafore, and he does, and that's a plot point, and you get a bunch of snippets of him, Kelsey Grammer, actually singing the HMS Pinafore.
Rym: So because of that, I knew what the HMS Pinafore was as a kid.
Scott: I had never heard of the HMS Pinafore before seeing that episode.
Scott: Me either.
Scott: And all I knew after watching that episode was, "Oh, it's a musical probably about a And it's probably long.
Rym: It's Gilbert and Sullivan.
Scott: It's arguably the first- Oh, I know who they are.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Do you remember which one's which?
Rym: One did music, one did librettos.
Scott: I did not know that.
Scott: I thought they just sort of did every- I didn't know that there was like that kind of separation of labor.
Rym: I just learned a lot about them over the last week because apparently the HMS Pinafore is way more important than you might realize, and it might be the first modern musical of any caliber.
Rym: But because of that Simpsons episode, the snippets of songs from the HMS Pinafore have been stuck in my head, and I cannot get them out.
Rym: So I went on YouTube, and it turns out- You can just replace them with some other musical.
Scott: There's plenty to choose from.
Scott: This is a little more- Might I offer some King and I?
Rym: I think because of the motifs and the way this is put together- Some fiddling on the roof?
Rym: It's catchier than Les Mis.
Scott: No, Les Mis isn't the most catchy.
Rym: Remember that Seinfeld when George just keeps singing Master of the House?
Scott: That's the catchiest song in Les Mis.
Rym: Yeah, this is more catchy than that.
Rym: But anyway, this is not a regular performance of the HMS Pinafore because videos of stage productions like that tend to be kind of bad or just not that engaging.
Rym: This is sort of a review performance of all the music with narrations linking everything together that the BBC did in 2005, and it is of the highest quality, and you should watch the entire thing.
Rym: Also, if you don't get the stationary joke, I'll be very disappointed in you.
Scott: Is the whole thing on Spotify?
Scott: There's a lot of musical soundtracks on Spotify.
Scott: You would be shocked at how many musical soundtracks are on Spotify.
Rym: I found Martin Garrah on there, so I'm not shocked at all.
Scott: Your fav.
Rym: I don't know if I particularly like Martin Garrah, but I definitely remember- Yeah, because it was very memorable.
Rym: It was like, "Try Hard Les Mis
Rym: 2.".
Scott: Oh, also it was your favorite.
Scott: It was Jekyll and Hyde also.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: That one's legit good.
Rym: Well, that's the best concept for a musical that was never turned into a real musical.
Scott: You want to know some interesting trivia?
Scott: All right.
Scott: So, Korea, I found out from watching so much Korean TV, they're obsessed with that Jekyll and Hyde musical.
Scott: Really?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: What's that song, the main song from it?
Rym: "I Need to Know"?
Scott: Whatever.
Scott: It's like the one song from it, it comes up a lot.
Scott: They'll sing it all the time.
Scott: It's a long musical.
Rym: What kind of song?
Rym: Give me anything.
Scott: I forget, but they sing it all the time in Korean.
Rym: Is it an angry guy singing about murder?
Rym: Is it a scientist guy singing all inspirational?
Rym: Is it a woman singing about memories and dreams?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: They don't sing the whole fucking thing.
Rym: They don't sing any part of it?
Scott: They're basically just, they'd say the chorus part in Korean or whatever.
Rym: That still doesn't help me.
Rym: There's no "the main song" in Jekyll and Hyde.
Scott: Hold on.
Scott: Let me look up the- In fact, depending on what version of it- Let me look up the tracklist.
Rym: It opens possibly with a different song.
Rym: The old concept album was the "I Need to Know" song.
Scott: Let me look up the soundtrack.
Scott: Musical numbers.
Rym: There's a lot of musical numbers in it.
Rym: "Alive" is when Hyde is going crazy and about to go murder people.
Scott: This is the moment.
Scott: They sing that song.
Rym: That song is real widely sung in the US as well.
Rym: You're hearing commercials.
Scott: Yeah, but it's like they got a thing for it.
Scott: I don't hear them.
Scott: There's a lot of songs that they're way into, but that song comes up.
Scott: It's come up on multiple shows, multiple times, constantly.
Rym: The notable part about that song is that in the original concept album, the singer can hold a note longer than you would expect a human to be able to hold a note that loud, and it's kind of amazing.
Scott: Eh.
Rym: Eh.
Rym: I'm into that.
Rym: Anyway, this is the entire H.O.S.
Rym: Pinafore.
Rym: Enjoy.
Rym: In other news, we got no conventions till MAGFest.
Rym: We're actually working.
Rym: I don't think we can say anything about it yet, but we're setting up the panels.
Rym: We're probably going to be doing The Grind, an updated version of what we did at PAX, and a brand new one on quitting, like from games and such.
Scott: I quit.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: You know, MAGFest is the con, unlike PAX, where we could do the joke where we just fucking walk out of the room.
Rym: It'd be real funny if we actually didn't come back.
Rym: I wonder if MAGFest would be mad at us if we did that.
Scott: I just walked out of the room and came back.
Rym: Oh, you're on video.
Rym: They'll know.
Scott: Great.
Rym: It ruins everything.
Scott: I'll give everyone a finger.
Rym: Yeah, it's in there.
Rym: My camera is there.
Scott: Will that get us kicked off YouTube?
Rym: No.
Scott: It's your YouTube account.
Rym: Unless I get my dick out, I don't think we'll be fine.
Scott: Oh, I can just get my dick out on your YouTube account.
Scott: That'd be great.
Rym: If you really want to, you're welcome to.
Rym: I'm just going to stop looking at this monitor.
Scott: I mean, the only reason I actually wear clothes is A, warmth, B, protection from elements, and C, you know, it's like, I don't care if anyone sees my junk, but I think they got a nude beach respect because they don't want to see my job
Rym: at a nude beach.
Rym: I might do a little bit of nude swimming, but I am never in my life going to risk a sunburn on the young master and his married gentlemen.
Scott: Well, imagine, are you going to rub sun tan, you know, block on your junk?
Rym: Not while I'm at the beach.
Scott: And the thing is, it's like, you know, I don't mind being naked at the beach, but I, I'm pretty sure other people don't want to see my junk, which is why I don't.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But I'm mostly protecting the boys.
Scott: If people told me like, Hey, Scott, we want to see your junk.
Rym: I'd be like, all right, if you want to also, you know, just getting older, they, they need a lot more support than they used to.
Scott: So it's kind of unpleasant to have these DC brought that up multiple times.
Scott: I think you're having some problems because I don't have these problems.
Rym: It'll come.
Rym: Uh huh.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: There'll be a little more room down there as time goes on.
Rym: I mean, you're younger than me, so you're not there yet.
Scott: Three months, three months younger.
Rym: So uh, yeah, we got nothing.
Rym: The book club book, which I assume Scott hasn't started reading yet because you have not updated the website.
Scott: Well, I had to tell you something about the book club book.
Scott: So I haven't seen them.
Scott: I, you know, I saw the movie twice in my think, but it was many years, many years ago that I saw it.
Scott: So I don't remember too much cause my memory is not good.
Scott: But as I'm reading the book, like memories of the movie keep coming back, but I can't tell.
Scott: Are they real memories or are they, are they false memories with the actors and actresses from the movie?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Well, I mean like I remember I fucking conflated this movie with some other movie.
Rym: that is in no way related to it, but anyway, uh, yeah, I started reading it.
Rym: So I guess you can update the website.
Scott: I'm trying to update the whole website.
Scott: It's a pain in the ass.
Rym: You can at least make the post about the book club book.
Rym: So, uh, yeah, other than that, uh, I guess PAX South is in the horizon.
Rym: distantly PAX East is going to come up not too long after that, uh, then PAX Prime, uh, we're thinking about maybe going to gamer X, even if we don't do a panel of us go to it cause it's in New York.
Rym: So stay tuned for all that.
Scott: I still don't know if that's a thing that we're supposed to go to not being gay.
Rym: I was invited to submit panels for it and it's not about gay games.
Rym: It's just a friendly convention.
Scott: I mean, yeah, that is primarily about games, but it's like I'm taking a ticket away from someone who is.
Scott: So it's like, is that right?
Rym: I don't think it sells out.
Rym: Well, that's pretty sure it doesn't sell out.
Scott: If you are a person who plays games of any kind and is of a non straight sexual orientation, you should go to this.
Scott: Cause it's a good convention.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: We will probably be there.
Rym: It's a new, I'll go to pretty much any con that's in New York.
Rym: I mean, uh, there's that new anime con coming next year.
Rym: We'll definitely be at that.
Scott: I guess we'll go and see what the deal is.
Rym: I think that was going to be a lot bigger and better than the much smaller one.
Rym: We, I said we were going to go to, and then I forgot about the thing that was near the hotel near my work.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: The one where I was like, oh, I guess I clearly a garbage con, but I was, that was a weird day cause I walked out of my office and there was a cosplayer and I was like, oh, oh, and then I was like, oh right.
Scott: Is that tiny shit convention anyway?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So, uh, yeah.
Rym: Otherwise that's it.
Rym: Patreon's going, we got YouTube channels.
Rym: This episode is streaming live on YouTube right now.
Rym: So you could have watched this live, including all the stuff in between when we actually do the bits.
Scott: You're better off not doing so.
Rym: So deep sea adventure.
Rym: This is a real simple game.
Rym: It's a Japanese indie tabletop game.
Scott: Our friend Chris has gotten obsessed with the Japanese board game industry, so he's getting lots of Japanese games and including this one, which is a good one.
Rym: They're real hit or miss.
Rym: Like all games are like all indie type board games.
Scott: Some of them have amazing aspects.
Scott: Like there's a game called Buddha bevel, which is not a great game.
Scott: It's basically just sort of like a vote who wins really fast, but the instruction manual is so gloriously hilarious in its English.
Scott: It is amazing.
Scott: And also the concept God with your tower that is too tall.
Scott: You want to win the game.
Scott: You have to build the tower of Babel.
Scott: That is the tallest, but isn't too tall because then it offends God.
Rym: It's uh, I feel like there's a really good game there, but it didn't quite execute, but deep sea adventure final judgment.
Rym: Oh, so the other common theme I'm picking up on because I see other people complaining about this too, is that for whatever reason, Japanese indie tabletop people can't seem to write rules very well.
Scott: I'm sure they probably well written some of them at least.
Scott: I mean, I've read multiple people in English can't write rules well, but I'm sure if we knew, you know, Emily read the rules, she could tell us a better ruling than the English.
Rym: So from what I have gathered, that does not appear to be the case.
Rym: The rules are just not as tight as I would expect from a game in general.
Rym: But Kickstarter games have the exact same problem.
Scott: I mean, games period have this problem.
Scott: People don't write game rules tightly and well.
Rym: It seems like the only games that don't have this problem are the like.
Scott: the people who write game rules well are rules lawyers and rules lawyers are usually bad at designing games.
Rym: It's Rainer Canizia and a few other people are the only people who write good game rules.
Scott: Or people with lots of editors.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: At big publishers.
Scott: But even they fuck it up a lot.
Rym: Deep Sea Adventure is so simple and so quick and I always introduce it to people as the drowning game.
Rym: It's a drowning simulator.
Rym: Let's go.
Scott: That's correct.
Rym: Basically you get a bunch of, I mean, it has a conceit and the conceit is pretty funny.
Rym: You're a bunch of shithead treasure hunters who all hate each other, but you're also poor.
Rym: So you get together and rent a terrible submarine.
Scott: You're all in the same submarine together with the same and you only have one air tank, but you want to get more treasure than the other people because you're not sharing on your turn.
Scott: You're sharing the submarine.
Scott: You're not sharing a treasure.
Rym: There's a shared set of air on your turn.
Rym: You go down and there's all these tiles.
Scott: No one had.
Scott: No one takes a tank with them.
Scott: Everyone's just got a hose connected to the submarine.
Scott: So if you breathe too much air, you will kill everybody.
Rym: So as long as you're going down and not picking up any treasure, a game just goes on forever.
Rym: Just do whatever you want and your options on the turn is you decide if you're going to continue going down or you're going to fucking bail and run back up to that submarine.
Rym: Then you roll some dice.
Rym: You roll 2D3 to figure out how far you move in the direction you chose and then you can choose whether or not to pick up treasure on that spot.
Rym: The treasures get better the deeper you go.
Rym: However, as soon as you've picked up treasure, every time it gets to your turn, the air goes down by the number of treasures you are holding, and that applies to every player.
Scott: There's one more thing that makes it even worse.
Scott: So if I'm holding one treasure on my turn, the air goes down by one.
Scott: There's only 30 airs.
Scott: If you got a lot of players, it's hard to 25.
Scott: It's not a lot of errors.
Rym: Not a lot of errors at all.
Scott: But anyway, uh, then, you know, when you roll the dice to move, remember it's 2D3.
Scott: You don't move a lot.
Scott: You subtract one from your total movement for every treasure you're holding.
Scott: So if I roll the best possible roll, a six and I'm holding two treasures, I only move four spaces molding two treasures and I roll a one or a two.
Scott: I don't move and my turn goes past the rules like to point out if you still use two air from holding two treasures.
Rym: And that is key because if the air runs out after the players turn and ended the air, anyone who's not on the boat drops all their treasure to the bottom of the ocean and dies.
Rym: And then you play again, you play three rounds.
Scott: The submarine goes back to the surface, so anyone who's in it survives even though they ran out of air.
Rym: There's a little bit more about how you can just drop treasure and try to race back for the boat and how the lot like there's also positioning based on the other people.
Scott: So when you move, if you step on someone else, you just sort of fast forward right past them.
Scott: So if there's a bunch of people in front of you, it's really easy to get to the bottom of the ocean quickly to get more fancy treasures.
Scott: But if there's not a lot of people behind you, it's really hard to go back up to that.
Scott: You need people in front of you, whichever way you're going to move quickly with a low roll.
Scott: So you want people to be close to you, but in front of you on your way back to the submarine so you can get up there quickly.
Rym: Now this game, if everyone knows how to play it, five minutes tops to play an entire game.
Scott: The thing that takes the longest amount of time is the dice rolling.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Maybe 10 minutes.
Rym: Teaching the game takes about two minutes and people just kind of get it.
Rym: And everyone I've shown this game to, because I own it now, really likes it.
Rym: Like everyone I've ever introduced this to and I had them play it, they just got.
Scott: really You can basically have all the fun of playing like infiltration is 90% of the fun of playing infiltration.
Rym: I hate to say it, I think this is better than infiltration.
Scott: I mean, because it's- Well, I think infiltration has some complexities and some, you know, meh parts, which make it sort of less pure and less good.
Scott: But it has a little bit more fun because it has extra bits like secrets.
Rym: Well it has the fun and the theme, but it also has this meta of, it always goes kind of the same way.
Rym: There's only two options on how that game goes.
Scott: But anyway, so yeah, you can basically have all, you know, I think in terms of fun per minute per dollar per unit, it's better than infiltration.
Scott: This
Rym: is like the perfect bust it out while you're waiting for the last person to come back from the bathroom to start a real game or bust it out when you're at a con and the room closes in a half hour and you can just get one more game out of the
Scott: way.
Scott: Or bust it out if you're on a literal submarine and you're divers.
Rym: Bust it out like at the table at a restaurant.
Rym: So the thing I have noticed also is that when you play this game with people who haven't played it a bunch, almost everyone dies or everyone dies the first two rounds.
Rym: This game, like everything's going fine and it's just, you know, it's a press your luck game.
Rym: So should I keep going?
Rym: Should I keep going?
Rym: Everything's fine.
Rym: As soon as one person decides to turn back, all hell breaks loose.
Rym: As soon as one person picks up two treasures, all hell breaks loose.
Rym: The game is all about leaving Scott to drown at the bottom of the ocean as fast as possible.
Scott: Hopefully you're not the one who's at the deepest part of the ocean when people start turning around, right?
Scott: If you're at the deepest part of the ocean, you should turn around first so that you get, you know, it's like, I'm, I'm the deepest right now.
Scott: I will grab a treasure, turn around and I'll get a pretty good role cause everyone else is right behind me and then I'll be on my way back and it'll be good times.
Rym: I've had a strategy.
Scott: If you're at the deepest part of the ocean and everyone else turns back and then it's your turn again.
Scott: Now this is a big gap behind you.
Scott: It's like, wait for me.
Scott: And now you're dead.
Rym: If I'm way too shallow, like I'm near the submarine going down and other people have picked up multiple treasures, I just immediately turn around and pick up all the shit treasures on my way out just to try to kill everybody.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: There's plenty of strategies like this.
Rym: It's that there's, there's a lot of depth to this game.
Rym: Oh, despite how simple it is and I really like it and it's just like if you, if you're the kind of person who plays board games with people, this is like a must have in your library.
Rym: So in general, I mean it's a press your luck game.
Rym: It's one of, it's almost a pure press your luck game.
Scott: There's plenty of press your luck games is like a, you know, fresh fish is a press your luck game in many ways.
Rym: To a degree, but it's much more obscured and complex, right?
Scott: The press your luck is only one aspect of it, right?
Scott: But there's a no thanks is a press your luck game in many ways.
Rym: Press your luck is a press your luck game.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The game show on TV.
Scott: Except if you figure out the pattern and you're not, the luck component goes away.
Rym: And press your luck is also a core, like it is a mechanic, either core or just sort of part of the game.
Rym: Like it's part of way more games that you might realize.
Scott: infiltration we just mentioned.
Rym: because all it really means is that you generally have the option like a real, usually a really simple dial where you can dial up your risk and it, yeah, and it dials up the reward at the same time.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You can just, you know, a lot of games can buy reward potential with risk, right?
Scott: In most games out there, you know, you're always making these sort of decisions based on a risk reward analysis sort of thing, right?
Scott: Like aha, I've got three moves available.
Scott: There's the risky move that has a big reward.
Scott: There's a risky move with a shitty reward.
Scott: Forget that one.
Scott: And there's a conservative move with an okay reward and you can sort of choose to, but a press your luck game is different in that you can choose pretty much anywhere along the scale of risk and reward.
Scott: It's like a free roaming, you know, needle, not just concrete actions.
Scott: And you can, you know, keep pressing.
Scott: And then at some point you flip and you know, this is sort of this movement of increasing the risk.
Scott: And so you stop and turn around and give up on the risk, you know, like a dealer, no deal and things like that.
Rym: Now, pressing your luck, like it's in most games where they realized or not like even wizard has a heavy press your luck mechanic or at least a component because once you're behind, you're not going to win.
Rym: You can, you got to go for increasingly desperate strategies to try to catch up.
Rym: So you just dial the risk all the way up in the last round.
Rym: You're like, yeah, I'm taking 10 tricks.
Rym: You just go for it even though you've got almost no chance because that's a conventional heuristic of almost all games.
Rym: If you're losing, you want to increase randomness or take on additional risk to attempt to get a greater reward because you play conservatively and you're behind.
Rym: You're guaranteed to stay behind.
Rym: Like you can't overtake someone with a conservative strategy if they're ahead of you because they're going to play a conservative strategy and at best you'll maintain your current negative lead.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So the hallmark of a game that's specifically a press your luck game is the turnaround point.
Scott: At which point do you stop increasing the, you know, it's like, okay, Rym one out of two chance of making a dollar.
Scott: Okay, I'll do it.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Now you have to bet.
Scott: You have to go all in on every bet or not bet.
Scott: So the four chance, the next one is a lot of four chance.
Scott: The next one's one out of eight, 16.
Scott: It's like, at what point do you say, all right, I'm just going to keep my money and I'm not going to go all in again.
Scott: Right.
Scott: How do you make this decision?
Scott: It's like, you know, you've already, you know, it's like obviously no matter what the odds are in any game, you're going all in on the very first bet, even if the odds are really small.
Scott: because it's like, if you don't win the first bet, you're, you're zero, which is what you can't have less than zero.
Scott: It's like turn one.
Rym: Like a PR a pure conservative strategy and wizard would be to always bid zero unless you have wizards.
Scott: Sure.
Rym: Like, yeah, you're not going to like, you'll get your two points every round probably, but you're not going to win if anyone takes even, and you're also going to take tricks by accident.
Scott: Actually lose.
Rym: Maybe.
Rym: Yeah, but it's easier to avoid a trick than to take.
Scott: you would never in deep sea adventure or infiltration on the first turn.
Scott: Just leave and be like, Oh, back in the submarine.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: That there's no reason to do that.
Scott: You might as well at least go out, get the first thing, you know, go in infiltration, go out, pick up one day to token and go back.
Rym: So there's two things.
Rym: On one hand it's, are you behind or not?
Rym: Like the further behind you are.
Rym: Yeah, fuck it.
Rym: Like full sail.
Rym: But there's also the, before anyone has made a full declaration, like I step out and take a little more risk.
Rym: And then Scott sees it took a little more risk and he also takes a little more risk.
Rym: Like let's go.
Rym: Like this game is totally safe until someone starts picking up treasure.
Rym: So at what point do you pick up the treasure and be that guy who caused the game to enter the collapsing state?
Scott: You have to handle it because everyone else takes their turn before you take your turn, right?
Scott: So they could all turn back and then you're the last person to turn back, which could suck unless you're already the person who is in the rear.
Scott: In which case then it's kind of okay because you'll be right.
Scott: This
Rym: is why in a lot of games you'll see,
Scott: so if you're all the way in the rear, you have to look at the layout of people based on the dice they've rolled and say, okay, if I roll, how likely is it that I will end up all the way in the front?
Scott: Because if that happens, everyone else will turn back and I'll be in deep shit.
Scott: So if I can sort of land in the middle of everyone, that would be okay.
Scott: I would go deeper, but if I can't do that, I should turn back now and leave them behind and make it harder for them to get back to increase, you know, and maybe take two treasures on the way back to make up for the fact that it didn't go as deep as they did.
Rym: Now it's a really satisfying mechanic and that's part of why I bring up deep sea adventure.
Rym: If you want to really sort of study how this works and what this does to bigger, more complex games like say infiltration, play the hell out of deep sea adventure because you'll see people, despite how really simple this game is, get surprisingly invested in it and that is like, that's one of the reasons why press your luck is such a powerful mechanic.
Rym: It causes you people to get invested.
Rym: The more you've risked, even if you're not going to win anymore, like I've seen people play this game, everyone else turned back and someone else like in the third round is behind.
Rym: Fuck it.
Rym: They go way deep and sometimes they almost make it out almost, almost unlikely.
Scott: Yeah, but while there have been times, for example, where people who are trying to make it out, made it out faster than they thought.
Scott: So once they're out, they're not using up the air anymore and this person is like left outside and the only air they're using is their own.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: They have complete control over what's going on.
Scott: It's not like the other people can come out of the submarine and breathe some air and use it up.
Scott: So now they know exactly like whether they can get back or not, if they should put treasures down or pick them up or what.
Scott: And now they can score with like a really deep treasure.
Rym: So some games like this almost have a sort of coalition building where there's the coalition of people who are continuing to press forward into deeper risk and the separate coalition.
Rym: These are just implied coalitions of people who are turned back, who have decided the risk enough and are bailing.
Rym: And depending on which of those is the majority is a big part of the dynamic of the game.
Rym: And then you'll see that exact same thing play out in infiltration, for example.
Rym: But there's all this other stuff sort of obscuring it.
Rym: Like it obscures the risk reward, even though really infiltration, not much more deep than deep sea adventure.
Scott: Oh, there's a bit of randomness going on.
Rym: A lot more randomness, but also like most of the things are not nearly as powerful as you'd expect them to be.
Rym: And you're very rarely rewarded for going super deep, but the game rewards you with these other things like theme and mystery, and you really want to see what those cards are if you go deeper.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando Kay for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: For those of you who might not be paying attention to the Patreon, I read the entire first chapter of Castlevania II, Worlds of Power.
Rym: I have multiple physical copies of this book by FX9.
Rym: For the patrons only, I read Chapter 2.
Rym: I'm going to read a chapter every week or so until I finish this book.
Rym: And that's a good thing.
Rym: now, I'm just going to read these amazing Worlds of Power books to all of you who are supporting us on Patreon.
Rym: So the weird thing I have for you today as a preview, even though this is otherwise only in the Patreon, is Chapter 2 of Simon's Quest.
Rym: It is titled, I believe, Simon, Chapter 2, Simon.
Rym: "Hi Tim," said the cutest girl in junior high to Tim Bradley.
Rym: Janet Morrison told me you could give me some good tips on where to get discount rates on video game cartridges.
Rym: My brother's birthday is coming up and I need to buy him a nice present.
Rym: Blink of chocolate brown eyes.
Rym: A smile so brilliant it dazzled Tim's brain.
Rym: From cerebrum to cerebellum.
Rym: Wow.
Rym: He'd always liked Carol Jan since he'd started here at Howard Junior High last year.
Rym: And though they shared homeroom and Carol was nice enough to acknowledge his existence, unlike the more socially conscious teenage females who shunned him, she'd never actually sought him out.
Rym: For advice yet.
Rym: Tim Bradley looked around him at the rest of the homeroom class at the hand of the clock close to the 830 bell.
Rym: How come everyone wasn't watching the momentous occasion?
Rym: How come there weren't trumpets and firecrackers and streamers flying through the air just like on New Year's Eve?
Rym: Um, well, Blockbuster Discount has a real good sale on them now, actually.
Rym: Carol sure smelled nice, too.
Rym: He realized he'd never been this close to her before.
Rym: And it was not an unpleasant experience.
Rym: Tim Bradley didn't normally notice girls much.
Rym: There were far more important things to be thinking about in his life.
Rym: However, with her brunette good looks perking just inches from him, he certainly noticed Carol.
Rym: And it was an experience with every bit the excitement of a nervous moment in the middle of a game of Zelda.
Rym: "Oh, good," she said.
Rym: But then a small cloud dimmed her smile.
Rym: "Oh, dear.
Rym: I haven't the faintest idea where Blockbuster Discount is," she smiled glowingly again.
Rym: "I don't suppose you'd be willing to take me there this afternoon, would
Rym: you?".
Rym: "Um, sure, sure, Carol.
Rym: I'd be more than happy to take you there.
Rym: It's not that far away from the school.
Rym: I mean, it's so close that we could just
Rym: walk.".
Rym: "Magnificent," she grabbed his forearm and squeezed it with enthusiasm.
Rym: "See you at the flagpole outside the main entrance at 3 15 p.m It's a
Rym: date.".
Rym: She gave his arm another squeeze, and she was off in a flurry of skirt, fluffy blouse, swirling hair, and that wonderful flowery perfume.
Rym: A date.
Rym: A date with Carol Jantz, 8th grade beauty.
Rym: It all sounded okay to Tim Bradley, especially since it involved video games.
Rym: That was something he could talk about.
Rym: He'd have problems with the other stuff.
Rym: Still, it wasn't a date date, not like a movie at the mall or anything formal like that.
Rym: It was just him and Carol going to Blockbuster's, looking for bargains, right?
Rym: But the way his heart was beating, you would have thought she'd asked him to the junior prom.
Rym: The bell rang.
Rym: Tim pucked up his books and drifted out into the hallway through the flow of noisy teams, elbowing and clomping toward first-period classes.
Rym: The odor of chalk dust and floor wax filled the halls.
Rym: Tim was fantasizing about kicking through a hot game of Double Dragon, Carol Jantz by his side, when he ran smack into Burt Alvin by the boys' room.
Rym: "It was like running into a
Rym: truck.".
Rym: "Hey," said the 9th grader, frowning down on him from about 20 stories above.
Rym: Tim peered up at the heights from the level of Burt Alvin's chest to his chiseled features above.
Rym: "Hey,
Rym: Bradley.".
Rym: "Huh?"
Rym: "What's this about?
Rym: a date with my
Rym: girl?".
Rym: "Date?
Rym: Girl?
Rym: Yeah, you know, as in female.
Rym: Pretty?
Rym: Carol.
Rym: Mine.".
Rym: Each of the last four words was accompanied by a hard poke from the forefinger.
Rym: Uh-oh.
Rym: Tim had forgotten.
Rym: Carol had a boyfriend.
Rym: A big boyfriend.
Rym: Maybe she was getting ready to dump him, though.
Rym: No matter.
Rym: Tim was still dead meat if Donkey Kong here thought he was trespassing on his territory.
Rym: "Oh, that?
Rym: Uh, gee, Burt.
Rym: She just wants me to take her shopping for video
Rym: games.".
Rym: "The video jockey wants to ride off into the sunset with my girl, huh?
Rym: Well, pal, let me tell you.
Rym: I'm perfectly capable of taking Carol to any store she wants to go to.
Rym: But I tell you, I feel like putting you out of commission just for thinking about going out with my
Rym: girl.".
Rym: "What to do?
Rym: What to
Rym: do?".
Rym: "Look, Burt.
Rym: I was just headed into the boys' room.
Rym: Can we, uh, discuss this when I'm
Rym: finished?".
Rym: Burt glared at him.
Rym: "Yeah, I guess so.
Rym: I don't want you having any accidents while I'm pulverizing
Rym: you.".
Rym: "That's, uh, very thoughtful of you, Burt.
Rym: Which reminds me of a funny joke I heard the other
Rym: day.".
Rym: Tim Bradley loved jokes.
Rym: He loved puns, too.
Rym: And like he always said, the badder the better.
Rym: "Why does the chicken cross the
Rym: bathroom?".
Rym: "Move it, man.
Rym: I'll be waiting for you right
Rym: here.".
Rym: Tim pushed through the swinging door.
Rym: He went to a sink, ran cold water, and splashed it on his face.
Rym: Boy oh boy oh boy was he in trouble.
Rym: What was he gonna do?
Rym: The word around the school was the last kid who crossed.
Rym: Burt.
Rym: Alvin was wearing concrete braces at the bottom of Bulmer Pond.
Rym: Tim was pretty good when it came to wrestling Hulk Hogan or Macho Man on his Nintendo trademark, but when it came to real life, he wasn't the kind of kid to fight much.
Rym: Gosh, he really wasn't a kind of jam, and it wasn't the good grape kind either.
Rym: "Excuse me," said a deep voice from behind him.
Rym: "Are you Timothy
Rym: Bradley?".
Rym: Tim jumped.
Rym: Startled, he looked up into the mirror.
Rym: Standing behind him was a tall, blonde-haired man who looked like a superhero from a comic book, only with short hair and a vulnerable, perplexed look on his face.
Rym: But boy, his costume sure wasn't from anything this century.
Rym: He wore what looked like a handmade sheep's wool jacket and trousers with a sackcloth shirt cinched at the waist by a wide leather belt.
Rym: His black boots were leather as well, and he smelled distinctly of garlic.
Rym: "Uh, yeah, that's me.
Rym: What is this, Halloween
Rym: already?".
Rym: "May I introduce
Rym: myself?".
Rym: Tim noted a distinct accent.
Rym: "I am Simon Belmont.
Rym: I have come here to your dimension to seek your help with a dreadfully important quest.
Rym: The fate of Castlevania.
Rym: To say nothing of my soul, my life, and the soul and life of the woman I love are at
Rym: stake.".
Rym: "Oh," said Tim, "and I thought I had
Rym: problems.".