Rym: So, a while ago, Andrew, our friend has been reading a bunch of history books and I've been reading a bunch of history books and Scott is here.
Guest 0: Do you read Scott?
Rym: But we sort of decided, like you were reading this book and a couple other people had mentioned this book recently, unrelatedly.
Rym: So I said, "Hey, why don't we do a podcast and we'll all read this book and we'll talk about
Rym: it.".
Rym: And it wasn't really a super big priority until the election happened and now I feel like it's a little more relevant, a little more worried.
Guest 0: I talked about it in August where I was like, "Oh, this is an interesting what-if.
Guest 0: Let's do some
Guest 0: hypotheticals.".
Rym: Like I remember talking to some, even with Emily, I was like, "Well, it's similar except there's these four fundamental things that are different about
Rym: America.".
Rym: Now it's like, "Well, there's two fundamental things that are still
Rym: different.".
Guest 0: Yeah, I feel like we should say what the book is for those who don't know.
Rym: So the book that we read, this is the GeekNights Politics Club, I guess, is The Coming of the Third Reich by Richard Evans, who was a pretty well-respected author, actually.
Rym: I was looking into his biz.
Rym: And I highly recommend all of you out there read the book because I don't trust myself to say any of the German words anywhere in this.
Rym: The names of these political parties, it's the Steel Helmets.
Rym: I don't even know.
Rym: Freecore.
Rym: But seriously, if you're interested in this at all, read the book because the book's not that long.
Rym: It's very detailed.
Rym: It's very good.
Rym: And it's half as long as you think it is because the entire second half of the book is just citations.
Guest 0: I know, right?
Guest 0: Two-thirds, I guess.
Guest 1: I was like, "Man, I have so far to
Guest 1: go."
Guest 1: And then there was like 100 pages of citations.
Guest 0: So I guess this is actually one of three in Evans' discussion on Nazi Germany.
Guest 0: So this focus is mostly on the intellectual background and the history of, I guess, where the state of German was from sort of the coalesce of all these sort of HRE states into a single nation state.
Rym: It gives this very nice sort of history of like, here's where the, I guess, zeitgeist of Germanic culture sort of arose.
Rym: And then here's where it stood at the beginning of the end of World War I.
Guest 1: I feel like this area of their history is actually way more interesting because it's way more interesting on how a society falls apart to become this Nazi regime.
Rym: Especially considering that it was arguably the most progressive and enlightened society of the day.
Rym: It had become this shining beacon of a representative democracy to a degree.
Guest 0: It's interesting how the seeds of a lot of what Nazism was based upon were laid down in these sort of semi-factual myths and sort of deification of people like Bismarck and kind of how that was eroded and twisted throughout the Great War up until the '30s.
Guest 0: This is like one of the first books or sources where they don't start at the end of World War I. They start in the formation of Germany and really this quote unquote second Reich.
Rym: Which is interesting because I realized, thinking about my studies in high school social studies, which is the last time I studied any of this formally, very few people study this even in university, is it goes right up through Bismarck and then it just kind of skips to World War I. And then there's like one paragraph on the interwar period and then bam, 1939.
Guest 1: I feel like this is like one of the original cases of a group of people trying to impose a democracy on a group of people that were not a democracy and didn't really feel that interested in it.
Rym: But at the same time, it is very arguable because one of the themes of the book seems to be that everyone had held the democracy in contempt except for like the slightly left social democrats.
Rym: Like they were the ones who were like, guys, let's do this.
Rym: And everyone else in the entire country felt that democracy was failing them either because it wasn't going left enough or it wasn't going right enough or wasn't doing enough or it was doing too much.
Rym: So that sort of this contempt was just built into German popular culture.
Rym: And then it so I guess.
Rym: I guess that contempt was always there and it just needed the conditions to be right for it to flare up fatally.
Guest 0: It wasn't just a contempt for democracy per se, but it was also to kind of go back to my previous point, this defecation of kind of the Prussian junker way of life, the upholding and defecation of the military and the role the military played in the government.
Guest 0: Because the big the big story you get out of the end of World War One was one, the sort of great lie and November traitors, whatever that the generals who lost the war put forward and supported to save face.
Guest 0: And then also the this kind of failure of the the new republic to support these veterans and all this military structure and really kind of transition them away from that type of way of life.
Rym: Well, there's where I was talking about the difference between not to get into comparing this to the United States, like so early in this talk, but a big difference that really stood out is that that stage was set partly by the fact that the war ended and Germany had lost.
Rym: And you had this mass conscripted society, like all these soldiers who suddenly just had to walk away from that and go back to what was left of their country and try to live their lives.
Rym: And they were sort of aimless.
Rym: And then in that environment, there were all these uprisings.
Rym: So they sort of just formed these militias and real militias, not like American sort of like tactical in the woods militias, but like for real, like paramilitary organizations that persisted all the way up to the Nazis.
Rym: Yeah.
Guest 1: Well, that's one of the things I don't think it's really their republic's fault.
Guest 1: I mean, these were rules put upon them when they lost the war.
Guest 1: So the republic was like doomed to fail under the restrictions that the the allied forces, you know, like the other European forces inflicted upon them.
Guest 1: like they they couldn't.
Guest 1: they could only have an army of so so big.
Guest 1: So it was almost encouraged to keep like, you know, these militias running with each political party, because they wanted to have an army, but they couldn't officially have one.
Guest 0: And I think but but it's also more than that, right?
Guest 0: It's it's the fact that the Great War, we're looking at millions of troops, and then to demilitarize that and just say, tough luck, and then also impose economic sanctions, and say, Hey, we need payments for you to build the rest of our cities.
Guest 0: Oh, and France is going to invade and occupy some of your territory, because fuck you, some of your most industrially productive territory.
Guest 0: Yeah, yeah, it's, it's, it's almost this trifecta of the allies, or I guess, the, the, the triple entente as it was kind of crippling them beyond, I guess, a justified way.
Guest 0: Because there was no ethical right or wrong in the Great War, right?
Guest 0: It was it was just war.
Guest 0: for war's sake, everyone kind of living this pre 19th century, 18th century idea of, oh, Germany will have a European states will have a fight and be gentlemen and, and kind of get on with our political lives.
Guest 0: Great.
Guest 0: Oh, this is my son.
Guest 0: He came back from the war, he's gonna be the next game, whatever.
Rym: Of course, there is a counterpoint to that a very powerful one, at least that all the evidence from inside of Germany and sort of, you know, before the war went south in the opposite direction that had Germany won the war, the exact opposite situation would have occurred, or at least that is what they believed would occur.
Rym: Like they, it is not like if Germany had won, they would have been the gracious benefactors of Europe.
Rym: So it's, and especially because it's easy to see, you know, there are a lot of causes to the war, but Germany was sort of specifically guilty of continuing the war far beyond when it needed to go and was widely seen as the aggressor that drove it to a world conflict.
Guest 0: Oh, for sure.
Guest 0: They were the aggressor.
Guest 0: I mean, you look at like the Schlieffen plan and the fact that their entire military government system was structured around a state of expansion, right?
Guest 0: They wanted any excuse they could take.
Guest 0: They, they deliberately escalated, you know, the assassination of Franz Ferdinand in order to enact the Schlieffen plan and take over France.
Rym: Which was an echo of how Germany formed in the first place with the Franco-Prussian war, where they basically just bothered France until France declared war in the old European way.
Rym: From the perspective of the Europeans, like, you know, the winners of World War One, it's very easy to see, like just from where they were standing, why they did what they did.
Rym: They saw Germany as a threat.
Rym: Germany still had this sort of massive economy despite the sanctions.
Rym: And there's a separate narrative in this book that I didn't really think about where it talks about how the sanctions really crippled Germany and basically made it impossible for the Weimar Republic to succeed.
Rym: But at the same time, it succeeded pretty well in spite of that and appeared to be on this sort of very clear long-term sort of recovery trajectory that almost got hijacked by the Nazi movement.
Guest 0: Well, yeah, there is, there's the fact that the Great Depression happened and other like massive inflation occurring in Germany throughout the 20s, even before the Great Depression.
Rym: But yet the Nazis didn't come to serious power then when they really had their rapid rise to power was like after things were actually getting better in Germany.
Guest 0: But even then, right, during out through that whole period, all these troops, all these sort of this, this national, and this is the big thing I learned is that the Nazis were just one of many.
Guest 0: They're just the one that succeeded, you know, whether or not you want to attribute that to the great man theory that like Hitler was somehow uniquely, you know, how do you need him?
Rym: Well, they always use the word mesmerizing, like he mesmerized us.
Rym: But remember in this book, there's that sort of pre Hitler, I forget the guy's name, but there was the dude who was basically doing the same things Hitler was doing earlier and just like didn't get traction.
Rym: And it's almost like a life of Brian situation where there kept being these people.
Rym: like that movement was always there for as long as modern Germany existed.
Rym: Like that 10 to 30% of the population was like they're sort of seething and ready and just the conditions weren't right for them to really flare up.
Rym: Like Hitler, I don't know if Hitler would have succeeded if his whole story somehow started was shifted 10 years to the left or 10 years to the right.
Rym: But a different person might've risen up at that exact same time.
Guest 0: Yeah.
Guest 0: And so that's why, like the fact that the Nazis came to power after things are getting better I think is a bit disingenuous because you miss all the groundwork that was laid throughout those formative, you know, post war years that gave rise to him.
Guest 0: You notice the fact that even the social Democrats and the centrists didn't really believe in the Republic and took every chance they could to sort of slightly twist and, and, and prevent the Republic from functioning, that undermine it in very specific ways.
Guest 0: The judicial system was completely full of nationalists.
Guest 0: They were, they were essentially officers of the military where, you know, anytime like, you know, people like Hitler or nationalists go to go to jail, they were essentially just set free because they were so nationalist and anti-communist.
Rym: I guess it just, it speaks to the strength of the social Democrats and just the democracy as a whole, that despite every level of its structure, basically being against it, like that party was still largely in power and was able to push its agenda.
Rym: in spite of that.
Rym: And even until the end, the Nazis never really got more than 30, 40% of the vote, despite open naked suppression and despite like the courts and the police and the military and everyone basically formally cracking down, like they still couldn't get the votes.
Guest 0: Yeah.
Guest 1: I think the mistake that occurred that really hurt the social Democrats was the rise of the communist movement.
Guest 1: The left was fractured and then the far, I mean the, well, the Russian controlled communists were, were vilified.
Rym: It did.
Rym: So I was sort of reminded of the fact that, you know, Comintern was actually a thing.
Rym: Like in that era, like there was an open communist, like internationally coordinated organization.
Guest 0: In the book itself, if you let me open it up, I'm pretty sure one of the pictures shows an alleyway just full of Russian flags and communists.
Guest 0: Yeah.
Guest 0: It's right here on a, I don't know, it's number 16, but it's just, you don't see any, like you wouldn't imagine that would be post post world war one, Germany, right?
Guest 0: You just see an alley full of, you know, sickle and hammers.
Guest 0: But it was a real threat.
Rym: Well, even if it was, you know, despite the threat, it was also a very popular movement.
Rym: Like the communist party wasn't small.
Guest 0: Yeah, no.
Guest 0: Yeah.
Guest 0: But there was, there's, you know, people wanting, there were like, you know, communists.
Rym: Yeah.
Guest 1: I mean that the problem there was.
Guest 1: you had the, the left was literally at war with itself with an extreme version of itself.
Guest 1: Meanwhile, the Nazis stayed away from the groups that tended to be closer to their ideology, like the nationalists and the steel helmets.
Rym: But they also did something very specific and I noticed this throughout the book whenever like when they were there, they would reach out to the steel helmets and like try to get them in on a particular coalition or in a particular deal or they reach out to the trade unions when they were still parties because they seem to collapse pretty quick in this whole story.
Rym: But they basically told every one of those people a completely different story of what their party was about.
Rym: And it worked.
Guest 1: It was funny to look at when the, the national socialists actually had a little bit of socialist message and then they like immediately dropped it.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: It wasn't immediate.
Guest 0: It was, it was after the beer hall pushed.
Guest 0: Right.
Guest 0: And, and Hitler realized that one, you couldn't just like take control of power with the police and the military, even though he didn't have the military on his side.
Guest 0: But he began to realize that if it was going to succeed, he had to take control of the party itself.
Guest 0: You know, they codify those rules that says Hitler is the one and only leader of the party, but that didn't really happen until they spread out into Northern Germany and the parts where they, they didn't have sort of the same nationalist been right.
Guest 0: You have to remember Northern Germany was much more socialist leaning and that's why they had to have the socialist part of the Nazi, you know, there was two parties at that point almost that were like loosely alive.
Guest 1: Yeah.
Rym: You see this very clever strategy.
Rym: I mean, I don't know if it was clever in hindsight or if it was a stated strategy, but they would sort of let the socialist wing of the party do its own thing in the regions where that was popular, but ignore that in their actual sort of longterm national strategy.
Guest 0: Oh yeah.
Rym: And they'd literally go to like, they'd even like, they'd reach out to the communists and say, look, the democracy is failing both of us.
Rym: Like they would literally work with anyone who would talk to them and say whatever they had to say.
Rym: And I think that, I mean, it's interesting cause they only got away with that specifically because this was an era when you couldn't necessarily catch them.
Rym: It would be very difficult to find out they had these different messages because these political camps were entirely separate from each other.
Rym: They had armed militias.
Rym: They were basically at war in the streets.
Guest 1: And that's one area that's like really hard to think about in modern time.
Guest 1: Like, you know, we have protests and riots, but we don't really have like two armed political factions like attacking each other.
Guest 0: There's no street brawls going on, right?
Guest 0: There's no people just out on the hunt.
Guest 0: And like they, they talked about how the, uh, the essay very early on was used to deliberately go and break up, you know, meetings of other nationalist groups, you know, they'd go in surround the hall and just, you know, slowly creep in and beat people with clubs.
Guest 0: It's like, and this is early on, this is like in the twenties and it wasn't just them.
Rym: I mean the communists had their gangs, there was basically street fighting almost every day and it was almost a footnote in the book, but there were multiple like municipal uprisings during this period that these paramilitaries would sort of just put down on their own.
Guest 0: Well the first one that kind of justified the nationalists is right.
Guest 0: after world war one, when the Bolsheviks really started taking control, the new Republic was extremely worried that they would lose to this revolution and they allied themselves with the nationalists and the free Corps to put down that Bolshevik rebellion.
Guest 0: and it kind of justified the existence of those militia groups throughout the twenties, right?
Guest 0: So once you justify them once and say, hey, we needed your help to put down the Bolsheviks, they're not going to go away, right?
Guest 0: They're now codified as part of like this extra government group because especially there's also no military.
Rym: And you see the government periodically starting to crack down on them more and more.
Rym: Like how many times were they disarmed?
Rym: But then one thing would lead to another and they would end up basically giving their weapons back because they needed them for something.
Guest 1: Yeah, I couldn't help.
Guest 1: like when the one, like one of the times like Hitler gets arrested and I was just like, man, they could have ended it like they could have probably dealt with this problem like right then.
Rym: As you saw, the judges, the courts, the judges were sort of, were very sympathetic.
Rym: So when all the Hitlers would get arrested, they would serve a token sentence and then be let out, excused for the fact that they were driven by passion and patriotism.
Rym: And meanwhile, when the communist mob did something similar, they just get shot.
Guest 1: Yeah, that, I mean, that was, that was one of our questions, right?
Guest 1: The, uh, like what didn't we know?
Guest 1: I didn't realize how much bureaucratically the system was against itself.
Guest 1: Like, you know, like you were saying, the judges weren't really interested in democracy.
Guest 1: They looked down upon it.
Guest 1: They were like hoping for a return to the, Oh yeah, well like the bureaucracy too.
Rym: Like when the, when the Nazis started to come to power, the bureaucrats who had spines all resigned, assuming that that would mean something, which just let the Nazis fill in their posts and sort of consolidate their power.
Rym: But the other half of the bureaucracy was kind of sympathetic.
Rym: Like they were ready and willing to work with.
Guest 0: A lot of people wanted to see the return of the Kaiser and not, not just the bureaucrats and not just the judicial system.
Guest 0: Um, but the entire military really from the get go of the world war one, one distance itself away from the government, made sure it wasn't under control of the government and really it was this sort of independent power waiting and sort of, you know, one working with the judges to get the, the free core and, and all these ex soldiers out of the line, um, making deals with like social Democrats when they can in order to bypass certain, uh, limitations of like the Versailles treaty and the military restrictions.
Rym: Which in a way was a very much sort of the fatal, one of like, I don't want to say the fatal flaw because there's like 400 of them, but that was at the social Democrats, even them, the like stewards of democracy.
Guest 0: They wanted to see the return of the Kaiser.
Guest 0: Yeah.
Rym: Like they would make these compromises.
Rym: They would compromise with all the people who literally would outlaw them if they ever had a majority.
Rym: So I guess the thing that I didn't know, and it's sort of very prescient to today, not to compare too much, but I didn't realize how politically sort of knowledgeable and savvy and active the German population was during the early days of the Weimar Republic.
Rym: Like the proliferation of newspapers, the fact that this was daily discussion, like everyone was involved in politics and everyone was very passionate about politics.
Rym: And there was, there were political clubs and this constant sort of debate, but what seems to have changed, I highlighted it in the book, but he brings this up like four or five times.
Rym: I think it was in 1920, 1921, all the sort of legitimate political press got replaced by these sort of street printed dailies full of just bullshit, just literal lies.
Guest 1: Wait, Facebook and Twitter?
Rym: But like, that's the most terrifying thing that, I mean, the percentage of individual people who knew a lot about the politics of their democratic government in an era before modern communication technology were passionate, voted, and yet still like form these functioning governments.
Rym: And then that all seems to have eroded pretty rapidly once the professional press broke down.
Guest 1: Well, that, I mean, that's like one of the big areas.
Guest 1: The national institutions were not able to, were not strong enough to withstand what was going on.
Rym: Yeah.
Guest 0: They weren't strong enough and no one believed in them anyways.
Guest 0: And that's the real failure, right?
Guest 0: Is that no matter how you sort of structure your government or how many checks and balances you have, if the people don't want it to exist, it won't.
Guest 0: And everyone is saying, oh, it'll be good in our hands.
Guest 0: You know, the social Democrats, when we're in power, yeah, it's okay.
Guest 0: We'll erode all these restrictions on power because we'll do it for good.
Guest 0: And then eventually someone comes to power and just takes it completely the other way.
Guest 0: And there's nothing you can do about it, unfortunately.
Rym: And I guess in history, like you sort of, like, I remember just being taught that the Nazis suddenly came to power and it's 1939 and it's war.
Rym: And they kind of did.
Rym: But after this, like three decades of simmering to like set everything up until eventually all the pieces were in place, because the final coming to power was him becoming chancellor.
Rym: And then it was just, they needed one excuse and it was over.
Rym: But it took so long to get to that point.
Guest 1: Like the last half of this book is just like at this election, they had this percentage of the vote.
Guest 1: Then this election was this percentage of the vote.
Rym: I'm scrolling through those now.
Rym: And yeah, even in the last elections in 1933, the social Democrats still got 120 seats.
Rym: Like they were still the second largest party by far, despite the fact that you would basically be attacked in the street.
Rym: If anyone thought you were going to vote for them.
Guest 1: I know, right?
Guest 1: If you ran, if you ran as a social Democrat, you were pretty much like beating the crap out of.
Guest 0: Yeah, but it was the, it was the centrists that wanted, they eventually voted with the nationalist block to bring Hitler to power because they wanted to preserve the Catholic church and a bunch of protections for themselves.
Guest 0: Right.
Guest 0: It was very much a fuck.
Guest 0: you got mine.
Guest 0: Fuck you get mine attitude.
Rym: Well, they were the swing state.
Rym: They were, they were the biggest party that wasn't specifically allied with the left or the right.
Rym: So whoever made a coalition with them had a majority government and had the reins of this basically unchecked government.
Rym: And the book goes into a lot about how radio and sexual liberation and like modern art and all these things were basically terrifying.
Rym: all the conservatives, like the regular old stodgy conservatives who ended up in the center party, either because of religion or land ownership or whatever.
Rym: And it seems like they were voting against modernity and they didn't really care about any of the other things that came along with that.
Rym: Like they would form a coalition with anyone who would oppose the sexual liberation and these changes that were frightening them.
Guest 0: I think it's not just that.
Guest 0: And I'm, I'm a little hazy on this, but I remember that they, they almost formed a democratic society prior to world war one.
Guest 0: And this is early on in the book and they go into sort of the root histories of the social Democrats and the center Catholics.
Guest 0: and why they hate each other is because of those reasons.
Guest 0: they fought each other in the Bismarck era, or I guess just after when they tried to bring the Republic out and the, and the centrist essentially voted against the social Democrats and said, fuck you against forming the Republic because of, you know, these.
Guest 0: one, I think it was like, it was a communist reasons, maybe not, you know, and then also because of these, this social reasons, like you said.
Rym: Well, the book goes a lot just into that a lot, how the Nazis sort of used radio and use sort of the new media much more effectively early on.
Rym: And at the same time, those technologies were sort of some of the symbols that the conservatives were actually sort of fighting against.
Rym: So they seem to not embrace and use these modern methods.
Guest 1: And then on top of all that, there was the antisemitism that slowly inched through all of society.
Rym: It is terrifying though, reading all the primary sources where like one, I mean, there were Jews who were members of these parties in the early days and everyone sort of wrote off the antisemitism as this sort of like expected part of politics, like, Oh yeah.
Rym: And the Jews like, that's just, we're not serious about it.
Rym: We wouldn't do anything about it, but that is something.
Guest 1: They're not actually going to deport 11 million undocumented immigrants.
Rym: Well, if they'd have deported undocumented immigrants, they would have deported Hitler.
Rym: But like there's all these newspaper articles, not just in the book, but that I've just been reading recently for some reason.
Rym: Like there was a Time magazine article from America talking about how Hitler's antisemitism is obviously just a call to these, like these unreachable people to bring them into a coalition of government, but that it's not serious.
Rym: And he's using it as a tool to sort of enlighten these masses.
Rym: And you see that throughout and it sort of comes from, I think, and the book brings it up two times that the Nazis and the conservatives differed in that.
Rym: the conservatives seem to just be very nationalist because Germany was a nation, even though like it was very culturally homogenous in a lot of ways, it was comprised of very different backgrounds because it wasn't a unified country until relatively recently, like in living memory in this book.
Rym: And the Nazis turned nationalism into also having a race component.
Rym: So a lot of people who were otherwise very sympathetic to the conservatives and to the Nazis ended up getting sort of sidelined because their ancestry wasn't correct.
Guest 0: But it's interesting how a lot of those tones, like the white nationalism, Aryan superiority, the antisemitism came from not German authors or Slavic authors, but people in England, America, and even, I think, Russia.
Guest 0: If you early on, they talk about all these different primary sources of so-and-so wrote this book and then they wrote this book and they're all English authors.
Guest 0: And so it's really not something you can be like, oh, this is like a pure German superiority thing.
Guest 0: It's like, no, it was co-opted by sort of people external looking at the German state who are like, oh, wow, look at all those Germans.
Guest 0: That's what would be so great.
Guest 0: if white people get together, they can form Germany and Germany begins to believe those lies themselves.
Guest 0: And then the Nazis use that as leverage.
Rym: You know, that happened in another realm too, because it's very clear.
Rym: This is something I didn't really know too much.
Rym: Like I didn't really know about the Italian history up until actual World War II.
Rym: Like that, I don't think that's covered in a lot of American schools, but Mussolini came to power with the fascist revolution way earlier than I sort of just had in my head.
Rym: And it was interesting seeing how Hitler and the NDA SP were seemed to be very specifically inspired by Mussolini and by the fascists.
Rym: And they sort of copied and mirrored them as openly and nakedly as they could.
Rym: So, yeah, I guess you're right.
Rym: These, a lot of the things that happened in Germany, like Germany was the place.
Rym: all these ideas coalesced and gave rise to the horrors, but none of them really originated there.
Guest 0: It is not a unique thing.
Guest 0: I mean, and this kind of goes, fascism wasn't vogue in the thirties and then twenties.
Rym: I mean, the Americans had a pretty vibrant sort of Nazi nationalist movement that only really disappeared, or at least went underground when the war started.
Guest 1: I mean, at the same time, you also had communism that was rising at that time.
Guest 1: at the same, you know, so it was like a war of these like extreme ideologies.
Rym: I just, one of the saddest parts of the book, you know, thinking about like, what was there a point of no return?
Rym: Because there's a point toward the end when things are getting really sour, but I forget exactly when it occurred, but the social Democrats had a chance to basically form up with the communists and resort to street violence and the social Democrats at no point would be willing to do that.
Rym: Like they had such faith in the democracy and the institutions that they had spent so long undermining that they continued even after the Nazis had complete power, filing lawsuits and trying to sort of take this very like democratic high road.
Rym: When I think there's an implication that if they had resorted to street violence and revolution alongside the communists at key points along the way, the rise of Nazi Germany might not have occurred.
Guest 1: At the same time though, the communists weren't really willing to work with them in any way because they had in the, well, they had other areas where they were trying to go forward that they didn't agree with the social Democrats and on top, and they'd been betrayed in the past by them.
Guest 1: True.
Guest 1: Like politically.
Rym: They also had the idea that if the democracy finally collapsed, they could begin a true revolution.
Rym: So they kind of needed it to collapse.
Guest 1: It's like those people that just wanted to punch the government in the face.
Rym: What's that comic?
Rym: I want things to be different smashes everything.
Guest 0: I want change smash.
Guest 0: So the other thing that surprised me and I don't think it's been talked about was the effect that I was surprised by how strong youth movements were important in Germany and how much they really influenced political thought in the day.
Guest 0: It wasn't just the Nazis.
Rym: You think not every political party.
Guest 0: Yeah.
Guest 0: Everyone hears about like the Hitler youth.
Guest 0: And I think for me, I always thought like, oh, that's something weird that they just kind of created for the kids as part of like Nazism.
Guest 0: But that really is a manifestation of a much more deeper line of youth movements throughout Germans early 20th century history.
Guest 0: And they talk about how a lot of the youth movements were the formation part or formation points of true nationalism and strong militaristic wills, so to speak.
Rym: But it was also political indoctrination.
Rym: I mean, politics is such a big part of day to day life that in the universities, too, a lot of these universities had crazy political demagogues running them.
Rym: And you see that everywhere.
Rym: Like there's these tiny sort of almost autocratic empires within all these spheres all throughout the German government, German society.
Rym: I mean, the unions were run like political parties.
Rym: The unions also had their own militias to a degree as far as I could glean.
Guest 0: It does call back to your earlier point about how politically active Germans were.
Guest 0: And maybe it says something about political apathy and how.
Guest 0: maybe it's all right.
Guest 1: Well, they were talking about.
Guest 1: they talk about the voting of a mature democracy or a republic from a like a new one and how, you know, you actually kind of want over time voting to almost drop out a little bit.
Guest 0: If people don't vote, that means they're happy, you know?
Guest 0: Yeah.
Guest 0: And maybe that's a good thing.
Rym: Well, is it just that?
Rym: do you need the formation of the democracy to be far enough out of living memory?
Rym: that there's this sort of this momentum humans seem to have where the way things were when they were born is kind of a default.
Rym: So if enough people are born during a world where this is just how the government works, did they just get used to it?
Guest 0: I don't know if I agree with that.
Guest 0: I think it's much more, you know, after a government is formed, what's the stability of a nation?
Guest 0: You know, what does the economy look like?
Guest 0: How is sort of the stepping stone of social mobility?
Guest 0: Is there any sort of classism going on?
Guest 0: Those are much stronger indicators of risks to a democracy or any sort of government versus, you know, I'm defaulting to the way it was 50 years ago.
Guest 0: Because even right now, I think everyone likes to default like, oh, the American democracy was so much stronger 30, 40 years ago.
Guest 0: But you look at the early 20th century, and it really was not the case.
Guest 0: I think it was much more brutal, and we kind of lose some of that.
Guest 0: And much, I don't know, much less stable.
Rym: Well, like, look at the era of the political machines.
Rym: Like, that is actually, it's less violent, but otherwise not that different from sort of the deformed structure of later Weimar Republic government.
Rym: Like, it was politicized, and people were very active in that politicization.
Rym: But at the same time, it was not a true democracy.
Rym: It was sort of these warring factions running their machines against each other.
Guest 0: So here's a question to kind of pull away.
Guest 0: And I think this is kind of a natural segue.
Guest 0: But looking at the way American democracy is now versus where the Weimar Republic was versus maybe other democracies, if you want to compare, what are the key indicators or what are the strengths and weaknesses that would allow for a corruption or fascist state or some other non-liberal progressive ideal?
Rym: Well, I think one big difference, just to compare it to Weimar Republic Germany, is that Germany had, basically, the military had its own political party.
Rym: The steel helmets were sort of like the military as a party.
Rym: And while there are leanings toward the Republican right among the military in the US, it's by no means universal or even a majority, probably.
Rym: So the military is not its own factor in our politics.
Rym: And it hasn't been, well, you can argue if you go far enough back, but it hasn't been in modern history.
Guest 1: Well, and it's also directly controlled by the civilian end of the government.
Rym: True.
Rym: But I think that's one significant difference is that there is no military party.
Rym: But it's possible.
Rym: that's just the side effect of the fact that there are only two parties.
Guest 0: I think it's also the assumption that it's apolitical.
Guest 0: But, I mean, to however much someone in the military can be apolitical, I don't know.
Rym: I guess we treat the institution as being apolitical as opposed to, it is a party that has seats and is voting in the body that nominally controls it.
Guest 0: Yes.
Guest 1: I was going to say, again, on the institutions, before this election, I would have said, and I probably still will say, that I think our institutions are just stronger, like our press.
Guest 1: We have a history of a free and investigative and hard-hitting press throughout.
Guest 1: And we have a lot of institutions like the ACLU and whatnot that have really always worked to kind of check the government when it can, whether that-- I mean, I think we've been doing a disservice politically as one party decides that it's better off to try to undermine-- Well,
Rym: like the undermining of the Supreme Court.
Rym: We've been sitting for a long time with eight justices on our Supreme Court.
Guest 1: Yeah, and that's what I mean.
Guest 1: And as I'm saying, one party, not name of names, decides to just undermine the executive and the courts and decides that bringing public support, like bringing it down for those institutions is a good political strategy because then they'll want them in charge, right?
Guest 1: But in reality, it probably just weakens all those institutions for everybody.
Rym: Well, for example, like the press, the press, like the professional press in the US, based on the Facebook data and some of the things we've been seeing just in the last few weeks, a surprising percentage of Americans seem to prefer fake news over actual news openly and may not be reachable by our otherwise strong institutions of the press anymore.
Guest 1: It's even more nefarious than that, it seems like.
Guest 1: It seems like because they view all media with distrust, they view like the Washington Post at the same level as like US Uncut or Breitbart News or some other like kind of sensational rag that's not really doing journalism.
Rym: But here's the sentence from the book.
Rym: What was undermining the political press in the 1920s was, above all, the rise of the so-called boulevard papers, cheap sensational tabloids that were sold on the streets, particularly afternoons, evenings, rather than depending on regular subscribers, heavily illustrated with massive maps of coverage of sports, cinema, local news, crime, scandal and sensation.
Rym: These papers place the emphasis on entertainment rather than information.
Guest 0: And each one of those papers was run by a political party.
Rym: They all had a naked political sort of push like they were all agenda.
Guest 0: There is definitely an agenda.
Guest 1: But I would note that political news report and newspapers with a bend is nothing like new for the US either.
Guest 1: I mean, we only had a unbiased, neutral news since the end of like World War II.
Guest 1: Before that, all the papers were run by either the Democrats or the Republicans or some random other force.
Rym: And I don't know if that's a strengthening or a weakening.
Guest 1: Well, it's clear we're going back to that in the United States.
Guest 1: So we'll find out.
Guest 0: I think a lot of it is social media, but also the way people will unconsciously look for news that justifies their own biases.
Guest 0: And everyone is guilty of this.
Guest 0: I'm guilty of this.
Guest 0: And it's hard to challenge yourself, especially when the Internet allows you to so easily surround yourself with sources that justify your worldview and doesn't challenge your worldview.
Rym: I mean, if I want to believe that what we're talking about here didn't happen, I can Google right now and find a paper that will tell me that it's all a lie.
Guest 0: But I think there is this period between the end of World War II and I guess kind of the dawn of the Internet where people are really limited in terms of where they could get their news.
Guest 0: There's only so many TV channels, only so many radio stations, only so many newspapers that had wide distribution.
Guest 0: And so there really was a sort of ability to strive for excellence in your job as a journalist.
Guest 0: Whereas now anyone with a keyboard can create a new quote unquote news site or source that looks just as justified, has just the same amount of information that the Washington Post has, but will justify your worldview.
Guest 0: And it's literally a click away, not even a click away.
Guest 1: I mean, at the same time, during those times in the Cold War period, especially the media was more likely to just take a blind eye to something the government was doing, especially if they were told to not really report it.
Rym: Whereas now, of course, even then, there were always leaks.
Rym: There was always someone willing to push.
Rym: How many military institutions during the Cold War bases and things were revealed by press who kind of wouldn't shut up?
Rym: That happened enough to where the press was far from the monolithic entity that you saw him say the Soviet Union.
Guest 0: Is there anything else we want to say about this?
Guest 0: Otherwise, I kind of want to ask questions about this week and the last two weeks.
Rym: I guess I got two last questions here.
Rym: When was it too late?
Rym: What was the point at which this was going to be inevitable?
Rym: This rise of this radical extremist genocidal far right?
Rym: Like, was there a point where there was literally no chance of return?
Rym: And how early was that?
Guest 0: I think it really was kind of the post Great Depression.
Guest 0: Howard, there was a president or prime minister of the... He was a social democrat who essentially took severe steps to limit the power of the government or the Reichstag and put a lot of exclusive powers under the president, whether justfully or not in order to get through that situation.
Guest 0: And I think that erosion of the institution of the government itself is kind of the last step.
Guest 0: And whether it was going to be the Nazis or someone else who took power, that's the point where this experiment of the republic has failed.
Guest 1: I also think I pretty much agree with you.
Guest 1: I think also just the widespread acceptance of violence in politics kind of doomed things, because there's so many times like we were talking about where people were arrested and just let go.
Guest 1: And you were just like, oh, okay.
Rym: Well, that was it.
Rym: It wasn't just that the government was turning a blind eye is that it only turned a blind eye to certain political movements.
Guest 1: I mean, they literally were declaring war on the communist section.
Guest 1: And while they were just letting the Nazis beat the crap out of everybody.
Rym: But yeah, in general, I think you're right.
Rym: Like Hitler becoming chancellor was just formalizing the fact that there was absolute power in that very limited body and all it would take was anyone willing to use it.
Rym: The Reichstag was done and the Reichstag elections basically became meaningless almost overnight.
Rym: Like it didn't matter that the Social Democrats still had most of the seats as late as 1930.
Rym: They were still the biggest party and it literally didn't matter because that body didn't actually have any power to affect change and didn't have any governance over the rest of the institutions of governments.
Guest 1: I mean, you could argue that they had a chance if like the Nationalist Party decided not to ally with the Nazi Party at that moment that they could have maybe turned things around.
Guest 1: But that's really like the point of no return.
Rym: There might have been a chance on literally like when Hitler was appointed chancellor, like when all those marches started all at once, like basically when the Nazis openly went out into the streets and started just actively attacking people and forming the marches.
Rym: That was that moment where the communists and basically everyone on the left and center, if they had met that with violence, might have undermined the new forming government and forced it.
Rym: It might have delayed the total coming to power of the Nazis by a few years.
Rym: I don't know if it would have stopped something eventually like this happening, but I think it might have stopped this instance of it from happening.
Guest 0: I think it really is like you can say, oh, they could have thrown one last violent act, but it would have to be extraordinarily coordinated and powerful to do that.
Guest 0: And that's kind of one of the risk is like as you normalize each one of these steps down the process of just taking down your Republic, it's that much harder to bring it back by whatever means violent or political.
Guest 0: So that's why you can let yourself get too far along that spectrum of normalization of, oh, well, it's okay if we do it, we'll just take this one step and it'll be fine.
Guest 0: Or, okay, we won't call out so and so or this political party or say this isn't right because they're a small minority.
Guest 0: They won't have a real strong voice.
Guest 0: And that's that danger of letting it get too far.
Guest 0: is that when you do get to that last point and it is kind of, you know, you're on the cliff, it takes an almost insurmountable amount of power to stop that change from happening.
Rym: I think there's also a side point there that I'm just thinking about this, thinking about all the interactions that the Nazis had once they had a little bit of power and the rest of the government sort of treated them as well.
Rym: They'll fail just like all of us did.
Rym: And then their movement will fizzle out and they'll become more normal and more like the rest of us.
Rym: And we'll have to form a coalition government again.
Rym: But the Nazis seem to be the only major party that acted directly in bad faith.
Rym: Like they would make a deal and then immediately renege on it like they would like.
Rym: any concession you made to that party was never given back.
Rym: And yet every other party would continue to give further and further and further concessions like a party that's acting in good faith.
Rym: You can't work with them on anything.
Rym: That's the whole fruit of a poison tree.
Rym: It doesn't matter that there's fruit there.
Rym: The tree is still poisoned.
Guest 0: When a non rational actor enters a game with only purely irrational actors, the system breaks down, right?
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Unless all of the rational actors agree to form a coalition.
Guest 0: Unless they call it that bullshit and they're like, hey, you're fucking just choosing your card at random.
Guest 0: Fuck you.
Guest 0: Then that's it.
Rym: But they didn't.
Rym: In fact, I mean, the center party allied with them, expecting that they would get these concessions.
Rym: And they were given like in writing these very specific concessions about the church.
Rym: And literally, as soon as the STP was out of the picture, all that disappeared.
Rym: Like, you can't negotiate with someone who themselves is in a position of power over you or could be in a position of power over you in the future.
Guest 1: I just I mean, the communists were like such the tragic group in that.
Guest 1: I mean, they had the wrong idea.
Guest 1: They kind of went about things in a way that undermined them and also undermined any other group that could theoretically work with them in a way that would have prevented.
Guest 1: And since they wanted to also undermine the government, just in a different way, it really put the social Democrats and the centrists in a really bad position to ultimately not have anyone else to back up and form a coalition government with.
Rym: Especially when they were just as well armed and organized paramilitarily as the Nazis were for a long time.
Rym: But they made an enemy of everyone so they could never really use that.
Rym: Not that I'm saying that that would have necessarily led to a better future for Germany.
Guest 1: No.