Rym: It's Wednesday July 27th 2016.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm scared and this is GeekNights tonight flying witch the anime.
Scott: Let's do this Mmm.
Scott: It's that time of the year You don't want to go to work when people obviously that's that's every time of the yeah When you don't have any fucking money.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, it's like the tail end of a lot of the expenses that came up.
Scott: It's like oh just bought me a plane ticket to PAX Yeah and bought some Tickets to PAX that I have to then turn back in and we didn't even pay for the hotel at PAX.
Rym: yet We're gonna pay for that when we get there right looming expense.
Scott: And then you know, it's like there's a lot of stuff that gets paid for.
Rym: like right after PAX I'm going to Australia with Emily too and I like my church paid for but hers isn't.
Scott: and then You know even people who aren't in like, you know a pack situation.
Scott: It's like they got a. you know, some people got to spend money on back-to-school shit.
Scott: You know, it's like some people, you know, so much.
Scott: It's for some reason no matter which kind of if you live in a you know, this society.
Scott: I guess this happens to be a time of year when the money gets spent and then you got to save the money again.
Scott: See how you have holiday monies.
Rym: I mean, I we don't worry about money like.
Rym: we're pretty well off money wise.
Rym: It's just kind of how it goes, you know tech guys in New York.
Rym: But this is the time of year when I go from ignoring my finances to paying my credit card and saying wait Really that much and then click it on transactions like what the fuck did I buy?
Rym: and then it's like oh, yeah I guess a bunch of plane tickets.
Scott: So, of course, this is also the time of the year when some guy finally decides to call me like two years After I fill out a web form and say hey you want to give me like a whole bunch of money and I'm like god Damn you.
Scott: Why are you calling now?
Rym: Oh, oh, I know what guy you're talking about Right the guy from the ticket office.
Rym: So they have not called me yet for whatever reason, right?
Scott: So, you know by there are certain things in life that are usually the realm, you know Usually priced in the realm where only rich people can have them like a Ferrari.
Rym: Yep Now a lot of these things are also things.
Rym: there are things that are rich.
Rym: people today are the only people who have them But in a distant past these are the kinds of things that a family would save up for in like half.
Scott: Yeah, you could have a Ferrari a long time ago.
Scott: Maybe if you were half rich.
Scott: Yeah now you got to be whole rich Right, but one of those things that you used to be able to afford even if you were not rich With season tickets to sporting events.
Rym: now, you can still afford them if you live somewhere terrible.
Scott: Well, okay, if you maybe if you live somewhere terrible, but also how much are season tickets to the Sabres?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I'm gonna try to look it up while you keep talking.
Scott: Like even if you want to buy Mets season tickets, right and you can sit in the nosebleed at the top of the stadium It's still a shit ton of games like 90 games multiplied by ticket price, right?
Scott: It's thousands of dollars to buy those tickets and then even if you do and even if you're a super Mets fan You don't have time for that shit, right?
Scott: But a long time ago years ago.
Scott: I filled out a form that said Yeah, I'll buy some season tickets to New York Rangers.
Scott: Why the fuck not if you call me and I can't afford them I just won't buy them.
Rym: I got on the list but I actually so way back.
Rym: I did the same thing.
Rym: But I put myself in the like.
Rym: I want a full season of really good seats because I figure by the time I get to The top of that waiting list.
Rym: I'm hoping that I'll be like 50 and rich.
Scott: Good luck with that.
Rym: So Scott, how much you think it costs to get a season ticket?
Rym: Full-on season a hundred percent season to a decent seat at the Buffalo Sabres.
Scott: I imagine it's like 50 games ish, right?
Scott: Yeah, all right every game like rings probably 50 games Times like let's say let's say ringside.
Scott: Oh, that's got to be at least like $200.
Rym: so no, there's it's 70 bucks a game.
Rym: It's three grand percent for center ice Most expensive the 200 Club like now, let's see.
Scott: Well, let me like at ringside.
Scott: so I'm thinking at the glass center.
Rym: Yes at the glass Not center ice but like one right of center ice.
Scott: Mm-hmm Yeah, that's the whole season it's only.
Rym: it's only 100 bucks to go to one of those games just buying a ticket, right?
Scott: So I bought Rangers tickets.
Scott: finally Oh my god They were able say I couldn't afford a whole season.
Scott: and even if I could have afforded a half season Which I assume would be three times.
Scott: I couldn't have afforded a half season.
Scott: Yeah, even if I that would have been like credit debt for a little while even if I could have afforded a Half season I couldn't have gone to all those games.
Rym: Yep, right And while we could easily scalp them to make up the cost that is a pain in the ass.
Scott: it's pain in the ass.
Scott: So they have the like the small the mini plan, which is 11 games and you know, they rip you off.
Scott: They make you buy the preseason game which cost the same as a regular game.
Rym: So really a cheap seat costs at a Sabres preseason game a cheap seat.
Scott: Yeah, 15 bucks up 14.
Rym: All right Yeah, 15 gets you down a whole rung anyway so The you can't really choose.
Scott: This is the first basically the way it works.
Scott: the more years you do it the sooner you get to buy the tickets We need more seats are available.
Scott: So since I'm in year one, I was actually shocked that any seats are available because they bit first.
Scott: you make a deposit $500 deposit and if you don't get tickets, you can either leave your deposit in to basically hold your space in line Or take your money back without losing anything.
Rym: a moral here Alrighties.
Rym: you kids complain about comic-con or PAX tickets.
Rym: It could be way worse Right.
Scott: So I left.
Scott: I put the final deposit in like months ago.
Scott: So they were holding on to my $500 for months Right, then they.
Scott: he calls me like a week ago and he's like, alright on Friday I'm gonna I'm gonna call you again and that's when you can actually buy tickets.
Scott: Here are the four.
Scott: here are the plans you can choose from.
Scott: So one of the mini I. there are four mini plans and one of them had better opponents and better times to go see the games.
Scott: So I chose that one And he's like you probably only buy tickets like behind the net.
Scott: I'm like, alright, whatever and next year maybe better tickets.
Scott: So he calls me on Friday last week and the tickets were a hundred and eighty dollars each times eleven.
Scott: So like four thousand dollars for two seats times two seats.
Scott: So a bottom and I can probably make the money back no matter at least half the money back because I almost all of them.
Scott: If you decide you don't want them, I mean, I'm either gonna go to a game which for $180 And actually the seats are in the corner.
Scott: They're not like straight behind the net.
Scott: They're actually really good seats.
Rym: I prefer sitting in the corner.
Scott: They're on the 100 level, but they're kind of high up on the 100 level.
Scott: So it's not like you're so low.
Rym: You can't see what's going on the other side, but like I for real I'd rather say That's all high up nose bleeds than perfect center ice most of the time.
Scott: Anyway, so and then I just paid the money, but the $500 deposit went towards it.
Scott: So it actually cost me only 3500 additional dollars.
Rym: All right, so I did any and I bought two tickets.
Scott: So if I go to a game I still selling the other ticket to somebody.
Scott: Yeah, either someone I know or someone I don't know I'm gonna charge him what it cost or I'm gonna charge, you know more than what it cost to make my money back.
Scott: yeah, and if they make the playoffs which yeah, I Can sell one.
Scott: you can.
Scott: you know I'm in line To get playoff tickets more easily and I can sell those.
Scott: that even if I buy five games of playoff tickets I'm buying four games at face value and selling one game at like way above face value and I can just pay for everything.
Scott: It's like the whole thing will break even if I just sell one game of playoff tickets.
Scott: Cuz one seat for the playoffs.
Scott: like a thousand dollars.
Scott: now you've got but I'm only paying like a hundred something for it.
Rym: You've got extra incentive for them to make the playoffs than normal, right?
Scott: And then next year I could just if I save my money I can do it again and get a better seat.
Scott: Yeah, you know, but yeah, we'll see how this goes.
Scott: So my parents bought season tickets in the nosebleeds in the 70s.
Scott: But if you look at those tickets, which they physically have it's like five bucks.
Scott: Five bucks per game times every single game for the Buffalo Sabres.
Scott: if you wanted to sit Run why do you want a chicken Buffalo Sabres on to check like, Arizona?
Rym: Because I feel like Sabres might.
Rym: it's just Sabres is a nice baseline for crappy tickets.
Scott: Why'd you take Florida Panthers?
Rym: $4,400 is season tickets ringside center ice every game And all the preseason.
Scott: so we moved to Buffalo for the same amount of money.
Scott: I could have seen every game and not just 11, but would you want to know?
Scott: Yeah Well, no if I'm in Buffalo, yes, cuz there's nothing else to do.
Rym: Drive to RIT and see for RIT games instead.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean you got time for both.
Scott: Yeah, what else are you doing?
Rym: So you got any news cuz it's anime day.
Scott: I got so much news right here.
Scott: So first little news is yep.
Scott: little news number one Naoki Urosawa's current manga Billy Bat which has been coming out slowly and sporadically but not in English at all Which I have not read any of not even like bootleg scans lation Whatever is coming out.
Scott: It will end in three chapters Which means if you follow the pattern of history all of his mangas have come out except for the ones that were way old Have started coming out in English after they finished in Japanese, right?
Scott: It's like 20th century boys.
Scott: The last volume came out.
Scott: then they announced it for English.
Scott: So they the Billy Bat is gonna end in three chapters.
Scott: So I assume that Viz will probably announce volume one like next year sometime.
Scott: Yeah, which is gonna be great.
Scott: Small news number two this week on the comic book delivery list is I think Queen emerald is volume one.
Scott: It's been waiting for for like ever.
Scott: It's actually a hardcover which is weird, but yet no Legi Matsumoto manga has not had great releases in the US.
Scott: I think there were a few volumes of Galaxy Express released a long time ago, and I don't know if any Harlock mangas came out.
Scott: I think there were some Adaptations that weren't actually the originals released.
Rym: don't see him even in like bargain bins hanging around at anime.
Scott: Yeah, there I don't think they were ever put out in English officially, but there's a ton of them and I'd like to read them.
Scott: So hooray volume one.
Scott: Yeah This was true in the past but it went away but now it's back.
Scott: you can watch the three Original Mobile Suit Gundam compilation movies on YouTube for a limited time with subtitles for free.
Scott: legally They keep putting them up and taking them away.
Scott: There's like a YouTube channel Gundam info Like put stuff up and takes it down and put stuff up and takes it down even other people.
Rym: What's funny is the same thing just happened to through Tana all of you.
Rym: Tana is just on YouTube right now legit.
Scott: Nice Subbed.
Scott: I assume I didn't check because it was on Hulu dubbed for a long time.
Scott: Anyway, yeah.
Scott: So yeah, I mean I just watched the TV show but people say you should watch the compilation movies.
Rym: It's faster to do that Watch the original Gundam.
Rym: So maybe I should just watch all these movies.
Scott: It's the same story, but the compilation movies cut out some stuff.
Scott: But really if you just read the Gundam the origin manga, you don't need any of these animes.
Rym: Yep I read a little bit of that and I got to just queue up time to read the whole thing because it It's real good.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: Now the real news at Comic Con Announced Fox.
Scott: All right, whatever has acquired the rights and is developing a film for Mouse guard.
Rym: don't get too excited because as you know movies can be finished and not actually come out.
Scott: that is true.
Scott: But this doesn't seem like it's one of those cases where they are Like got the rights and did not making anything.
Scott: It seems like they're actually making right?
Scott: So the guy riding it is Gary Witte who wrote the Star Wars Rogue One movie that we haven't seen yet Yep, and they got some big animator resources.
Scott: He's been like a mouseguard fan for a while And also they're using like this motion capture CG technology to do it Which is the same stuff they used for like one of the recent Planet of the Apes movies
Rym: jungle book Which I heard mixed feelings on but at least is beautiful.
Scott: Yeah, so that's the technology They're gonna use to animate this which I guess is a lot easier than you know.
Scott: hand drawing In the style of.
Scott: could you imagine trying to animate it like by hand or even by computer and have it look like the David Peterson artwork it's like out in 2013?
Scott: Yeah, something like that it would take for fucking ever.
Scott: so I guess that's a good choice and David Peterson doesn't seem upset.
Scott: He's probably happy that is being made and also happy.
Scott: He's good money.
Rym: Yeah, I imagine he's happy about this.
Rym: Mouseguard is pretty cool.
Scott: He seems thumbs up on this like yeah, like oh, yeah.
Scott: So if the guy who made the originals thumbs up, why wouldn't we be thumbs?
Rym: He's also a pretty cool dude.
Scott: if you watched any and thankfully because it's something that's all mice then You can't.
Scott: we don't have to worry about a lot of issues like whitewashing or actor selection.
Rym: What about man?
Rym: if it's just mice?
Rym: Why mice and men?
Rym: why are we leaving the men out?
Rym: Man erasure.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, which way did you go?
Rym: Yeah So Something happening.
Scott: Well, I think this is now like the one of the only makes the shortlist of movies to be hyped for in the future.
Rym: I am moderately high.
Rym: Uh What if I was what was I hyped for before this?
Scott: I guess Zootopia I'm also hyped for.
Scott: I'm hyped for Rogue One.
Scott: So Gary what is gone to out of the short list?
Rym: I am super high for Rogue One because while Star Wars episode, you know, the newest one was not the best movie ever.
Rym: Pretty good, like it reminded.
Scott: I mean I'm just.
Scott: I don't even care if Rogue One is garbage because I'm all about spaceships gonna pee pee.
Rym: Pee also now.
Scott: So you tell me we're making a new Star Wars movie and not only are we gonna have Starships going pee-pee-pew like every other Star Wars movie we focusing in on that shit and I'm like, well, I don't care This is garbage.
Scott: Yeah, you got X-wing.
Scott: Yeah, you got a tie fighter.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Well, also our time money shut up and take my money.
Rym: Vice Admiral Thrawn up is now canonical in the new Star Wars universe.
Scott: Yeah I don't think he'd be at any live action in the theater.
Rym: It would make a lot of sense for him to be in one of the regular trilogy movies that are coming out.
Rym: I would hope they would because there is a way to have him.
Rym: like, you know The Empire sent people out to the Outer Rym and he was leading them.
Rym: He shows up and goes.
Rym: what the fuck happened here because one in charge.
Scott: Well, I read those throng novels that are so hyped by people.
Scott: They're not good They're way overrated.
Scott: and if you tell me those are the best Star Wars novels I'm not reading any others garbage, but that doesn't mean the character of Admiral Thrawn is not the ultimate badass best Star Wars character.
Scott: there is period.
Rym: I Learned you he was when I played TIE fighter and Darth Vader's like sitting signal Vice Admiral Thrawn I have the tie squadron attack or whatever and then it cuts to this dude and he's sitting there holding stroking his chin.
Scott: He clearly knows what he's doing.
Scott: Yeah Like he looks like a badass.
Rym: him and Darth and the moth the grandma for the only people who seem to know what they were.
Scott: You know, the thing is Vice Admiral Thrawn.
Scott: He looks a lot like one of my favorite x-men villains, mr Sinister, so I think I just like evil dudes with square heads.
Rym: Yeah, maybe bluish tint to the skin - mr Sinister is kind of white.
Rym: Yeah depends on who and when who drew him and when.
Scott: Yes Mr.
Scott: Sinister who is not like a white?
Rym: I've seen him white with like like, you know the shading on a face I've seen like blue shade.
Rym: blue is shading on the face.
Scott: He's got a red diamond thing stuck in his head.
Scott: Yeah And he's got a wicked cool cape that's like made of strips of like.
Scott: It looks like his cape went through a shredder and he put it back on.
Scott: Yeah, you didn't give a shit.
Rym: So at the comic-con another thing that we saw briefly and we don't really have any thoughts on other than we'll probably the only time We have Wednesday news and there's a comic-con and we blow it all in one episode.
Rym: Yep, but just guy Rishi's making a King Arthur movie.
Scott: Oh, yeah, that's making the shortlist for hype - cuz hey, I don't care if that's garbage either It's Guy Ritchie and a King Arthur movie.
Rym: cuz you might be thinking wait Is he just gonna make a King Arthur movie but with the beats and tropes of a heist movie?
Rym: And yes, there's apparently.
Rym: yes, that is exactly what he's now.
Scott: The only disappointment I have in the trailer is that he pulls the sword from the stone.
Scott: But if you know Lady of the Lake you wanted right under water Standing of King Arthur ness, right?
Scott: Yeah young King Arthur pulls the sword from the stone and then somehow it gets lost or some shit.
Scott: No, no, that's not what it was.
Scott: I remember.
Scott: now He pulls Excalibur from the stone when he's a young.
Scott: The sword that the Lady of Lake gives him is not Excalibur or the sword in the stone isn't Excalibur and the Lady of Lake Sword is Excalibur.
Scott: I think that's what it is.
Rym: I Don't actually remember.
Rym: I used to.
Scott: I'm pretty sure that's what it is.
Scott: The sword in the stone is not Excalibur, right?
Scott: He pulls the sword from the stone and that's how they know he's gonna be king.
Scott: But Excalibur is a magic sword that doesn't make you king or anything.
Scott: It's just awesome.
Scott: And that's what you get from the Lady of the Lake.
Scott: So Sword in the stone is supposed to belong to young King Arthur so that they know he's gonna be king and that's why Merlin starts You know hyping him up when he's young.
Rym: Excalibur and the sword in the stone.
Rym: Arthurian romance.
Rym: Arthur obtained the British throne by pulling a sword from a stone.
Rym: Father Sigmund and account cannot be from trying to figure it out.
Scott: The sword in the stone is not Excalibur.
Rym: Yep and I want if you go to the Wikipedia on Excalibur the first big set segment is called titled Excalibur and the sword in the And it's not the same sword.
Rym: However in what was called the post Vulgate cycle Excalibur was given to Arthur by the Lady in the Lake sometime after he began his reign.
Rym: she calls the sword Excalibur as to say that that is to say as cut steel in Vulgate Mortar to.
Rym: Arthur orders Grifflet to throw the sword into an enchanted lake.
Rym: after two failed attempts He finally complies with the wounded Kings request and a hand emerges from late to catch it Etc.
Rym: I never really knew Arthurian legend that.
Scott: well I'm saying is that Lady Lake is better than the stone.
Scott: That's all I'm saying.
Rym: So another great thing happened at comic-con it looks like but I'm saving that for my thing of the day.
Rym: and something kind of shitty happened as well.
Scott: This was my money by that in the Holy Grail say watery tarts.
Rym: So there was a women in film production panel at SCCC, that's fine, that's a good panel.
Rym: looks like it was a really good panel.
Rym: Apparently a SDCC staffer was in charge of the room to be like the moderator or whatever But the women on the panel were moderating it themselves and everything was fine.
Rym: and apparently near the end of the panel This dude who is officially in charge basically just takes over the panel and
Scott: Physically
Rym: like he walked he walks up and like gets the starts talking to the crowd like so and starts telling his own stories Like out of nowhere,
Scott: but why don't the people on the panel say who like?
Scott: if we were doing a panel, right?
Scott: And someone just came up on the stage and started talking.
Scott: we'd say who the hell are you get off the stage?
Rym: So it's got.
Rym: most people who run panels or speak on panels are not really willing or prepared to do something like that.
Scott: Then you how can you be on a stage if you can't even tell?
Rym: One that is how the vast majority of people are to.
Rym: the people who are usually on stages giving panels are There because someone else got them on.
Rym: they're not really professional Performers or panelists like we are.
Rym: they're just on a panel because they're an expert on the thing.
Scott: Also, it's saying you're a comic-con.
Scott: It's way bigger than every other con Isn't there?
Scott: like a security or a person in the panel room who would be like who are you getting off?
Rym: He was the security.
Rym: He was the official staffer in charge of the room.
Scott: There's only one staffer in the room.
Rym: Well, he he was in charge, I guess and basically as often happens You know the women on the panel didn't want to like make a scene and they were polite and they tried to sort of walk Him back into letting them talk and he just took over the whole thing.
Rym: It was a super shit bird and this happens kind of often at nerd cons.
Rym: But it's sad that it happened at SDCC because how do their staff work?
Rym: Like is it just volunteered like shit lords?
Scott: or did I know the organization that runs the convention?
Scott: Is it like, you know, like what it like?
Rym: I don't know how the SDCC is organized but I this sort of crap would not fly at a convention that I have power over.
Rym: and It's kind of terrible and sad that SDCC is so unprofessional.
Scott: I get packs it's like and it's unthinkable that like an enforcer would ever like say anything other than here's where to sit or Panels over.
Scott: everyone leave.
Rym: Yep and I have been on panels where at Conventions where the convention staff appointed a moderator and said moderator didn't know shit and was just Basically made the panel worse as opposed to better.
Rym: But I've mostly gotten around that by moderating my own panels when we do panels if it comes up.
Rym: But yeah, this you can read the whole story here and the women involved kind of tell the story fully.
Rym: I don't want to put words in their mouth, but Shame on you SDCC.
Rym: Like this is baby's first mistake.
Rym: Why was this guy staff?
Rym: Why did you even let him talk on this panel?
Rym: And if you're gonna appoint someone to be a moderator or facilitator for a women in X panel Should probably have the moderator be a woman just saying anyway things Of the day.
Rym: So this is pretty amazing.
Rym: This happened at SDCC.
Scott: I was everything today is from SDCC.
Rym: Yep, so the creators of Rick and Morty there's.
Rym: there's a famous court transcript that FARC loves the shit out of and I'm gonna link to that too.
Rym: It's just images of this.
Rym: This is a real case.
Rym: This is the transcript of the conversation between the courts which is the judge and Mr.
Rym: Allen the defendants and it is in a which court is this Georgia?
Rym: somewhere in Georgia's murder trial.
Scott: Mr Allen allegedly murdered someone and This is a real murder trial.
Rym: Yes, and he is accusing the court-appointed lawyer of Demanding that he sucked the court-appointed court-appointed lawyer's dick and all sorts of craziness.
Rym: Hey, so the guy who's accused of murder is demanding a different lawyer is because he says the first lawyer Tried to make him suck his dick.
Scott: he says that the Public defender that was assigned to defend him and make him not go to jail asked him.
Scott: the Person accused of murder suck the lawyer's dick.
Scott: You suck the dick of the public defender.
Rym: later He changes the story to I believe eating one's ass.
Scott: He's basically saying my public defender asked me to suck his dick.
Rym: Uh, that is the beginning of the exchange.
Rym: I think the least crazy thing that happens in the and I have a new public defender.
Scott: This one has actually harassed me.
Rym: the best part of this like my favorite part of this whole thing is the judge being like That's fine.
Rym: I mean it's up to you.
Rym: I told you what your choices are.
Rym: You can go to trial and then mr Allen's like.
Rym: I'll hold myself in contempt and the court and the judge is like listen to me.
Rym: Mr.
Rym: Allen.
Rym: Fuck you The court.
Rym: listen to me.
Rym: Mr.
Rym: Allen go fuck yourself.
Rym: I'm through here.
Rym: y'all done the courts.
Rym: I'm finding you in contempt of court.
Rym: Mr.
Rym: Allen.
Rym: I don't care.
Scott: the court I know you don't that sounds like is in contempt to me.
Rym: I know you don't and I sentence you to 20 days for that.
Rym: and if you say anything else I'm going to add 20 days for everything you say.
Rym: Mr.
Rym: Allen.
Rym: Fuck you the court 40 days.
Rym: Mr Allen, fuck you the court 60 days.
Rym: Mr.
Rym: Allen go fuck yourself.
Rym: the court a year.
Rym: Mr Allen your mama the court ten years.
Rym: Mr.
Rym: Allen suck my dick.
Rym: the court, you know something.
Rym: This is gonna be an interesting trial.
Rym: Mr.
Rym: Allen.
Rym: You're not supposed to smile in court, you know This goes on and on and on.
Rym: So this is this is an entertaining reading of itself.
Scott: I mean shouldn't mr Allen go to the like the ward and not the prison?
Rym: but my thing of the day is that the voice actors and creative team behind Rick and Morty voice acted the entire Transcripts to an animatic isn't there?
Scott: Can't we just watch a video of the original?
Rym: I don't believe there is a video of the original.
Rym: There's just the transcripts.
Scott: Is there like a nice pastel drawing by a court artist?
Rym: I'm pretty sure there is.
Scott: I want to see what mr.
Scott: Allen looks like.
Rym: Mr.
Rym: Allen is this like Shitty looking shit lord looking white guy with like kind of career.
Rym: I'll pull up a picture of him.
Rym: Let's see Allen.
Rym: What was his name?
Rym: I got a search for this weird Google thing.
Rym: Let's see.
Rym: His name is Allen Chazar Denver Fenton Allen.
Scott: Well, that's a pretty unique name.
Scott: I don't think you're gonna find a picture of the wrong person.
Rym: It could be Denver the dinosaur.
Rym: Well, I type Denver and it would and it recommended Fenton Allen.
Rym: Here, here's the guy.
Scott: It looks like a white guy with crazy eyes who did some drugs.
Scott: Yeah, he's definitely having his mug shot taken after doing the drugs.
Rym: Yep, and is on FARC Murder defendant Denver Fenton Allen.
Scott: That's your thing in today a crazy white guy.
Rym: my thing of the day is the video from SDCC of these voice actors Re-enacting the entire Transcripts and so my thing is also from SDCC.
Scott: This guy has a pretty clever stick He basically he looks like Doctor Who and I don't know even a fan of Doctor Who and I know that he looks like One of the Doctor Who's cuz he got the bow tie in the in the curly fro hair.
Scott: But he basically he says that he is you know Superman's little friend.
Scott: What's it?
Scott: What's the guy's name?
Scott: Oh The little reporter kid.
Scott: I don't remember that guy's name Jimmy Olsen.
Scott: He basically pretends to be Jimmy Olsen and he goes around asking people at the Comic Con a question, right?
Scott: And he asked everyone the same question to make a funny video.
Scott: So sometimes he has a wide variety of people in this video.
Scott: He asked a guy cosplaying as Robin.
Scott: He asked like just normal people just at her that are at the Comic Con.
Scott: He asked Natasha Allegri the only famous person in the thing I recognized.
Scott: ah, right and he asked them all the same question.
Scott: The question he asked is who for president?
Scott: Donald Trump or Lex Luthor?
Rym: Definitely Lex Luthor.
Scott: Everyone picks Lex Luthor.
Scott: So I don't think all right.
Scott: So the reason I'm making this thing of the day Is because a it's a good video.
Scott: It's funny.
Scott: Yeah, but also be Every single nerdy person on Twitter and Facebook and such who spends all day complaining about Donald Trump.
Scott: None of the nerds are voting for Donald Trump.
Scott: Nobody following you is gonna vote for Donald Trump.
Rym: Unfollow me.
Scott: it is completely pointless for you to tweet that nonsense because you're not talking to anyone who disagrees with that nonsense.
Scott: If you want to talk about how awful Donald Trump is Put it somewhere besides my Twitter feed because I'm not voting for him either.
Scott: You're completely wasting your breath on this.
Rym: God, you're gonna get.
Scott: Keep it on Facebook where you might have crazy relatives that will be upset.
Scott: Keep it off Twitter.
Rym: if I had a Facebook my goal would be to get all those people to block me.
Rym: I don't think I have any relatives who are those people on Facebook though.
Scott: Don't know how to block.
Rym: Oh True.
Scott: They don't know how.
Scott: Right, so right and they feel obligated.
Scott: They can't even unfriend because there's like, you know, they're family or something.
Scott: They can't they can't bring themselves to do that.
Rym: I had to put it up with that a little bit over.
Scott: that's why Facebook is even more that than Twitter.
Scott: but Twitter people Just stick to the nerdiness.
Scott: there's no point in those tweets.
Scott: look not a single nerd Right is on the wrong side of the board here.
Scott: Well, that's because the choice and the only people following you on Twitter are nerds.
Rym: how many of those nerds are gonna throw their vote away on like Jill Stein's crazy anti-vaxxer or What's his name's libertarian nonsense?
Scott: Every one of these nerds is throwing their vote away on Lex Luthor, which is perfectly fine.
Rym: But if we all throw our vote away on Lex Luthor in my win That's good, yeah, I would be okay with Lex Luthor.
Scott: I mean he's mad.
Rym: he knows how to get stuff done.
Scott: He'd have a pro kryptonite policy.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Rym: You want some Superman telling you he's better than you and much Right.
Scott: It's like it's fine In the moment.
Rym: the booklet book is Oryx and Craig by Margaret Edward next Thursday.
Rym: We're doing the show on it.
Scott: Did you read it?
Rym: I'll have it read by then.
Rym: Have you read one?
Rym: I just finished the book.
Rym: I saw the Broken Horse.
Scott: Oh You guys see the Broken.
Rym: I uh, I just finished the great ordeal.
Rym: as you guys know our scout backers latest book came out.
Rym: I just read it as fast as I possibly could and Yeah, there's a Broken Horse at the end of that book.
Rym: No horse gets broke so hard like that is the most broke I've ever.
Rym: I could imagine a horse to be more broken.
Rym: It wouldn't be a horse anymore.
Rym: Nope.
Rym: That was some good horse breaking.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I my boy Also my boy our boy He breaks men too, but a horse seen that actually happen yet.
Rym: Yeah So, yeah, that's done now meaning there's nothing to stop me from finishing.
Rym: Oryx and Craig I'll have it read by then.
Rym: You should read it.
Rym: It's short.
Rym: It's good.
Rym: It's Margaret Atwood.
Rym: We've talked about Margaret Atwood before.
Rym: we're going to be at Pikes West Saturday September 3rd 5 p.m.
Rym: The chicken theater in the convention center.
Scott: Can it be the horse theater?
Scott: Then we could break it.
Rym: Oh, yeah, get kicked out of packs break the horse And very likely me and Keel White will be hiding somewhere and doing a long spoiler ridden Podcast about the wheel of good.
Scott: you waste your precious packs time podcasting.
Scott: I'll be gaming you.
Rym: I got six fucking days of packs.
Rym: I can waste some time if I want to that's it.
Scott: But that that wasting packs time it's like one minute of packs time is is worth as much as like a million dollars, but I There aren't that many people I can talk about that stupid series with.
Rym: I gotta get it all out.
Scott: Don't talk about it stupid.
Scott: Let's just talk about horse break.
Rym: I gotta get it all out in one go.
Scott: Let's just talk about horse breaking.
Rym: Oh, yeah, not so much horse breaking in the wheel of time.
Rym: some horses die, but none get broken.
Scott: does What Bella is Bella make it.
Rym: Bella makes it.
Rym: yeah Bella.
Rym: in every book Bella's like someone.
Rym: Bella like disappears forever.
Rym: And then every now and then some characters like I gotta get out of town cuz shit's going crazy And they go to.
Scott: Bella happens to be in the stable in this town.
Rym: Yep That was like a fat chocobo.
Rym: It's always there when you need him.
Rym: Also the patreon the sieve.
Rym: five videos you ten of videos more ten of videos to come.
Rym: the t-shirts.
Rym: Magfest is the next convention after packs Tiny chance one or both of us go to PAX Australia.
Rym: I haven't decided yet.
Rym: the problem is I'm gonna be in Australia for two weeks two weeks before PAX Australia.
Rym: So if we do PAX Australia, it means I'm gonna be home for two weeks and then fly right back to Australia.
Rym: I can't quite take a month and a half off work.
Scott: Kind of want to go somewhere else.
Scott: someplace has a palm tree.
Rym: We're thinking about doing a giant s and extravaganza in 2018.
Scott: That's fine.
Scott: I need to 2016 2017.
Scott: I won't go anywhere in 2016.
Scott: I want to go someplace as a palm tree.
Rym: Just go to slightly.
Rym: no go to pack sauce and then go slightly further north after it.
Rym: Yeah, maybe go to like Brisbane or Cairn or whatever.
Rym: those places are up top.
Rym: There's the only two places I know up top.
Scott: I can go someplace in this hemisphere though.
Scott: No It's faster to get there and have more palm tree time.
Rym: We're working our way through all the anime that we already reviewed when we did our judge anime by its cover At anime Boston and this is yet one more of those flying which?
Scott: It's in the genres of according to anime news network comedy Magic slice of life slice of life Anything that's quiet which is anything that's quiet gets a slice of life Genre attached to it if I like it.
Rym: I watch like four episodes.
Rym: I think I'll watch the rest of it.
Scott: Yeah, I watched a few episodes and then they were like at the start of the season.
Scott: I started watching a bunch of shows and I finished that lost village one.
Scott: Yeah, I think I'm one episode or two from finishing Sakamoto, I know not to finish the lost village one and I only watched a few episodes of Little Witch And I kind of wanted to watch more.
Scott: but the thing is the show is So episodic and there wasn't a driving plot.
Scott: that like made me eager to see the next episode Even though I enjoyed the episodes I saw.
Scott: Yeah Make me want to watch more but that's not true.
Scott: I for example I was among a dial.
Scott: another show that people call a slice of life show whether it is or isn't Made me want to watch more episodes every time they came out.
Rym: I think the problem with the show or the release the reason you're not driven to it cuz I really like the show.
Rym: I like it too is that it does move real slow and it's like every episode is 40% magic and that magic part is great.
Rym: and 60% Making tempera.
Rym: Then exquisite and excruciating detail with some stuff that they picked off the side of the road.
Rym: and you see like now They're washing the things now.
Rym: They're making the tempera oil.
Rym: Oh, hey, you can tell when the oil is ready if you put the chopsticks anyway.
Scott: Usually when you have an episode it's a full-length episodes.
Rym: It's not a short show like only one magic thing happens per episode, right?
Scott: Well full-length episodes.
Scott: usually even in a Simpsons episode you have two or three plots Intertwining right.
Scott: that then come together at the end of the a and the B right.
Scott: or in even you know Lost Village which we talked about before there's a bunch of different characters that all have plot lines to jump to.
Scott: in Little witch there's only one characters plot line, which is the little witch's plot line, right?
Scott: The other characters are just side characters.
Scott: So with only one plot you've got one thread and everything else is just atmosphere environment around it, which is all nice.
Scott: It's a really nice environment and such.
Scott: like the animations good the care Not enough stuff in one episode to carry 20 minutes.
Scott: So you spend a lot of time watching tempera cook, right?
Scott: or the things that happen are Done in more detail and take longer like how long did it take her to pull that?
Rym: The mandrake out of the ground is worth it because the payoff on the mandrake.
Scott: No, that was great But it's like.
Scott: how long did that whole scene take?
Scott: you could have done that soon.
Rym: She's trying to weave the farm and she's like and pulls the weed out and falls in her butt and goes, right?
Rym: I almost pulls the weed out again.
Scott: I almost wish that like the dude character or maybe the mom or the little the sit.
Scott: You know the cousin a little cousin.
Scott: we're like also a main character and you could just get two plots in one episode.
Rym: Yep, or Those characters just need to have like even if you don't see their plots.
Rym: They just need more going on.
Rym: They're all just really because they're all.
Scott: they're all.
Scott: everyone is a side character.
Scott: They only come in and come out and come in.
Scott: They're never like the main focus, you know All the thing though.
Scott: to their credit though every single character even the minute every character is great Like.
Scott: there's no characters who were like all lame character I don't care about.
Rym: like there's a suspicious girl who's worried about the fact that she knows about which is.
Rym: there's the little sister Who's dubious but also into it the witch's sister who's like the ultimate?
Scott: Yeah She ever.
Rym: their relationship reminds me of a like 90% deluded version of Lena inverse and her older sister, right?
Scott: You get like the the one episode.
Scott: weird guy who cut like weird.
Scott: which dude, you know Who's magical and doesn't say anything.
Scott: who comes in?
Scott: It's not like a no face.
Rym: You've got the harbinger who is just funny.
Rym: I like him a lot because he's like, uh Come on, I'm not scary.
Rym: What's up?
Scott: Come on.
Rym: Come on.
Rym: Let me in.
Scott: Yeah, that's the guy.
Rym: Yeah, it's surprising how emotive his face is for being just two holes.
Rym: Yeah, a little owl nose of the girl who accidentally turned herself into a dog.
Scott: It's like every single character is like way cool.
Scott: You know There's just not enough stuff happening to where.
Scott: I can like keep my attention on it for more than an episode at a time now Eccentric family and on the surface moves similarly slow.
Scott: eccentric family is but a better show.
Rym: eccentric family is dense with Things other than just what happens in the episode.
Scott: Okay, first of all eccentric family has like four different plot lines going on right to pay attention to.
Scott: It also has tons of mystery and suspense and action.
Rym: Those are things that this show does not have.
Scott: No, it doesn't have any of those things right?
Scott: This show is like you.
Scott: just take one slice of eccentric family.
Rym: Yeah, right the cute tanuki part only and the rest of it is just let's temper this stuff on the side.
Scott: Don't take the ones from the utility pole because the show is really good But it's a show only for a certain mood.
Scott: It's not a show for all seasons.
Rym: Yep It's a show you put on like sitting there idle before you like cook dinner or something.
Rym: And even
Scott: though it's a show that takes place in the summer because it's all about this witch who goes To stay with her family a different part of her family during the summer, right or whatever Only temporarily or something this show I think is best watched in winter when you're cooped up in the house Yeah, and you want a summer vibe?
Scott: Yep, cuz why did you put the show out in the summer?
Scott: I guess because it goes with summer but now watch it in the winter to warm yourself up.
Rym: I would also say that the show Reminds like on the surface detail like just looking at the cover art and everything.
Rym: It reminds me of some days dreamers, which when I saw it way back I was like, ooh, that's gonna be a kind of show I like and I remember some days dreamers was so boring Didn't go anywhere and I just didn't care and I watched one episode.
Rym: I just never watched the rest of it and I feel like this is Better and that I will watch the rest of it, but I don't know when I'll finish watching.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know when It's sort of like.
Scott: it's a really good.
Scott: It's like butter.
Scott: It's really delicious.
Rym: You don't want to eat.
Scott: just it got spread way thin and it's gonna take you a long time to eat it all.
Rym: Yep, and meanwhile, there's like hero Academy or one punch man or all those other shows that it's just cocaine right in your face.
Scott: Yeah, I mean one punch man.
Scott: I watched like Faster than it came out.
Rym: Yeah, right the show is if I didn't read it.
Rym: It's just.
Rym: it's pleasant and inoffensive.
Rym: Mmm, nothing real bad to say about it, except it's not particularly Like another show that we've complained about a long time ago cosine or Jimbo that you start to watch it.
Rym: It's also slow.
Scott: Yeah, but it doesn't have characters you care about.
Rym: Yeah, I think nothing happens.
Scott: You can't tell what's happening and you don't care.
Scott: So it's like the same pace as guys know Jimbo only with good stuff It's not a bad like.
Rym: imagine if every character because they know your Jimbo were awesome But the show otherwise went the same pace that it went.
Rym: I probably would have watched it.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So yeah, I'll watch the rest of this.
Rym: whenever.
Rym: I only watch the first four I only saw up to the girl who got drunk and accidentally turned herself into a dog.
Scott: Yeah, did you watch?
Scott: Space Patrol Lulu Co not yet.
Scott: No, you should.
Rym: I think I will watch.
Rym: I gotta watch.
Rym: I think I'd watch my hero academia or whatever next.
Scott: I don't know if I'm gonna watch that at all.
Rym: That looks pretty good.
Rym: Everyone's talking about it.
Scott: So I haven't seen anyone talking about it.
Rym: I've seen a lot of.
Rym: yeah, I think I follow a very different set on Twitter than you.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.
Rym: The patreon patreons for this episode of GeekNights are in the order of the amount of money.
Rym: They give us on a continuing basis Alan Joyce Rebecca Dunn Nicholas Brando Heidi McNichol Amanda Luchette James David White Christian coons construction noises.
Rym: my city.com.
Rym: Sean Hayworth William Eisen rose Jeremy minor Chris Reimer and Thomas on.
Rym: Michelle Garcia Brian Fisher sailor Vista Devin Goodman Iggy kid Matthew Smith kachara tovish and Joe Shiro.
Rym: Joe star Tyler Eller Don Schleich Sean Yeager Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand.
Rym: Ryan parent drew open.
Rym: lander rare Lavelle Brian Sidroni Rochelle, Monta, Nona Finn Eric silver on bonsai Buddy Aaron's the Reese Chris midkiff Chris Knox.
Rym: I paid five dollars and all I got was this lousy shout out Sam Corddry Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: We're actually still coughing from all this nonsense.
Rym: So we'll get the Q&A up real soon.
Rym: tomorrow I'll post the link and we're gonna do the AMA on running conventions and all the Stuff you might be interested in on the back end of running conventions.
Rym: That'll be for patrons only of course, but it'll be everybody not just the $5 people.
Rym: I'm definitely gonna have another antenna video a short one up this by the end of the weekend as well as Probably one more sieve video Probably not the Atari game design.
Rym: There's a lot of work.
Rym: I got to do to get that panel up.
Rym: There's a bunch of editing nonsense.
Rym: I have to set up before I can really put that one together But also probably some rims rants and other things and a bunch of just stuff.
Rym: So hopefully I'll get that up soon.
Rym: the next remastered episode.
Rym: I think I figured out the deal between the two versions of the third beta episode.
Rym: So I'm in the process of remastering that and Doing my commentary.
Rym: They said the beta episodes of GeekNights are what they are.
Rym: So now I leave you with Something kind of weird.
Scott: why saying my song and I made a snow come down And I did my dance.
Scott: now I'm gonna lose my pants if I don't make it stop.
Scott: Look out here comes a snowball filled with rocks.
Scott: Thank you.
Scott: Don't dog away.
Scott: That's all they hear them say.
Scott: I Didn't expect this lot.
Scott: I'm soaked right to my you know what and I'm really in a jam.
Scott: things really got our ahem and they're throwing beer cans and they swear and they say Thank you.
Rym: Don't dog away.
Scott: Thank you.
Scott: Don't dog away.
Scott: So I really overdid it and I can't make it stop.
Scott: look out Here comes another snowball really filled with big rocks.
Scott: Thank you.
Rym: Don't dog away.