Rym: It's Wednesday March 9th 2016.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights.
Rym: It's warm out and tonight We are reviewing.
Rym: mama hosted us the boy and the beast beasts.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: and Yeah, TLDR version.
Rym: We're gonna tell you to go see it, but the review will get into more detail.
Scott: I guess what if we ever said for an anime movie don't go see it.
Rym: Yeah, I mean the anime movies We'd tell you not to go see are the ones that we either didn't watch or we don't talk about or we're not gonna watch.
Rym: Yeah, there aren't that many bad anime movies that I've seen?
Rym: well I guess there are.
Rym: I mean we never did.
Rym: we never did like Armageddon or do Megalopolis.
Scott: I guess I won't necessarily tell you not to watch.
Rym: actually I was talking to multiple people about Both of those anime recently and in all these conversations the end result was basically It's kind of like apocalypse.
Rym: zero may not be the greatest thing, but it's worth seeing it.
Scott: for reasons?
Rym: Yeah, not not because reasons is boy in the V's exactly But yeah, so it's crazy warm out and it's biking season.
Rym: finally I think I'd like to work tomorrow.
Scott: I'm in a new office or the biking situation is not fixed yet But my boss.
Scott: boss was like I'm gonna take a project and fix that.
Scott: so I guess I got to wait for the old bikes And building.
Rym: yeah, my old company kept saying that they never fixed it.
Scott: well apparently this building used to have a bike Rack in the basement, but it's under construction now and like renovating and shit.
Scott: So I is when it finishes that might resolve.
Scott: But my co-worker who bikes he put his.
Scott: he tied his bike up outside the off.
Rym: I would do that if my company gave me in writing Something that said they will buy me a brand new bike of equivalent quality.
Rym: if my bike gets stolen Any number of times if it's stolen while I'm working so?
Scott: But when we just I just left the office with him I was in the elevator.
Scott: We walked out.
Scott: his bike was gone.
Scott: his bike was right there in front of the building.
Rym: Yeah, I mean I locked my bike up in Manhattan like 50 or 60 times before that one day.
Scott: It was gone, so Goodbye a Easier to carry lock.
Scott: the lock I have is like way big.
Rym: yeah I know I have.
Rym: I have one like pretty big lock and I have one crazy lock that I use like when I go to Brooklyn.
Scott: yeah, I'll go buy.
Scott: I should buy like a normal size one with the cable attached to it.
Rym: So anyway, I got.
Rym: I got some news.
Rym: It's an animated movie.
Rym: because I'm not reviewing it now But I'm gonna geek bite it briefly up in the patreon.
Rym: Emily And I are gonna do in the room.
Rym: Lee reviews a full review of it this weekend, but Zootopia Probably the best Disney movie in 20 years and 20 years.
Scott: Yeah, let me see what's happened.
Scott: 20 years ago was 96. yeah, you're gonna go like when did Lion King Aladdin come?
Rym: uh when did they come out?
Rym: probably before then?
Rym: I've lost track of all that Yep, so uh you know what.
Rym: yeah better than line.
Scott: Aladdin was 92.
Rym: Yeah, all right all right.
Rym: so Lion King Aladdin are beyond the horizon.
Scott: a Disney movie since 96.
Rym: Aladdin and the Lion King.
Rym: Let's see here.
Rym: I get a list of every Disney movie, so let's see 95.
Rym: Toy Story was 95 That's not 96.
Rym: Yeah, 96.
Rym: James the giant peach.
Rym: no the hunchback of Notre Dame Hercules.
Scott: well I mean you got.
Scott: if you're Hercules you got to go to a story to Toy Story 3.
Rym: all right all right.
Scott: Toy Story 2 All those others all those other Pixar movies Dinosaur.
Rym: oh So I really like the Emperor's New Groove.
Scott: Yeah, I think that movies overrated.
Rym: I think it's the best Disney movie other than Zootopia in that era.
Rym: what about that?
Rym: may be like Toy Story 2 3.
Rym: Lilo & Stitch was super good.
Rym: all right Might be better than Lilo & Stitch by a tiny hair.
Rym: get it anyway.
Scott: What else is down there?
Rym: Tales of Earth?
Rym: oh, that's just yeah tales of Earth.
Rym: the Ghibli so Tangled was really good.
Rym: Yeah, Mars Needs Moms not not gonna.
Rym: Brave is pretty good.
Rym: Wreck-It Ralph is pretty good.
Rym: Frozen was okay.
Rym: I Actually almost why.
Rym: well, I guess this is also mixing Pixar and Walt Disney Studios.
Scott: Well, I mean isn't Zootopia Pixar movie.
Rym: No everyone keeps saying that it's not okay.
Scott: That's interesting.
Scott: It's a Disney Studios movie, so why is it all CG and not all 2d.
Rym: It's animated all right In fact.
Rym: uh you were I think 90% of the people I've talked to about this movie assumed It was Pixar incorrectly.
Scott: what other CG movies has Disney made that weren't Pixar?
Rym: Emily's shouting from the other room correcting Scott heavily, but I digress.
Rym: Zootopia is Crazy good, and I would not say that lightly because I go into movies like this.
Scott: It was funny.
Rym: Yeah, so Then you know there's always the worry if a trailer is pretty good like that.
Rym: like will the movie be as good?
Scott: Usually you put your best joke in the trailer.
Rym: Yeah, the movie did far from that.
Rym: so Zootopia Exceeded my expectations in a way that I can.
Rym: I can name very few movies that have ever actually Legitimately exceeded my expectations to that degree and I already came in with pretty high ones.
Rym: so What I'll say is that it deals with issues of discrimination very pointedly and in a Surprisingly elegant and nuanced way.
Rym: I am deeply impressed with this movie and all I'm gonna say is that you should definitely go see it If you haven't seen it already.
Rym: also it appears to be on track to break some box-office records.
Rym: It's going crazy in the theater.
Scott: Well there haven't been you know a movie that got the kids out to the theater since like frozen me so
Rym: so Funny when we were at the theater the audience was about a third families with kids on a Sunday like evening show And the rest of it
Scott: was em furries.
Rym: Yeah, the rest of it was all adults like us, right?
Scott: I mean you know that's what's happening these days.
Scott: Yeah, I mean like a movie is gonna get the most people in cuz you get the families and the nerds like yeah A good dichotomy.
Rym: you'll see is there's those equestria girls movies that sometimes are in theaters.
Rym: That's pretty much all little kids.
Rym: But when the right the actual My Little Pony feature film comes out pretty sure whenever I go to see it It's gonna be mostly people around my age in that theater.
Scott: Yeah, I'll go see that.
Scott: Yeah, actually based on gonna see in the theater the whole getting DVD.
Rym: Oh I might see in the theater just because I want to see it early cuz you know weebs are gonna ruin it By telling me everything about it, how's that gonna ruin it?
Rym: uh yeah, you have your weird spoiler opinion that I still disagree with.
Rym: I'm not saying spoilers are the biggest deal in the world, but you take a Somewhat narrow view of it.
Rym: anyway Go see.
Scott: something can be ruined by learning information, but it was not good in the first place.
Rym: no But the experience is different.
Rym: the second time you see movie Someone better when you know more now why not see it twice, and then you get both experiences.
Scott: They are both different because the first I could just learn everything about it And then see it.
Scott: it'll be a great experience, and I only had to pay waste my time once.
Rym: Uh I guess if wasting your time is how you treat watching movies.
Rym: then go nuts anyway.
Rym: go see Zootopia.
Rym: It is utterly fantastic and nuanced to a degree that I did not expect.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: it's like if a food is delicious right is it?
Scott: is it not delicious the first time and the second time is different.
Rym: God there are very few movies that I watch more than three or four times.
Rym: But I eat ice cream hundreds and hundreds of times in my life.
Scott: Huh was it?
Scott: was the ice cream spoiled that the second time you ate it.
Rym: It was very as a different experience because the first time I had never experienced that before.
Scott: so there's Delicious the second time.
Rym: I don't have a tongue orgasm the hundreds time I ate ice cream But I probably had one the first time.
Scott: no I'm pretty sure a tongue orgasm every time.
Rym: I still disagree with you.
Rym: anyway Do you have any news?
Rym: since you're the reason we have to review Zootopia on the patreon is cuz you're probably not gonna see It.
Scott: why would I go to the movie theater to see that you don't see any movies anymore.
Scott: I see a lot of movies.
Scott: I watched every Zatoichi.
Scott: Yeah, you watch a lot of 26 movies to your one movie.
Rym: Well, then maybe you should do a patreon and review them all.
Scott: maybe I shouldn't because no it's not worth paying money for But you can watch all.
Scott: you can watch all the Zatoichi movies on Hulu for zero dollars.
Scott: You should do that.
Rym: I'm curious how many of you would pay a dollar to listen to Scott review all the Zatoichi movies.
Scott: Stupid people.
Scott: All right, if you've got a dollar for that, you should just invest the dollar.
Rym: There's a website I went to today that's got a dollar will make you rounding zero dollars over your entire life.
Scott: That is correct ever.
Scott: I went to a website today that said if you invested a dollar every day of your life How much would you have invested?
Scott: because how many days have you lived and how much would that be now?
Scott: And if I had done that I would have spent like twelve thousand dollars and I would have about fifty five thousand dollars right now.
Rym: Yeah, but about dollar that's just like thirty bucks a month.
Rym: That's what most people are putting away into like their 401ks because I don't have a lot of money.
Scott: I'm putting a lot more than thirty dollars.
Rym: Most people are putting any maximum Maximum allowed percentage.
Rym: Anyway, do you have any animation or comic news?
Scott: Yes, the speaking of Hulu where you can watch all 26 25 Zatoichi movies.
Scott: You can also watch best they put it on there like less than a week ago all 25 or 26 episodes of Azumanga die.
Scott: Oh, you know again, I watched two episodes and That show is still good.
Scott: But you know what?
Scott: It's kind of weird because compared to my memory It's the exact same show except for two things.
Scott: number one Something being in a non widescreen aspect ratio and like 480 not non widescreen is a lot like laugh tracks now Not P at all and some of the drawings are not that they looked really good back then But now it's like there's some definitely bad drawing.
Rym: I had that problem the other day when you know Cuz the new Powerpuff Girls is coming and I watched one of the shorts they did.
Rym: it was great.
Rym: So I went back and watched one of my favorite old episodes of the Powerpuff Girls.
Rym: It was good, but it was weird to see something so low-res and in a square effectively.
Scott: Yeah, by the way in the new Powerpuff Girls trailer You know, it is confirmed.
Scott: the most important thing that makes me know that shows gonna be good as good as the old one At least is that.
Rym: yeah, of course him was there.
Rym: him is the best part of the Powerpuff Girls.
Scott: I wasn't sure they were gonna keep him.
Rym: Well, the second best part the best part is that the professor's kind of a doofus Him is still in.
Scott: Yeah, that's what we need to know.
Scott: Oh, so yeah, the other thing about Azumanga die Besides the square shape is that that show is really disjointed.
Scott: I mean it was always based on like yeah the four panel comics, but it's like The episodes just like all way more.
Scott: there were always all over the place But they're even more all over the place than I remember.
Rym: I guess that's kind of what I remember and expected.
Scott: Of course, I have also.
Scott: everything else is still true.
Scott: Like the drunk teachers the best.
Rym: Yeah Oh, it's like I with that knife.
Rym: Yeah, or when she's in the bathroom constantly.
Scott: Oh my god I just remember that.
Scott: get it together.
Scott: I just remember the screensaver.
Scott: Yeah, I Was like I'm walking around the CG room doing stuff.
Rym: Yeah We had that on both our computers in RIT for a long time.
Rym: Good days.
Scott: Maybe I can find that and run it.
Scott: Will it run on Windows 10?
Rym: I think the other reason that I'm not surprised by the disjointedness or I guess like I wouldn't I don't think that would be Something that I would have forgotten and then go.
Rym: Oh, right Is that I basically watched all of Nichijou which does the same thing and I also really like Nichijou.
Rym: It's kind of in the same genre.
Scott: I only watched like two episodes of Nichijou and I didn't see any goats getting somersault.
Rym: You should watch all of Nichijou.
Scott: I couldn't even tell what was going on in the two episodes I watched.
Rym: there are pretty straightforward short narratives.
Scott: It's usually something like I don't like introduce the characters though.
Scott: Okay, I'm just like.
Scott: I'm just like who the hell is this?
Rym: Star Wars did such a great job of introducing all the characters.
Scott: Azumanga Daioh does a good job of introducing the characters Because it has more of a very hard.
Scott: the very first scene is they show after the teacher You know crashes or drops your chain off her bike and they get to the classroom.
Scott: They show you each person and show you their name on the screen and it's like Tomo-chan the crazy You know Genius, you know prodigy.
Scott: in GeoChat.
Scott: They tell you each person is.
Scott: and then the second episode is just an introduction of Osaka.
Scott: The whole second episode is Osaka omen Things of the day.
Rym: Emily found this last night and it's that's good because she's better fun things really really really good.
Rym: So red line was an amazing movie.
Rym: We reviewed on GeekNights some time ago.
Rym: It's not my favorite anime movies Like the more I think about it.
Rym: pretty good just it's that kind of weird movie that I like.
Rym: that is not.
Scott: I only watched it once.
Scott: I feel like I should watch it one more time because I can.
Rym: it's why it's a movie.
Rym: I feel like I could watch matrix level number of times and never get tired of it.
Scott: I don't know if I watch it that many times.
Scott: think I could.
Scott: I should watch the matrix and I go.
Scott: So this is an AMV to Red line isn't it the whole thing on AMV to begin with?
Scott: is it really necessary to make AMV out of it?
Rym: Well, this AMV does a very good job.
Rym: 5 5 5 AMV.
Rym: There's two fundamental kinds of AMVs on this level.
Rym: There's the AMV that just takes the aesthetic of a show and does something with it And there's an AMV that retells the show or retells the movie With the backdrop of music almost like a summary.
Rym: This is more like the latter kind.
Rym: So if you've never seen red line go watch red line first Then watch this AMV.
Rym: It's one of those AMVs that reminds you how fucking amazing red line is.
Scott: Yeah, just watch Oh, baby, baby.
Rym: Yeah Because that actually doesn't really spoil anything significant about utana Even if it does.
Scott: but you wouldn't understand like you wouldn't know what the fuck you're seeing.
Scott: It's more like it hints at whoa The show goes way off the rails down the road and also it's got you know, some Sega Saturn actions Like you see someone fighting and like they're gonna duel and they might not not anyway, the Thing of the day, right?
Scott: So someone made this funny video cowboy beep boop beep boop beep boop.
Scott: It's a little funny kind of like retelling of an early episode of cowboy bebop the one with the ventriloquist dummy That's like alive but as a person but isn't or whatever, you know, they're the kid who looks like one but it's young.
Scott: You should see that episode.
Scott: It's actually one of the I think not as good episodes a cowboy bebop.
Rym: I would agree with that.
Scott: But here I mean not that you know, even the worst episode of cowboy bebop is great Like other people don't like the chess one.
Scott: I like that.
Rym: Well, it has the problem of that.
Rym: It's in that Twilight Zone between the first episode and the fifth episode that everyone goes.
Rym: Oh shit It's in the Twilight Zone between cowboy bebop and Batman.
Scott: But yeah So but someone retells that episode in like a few seconds with this quirky little not even animation like Animatic almost just some pencil drawings and some voiceover.
Scott: good and it's still way funny.
Scott: It's like it's like a gift plus plus.
Scott: It's worth your 10 seconds of time Beep-boop in the meta moment.
Rym: The book club book is probably gonna be Oryx and Craig Margaret Atwood.
Rym: So stay tuned.
Rym: I haven't announced it yet.
Scott: Yeah, no good ideas.
Scott: You're on your.
Scott: still my ideas.
Rym: I got that idea from Emily and Adam and Kate not from you.
Scott: I got the idea cuz I kept hearing Margaret at was named like a hundred times.
Scott: Yeah Adam and Kate more people than that But yes them also else.
Rym: name one other human being who brought that book up something on internet such as someone Some guy in the internet.
Scott: I saw some tweets or something.
Scott: Plus there was that video where she was a hockey goalie.
Rym: No, yeah, which was my thing of the day.
Scott: It's fine.
Scott: Doesn't matter?
Scott: I kept hearing it a bunch and I said, all right next book club book.
Scott: I get I'm picking one of your books and then you come in Picking one her books.
Scott: now, I got to find something else like a different one of her books.
Scott: We're not doing the same author twice in a row.
Rym: Why not?
Scott: That's not allowed.
Rym: I'll just do.
Rym: I'll just do every Prince of Nothing book one by one.
Scott: No, we got spread some love love must be spread But I haven't announced it officially.
Scott: she doesn't deserve two picks.
Rym: I'm saying no one deserved two picks cuz I kind of started the 11th book of the Wheel of Time.
Rym: I'm finding out more about what Randall tour is up to.
Rym: I get spoilers.
Rym: He's still alive.
Scott: You don't say yeah The main character lives to all the books and you only can die in the last one.
Rym: actually is anyone know?
Rym: So I'm so I haven't read the end.
Rym: So this is not a spoiler.
Scott: if you're a main character You can't die until the end of the book at the final book.
Scott: That's how things work.
Rym: Ah, yeah, you can Really?
Scott: Okay, so That's dead is what you're saying.
Rym: It's not a spoiler because well, he died and then came back.
Scott: Yeah, that's a shame.
Rym: But anyway, it's not a spoiler cuz I didn't read the end yet.
Rym: I don't know what happens.
Rym: I'm pretty sure.
Rym: lose Theron in his head will die and Rand will not and that's the like thing that's gonna happen at the end.
Scott: Or ran will die and lose their hero.
Rym: Yeah, there's kind of a dick.
Scott: That's my guy.
Scott: Yeah a Really powerful dick, dude That's always the best character the really powerful jerk, right?
Scott: Yeah, or like the legendary.
Scott: Whoa, that guy's so strong right like in one piece.
Scott: You don't give a show.
Scott: Okay, Scott red shanks is the man It's already.
Rym: there's a car.
Scott: who is the who's?
Scott: the pirate that's in the opener who actually found the one piece and hit it.
Scott: That guy.
Scott: Oh, yeah, that's the best guy right you will like.
Rym: this is one character.
Rym: I don't know what book she comes in.
Rym: Her name's like Codswine or something But she's an as did I who's super fucking old so old that everyone thought she was dead and apparently she's one of the heroes Of legends.
Scott: Yeah, so she comes back like she was friends with the king of Man of Theron who's also a badass.
Rym: Well, not that old.
Rym: Okay, but basically she comes back and every as that eyes like holy shit, and they're afraid of her.
Rym: Yeah, she goes up to Randall door basically punches in the face.
Rym: be like listen you shithead.
Rym: That's what's up.
Scott: Yeah, you gold lady.
Rym: Yeah, that seemed like book seven or six.
Rym: I don't even know.
Rym: it all just blurs.
Scott: Yoda Yoda's pretty good Badasses.
Scott: no one wants your lame-ass weak asses.
Rym: Otherwise stay tuned on the patreon for me and Emily's really review of Zootopia or save your money and don't we're gonna be.
Scott: add We're gonna make those things if you don't pay.
Scott: so if you all stop paying he'll just have to make those things public.
Rym: No, I probably wouldn't make him.
Scott: He would still make probably not.
Scott: he can't help him Scott.
Rym: It's warm outside.
Scott: You're not gonna make any.
Scott: that's the other thing you keep paying in the summer, you're not gonna get your money's worth.
Rym: Go for a video of me if I can to work.
Scott: you're gonna get nothing for your money in the summer.
Scott: hold stop pay Even if you're dumb enough to pay.
Rym: don't pay until it gets cold again, but we should be at anime Boston.
Rym: We should be.
Scott: I guess we're going.
Rym: Yeah, we're doing our usual gamut of panels.
Scott: We'll eat secret breakfast.
Rym: Yep, we'll be doing a zinc icon or at least I will.
Scott: Scott probably will Check my tomorrow, I'm gonna check my work days off thing.
Scott: Not that I don't.
Rym: I'm not taking a day off Not that I after work.
Scott: I'm saying not that I don't have enough days off It's just am I going to use them, you know, I'm gonna have.
Scott: I entered them.
Rym: I'm not taking Friday off.
Rym: I'm going Friday after work.
Rym: I'm coming back Sunday.
Scott: What a waste of.
Rym: I'll see One day and be really drunken surly the next day and then go home.
Rym: Mm-hmm Also, Anthony and Chris will be there and Ross and everyone.
Rym: so poor games poor games the whole time.
Scott: Maybe I'll bring my board game.
Rym: Yeah PAX East will be doing Atari game design one of our most recent lectures designing game rules, which People really seem to like this one.
Rym: And actually I watched it cuz I had to edit it.
Rym: It's pretty good panel.
Rym: Like we do a job.
Rym: I'm actually I'm proud of it.
Rym: It's in the.
Rym: it's in the top 10 panels.
Rym: We did a better job of it at magfest though Yeah, and I think we didn't record it there because we're like every video did.
Rym: who cares?
Scott: I was just too lazy.
Rym: Yeah, laziness is a big part of that but it's up on YouTube.
Rym: you can watch it.
Scott: There's no point in posting the same panel twice.
Rym: I posted the same panel twice a few times if we've crooked enough.
Scott: Yeah, make it time.
Rym: Beyond D&D is up twice because it evolved a lot between those early times and when we did it at PAX OS.
Scott: So our man mom or hosted continues to bet a thousand, you know, if you don't know who mom or hosted it is Right.
Scott: This is a guy who directed a bunch of animes and he sort of got really going with his Digimon movie.
Scott: We've is one piece movie.
Rym: We've reviewed most of the feature films.
Rym: He has ever done.
Scott: I don't think we reviewed girl who that through time.
Rym: I'm pretty sure we did.
Scott: if we didn't I cuz I don't think I've seen it.
Rym: I saw it with that.
Rym: You know what Emily and I can review it.
Scott: then on the patreon and I don't think Did he do the wolf children?
Scott: Is that?
Rym: yeah, there was wolf children.
Scott: I didn't see that one either.
Rym: You didn't see wolf children now, and then we saw summer wars Which was three years before Wolf children.
Scott: Yeah, and What else did he do besides bullying the Beast which we're talking about today?
Rym: Uh, one piece Baron.
Scott: Oh, not sorry I mentioned that already.
Scott: we reviewed that.
Rym: Yeah, I think he did the the anime opening samurai shampoo.
Rym: He did something with the opening.
Scott: I mean that doesn't.
Scott: I'm talking about like movies.
Scott: He's made.
Scott: He's a movie guy.
Scott: now Come to New York because he's already working on another movie.
Scott: He's like cranking him out.
Rym: Well Scott, if you're talking movies, the only other thing really in there is that super flat modding at Rym Which isn't really a movie.
Scott: just know it's not really okay, so that's all his movies.
Scott: So his new movie is the.
Scott: that's out is the boy and the Beast.
Scott: you can see in theaters in the US now.
Rym: Every one of his movies has been on a trajectory of increasingly furry and the trend has continued.
Rym: Girl at their time zero.
Rym: He is some wars the girls of kitsune in the in the magic space wolf children.
Rym: Yep, boy and the Beast.
Scott: Yep What was this wasn't his movie?
Scott: What was that movie?
Scott: It was like a fantasy Furries but not you know perverted ones and it was like that ballerina animal and there was like an adventure thing You're thinking of.
Scott: I'm not imagining this right.
Rym: No, you're.
Scott: I Think it was one of those ones where someone goes to another world.
Rym: Why story?
Scott: oh, yeah.
Scott: Okay that one aspects of hostedness in it.
Scott: Whoever made it?
Rym: Anyway, but yeah member host is batting a thousand in the sense that while not every movie He has made has been a home run then a thousand just means you hit every ball.
Scott: Yeah, it's like every movie you make is a really good movie.
Scott: We're seeing.
Rym: yep So the TLC are better than others.
Rym: like we said, this is an anime movie.
Rym: It came out recently.
Rym: It's really good and you should definitely go see it.
Rym: if you care at all about anime or animation.
Rym: If you happen to like wolf children summer wars the girl who left through time You should really go see this movie because it is in his fashion like the kinds of things he's done before.
Scott: Yeah, it's like there's some people like Miyazaki or Satoshi khan where every time they get up to the plate home run.
Scott: Maru hosted it.
Scott: It's like every time he gets up to the plate he hits Sometimes home runs sometimes just double.
Rym: I think Satoshi khan is the only Anime director to have literally only hit home runs.
Scott: I think so.
Scott: Even Miyazaki is sometimes hit non-home run.
Scott: Well, you said Miyazaki which could include go And Tezuka is just the guy with so many at-bats that even though he strikes out sometimes his total numbers He's like how fast he's like.
Scott: he's like Cal Ripken, right?
Scott: He just goes.
Scott: he just keeps playing.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, but yeah, so the Boy and the Beast is actually two hours long.
Scott: Yeah, so this movie is like way long But on the one hand it's like you think something that's so long will get drawn out.
Scott: But no, it's like the pacing was like the biggest thing I noticed and the first thing I thought of when it was over Because it keeps moving along.
Scott: There's no point in which it drags.
Scott: There was a part where I thought it was gonna like Yeah suddenly become.
Scott: there's like this major point in the movie where it's like, okay Now we're going in a quest to visit all the Beast Kings and all the different Beast kingdoms, but BAM It was a montage.
Scott: They just breezed right over that and I'm like, is that?
Rym: and then my exactly like brave story.
Scott: And at first I thought it was gonna just be a traveling montage.
Scott: But no they montaged over every single right through all the Beast Kings and I'm like, whoa Now that is moving right along here.
Rym: We'll avoid spoilers at least till the end because it's anime.
Rym: We just go see it.
Rym: But the one thing I will say is this movie the trailers and all the stuff I saw at this point Didn't really tell you shit about what it was about.
Scott: No, I had.
Rym: no I couldn't and that's a good thing because it covers some ground.
Scott: Yeah, it goes.
Scott: it's like it keeps moving along at this pace and where you're not dragging on any one part for too long right.
Scott: and Just when I think this things like it's heading to the climax part like, you know 75% of the way through I didn't know how far we were in right, but it felt like okay Here's the climax the thing we've been waiting for since the beginning the battle to see who's gonna be the new You know Lord of the Beast Kingdom.
Scott: here it is and I'm like, wait a minute.
Scott: There's like this big thing that is an obvious foreshadow.
Scott: There's a Chekhov's gun that hasn't fired.
Scott: that has nothing to do with this Chekhov's well Moby Dick.
Scott: yeah, there's a Chekhov's character who hasn't resolved their deal and it won't be resolved in this climax part.
Scott: and This is being movies been going on for a long time
Rym: now unlike Well constructed movies that Chekhov's characters gun like the I'm like character almost
Scott: felt like something that would be resolved in another Episode or another movie later and not this movie and I hadn't looked at a clock But it felt like it'd been going on so long.
Scott: I'm like it's got to end now.
Scott: but no that they kept going after that climax and fired that Chekhov's character and had the real the real climax after that and That character is one more act.
Rym: a less well done movie would have had a lot more telegraphing of what that was all gonna be about.
Rym: this one had a few context clues and Mostly it was.
Rym: it was Chekhov's back.
Scott: I don't know I don't know how many acts there were but at the end of the second to last act There was the climax and then the final act I didn't even know was gonna happen.
Rym: I thought that second last act was the last one but like in a bad movie that was like the characters holding the gun.
Rym: This was more like in Who's Afraid of Virginia Wolf where the gun is on the mantle in the background.
Rym: You can see it there, but no one's saying anything about it.
Scott: Yep Alright, so the deal with this movie this boy.
Scott: and there's a beast and the beast is awesome beast.
Rym: Okay, it's here.
Rym: He's from the land of beasts.
Scott: The Beast is basically Toshiro Mifune from Seven Samurai.
Rym: Yeah, pretty much.
Scott: Right?
Scott: Well then in mannerism in in Every aspect of this person Right and he's in the Beast Kingdom and he's competing to become the new Lord of the Beast Kingdom when they super awesome Current Lord of the Beast Kingdom is the best character.
Rym: Oh my god that rabbit.
Scott: He's basically the grandma from summer wars.
Scott: He's got to compete against the also awesome, but opposite personality got beast Who's like a sort of a bore, right?
Rym: Yeah Who is well a neat tidy organized a good person in every possible aspect?
Scott: Yeah, the other Sam, you know the lead samurai in the seven Sam, right?
Scott: Yeah, I forget his name, but he's a lot of Curaçao movies.
Scott: But anyway, so they're gonna compete to become you know, the new Lord of the Beast Kingdom.
Rym: But anyway, so independently next to all this is Tokyo Japan modern-day Japan and a kid runs away from home.
Scott: Well, so the kid doesn't just run away from home, right?
Scott: His parents are dead.
Scott: He's good He's living with like some step pair, you know some like mom's Parents or so his family's rich Sure, but he's a family.
Scott: He doesn't like that doesn't like him right?
Scott: It's almost a oh What the hell was that anime that's good, but then becomes perverted.
Scott: What is it one with the that still doesn't narrow down.
Scott: no He is the girl who's like grandpa's daughter and he adopts her.
Rym: Oh We did.
Rym: we reviewed it on anime Boston.
Rym: Yeah in the end they sex.
Scott: Well, yeah, but that's in the manga and I stopped watching buddy.
Scott: Yeah, yeah bunny drop, right?
Scott: It's like others.
Rym: they sex.
Scott: Yeah, it's a bunny drop situation without the sex part.
Scott: Right only runs away from home instead of living with this family that doesn't really care about him that much.
Scott: They they seem to want to take care of him.
Scott: They're like, oh you'll be taken care of and whatever but doesn't seem like there's any love or caring in that relationship.
Rym: right runs away and has a little bit of Personal drama around that in shades of perhaps nurse little Kayla Gwynn novel.
Rym: So he stumbles into the Beast Kingdom and but it's just on the other side of an alley from Tokyo.
Scott: Yeah, and the Beast Kingdom is a metaphorical kingdom, but it's also a totally literal Kingdom.
Scott: It's a literal place.
Rym: Now that is actually literally my favorite part of this movie.
Scott: Yeah, you thought you could have easily done this.
Scott: We're like, oh, it's a hallucination.
Scott: Oh, it's it's.
Scott: um, what's the movie with the guy in the boat with the tiger?
Rym: Life up high.
Scott: Yeah, where the whole thing's a metaphor and he wasn't really on a boat with a tiger, right?
Rym: One could argue that he was sure right metaphorical.
Scott: This is literally yes There is a Beast Kingdom and a real Tokyo of modern day and they both really exist for real and Hosanna goes out of his Way to make sure you cannot interpret this as anything.
Rym: but this is the literal reality.
Scott: now You can't be like, oh the Beast Kingdom was just like a dream for like and it was a metaphor for the orphanage He was in or something.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: no there was a Beast Kingdom.
Scott: He was raised by this beast, right?
Scott: He was the beasts, uh, you know, what's it called?
Scott: Student student.
Rym: Yeah, you're you're forgetting every written words tonight.
Scott: Yeah words.
Scott: It's warm out.
Scott: I'm not thinking about being in here doing a podcast but instead of like it is literally the reality.
Rym: But that literal reality of this animated world is itself heavy allegory.
Scott: The word was a student is apprentice, right?
Scott: Yeah, the Beast needs apprentices to like, you know become the Lord of beasts, which he wants to be for some reason.
Scott: That's the one part that's confusing.
Scott: Why does he want to be the Lord of beasts?
Rym: you feel like he wants to be because he's expected to want to be.
Rym: I think he doesn't want to get shown up.
Scott: Yeah, I think it's mostly he just wants to fight the other guy and Wayne.
Scott: I don't think he actually wants to be the Lord of the beats And no one else seems to want him to be either.
Scott: The other guy would actually probably be a better Lord.
Rym: The same time they're all kind of anyway, you know, it's interesting.
Rym: the Beast world basically perfect.
Rym: Yeah, basically like no one appears to want for anything.
Rym: Everyone's happy all the time.
Rym: as far as you can tell It's almost a Miyazaki thing, right?
Scott: We're like the place that is low-tech is And you know is all traditional is all happy and peaceful.
Scott: Yeah, you know, it's sort of like a dr.
Scott: Seuss thing, too.
Scott: It's like oh, yeah the place with the factory that eats up all the tough of the trees is bad in the place You know same deal.
Rym: Yeah, but at the same time that's a magic.
Scott: land is all happy and perfect life.
Scott: And the human world has darkness.
Rym: Yeah Well, well human cell phone because humans have darkness inherent in them and beasts do not have similar inherent darkness.
Scott: But I guess the human world has light in the library.
Scott: The library is a nice place in the human world Yeah, but it's hard to without because they're.
Rym: this movie covers so much ground.
Rym: you really should just see it.
Rym: Yeah and I don't want to get into Why.
Rym: it's important that the human world and the beast world are both literal realities and how that ties into Pretty much.
Scott: what you can expect from this movie is you know, the awesome sort of general apprentice Adventure kind of thing with you know, the you know, the apprentice being better than the master in some ways and whatnot?
Scott: learning You know, but the mat the master while being goofy is also, you know wise in other ways, right?
Scott: You know pretty typical expected sort of relationship there, you know growing up thing.
Scott: But then once grown up, you know resolving of plots that were there.
Scott: since you know The beginning part it's like aha you actually it wasn't just the girl up.
Scott: end of movie.
Scott: you're grown up now Congratulations.
Scott: It was you grew up.
Scott: now you can do the quest and we have time so we're gonna fucking do it.
Rym: Yeah so the movie is despite also being very serious and having very heavy allegory that Full disclosure might be a little too close to home for some people in the audience.
Rym: Oh It is also legitimately Outright hilarious at points.
Rym: It is a really funny movie.
Scott: Just and Bennett's the humor is and they don't stop the humor until that very final act right right up.
Scott: But even that climax I talked about in the second to last act still has humors in it But it's clever like.
Rym: the humor reminds me actually of a lot of those Mufune type samurai movies that like that kind of humor.
Rym: A lot of it is.
Scott: well a lot of the humor comes from the monkey guy and the monk.
Rym: Well, like there's the moment and he's like, what should I call you?
Rym: Well, you're nine years old, right?
Rym: I'll call you cute.
Rym: Ah, right you're not.
Scott: and there's also these three sort of Like these guys that are sort of like these side characters way out like double side characters But they're basically the exact same characters.
Scott: is the three old guys in cowboy beep-boop.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Yep Okay, there's 100% and they provide some humor humorous interjections as well, right?
Rym: But there's clever humor constantly and the Beast Lord is never not funny He's pretty much a hundred percent funny, I mean everyone's great I don't.
Rym: Movie is just delightful.
Scott: There's not a lot of humor in the human world.
Scott: It's not a funny place true It's a place where kids are orphaned, right?
Rym: But the overall when I guess you know the whole literal reality of it What makes the movie go from just being really enjoyable and delightful to being I think a really good movie Is that the allegory is very well presented and the allegory primarily has to do with you know?
Rym: nature versus nurture?
Rym: to a degree Who is your family?
Rym: You know the the combination of blood versus who raised you?
Rym: how do you like?
Rym: What is the difference?
Rym: the relationship with an estranged family member?
Rym: Perhaps?
Rym: How do you start that up to?
Rym: How do you carry the memory of perhaps lost family members in your heart?
Rym: And how does that change you as a person?
Rym: How do you show compassion to people who had a different upbringing that left darkness in their heart?
Rym: Right literal darkness in this case that turns into psychic death powers.
Scott: It also covers the same topics that like 50% of Japanese movies I've seen.
Scott: cover which is like should you live as you've been expected to live by your parents in society or live your own life?
Scott: and taking tests And all those sorts of things right You know?
Scott: should you be that you know person who has all your shit together?
Scott: You?
Scott: should you be that wild person you know who lets loose yep?
Rym: And it's it.
Rym: very elegantly takes all these different allegorical threads and Weaves them together into one story.
Scott: one coherent story.
Rym: Yeah One all over the place story like a really coherent story like it comes around full circle in the end Almost shockingly because of how long it was and how many threads that opened.
Rym: it's kind of amazing to see them all collapse back together.
Scott: Yep, the animations are like top tier.
Rym: Oh those fights the fight scenes right.
Scott: the only thing I got to say though is all the animations were the top tier.
Scott: I say some of the drawings like the Backgrounds were the second tier because like for example the clouds.
Scott: They're not you know.
Scott: They're not the top tier class.
Scott: Right we know who we're thinking it.
Rym: What's up?
Rym: certain centimeters per second clouds.
Scott: We know who makes the best clouds.
Rym: I promise no early days clouds.
Scott: These are the second best class.
Scott: all right you know, but yeah the animation is still incredible right?
Scott: You know it looks like they drew it with computers, but it's still 2d.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: it's not a CGs in any way All right, so are you looking for these clouds?
Rym: Yeah?
Rym: Clouds right there.
Rym: look at that one the real clouds right.
Scott: yeah, so you know you know it's.
Scott: it's pretty much You know the best 2d animations you're gonna see from Japan.
Scott: It doesn't look like a Ghibli movie But it looks as good as it's gonna be just in a different style than Ghibli style.
Rym: right I did really enjoy the style because Actually because of the Beast world.
Scott: But and they did with the human beast world in the human world have totally different styles right and totally different colors.
Scott: But every character in the world is totally dark usually even like and they don't really go to the human world a lot during daytime.
Scott: Very rarely do they go to the human world during daytime and usually it's like really tight shots.
Scott: So it'll be you know poorly lit or like.
Scott: you'll see the Sun going down and in the Beast world It seems like it's just like always.
Scott: daytime I don't.
Scott: you don't see a lot of night shots But it's usually indoors with candles and stuff and lights on in the Beast world at night It's you don't see a lot of like dark places in the Beast world.
Scott: They're not going around in caves or anything like that right even when it becomes nighttime.
Scott: It's like a well-lit festival kind of atmosphere all the time and bright colors.
Rym: But that style let him.
Rym: every single character is deeply distinct both in personality and appearance Which actually lets the characters be very strong?
Rym: Which actually is one of the things that really pushes the movie forward and prevents it from sort of For a movie this long with this kind of subject matter like Scott said it feels like it's on the edge of dragging Every second and then it always Steers.
Scott: you feel like something's gonna be dragging out, but they don't I know.
Scott: the reason they can avoid dragging is Usually they'd be like a lot of movies will like have unexplained things.
Scott: right this and this movie Just bothers not to make things questionable.
Scott: see they're not left unexplained.
Scott: for example You just goes to this Beast world right in another movie.
Scott: You might think how is the Beast world in the human world connected?
Scott: I need to know more about this.
Scott: This doesn't make a lot of sense, but in this movie.
Scott: It's like beasts and humans to just go back and forth.
Scott: It's like a physical tunnel you just to walk through it or something whatever and you don't.
Scott: you're not questioning that right It's just there, and it's not like a mystery.
Scott: So because it's not a mystery you don't need to dedicate any time to explaining it.
Scott: you just show it happening And you're done.
Scott: yep And by doing it does that with like a whole bunch of different things So that you only things you're thinking about are like these core plots that they're gonna spend.
Scott: actually you know dedicate Seconds of you know film to.
Rym: so so if I had any complaint about this movie at all.
Rym: it would be that The dialogue in the fourth fifth of the movie like before the climax But kind of ab.
Rym: so after the fight and the sort of big like game-changing moving to the end of the movie event and The actual end there's this middle part where a lot of characters spend a lot of time sort of explaining things to each other.
Rym: and That is the only time in the movie where it sort of did the characters talking as opposed to just showing you something and letting You smart enough to figure it out.
Scott: And there's a lot of like it felt like a lot of the things they were saying didn't matter or they were repeating.
Rym: the same People complain that oh the dub must have been a bad script because the characters kept repeating themselves and like we're saying sort of inane Or obvious thing.
Scott: we didn't see the dub by the way.
Rym: yes But I saw that sentiment from multiple people.
Scott: it is it has been dubbed.
Scott: so if you see it in the u.s.
Scott: It might be dubbed.
Rym: yep But I didn't know that at least in the subtitled version that we saw those same scenes Just as draggy kind of pointless dialogue.
Scott: right like he goes sees He sees the girl in the library, and then he sees her again And I think he sees her like I can't remember how many times But they pretty much what feels like they had the same conversation every time right?
Scott: yeah, it didn't feel like they were Advancing much other than okay.
Scott: They saw each other again But yet the movie did.
Rym: other aspects like the other four fifths of the movie Did the read.
Rym: they really did a good job of showing and not having a character explain it like the Chekhov's gun character who is?
Rym: Obviously a human Like but nothing is said about that.
Rym: the characters just doing just thing.
Rym: and then there's one scene Where that character is older and his brother is like futzing with his tusks cuz he knows a born.
Rym: is this real toss?
Rym: He's just kind of futzing with it, and it cuts to him, and he's kind of covering his mouth with the scarf.
Rym: And I told you literally everything you needed to know about the characters their interactions the gun Chekhov is hanging out there in that tooth.
Rym: and Then the rest of the movie.
Rym: it was characters explaining to you where the guns were and when they were gonna go off and why?
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: So yeah, I mean if this is playing anywhere near you go see it.
Scott: If not, it'll be on DVD way soon.
Scott: probably you can see that and you should definitely.
Scott: It'll probably be streaming somewhere right you know you got within the year.
Scott: everyone listening to this will be able to see this movie Pretty without much difficulty, and it's worth your two hours of time.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: The patrons for this episode of GeekNights are in order of the amount of money They gave us on a continuing basis Nicholas Brando Rebecca Dunn John our knobs.
Rym: the second Amanda douchette James David white Christian coon's Jess mechanical mind William Eisen rose Jeremy minor.
Rym: you expect the next name to be yours But it was me.
Rym: do.
Rym: Shawn Yeager Clinton Walton my state II.
Rym: calm run from New Zealand.
Rym: Robert Lee Ryan Perrin drew Openlander rare Lavelle Brian Cedroni Rochelle, Montana.
Rym: Then Eric.
Rym: silver.
Rym: odd can't melt steel beams.
Rym: kinetic man Aaron Cerise Chris midkiff Chris Knox Trump Cruz 2016.
Rym: I've thought carefully and I'm still going to pay Daniel Redmond.
Rym: Chris had odd Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: You know usually Many of you will comment on my choice of odd things to put at the end or will at least point out to me either Directly or on Twitter or in the forum or something that you were one of the lucky few who?
Rym: Recognized where it came from what it was what I was referencing Last several no one said anything about.
Rym: so I'm just curious Do any of you know?
Rym: What any of the last three weird things I put at the end of the show were or have I actually gone?
Rym: Beyond the event horizon from which even you will never stumble upon these things on your own?
Rym: But anyway that aside I'm gonna do just a weird fun thing because you guys seem really some of you are really into changing your names To mess with me in the patron manager, so what I'm gonna.
Rym: Do is.
Rym: I'm gonna post a patreon thing either tonight or tomorrow, and it'll be a form.
Rym: it'll be like the Q&A, but it'll be totally separate and Just put a some number of words.
Rym: Hopefully a small number.
Rym: if you put any too many words in there I will just ignore them, and I will probably just read Everything you've submitted in order that you submitted them from start to finish.
Rym: I'm gonna figure out exactly what the details of this are gonna be and we'll see how amazingly dumb.
Rym: This is.
Rym: and Now I leave you with something particularly odd starring Mark Hamill who's back from Star Wars And Annie Paz who's out of this world.
Rym: If he knew as much about girls as he does about cars.
Rym: He wouldn't be so nervous.
Scott: You love them dead sailor, and let me see what you got sure.
Rym: And if she knew as much about cars as she does about boys.
Rym: She wouldn't be so jealous.
Rym: And if you knew as much as they know about this candy apple metal flake Corvette You'd be chasing it - I'm helping you don't?
Rym: I'm helping you find your car.
Rym: You run up against a car thief.
Rym: be liable to wind up at the bottom of Lake Mead.
Rym: He's in the fast cars Wanted to write a letter to the car Dear car.
Rym: She's in the black velvet.
Rym: Together they find Excitement and danger Trail of a stolen Corvette.