Rym: It's Wednesday January 13th 2016.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: instead of talking about hog hawks We're talking about my little pony.
Rym: friendship is magic in its continuance since we talked about it once a long time ago and More ponies to come out since then and I did a long opener just now.
Rym: Cuz Scott doesn't like it when I do that.
Rym: It's not good Burma shave.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So I made a vow that I wouldn't talk about my bicycle commute at any point for 2015 in the beginning of GeekNights and it's now 2016 and someone reminds me I can totally talk about my bike commute again and In some sort of gift of the Magi bullshit.
Rym: It's winter and I'm not biking to work.
Scott: Why don't you bike to work in the cold?
Scott: I see people doing it.
Scott: I thought it's not snowing.
Rym: I've actually thought about it a bunch of times.
Scott: you like buying fancy equipment that I refuse to buy.
Rym: I already have that equipment because it's the same kind of stuff.
Rym: I use when I ski sometimes.
Rym: The only reason I haven't is That I usually wake up and it's kind of too late to get all that shit together.
Rym: Like it's a it's a production to put on the stuff to be able to bike in the cold like that.
Scott: Sure, but I mean if I bike to work I get there sooner than taking the subways these days.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah That's fine though.
Rym: Cuomo's got a plan.
Rym: They're gonna shut down like half the subway for multiple years.
Scott: That'll make the train go faster except no won't?
Rym: it's all cosmetic work primarily.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: No, it'll make the train go faster Skipping those stations.
Rym: Oh in the interim At least they're not shutting down my station.
Scott: So and they're shutting down only one of the two stations that are equidistant from me on the same train.
Rym: So they might shut down the L into Manhattan, which actually might be a disaster.
Rym: I think more humans commute on that subway then live in most counties in the US.
Rym: Good like I think I think more economic harm will happen by that one subway line being down.
Scott: Then if multiple cities got nuked in the US, I mean, this is a person who's on the way out, right?
Scott: You know, it's like he's basically just fucking everything up on the way out like aha
Rym: Yeah, if you
Scott: wouldn't do this at the start of your term because then you get unelected the next time
Rym: He's doing all this stuff and then he's doing all this PR saying hey, New York.
Rym: I got your back I think the regular old Democrats not to get into New York State politics too much.
Rym: We're worried that yeah Cuomo won the governorship But Zephyr teach-out got like the majority of the vote in New York City Of course cities starting to turn against upstate real hard because upstate can eat a dick.
Rym: But I digress.
Rym: that's my opening bed.
Rym: That's what I got for the first part.
Scott: They're all the most all 99.9 percent of listeners who don't live in New York.
Rym: Yeah, you know what?
Rym: You guys should live in New York.
Scott: You should even if they did live in New York.
Scott: if this is the New York podcast No one wants to hear about are you getting?
Rym: that's all guy.
Rym: I subscribe to the Gothamist.
Rym: That's all the Gothamist is is stuff like that?
Rym: It's just like hey, no, look at this thing.
Scott: I subscribe to the Gothamist for pizza rat stories.
Rym: Do you see how pizza rat was fabricated?
Rym: That's fine that same person you fabricated all those rat videos.
Scott: I don't care.
Scott: Yeah, I'm just.
Scott: I mean I see I have.
Scott: that's the level everything.
Rym: I mean, I don't trust any.
Rym: get you guys probably heard about our pizza rat.
Rym: You have no idea that there was a conspiracy to create pizza rat.
Scott: I mean, you know, I don't believe anything.
Rym: I read the internet anyway, so yeah, I mean it did happen.
Rym: It was just contrived.
Rym: Sure It's like when you see two cosplayers do a funny skit in the middle of an anime con.
Rym: They plan that shit ahead of time.
Scott: No kidding.
Rym: So, uh in other news bunch of Anna Twitter was sort of talking about how Netflix changed the way categories work and how?
Rym: Anime just shows up in its normal category instead of in the anime category.
Rym: Hooray.
Rym: So I thought hey, that'll be good news for GeekNights cuz I get a lot to say about that.
Scott: But is it true?
Rym: Yeah, so I went poking around and there was no article saying that this happened and I basically had to do some investigative journalism.
Rym: So I logged into Netflix actually forgot my password for Netflix.
Rym: So it took me a minute and I logged in and sure enough the anime category is still there.
Rym: But if you go to sci-fi Sci-fi anime just show up with everything else like they're normal like they're just popular media alongside some cartoons.
Scott: I really like to see that data on whether some animes get more watched or how many people who've never watched anime before watch One and things of that nature and what pages people click on anime series from to begin watching them.
Scott: Like our anime is only getting watched by clicks from the anime category page.
Scott: or are they getting watches?
Scott: You know from the sci-fi page?
Rym: because frankly we've talked about this like tangentially on a bunch of other gig nights episodes and pretty much anyone who knows about the anime and comics industry knows about this.
Rym: but Basically anime and manga are crazy popular in the u.s Mad popular.
Rym: yet the press talks about comics like they sell at all Like they're like, oh they talk about.
Rym: oh some Superman comic sold You know 10,000 copies.
Rym: crazy.
Rym: Holy shit, and they kind of forget that like any given shit Oh manga sells more than like the sit like number two through number nine in the top ten lists.
Scott: I mean attack on Titan out sells like Batman and Superman and all that stuff.
Rym: Yeah,
Scott: so
Rym: the media coverage of American comics Makes it seem like they're very popular But in reality they pretty much get outsold by random shoujo manga number four
Scott: The New York Times has two as two lists, you know, because they manage all these bestseller lists and you know This is the main, you know, New York Times bestseller list of books of novels, right?
Scott: but they have a whole bunch of other ones way down there and they have a graphic novel bestseller list and then they have a separate Manga bestseller list.
Scott: and why do they have this?
Scott: because they didn't have it.
Scott: It would just be the manga bestseller list.
Scott: because you know Even the top things on the not manga bestseller list like don't come close.
Scott: Yeah, it's like what's near the top of the graphic novel bestsellers.
Scott: good stuff really great stuff Like I think Kate beaten princess and the pony was up there.
Rym: That's good stuff.
Scott: But as much as I love Kate beaten and bought that book and you should do and buy the stuffed animal But I didn't buy that.
Scott: It doesn't outsell attack on Titan.
Rym: So I think this is a really big deal because Most people I know who got into anime from nothing who aren't just ultra nerds Get into it either because a friend tricks him into watching some anime and they're like, oh shit.
Rym: That was good or They stumble onto it because they were looking for a sci-fi movie.
Scott: Well, it's also you know people when they think of the popular of anime They try to think of like the number of anime fans.
Scott: and first of all that number is a lot bigger than people think They're just not paying attention to the fact how big like anime Expo is.
Rym: Yeah, I mean you're talking about comic cons.
Rym: All right, there's two or three comic cons that are big most comic cons.
Rym: I have attendance in the thousands.
Rym: Meanwhile Otakon if you count the way comic cons do has like 90,000 plus people at it and no one talks about it, right?
Scott: So you also had to consider the fact is all these people who aren't anime fans, right?
Scott: They wouldn't say that they're an anime fan.
Scott: They don't go to anime news network.
Scott: They don't follow anime people on Twitter, right?
Scott: They don't go to anime convention, but they watch an anime.
Scott: They watch a lot of animes.
Rym: I know I run into a lot of people who've seen my mom My mom watches animes.
Scott: all the kids at the high school know what Dragon Ball is Right, even today high school kids like kids who are 16 right now watch Dragon Ball know what it is, right?
Scott: Yeah, you know, they know that Soul Leaders Like, you know.
Scott: now if you ask them if they're an anime fan, they'd be like no, but you know They're into like video games or something.
Rym: Maybe they're right but but this is a big deal because the anime ghetto has to go away in certain like in Netflix and everything.
Scott: All ghettos need to go away.
Rym: No, yeah, that's the whole point of gig nights.
Rym: geek, you know broaden your horizons.
Rym: you should listen to all the gig nights and be into games and anime and Politics even though Scott's not into politics, but I am I'm a nerd about politics But anyway time.
Rym: so I yeah, I'm right here in the sci-fi and fantasy on Netflix.
Rym: So there's that old live-action He-Man Masters of the Universe Jules Verne center Jules Verne center of the earth like the old.
Scott: Oh, yeah Center the earth is a good book.
Rym: the forgotten berserk Oh that anime berserk is just hanging out right here.
Rym: next to all that shit some Star Trek Full metal alchemist is in here little witch academia.
Rym: Oh shit.
Rym: The little witch academia is here.
Rym: Mm-hmm I forgot that came out like we should watch that like real soon.
Rym: Yep uh, I cannot stress to you enough how important it is that Netflix did this.
Rym: and Also how don't subscribe to crunchyroll just subscribe to Hulu.
Rym: most of the anime is in there.
Scott: That's where most crunchyrolls adding a bunch of new animes recently.
Scott: I mean new to crunchyroll anime Yeah, but it's like.
Scott: Hulu has all the anime you actually want to watch right now and you can get the ad-free version.
Scott: I guess if you finish watching everything on Hulu Then you could sign up for crunchyroll and watch the other stuff.
Scott: The one thing I miss from the crunchyroll who doesn't have are the weirdo anime.
Rym: Yeah, right Like folk tales from Japan, which is still one of my favorite shows our news Our news.
Scott: You know the weirdo ones, but that's okay.
Rym: Yeah, I mean she by denial, yeah that one.
Rym: so in other news we were talking about this before the show, but there's an old penny arcade comic where one of the characters like is off and there's two characters sitting there and suddenly a weird clock rings and the stars align and Someone's like that clock.
Scott: never you don't remember what that comic was about.
Rym: And then Gabe jumps in being like hit points.
Scott: mana Right because basically, you know at that time period right?
Scott: Mike Krahulik right Gabe was a person who did not play the RPGs at all.
Scott: He was not didn't play didn't play the Final Fantasies or the dnds, right?
Rym: So he wasn't paying attention.
Scott: the Jerry Holkins.
Scott: You know the tight the bald taiko In the comic.
Scott: he was the D&D dice-rolling type of person and You know at that point in time is when you know the clock rang For the first time.
Scott: and now Mike Krahulik is like making RPGs and shit.
Rym: He's like the D&D master, but that you know, I feel like the Lupin clock might be ringing again.
Scott: Yeah, it's not a clock that never rings.
Scott: It's a clock that hasn't rung in a while.
Rym: Yeah, well he had played RPGs other RPGs in the past just kind of stops Like them and we want to play.
Scott: that.
Rym: I mean remember when PC gaming was dead Yeah, and then suddenly there was a tolling in the distance and gave in.
Scott: well You know Lupin is one of those things with the people in charge of it.
Scott: So wisely, you know bring it up and hide it away and then bring it up and hide away.
Scott: It was always there.
Scott: you'd get old.
Rym: thing is it is always there It's just.
Rym: there's a lot of shitty Lupin's that came out for a long time.
Rym: Not like not recently though Yeah, so pretty Fujiko Mine came out and it was crazy good and it brought a style of animation and storytelling that Deeply rustles my jimmies in a good way and that shows fantastic.
Rym: So a bunch more Lupin came out after that in a similar style like the grave of jig and dice.
Scott: There's a brand new Lupin likes the fourth season or whatever.
Rym: So Emily and I are actually going through from Fujiko Mine Onward of every Lupin that's come out since then.
Rym: we're just watching them as fast as we can.
Scott: why not?
Rym: because they're great.
Rym: So there's a new Lupin the third TV special coming out.
Rym: I guess it came out in January 8th, so it just came out real recently called Lupin the third the Italian game.
Rym: and My thing of the day is just you know when we get to?
Rym: that is just the trailer for this TV special.
Rym: But holy shit did that clock just ring so hard that it exploded?
Scott: I hope that this trailer that none of the things in the trailer are actually in the movie.
Rym: I hope that all but one of the things in the trailer are in the movie, but happen in the first five minutes.
Rym: Yeah, if the tree if this TV special the trailer is just a flashback Lupin has during the movie.
Rym: yeah, holy Shit, did I forget how much I love Lupin when Lupin is good?
Rym: Also, this is the rare blue jacket Lupin.
Scott: Oh, yeah, yeah Not green.
Rym: I'm not gonna talk about it any further because this is the kind of thing if you're an anime fan at all just watch It and if you're not an anime fan, and you like anything even remotely vestigially similar to James Bond watch some Lupin.
Scott: So if you want to talk about bells that ring and ring and ring and ring and never stop ringing and never will stop ringing Even after we die.
Scott: Pokemon is 20 years old.
Rym: God damn it.
Rym: That means when Pokemon came into existence in Japan I was like 14 or something which is weird because it's kind of like that Preferage farm remembers where you kind of forget that things didn't exist forever Like I remember when Pokemon came into existence.
Scott: I saw it in a game Pro magazine.
Scott: I was like oh, there's some kids game why they making a big deal out of it.
Scott: Yeah, and then my brother got it on his Gameboy pocket And then I played it a little bit and I was like, oh I didn't realize this thing.
Scott: that looked like garbage from a few pictures of you know Pikachu was actually earthbound.
Rym: see no one near me got into it in high school.
Rym: So when I was at RIT, I bet like I knew what Pokemon was I didn't really care about it or think about you where I was.
Scott: we were poke battling in high school.
Rym: Yeah, I was not.
Rym: so I when I started paying attention to Pokemon I just had this sense that it had been around Forever like as long as I'd lived like.
Rym: I couldn't think back to the origin of it.
Rym: I can yeah you can.
Scott: So, uh, so it's 20 years old and to celebrate this 20th anniversary They're re-releasing like 3ds's that have Pokemon red or blue installed and they're doing stuff with the CCG.
Scott: They're basically going all out for this arbitrary number.
Scott: I can't even imagine what they're gonna do five years from now for the 25th anniversary or the 50th.
Scott: I hope to see it.
Scott: You know what?
Rym: So the 25th anniversary?
Rym: because by then that Pokemon ingress AR game will be in full swing.
Rym: so on the 25th anniversary what's gonna happen probably is Everyone's.
Rym: pokédar is gonna start going off to set up some giant event.
Rym: Yeah and then every kid in the world is gonna converge on like these Monoliths in the centers of cities and then the message will come in there is a gun taped to the bottom of your chair.
Scott: So there's a Pokemon p-cross.
Scott: I'm playing a lot right now, by the way I like p-cross.
Scott: Why what's wrong p-cross?
Rym: boring Sudoku?
Rym: It's the same as Sudoku.
Scott: It's better than Sudoku.
Scott: How?
Scott: so you get a picture at the end?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Okay, you get a a one-bit picture.
Rym: Well, I guess not one.
Scott: also unlike Sudoku You can get really really big ones that are much more complex and interesting without making them like, you know Impossible and unfun.
Scott: if I may if I give you a Sudoku that's like enormous with really tiny squares You know that goes to like one to a hundred in each row and column.
Scott: You're like fuck that.
Scott: but if I give you a p-cross, that's like 30 by 15.
Scott: It's like that's doable.
Rym: They fuck that and just play Advance Wars.
Scott: Anyway, anyway So one other thing that they're doing that's really fascinating is they have paid for a Pokemon 20th anniversary Superb owl commercial.
Scott: Oh I want to see this commercial.
Rym: What are they gonna?
Rym: is that gonna?
Rym: are they gonna launch something with that?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: gonna be some big launch announcement.
Scott: a live-action commercial will air during the Superb owl on February 7th.
Rym: I I'll bet it's for the AR stuff.
Scott: I don't know if I will promote the 20th anniversary's train on motto train on.
Scott: Yeah, as it as in keep on training Pokemon not get on the train.
Rym: Yeah, maybe it is.
Rym: Maybe they'll introduce a train.
Scott: I know it's train on like keep training.
Scott: go for it trainers Pokemon training.
Rym: Yeah Things of the day, like I said, my thing of the day is the opening to Lupin.
Rym: the third the Italian game.
Rym: Holy shit.
Rym: Do I want to watch this real bad?
Rym: I also want to watch it pretty bad Like if you can imagine a video designed to make me filled with determination to see something.
Rym: This is like when we saw the beginning of project blue earth cheeky.
Rym: Oh, we were like, holy shit This has everything and then we were let down.
Rym: so I hope this doesn't let me down.
Scott: Hmm This is YouTube channel, I discovered by someone linked to one of their videos, which is the one I'm gonna talk about Which is called retro blasting and they basically just review really old stuff, right?
Scott: Like, you know Ninja Turtles cartoon spider-man amazing friends and you know, Indiana Jones toys from back in the day You know nerdy 80s 70s stuff, whatever.
Scott: But the videos are well produced actually and they have this one video that is about the Dungeons & Dragons cartoon the old Now.
Scott: that's a cartoon that you know.
Scott: My memory of seeing like one and a half episodes was not positive because it was also it was kind of before our time.
Scott: Yeah, it was.
Scott: it came out basically when I was zero right ish.
Scott: So, you know, I was not a fan of this thing.
Scott: I thought it was you know bad, you know, just old bad stuff lumped in there with he-man, but this review of it Really sort of makes a good case for why this was a good cartoon.
Scott: good like relative to Contemporary cartoons or legit good legit good like they're making a case for it.
Scott: ah, and I kind of want to go back and verify whether that's True, but I also don't.
Rym: that's a dangerous direction to go.
Scott: I think your best bet is to just instead of actually watching the D&D cartoon from back in the day Just watch this YouTube video that's actually like 26 minutes long and you'll learn everything You need to know about it.
Rym: and see everything you need to see might give you a false impression though What if it's wrong?
Scott: they're pretty convincing.
Rym: yeah, I could make a pretty convincing video about a thing that I made up.
Scott: I'm not a hundred percent saying that they're right.
Scott: I'm just saying they're convincing.
Rym: Nah in the meta moment pecs out coming up real soon.
Scott: Whoa pecs out.
Rym: Saturday 11 30 a.m.
Rym: Atari game design.
Rym: Saturday 5 30 p.m Scared yet a discussion of horror and games.
Rym: Sunday 1 p.m Designing game rules.
Rym: Also mag fest coming up pretty quick after packs and then an anime Boston and And another PAX East.
Rym: I put in five panels for PAX East and let me tell you Assuming we go to anime Boston one of the ones I put in is another foreign anime openers panel.
Rym: I got all new content now, and I found the others a new treasure trove.
Rym: I found such a deep treasure trove and no multiple people.
Rym: It's not the Russian anime opener treasure trove.
Rym: I know of that.
Rym: I found further buried gold.
Rym: All right, Oak Island.
Rym: I just kept digging and kept digging.
Rym: I Think I've got enough too deep.
Rym: Okay, I died Scott.
Rym: I went too deep that that dramatic reading might be one step below hitting the bottom.
Rym: There's things coming out Balrog's killing everyone in the panel room.
Rym: But yeah, it's gonna be good times.
Rym: The mag fest schedule is looking pretty good.
Rym: We're on like seven panels But we were split up.
Rym: So like we're not both on all the panels.
Rym: So we'll see how that goes.
Rym: Book club book.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I'm still reading though.
Rym: I'm like book eight of the wheel of time at this point Patreon.
Rym: I go twice on book club since you're not going but then I'll have to stop reading the wheel of time which is continuing in its steady pace of being average quality.
Rym: fantasy book the novel, okay, and Pretty much.
Rym: I'm just in a holding pattern until the our Scott backer book comes out.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: That's coming Patrons going strong.
Rym: We're not that far away from the beta episodes thing.
Rym: We put up the December Q&A.
Rym: So dog, I'll submission form for backers to submit questions for the January Q&A.
Scott: Don't do this.
Rym: However, people have said that they really like the Q&A episodes and some people really like the rims-rants things that are in there.
Scott: You could have spent your money on something good or spent your time watching something good.
Scott: Like I don't know even that D&D cartoons probably better than GeekNights.
Rym: I'll tell you what, if you got spare money send it to Child's Play.
Rym: if you still have spare money Send it to Neil Cisarenga's patreon.
Rym: and if you still got money Maybe put a little bit in our.
Scott: buy some food.
Scott: get a better lunch.
Scott: You know if you're eating like a peony B&J for lunch get a steak instead.
Rym: and oh, yeah The t-shirts are still selling like one or two a week.
Rym: So It's a good t-shirt.
Scott: so you go get a nice t-shirt from threadless It's a pretty nice t-shirt.
Scott: or go to Tepedo Co.
Scott: any any shirt on all of Tepedo Co is better than the night.
Rym: So guys, I'll tell you what.
Rym: I have an Amazon merch account for us and apparently they're hard to get for some reason like there's a long Backlog.
Rym: really invite only.
Scott: Oh, I didn't know this.
Rym: so I can sell up to 25 shirts at a time.
Rym: So I'll tell you this if you want to sell a t-shirt that gets a cool one through GeekNights I'll give you like.
Scott: you're better off selling it anywhere else.
Scott: The profit margin is so bad Yes, but the effort level is so low.
Scott: You could just open your own web store with like a Shopify for you ever.
Rym: No, I've done that.
Rym: Do you know what?
Rym: you're fucking pain-in-the-ass?
Scott: that you could just make up PayPal.
Scott: one link for PayPal put.
Rym: no No, that's not what they're saving you.
Rym: The thing is they print on demand any size any style multiple t-shirt colors.
Scott: If you make it a GeekNights shirt This makes sense.
Scott: if you want to make send us a design and we'll give you the profits.
Scott: But if you're making a shirt for your own shit, don't.
Scott: why would you do this?
Rym: No If you're just if you just have a cool shirt that you want to let us sell for you with no So many other people that will sell it for you better.
Rym: They'll take more of a cut than this takes.
Scott: No, you can go like thread lists to pay to go save a.
Rym: yeah to pay to co is invite only and there's minimum requirements.
Scott: I'm just saying if you can't meet those requirements your shirt isn't with mine.
Rym: Yeah, let's see.
Rym: We're about our level.
Rym: We're not to pay to co.
Rym: I mean, I don't know if we get to pay to go.
Rym: We never tried to to pay to co.
Rym: No So you may recall a time back in 2011 a heady time where?
Rym: Someone posted in our forum saying hey guys the new my little pony show is really good and we were like what what why?
Scott: Well, and then I saw it posted a bunch of other places and then it turned out to be true.
Scott: So we watched it.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So we didn't even get in on that pony craze until about halfway through the first season and Many of you who are close to us may remember that it hit pretty hard.
Scott: it hit hard and then it faded but it didn't Completely fade.
Rym: but it hit hard for like two years Hard for a while.
Rym: there was a time a period of about two years where we pretty much just wouldn't fucking shut up about ponies.
Rym: Mm-hmm, and I still really like ponies, but I don't talk about it every day.
Scott: I have every single issue of the pony comic series released by IDW and that comic series is Fantastic.
Scott: It's so good.
Rym: It's the.
Rym: it's better than the show right now.
Rym: Yes other than it doesn't have music You can listen to.
Scott: no But yeah, if you want ponies you're not getting enough.
Scott: get the comics.
Scott: they made this two main series which is You know friendship is magic, but there's also main like ma ne.
Scott: There's also friends forever Which is like they have multiple pony comics the same way that there's spider-man an amazing spider-man and spectacular spider-man.
Scott: Yeah, and spider-man is amazing friends spider-man 2099.
Rym: But especially if you really like the first two seasons of my little pony and then you're a little bit disappointed in like season 3.
Scott: Quality you know as ponies is good, but the quality has varied wildly right even within the first season Which is still the best season, you know The sonic rainboom episode and they visit the dragon on the mountain episode far surpass.
Rym: Oh my god that dragon episode might have been one of the best episodes ever.
Scott: They far surpass all other episodes and all the other seasons Right a list of all the.
Scott: the quality goes from high to low, right?
Scott: But recently I caught up on every single episode through the newest season which is completed.
Scott: Rym I think is a little bit behind.
Scott: isn't that?
Rym: I've seen most of the current season But I've seen all those like rainbow rocks nonsense that I didn't see any of the ones where they're not ponies.
Rym: So I know some stuff.
Rym: well.
Scott: So and I know that they have no they never came into play in the actual cartoon.
Rym: So our ponies other way around they do and both worlds exist side by side and there's some back-and-forth stuff going on.
Scott: But anyway, I didn't see any back-and-forth stuff in the show.
Rym: You don't need to you do not need to see that garbage, but I digress.
Rym: So my little pony and this is about a pretty long run and we haven't talked about it It's still running.
Rym: there's gonna be another season as season six is confirmed for this year All right, and season five just ended.
Rym: so much like we did with adventure time when a show is long running You can't just review it once and be well can't do a final thoughts cuz when's the final thoughts gonna be?
Scott: Yeah, I mean, let's do Flintstones final thoughts.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, it's like yeah this thing didn't it's the honeymooners But more family-friendly, right?
Scott: I mean, you know that people don't remember that show ran for a fuck ever right, you know?
Scott: So it's like if we if it was still running we would might not.
Scott: you know, when can you do a final thoughts on it?
Scott: Yeah, well you get the thoughts on things that are limited like anime 26 now.
Rym: They're like 117 episodes of my little pony friendship of met as magic not as many as fist of the North Star.
Rym: that is a Little over half as many as Sailor Moon's run.
Rym: Yep Sailor a lot happened in Sailor Moon like if I was gonna review Sailor Moon based on season one Very different thoughts from if I've seen s or stars.
Rym: So I still really like my little pony and I actually think like season four especially the recent season five The quite the average quality has been rising from.
Rym: I think the season three kind of had this Deep not deep Pete look drop, but not the best episodes like you could definitely see.
Scott: I agree that the if you average each season's total episodes together that yeah That third season was definitely the weakest season.
Scott: Well, but it still has some good stuff in it.
Scott: I wasn't bad It didn't make you want to stop watching.
Rym: season one was Lauren Fowles like a hundred percent and season two was Lauren Fowles.
Rym: direction is still there.
Rym: Yeah season three was when they started having to go off on their own and they made a lot of decisions that made the show a little less Good.
Scott: Hmm.
Rym: It's hard if I had to describe what bothered me about it.
Rym: It wasn't that the show got like simpler or anything.
Rym: It was more than the in the first two seasons.
Rym: What I liked about the show was that they were very careful to release like little bits of information about the world Tangentially like something.
Rym: you'd see something in the foreground or you'd see a character do a thing and it would imply a bunch of stuff Of the world.
Rym: but they wouldn't then zoom the camera on that and try to explain it all with a giant flashback.
Rym: And as the show goes that got on they've really started to say hey you want to know the deal about this let's zoom in on this and do a huge flashback and tell you the story.
Rym: and they also stopped paying attention to the like Rigid idea that the ponies have hooves and can't just hold stuff.
Rym: Hmm because in more recent episodes They increasingly kind of just ignore that and just yeah that ponies holding the cane because well, we just animated it that way.
Rym: Sorry guys.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: Oh Well, but yeah.
Scott: and the more recent seasons the average quality has been going up But you know the I think the variance has increased right?
Scott: there's some episodes in the newest season that are like so so good And there's some that are so so bad like probably some of the worst episodes in the whole show.
Rym: the fan pandering is what's doing it?
Scott: Yeah, there was an episode.
Scott: item was the title of it.
Scott: Do you have it there?
Rym: Pulling up the list it was The best episode of this season.
Rym: far and away.
Rym: was rarity investigate.
Scott: No, that was the same.
Scott: It's tied I think with the moon dancer episode.
Rym: I can't believe just because their rarity investigates is so good Yeah, especially because at the end of the oh and his disingenuous smile.
Scott: Yeah But yeah, there was an episode in the newest season that consists of life.
Scott: Right, it consisted of nothing.
Rym: is this episode have its own Wikipedia page?
Scott: Because it's so much fan pandering references.
Scott: They have to explain right?
Scott: So the whole episode was nothing but taking the fan in right and making it canon.
Scott: every single thing that the online pony community right like created like all these personalities for characters and relationships between the characters
Rym: and names in some cases,
Scott: you know, Doctor who jokes and it was basically like watching tumblr on TV and I was like, oh my god kill it with fire.
Scott: Yeah with fire.
Rym: there is a way to cater to your fans and their theories Without just taking all their bullshit and cramming it into your show.
Rym: The ponies just kind of did the opposite of what they should have done in this regard But at the same time I say should have The fans of my little pony loved it.
Rym: as far as I can tell.
Scott: I mean if you're the person the kind of person who writes a you know, Sherlock pones fanfic and then suddenly, you know You like that you're really into that.
Scott: and then suddenly it's real and you got acknowledgement from the people who make the pones.
Scott: That's like, you know, that's like if you go to some beaver concert and he touches you, right?
Rym: Yeah, it's just.
Rym: I liked it more when it was subtle like the show had a lot of cameos of like.
Rym: hey That's obviously a character of a famous person, but they didn't zoom in on it quite like they do With this fan stuff later.
Scott: Yeah, that episode was just so bad, but thankfully they left it out of further episodes.
Scott: They contained it within that one beast.
Scott: Yeah I didn't let it leak into the other episodes some of which are quite good.
Rym: What actually the thing that has been most disappointing about the episodes that weren't great is that they had that conceit of well Twilight's too powerful now and we need this plot of.
Rym: let's just take these three characters and send them off on an adventure So we can write a story just about them.
Rym: yeah, which I don't know just from a production standpoint makes sense because I heard of a rumor and an anecdote that Teen Titans go is Apparently really hard to storyboard and put together because every shot is all the characters all the time.
Rym: Like there's a bunch of characters and they're always there always in the shot always doing their thing They're all involved in every plot and the same thing goes.
Scott: you read x-men comics, right?
Scott: And when I was a kid I buy an x-men comic and on the cover would be gambit and you'd read that issue And the only x-men who would be in that issue would be like gambit rogue.
Scott: They talked to Professor X once and maybe Wolverine was there because he's in every issue.
Rym: Where's beast?
Scott: always working on the sandwich and you'd only see all the x-men at once and like, you know x-men number one.
Scott: Here's a shot of them all in the planning room deciding on what to do.
Scott: But then they'd only be in this, you know, two-page spread.
Scott: You just see them there and only a few of them would actually you know be talking and directly involved in the plot of that issue.
Scott: Right, you can't.
Scott: you can't write a story with like a hundred characters all actively doing everything all the time.
Rym: Yep Pretty hit or miss though how well they did this, right?
Rym: Well, I didn't use it as often I expected them to.
Scott: well the thing I liked about it was that you brought back to the thing that made me like the first season so much which is The fantasy adventure.
Scott: It's like there's a magical table that tells you where to go on a magical quest.
Scott: Yeah, there's all these magical questions about elements of harmony and stuff that were you know.
Scott: It's like the real reason to watch the show is for epic fantasy stuff and they brought that back.
Scott: but occasionally it's like the table tells up only Applejack and and Pinkie Pie should be going this way.
Scott: No, no one else can go on this quest.
Rym: yeah, which Could make sense like you could make like.
Scott: oh if the rest of them went then like the table knows who needs to go to Solve the problem if anyone else went the problem wouldn't be solved.
Rym: Okay, if the table itself became a plot point Allah quantum leap Mm-hmm, but it doesn't.
Scott: I think it will.
Rym: I don't think it will.
Scott: Well, I guess it's more than the table every although all of the previous table equivalents in the show were plot points Such as writing letters to the princess and such.
Rym: but the plot points in the first few seasons were much more Subtle or much more Open-ended and these plot points that have been introduced increasingly as the show goes on Become very little literal and direct and are spotlighted and solve a specific problem Immediately and are fully explained at some point.
Rym: Yeah, which is kind of boring sometimes.
Scott: Another thing I like is that because the show is sort of expanded the ponies are like getting around, right?
Scott: It's not.
Scott: it's not just Ponyville.
Scott: It's like we're going to Canada.
Rym: We're going to you know, Clowsdale Griffin town and it turns out all Griffins are just like horrible people.
Scott: We're just going to Manhattan.
Scott: We're going on a quest into the scary place.
Scott: You know the Manhattan.
Rym: they're going back and forth.
Scott: We're riding.
Scott: We're riding that train all the time.
Scott: Yeah, I think I hadn't.
Rym: kind of often and like coming and going and doing so like where you opens a business there We're super important ponies.
Scott: We got to go around Equestria doing stuff.
Scott: We can't just be sitting Ponyville all day.
Rym: But I like that aspect that like rarity like tries to open a shop there and the resolution is kind of like yeah Shop still there like stuff happens like she's she'll live there for a week in an apartment doing something like it's.
Rym: it's more like a Real show that has a bunch of stuff going on like Seinfeld.
Rym: They're going places and doing things.
Rym: Um, I mean, I still like the show a lot.
Scott: Yeah, it's still good.
Scott: Yeah But yeah, so the let's just talk about the really good episode.
Scott: So the Moondancer episode right Harkins back.
Scott: It takes a reference from the very first episode Some Simpsons quality.
Scott: back reference is a part in the first episode of the whole show season one.
Rym: What about Moondancers party?
Scott: right spike is like hey, you know Moondancers having a party Do you want to go?
Scott: and so I was like no I'm busy.
Scott: and then twice, you know They even make a note in that first episode that spike about Moondancer a present that never got delivered or anything.
Scott: Yeah, and in this Moondancer episode basically Twilight remembers that.
Scott: you know that for that Had friends before Ponyville sort of she had friends, but she was super close.
Scott: He wasn't close to them because she was just studying and she realized she's the.
Scott: you know He's the princess of friendship and she really used to really suck at friends Which is part of why she became the princess of friendship.
Scott: So she goes back.
Scott: It's like her old counterlot house, which I guess she just abandoned.
Scott: who was paying for it?
Scott: I guess it was princess territory like it's federal territory part.
Scott: It's part of the palace and like no one had ever bothered to go there or clean it up or look at it since the first Episode where she just ran out and got in a balloon.
Rym: Well because she was special I remember she was elevated that position because the dragon thing works usually.
Scott: Yeah, it's like if I just if I just leave my house and don't come back someone's gonna go in.
Scott: Maybe but everything's still there including the president for Moondancer and everything.
Scott: And then the episode is all about like who is Moondancer and you know.
Rym: Oh There's a problem with that episode.
Rym: that happened in a couple other episodes to.
Rym: that bothers me a little bit.
Rym: that a lot of times.
Rym: Yeah, there was that one flaw with the episode Solution to the prop through the problems of a person.
Rym: Well, I guess a pony Tend to be really simplistic.
Rym: Yeah and tend to have kind of a bad message for like a kid who might be watching the show because a lot of moon dancers episode was basically She became an introverted shut-in because of that incident.
Scott: and that's not true.
Scott: There's no way.
Scott: Yeah, it one incident is gonna make someone like that.
Rym: It would have been a lot better if the gift and that if she is just an introvert and that's fine.
Rym: And they resolved it a much more subtle way.
Rym: but on the other hand with some of the Fluttershy episodes They did that really well because I thought the scary Halloween one.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: She's so bad.
Scott: That's probably that's right underneath those other two of those those animals that she made.
Scott: Oh my god.
Rym: I Love how she's.
Rym: you know that she's totally a weeb.
Rym: Well, I like I like that also.
Scott: is they how they?
Scott: they sort of giving you a some sense of time and that they're reselebrating All the holidays.
Scott: there was another grand galloping gala.
Scott: There was another, you know all spooky Eve.
Scott: There was another heart swarming, right?
Scott: It's like another year has gone through, you know, the seasons changing it.
Scott: They didn't do another winter wrap-up.
Scott: they should.
Rym: but I look at the moral of that episode.
Rym: was Fluttershy.
Rym: It's totally okay that she's not good at or into something like fine.
Rym: Cool the end.
Rym: They didn't fix her and make her love the holiday.
Scott: She just did her own thing, but they did show her being awesome at it.
Rym: Yeah, they did the same thing with Fluttershy in the the one with her singing Mmm with the lip-syncing thing and now she got really into it.
Rym: and then the moral at the end wasn't oh now she's over Her stage fright.
Rym: it was yeah, she's still into singing But she still has stage fright and that's cool.
Rym: and I feel like half the episode.
Scott: wonder she became a model.
Scott: Yeah, I was like, I don't want to be a model anymore even though I was famous.
Rym: But half the episodes of the new seasons have a good complex or at least nuanced moral like that Harrison Bergeron episode.
Scott: Yeah, you didn't see the final episode of the season where the Harrison Bergeron pony comes back.
Rym: I didn't know she was gonna come back.
Scott: I didn't know either cuz they were talking about someone I'm like, who are they talking about?
Rym: I'm like, oh the Harrison Bergeron pony Is it done well and have a nuanced point or is it?
Rym: well It's a little bit Little bit simplistic again.
Rym: No, I mean it's okay Alright But see that's the quality of individual episodes has been kind of inconsistent and it's getting I think more swingy But at the same time the average quality is still slowly increasing again.
Rym: Hmm just nothing's quite as good as that season two season one.
Rym: Yeah season one season two had a lot of good stuff going on there.
Scott: Why not?
Scott: You know didn't have a rainbow thing.
Rym: No, but it did have that hearts and hopes day episode.
Rym: Also Dragon Quest was season two really.
Scott: no Oh Dragon Quest is the one where there's a bunch that spike goes to sparkle crackle.
Scott: Yes, that's Dragon Quest.
Scott: Yes, that was a good episode sure But no the good dragon episode was season one Which is the one with Fluttershy going up the mountain and talking to the dragon.
Rym: Yep Yep, so pretty much if you've been ignoring cuz you know There's a lot of cartoons that you can watch right now that are probably better than ponies actually.
Rym: But like the wide set like all the stuff that I watch and I kind of go through phases like I didn't watch a lot Of ponies for a while because I was watching a whole bunch of gumball and Steven Universe and Adventure Time and I sort of rotate In and out.
Rym: so if you're rotated ponies out because you're watching all this other stuff It's actually a pretty good time to rotate it back in one punch man is done.
Rym: Yeah ponies is done.
Rym: now You can just catch up until season six.
Scott: That's how I did.
Scott: I just watched all like the ponies I missed.
Rym: like recently Adventure Time is just starting up again after stakes.
Scott: Oh, well I'll see that out at this weekend.
Rym: Yeah, Adventure Time is you know, if I had to list the shows that I watch immediately when they come out It's still just Adventure Time and Steven Universe.
Rym: Those are the only shows I watch like immediately.
Rym: the second they come.
Scott: I don't watch anything immediately anymore.
Rym: I'll do Adventure Time immediately because that shows just do good.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and my comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Rym: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and our wonderful patrons for this episode are in order of the amount of money they give us.
Rym: Nicholas Brandau Rebecca Dunn Amanda Duchette James David White Christian coons Jess mechanical mind William Eisen rose.
Rym: The donation is coming from inside the house.
Rym: Clinton Walton my stady comm Phil Ulrich Renee from New Zealand Robert Lee Ryan Perrin drew open Lander rare Lavell Brian should Sidroni Rochelle, Montanona Finn Eric Silveraude and then he placed a single finger upon his mustache.
Rym: Kinetic man Aaron Cerise Chris midkiff Chris Knox shut up Scott and take my money.
Rym: Samuel Cordery Daniel Redman Chris Haddad Doug Schneider Shawn Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: I'm working hard on the utenna episode.
Rym: We've got you know, the two recorded already But I'm also working on all our panels for packs because it's my turn to do the panels.
Rym: But luckily that'll really dry out because once I actually get these panels done We're hopefully doing pretty much the same panels at magfest along with all the other like panel panels that are actually a panel of people and At least one of them is gonna overlap with PAX East.
Rym: so a lot of the work I'm doing now is gonna get us through many months of convention season meaning I'll have more time to finish your tenna to do my rims rants to do all that other stuff.
Rym: Questions for the January Q&A will open shortly.
Rym: and now I leave you with something pretty weird.
Rym: This guy's a real old-timer Grandfather of VR.
Rym: Dr.
Rym: Morgan Who are you?
Rym: I'm Sidney Bloom.
Rym: What do you want with me Sidney Bloom?
Scott: I Want to know how virtual reality works.
Rym: are we communicating right now I guess but you can't see me and I can't see you.
Scott: Is that right?
Rym: Yeah, we're both having an experience that requires each of our minds to fill in the blanks Isn't that right?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, that's it.
Rym: You just had a virtual experience.
Rym: Now going back to your sorority house But I'm forget it.
Scott: If you're not a white-eyed sorority girl, you you're a cyber geek.
Scott: You'd rather shove quarters into some machine and cry for poly out.
Rym: I Just I have to talk to somebody.
Rym: That's the smartest thing you said since you walked in here Sidney Bloom.
Rym: well, so what do you need to talk to somebody about?
Rym: It sounds like you're all set up.
Scott: Well How far have you come through?
Scott: like Like.
Rym: how real it's real as I want to get all five senses.
Rym: Three once was smell and my wiring caught fire.
Rym: Why what can you do?
Scott: And just just call it a theory.
Rym: Hey look whatever it is that you're doing is stop I Can't hey can't get a hobby write a novel Watch TV.
Rym: You'll be much better off in the long run.
Rym: I'm sorry.
Rym: I can't help you.