Rym: It's Thursday, December 8th, 2016.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We're talking about the concerns of the bathroom possibly part 1.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So Scott I heard you had some pretty good opening bit for the show.
Scott: we had opening bit.
Scott: last time I forgot it.
Scott: I know we went out to eat and I remembered it.
Rym: and I told you Told me and you were like, I'll tell you so that we don't forget.
Rym: and I even thought then at first I was like Oh, yeah There's no way I'll forget that as I always think.
Rym: but then today today Rym Remembered that it is literally impossible for me to remember a show idea.
Scott: Yeah Happen, I don't remember what the opening bit was Like.
Rym: I have lost your ideas forever because I had erased a whiteboard The only one that I have in my Google keep.
Rym: I have a. where is it?
Rym: Thing that says news topics.
Rym: I have things just show ideas.
Rym: The show ideas has one thing in it and that thing has been there for more than six months.
Scott: Oh, I know what that is.
Rym: Yeah, that's actually a really good idea for a show, but it requires Maybe an hour or two of preparation.
Scott: That's why it's a bad show that it never happened.
Rym: Yeah, it's a good show though It'll be a really good show.
Rym: I think I think we actually we could live stream it like plan like we could do good stuff.
Rym: Maybe we'll see.
Rym: Yeah, so I'll talk about this more on the next Monday show.
Rym: but you know, I pulled the trigger on buying that new computer and a bunch of the components have arrived and That feeling of building a computer.
Rym: It's real powerful and you might if it's been a while you might forget what it feels like to build a brand new computer.
Rym: Especially because I realized something Every time I have built a computer in my life with the exception of the first one it was always a computer that I needed quickly and I was in a hurry because it was always like My old computer literally is failing or stop working.
Rym: I need a new computer as soon as possible.
Rym: Oh fuck, but research by the components.
Rym: build it like as fast as possible in one day and throw together Like one time when my old computer started crashing the previous one before.
Rym: this one has some voltage errors.
Rym: It was basically Preventing us from safely doing GeekNights until I built the new computer.
Rym: So like the parts came and like I built it as fast as possible that day to do the show.
Rym: this time I'm replacing a perfectly functional computer like this.
Rym: computer's only fault is that it's slow and one of the USB headers I disabled because I think it has a problem.
Rym: So, uh, yeah.
Rym: Anyway, I got any news on the lounge this Thursday episode of GeekNights.
Scott: I do have a news the news.
Rym: No one cares about but me something with kpop eyes.
Rym: It's either netrunner kpop maybe kpop team appearing as a cameo in a netrunner card.
Scott: I figure right, you know, I try not to bust out those things that no one cares about.
Scott: but me Rym has no shame.
Scott: He just busts out the thing.
Scott: He cares about it.
Rym: No, you think I have no shame.
Rym: What you've read what you don't realize is that to become a monster to fight monsters.
Rym: You must become a monster.
Scott: That's not true.
Rym: The things that I show that I share as things of the day that you think are horrible Internet's things related like potato conditions are the mere surface of your evil.
Rym: that is the AT field.
Scott: sure by showing you that I dissuade you from going deeper point is I have self-restraint, but Sometimes the wells a bit dry.
Scott: So, you know, I'll dip into that pool right and maybe someone will jump in the pool with me because it's you know It's not evil stuff.
Scott: It's just.
Scott: it's just stuff that no one else cares about and I don't want to make you care about it.
Scott: I know that.
Scott: see the thing is right.
Scott: I know that guy that guy who comes up to you and tells you all about that thing He really cares about so much that you don't care about at all.
Scott: And that's an annoying guy.
Scott: I want to make go away.
Rym: So Scott the train Tell you about the W train, you know.
Scott: so I do not want to be that guy and that's why I don't use these sorts of things of the day or news.
Scott: is that often?
Scott: but whatever.
Scott: so the most important kpop group in the history of ever is Big Bang Bang bang bang.
Scott: Yeah, right and even if you don't like kpop you must like Big Bang.
Rym: Did they also do that GGGG song?
Rym: No, that was someone else.
Scott: Those are not even the same gender.
Rym: I don't I don't know.
Scott: Big Bang is dudes.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: Anyway, there's In South Korea.
Scott: Military is mandatory.
Scott: It is mandatory conscription, even if you're G dragon You have to go in the military.
Scott: in case they have to shoot North Koreans in the face or get shot by them.
Scott: They have to go to the military for like two years, right?
Scott: Yeah, even if your name is G dragon, so next year Big Bang is gonna go literally bang bang bang Instead of just singing bang bang bang and So the last chance for them to do any music stuff for the next few years is like right now.
Scott: So last year in 2015 They released four little albums of two songs each that were called made.
Scott: the first one is M. The second one was a D and the fourth one Inexplicably was F. We don't really know why and the fourth one was E and that was pretty much the music of the year in Especially the song bang bang bang.
Scott: But they promised that there would be a full album.
Scott: That was just called made.
Scott: Yeah, that didn't happen.
Scott: But now I like the last second.
Scott: before they have to go shoot people or practice shooting fake people They're gonna do it and they've added three new songs Which I forget the names of but it doesn't matter because the first song which I assume is the title song The featured song is called fuck it.
Rym: Yeah, I believe it is technically called fxxk it
Scott: sure But I mean that's a good thing to say if you're about to go Conscription And that's coming out like In a week or two like way soon and that's gonna blow the doors off and you know You might be thinking it's still crappy pop music in the end.
Scott: Yes, and no because let me tell you big bang is unique in the history of boy bands and that unlike all the others They are a actually talented.
Scott: Yeah Be not short-lived Right.
Scott: They've been around for like nine ten years already.
Rym: Say that the new kids on the blog are still around.
Scott: they came back, but they went away.
Scott: Big bang has been there consistently.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: They're doing a tour now.
Scott: Yeah, sure, but they were.
Scott: we went away for like a decade plus.
Scott: yeah, they haven't been around since.
Rym: okay They're 90s.
Rym: So they were only active for a decade sure and now there's been hair back as a Big bang still going.
Scott: they're not.
Scott: they haven't stopped it except if it wasn't for going to the military they'd keep going anyway.
Scott: but also They kind of make their own music sort of right like if you look at the credits It's like, you know music lyrics G Dragon G right and also other people but also them Whereas I don't think the new kids on the block have made a song ever.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: So that's what sets them apart there.
Rym: so I fly a lot and This news some I don't know how many of you fly a lot versus don't fly at all.
Scott: But even if you fly moderately like a few times a year like me, it's enough.
Rym: Yep So United Airlines is not the greatest airline to begin with.
Rym: No, I think that is a bad airline.
Scott: I will say that much.
Rym: I think 3/4 of all the attempts I have ever made to fly with United Aided with me not getting to my destination.
Scott: right now.
Scott: It's not the worst airline like some Ryan air.
Scott: it spirit garbage right, but it's real bad.
Rym: So apparently they announced starting in 2017 that if you have a carry-on bag and You want to put it in the overhead bin?
Rym: It's gonna cost you good.
Scott: Fuck you.
Rym: So on the day, so here's the problem with that.
Rym: I have at least other than the fact that.
Rym: so there's this sort of like, you know, the whole post truth era Thanks to US politics.
Rym: They have been Repeatedly saying all over social media press conferences everywhere that that is not true.
Rym: They're not charging people to put things in the overhead bin.
Rym: What they are doing is on their own words is offering more fare options.
Rym: So there's a lower budget tier of people who have like the no frills experience.
Rym: You can fly somewhere super cheap.
Rym: However, they also say in a separate place that the fares for this new basic economy That does not include bin privileges will be about the same as what their current economy tickets cost, right?
Scott: So the thing is people don't realize this even though I might have explained it on the show before.
Scott: The baggage fees and things like that aren't actually baggage fees.
Scott: What they are is that most people buy plane tickets today from sites like kayak, which are aggregators.
Scott: Yeah And they search for their their home and their destination and they sort by price of the lowest price first and that's what they buy.
Scott: Yeah, whatever is cheapest no matter what right that price that the lowest price Right is the price before all the fees.
Scott: So it's costing you the same if you pay for the checked bag and the overhead bin and the whatever other Privileges.
Scott: you were right.
Scott: It cost you the same as a plane tickets cost before.
Scott: they're just taking as many things out of the base price and moving them to a fee as they can in order to have a Lower advertised price in the aggregator so they can show up first when you search for your tickets Which you're not actually like you.
Scott: it feels like you're getting ripped off when you pay the 20 bucks for your checked bag fee.
Scott: But really it's no.
Scott: you're actually saving 20 bucks for that.
Scott: one time You don't have to check a bag and the 20 bucks you pay when you do check a bag Is it 20 bucks you were gonna pay before?
Rym: in this case Their prices for economy will be the same except by default.
Rym: You don't get bin privileges anymore.
Scott: Well, that's also good.
Rym: So they're not actually lowering the prices.
Scott: Well, that's interesting.
Scott: Yeah, but also fuck people who use the bins.
Rym: I use the bin.
Scott: Here's the bin.
Rym: Well, where do you put your shit?
Rym: Cuz I bring two bags.
Scott: I check my shit.
Rym: Yeah, usually I also check my shit.
Scott: My shit goes under my seat and I check it.
Scott: I don't put anything in the bin.
Scott: There's nothing.
Rym: there is nothing in theory wrong with the bin.
Rym: here are however, my primary complaints about the bin number one.
Rym: People fly with bags that are bigger than you're allowed to and they don't fit in the bin, right?
Scott: There's a thing at the front of the airport That's like here's how big the thing can be and people bring stuff on that's bigger than that thing and no one stops them.
Scott: Right, it shouldn't they enforce it and be like, hey your things too big.
Scott: It's bigger than the metal, you know rectangle primarily a US problem because I want to check that.
Rym: fuck you when I fly overseas I have Repeatedly been getting on flights where they stop someone who said yeah, we're taking that to check it You can't bring it on the plane.
Scott: good.
Rym: I like I see that happen all the time good but at the same time I also fly premium economy or business usually overseas and You remember the fuck you want.
Scott: then they're like, so well if you're paying for, you know Whatever you could bring your check the giant shall I take sirs jacket and hang it in the closets in the golden closet in the golden hanger?
Rym: But to people in general.
Rym: I don't know if this happens elsewhere in the world because I don't have enough sample size of people in general.
Rym: But when I find that you ask a lot of people I see Seem like they pack Way too much shit.
Rym: Like I don't know how long you're going to where you're going.
Rym: There is no way you need that many bags under any circumstances.
Scott: Yeah, unless you're going like Let's say I'm going on a trip for months.
Scott: right like months and months I'm gonna be just permanently away living out of a bag.
Scott: There's a limit to how much stuff that I can is like a maximum, right?
Scott: It's like well This is enough clothes to get from laundry to laundry and it's all the stuff I need to live every day Travel for a month and decide they're never going to do laundry.
Scott: It's like a full set of toiletries the equipment I need for everyday life like computer and camera and whatnot.
Scott: Yeah, electronic bit I even better if I'm going Enough enough clothes to get from one laundry to the next laundry and then that's the maximum I could need no matter how long the Trip is.
Rym: but if I'm going somewhere longer than two weeks, I Actually, like I don't bring any toiletries.
Rym: I buy all that shit in the other destination.
Scott: You can do that, too.
Scott: Yeah, buy some temporary stuff on the other end.
Scott: I mean, I'm sure if the trip is long and if you're gonna be replacing you're gonna run out of soap and have to buy More.
Scott: Yeah, right, but still so.
Rym: the third thing is that a lot of people are getting on planes And I make exception.
Rym: like there are people who have legitimate Handicaps or concerns very.
Scott: they get on first the separate their separate boarding just for them.
Scott: So it's all good.
Rym: the number of able-bodied Young adults who seem to pack bags that they are incapable of lifting over their own heads and putting into the bin Shocks me if you cannot pick up you like I'm weak in the arm Right.
Scott: I can't do the push-up.
Scott: Yeah Like Scott's legit weak in the arm But I can take a bag of luggage a carry-on bag lift it over my head and push it up and down.
Rym: now What I notice is that it doesn't seem to be an issue of strength like these people.
Rym: It's not like they're feeble in some like ridiculous way.
Rym: What I see is that they lack basic coordination and like movement planning abilities.
Rym: The other thing they're standing there and they're like trying to lift it like straight up in front of their body like this and then Turn it like pivot at 90 degrees.
Scott: you put a hand put a hand under it and do like a hookshot Right.
Rym: It's like the people's job.
Rym: I'll be sitting in a plane and these jackasses behind me.
Rym: Well, I grab the top of my seat and yank it like they're killing someone to stand up Like they can't stand up under their own power.
Scott: The other thing is that people can't seem to put a bag in the bin from their seat.
Scott: They have to stand in the aisle making everyone stop walking.
Scott: It's like when I get to my aisle I put it in from the seat I step into the aisle seat letting people go past and I can toss my thing into the bin if I have to.
Scott: I do this on the bus usually right while people are walking past me so I don't delay anyone at all Right.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: this is why it's like screw you people using the bin.
Scott: You're too damn slow, right?
Scott: We just and you're not using anything in that bag on the flight.
Scott: You don't need to bring it on the flight.
Scott: You could check it now.
Rym: So this is where my make my counterpoint to you.
Rym: Most of the time when you fly you do check bags So you getting off the plane those people being slow as fucking delaying you don't actually delay you because there is no way You will get to that carousel after your bags get there.
Scott: Yeah, you know at first I was thinking yeah You know these people right?
Scott: It's like if we.
Scott: it's like that time you're losing boarding and D planning with all these slowness of people who can't deal with the bins.
Scott: Oh, it's like if you save that time then suddenly, you know That's that's way more time than the time you're losing waiting for the carousel.
Scott: But it's also true that even with the slow as D planning I have never gotten to the carousel before it starts moving and spitting bags out.
Rym: now I have.
Rym: but that's just because if I do if you do fly business class one of the secrets is they let you off the plane like right away, even if they don't let the economy people off and Those bags are flagged and they're almost always waiting for you.
Rym: But like
Scott: they go up to the plane right away open it up take those bags out and rush them over to the carousel They put them
Rym: in a separate like you'll see a little car sometimes depending on the flight Run off the plane
Scott: grab bags and then run back to.
Scott: the
Rym: Bags are usually put together in one area and
Scott: then they and then someone comes to get the rest of the bags like yeah
Rym: All right I have more than half the time when I fly business like get gotten to the carousel and my bags are not even going around.
Rym: They're just sitting with all the other business class bags next to the carousel like waiting for me.
Rym: There's usually a person standing there But I don't get like.
Rym: I don't fly business in my normal life Like I only get to do that when I'm traveling for work because somehow that's separate from life.
Scott: Well, it's dead.
Rym: Well in that I'm not paying for it.
Rym: I would not pay that much money to fly If I were.
Rym: I'd have to be pretty rich to where that amount of money would seem like.
Rym: okay, whatever it's worth it.
Rym: Yeah But you also like you don't lose that time in the way in either because it feels like it takes everyone forever to get on The plane but the plane scheduled leave at a time.
Scott: Anyway, now there's only one counter-argument to this right which is if this is across the board.
Scott: You know Deplaning and planning times or deep boarding times were decreased because of people not loading bins and not being able to close them and all that Other bullshit.
Scott: they could reschedule the plane.
Rym: Nope, because all they would do is start boarding later.
Scott: They could flight leaves at six.
Scott: they could add extra flights and squish it.
Scott: JetBlue actually one of their big deals was like hey look we can like land a plane and just take it off again real quick Because like we're cleaning the plane while it's in flight saving time.
Scott: You could save a lot more time if you didn't have any bins on there and right.
Scott: it's like yeah.
Scott: But then air airport slots, which you know I'm just saying is like, you know, they were all about saving those few minutes not having to clean the plane.
Scott: Yeah, you could save a lot more minutes by not dealing with these stupid bins.
Rym: Also the last few times I've flown JetBlue the planes are kind of dirty.
Scott: so What plane is super clean and fancy?
Scott: That's not a luxury amazing plane.
Rym: Actually domestic Delta flights are usually pretty good.
Rym: Mm-hmm Like I. actually I flew enough this year for the first time in my life I've status so I get like all the free upgrades.
Rym: It's weird.
Rym: The problem is I don't know if I'll fly enough next year to maintain it.
Rym: So I'll get one year of this and I got to go back to pleb land.
Rym: But the I guess the final thing is that when I do fly and I don't check bags It's always because I'm doing a short trip.
Rym: like one time I flew to Hong Kong and I was literally only gonna be there for a couple days.
Rym: So I just brought a backpack and in that case put it under your seat.
Rym: No, it wouldn't fit.
Rym: It was a. it was a like carry on back, but at least it's small, right?
Scott: So like
Rym: it was the size that you are officially allowed to put in the bin
Scott: I mean if you put that in the bin It's not sticking way out and not being able to close not some hard rectangular thing that's like five inches too long
Rym: that the lady puts in sideways because it doesn't fit and she's trying to hide that fact before the Stewardess comes and takes it away.
Rym: Yeah and gay checks it.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: I don't know the moral is.
Rym: I hate everyone I fly with and Mary flying domestically is just awful.
Scott: I think the rule should simply be this right if your bag is you know a bag with a firm Rectangular shape and wheels and such you have to check that shit.
Scott: That's not dumb.
Rym: I think it with a better way.
Scott: we're going in the bin.
Scott: It's gotta be squishy.
Rym: No, the the real way to handle that which is how some airlines do handle it.
Rym: if it goes in the bin It has to go in the official way and if you can't fit it in that way they take it away from me.
Rym: They don't let you fly and they tase you.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Rym: So see I have a more relaxed rule, but a more severe punishment.
Rym: I Think the real fundamental problem though is just that this is sort of like almost systemic of just American culture in general which I think is actually driven by the fact that our economy has gotten kind of increasingly Fucked and there's a huge gulf between have enough money to live and don't have enough money to live.
Rym: that Flying either.
Rym: you just buy normal tickets and don't care cuz like you're like us like we're flying to pegs We just buy whatever ticket and we're not gonna ever fly like crapos spirit.
Rym: But if you don't have a lot of money and you've got to fly to like a wedding or a funeral or something Even even if you might argue like culturally Americans just get the cheapest one.
Rym: They don't care about the quality.
Rym: There's no like middle ground anymore.
Rym: There arguably might not be enough of a middle class to pay for or demand that middle ground.
Rym: That's why premium economy is like two rows of seats and then there's like a hundred rows of shit economy.
Scott: So I think there's also like regulations about how many rows of what you know, you can't just make a whole flight.
Scott: That's first class.
Rym: So premium economy counts as economy because they're in the same Like this, you know those rules.
Scott: they can't just do whatever they want.
Rym: Well, the rules are why we don't need every every couple years like because people on LinkedIn like to share this shit all the time That concept design of these standing airplane.
Rym: Ooh Meaning you can buy a super cheap seat, but you stand leaning against this like pad with armrests Hmm, and it's all short flight as is cheap enough.
Rym: Yeah, you're what's wrong with America's got?
Rym: I like standing Stay on a plane for an hour.
Scott: Oh the front like the seats are not really that comfortable.
Scott: right standing might be more comfortable for depending on people.
Scott: Yeah for me It might.
Rym: anyway the rules prevent that kind of thing because that exceeds the density you're allowed in the case.
Scott: I assume that's also dangerous even though it might be more comfortable.
Rym: There may not be depending on who you are But I just people usually like to cite things like this as an example of how Americans go for the cheapest bullshit.
Scott: Why can't we have a plane with like bunk beds, right?
Scott: So it's like I could be on tier.
Scott: like you could use the height of the plane to fit more people.
Scott: I actually know why I could lay down and be on the third way up top.
Scott: I don't care.
Scott: At least I'm laying down.
Scott: everyone's laying down horizontally.
Scott: You can't get more comfortable than that.
Rym: Have you seen the concept designs to put two seats like this and then one seat kind of up and one seat kind of down to like stagger and out?
Rym: the problem with all those fancy designs like the bunk beds is They're fine for flying.
Rym: they are in patently unsafe and deadly.
Rym: in an emergency.
Rym: You can't evacuate that plane quickly.
Scott: I'm fine with that.
Rym: Yeah egress is the reason why?
Rym: Cool designs like that don't work.
Rym: the FAA regulations on egress are very strict And in fact the fact that they're so strict is probably the only reason you can still sit down on a plane.
Scott: I don't need to egress if I'm gonna.
Scott: if I'm gonna die I'm gonna die.
Scott: Right, it's like I'll be super luxurious.
Scott: I'll be lying down horizontally taking a nap on every flight except for the one flight that crashes.
Rym: Okay in the words of Homer Simpson, I had a good run.
Scott: Yeah, that's good.
Rym: But anyway things of the day.
Rym: so every time you know, if you build computers all the time or You're in high school and you're a nerd You just always stay on top of like the current state of computer building design in general.
Scott: But I only stay on top of those times when I have to build the PC and otherwise I forget and I don't see what's happening.
Scott: And when I check again, it's like oh look at everything that's changed.
Rym: so subtle things that have actually changed in the last five or six years that you might not expect like Like water cooling five years ago was dumb and now like it's kind of matter now.
Scott: You can't get yourself wet.
Scott: but
Rym: the best that the thing that we have now like way more than we've ever had before is that you can just go to YouTube and there will be like a hundred videos of people installing the Exact weird thing you bought in the exact case you have with the exact motherboard and the exact everything,
Scott: right?
Scott: It's like back in the day I used to just go to Newegg and you have to look at the reviews and it's a look at the questions and look at All the specs to figure out like it's all this stuff gonna work together.
Scott: But now I mean you're we're normal people.
Scott: we're gonna buy this stuff on Newegg.
Scott: That's super popular.
Scott: We're not buying some rare one egg stuff, right?
Scott: We're buying the highly rated stuff that everyone else is buying.
Scott: There's already thousands and thousands of people who have bought the exact same product and PC building is a big industry that makes a lot of money.
Scott: So, of course, there's people on YouTube making videos of building PCs all over the place.
Scott: You can get all your questions and all those little fiddly subtleties of the exact stuff you're thinking about buying by watching a YouTube video of someone else who bought the same thing already and it Answers the good that.
Rym: the thing they helped me with in particular is they answer the questions You're not really sure about like like.
Scott: how exactly do I mount this?
Rym: Yeah, this back panel does it go on front ways or back ways?
Rym: because it kind of fits both ways, right?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: will this video card actually fit in this case?
Scott: It says it will.
Scott: it's like.
Scott: it says it's a. you know Short enough, but I'm gonna put this radiator in there.
Scott: Is that measurement include the space of the radiator or not?
Rym: now as an aside?
Rym: It looks like the better channels here like this video.
Rym: I'm gonna link to from this channel I found only has like 200,000 views and it looks like The companies all I can tell and g-skill and aces just give her Everything.
Scott: Yeah, if you're making videos of products and reviewing them and making high-quality youtubes people sponsor you with stuffs.
Scott: That's how it works.
Rym: But this channel Joanne tech lover is actually pretty great for this.
Rym: So it's my thing of the day and I'll link to a particular video from it.
Rym: The title is Skylake build part 1 LGA 1151 z170 ddr4 USB 3.1 and she also puts in the Kraken x61.
Scott: If that's a. if you're buying a gaming PC today, that's what you're gonna buy.
Rym: Yeah, you're gonna build this exact computer just in case December 2016.
Scott: Seriously.
Rym: I'll get a different case because the case she's building is Radonculous.
Rym: it is so big and so crazy Trying to get to it.
Scott: Also that RAM looks dumb, but not as dumb as your RAM.
Rym: Yeah, because you're the public.
Rym: all g-skill RAM looks dumb.
Rym: He's gonna live with it or pay.
Rym: you actually have to pay more to get less dumb-looking RAM.
Scott: Yeah, actually crucial RAM is more expensive But it's just RAM chips the RAM I bought.
Rym: the reason I got it is that a lot of the higher-end Spec ddr4, especially if you get a 16 gigabyte module, which you got to get They actually run a little over voltage which can over time fuck up your core i7.
Rym: interesting.
Rym: So make sure if you have DDR and also people are dumb and like they don't realize that ddr3 and 4 are different.
Rym: DDR4 is 1.2 volts.
Rym: never ever use RAM that says it uses more than 1.2 volts ever.
Rym: If you think you're the exception you're not.
Rym: And it don't.
Rym: and if you start saying well, what about ddr3 LV shut up?
Scott: So you gotta think of the day.
Scott: I do so, you know often in the past you've had things of the day Pertaining to the other Korea the North Korea best.
Scott: I'm doing it to Korea the day, right?
Scott: There's only one Korea.
Scott: No this too.
Scott: So At least now there is and there didn't used to be and there might not be in the future, but there is now.
Scott: yeah, so North under our former North Korean things of the day have usually been like Russian guy takes train into North Korea takes photos or Someone goes into North Korea officially here.
Scott: photos.
Scott: they took Accounts of a person who went there and interviewed, you know, whatever.
Rym: well like that heart-wrenching one of the guy who escaped.
Scott: and right Here is something I have never seen before ever.
Scott: These are people who escaped.
Scott: they are North Koreans.
Scott: They live there their whole lives and then got away.
Scott: The one girl got away by going over the frozen river into China during the winter.
Scott: Oh just by walking over the ice ice right not getting shot.
Scott: and They're in South Korea now and this person just interviews them about what North Korea is actually like.
Scott: this looks Fastness is information.
Scott: That is none of its information that like you completely wouldn't expect.
Scott: like nothing.
Scott: that'll like blow you away But it's like.
Scott: it's more like confirmation right of like things you think you know are definitely for reals and It's like whoa.
Scott: that person actually lived there and they got away whoa.
Rym: Those perspectives are also just very interesting and I've never seen anything like this before.
Scott: I'm sure someone will point to some link somewhere where other escaped people, right?
Scott: But this is the first one I've seen.
Rym: yeah, well, especially because it's more.
Rym: well I haven't watched the video yet But I was clicking around through it and looking at some of the comments.
Rym: what the questions are?
Rym: This looks like very more like daily life and like from the perspective of someone Who lived there then saw real Korea and the rest of the world and then had that perspective like all at once over time.
Rym: in the moment the book club book is Rebecca some listener tweeted me like they finished it already and I'm like, all right I'll start reading it cuz I just finished.
Rym: well, so I watched a bunch of Black Mirror Netflix on my phone with the download mode.
Rym: It works great.
Rym: Okay, like mirrors super good It's and it's only like seven episodes total and they're all.
Rym: they're basically all mini movies Like kind of Asimov style like short sci-fi dystopian pointed.
Scott: Anyway, oh, it's like the Twilight Zone Yeah, but all focused around.
Rym: Yeah, I'll show you one but they're like one of them that you'll probably really like.
Rym: It's just this story about this world where people are like riding on exercise bikes and doing things and they get merits And then they use those merits to like trick out their avatars But they don't seem to actually interact in the real world anymore.
Rym: And it's just.
Rym: it's real.
Rym: It's like that Harrison Bergeron made-for-tv move and I already know this story, but it's not the Harrison Bergeron story It's just like that.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: It's not the story of make everyone the same It's a way different story and it's just way good.
Rym: But I watched all that and I read all that.
Scott: Is it the rat in the treadmill story?
Scott: Cuz it's just the matrix.
Rym: No, it's.
Rym: it's not that either It's.
Rym: I was surprised and very interested in how that episode ended Surprised at many things that don't surprise me.
Rym: Ah, very little surprises me But anyway, I'm done with all those things.
Rym: I'm gonna start reading Rebecca tomorrow.
Scott: If anyone doesn't I mean like.
Scott: if anyone doesn't know why we inappropriately go Rebecca We should link to cat bug.
Rym: I'll link to cat bug.
Rym: Otherwise.
Rym: the GeekNights Politics Club is also doing his thing.
Scott: It is Rym and Scott but a different Scott because bad Scott.
Rym: Yeah, that Scott's pretty good bad.
Rym: And the first book we did we recorded the first of two episodes about it And the second episode will be up pretty soon.
Rym: It's Evans the coming of the Third Reich Might be a little on the nose.
Rym: I'd recommend you read that book and just synthesize the information in it and decide Why don't we read the going of the Third Reich?
Rym: Uh That's just every World War two book.
Rym: I did just read a couple of books about that like the you know The end of World War two.
Rym: all that nonsense.
Rym: the next book in the GeekNights Politics Club I'll post a link to it, but it's basically a book on the current modern history of voter suppression.
Rym: So we'll be doing that and we doing podcast.
Rym: It'll be Rym Scott and Andrew.
Rym: Yeah different Scott.
Rym: Yeah, you know you want to talk about real things.
Rym: I just want to talk about Rebecca.
Rym: Yeah, check out the GeekNights YouTube channel, which is actually just my channel and Scott's channel.
Rym: They both have stuff Scott still has not uploaded.
Scott: When was I supposed to do this?
Scott: between the past two days?
Scott: the world wonders When what what what hour during the past two days I supposed to do this And we will be live at Pac South.
Rym: at least one of our panels is Scheduled and that is going to be in the cactus theater on Friday January 27th at 4 p.m We are doing another iteration of that grinding panel.
Scott: cactus isn't an animal.
Rym: I Guess that's true.
Rym: Huh end of an era.
Scott: it's not even a fictional animal.
Rym: Well, maybe cactus is the name for an animal in a fantasy world.
Scott: Could it at least been the cactuar theater?
Rym: Yeah, it sure that might be trademarked.
Scott: I don't give a shit.
Rym: Yeah Anyway, this is similar to the grind panel we did before but updated with much more information and sort of focus better.
Rym: So We might do other panels, we'll see.
Rym: if that happens We'll also be a magfest being on like five panels.
Scott: a magfest concert schedule was released.
Rym: I didn't even looked at it yet I also saw some rumblings.
Rym: I didn't look into what this is yet.
Rym: Multiple people have said there appears to be a Castlevania themed escape the room puzzle at magfest this year.
Scott: It was a. the poster that listed all the concerts was Castlevania themed.
Scott: Yeah, also You know machine everything Is playing magfest again and Immediately afterwards they are going on the US tour.
Scott: So they're gonna play New York like immediately after magfest and daddy can't - yeah but If you don't aren't live in magfest territory, you should go and see where they at.
Scott: Yeah, at least get a fraction of a magfest near you.
Scott: So there you go speaking of Castlevania themes.
Rym: if you're a patron of the patreon for GeekNights I am reading like an e-book the entirety of FX 9's worlds of power Castlevania 2 Simon's Quest novel ization.
Rym: So in my bathroom, well one of the two bathrooms in this apartment, but you have a concern in there.
Scott: Well, I have.
Scott: so I don't mind that concern.
Scott: I don't have any concerns whatsoever.
Rym: It is my.
Rym: it's one of the favorite things in my house your bathroom.
Rym: No in the bathroom group sign I have a poop sign right?
Rym: It's shaped like a stop sign, but it says the word poop and it is set down Low so that if you sit down to say have a poop It is staring you directly in the face at eye level
Scott: and telling you not to poop Or telling you to stop and poop.
Rym: this comes up every time.
Scott: this sign is Sorry, a stop sign says stop on.
Scott: it's telling you what to do.
Scott: Yeah, but a sign that is shaped like a stop sign Even if it doesn't say stop on it is somehow still saying stop but when it has the word poop on it, it's sort of telling you to poop and But it's also telling you to stop.
Rym: Yeah, but the way I handle this is a simple series of two questions.
Rym: I ask a person.
Rym: What do you do to stop sign stop?
Rym: What do you do to poop sign?
Scott: But it's not a poop sign.
Scott: It's a stop sign.
Rym: It's a poop sign that has a shape like a stop sign.
Scott: It's like it's like when the word green is written in the color blue.
Rym: I Always crack up a little bit when I see that ever since Ever since it was pointed out to me that that's a thing because I had never encountered that in my life You write the word yellow with a red pen.
Rym: Yeah, it's good stuff.
Rym: That's probably the most interesting feature of my bathroom those that poop sign.
Scott: my bathroom doesn't have interesting features I thought we were gonna talk about like shampoo soaps and things.
Rym: those are concerns the bathroom.
Rym: We start.
Rym: we'll start with the products of the bathroom.
Rym: What kind of soaps do you use in the bathroom?
Scott: So this is actually a big deal.
Scott: So for my whole life at first when I was young days, right the baby times I used the Johnson baby oil, which is the Shampooing the nut for everything right?
Scott: It was like the.
Scott: no more tears.
Rym: No more tears my ass just as many tears.
Scott: Yeah, it's lying first But it is safe for babies.
Scott: if you have a baby or you're tiny.
Scott: That's what you should use the baby so that you know that you know the shit I'm talking about.
Rym: How does that pain notice?
Scott: how that product doesn't have a lot of competitors?
Scott: Yeah, it's cuz it's legit.
Scott: And after that, I would use the most cheapo gennaro soaps.
Scott: I could get the ones that smelled good like.
Rym: yeah I smelled a little.
Rym: so the problem is that occasionally when you like RIT you'd use like the cheapo shit soaps Like we had the Irish sprang.
Scott: all that meant was an Irish spring.
Scott: Irish spring is actually way better than that free stuff We got.
Rym: yeah, that free stuff was the worst.
Scott: Yeah, but disintegrated.
Rym: and the times you would use the Irish spring.
Scott: all that man I didn't use.
Scott: I never used Irish spring in my life.
Rym: Whatever bar soap you use I use coasts that you said smelled good.
Scott: It does smell good.
Scott: Oh, it smells like you're like it's like it makes you feel like you're on the beach.
Scott: It's like it has pictures of waves on it But like I know that's just marketing but literally like if I bust out a bar coast It feels like aha Beach.
Scott: Aha, and then if you use it while you're at the beach and outside shower for some reason it just doubles in power somehow.
Rym: from My perspective it just smelled violently like soap like you smelled so strongly of soap that it was notable.
Scott: Smells like it's.
Scott: now it feels like you're on the like the tropical.
Scott: It's so good.
Scott: It's just.
Scott: it's like this our and it makes you feel so clean to it like oops My all the oil just cuz like blasted away from your body.
Scott: Like you just got hit with like an anti-oil fire hose.
Scott: It's like boosh.
Rym: So my whole life I used for shampoo at least in soap, especially soap Whatever the family bought because I was a kid.
Rym: I didn't give a shit.
Scott: One of my family had their own biz.
Scott: There were five people there were five shampoos There were five people in five soaps.
Rym: See, I feel like other people in the family like cared more and like bought different stuff.
Rym: But I just used randomly whatever was in the shower when I went to use the shower Mm-hmm.
Scott: And when I went as soon as I did that in other people's houses sometimes.
Scott: Yeah, but not in my own house.
Rym: but when I got to RIT and I had to get so I Decided to be modern and use only like basic liquid soap.
Rym: No bar soap.
Rym: No that old-style nonsense.
Scott: Yeah, I did for you know, I was I was buying like Swayve Yeah, and you know very Gennaro soaps.
Rym: I think I bought some fruity one like fuck to see something because it was on sale at Wegmans Like it was all day on sale.
Scott: It was also a time in my life when I had some dandruff actions and I was buying the strongest shit We got to separate between shampoo and so very different discussions.
Scott: But anyway, the point is, you know, I was using coast and I was using Gennaro liquid soaps.
Scott: But eventually, you know, I went on Amazon and I searched and I searched.
Scott: I'm like I need to fight.
Scott: You know cuz like.
Scott: usually when you use a product like you're way happy with it.
Rym: You're like wow This is the shit for me, but or you don't notice it and don't think about it, right?
Scott: But like liquid soap I realize like hey I keep buying whatever is cheap because I don't like whatever I buy.
Scott: like I'm not super in love with any of these.
Scott: Let me find a soap for the shower that like I'm fucking down with and I found the greatest shit.
Scott: It is Neutrogena rain bath.
Rym: you and your fucking Neutrogena.
Rym: You're like obsessed with this stuff I don't know.
Rym: So Neutrogena rain bath is like yes, we know it's pronounced Neutrogena Scott's just weird.
Scott: Yeah, so you can buy it in like this giant, you know liquid plunger thing and it's what like a gallon It's really.
Scott: it's like a liter bottle with this with a plunger on top Because it's really style.
Scott: it's really expensive but you got to see you gotta buy it in bulk to get value, right?
Scott: But when you use it, it feels and smells like luxury hotel.
Scott: It's like ah luxury Oh, so now it's like every single time I take a shower.
Scott: I feel like I'm in a five-star hotels.
Scott: The great.
Scott: it's totally worth the five to ten dollars more it costs compared to the genero.
Scott: So so I was usually gets you so clean and like a tiny bit lathers up like crazy like other soaps that were cheap.
Scott: I'd have to use a whole bunch of it to get it to lather enough.
Scott: But like the rain bath I can plunge like half a plunge even and it'll go into the foofy the poof.
Rym: Oh, you use the loofa.
Scott: Yeah, you I bought like a bag of like cuz the poofs quality is like you can't find a good one.
Scott: So I bought a bag of like 20 cheap ones.
Scott: Like I have a sack of them.
Scott: so I like half half a plunge onto a poof will make a Million suds everywhere and you can shower your whole body.
Rym: Interesting because I You I you when I was younger.
Rym: I'd use washcloths for the washing.
Rym: I still use a washcloth like on my face and say RIT I would use like I had a loofah or two or whatever for the last decade.
Rym: I don't use anything.
Scott: You my hands you just put goop on your hand and so and I get any friction the fraud.
Scott: So I went to a dermatologist for an on.
Rym: this is like a decade ago to cut out like an unrelated like little cyst I had like on my face a little tiny one.
Rym: and They you know, I feel like dermatologists.
Rym: if you come in for something minor They just really want to tell you all this advice about skin.
Scott: Yeah but every other every dermatologist tell you something different.
Rym: so this one was just like Cuz I cuz.
Rym: I was just asked me all these questions about skin and everything and she was like So what do you wash with?
Rym: I was like I use a loofah.
Rym: she's like, yeah that pretty much just like Exfoliates you for no reason and it'll actually make you more prone to acne or whatever.
Rym: Like you'll get more pimples and stuff.
Rym: and I was like sure I do.
Rym: and she was like look at your fingers My fingers and she's like they've got little ridges.
Rym: They got friction.
Rym: Just use your fingers.
Rym: They'll be fine.
Rym: Uh-huh, so I started doing that and it was great.
Scott: and I had a biology teacher in high school ones.
Scott: He said yeah, I ain't gonna vaccines and I didn't get any polio.
Scott: So it'll be fine up.
Rym: So I just want out.
Rym: do I smell bad?
Rym: Have I've gotten a stye in the entire time that you've known me.
Scott: I don't really pay attention to anyone's styes I've ever got.
Scott: you don't smell good.
Scott: You don't smell like luxury hotel like I do.
Rym: I think I smell pretty good.
Rym: No, I think I smell more like like a human as opposed to a luxury hotel.
Scott: Wouldn't you rather smell?
Scott: Or a human who just stayed in a luxury hotel?
Rym: But so I do use soap now But I use that shitty liquid soap at RIT for like couple years same same deal as you buy the cheapest crap.
Scott: Never liked it when I ran out didn't have a lot of money.
Rym: Yeah, I'd buy whatever the cheapest crap was and one day I ran out of soap and I just kept washing myself.
Rym: I just basically would rub myself down with my hands with the water and I'd shampoo But I would never soap.
Rym: Well also and that worked fine and I stopped using soap for like six years.
Scott: That's gross.
Scott: Also You know what?
Scott: It is true.
Rym: No, it was like I was fine.
Scott: Sure It is true to some extent at the greatest trick the devil ever pulled is telling you that shampoo and soap are two different things.
Rym: So there are differences.
Scott: there are but you can if you have.
Scott: you can clean your body with shampoo and you can clean your body.
Scott: Let's clean your hair with soap.
Rym: No, so if your hair is longer than like two inches You cannot clean your hair with soap.
Rym: I'll fuck your hair up.
Scott: Also while you must use soap on your body I don't think you have to in the shower.
Scott: Do not have to actually use shampoo or any sort of thing to clean your hair.
Scott: You can clean your hair with just water it depends.
Rym: so Dandruff has also been a problem for me.
Scott: So yeah, so dandruff is a different issue.
Scott: But if you're just talking about cleaning hair without a dandruff problem, you just need to what you know water.
Rym: So I use dandruff shampoo occasionally like whenever I need to but if I don't use that I don't use any shampoo ever So I don't have hair.
Scott: Yeah, you still get dandruff.
Scott: So the secret I learned right is cuz actually I'm not really shit.
Scott: I don't really have dandruff as a problem anymore.
Scott: I have this thing called the seborrheic dermatitis.
Rym: No, cuz that's what I get.
Scott: It's called tinea versicolor.
Rym: Oh, we have two different dandruff.
Scott: So tinea versicolor is not a dandruff.
Scott: It is a fungus.
Rym: Oh I know why you and fungus is.
Scott: it's basically there's like this yeast that's everywhere right tinea and on some people their skin goes ah yeast and makes like colors and Most people it doesn't.
Scott: but for some they don't even know.
Scott: like they don't even know about this Like I don't think anyone's researching it enough or anyone cares.
Rym: Oh, well, yeah The info is like em.
Scott: a lot of people get this because it doesn't do anything to you.
Scott: It just shows up as like colored patches on your body.
Scott: Yeah, and the way to make it go away is with selenium sulfide.
Scott: So when I went to a dermatologist they prescribed for me like 2% selenium sulfide and the instructions were like Shampoo your body with this and wait a while and then rinse it off.
Scott: but selenium sulfide is the same thing.
Scott: that's in Selson which is selenium salt, right?
Scott: Yep.
Scott: It's in the name now.
Rym: before that I remember you used to use the stuff that had like coal tar in it, but that's carcinogenic, right?
Scott: Well tea people didn't know that when I was using it first of all And that was I used that like way back in the day and that was for dandruff.
Scott: now that I have no hair Right.
Scott: I'm mostly.
Scott: I'm worried about this, you know versicolor.
Rym: So shit, I don't get like nor like, you know, it's stereotypical like dandruffy people Like there's just white flakes like all over their clothes.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: I don't get that.
Rym: I get the seborrheic dermatitis style.
Rym: or basically if I don't use a dandruff shampoo on a regular basis Then if you did like if I dig my fingers into my scalp and I go like this I'll pull out a bunch of flakes, but they don't come out on their own.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: But if I use this stuff it basically is a hundred percent not there at all.
Scott: So the seek.
Scott: so the thing is I start.
Scott: I tried to use the selced instead of the prescription For the same thing cuz I didn't renew the prescription in time and I ran out so and it wasn't working.
Scott: But then I realized and this is important if you read the instructions It says leave that shit on your head it don't just rinse it out right away like normal shampoo.
Scott: So when I was like, oh, maybe I'll actually try doing that like it.
Scott: see it works doesn't?
Rym: it's like night and day.
Scott: The instructions also tell you like do it twice and I'm like, that's bullshit.
Scott: You're trying to make me waste product and spend twice as much money Which they are.
Scott: but what I do is I get in the shower and I put it on my head Yep, and I don't rinse it off until the very end of the shower same strategy.
Scott: and now tinea versicolor No longer shows up like on my shoulders or my back or anywhere where it used to show up You know, even though I'm only putting it on my head.
Scott: I guess it sort of flows down, right?
Rym: Yeah, well, so the funny thing is with the with the dandruff you stuff I'll get it on my head like that's normal But if I if I'm not careful It'll appear in my sideburns and occasionally on like one area of my chest the exact same area.
Rym: So I wash those areas with selson, but I don't otherwise use soap in those areas.
Scott: So you just you got to put it on there and at the beginning of the shower and rinse it off at the end And that's long enough for it to sort of have its effects.
Scott: Yep, well son if you do that every shower, you'll be fine.
Scott: those instructions were there for a reason But don't do it two times because then you're just wasting stuff and spending twice as much money.
Rym: Yep, but Intern conditioner, I guess you don't know.
Scott: also, you know, we weren't paid to promote any of these products In any way shape or form in case anyone was thinking that.
Rym: so, oh, yeah.
Rym: So before I get to condition, I haven't used soap for many years, but I started using soap again recently.
Rym: Oh, you started using soap because Emily's mom got me just as a gift randomly a bunch of other other stuff this like bar.
Rym: So like fancy bars though, weren't you all like?
Scott: bar soap is the worst Cuz.
Rym: I had a hitherto every bar So but ever used been some like Irish sprang bullshit.
Scott: coast is so good coast is not good.
Scott: I still you like even though I clean it myself with a rain bath I still use coast to like clean up between my toes and stuff like that.
Rym: Ah so I Usually I've scrubbed my feet more so than put soap on them.
Scott: Hmm.
Scott: I mean, you know, it's gonna get some soap down.
Rym: Yeah, but you use the heavy scrubbing, but this soap has like big chunks of salt embedded in it everywhere.
Scott: So make to make it scratching.
Rym: Yep, and it's just like the most comfortable soap.
Rym: So I use it now, but I only.
Rym: I basically only does the George Carlin.
Rym: I wash the.
Scott: you could always use lava soap if you want scratchiness.
Rym: So I also super clean eyes separately have some.
Rym: it's basically lava.
Rym: So like that kind of.
Scott: so you're gonna get the lava brand lava soap.
Rym: Yeah, it's not long It's not.
Rym: it's not the full-on pumice II situation.
Scott: Oh, that's so good.
Rym: It's got real lie in it and I use that if I get like Bicycle grease on my hands lava soap.
Scott: It's always good to have one bar of actual lava brand lava.
Scott: So but that's what we used to use back in like art class when we were kids Clean paint and stuff.
Rym: I used it as a fireman to get you know fire off his head.
Scott: It's like when you're in a situation where like you're not taking a shower or something You are just literally usually your hands But any part of your body is actually filthy from something and you must get it clean.
Scott: something like grease Right.
Scott: It is like it is.
Scott: it's pumice.
Scott: It works based on friction.
Scott: It is the powerful soaps.
Scott: It will get the job done.
Scott: You got to have some of that because you never know when you're gonna like get something gross all over you from a dirty job.
Rym: So I guess you don't use conditioner.
Scott: I've never used conditioner.
Scott: I in fact once I bought a conditioner by accident and I couldn't figure out like how it worked cuz like it was.
Scott: so the like the The liquid was such that like I couldn't even get it had hair.
Scott: Then I bought a conditioner by accident thinking it was shampoo, but I literally couldn't get it in my hair.
Scott: It was like a almost nearly solid kind of goop.
Scott: It didn't work.
Rym: So what's interesting is that if your hair is short, you pretty much don't need conditioner.
Rym: You only really need it if your hair is like fucked up in some way.
Scott: I mean I've used.
Scott: there were times when I used a shampoo that was also a conditioner and I didn't notice any difference between That and a regular shampoo.
Scott: The only thing I use conditioner for cuz remember I don't really use Conditioner is like a made-up product just to get by more.
Rym: So here's the main thing is long, right?
Rym: My hair gets like a little bit tangled over the course of day like tangles appear The you put the conditioner in my hand.
Scott: I mean if you put a bunch of wires next to each other they get tied in dots just naturally.
Scott: So
Rym: all I use conditioner for is I put it in my hair and then while I'm in the shower While the conditioner is in my hair I take a wide-tooth comb and I comb my hair and the conditioner is like the lubricant to untangle the hair 100% and then I rinse it out and that's what I usually for that.
Rym: No shampoo does not lubricate.
Rym: shampoo in fact dries out reduces the oil makes the tangle more Mm-hmm.
Rym: So the conditioner replenishes.
Scott: my you know Co method would mark on my you know bucket of cables.
Rym: Spray conditioner into your Christmas lights and then start combing them and see what happens.
Scott: It could work.
Rym: that could be a funny YouTube video.
Rym: Sure.
Rym: That'd be like a key and peel.
Scott: So Shaving wise I you already talked about shaving in a whole episode.
Rym: we can so I changed though for a long way back.
Rym: you and I both use the the like pre-whipped bowl of fancy.
Scott: I still use the premium bowl of fancy stuff.
Scott: one bowl last me like five years.
Rym: Yeah, I have one.
Rym: You know that fancy soap I start was using That stuff is the best shaving soap I've ever used in my life.
Rym: You're using the same soap for your body and your shave So I have to pie of a puck of it that I got Four years ago.
Rym: that is in my shaving cup and it's fine and I use it every time I shave.
Rym: It is like it is the best shave like fuck every other shaving soap I have ever used.
Rym: using this soap in a shaving cup is like the best.
Scott: I've used different soaps and I haven't noticed a difference really well I think they're all good enough.
Rym: my beard II gets thicker than yours.
Rym: I also do a for I do an against-the-grain shave like super close.
Rym: Mm-hmm, which I think you don't do for curly reasons.
Scott: I'm just sad.
Scott: Any difference between any soaps besides how they smell.
Rym: I've noticed significant differences.
Rym: granted Of course the bigger difference is gotta actually change your blade regularly, but mmm the soap makes a big difference.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So blades I've been by.
Scott: I bought on Amazon like 10 pack like 10 different blades.
Rym: Try them all.
Rym: the Ross free platinum is still like the Merkur one.
Rym: like every other blade has been garbage.
Scott: No, the Merkur one's actually not so good.
Rym: Ross free the food good one.
Scott: Not the cheap one I don't know, but the one that I tried.
Scott: that was actually way good.
Scott: like of the pack.
Scott: There was like a whole bunch of different ones in there and I'm like surprised that all these blades are still made Like there was one with a soccer ball on it.
Scott: They're like so many different kinds.
Scott: It was kind of hilarious, right?
Rym: Like that is the best blade still.
Scott: I couldn't believe that there were so many but the one that I of the pack.
Scott: So I haven't even finished the pack.
Scott: There are ten blades in there.
Scott: I bought it like over a year ago It's how outright but there was one that said feather on it.
Rym: And now that's the alternative brand.
Rym: That's like the second one.
Scott: That was the best one.
Scott: yet was the one that said feather.
Scott: It was so sharp and it lasted a little bit longer than the other ones and whatnot.
Scott: So if I had to buy a whole pack of blades that were all the same and not a sampler I would get the feather one.
Scott: I still think depending how much it costs.
Scott: I prefer the Merkur But I also those one that was like bluebird.
Scott: That one was really bad.
Scott: I got you.
Scott: you couldn't even use it.
Scott: once I had to throw it out.
Scott: It sucked.
Rym: but I use feather blades in because I have a little.
Rym: I have another shaving key another device basically that I bought years ago that I've been using and It takes this tiny like weird quarter blade.
Rym: That's like wide on one end and it's like three millimeters wide on the on the small end And I use it just to shave the tiny bits of hair that grow right at the inside of the bottom of my nose Because I can't shave that with my big razor.
Scott: I just sort of pull my nose up and shave you with my real razor.
Rym: I've tried that but I've cut myself a few times.
Rym: My nose has like a little ridge there.
Scott: That's just you know.
Scott: Yeah, it's a little bit annoying.
Scott: I could see how a specialized tool would make that nice.
Scott: I just don't feel like it's necessary.
Scott: Especially to buy something needs reusable blades just to do that one tiny thing.
Scott: So the other thing I sometimes like if it's really bad It is one that I can't get with it.
Scott: I'll just get a scissor in there.
Rym: but it also means I can shave my eyebrows and like do a little bit of sculpting and Stuff if I need to.
Scott: yeah, I don't shave my eyebrows.
Rym: I do otherwise they get a little they get Bell dandy thick.
Scott: What's wrong with that?
Scott: One thing I will do though is if there's sometimes they'll be one eyebrow hair this by itself or really long That's by itself and it's like double thick and way long and like.
Scott: I can feel it Like it's like one monster eyebrow hair.
Scott: Like imagine if you were an octopus with a bunch of tentacles and one tentacle was just like super buff Like.
Rym: yeah, this is my super strong tentacle and all the other tentacles just like I really like clean mine up because I had In the middle like, you know going out I had a bunch of hairs in my eyebrow that were as long as my entire eyebrow.
Rym: Like you had to comb them with the eyebrow.
Rym: they were like more than an inch long.
Scott: So if one of those appears which is like once every beer or so, they'll be one like that.
Scott: I have tweezers.
Scott: They're tweezer man tweezers.
Scott: They're like, it's a Surgically pointy.
Scott: It's a little more expensive than other tweezers, but it's so pointy.
Rym: I don't want the pointy I want the like wider but with us like a razor edge.
Scott: I need it to be so pointy so I can grab just that one hair and yank its ass out.
Scott: Otherwise you're grabbing like a whole bunch of hairs and it's like ah, I want to grab just one.
Rym: So hand soap.
Rym: I use the foaming stuff.
Scott: I Tried so many hand soaps.
Scott: first methods sweet water.
Rym: foaming stuff has the best smell the best feel and that Little like the pump of it lasts forever.
Scott: So at first I was using the soap that smelled like melon just because it smelled the best.
Scott: But then that soap had tricklesand and we learned better.
Scott: so I stopped using that.
Scott: so then I tried the Myers whatever.
Scott: but that soap had a problem and that it was like had oil.
Scott: I didn't realize when I bought it it had oil in it.
Scott: So when I wash my hands with it, my hands didn't feel clean.
Scott: They felt oily.
Scott: I want hands a feel clean.
Scott: So then I got the foamy soap and I got the pear variety and that's okay.
Scott: I've used that one.
Scott: It smells great and my hands feel so clean.
Rym: You can buy the bulk refill, right?
Scott: My hands feel so clean after washing with the foamy soap.
Scott: So that's the best.
Scott: right now I was trying to find a hand soap that was like Neutrogena rain bath of hand.
Scott: so They don't make such a thing.
Scott: Neutrogena doesn't make a hand soap.
Scott: There's no luxury hotel hand soap available that I could find outside of luxury hotels.
Scott: So if anyone knows of one Let me know.
Rym: in public bathrooms Whenever there's that like Hanging vat of generic pink soap the pink stuff.
Rym: I don't touch that stuff I just wash my hands without soap.
Rym: I cuz one time I was at work right and that vat was there and the top was like kind of open and I Opened it the rest of the way and looked in and there was a layer of dead flies on top of it.
Scott: All right, usually it's a plastic bag.
Scott: Yeah hooked up to the front So it doesn't matter if this flies.
Rym: outside the bag there were flies like having drowned in it.
Scott: It looked like alright, but anyway And my work they just have built-in plungers.
Scott: You don't see what brand of soap it is.
Scott: But yeah normal soap comes out.
Rym: that stuff always smell you will usually smells weird though Like I don't like to smell a lot of that public.
Scott: So I don't know.
Scott: but it's not pink stuff.
Scott: It's just the same soap you'd buy at the grocery store.
Scott: They just buy it in bulk from like Amazon or something.
Scott: Yeah But yeah, if I'm in a public restroom the foamy stuff where you put your hand under and automatically comes out That's the best stuff.
Scott: That's like I was at the doctor's office and that's what they had there.
Rym: It's automated goes like and you're like a puff in your hand.
Rym: Yeah, that's the good stuff.
Scott: That's the good stuff.
Scott: If you're making a public bathroom install those.
Rym: I think we've.
Rym: this is almost an hour long.
Rym: I think that worked.
Rym: Okay, we did a show.
Scott: we didn't even talk about toilets.
Rym: Oh, that'll be.
Rym: that'll be part two of bathroom concerns.
Rym: Sure This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the name picture on patreon is in order.
Rym: the monitor.
Rym: They give us non-continuing faces.
Rym: are Alan Joyce Rebecca Dunn Nicholas Brando.
Rym: How do you nickel Amanda Duchette?
Rym: Marty green?
Rym: yet construction noises ivy fame my state II calm.
Rym: William isen rose Jerry a minor Chris Reimer and Thomas on Christian coons.
Rym: Chris Reimer and then and and and and and and and and Thomas on Sherman one horrible icky kid rare Lavell James David White Rochelle, Monta Nona Superboy.
Rym: Don't look at me.
Rym: I voted for the goat Aaron Cerise Brian Fisher's sailor Vista the amazing $5 Rym remote registered trademark exclamation point Matthew Smith Don Schlegs our topics and Joe sure Joe star Tyler Eller Sean Yeager Sam quarter Clinton Walton Renford, New Zealand Ryan parent drew open letter.
Rym: Brian Cedroni Finn Eric Silverado redacted Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn guys really working hard to trip me up here.
Rym: But yeah If you want to have some fun keep asking Scott when he's gonna upload that cooking show that he made.
Rym: Maybe you could suggest that he should use the editing knob to make the editing go faster.
Rym: But anyway, I'll see you guys at some upcoming conventions and Scott and I are going nowhere for the rest of the holidays So we'll be around continuing to do GeekNights.
Rym: and now I leave you The I.