Rym:
Scott: It's it's it's.
Rym: it's Thursday July 21st 2016.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott and this is GeekNights still recovering from the illness that laid us low last week and tonight We're talking about garments and clothes and to a degree fashion.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So those of you who do follow the patreon I did a thing a while ago where I explained something I'm doing and With when I bike and I am Literally still calling the police on every single car I ever encounter when I'm biking.
Rym: That's blocking a bike lane.
Rym: It's actually working pretty well, so I've noticed something pretty interesting Even if it's the police you call.
Scott: Hmm, even if it's a police car.
Rym: Yes, actually, I've reported for police cars and they did like I did hang around once There over the holiday weekend 4th of July weekend and what I saw is eventually this other cop car rolls up and They talked to each other a little bit and then both cop cars drove away Because it's 311.
Rym: So even if like they don't want to do something the complaint goes through all this bureaucracy.
Rym: So like that I get all these updates.
Rym: It's like all the updates to the ticket and what happened and everything.
Rym: So I get this sort of like fascinating view inside Cops who may maybe don't care but there's a thing that's gonna bother them until they go do it.
Scott: Why don't you go post about this in bike right and be like, hey this works.
Scott: Maybe you get a hole.
Rym: Well, I'm expanding a little bit.
Rym: So John Kelly is joining me now in the crusade.
Rym: So he's doing it too because you think we bike hardcore John our friend John.
Scott: All he does is buy.
Scott: Yeah, like he is does he even have a job?
Rym: Uh, I don't know what.
Rym: I never knew what he did for a living Other than being a really good photographer and biker.
Rym: Yeah and such Being a side character being cooler than everyone else.
Rym: Yeah, he's pretty he's a cool, dude.
Rym: But what I noticed and it's only anecdotal so far but after I started doing this for several weeks, I Basically almost never encounter cars parked in the bike lanes on my way to work anymore and I used to encounter five or six a day.
Rym: so it might have finally started to work because Because suddenly like there aren't people parked in the bike lane anymore and I'm gonna see if this continues and because I have a log of every time I complain about one and because I log my commutes every day when I bike I can actually like do a regression analysis down the road and figure out if I had an effect or not or at least if there's a correlation between me doing this and People not blocking the bike lane anymore.
Rym: but The other interesting thing is the people who notice me like taking down their license plate number Even if I try to be surreptitious tend to get really mad and yell at me.
Rym: But then they also get out of the bike lane because they're actually afraid of the cops coming.
Rym: So it kind of works.
Rym: We'll see if I get shot, but I'm gonna continue doing this and I think I'm doing the work of the gods Got where would be pleased.
Rym: Okay, you got any news.
Rym: news day.
Rym: It's Thursday.
Rym: It's the lounge.
Rym: You can talk about anything.
Scott: Sure Nintendo announced.
Rym: Oh, so you agree.
Rym: It's the lounge.
Rym: No Still low energy and ill.
Scott: the Nintendo announced they're making that tiny NES.
Scott: It has like 30 games in it.
Rym: Oh, yeah I didn't even look at what 30 games are in it.
Scott: Uh It's pretty good selection.
Scott: It's like Mario 1 2 3 Zelda 1 2 Metroid.
Scott: You know, well, you know, that's like the opposite Castlevania Castlevania 1 2 Contra, you know, it's like Real games like the core set.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I remember I don't remember if Kirby's Adventure was on there.
Scott: I think it is better be.
Scott: it's pretty much top 30 NES games.
Scott: There's some in there that are like like they have Gradius but they didn't have.
Scott: a. life force is like life.
Rym: Yeah, it's fine.
Rym: Of course wasn't actually that good.
Scott: What are you talking about?
Rym: I do not enjoy.
Scott: life force is like way better than Gradius.
Scott: I don't know what's wrong with you.
Scott: Actually.
Scott: Sorry salamander With also the best Famicom cartridge there is if you've ever seen the cartridge It's the best one.
Scott: Anyway, I mean clearly there's some games that are left out But it's like you could have made a much worse selection than this.
Scott: So the thing caught is gonna be out in November for holiday season.
Scott: it's gonna sell out everywhere.
Scott: You're not gonna be able to get one and the price is gonna be way high on eBay.
Scott: So I'm gonna get as many as I can at retail price.
Scott: Also, they're selling the controller by itself for 10 bucks and it appears that The controller can plug into the bottom of a Wiimote.
Scott: Is that kind of plug?
Scott: USB man, so You could just buy the controller by itself for 10 bucks for use with your Wii virtual console.
Rym: I don't have a Wii I do.
Scott: Okay, or you know, I'm sure people will be.
Scott: it's still a brand newly manufactured NES controller.
Scott: I'm sure people will be making adapters or cutting the cable and making it USB or who knows what right anyway.
Scott: but yeah, the thing is I don't need who needs one of these.
Rym: I've bought all those games so many times in my life.
Scott: I have all those games emulated.
Rym: you have all those games on card.
Rym: like.
Rym: if you buy Like.
Scott: if you buy one of these to use it's like wow Talk about like.
Scott: the more he's complaining of people who like have extra boxes under their TV because they refused to go with the HD PC, but it's like.
Scott: this is like the most egregious.
Scott: You have a box under your TV just for these 30 NES games, even though it's a tiny box.
Scott: Are you fucking kidding me?
Rym: and you're gonna pay like 70 bucks for this?
Rym: Oh my god, you know what I would use it for if I ran a low-rent convention In the video game room.
Rym: I just put like 10 of these in a row.
Scott: Yes, that is a good see that's a use for it right because it doesn't like one tiny crate.
Scott: It is cheaper than an HD PC.
Scott: So if all you need it for is those games and you want to say make like any as game station or you know.
Scott: Then it like it has purpose but also useful to buy it for your house.
Rym: Okay use Use this like for example Say you own a bar in a hip part of a town like New York.
Scott: Sure You put it.
Rym: just you put it there and let people just play it like that's great.
Rym: And then you know every few months one gets smashed and whatever you bought like a hundred of them.
Rym: Yeah, or if you're the kind of person who still knows what Nintendo is and has played NES games and enjoys them but simultaneously Don't know how to make emulators go like you're just one of those people who doesn't know things you could be.
Scott: it's not hard.
Scott: You could become smarter.
Rym: Yeah, I mean not to disparage people but NES and SNES emulation is the easiest thing.
Scott: you Thought you were gonna be giving an excuse for those Mara.
Rym: No, no, we solved NES emulation when I was still in high school.
Scott: It's like the easiest like it just works like I'll get every game and not 30 games.
Rym: Yep I mean, I guess the only hardest part is you have to know how to download an emulator without getting a virus.
Rym: Oh my god, which is actually really hard.
Rym: if you're one of those kinds of people maybe tell ask as some random schmuck to download putty and Even odds and I'm downloading a virus instead of putty.
Scott: putty is a unique condition situation.
Rym: Well, yeah, cuz it's not a weird website that even I every time I download putty.
Rym: I'm like, is that really it, right?
Rym: I mean, I do trust it but only because I have noses.
Rym: the anagogic schools would not understand.
Rym: So, uh, I don't know.
Rym: I think that thing is it's cool but stuff like that comes out periodically.
Rym: It's just the best Iteration of that kind of thing and it's the most legit one.
Rym: I've like ever seen.
Scott: Yeah, but the commercial is pretty good for it.
Scott: Oh, yeah, it's old style.
Scott: It looks like an old Nintendo commercial for you know, us Nintendo You know what?
Rym: I would love to see that Nintendo would probably never announce.
Rym: I'd love to know the actual like for real sales numbers of that thing because just knowing that You'll find out I don't know Nintendo's weird and cagey about their actual sales numbers.
Scott: No, you can find out how many game how many copies of games have sold?
Rym: But how many copies of that thing?
Rym: I don't know if it'll be easy to figure that out.
Scott: No It'll be published.
Scott: think we will.
Scott: Yeah, I'm gonna say, you know, how many wheeze were sold and how many you know?
Scott: Everyone knows all this stuff.
Rym: There's debate as to how Company, ah, that doesn't necessarily mean all those things get published you'd expect.
Scott: and there's the video game research whatever You know, they that tracks everything so they might try to figure it out.
Scott: No, I'm saying some someone will pay for the report from the ADAR whatever it is and then some write an article about it.
Rym: I'll put it this way if it sells a lot That is it's gonna sell out.
Scott: Yeah, how many are they gonna make?
Scott: it's gonna sell out?
Scott: It'll be the holiday toy that everyone will buy a million of and they'll be.
Scott: you won't be able to get it.
Scott: when you go To this we'll see.
Rym: I'm gonna put a Google reminder for six months from now to check on what happened with this thing.
Scott: It'll be the well, it comes out in November.
Scott: So it'll be.
Scott: I mean, it'll be all over the news, right?
Scott: Oh my god, 2016 is took on the Elmo then tiny NES.
Rym: So in other news Let me pull it up here.
Rym: This is I just bumped into this because I buy, you know, I'm one of those people.
Rym: I buy everything online.
Rym: I pretty much buy literally everything on Amazon Newegg or fresher 90% of things plus.
Scott: I buy online like clothes.
Rym: the only things I don't buy like that are Like one-off specific ingredients for like a specific thing.
Rym: I'm cooking right now like to that day.
Rym: I Guess I don't buy clothes except like sports clothes.
Rym: Like I'll buy sports clothes online, but I won't buy like a nice shirt.
Rym: I'll go I'll go try the nice shirt on in person.
Scott: I wouldn't buy other people do.
Scott: But I would not buy a bicycle online.
Rym: I did but I had it delivered to a bike shop to put together for me and I test-rode a very similar model before.
Scott: Yeah, but people buy bikes and more bike parts delivered to them and put them together.
Scott: I put together a computer.
Rym: there was a time I would do that in my life.
Rym: You know when that time ended when I started using carbon fiber, I'm not willing to put together carbon fiber shit.
Scott: I would buy a car online if I was gonna buy a car.
Rym: I would definitely buy a car online.
Rym: There's no even a reason to test drive a car anymore.
Scott: It's a car.
Scott: It's gonna work.
Rym: Yep Just do it.
Rym: What what features do you want?
Rym: And how much?
Rym: how many dollars do you want to give up for that car?
Rym: But yeah, so basically Amazon.
Rym: One thing that I've done.
Rym: I'm wearing them right now because I just got home from biking to work And also I figured out why I felt like such shit.
Rym: when I got home I had a notification in my inbox.
Rym: Not only is it a heat advisory like danger warning out like you might die in New York City like the health problems But the air quality index is like a hundred and thirty right now.
Rym: So like it's basically just like a soup of poison outside and it's super hot.
Rym: So I'm wearing some bike shorts now because I commute I wear bike shorts every day and I wash it like I. so I wanted a bunch of pears so I don't have to do bike short laundry like every two days and I didn't want to wear more than once because bike shorts start to smell and while I have some nice like real bike butt stuff I don't want to wear those every time I go to work.
Rym: so when I went on Amazon and I found a really nice bike short that did what I wanted it had the the butt pads and everything integrated into it and It was like 10 bucks and I was like really 10 bucks.
Scott: that seems like a knockoff.
Scott: That's gonna disintegrate and hurt and not fit well, so I bought one cuz.
Rym: I was like wow That's a $10 lottery ticket like sure and I put him on.
Rym: and they're not the best bike shorts in the world But they're fine for biking under like a hundred miles over the course of a day.
Scott: Did they disintegrate in the washing machine?
Rym: Nope, so they.
Rym: I washed them a bunch of times.
Rym: They were just great.
Rym: So I bought like eight more pair Mm-hmm, and I just haven't piled up and Emily and I can wear them both.
Rym: So we just share them and they're just like I'd wear these things and they're great.
Rym: They are totally like Chinese bootleg.
Rym: bullshit Like this is the kind of thing where some company clearly makes like quote-unquote real branded bike shorts by day for some company And then at night they just illegally make a whole bunch more and sell them illegitimately on places like Amazon.
Rym: Now as a consumer This is great because I just basically got a really well constructed product for almost no money when I would have to pay like 80 bucks to get this thing legit from the company that actually Sells the quote-unquote official version of it, right?
Scott: Cuz you only have to pay for the manufacturing and shipping.
Scott: You don't have to pay for the designing and the marketing.
Rym: that and the manufacturing is pretty much the same as the real thing.
Rym: Yeah So on the other hand, I'm looking up In fact, I just picked up my hand to a battery a couple of different batteries that I've bought.
Rym: So wasabi batteries, this is a legitimate Panasonic battery All right That's safe that I paid a hundred and ten.
Scott: there are bootleg batteries that are Somewhat difficult to tell apart from legit ones.
Scott: Yeah that will actually say like Sony or Panasonic on them.
Scott: But this guy's online for you how to tell they're fake.
Rym: Yeah, so this battery goes like 110 bucks.
Rym: I also bought a bunch of wasabi batteries.
Scott: Wasabi is legit.
Rym: They're they're.
Rym: they're mostly legit.
Rym: their batteries have Let's say wide ranges of actual operating voltages.
Scott: I have never had a problem with the wasabi battery.
Rym: I have had many problems with wasabi batteries.
Rym: hardly news to me.
Rym: So my camera worked with.
Rym: wasabi battery is great and the wasabi batteries lasted like twice as long as the official battery.
Rym: Well, like 80 50 to 70 percent longer Let's say not actually double double but they're significantly longer.
Rym: They held a much bigger charge.
Rym: They didn't lie.
Rym: They even said they held a bigger charge.
Rym: Yeah, no, it's more dangerous.
Rym: Yeah, but after like two months Suddenly the camera would be like oh shit voltage warning and shut down.
Rym: Oh and that happened to me with Every wasabi battery I ever bought within six months of purchase failed in that manner except one and I still use that one.
Rym: So wasabi is also hit or miss.
Scott: but if you have to write my camera I have one legit and two wasabi batteries.
Scott: They all work perfectly.
Scott: They've always worked perfectly.
Rym: I think a difference is that this is an old camcorder and actually draws a lot of power Like way more than you'd expect and I think it has.
Rym: it has like tighter tolerances for what it can deal with in terms of the battery.
Rym: This is but this is only a twenty six hundred million.
Scott: I've also used wasabi batteries in my GoPro.
Scott: never had a problem.
Rym: Oh, yeah, and the GoPro the GoPro wasabi batteries work fine But the wasabi batteries for my like big camcorder and not great.
Rym: But bootleg batteries are this other ballgame because the legit batteries are real expensive.
Rym: The next tier down are the batteries that are not counterfeits.
Rym: They just happen to have the same form factor like they'll work with the official thing But they're not the official thing and they don't even pretend they're the official thing.
Rym: They're like, yeah, this is a Sorni battery.
Rym: Good luck have fun.
Rym: not for not even gonna lie to you dude that we made this in a factory.
Rym: It'll give you seven ish vaults go nuts.
Rym: At least those don't lie to you.
Rym: The most dangerous batteries are the ones that say they're the official battery But they're not because that shit is just like we are counterfeiting stuff.
Rym: Like.
Rym: there's probably just like a bag of sand in there.
Rym: It's like up some battery acid, but no actual battery.
Rym: It's just a rock.
Rym: But the point is Amazon has pretty much Every bootleg thing in the world is in there and it's often real hard to figure out if a listing is a legitimate thing or a Bootleg.
Scott: take the reviews.
Rym: Yeah, but it's high.
Rym: with technical things The reviews always work because there's always people who are like they know their shit and they're like.
Rym: This is clearly a bootleg shuttle pro because the real shuttle pro is this extra button.
Rym: blah blah blah.
Scott: one time I was buying a Lenovo laptop battery on Amazon and I thought it might be bootleg cuz it was so cheap.
Scott: So I messaged Amazon and I said is this real and they said if it's not real we'll refund you and I got it.
Scott: It was real.
Rym: so Birkenstock Decided that they make hippie sandals.
Rym: did they make the best sandals though?
Rym: Like they're not gonna lie like this might date us as being a little bit old and white But they're pretty much the best sandals in the world.
Rym: Like I Wear them they're okay.
Rym: They're hippie sandals Yeah But they're just real comfortable and also they are one of the few sandal people who have the three strap sandal fuck.
Rym: the two strap or the one strap and Toe holes are the worst possible sandal, but Birkenstock and all those subsidiaries were like Amazon.
Rym: Nothing, nothing we make will ever be legitimate on Amazon.
Rym: We refuse new business with Amazon.
Rym: Amazon doesn't care Yeah, so if you ever see a Birkenstock thing on Amazon, it is definitely a bootleg.
Scott: So it's probably just as good and looks the same and cost less.
Scott: Yep So all they're doing is not as losing their own sales.
Scott: Well, the problem is I only buy shoes on Zappos, which is also Amazon.
Scott: So then you take this stuff off Zappos also, I don't think so, but Zappos.
Scott: Zappos doesn't sell bootlegs.
Scott: You don't can't list your stuff on Zappos, but Zappos is the only place that go to buy shoes.
Rym: Well, see that's the thing.
Rym: I only buy shoes on Zappos because Zappos is Amazon while I don't care, but it's not.
Rym: but it is Birkenstock, yeah, it's all there.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But the thing is on Zappos They're pretty expensive and they're good sandals.
Scott: Well, Zappos is never a discount place like Amazon.
Scott: Yeah, Zappos is just excellent customer service normal price.
Rym: It's like going to B&H to buy like some video equipment like.
Rym: yeah, it's expensive.
Rym: But there's someone there who actually knows it's not expensive it's just normal price.
Rym: Yeah, but normal price is expensive in the modern world of ZRAI, see through anything.
Rym: So Basically, what the problem Birkenstock saw was that no one ever bought the legit sandals on Amazon.
Rym: So taking them off Amazon doesn't actually hurt them.
Rym: People only bought the bootlegs because the bootlegs were like 20 bucks.
Scott: You're not gonna make Amazon stop selling the bootlegs, though.
Rym: so they've tried because it is illegal for Amazon to continue to sell to like.
Rym: let them sell these things and Amazon basically just doesn't enter like doesn't do it Like doesn't deal with it doesn't respond and kind of just lets the marketplace be the Wild West.
Rym: As far as I can tell this wasn't a huge problem until relatively recently When Amazon changed its rules.
Scott: I feel like there's been bootleg stuff on Amazon for a long time.
Rym: There was but it got way worse When they changed their rules and allowed Chinese manufacturers to sell goods directly on Amazon Which was not allowed before.
Scott: so what were they?
Scott: how were they doing it before?
Rym: they had before their shell companies?
Rym: At least have a shell company or an importer or someone like laundering the counterfeit goods.
Rym: But now like the company that makes the bootlegs can just straight-up sell the bootlegs.
Scott: So you don't need your art vandal a anymore.
Rym: No more.
Rym: I importer exporter.
Rym: So if you want to buy chips legitimate chips.
Rym: So I don't really have a moral here.
Rym: It's just.
Rym: this is a very interesting problem because on one hand if if you buy a Bootleg, that's just a night run from a factory.
Rym: It is literally as good as the official version.
Rym: You're basically just stealing from the company that paid to do all the research and design and marketing.
Rym: But if you buy a bootleg that is on like a knockoff in the sense of someone just copied someone else's design Independently and sells a shitty version of it.
Rym: You're basically paying less for a shit-tier version, right?
Scott: It's like I'm fine buying something.
Scott: That's just as good as the original like a wasabi battery.
Scott: I just don't want to buy a bootleg if it's not gonna work.
Scott: for example I recently Bought this thing that plugs into the bottom of the iPad and lets you connect an SD card to get the photos onto the iPad.
Rym: Oh, my phone just takes SD cards.
Rym: a full-size ones Well mini ones I can put the 64 gig one in there.
Scott: You can have anyway, so 64 gig just hanging out so I can load raw photos into Lightroom mobile Anyway, which they just added as a feature.
Rym: So I did not notice that.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway the Apple sells one of these things for a bunch of money and I went.
Scott: I'm like, well, here's the price of the Apple store.
Scott: I could stop and get one at the Apple store on the way home But let's see how much they are in Amazon.
Scott: So I find that an Amazon and then I read the comments and the comments are like, uh, this is not legit product This is a Chinese thing that didn't even work.
Scott: and I'm like, oh well if it doesn't work I'll buy the legit one that's overpriced right, but if that one worked I don't care if it's Chinese as long as it works.
Scott: Yeah, sometimes it doesn't work.
Rym: I guess that the real danger I see is that in the race to the bottom of you know Most people just buy the cheapest version of anything and we do know what one of the end games of that is.
Rym: You've seen how airplanes are.
Rym: Economy is nightmare mode if you're flying overseas and anything better costs an order of magnitude more money and nothing in between.
Scott: Right, but if the price difference there is too big I can't afford the quality that I want Yeah, whereas here it's like if I can afford the level of quality that I want.
Rym: But the knockoffs especially with technology are often dangerous or like broken in some way that a normal person wouldn't understand.
Scott: Yeah, that's no good.
Rym: But the bike shorts you got were fine Yeah, but at the same time I went into the bike shorts knowing one like I knew a hundred percent that this might be some bullshit Mm-hmm.
Rym: I don't think most people buying the cheapest battery on Amazon know that it might be some bullshit.
Rym: I think they see the Sorni battery and they're like looks legit.
Scott: Hmm.
Rym: It's just all an interesting thing that there's no good answers.
Rym: I mean globalization and all these issues are just culminating into an Unanswerable question that no nation is willing to deal with and everyone has complexity.
Scott: companies want to benefit from free trade having their stuff Made in China.
Scott: Well, then it's not just companies that should be benefiting from the free trade.
Scott: individual People should be benefiting the same way as well.
Scott: Yeah If you don't want the free trade then either everyone has the free trade or no one has the free trade.
Scott: That's the choice.
Scott: It's got to be equal.
Scott: You can't be like up companies.
Scott: If you have a company you could buy stuff from China for free But if you're an individual person, no, we can't let no fuck you.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: That's why I'm very much kind of for Decreasing free trade.
Rym: right?
Scott: all the people who complain about globalization, right?
Scott: It's like there's like, you know, they're complaining, you know that they want to end it right there against it But it's like no really I'm.
Scott: I'm for it as long as I can benefit from it individually as well.
Scott: Right, then the problem goes away.
Rym: As long as it It is the tide that rises with all the ships in the harbor.
Rym: It can't be like there's one giant Megacorp ship sitting in a lock and it goes up and down and everyone else is just dried out on the beach Exactly.
Scott: Well splooshed by the waves and in the wake of the giant shit.
Rym: Yeah, my metaphor is already breaking down, but you know what I mean?
Rym: But yeah.
Rym: Anyway, the only other news a lot it is interesting.
Rym: How many of you were like texting me and messaging me when this was going on?
Rym: because I literally went into the subway to go on a trip, but yeah turkey had a coup and All my friends are safe except for a few friends who they're safe.
Rym: But I realized in retrospect like four days before the coup I have a couple of people I know who basically were like yo dog.
Rym: So here's my resume.
Rym: just in case anything pinky happens If you ever need someone who speaks Turkish and knows tech I might be moving to the states real soon.
Scott: Yeah, you got a h1b or green card.
Scott: Good luck.
Rym: Actually, most of them went to Canada.
Rym: Canada is like where anyone who was smart who had money in Turkey and is young and at a text like tech skills They if even if they didn't GTFO They got visas to go to Canada for long periods of time in Canada way colder than Turkey.
Rym: Uh Turkey's actually pretty temperate Turkey lays like a little bit warmer than New York.
Scott: I mean it has mountains where it snows but I can't imagine it's snowing on like the Mediterranean coast Turkey is Surprisingly similar to like a Great Lakes climate in a lot of ways.
Rym: There's lake effect snow from the Mediterranean in terms of like the water around especially Istanbul in that part of Turkey.
Rym: I mean, obviously Turkey's huge.
Rym: I got snow plows and parts of Turkey are by Syria.
Scott: They play ice hockey somewhere.
Scott: There's not the mountain.
Scott: now.
Rym: take it like everything and shift it one step warmer.
Rym: But otherwise, there's a similar vibe.
Scott: And again, that's just all I'm saying if you leave Turkey to go to Canada We should invest in coats.
Rym: Well, most of them that I know at least they actually went to Vancouver which has really warm.
Scott: So Vancouver is fine.
Rym: Yeah, I mean winters are death there.
Rym: That's the least.
Rym: the least cold part of and also one of the words It's it's the winner is awful.
Rym: But the Sunshine Coast is called the Sunshine Coast.
Rym: words Things of the day.
Scott: What was my thing?
Rym: Okay.
Rym: So this is a YouTube series.
Rym: It's only six episodes.
Rym: It's short and a super high production values.
Rym: so you can each episode is like three minutes long, but it's basically Sesame Street like puppets and teaching kids about creativity and imagination and all these things.
Rym: but Remember that video that video.
Rym: we use this thing a day a long time ago.
Rym: the let's all go.
Rym: It's the.
Rym: it's like the pre-roll to a drive-in theater like go get your snacks before the movie starts Yeah, and then it slowly gets sinister and then it gets creepy.
Rym: The show is happy three friends.
Rym: This is like that.
Rym: Don't hug me.
Rym: I'm scared.
Rym: It's kind of disturbing.
Scott: Really well done.
Rym: and those of you who listen to the weird stuff I put at the end of the episode for the patrons and the patreon This is where I've been getting the clips from for the past week.
Scott: This is your internet weird kind of shit.
Rym: It's really good though.
Rym: Like this would not be out of place in a film festival or on television late at night.
Rym: A Warning like for real.
Rym: the music in it'll get really badly stuck in your head.
Rym: Hmm.
Scott: So the Sega Saturn one of the Somewhat forgotten but also awesome and important gaming consoles of history It's it's.
Rym: it's why it's a very important console and it had some legendary games some very legendary game Yeah, anyway.
Scott: So the Sega Saturn has been a problem for a long time because it uses a disk drive optical ness and the problem is that those disk drives are Wearing out you.
Scott: if you buy a Sega Saturn, it's kind of not easiest to find one with like a working CD-ROM drive.
Scott: And also there was a DRM system for those CD-ROM drives that was actually rather fancy and hard to get around.
Scott: it had like they made custom CDs that had like a Like a wavy line drawn on the in like on the first ring of the the bottom And it's like you can't make your CD-ROM burn that.
Scott: so if you want to burn a disc and put it into a Saturn You basically can't.
Scott: Alright.
Scott: so the Sega Saturn also on the inside of it The hardware was really complex like it has two CPUs and it has a separate CPU just for the CD-ROM.
Scott: It's like it's a really complex kind of hardware.
Scott: It's all you know, it's like an arcade hardware, basically It's sort of a miracle that people made games for this thing.
Scott: So some guy he had this project where he was gonna figure out how that CD-ROM actually fucking worked and how that whole system worked so that he could basically rescue the Sega Saturn.
Scott: and He basically went above and beyond the Call of Duty and managed to create a like a board That you could put in the expansion slot in the back and then just like forget about your CD-ROM Just load games through the back.
Scott: All right, no problem.
Scott: So He made a video like explaining everything and if you don't know enough about computers You might not understand everything he's talking about, but maybe even then you'll still learn something about computers.
Scott: All right D I'm just looking at all these Sega Saturn games and you'll learn something really fascinating about the Sega Saturn and CD-ROMs and Gaming and cool stuff.
Rym: So this is way beyond the like.
Rym: even in mod ship I soldered into my PlayStation.
Scott: even if you're never gonna use this or Play me Sega Saturn games though.
Scott: You should.
Scott: you can learn a lot of awesome stuff from this guy's video.
Scott: He's like a mad genius of us, you know hardwares and whatnot.
Scott: So I'm looking forward to maybe this developing further so that I could play some of those long-lost Saturn games.
Scott: Well, they're not long-lost, but you know, I've never been able to play the man wave Crime wave.
Scott: there's that one Japanese one.
Scott: That's like the boat that's supposed to be like the best game ever, but no one's ever no one in the US can play it Even just to play something like that.
Scott: fighting game was I think was called like fighters megamix they had like The robot and the police girl and whatever.
Scott: and then you know, there are a lot of Saturn even just playing Saturn Bomberman.
Scott: It's like come on.
Rym: Yeah I mean the Sega Saturn's.
Rym: not like emulators for it or not great as far as I can tell either.
Scott: Well, the emulator people have learned from the things this guy learned to greatly improve their emulator.
Rym: Oh that actually makes sense.
Scott: So it makes a lot of sense at least the part of the emulator that cares about CD roms.
Rym: in the moment We are going to be live at PAX West 2016 the grind on Saturday September 3rd at 5 p.m In the chicken theater.
Scott: I actually bought two tickets to fax for West Prime Don't Rome and I now don't need Rome.
Rym: I okay good cuz she got caught up.
Rym: She was accused of being a Scalper really by the coup system.
Rym: I don't know if she lost her badges or not But but there are many reports of people who got badges taken away who were not scalping.
Scott: They got some false positives.
Scott: It's not good.
Rym: Yeah, cuz she I would like I know our friends.
Rym: No one we know is ever scalped a PAX badge.
Scott: Yeah, well, I wonder what they did that triggered it.
Rym: So the way I from what I can gather it was because two different sets of badges ended up getting delivered to the same street address And that was enough to flag it.
Scott: Oh Jeremy also bought badges separately something like that.
Rym: I don't know the full story, but that that was the most common theme was like roommates in a house mostly like college students were like four of them would all buy four badges each separately But they all lived in the same like a street address and that was the kind of thing that triggered it.
Rym: Mmm, anyway, we'll see.
Rym: if she if our friends don't need him then yeah What are you lucky?
Rym: people might be able to get them?
Scott: Yeah, cuz I could use the money they cost.
Rym: This is our 40th packs panel.
Rym: We've never paid for a packs.
Rym: we go where every year They invite us back to every packs to do panels and yet every year I'm so paranoid and terrified that they won't bring us back for some really surprise man.
Rym: Yeah I'm not worried about any other keg now like if they didn't invite us to PAX South I practice wouldn't go or paxies like I but PAX Prime I would go to.
Scott: Well PAX South I can just buy a ticket if they don't accept our panel, but paxies Enforcing.
Rym: Yeah, so we can go if we want to but Australia.
Rym: we pretty much told us we could do a panel.
Rym: We just got to decide if we're going to.
Rym: you want to go.
Rym: we got patreon money and go somewhere else.
Rym: We're gonna go.
Rym: we could save that patreon money and do a nice with the palm tree.
Rym: want to do an Essen Extravaganza.
Scott: with the picture we're going to Essen in 2018.
Scott: I guess this year.
Scott: I wanna go someplace with palm trees.
Rym: All right, you go to northern Australia.
Scott: Anyway, where the palm tree Brisbane can palm tree Florida.
Rym: just go to Florida.
Scott: No hundred bucks round trip.
Rym: It's boring.
Rym: Go to I don't know Singapore.
Scott: That's not the nicest place.
Rym: Hong Kong is super nice.
Scott: It's now size problems.
Rym: What like what?
Rym: what problems would you have in Hong Kong?
Scott: None?
Scott: Probably?
Rym: Yeah It's problems do not affect us.
Rym: we're not booksellers nor are we agitators for democracy.
Rym: in other meta news now if remember how I said that one now that we're back and we're not sick and Kineticons behind us we're gonna start cranking content out.
Rym: Scott is gonna be making a shit ton of video this weekend Unless the weather is super good.
Scott: Maybe at night.
Rym: yeah, and I uploaded episode 15 of GeekNights presents utenna and Not only get a ton of views but holy shit, there are a lot of comments like you guys are into this show.
Rym: I'm actually how many?
Rym: So there's 41 comments on it now, and I just uploaded the video like this part or yesterday morning.
Scott: That's not a lot of kind for us.
Rym: That's a lot of comments.
Rym: That said that 41 comments are good, dude If we get like 30 or 40 thousand views on a video I consider that pretty good because we're not.
Rym: There's not a wide audience for what we do.
Rym: What is the audience of people who want to who not only know what anime is Know what utenna is and want to watch us talk about it for like 40 minutes an episode?
Scott: I hope that audience would be zero.
Rym: that audience is five or six thousand at least as far as I can tell.
Scott: That's too much audience.
Rym: Yeah So, uh, it's up and we're gonna make a whole bunch more stuff as soon as we can.
Rym: the Civ 5 videos.
Rym: I'm gonna crank out.
Rym: I got an Atari games.
Rym: I'm video to put out.
Rym: Oh We're both still coughing.
Rym: So yeah, that's all I got the book club book orcs and Craig.
Scott: Oh the book that I read in six hours and you said you would have read by today But I said I would read it for them for the next also.
Scott: Yeah, you say that was your Previously said you would ever had it read by today, but then I said the.
Scott: I said Like weeks ago, that's like saying, you know, that's like if Monday I say I'll have it done by Friday and then on Tuesday I say I have it done by three Fridays for now.
Scott: Yeah, and I say I but I said I'd have it done by three Fridays now.
Scott: Yeah, you also said you would have done by this ride.
Rym: I changed the date Because the Prince of Nothing book came out.
Rym: I had to read it.
Scott: I'm reading Prince of Nothing Also, I didn't have a problem doing already done.
Rym: I you I started reading this book the Prince of Nothing.
Scott: But listen you had months to read this book.
Rym: Yeah, so did you.
Rym: and you just read it recently.
Scott: it took six hours.
Rym: Yeah, I'm gonna.
Rym: I'm going to the beach this weekend.
Rym: So I'll read it this weekend for sure.
Scott: It'll take me six hours, so we had to come up with an alternate show idea.
Rym: Yep, and that alternate show idea is Clothing great cuz we did it.
Rym: It was your idea great crab people you got there.
Rym: I had other ideas, but you don't want to talk about the.
Scott: you had a perfect.
Scott: we had a perfect show idea.
Scott: You know, you didn't do it.
Rym: We could talk about the prince of nothing book about Shinji in his day.
Scott: I only read half of it so far.
Rym: so far half this book is Hey come with me to talk to my dad.
Scott: That's only the most recent chapter.
Scott: That's half the book.
Rym: there There's another dad.
Rym: Oh Sure.
Rym: Okay, whatever and there's a third day.
Scott: Yeah, there's a bunch of people going to talk to their dad.
Rym: everybody's going to talk to their dad.
Rym: That's that's what's going on all that.
Scott: It's all the sons going towards dads.
Scott: Yep But daddy issues all over the world.
Rym: We've done shows on shoes.
Scott: We've done and literal dads.
Rym: We've done shows on underwear specifically back in 2008.
Rym: We've done shows on a bunch of like oddly specific things.
Rym: We did a show on fire once.
Rym: that's what happens when you do like 1,200 shows over the course of 11 years.
Rym: But we've never done a show on the concept of clothing our naked bodies and garments of some fashion.
Scott: Well, first of all personally other than protection from weather and elements Like I would be perfectly fine going somewhere where clothes were in a thing
Rym: I would pretty much like on a day like today if I could get away with it Like if it weren't for the fact that like my office building wouldn't let me in I would not wear shirts like.
Rym: I would just not wear a shirt.
Rym: Hmm, but I would wear Something over my genitals.
Scott: and but I mean just for protection for the elements like and the thing is like but also to protect the Elements from me.
Rym: it's protection both from and for the elements.
Rym: For example, right?
Rym: It's like I don't like to be naked.
Rym: I don't want to sit in my office chair naked because now there's butt all over my office chair exactly.
Scott: But also It's also like in terms of other people like a lot of people don't want to be naked because they don't want other people to See them like.
Scott: oh you've seen me.
Scott: Oh, no, but it's like I don't care if you see me naked.
Scott: The thing is you see I'm afraid that you don't want to see me.
Scott: So that's you know, that's why I'm like, you know I'll still I won't like just change in the middle of a room of people because pretty sure they don't want to see that.
Rym: Yep, so it's interesting.
Rym: I've gone through different phases of clothing up like when I was really young like elementary school From what I can remember and like.
Rym: even before elementary school I cared a lot about what like.
Rym: I wanted to be fashionable I guess and I cared a lot about what clothes I wore.
Rym: But at the same time I was super picky about it And I would just spend forever trying to decide what clothes to buy and my parents would just buy shit for me without my permission Because they didn't want to deal with it.
Rym: and then I just gave up and never cared about clothes again.
Scott: My caring about fashion is pretty much I don't want to advertise Something on my body that I don't like so I won't.
Rym: that's why I do what you don't wear.
Rym: Nazi uniforms good That's a good one.
Scott: But like for example, there's a lot of clothing stores you go to like underneath my previous office like a block away from my current office There is a super dry and if you go to super dry, I'm advertising them now, I guess fuck them.
Rym: They make okay stuff.
Scott: you look at their stuff and actually I can't deny their clothes are way cool Like I would buy those clothes But they're overpriced of course, but not by that much.
Scott: They all say super dry all over them all over the fucking place.
Scott: It's like dude, if you just took your fucking logos off those clothes I would buy them.
Scott: so I end up going to Uniqlo.
Scott: because you go to Uniqlo The only place it says on the clothing anything is on the tag on the inside.
Scott: So, you know when you buy a red shirt there, it's a fucking red shirt.
Scott: It's just red.
Rym: on one hand I see where you're coming from.
Rym: Like when you see a person who's wearing just like a coca-cola shirt.
Rym: You're like why?
Rym: Exactly, but at the same time I don't care that much and Definitely with height.
Rym: with fashion There is definitely a. the brand itself is part of the fashion.
Scott: whether or not you take that as a pure commercialist Nyla, oh, no, it is the part of the fashion Only fashion decision that I care about.
Rym: the super dry logo that just says super dry I kind of like.
Scott: I don't like that.
Rym: Like I don't mind it.
Scott: I like where it packs logo I'll wear a packs logo.
Rym: Well, like right now I'm wearing an Under Armour logo Just because they put their logo on all their shit.
Rym: And that's actually, you know, that's a trend.
Rym: That's that's something that's changed in my life a lot.
Rym: I used to wear nerd shirts or dress shirts or like more clothes like that, but as time has gone on I've replaced a lot of the kinds of clothes I used to own with technical sports gear.
Rym: Like I threw away every undershirt I owned and the only undershirts I have are various forms of technical or specialist like sports fabric Like either form-fitting or compression or like moisture wicking or those super super thin ones that Uniqlo has.
Scott: I mean, I'll wear stuff in a situation where it's warranted but like but like I'll use them as undershirts.
Scott: How much of that do I really need?
Rym: but like if I need an undershirt under like dress clothes I'll wear like a fancy sweat wicking like Under Armour thing.
Scott: I wear a regular undershirt.
Scott: What's it?
Scott: Why?
Rym: Well, cuz then they don't wick the sweat and I get sweaty or they're uncomfortable or I don't have those problems.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I'd prefer to be more comfortable.
Scott: Also those any more comfortable.
Rym: What do you mean by a regular undershirt?
Rym: Do you mean like a cotton undershirt?
Scott: Yeah, like a t-shirt.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Why would you ever wear that under a nice shirt?
Scott: Why not?
Rym: because one it creates unpleasant lines.
Rym: because the shirt is obviously a nice form-fitted shirt You're ruining the lines.
Scott: It doesn't?
Scott: that doesn't seem to happen.
Scott: That just means you're doesn't bother me and I don't care.
Rym: that just means you wear two baggy shirts for one.
Rym: Two you don't want the collars show.
Rym: The collar helps the undershirt When?
Rym: why?
Rym: the only time you ever want to collar the show is if you're unbuttoning the upper collar and you want that color accent.
Rym: And frankly, I don't like that style.
Scott: You can also See, this is the thing you care about all these styles.
Scott: I don't give a shit about styles.
Scott: All right, three You could also wear a v-neck t-shirt and then the collar doesn't show.
Rym: Regular cotton undershirts don't wick sweat and that's just uncomfortable.
Scott: I don't have sweat unless I do something athletic.
Rym: I'm always doing athletic stuff.
Scott: You're running around and you're wearing dress clothes.
Rym: I'm walking quickly.
Scott: Hi, you sweat just walking quickly.
Rym: I think I walk faster than you.
Scott: now I don't I don't.
Scott: I walk pretty fast and I don't.
Scott: I don't sweat unless I actually am Exercising.
Rym: most important the fancy technical stuff never smells bad no matter how much you sweat.
Scott: Yeah My clothes don't smell bad unless I wear them like three or four times.
Rym: And and also kind of the side thing the nice clothes like this they move the seams.
Rym: They don't have seams like on the top.
Rym: The seams are all out of the way.
Rym: So they'll never chase and never mess up your lines.
Scott: I never had those problems.
Rym: Okay, I care about this.
Rym: Also, you don't run like you don't do most active sports.
Scott: I'm not running if we're in dress clothes.
Scott: Yeah, I have active type things But I don't have a lot of them because I only wear them when it's time to do something active.
Scott: I don't wear them just like every day.
Rym: So I do active stuff like I like to work every day.
Rym: So I wear like sports clothes every day.
Scott: You're right, but you're underneath dress clothes.
Scott: You go to a fancy party.
Scott: You gotta wear sports clothes underneath now.
Rym: So in that case I don't.
Rym: but like when I'm working a convention and I like the staff shirt like the enforcer shirt I wear the Sacrificial undershirt, so I don't get the enforcer shirt sweaty because I only got one of them for three or four days.
Scott: I knew I've worn the enforcer shirt for three or four days and it's never been smelly or sweaty.
Scott: I Don't know cuz I'm not a sweaty.
Rym: beasts on Sunday We'll give your enforcer shirt and I sniff and see how it smells.
Scott: go for it.
Rym: All right, the under the enforcer undershirt challenge.
Rym: All right All right, fine.
Rym: I'll say put it this way Scott independent of us and our magic powers.
Rym: Imagine the average person out there normal American.
Rym: They need to be wearing Don't smell bad clothes.
Scott: They need to if they smell bad stop smelling bad Huh?
Rym: But it's baked in is marinated.
Scott: That's fix your body But it's a broken body.
Scott: but basically
Rym: the other difference is like when I used to travel like Edward jeans when I flew or I'd wear like pajamas when I flew sometimes like I would just wear something that seemed comfortable as normal clothes changing to wearing like Technical fabrics or like sports clothes like I have some pants that are basically only for like hiking and travel and that kind of stuff.
Rym: Holy shit, is that a billion times more comfortable when you're on a flight for 12 hours than wearing like any form of jeans?
Scott: Yeah, I have really comfortable jeans.
Rym: They're just like Yeah, but jeans have like bits in the back That'll dig into your butt or waist if you're sitting for 12 hours in a row if you have uncomfortable jeans that have those bits.
Scott: Oh, that's the thing is I might not care about styles or lines or whatever the fuck you're paying attention to but comfort and Fitting properly is like, you know, these jeans have a seam near that comes up near the butt.
Scott: I've never had any pains associated with any seam on a jean.
Rym: Did you wear jeans flying to Australia?
Scott: I think we're shorts.
Scott: because yeah, okay.
Rym: Okay, but I mean I've Took hold on a plane like that.
Rym: I've worn jeans on planes many times Like four or five hours, but most of my flights are like 12 to 25 hours.
Scott: So I mean some jeans are definitely more comfortable than others, right?
Scott: Like there's that huge trend of like selvedge.
Scott: does all these like selvedge denim, which is basically denim.
Scott: That's stiff as a fucking board.
Scott: Yeah, and it's like yeah, why would you?
Scott: I'm like, oh you break it in never wash It just keep wearing it and never wash it.
Scott: and I'm like get out of my face you dirty hippie.
Scott: I used to get some soft jeans that are nice.
Rym: I used to wear normal heavy traditional denim jeans and I used to have that sort of disdain For the not just denim jeans, but now all my jeans are like denim rayon denim spandex hybrids Like all my jeans are basically stretch pants that look like jeans.
Scott: I just get the soft ones that are comfortable.
Scott: Yeah, don't even pay attention.
Rym: I do get the super tight jeans though.
Scott: I mean, yeah, that's the other thing It's like, you know people who care about fashion.
Scott: There's always things that are in fashion and out of fashion, right?
Scott: But the truth is if you were to say dress in You know 70s fashion 80s fashion 90s fashion and you pick any decade 1890s fashion, right pick any decade.
Scott: take something that's fashionable at that moment that fits you properly and is comfortable And if you wear it today You'll look great, ah, you can.
Scott: what was in fashion in the 40s today?
Rym: Large sunglasses huge sideburns.
Scott: sure I see people walking on the street like that occasionally.
Scott: as long as you do it You know, it's like if they would have looked great then they look great now.
Scott: But obviously you can do any fashion Poorly if you think where things that don't fit or don't match or well don't match is the most important one the people who?
Rym: Add a trilby or fedora.
Scott: you can go Just unmatched clothes.
Scott: You can buy 2010s fashion the latest trends and get something It doesn't fit you and doesn't match and you'll look hideous and you can get something that's so out of style for the 90s You know, but totally fits you and totally matches and you could look great in it.
Scott: It's you know, it's like you don't got to pay attention to what the trends are.
Scott: You just have to get something that is good no matter when.
Scott: yep.
Rym: One trouble I've had those that my typical feel like the clothes I typically wear if I'm not doing sports and I'm not like dressing nicely for some reason is either board shorts and a Hawaiian shirt or Jeans and a nerd shirt.
Scott: now where jeans in a nerd shirt or shorts in a nerd shirt or shorts.
Rym: I don't wear shorts in a nerd shirt that much anymore.
Rym: if I wear shorts I pretty much always wear Hawaiian shirt just because that way I can unbutton it.
Scott: I'll wear a shirt like this, which is a collar on it, which is basically just a t-shirt with a collar buttons.
Scott: or You know in the winter I will wear like a long-sleeve shirt and then since it's so fucking cold a sweater on top of that Because it's so fucking cold, but I do.
Rym: over time it sort of grew on me.
Rym: I really like Hawaiian shirts now, even though I want at one time and it doesn't pass did not and that sort of.
Scott: you know You that you got that style that old guy with the mustache in the Hawaiian shirt Birkenstocks and my board shorts, right?
Scott: That's your.
Scott: that's who you are but
Rym: I actually like older like for real Hawaiian shirts more than like Just happens to be a short sleeve shirt that has a dumb pattern on it And like it's the fabric and the and the sewing and the cut and the feel way more than what it looks like.
Rym: Like.
Rym: I don't really care about the ugly patterns that are traditional on those kinds of shirts.
Rym: I just like the fact that I can leave it unbuttoned in the summer and I it basically lets me be wearing a shirt technically But not really wearing a shirt.
Rym: It's basically just kind of a cape with little like armholes in it.
Rym: Like that's my that's my style.
Scott: It's actually you know, there's a lot of people in the world who have like it's more quote extreme fashions.
Scott: Right, like, you know some crazy goth type person who wears like a crazy giant shoes like a life styler Like they have a scent like guy like there's a lie.
Scott: There's a lifestyle fashion thing and actually, you know I've thought about that from time to time like huh?
Scott: I could probably do some of those and you know I don't.
Scott: it's so much fucking effort.
Rym: Fuck that.
Scott: Yeah the problem I wake up in the more like.
Scott: imagine if I was like gonna be all like metal and we're like Spikes and shit and like, you know get some tattoos.
Scott: It's like it's so much fucking work You wake up every morning and deal with all that nonsense.
Scott: Well, it's more than and for what?
Rym: To have a wardrobe of anything beyond just formal wear and everything else in sportswear.
Rym: You got to buy that stuff in person and what I say the beginning of the show.
Rym: I'm everything online.
Rym: So I only go clothes shopping.
Rym: when I Run like a prop an article of clothing that I have is worn out and I'm short on that article of clothing and then I have to do what I'm doing.
Scott: laundry too often because they don't have enough of a clothe is when I buy a clothe and Usually it's because I take some old clothing give them to the goodwill because they're all messed up Yep, but like and it's like oh shit.
Rym: I don't have enough shorts because I just get for them to goodwill Your shirts to where I rotate them such that none of my nerd shirts are wearing out.
Rym: So I can't buy more because I have enough nerd shirts to live like a month never doing laundry.
Scott: Well sometime, you know over time eventually, you know a shirt will wear out and I'll have to retire it to the under-the-bed store doesn't happen to me anymore.
Rym: look at it.
Rym: just look at gig nights videos of our lectures from like 2008 and I'm wearing the same t-shirts that I wear it now.
Scott: Last a long time but still some of them like they don't last for that real life sure.
Scott: Well, that one is like the oldest of the cafe press.
Scott: what I'm not talking about Like by not drawing them you can preserve the art on the front, but other things will happen Like maybe they'll stretch out or maybe you'll get a stain on them or you know things can happen.
Scott: Right that can make a shirt go like even like some shirts that are perfectly good.
Scott: They have a tiny hole in them and I'm like, what is that?
Scott: It's like is that a moth that made that hole?
Scott: where the fuck that hole come from?
Scott: but it's like.
Scott: well
Rym: But like my sportswear I do a ton of research and I buy like very specific clothing for very specific reasons and purposes and I spend a lot of time on it because Then I know what I want and I can just order it online Don't have to go anywhere.
Rym: But with real clothes like normal clothes have to go to a clothing store and I only go to a clothing store when ah Shit, I need like I'm like, oh no my linen jacket that I wear all the time at conventions is Fucking worn out and I need new ones and pretty much because I hate going to stores Even though I could do that same level of research and care and like go buy like a bunch of really nice Hawaiian shirts I don't.
Rym: I just go to Uniqlo or H&M or one of those places usually both of them because they're like next to each other In this one neighborhood.
Scott: They're cheap and they have everything in one store.
Rym: and I walk into the store and I just walk around And I and as soon as I find like up here's a pair of jeans that fits me and looks good to replace the jeans ahead before I buy like five pairs of jeans that are the same one just different colors because that's the maximum like Output of clothes per input of time in a store.
Rym: and then while I'm there I go over to the shirt section.
Rym: I'm like, are there any Hawaiian shirts here that are good?
Rym: I look at them all and if there are I buy them all.
Rym: if there aren't I don't.
Scott: yeah I do the same thing where I buy different color because it's like you could do the Steve Jobs.
Scott: You just buy the same exact thing a hundred times But it's like I'll buy a different color.
Scott: Imagine if you went to work every day doing the same exact clothes.
Scott: Yeah, that would be like, uh-huh when project smashmouth concludes.
Rym: Maybe I'll do that instead.
Rym: I'll wear the same color shirt every day until someone says something.
Scott: the advantage is no one knows if you did your laundry and they Can't challenge you on it.
Scott: Yep Whereas I you know It's like I'm mostly worried.
Scott: The only reason I change clothes really is because I need to let people know that yes, I have done laundry.
Scott: Look at me.
Scott: I change clothes.
Rym: when I when I had before I was like Respected in my career enough to where people knew who I was and I could kind of like I didn't have to keep selling myself anymore Like when I was trying to rise through corporate ranks and everything like in the old days like when I first got my job in Wall Street and IBM Like I dressed up to work every day like I wore like a suit not a tie but I wore like a suit and a dress shirt and like nice pants.
Rym: and like I dressed up every day and I always tried.
Rym: my rule was always Look at all the people who are at my level in the company and all the people who are level above me And I would dress better than the most slovenly person above me.
Rym: That was like my rule.
Rym: now that I kind of just like him in an unfireable person who like knows stuff and could trivially get a job I Literally wore just like a compression under armor shirt and bike shorts to the office today and like no sock bike shoes Because I just don't care.
Scott: Yeah in terms of like office people always talk about like dress for the job you want I'm wearing bike shirts and bike sharp pressing for the job.
Scott: I want you know what at least at my company.
Scott: I don't have any other companies.
Scott: That's total bullshit cuz like.
Scott: there are people who are in my team who are like like.
Scott: there's another Scott.
Scott: He dresses like, you know, like real dress clothes.
Scott: He cares a lot about fashion.
Scott: He's always like dress it up every day.
Rym: Has he been promoted hasn't?
Rym: no so I got.
Scott: I got a terrible story the car and there's people dressing like way shabbier than me every day and There doesn't affect that right.
Rym: it's like no one gives a show when I was at the broker dealer you know when I first started working for like Wall Street nonsense and I dressed up every day and The dress code at the company was way under what I was dressing as.
Rym: so I dressed up and then like my co-workers like we all started dressing up in my one department and no one else in the company did except management and Later on the company put out a thing and they were like we're relaxing the dress code.
Rym: You guys can basically wear whatever the fuck you want to the office like shorts.
Rym: don't care go nuts Just don't be a slob.
Scott: Good job.
Scott: That's the kind of dress code I like.
Rym: so everyone else don't be naked everyone else relaxed a little bit, but we double down.
Rym: We all start wearing suits and ties every day.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: And that was just our thing.
Scott: I can't stop you.
Rym: Yeah, and It actually appeared to bother upper management because it was very clearly a dress for the job you want not the job you have.
Rym: Situation because we all knew how like important we were.
Rym: and Then we did a giant company photo for like this big website marketing thing.
Scott: Yeah, a bunch of people in suits and standing next to a whole bunch of slobs They actually made all of us take off our suits and ties for the photo.
Rym: Mmm, it's because only and and then in the photo they like they composited together Like we didn't take the photo all at once because that no one has a panorama.
Rym: Yeah, no one has a panorama that big for like a company with with like hundreds of employees.
Rym: So they like made this.
Rym: all the management wearing suits in the photo Management had suits.
Scott: we didn't and I didn't clear in the photo who is a manager.
Rym: I quit not long after that.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: And yeah, I got promoted by quitting not by dressing up at my stupid company every day Mmm, the moral is quit to get promoted don't?
Scott: it's actually true Like I've known this for a long time that if you just keep like if I just kept changing jobs like every time recruiters called Yes, I just kept changing CTO some like Dumbo company by now like I'd have so much more monies.
Scott: But it's like.
Scott: do I really want to do that?
Scott: Maybe it's like I you know Do I go to a bunch of shitty jobs and keep changing like twice a year to just to move up and up and up?
Rym: See I did that but I did it every four years and actually it's weird because now I'm in my fifth year at this company.
Rym: I haven't quit yet.
Scott: I'm my seventh year.
Rym: Whoa Whoa, Scott the only thing I've done for well other than gig knives in Connecticut I've never done anything in my life for seven years.
Scott: Yeah fly years Yeah, but nowhere to go.
Rym: every time I've all every time I've quit I've basically like jumped up one full corporate wrong or whatever and it actually worked out super well.
Rym: but the one thing about quitting that all like when you quit is that There's that moment when you walk out the door of oh, yeah All that stuff that I had to take care of is someone else's problem now.
Scott: Hmm And then this and no one can call me not as new stuff.
Scott: That's your problem.
Rym: But the new stuff Is new so I can ask questions and be like wait.
Rym: Well, no, I don't want to do that.
Rym: What's this?
Rym: No, that's not part of my job.
Rym: He didn't know I did not take this job to do that.
Rym: But yeah Dressing like out dressing your co-workers or any of that like dress for the job you want Only seems to work in the kinds of jobs that I would never want and never seem to work in any job I ever had.
Rym: in fact the people like in like when I was in that hospital.
Rym: All the people who dressed like above their station in the job Were kind of not good at their job.
Rym: Try hards who were obviously Try hards.
Scott: Yeah, if I see someone doing that it reeks of effort.
Rym: Yep, and the moral is never reek of effort.
Scott: I mean, I know people who do it who aren't reeking of effort, but it still it feels like that, you know.
Rym: Yeah, I feel like I could do that more easily if clothing was not the one thing I have to go to a physical store mostly to buy.
Rym: now there is I mean just do it.
Scott: if it's a thing that you Like like you can't you want to do it like you would do it Even if you had no job like?
Rym: some of our friends are way more fashionable than us Obviously and that's because that's something care about.
Rym: that's awesome.
Scott: It's a nerd.
Scott: It's geek.
Scott: It's a geekery like any other.
Rym: so I found his service I will not say the name of it on the show.
Rym: There's a couple of them now.
Rym: They're basically blue apron for clothes.
Scott: I've seen a lot of those and they all work slightly differently and I thought about trying one.
Rym: I thought about doing one too.
Scott: But and I've seen I went on YouTube and a lot of people like opening and reviewing different ones as a guy who got one Box from all of them.
Scott: Whoa, and he reviews like all the different ones.
Scott: and it's like.
Scott: the problem is they're all way expensive.
Scott: And it's like well fuck that.
Rym: Yeah cuz blue apron does not cost me that much more than groceries.
Scott: see what I really need is not someone to pick out the clothes for me.
Scott: is I need somebody?
Scott: I need a tailor to Make all the clothes fit me perfectly.
Scott: Yes, even if you go to the store and it's like I have determined that I am medium It's like it's still like like for example, my arms are long, right?
Scott: So I'll buy clothes that fit in every aspect except the sleeves are too short and I might go up one size.
Scott: Okay, the sleeves are the right length, but it's like a balloon now.
Rym: So Scott I don't have that many but I got to tell you so This is definitely a like rich person thing.
Scott: So I need you know, it's like I need you know to in any human being is a slightly different size.
Scott: So even it's very rare that you will be a person where you can buy clothes from the store.
Scott: That will be a hundred percent fitting you perfectly because I'm so you can find the store for you.
Rym: H&M is the store for me.
Rym: their shit fits me real good Like I'm standing 90%.
Scott: but hundred percent is hard to achieve.
Rym: so it's got a weird body.
Scott: It's even harder.
Scott: So it's like, you know, no matter who you are.
Scott: It's like I want a tailor.
Scott: They'll make everything fit me 99%.
Rym: I got multiple tiers of like fitted stuff and There's one level like you get something that has all the measurement like you have yourself measured by a tailor.
Rym: Are you buy a dress shirt while the measurements match you?
Rym: Yeah, that's real good.
Scott: If you're buying fancy clothes, you're obviously gonna get them tailored.
Scott: But I'm talking like my every like tailor my jeans tailor my underwear to everything.
Scott: So everything perfect.
Rym: Several fancy dress shirts that I got mostly for free through work connections because I did.
Rym: as wealthy as I am I'm still not the kind of person who will just like hire tailors to tailor me clothes.
Scott: That's a lot of money.
Rym: It is it is you think it's a lot of money.
Rym: It is so much more money than you think it is Unless you know enough to know how to get a cheap tailor like in Chinatown.
Scott: You could also hire a personal stylist.
Rym: It's pretty cheap to like get a tailor to like make you a custom suit and like suit stuff.
Rym: But if you want like regular old dress shirts or anything, that's like a little bit out of the ordinary.
Rym: It's a lot harder to do unless you have a lot of knowledge a connection or a lot of money.
Rym: But I have several dress shirts that are like 100% custom tailored With way more measurements than normal tailoring does and Custom like my arms fall a certain way and my shoulders are a certain way.
Rym: So they're tailored specifically to me.
Rym: Holy fuck.
Rym: Are they the most comfortable things in the world?
Rym: And it's like Oakley's like Oakley's not the best sunglasses.
Rym: Their only power is that they kind of make like they look good on anyone.
Rym: Mm-hmm The tailored shirts.
Rym: they just make me look like a better human being like they made me look close.
Scott: fitting Mesa is what makes them look good more than anything else.
Rym: That's why I got a lot of respect.
Scott: if you got a really you could go and buy like a ten thousand dollar You know fancy shirt with a name brand on it And if it doesn't fit you perfectly it's gonna look ugly and you could go to the store and buy a five dollar you know.
Scott: thing for the from the.
Scott: you know, the like What's it called the discount bin?
Scott: Yeah, whatever the rack Yeah, the the shittiest like, you know goodwill you can write off the turnip truck.
Scott: You can buy clothes from Goodwill and if they fit you perfectly they gonna look good.
Scott: Yeah, that's how it is.
Scott: fitting is the most important clothes, right?
Rym: but custom tailored clothing I got to admit if I got a lot richer That's the thing I like.
Rym: the two things I would probably waste a ton of money on and do like rich person bullshit with would be traveling and Custom clothes.
Scott: now there is one problem though.
Rym: the tailoring is that if your body changes well Then the tailor changes it and actually that at least for now is not a problem.
Rym: I have a philosophy that I decided on in middle school.
Rym: I decided when I was in eighth grade because I got a little bit of a gut probably from drinking nine or ten Dr.
Rym: Peppers today and Then I worked out and that got one away.
Rym: But I decided that my waist Whatever that size was would never get bigger and I would never in my life ever buy pants That were larger than the pants.
Rym: I had at that time ever.
Rym: So if my gut started not fitting in my pants, I'm fucked.
Rym: I either have to squeeze in or lose weight and I'm pretty sure I can keep that going for the rest of my life.
Scott: You know what happens though?
Scott: Is it in the winter?
Scott: And in the summer, uh, and that's like.
Scott: well at least that works because I have summer clothes and winter clothes.
Scott: My shorts could have a smaller waist than my jeans.
Rym: I actually have that problem.
Rym: my shorts do not 100% fit me in the winter and in the summer they almost fall off at me because I just get crazy skinny in the summer You know, but that's how it works.
Rym: Yeah, but I pretty much have decided that barring catastrophic illness or injury.
Rym: I Will never need different sizes of clothes from what I wear now.
Scott: Well, you get old and you get shorter and you know stuff will happen.
Rym: I'm gonna make sure.
Rym: I'm gonna be that skeletal man who's still jogging when he's 90.
Scott: I hope that he his clothes from you know for 40 years ago don't fit him.
Rym: No, just belt.
Rym: cinch it in.
Rym: just belt it up.
Rym: You can cinch in way easier than you can cinch out.
Scott: It's not gonna look good though.
Rym: No, it's not but at that point I'm basically just a hanger.
Rym: Okay, go home This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and brand.
Scott: Okay for the logos be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night.
Rym: The patrons for this episode of GeekNights in order of the amount of money they give us on a continuing basis are Alan Joyce Rebecca Dunn Nicholas Brandau Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette James David White Christian coons construction noises mystady.com.
Rym: Sean Hayworth William Eisen rose Jeremy minor Chris primer and Thomas Hahn Brian Fisher sailor Vista Vince Clortho key master of coser Volgus the silt reward Lord of seabull Iggy kid Matthew Smith guitar Thomas and Joe Shiro.
Rym: Joe star Tyler Eller Don Schleich Sean Yeager Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Robert Ryan parent drew open lender rare Laval Brian Sidroni Rochelle, Monta Nona Finn Eric Silverado Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: Chris Smith give Chris Knox who thought this was going to be Thomas Hahn But it was me do Sam Cordray Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn and a large number of people who give Less than five dollars a month, which is totally fine because frankly if everyone who listens to GeekNights Gave us just a dollar a month We'd have enough money to do a lot of crazy crap, so I don't necessarily expect people to give us a lot of money.
Rym: We are working on what we're gonna use that money for.
Rym: it's still in a queue.
Rym: We'll let you know of every specific thing we spend it on.
Rym: We're vaguely looking at outside of obvious basic stuff like buying new equipment and doing some stuff in Australia.
Rym: We might do some sort of S in extravaganza in 2018 independent of very likely starting our convention in Hopefully 2017, but anyway like I said we're back.
Rym: Scott's still coughing so I can't really get the Q&A is done until he's not having.
Rym: hideous hacking fits constantly in the background of the show and You'll see a lot more videos in a hurry including maybe tomorrow and survive video.
Rym: And now I leave you with something strange and this time because I made it my thing of the day.
Rym: You'll know that this something strange is The same thing that I got other.
Rym: something strange is from.
Rym: it's a YouTube series called don't hug me.
Rym: I'm Scared.
Rym: time is a tool you can put on the wall or wear it on your wrist.
Rym: The past is far behind us.
Rym: the future doesn't exist.
Scott: Oh, what's the time?
Rym: it's quarter to nine time to have a bath.
Rym: What do you mean?
Rym: we're already clean.
Rym: scrub scrub scrub till the water's brown.
Rym: time is a ruler to measure the day.
Rym: It doesn't go backwards.
Rym: only one way.
Rym: what should go round like a merry-go-round going so fast like a merry-go-round?
Rym: Let's go on a journey a journey through all time the time that's changing all the time.
Rym: It's time to go to time But we don't really want to.
Rym: we're going to miss our show.
Rym: Don't be stupid friends.
Rym: come on.
Rym: It's time to go.
Rym: Cobbles and chimneys a simpler time.
Rym: Three that is older.
Rym: circles inside tree.
Rym: that is older And I rot over time.
Rym: Time could be told by the moon or the Sun, but time flies fast when you're having fun Mm-hmm there's a time and a place for mucking around.
Scott: I'm friends with my dad And then what happened after the olden days?
Rym: Time went new and got old.
Rym: like history stuff from the past went into a mystery.
Rym: an old man died.
Rym: look a computer.
Rym: Everything's cool.
Rym: It's the future.