Rym: It's Tuesday August 2nd 2016.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm scared and this is GeekNights tonight the games that rims playing and Scott's not playing.
Scott: I guess Let's do this.
Rym: We're actually still a little bit sick like You know like usually when we get sick like there's a week of like no GeekNights And then we're just good to go again, but we're both still kind of sick, and it's weird sick.
Scott: It's just like I keep having phlegm.
Scott: I keep coughing up, and it like like.
Rym: this is the longest lingering virus I've ever had like it's.
Rym: actually if we if we keep lingering coughing for like another couple weeks This will be longer than Lyme disease Like it.
Scott: just you know like it waxes and wanes like at night.
Rym: It's bad, and then the day Who do we even get this from?
Rym: thanks ConnectiCon mm-hmm?
Scott: Followed the protocol.
Rym: yeah protocol did not save us that time.
Rym: I mean I buy.
Rym: I even use the alcohol like hand wash Pretty regularly just because you know as the head of the panel's department I was like walking around touching shit like touching microphones.
Rym: That's the kind of stuff.
Rym: I don't do like at a normal packs other than the one panel We're on.
Rym: it's not like we're walking around touching things other than board games.
Rym: So I have in.
Rym: I had other gaming news But this is important enough because we'll see if it sticks around.
Rym: I tried to figure out the exact and specific legal reason why and how this occurred.
Rym: and Holy hell is the publishing provenance of Nintendo power difficult to suss out?
Rym: But the best I can tell is Nintendo ceded the rights to this other company Future which was a subsidiary of a British company also called future Which apparently also owns things like games radar PC gamer maximum PC and all that nonsense.
Rym: but anyway the news is all of Nintendo power.
Rym: every single one is scanned and online.
Rym: at archive org you can just read through Nintendo power.
Rym: and It was a real real hardcore nostalgia trip because I our family we subscribe to Nintendo power Literally from day one.
Rym: I received in the mail every episode of Nintendo power except the first one.
Rym: we bought the first one in the store and Subscribed from it and got the next one in October.
Rym: So yeah, the Nintendo power was pretty much just An ad that I paid for.
Rym: Every month an ad came and I read the ad and I read the ad so much that when I was flipping through these things today I Remember Almost every one of these issues in frightening detail Like I remember what games were in them.
Rym: I just lay there as a kid like read them but over over again The most important one I think is probably 17.
Rym: I think it's 17 17 whichever one was the Final Fantasy guide Because that one most starkly shows the difference between a kid brain and an adult brain.
Rym: when I was a kid my kid brain I'd played Final Fantasy 1. but when I had the Final Fantasy 1 Nintendo power strategy guide, which I think was this year 17 I changed the way I played Final Fantasy 1. and what I would do and I do this about once a year is I would use The guide to do the perfect step count effectively other than leveling up but to just go through the game like no puzzles No getting lost no danger.
Rym: Just fight your way through get the floater and beat the game.
Rym: Like I would read a strategy guide and use it to play this optimal path through a very long game.
Rym: and I would do this Semi often as a child.
Rym: and that's the kind of thing that adult brain would not only disdain But actively try to convince people not to do.
Rym: I don't know what it was but I guess all the nostalgia I would get for playing Final Fantasy 1 again is 100% covered by just reading this issue of Nintendo power again.
Rym: In fact, I think I'm gonna read it again right now.
Rym: You got any news?
Scott: I do have a news.
Scott: So the game that I played perhaps the best game of a few years ago Whatever year it was that I played so much that I became one of the best maybe hundred players in the world Pac-man CEDX, XDX.
Scott: Pac-man.
Scott: Well, there was Pac-man championship edition Which I actually did not play.
Scott: then those Pac-man DX which is the real one and then they even had like DX plus which is like what you'll buy on Steam now.
Scott: Whatever right or see you all Whatever CEDX plus.
Scott: Yeah, it was 17 man, anyway anyway, so You know that game, you know has been Sort of people like lost because basically, you know, it's a game I'm good at.
Scott: but the way the game works is really a game of optimization, right?
Scott: There's so many maps and you optimize each one and then after you figure out how to optimize each one It's just can you execute that optimization the end and if you can, you know Every little bit counts and that's your score.
Scott: and whoever gets the highest score the fastest time because there's time modes and score modes.
Scott: That's pretty much it.
Scott: And then there's not much.
Scott: once you've reached like the limit There's only so much more you can improve and it's really not worth it to most human beings to sit there that long to Marginally improve by like a fraction of a second.
Rym: I mean, it's a lot like like for real more legitimate racing games like just get your time better by a few milliseconds.
Scott: Yeah, so over and over again memorize reached almost my maximum, you know Ability and results so I didn't play it as much.
Rym: You don't want to be a world contender I mean, I basically am a world contender.
Rym: So you should answer like packs.
Scott: a lot of the people who are ahead of me on the score chart were basically fake Entries that were not real people.
Scott: So yeah, it's pretty high up there.
Scott: but part of that was also because the way that the rankings worked.
Scott: is it you it combined.
Scott: there's like.
Scott: there's the combined ranking of Like.
Scott: I think at my highest ranking I was like, you know Like top 20 something.
Scott: but it's like it combined your scores for everything and I did everything in the whole game.
Scott: But if you looked like I was like on the regular old course the basic course, I was like 200 something, right?
Scott: It's still there are a bunch of fake people above me, but it's like I did all the courses It's like on the combined total ranking.
Scott: I was like 20 something, you know, but much higher anyway.
Scott: They have announced and produced many videos displaying and advertising the upcoming thankfully after packs Pac-man championship edition - Which is now which looks to be from the videos An awesome game but also a different game from championship edition different enough that it's not the same game.
Scott: So I think a lot of the same skills will apply.
Scott: It'll be the same kind of game about optimization but it seems much more complex and more interesting and will probably Take a lot longer to master.
Scott: and you mean you're gonna get to start from scratch no matter what.
Scott: So let's play this game because I can play this game.
Rym: Ah I played the original game and it was fun But I'm actually very much more a fan of sort of shared screen direct competition games Like video ball.
Rym: then I'm going to master this one particular skill Memorization games.
Rym: I have never liked games like Ikaruga never even really liked memorize these shmups that much it is Technically the same kind of thing is Ikaruga.
Scott: Yeah for some reason I mean, it's not that fun, but pac-man is way fun.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know what differences
Rym: I've been is way fun until I got really good times on everything and then I could foresee I could forecast I could see the future I could look at one of my times or one of my scores and I can imagine what it would take to make that score better.
Rym: and As soon as I hit that point where I was not getting a better score almost every time I played I no longer cared.
Scott: That was pretty much the same thing that happened to me.
Scott: only the score that I got before I couldn't improve it significantly was much Higher than the one you got.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, so So in other news, I'm not gonna go through the details of it But Pokemon go got a couple updates and I've noticed it still haven't even installed this game.
Rym: It's uh, so here's Scott Here's the way to treat it like for real like real talk to really ignore it.
Rym: No, go play it because it is it's a fun thing.
Scott: It takes no time Wasn't fun to play?
Rym: tang that it is Pokemon snap and Play it as such.
Scott: Why don't I just play Pokemon snap?
Scott: Because it's better than Pokemon snap at being Pokemon snap.
Rym: Yeah, cuz Pokemon snaps actually not that I want to remade Pokemon snap.
Scott: I want to share but Pokemon snap is amazing.
Scott: What's wrong with you?
Scott: It's old.
Scott: It's great.
Scott: Yeah, what do you mean?
Scott: And what's the last time you played it?
Rym: last time I played it was when it was a contemporary newish game Mm-hmm, and even then I only rented it for your n64 that you didn't have.
Rym: no, uh by who?
Rym: uh, I Don't remember the names any Adam Adams n64.
Scott: The point is Pokemon snap is still an amazing game.
Scott: Even today.
Scott: You don't know what you're talking about.
Rym: Yeah, play it again I dare you.
Scott: All right.
Rym: It's not that fun.
Scott: It's great.
Rym: This is this.
Rym: Pokemon snap is better because you're taking pictures of real Pokemon in the real world on like other people's crotches and things
Scott: Mm-hmm,
Rym: but the game has had some updates and some features have been added and removed and there was a so-called cheating thing where you could go to Google Maps and see where all the Pokemon were and And Niantic cut that off.
Rym: so that doesn't work anymore and people were bitching.
Rym: My advice to all of you out there because I play the game idly but like don't try to level up Don't try to maximize your IVs.
Rym: that stuff's not gonna matter ever.
Rym: But for real Don't complain to Niantic about the fact that they made the game more annoying for you.
Rym: You don't seem to understand the fact that this is a free-to-play cell phone game.
Scott: This is a garbage game and you're complaining that they took away what like something from it.
Rym: It's like it's not that garbage Scott like.
Rym: I don't know why you have such as like starkly dour opinion of it.
Scott: You walk around you mindlessly press a button.
Scott: you walk to a different place and mindlessly press a button.
Scott: This is not even like.
Scott: it's very actually.
Rym: no, you don't just press a button.
Rym: It.
Rym: you see you but you see a Pokemon composite on the real world like perched on something okay, and they're in that spot like other people only see that Pokemon in that one specific spot and You have to throw a pokeball and hit him.
Rym: get him.
Scott: Yeah, wouldn't it be better just play Angry Birds, which is more skill-based Because they're completely different thing.
Rym: Angry Birds is a game you play while you're pooping and you're trying to get a high score.
Rym: This game is oh shit.
Rym: There's a Bulbasaur in near this park and I don't have it.
Rym: I'll get this Bulbasaur.
Rym: Yeah, I got a Bulbasaur.
Rym: you fill out the pokedex and then you're pretty much done.
Scott: Yeah, I don't do that.
Rym: All right, but plus, you know the social phenomenon.
Rym: it is Really interesting to me how the crowds of people who are out like catching Pokemon are only growing despite the you know Complaints about the game.
Scott: I don't need to play it to see morons in a group going around catching Pokemon.
Scott: I can I can get or to see Pokemon in potent super imposed on things in the real world in a funny way.
Scott: I can see that on Twitter.
Scott: There's no reason to actually install and waste time on this.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Well, it doesn't take really any time.
Rym: It's not like you're leveling up.
Rym: There's nothing to do.
Scott: It's less effort than ingress, but you know, it's less ever nothing.
Rym: All right, but what I'm seeing out there that's still real interesting.
Rym: It's like every time I walk at the lunch There are easily like 30 or 40 people like right outside of even my office and any phone I look at like any random phone that's out where someone's standing looking at it.
Rym: more than half have a Pokemon go open and on adults kids there seems to be like a Completely flat demographic of just anyone with a smartphone pretty much.
Rym: Yeah, I see it on almost every phone I look at and it started a lot Like I'd see a lot of strangers talking to each other which did not really happen in New York City parks before.
Rym: Like you did not talk to a stranger and yet I've had strangers walk up to me.
Rym: Cuz I'm poking at the game and they're like, oh man There's a Clefairy like right over there, dude and it's.
Rym: it's weird and interesting to me that strangers will talk to me in New York City and I let my shields down enough to look them in the eye and possibly respond with human words that are not.
Rym: no Thanks, or I'll call the police.
Scott: Shouldn't the response be get the fuck away from me.
Scott: Who are you?
Rym: Pokemon guy.
Rym: Pokemon trainers are good.
Rym: They're all like.
Rym: they're all like the NPCs in Pokemon, but I'm an evil Pokemon.
Rym: I'm telling you knock a kid out and steal his fucking Pokemon.
Scott: Dude if they let you do that, like if I if my Scott they do it's called the real world.
Rym: Just hit people and take their phone.
Scott: if I took someone's phone and I could just Transfer all their Pokemon into my pokedex or my PC.
Rym: They're adding trading so you will be able to do that.
Scott: No, just giving like just take like all in one shot really quickly.
Scott: Yeah, then I would totally do that rocket mode.
Scott: Yeah I'd go around and just steal all people's Pokemon when they're not looking.
Rym: if you tied it to Google Wallet and then if you beat Someone in a Pokemon duel it literally took their money and gave it to you.
Scott: Yeah, all right.
Scott: I would play that.
Rym: Okay speaking of which Google Wallet?
Rym: the thing that you Desperately tried to argue with me and convinced me a long time ago that it was done And website said it was no the website didn't.
Scott: the web multiple articles saying Google Wallet will no longer let you put money in.
Rym: Nope You said that and you were a hundred percent wrong.
Rym: every one of those articles linked to one article and that one article said Google Wallet will not let you put money in for the purposes of using a Google credit card Well debit card for transactions.
Rym: They were ending the debit card component of it.
Rym: Not the rest of it.
Rym: And I point out it is now by six months since the date that you said Based on poor reading of a website that Google Wallet was gonna die.
Rym: and not only is Google Wallet still working But I used it today.
Rym: So you were wrong about that 100%.
Scott: the website was wrong about?
Rym: no the website.
Rym: In fact, I can find the website again a link to it.
Rym: The website was a hundred percent, right?
Rym: The website said Google Said You'll find the website again because I'll find the website again.
Rym: I saved it.
Scott: All right, go ahead.
Scott: All right, you were wrong.
Rym: But my advice to all you Pokemon go players out there is that if you expect Niantic to respond To you or care about your complaints.
Rym: This is a free-to-play cell phone game the free-to-play cell phone games.
Rym: Especially if they have a candy box model and have any sort of interaction between players or levels or anything.
Rym: They they make their money by annoying you.
Rym: They're not gonna stop annoying you because the only way you're gonna put money into the thing is if that money avoids some annoyance.
Scott: It just never ceases to amaze me that like I'm 34 and I figured out sometime Around high school in college you know how to separate you know a game from its skin and like recognize the two things as a separate thing and see through the matrix and recognize a game for what it is and How many people in the world despite how much I spread this knowledge to them?
Scott: Completely failed to recognize this and like they can't see past the fact that this Pokemon on their screen and realize that there's some garbage Useless game underneath Scott.
Rym: Here's the article I had saved the link quote When to support.
Scott: I don't think that's the right.
Scott: the same article.
Rym: This is definitely it.
Rym: Google is shutting down.
Scott: That's not the same article that I saw.
Rym: Well, if you claim that then the article you saw one doesn't exist and two was wrong.
Rym: So that either the best-case scenario is that you're bad at vetting websites and that you fell for a scam site.
Rym: I mean, this is CNET.
Rym: There's no.
Rym: this was like the source.
Rym: This is still the top link.
Rym: if you search for that Wrong for some reason you're resisting it somehow here.
Rym: another one.
Rym: Google ready to kill its physical wallet card Got a wallet card.
Rym: Google is dropping support for it on June 30th.
Rym: separate article There is no article anywhere saying that Google Wallet itself is ending on that day.
Rym: You made it up.
Scott: There is an article that said Google Wallet will no longer let you put money into it.
Rym: There is no article that says that there is.
Scott: I'll find them.
Rym: Nope.
Rym: I dare you to find it because it does not exist.
Rym: So but Pokemon go at least is the minimum effort and it is fun enough like it covered the basics.
Rym: There's a Pokemon in the real world.
Rym: I can throw a pokeball at it and catch it and you can ignore every other part of the game.
Rym: What frightens me is that there are people who are not ignoring the rest of the game and are actively trying to level up and Play it and our certain friends of ours.
Rym: In fact are going so far as to IV train their Pokemon.
Rym: I guarantee that that IV training stuff either will never matter or If they add features to the point where it does matter.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: So here we go.
Scott: Mr.
Scott: All right This is the CNET article that you brought up.
Scott: All right, let me read it word for word.
Scott: All right When does support for wallet cards and wallet cards not wallet?
Scott: Hold on wallet cards will stop working on June 30th 2016.
Scott: Okay, sure.
Scott: Yeah, and You will not be able to add money to your Google Wallet account after May 1st 2016 Period.
Scott: so the article is written poorly.
Scott: It says you will not be able to add money to your Google Wallet account.
Scott: It doesn't say you will not be able to add money to your Google debit card.
Scott: You will not be able to add money to your Google Wallet account after May 1st 2016. clearly that is not the case because you can add money to your Google Wallet account and we are now after May 1st 2016. but those are the exact words in this article from CNET the Vented place or whatever.
Rym: All right, so you know those words were wrong.
Scott: I'm not wrong.
Scott: I just read those words and those words lied to me except every other website contemporary to this Says can you guys are those the words that say are that are on that page?
Rym: I'm reading the whole thing now.
Scott: Are those the words that are in that side?
Rym: So you are just there's some.
Scott: I'm dumb because I read what the word said.
Scott: You're the one who said something different from what the words say.
Rym: ah But I remember when we had this argument.
Rym: you Refuse to acknowledge all the other evidence of all the other sites that did not say that.
Scott: I'm just saying that's what they wrote here.
Scott: They wrote a wrong thing.
Scott: We can't yet tell me I'm dumb because someone wrote a wrong thing.
Scott: Well,
Rym: yeah, if one website says one thing and every other website says a different thing I'm
Scott: just saying and
Rym: you believe CNET
Scott: CNET that you were just trying to say this because
Rym: I was trying to give you the benefit of the doubt and find any website that Corroborated your made-up bullshit about Google Wallet.
Scott: I'm just saying you will not be able to add money.
Scott: That's a pretty clear statement.
Rym: Yeah, and if that's true, then how come you'd still argued against me even then when other websites said the opposite?
Rym: Why did you trust CNET over all these other websites?
Rym: I didn't read any other websites even when I showed him to you on my phone and I was like hey That's what it says right there.
Rym: In fact believe many of our friends were present for this argument and we're waiting for me to bring this up in the future.
Rym: when?
Rym: You were definitely wrong Because no one agreed with you and everyone thought you were wrong.
Rym: and sure enough you were wrong.
Scott: Yes the whole world.
Scott: I'm just saying those are the words that are in that article that led me to believe a thing that is wrong and those words Are pretty clear.
Scott: So that's what happens when you read things up further on in the article.
Rym: It actually is pretty clear.
Rym: So you focused on one sentence of one article among a sentence among many in an article among many.
Rym: I'm just saying I'm just saying yeah, you were super wrong on this.
Scott: Let's go find the things.
Scott: room is wrong about no name name one thing.
Rym: I'm wrong about many things such as So Scott what's funny?
Rym: because you I know you don't listen to the patreon stuff But I've been listening to the beta episodes of GeekNights.
Scott: Why why do you hurt yourself that way?
Rym: We until the the one I just remastered was the first time we did a real episode of GeekNights.
Rym: Before that it was just us arguing about stupid shit like that And I was kind of nostalgic for those days like we argued about the dumbest shit.
Scott: you stop listening to this shit.
Rym: It's amazing though.
Scott: No, it's not Scott.
Rym: you and I both were super convinced and excited That Karl Rove was gonna get indicted for treason.
Scott: No, I guess that could happen.
Rym: yeah, yeah, but we both like really believed it and you talked a lot about Janet Reno.
Rym: You seem to know a lot about her.
Scott: I guess I'd used to yeah.
Rym: But anyway, uh, that's another GeekNights tradition of the dumb argument that goes on forever.
Scott: There's not a point.
Scott: It's like what good load of caring did to help write nothing.
Rym: Pokemon go is Fun despite what Scott says but do not in any way Spend money on it.
Rym: Do not in any way spend time on it other than collecting Pokemon and doing the basics.
Rym: Like if you're walking around catch some Pokemon Don't spend hours using lucky eggs to level yourself up to hit a specific level and Also that level cap of 30 that you're all obsessed with.
Rym: that's gonna take, you know hundreds of hours to level up to.
Rym: They're gonna raise it.
Rym: They're gonna keep raising forever.
Rym: candy box games have to raise the levels forever.
Scott: Your life is only so long.
Scott: how much of your life are you gonna spend making a number go up on your phone?
Scott: even if you like even if you're walking from point A to point B is Your life going to be enriched more by looking at your phone Mindlessly tapping in the picture of a Pokemon or by looking around you?
Rym: that depends on where I am.
Rym: If it's a place I won't let play a worthwhile game.
Scott: if you're gonna be doing that a game with some amount of thought Involved like what that you can play while you're walking You can play while you're walking.
Scott: a game with thought involves some kind of some kind of like puzzle or something.
Rym: You know, you're gonna stare at your phone staring at a puzzle while you're walking.
Scott: Hey, why not?
Rym: I guess it could be an audio puzzle.
Scott: Well, that's not bad idea.
Rym: I wonder if we could make that like audio puzzles share for blind people.
Scott: They exist.
Scott: Yeah Where what?
Rym: What do you mean?
Rym: They exist where?
Scott: There's all kinds of search for.
Scott: I've done this before.
Scott: they search like video games for blind people and there's all sorts of like audio Only games text adventures are actually really popular.
Scott: Use that.
Scott: use the voice the text to voice and voice to text both combined and you can you know, ah Actually, here's one.
Rym: when NPR does is it's wait, they're always logic puzzles, but they tell you a logic puzzle.
Rym: You have to figure out the answer.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: I don't think they give you the answer though Maybe they give it to you next week.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I already lost interest.
Rym: Don't just do not invest significance time or resources in Pokemon go because what it is now it will never be Substantially more than what it is Now.
Rym: if you're investing in it thinking that is going to be more than it is now in the future You're going to be deeply disappointed in the future.
Rym: I'm surprised people aren't disappointed already Because it's actually way better than the minimum effort had to be.
Rym: Shockingly, yeah, okay it is it could have been way less and it was way more.
Scott: I guess it can always be less but it's still not enough.
Rym: Oh, what would be enough?
Rym: What do you want?
Scott: What would be enough to make me play it?
Scott: Yeah had to be an actual game of skills.
Rym: What like Pokemon?
Scott: Pokemon is more game of skills the book.
Rym: So what if it was regular Pokemon except in the real world like a are MMO?
Scott: Maybe?
Rym: then maybe you'd play it maybe Anyway things of the day.
Rym: so Most of you probably have no idea about this.
Rym: But if you play Mario Party, I think seven six or seven was the last one I play because Mario Party fucking sucks.
Rym: I'm just sorry, but Mario Party Has something that you might not have known because you've probably never actually put the AI on easy.
Scott: Well, you've never been so sad as to play Mario Party against the AI.
Rym: now I first encountered this with a red supray.
Rym: It's one of the things you'll ever see.
Rym: It's Mario Party of one and it's a kid playing Mario Party.
Scott: I think that was the prettiest thing of the day.
Rym: calm calm and calm.
Scott: But well calm one come to come through.
Scott: I should do that.
Rym: If you put the AI in Mario Party games on easy like you set the game to easy mode and You're the only human the AIs conspire to make you win.
Rym: and this video And there's one of these for every Mario Party it's just a compilation of a ton of mini games in Mario Party 10 where Luigi wins by inputting nothing at any point into the game and It's kind of amazing to watch Especially considering a lot of the comments are people who are either saying it's fake or who are Angry at the other players for being so bad.
Rym: Do not understand that.
Rym: it's the AI.
Scott: Yeah, Rin sent me this link and I'm like, why is it?
Scott: I just watched the video and I'm like, why is this interesting?
Scott: it's just like somebody made a bunch of clips of Luigi winning it Smash Brothers and Mario Party without pressing any buttons.
Scott: I assumed that some other people were controlling all the other characters and just making them be stupid.
Scott: Yeah to create this video and I'm like, this isn't really funny or interesting.
Scott: What's the deal?
Scott: Why do you like this?
Scott: And then I realized Smash Brothers is only one and they probably did the Smash Brothers one like a bunch of times.
Scott: Yeah, but the until they got the result they wanted but the Mario Party ones is yeah It's the AI went on easy is so bad that it loses on purpose.
Scott: So they were able to show I don't know why they didn't need to do so many of them to demonstrate this but it's like Yeah, well the thing is an easy loses on purpose.
Scott: You can literally input nothing and win.
Rym: This is in a court one of those ghettos on the internet, especially on YouTube There are.
Rym: there's this whole underground world of no input wins in games and there's a community of people.
Rym: It's kind of like the lot Running community.
Rym: They're not.
Rym: they're not like super big but I found this whole game.
Rym: There's a lot of videos about this stuff and as people try to win games by not inputting anything
Scott: I've seen people make Mario Maps before Mario maker and the old like hack ROMs and stuff where they make their own maps where they design the map where you don't input anything and it starts and then Mario just goes like Through a crazy amount of stuff and eventually wins the level without pressing anything.
Rym: This is a step beyond the half press a. So you got a thing of the day.
Scott: yeah, I do have a thing of the day.
Scott: So, you know under your bicycle you got gears and you got a gear in the front and a gear in the back Hopefully a bunch of gears in the back unless you're really dumb and there's a ratio between those gears.
Scott: right if you got a big one in the front and a small one in the back one crank in the front might turn the back one Like five or six times.
Scott: that's like the ratio is the number of times the other one spins and you turn the crank once.
Scott: if you had a little One in the front a big one in the back You might turn the crank once and have the back one spin like not even one time And then your ratio is like less than one.
Scott: It's like point five.
Rym: That's how you go weeka weeka weeka up a hill.
Scott: All right, exactly.
Scott: But when the ratio is low less than one or you know well the lower the ratio the easier it is to turn the handle.
Scott: the crank is real easy to turn and The bigger the ratio you go a lot faster.
Scott: less cranks will get you a lot of spins, but it's hard to turn like.
Scott: You need more energy.
Rym: Oh, I was gonna look up something about gear ratios And all I found is these fixie people who are obsessed with a 44 16 ratio and how it's the perfect rate.
Rym: fixie people Whatever.
Scott: So this guy this has nothing to do with bicycles.
Scott: He just set up a bunch of gears and these gears have Particularly, they're designed in particular way such that the ratio is ridiculously Ridiculously low or high depending on which end you put the crank on.
Rym: Oh, it looks like it's a bunch of planetary nonsense in here.
Rym: Yeah, well no It's.
Scott: it's really the other gears that are the main ones.
Scott: you just use the planetary ones to sort of multiply the effect of the other ones, you know if you watch the video, but basically He's got a whole bunch of gears all stacked up in a really interesting configuration.
Scott: That's easy to understand if you watch the video such that you have you would have to turn the crank over 11 million times to get the big gear to turn one time.
Scott: So such power.
Scott: so it's like dude Turn the big gear one time put a lever on it and pull it and make the handle spin 11 million.
Scott: Just do it.
Scott: Of course.
Scott: It would be so hard to turn that you actually I'm pretty sure It might just explode if you do that.
Scott: Well, I'm pretty sure I need a lever So big.
Rym: if you tried to do that it would If it was a perfect system that doesn't exist in the real world.
Rym: Yeah, the other end would go faster than the speed of light which is why this is impossible Independent of the material sciences concerns, huh?
Scott: That's interesting, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I know the answer.
Rym: I know where you're going with this behind you.
Scott: What's the answer then?
Rym: So the answer is Materials are not actually rigid.
Rym: So no matter how long a lever you think you're gonna make because you're thinking make a lever so long That you could force something else to go faster than the speed of lights, right?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: The answer is materials aren't actually rigid.
Rym: So just because the bending of the thing y'all couldn't can't actually make a rigid body Mmm, cuz remember it's just electrons like nothing's touching anything.
Scott: So even though on paper it would happen You can't actually do it because there's no material you can actually make.
Scott: that would make it happen.
Scott: Something else would mess you up.
Scott: Yep, physically.
Rym: Yep physics gets in the way.
Scott: It's like we just it's like oh, haha It didn't actually happen the way you thought all this video.
Scott: I didn't make one that wouldn't explode.
Rym: I was clicking around the video and I hit the page where he shows the equation of the gear ratio.
Scott: It's not really a complex math at all.
Scott: He's just multiplying the ratios of all the gear after gear after gear, you know All together, so we should make an art installation with a robot that's slowly turning that 11 million times.
Scott: Go for it.
Scott: Yeah, you can 3d print all his gears.
Rym: Yeah, I Go.
Rym: Whoa, there's a. so I found another ghetto on the internet.
Rym: Oh That's all his channel.
Rym: I was about to say now There's all these recommended videos of crazy gears, but it's all the same guy's channel.
Scott: He 3d prints gears.
Scott: That's his deal.
Scott: So you could actually add his channel to the thing of the day if you want as well.
Scott: But the extreme ratio is the most interesting one, right?
Scott: Yeah bigger go home.
Rym: I really do just want to do what you're saying and put something on the inside gear.
Rym: just give it a twist.
Scott: That's what I'm saying.
Scott: At least you know, you know If you can't do the 11 million right at least cut it down to like 1 million and then turn it like 90 degrees.
Scott: You don't need to turn all the way and you get 250 K spins in one pole.
Scott: It's like go for it.
Scott: Pretty awesome, right?
Scott: I wonder what that has to be a point at which it's doable.
Rym: Well, the gears either.
Scott: even 10,000 spins in that amount of time would be really cool.
Rym: I suspect things will either melt catch fire or shear or explode.
Rym: Those are the four options.
Scott: melt like no, all right, you know put a knife on it and pull it right cut something Put a knife with like an apple and like You know, we've.
Rym: if we were better at this we could just video ourselves.
Rym: Like we're gonna turn the other way and make a whole video and then you like walk up to it and you start to turn It and then we just composite it exploding and killing both of us Do it like a live stream prank and then just shows us sitting there dead and the live streams keeps going after that.
Rym: Whatever in the moment the book club book, which we are talking about on Thursday.
Scott: You actually read it.
Rym: Yeah Book took me like five and a half six hours to read according to Kendall.
Rym: That's what I took me or extend Craig by Margaret Atwood.
Rym: if you ever wondered what cheeky knobs are now, you'll know goons pig goons.
Scott: You know actually that cool a pig cheeky knobs also.
Scott: pig goons ring goes from the shell to man machine interface.
Scott: Ah, I feel like they were the main plot point if you could pay attention and understand what the hell was going on.
Rym: Something that is very important to modern society is that I think Chicky knobs would be a good idea.
Rym: Like I feel like we really should make things like that I would eat chicken them.
Rym: I would eat chicken knobs all the time.
Scott: delicious.
Rym: Yeah and nutritious fried chicken Delicious only can make himself for.
Scott: I love fried chicken everywhere in the world delicious.
Rym: But we're gonna talk about Thursday.
Rym: It's the GeekNights book club.
Rym: I know it's been a while because in between the last book club Which was the first book of the wheel of time and oryx and Craig I read the entire wheel of time and the new prince of nothing book.
Rym: So It's been a while, but it's gonna be spoilers.
Rym: So read the book before you listen to this Thursday episode cuz we're gonna assume you read the book and we're just gonna spoil it.
Rym: Oryx and Craig.
Rym: like I'm not even gonna tell you just read it.
Rym: it's a book you should read.
Rym: it's a gene-fueled science fiction dystopia.
Rym: Mmm, it's not that unlikely.
Rym: some of the things that happen in it.
Rym: Hmm Otherwise we're going to be at PAX West 2016 on prime Saturday September 3rd the real packs at 5 p.m.
Rym: In Physical plant in the chicken theater.
Rym: We're gonna be doing a the grind talking about grinding and games.
Scott: I should probably get on that.
Rym: I started making some diagrams and things, but I haven't made slides yet.
Scott: I started outlining.
Rym: All right Let me know when you make the slideshow and I'll start making some diagrams and things of.
Rym: you know The because you know those diagrams of like the hero's journey.
Rym: I feel like there's different grind journeys and different kinds of games.
Rym: I'm working on some diagrams to show that Pokemon go we can talk about because there's a candy box in there.
Rym: Hmm but yeah, we'll be there.
Rym: Otherwise, it's just four or if you're me six gay days of gaming and hanging out and such.
Rym: So, uh, I'm playing a lot of games.
Rym: What are you playing Scott?
Scott: Nothing.
Rym: Why aren't you playing anything?
Scott: Summer, why would I play games?
Rym: But what are you doing instead of playing games?
Scott: Not playing games.
Rym: All right, like what?
Rym: like anything?
Rym: anything other than laundry like it's.
Rym: it's nice out but like it can only bike so much in a day Biking around.
Rym: Yeah, I've been biking around reading books.
Rym: I've been reading books.
Rym: I've been powering through some books Watching some internet videos watching Korean stuff.
Scott: Yeah, you know the same amount as every week.
Scott: Yeah Cooking some blue aprons.
Rym: I've been cooking those.
Rym: I've been watching a lot of TV.
Rym: actually cuz Steven Universe is like in full steam again.
Rym: Bojack just came out Rick and Morty's coming real soon.
Rym: Stranger Things looks real good.
Rym: It looks like It looks like some Stephen King style horror nonsense with a modern sensibility but with some throwback sensibilities as well.
Scott: Yeah, I don't watch any of that trick.
Rym: It's probably really good and critically acclaimed.
Scott: Yeah, whatever.
Rym: So I thought I thought your whole definition of non-drek was like it has to be critically acclaimed in some way.
Scott: No, I just don't like American television really.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So what about critically acclaimed American television?
Scott: Yeah, we'll see if anyone even remembers it in like five years.
Rym: So have you watched the wire?
Rym: Nope, cuz that's still remembered.
Rym: It's been a long time since that came out.
Rym: Yeah, you're not playing any games at all because you don't even come to like game nights.
Rym: We do over here anymore.
Rym: No, no, you're not playing like games.
Rym: Yeah, you didn't even really play all the games we played at the party.
Scott: You only played Motai night, which is a bad game now.
Rym: We played a few other games.
Scott: What are the games you play?
Rym: mostly glory to Rome?
Scott: I played that once.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's also not a good game.
Scott: That's a good game.
Rym: It's a real good game.
Rym: I like Motai night a lot.
Rym: I still think I like glory to Rome more, but I feel like they're.
Rym: they serve different purposes.
Rym: glory to Rome is just a romp through this heuristic space.
Rym: and Motai night is you stare at each other and then you all do a thing and then you all go well shit.
Rym: And then you stare at each other do it a few more times and someone was smarter.
Scott: I don't like any of those games.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So what game what game do you want to play if you're not playing any games?
Rym: Like what game would break you out of your not gaming funk?
Scott: It starts snowing so I can't go outside.
Rym: I have to play a game So there's no game you can think of.
Rym: that would get you to stay inside and play a game like today.
Scott: It is kind of raining today.
Rym: Yeah, it was raining yesterday's why I didn't bike to work.
Scott: I spent all night playing overwatch a game where I like wouldn't go home and eat dinner.
Scott: I'd play the game instead.
Rym: Yeah, like I'd say like after we do the show We just play the game cuz I can name like.
Rym: I could easily come up with 40 or so games.
Rym: I would do that for right now.
Rym: Mmm, some of those games don't exist.
Scott: Nothing I'm not in a gaming mood.
Scott: It's not game time.
Rym: What is it?
Rym: But it's like this ready with.
Rym: Valhalla came out video ball came out.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, I've installed video bomb.
Scott: didn't even know play it yet.
Scott: Uh, if you played Valhalla Installed that too and didn't play it yet.
Rym: Oh, you least installed it.
Scott: It's not going anywhere.
Scott: That's a single-player game.
Scott: What's the rush?
Rym: Yeah, it looks like there was an update to it already.
Scott: I can wait for a gaming mood and then play.
Scott: it's not going.
Scott: It's nothing, you know, it's not gonna be a different game than it is now.
Rym: So I got the expansion to camel up.
Rym: Now we can do 10 player camel ups.
Scott: if you had 10 people I might play that once.
Rym: Yeah, in fact people are coming over tomorrow.
Rym: We're gonna play some board games.
Scott: I don't think you have 10 people though.
Rym: No, I don't agree to have 10 people either.
Rym: Camel up at this point is my.
Rym: there's more people than we have room in a real game to play.
Rym: So we're gonna play camel up instead pretty much.
Rym: That's the game I mean, it's fun, but it's not as fun as say st.
Rym: Petersburg or Kayla's.
Scott: Now I'll play games at PAX too, right?
Scott: So why should I play games now?
Scott: I'm gonna spend four day.
Scott: I'm gonna fly across the country to spend four days playing games.
Rym: Why would I play a game now just play a game then but you're gonna get over there and we're all just gonna want to Play overwatch and we'll just go to the PC area and play an overwatch.
Scott: Okay, you can't do that for more than like 20 minutes.
Scott: So good luck with that.
Rym: I could I could.
Rym: I could enter the tournament cuz that was the secret I learned from that packs.
Rym: where I went I entered the Counter-strike arms race tournament.
Rym: because basically and this seems to be a trend at PAX is if you enter those like second tier PC gaming tournaments at PAX is The enforcers like set you up and it's sort of self-regulating like they don't really pay attention to you that much.
Rym: So you do the qualifier and you lose or whatever?
Rym: But usually no one comes over and makes you leave because those pcs are dedicated to that tournament and you can just stay in There and keep playing counter-strike for like hours and no one will say anything to you.
Scott: That's how you want to spend your pecs playing a game that you could play in your house Playing it on a LAN with other people or physically next to me yelling and screaming.
Scott: Mm-hmm slightly improved, but it's not.
Scott: Experience not really worth the.
Rym: I think it is more than like one or two because the LAN experience is actually rare Er than it used to be.
Rym: so I don't commonly experience the LAN But on the rare occasions when I do usually cuz I'm at a con by accident.
Rym: Like I play a game on a LAN suddenly like How come I can avoid coughing in the microphone.
Scott: but you can't you think you've been coughing constantly for a while?
Scott: But I go is go away from the microphone like chocolate rain.
Rym: I still have a filter that edits the cops out at least for you because yours are yours are pretty Regular and consistent.
Rym: I can show you the cough filter if you want.
Rym: It's a noise filter that looks specifically for cops and reduces them.
Rym: But the LAN experience every time I do it like especially a couple weekends ago.
Rym: our friends came out and Phil and Jan and we we just played overwatch while they were here.
Rym: They stood up in the living room.
Scott: Why didn't?
Scott: why they even come?
Scott: they could have just stayed at home.
Rym: There's something about the LAN experience.
Scott: I mean, yeah, there's something about the LAN experience, but I'm not gonna do it more than like two games worth at a PAX.
Rym: I mean, I used to go to LAN.
Scott: The LAN experience does not even come close to the PAX experience.
Rym: The LAN experience is the PAX experience.
Rym: Yeah, it's all part of the same experience.
Rym: No All right.
Rym: Well, I'm gonna keep doing it.
Rym: But yeah overwatch is pretty much my overarching game right now.
Rym: Like I'm actually playing it's interesting.
Rym: We've sort of flipped for some reason Scott's I guess doing laundry and watching Korean dramas.
Rym: I'm playing more games than I've played.
Scott: I don't watch any dramas.
Rym: Ah, just the variety shows.
Rym: But like I'm gaming a lot lately.
Scott: The dramas are probably even worse than American television.
Scott: I mean, yeah, they have their merits but it's like oh my god, you can't watch it.
Rym: But I honestly play overwatch like an hour or two every night and you're never getting those hours back.
Rym: You know what dad you never get those tribes two hours back yet either.
Rym: Do you regret those tribes two hours?
Rym: Maybe what do you really regret?
Rym: playing tribes - those are good time?
Scott: I could have done some good stuff instead.
Scott: if like what less stupid?
Rym: Oh, well Like what if we had died.
Rym: if we had done like we're gonna fucking make shit.
Rym: back then when we were in college instead of playing Games, we wouldn't have played enough games to be able to GeekNights.
Rym: now Mmm, like we wouldn't have known the things that we.
Scott: so I running out of you guys ideas now cuz they're making shit and not.
Rym: So we got to play more shit.
Rym: No, why not?
Rym: because then week one I don't want to because either we can make more because we've played more or We're just playing games like in the old like, you know those days.
Scott: problem is I've seen through all games.
Scott: There's nothing.
Scott: there's nothing new in gaming.
Scott: That is different than anything.
Scott: I've seen before it's not you know, it's not getting me excited.
Scott: Every time I look at a new game, I'm like, yeah.
Scott: All right.
Scott: That's just one of those.
Scott: whatever That played that what?
Rym: if that's true then how come you don't win new games when we play them?
Scott: It doesn't mean that I have the skills.
Scott: It just means that I'm not interested.
Rym: but you saw through it.
Rym: So clearly you didn't actually see through.
Rym: you Don't really know what's going on.
Rym: What do you mean like in a random board game?
Rym: Look, you play.
Rym: we play some new board game Like you don't really see if you understood it enough to win it.
Scott: I understand it enough that it is not stimulating me in a way that is bringing me.
Rym: Joy All right, so what kind of game would you would be new?
Rym: what kind of game do you want to play?
Scott: No games Not any game.
Scott: I can bet a game.
Rym: What kind of tabletop game?
Rym: any game?
Scott: You just play some teeny I guess.
Rym: so just play teeny again.
Rym: Mmm.
Scott: What else you want to play?
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I actually kind of want after doing that show the other day.
Rym: I kind of want to play Kayla's again.
Rym: Yeah, I miss Kayla's.
Scott: I think I'd actually like to play a legacy game.
Scott: but the problem is the only legacy games are risk and pandemic.
Rym: if there was something else legacy like Agricola legacy Everyone we know has seems to agree that if they played risk legacy or not race legacy pandemic legacy It's not the best game, but the pandemic problem is eliminated by the fact that it is just legacy.
Rym: It's more like you're playing this sort of adventure game together and then you react to stuff that happens and it's not the well Let's beat this very trivially optimized semi-random game again.
Scott: No, I just believe them.
Rym: We should play it and find out you don't know.
Scott: you go for it.
Rym: Yeah, so you're not gonna play it.
Rym: you tell me first and then maybe okay, but if I play it I'm not gonna play it again.
Rym: There's only play the game once.
Scott: Oh, you got a you know, but you got to play multiple sessions.
Scott: That's what the legacy is about.
Scott: So play the first set.
Rym: Yeah, you play the multiple sessions with the same people.
Rym: I'm not gonna.
Rym: I'm not gonna split up my group once I make a group.
Scott: Good luck getting the same people to shove every time.
Rym: Ah I think I get some people to show up.
Rym: actually I'm pretty sure we're gonna start up the burning wheel game again.
Scott: No burning wheels a good idea.
Rym: You wanna play burning wheel.
Rym: play my thief game.
Scott: I don't play your thief game.
Rym: What game do you want to play burning wheel then?
Rym: Cuz that's the game.
Rym: I'm running.
Scott: Yeah, actually gonna want to play not burning wheel RV.
Rym: What RPG do you want to play?
Rym: I'll fucking run it for you.
Scott: Jesus I don't want to play a game.
Scott: Rym runs.
Scott: Why I just don't like you?
Rym: what DM to you?
Rym: Who do you want to DM then?
Rym: What do you want like Luke crane to personally curate a custom RPG for you in your house.
Scott: I wouldn't complain about that, but I'm not gonna ask for it either.
Rym: Just not Rym Pretty much anyone else when I don't know if you've ever played in a game.
Rym: I DM'd I Can imagine.
Scott: I don't think you know, I know you've all know.
Rym: you never have.
Rym: you've never played in a game.
Rym: I've DM'd.
Rym: I don't think ever.
Scott: Let's keep it that way.
Rym: I played in your burning con game that one time Mmm, I also played in your door fortress game.
Rym: Then we'll never speak of again.
Scott: No, even though the last session was pretty good That's why I figured out how to make shit up.
Scott: No No, it's.
Rym: I know what I'm doing now makes it up but also follow the rules.
Rym: That's how you do it.
Scott: Yeah, I wasn't making shit up before that last game.
Rym: Yeah, so you want to play.
Rym: what kind of RPG?
Rym: Do you want to play or who do you want to run?
Rym: What kind of DM?
Rym: Do you want?
Scott: I just kind of want to play like cuz.
Scott: I got so many indie RPGs that I bought and are on the Urban played.
Scott: I don't want to play each one like one time each.
Rym: I'm up for that.
Rym: Like I got the Warren I'm pretty excited to run it.
Rym: Actually.
Rym: I could play a Warren once play the Warren So I don't want to play it once.
Rym: I want to play at least one short campaign because most Kind of like I'm not interested in the one-off RPG anymore because all the like advancement mechanics and legacy mechanics Those are the things that have always made RPGs really fun.
Scott: Yeah, I mean while I do agree that the campaign that goes on has gone forever I'm talking like six sessions has you know, much more power and quality than the one-off.
Scott: There is no denying that.
Scott: It's just that I don't want to commit to anything.
Rym: So your main complaint about other people is that they won't commit to anything.
Scott: That's also true.
Scott: But I'm also people that won't commit.
Rym: your complaint is about yourself.
Rym: So do you want in the thief game or not?
Rym: Cuz I'm gonna start it up again as soon as the weather gets a little bit south like right after packs.
Scott: Well, I mean after packs, it might be in a game mood again.
Scott: Who knows?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: until then you're in the mood for anything.
Scott: I mean laying in the Sun like I'd say.
Rym: you're missing the boat on overwatch.
Rym: But overwatch is only gaining steam like it's not slowing down.
Rym: It's expanding.
Scott: I don't really want to play enough.
Scott: Yeah, why not?
Scott: I mean, I just don't want to play enough.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: So what what if tribes 2 was remade?
Rym: but it had everything good about tribes 2?
Rym: Everything like it was perfect as far as our game design sensibilities were and it just came out again tomorrow.
Rym: But it was like tribes to 2016.
Scott: I Mean they did come out with those other tribes and then one of them I played like.
Rym: those are all kind of bad.
Rym: We knew they were bad.
Rym: There's even a penny arcade talking about how like they'll get you through the night, but they're not a real substitute for tribes to.
Rym: I Weren't.
Rym: they were kind of bad.
Scott: Maybe if I was in a given mood, I'm just nice not game time.
Scott: All right.
Scott: I'll play pac-man.
Scott: Say pac-man championship edition - that's good.
Rym: That's just a single-player game.
Rym: I guess I'll play it enough to review it.
Scott: I'll play it.
Rym: I'll play it to review it.
Scott: if it'll run on my ancient htpc Why would I think it's gonna run in pretty much any?
Scott: X86 computer?
Rym: I hope so.
Rym: We'll find out because actually video ball a little bit of trouble on my htpc.
Rym: Video ball runs way better on my main PC Which itself is not not a spring chicken compared to the htpc.
Rym: Remember the htpc is also 2009 era but it was less than a third the cost of my other PC 2009 era.
Scott: I mean mine's like i3 as a GPU.
Scott: I would be nice.
Rym: I can't play 2d video of all the frame rate not as good as on my main PC.
Scott: I'll have to test it out.
Rym: You should the game does not work a hundred percent great.
Scott: I mean now's the time to buy computers.
Rym: So Yeah, it's either buy it now because if you buy a computer like six months from now, it's not gonna cost much less.
Scott: Well, you know what?
Scott: It packs.
Rym: You'll have less time with the new computer, you know, we're going to a packs.
Scott: We can go around to all those little booths with all the hardware vendors.
Rym: That's what I did at the last packs We went to.
Scott: well, yeah I keep that for some reason.
Scott: I keep doing that at packs and then even though I've done it packs like three or four Times I've never actually bought anything in there.
Rym: But this time I don't buy things.
Rym: what I do is I add them to my.
Rym: I have that wish list that I'm constantly updating of the piece.
Scott: I'm gonna go look at the small computer vendors like zotac and whatnot and try to see if I can get a htpc, maybe get like a 1070 in there and then I won't need another htpc for like ten years.
Rym: Yep but that's why you know, I chose what case I'm gonna build my new computer in because I poked at all the cases that a And the one that had the most marketing around.
Rym: it happened to also be the easiest to use case.
Scott: I happen to fall for the marketing and then make an excuse as to why I didn't fall for the marketing.
Scott: so I can believe that.
Scott: Continue to believe advertising did not work on me when it totally did
Rym: now because there were others flashy booths But mostly those other pcs like those other cases were either like weird liquid cool bullshit that I don't
Scott: want
Rym: or they were loud or
Scott: They
Rym: were like really
Scott: really heavy.
Scott: you can't judge the loudness on your impacts as you're in this giant loud room Every computer sounds quiet.
Rym: No, I went out and read some reviews.
Rym: I mean what might have helped is that the one vendor we looked at like the one that like that case
Scott: is in the quiet Area,
Rym: yeah they were outside of the expo hall so I could stand next to it in a quiet area and see what it sounded like and It had like big stuff inside of it and it was not that loud.
Rym: Hmm it also had that baffle in the front.
Rym: most of the cases that I looked at don't have the baffling and the baffle according to reviews Definitely decreases the noise substantially.
Scott: Mm-hmm and That's what doesn't matter cuz you're gonna put a 1080 in there and it's gonna go.
Rym: So I'm not gonna get a 1080 yet because I want to.
Scott: oh, I mean you just wait for one day.
Scott: There's no reason to buy anything.
Rym: any other GPU And I sorted basically by reviews and every day 1080 I would buy is sold out out of stock.
Scott: Yeah, you just wait for them to come back in stock and use whatever GP you already have.
Rym: So I did some research.
Rym: there are two quiet 1080s.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: They're real performant just like the other ones.
Rym: You know why they're quiet water cooling water cooling Yeah but the water cooling is built in to the card and it just has the Assembly with the radiators and you stick that in one of the radiator assembly spots in your case.
Rym: But you have to get a modern case.
Rym: Mm-hmm Like this case I got here does not does not support that kind of modern shit.
Scott: Mm-hmm I've been doing my research the I gotta buy this PC real soon because like I said So there's a what is a pump for the liquid cooling on the GPU and you need to plug power into it from your power Supply.
Scott: no
Rym: So basically so it looks like it works the same way as the CPU coolers where instead of a big heat sink fan thing You put you have the nubbin that is on the heat source and there's two tubes coming out of it And those tubes go to a block that has fans and radiators in it.
Rym: It's like a square.
Rym: it looks like two fans stuck to each other and Modern cases have multiple places where you put those like on the top inside or on the back inside.
Rym: So they work as a case fan, but they're pulling the air over that thing Mm-hmm.
Rym: That's pretty much how anyone who isn't crazy does it.
Rym: now.
Rym: if you're crazy then you get a motherboard that supports that and instead of buying like All these like you don't buy like a CPU cooler that has its own fans and then a separate video card cooler to zone fans you buy a cooling rig that will connect to multiple devices with a larger loop and You have the cooling rig and the giant set of radiators but then it's
Scott: a loop.
Scott: wouldn't you be sending like hot liquid from the CPU to the GPU and then to the cooler?
Scott: and that's A bad idea when you want each one individually going to them.
Rym: Well, it's sort of like it's like heat pipes.
Rym: They effectively act like heat pipes, so you're just pushing heat out of the system.
Rym: There's complicated.
Rym: I mean it's got.
Rym: I'm not an expert But that's not a concern.
Scott: Don't you still need a pump?
Scott: and doesn't the pump make noise?
Rym: Oh, yeah, quiet pumps cost so much fucking more than loud ones.
Rym: Oh like it's ridiculous, but basically reading the reviews like if you buy a cheap pump either, you know what you're doing or God help you.
Rym: But the crazy ones like the crazy people and I don't I'm not doing this The motherboard will have two little holes in it on the back and you plug Like you basically plug your pump system into that and it cools the motherboard itself.
Rym: So like all the bridges and all the things that have like, you know Your motherboard is like heat sinks all over it
Scott: and like I mean for something like this I think you're gonna like have to not build your PC and just find someone who put you got a Compatible motherboard case CPU cooler GPU cooler that all work together and put them together for you in advance.
Rym: Well, I've been doing my research and instead of that It seems like the way to go.
Scott: if you can take care all the other parts But it's like the GPU the motherboard the CPU and the case.
Scott: I mean You could put that together for you and then you do everything else to roll your own.
Rym: You have to have.
Rym: you have to put in the remember.
Rym: when we were kids like before we knew shit and we'd like research building a Computer like in high school my computer shopping magazine.
Rym: Yeah, you you would have to do that level of research Like you've been.
Rym: you basically have to spend the amount of time that I spent in high school in college learning about like specific detailed computer component integration shit to build a modern computer.
Rym: roll your own with modern liquid cooling and As an adult, there's no way in fucking hell that I'm gonna do that.
Rym: So the options are either do what you said or buy all the components from the same company and they pretty much just work together Mmm, so like.
Rym: but if you buy a case from like the people I want to buy that case from.
Rym: Only buy the cooling stuff that that company also makes.
Scott: well I'm sure at pecs we could go to say the Cooler Master booth and we could be like up buy those four things that we See assembled right there before us.
Rym: people on the internet seemed to hint that Cooler Master is overpriced and not great.
Scott: I'm sure it isn't but I'm just that's just an example of a brand.
Scott: I'm sure you can go to the new egg booth the Intel booth no highs no lows Just Cooler Master.
Scott: you could go to any of the booths Right of hardware vendors and they will have at least one setup computer That has demonstrating this technology that you could look at and say yeah, I'll buy those four things.
Rym: But I also I poked it overwatch.
Rym: I turned a bunch of settings down to get my frame rate up because I'm actually there's a little bit of a frame rate issue.
Rym: just you know, My computer is pretty old and Yeah, I need a new computer.
Rym: Mm-hmm I really need a new computer because it is PC gaming season because the other thing I'm playing pretty much constantly is Civ 5.
Rym: Now, I know the videos are going up.
Scott: pretty sure you can play Civ 5 on any computer.
Rym: Civ 5 I can play on my laptop.
Rym: But I've been playing a lot of Civ 5 and you guys seem to like the videos are putting up of our games.
Rym: I'm gonna start putting those up a lot faster because we've blown through multiple further games beyond the ones that I've got up on YouTube so far and I kind of want to start one of those up again with Scott.
Rym: So you want to do it?
Rym: No, not really not even not even if we make it with two AI.
Rym: So it's not just like a stupid donut duel on a bullshit math Where I put like one unit between you and the city-state and game over.
Scott: I mean, that's better, but it's still not that exciting Not exciting.
Rym: It's like it's.
Rym: you take one turn of a complicated German board game every day or so.
Rym: Yeah, I mean I've got four.
Scott: I'm not even like reading webcomics lately.
Rym: I've got four GM our games going now.
Rym: They're all like gigantic and it takes maybe ten minutes out of my day every other day or so.
Rym: tops Cuz with eight players like people don't take the turns that fast.
Scott: meh Nah, I'm actually like glad.
Scott: I just you know quit that other game because it's like how much time would I spend on it by Now, I don't know how this is like that episode of Seinfeld where Kramer's like Well, how do you?
Rym: it takes me like two hours to take a shower and just saw Jerry's like, uh You're spending way too much time in the shower and he needs help because he's spending too much time in the shower.
Rym: Was it that situation like how much time do you spend on your turns?
Scott: I look at every city and then gonna move every unit.
Scott: Yeah, so like two minutes tops And look at all that, you know every possible thing that's going on.
Rym: Yeah, so three minutes.
Rym: if you also like look at the crazy deep arcane bullshit and like rearrange great people production and then you know Try enough like different combinations.
Rym: I just take my turn and go I don't redo my turn anymore at all.
Scott: Mmm, you know got to see what's going on.
Rym: The only time I ever redo my turn is if I sometimes you miss click and a guy moves cuz you've meant to click somewhere Else.
Rym: then I redo my turn cuz I'm not going to eat the fact that I moved a cellar to the wrong spot next to a barbarian.
Rym: I'm gonna restart my turn if I do that But I never like.
Rym: I don't like.
Rym: And then oh that didn't work out and do the war again cuz no nobody's got time for that.
Rym: I just play.
Rym: hmm No, you know don't want to play that.
Rym: Danny to two minutes.
Rym: two minutes every other day can't handle it.
Scott: It's also you got to keep sieve like open on your computer.
Rym: You know, it boots in like 30 seconds tops.
Rym: I just hit play and then some pops up.
Rym: then I take my turn and I close it.
Scott: Even though my computer is way faster sieve does not boot quickly.
Rym: how Scott my sieve is on a spinning disk On say to three.
Rym: I've got 12 gigs of RAM.
Rym: Like.
Rym: in fact sieve is not only on a spinning disk.
Rym: It's on my system partition.
Rym: How is my computer faster than yours?
Scott: and if your computer isn't faster than mine, but sieve does not boot up quickly Boots up pretty quick.
Rym: I don't leave sieve running.
Rym: Like sieve boots up quicker than overwatch does Mmm, it's not boot up quickly.
Scott: made them.
Scott: do I have more sieve stuff than you.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I'm playing games that have like eight player like giant nonsense late-game like bullshit going on.
Rym: In fact when I'm in the game It takes a long time for the turn to load.
Rym: now because the game is just so big there's so much stuff Hmm.
Scott: Oh, it sits on the screen.
Scott: That's like Civ 5 logo with all the shit in the background before the main menu comes up for a long time.
Rym: Yeah, are you on an SSD?
Rym: No, no, that's part of it I guess.
Rym: but I mean I'm not on an SSD.
Scott: I install all my steam games on this Spinning disk.
Scott: It's like I colon slash steam.
Rym: I installed overwatch and a couple other games on my third SSD the one that I bought a while ago cuz they were cheap.
Scott: Maybe I'll move it to SSD.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Yeah, that might help.
Rym: Will you play a two player with two AI Civ game again?
Rym: Once it starts raining and is cold again in the winter It's gotta be.
Scott: if I'm in a gaming mood, I'll probably want to play all the games.
Rym: What'll it take to be in a gaming mood again?
Scott: gaming season, which is current I mean, I'm not baking anything either.
Scott: why cuz it's caught out and I'm gonna turn my fucking oven on.
Rym: cuz I got a concern.
Rym: what if you're?
Rym: you're the noble from far away who comes back to play.
Rym: go at the Capitol and Everyone surpassed you.
Scott: so what then?
Rym: it won't be team room and Scott anymore.
Rym: I gotta get a team over someone else to have the guaranteed joint victory or 50/50 shot.
Scott: What have you ever actually teamed up with?
Rym: We got to keep the illusion up that we never team up But really I want one of us to to win because fuck everybody else.
Scott: You've never teamed up with me ever.
Rym: You're the one who attacks me out of nowhere Usually like make sure you don't win.
Rym: Like look the last board game that you and I actually played together of the we were playing Hanza, right?
Rym: Yeah, and what'd you do immediately?
Rym: You use the item to just attack me all over the board and played as fast as possible.
Rym: Who won that game?
Scott: I Don't remember.
Rym: You really don't remember that.
Rym: I won by so much that not everyone even counted up their scores.
Scott: I mean you could be sad even remember.
Scott: We don't remember so I have no idea.
Rym: other people are in that game.
Rym: They'll remember that I won by so much.
Rym: No one counted up their scores.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night.
Rym: the patrons for this episode of GeekNights in order the amount of money That amount is above $5 a month are Ellen Joyce Rebecca Dunn Nicholas Brando Heidi McNichol Amanda douchette James David White Christian coons construction noises my statey.com.
Rym: Sean Hayworth William Eisen rose Jeremy minor Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn Aaron Cerise Michelle Garcia Brian Fisher sailor Vista Devin Goodman Iggy kid Matthew Smith Don Schleich jar Tovish and Joe Shiro.
Rym: Joe star Tyler Eller Sean Yeager Sam Cordery Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan parent or open letter rare Laval Brian Cedroni Rochelle, Monta Finn Eric Silver on bonsai buddy Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: Scott won't play any games anymore.
Rym: We couldn't come up with a show topic.
Rym: I was gonna talk about games we were playing and he's literally not playing and he's not even playing netrunner right now.
Rym: So, uh, Yeah, I'll figure out what to do next Tuesday show on.
Rym: maybe by then he'll play Valhalla or I'll trick him into playing video ball.
Rym: Otherwise, I'll just get the other Scott on the show and we'll talk about overwatch.
Rym: anyway We're still coughing.
Rym: that's kind of slowing down some of the extra audio content.
Rym: I actually had to edit out a lot of coughs while I was doing that other patreon update before with the remastering and the whatever.
Rym: But stay tuned.
Rym: Hopefully we'll be over this thing at some point.
Rym: I will definitely see you guys I assume at PAX West.
Rym: and now I leave you with something kind of weird.
Scott: Thanks for the trip dad.
Rym: be grateful for the opportunity of pleading your case before the assembly.
Rym: What a crazy thing Call the bones connected to the neck bone and the neck bones connected to the head bone.
Rym: now There's connected info.
Rym: youth with its enthusiasm Which rebels against any accepted norm because it must and we sympathize It may wear flowers in its hair bells on its toes but When the common good is threatened when the function of society is endangered Such revolts must cease.
Rym: They are non-productive and must be abolished.
Rym: number 48