Rym: It's Monday, February 8th, 2016.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights Tonight, why Twitter can't make money.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So I finally did it.
Rym: It was one of those shit or get off the pot moments.
Rym: So I purchased two things in the last 12 hours because...
Scott: If something you purchase is worthy of opening, but it must be expensive.
Rym: They're moderately expensive, but they're technology.
Rym: But there's the thing that I've noticed.
Rym: It bothers me when other people do it.
Rym: And I vowed to never do it myself.
Rym: Where you have a complaint.
Rym: Like, I'm doing X and I'm a professional at X. But there's a problem doing X. And yet there is why.
Rym: A piece of technology that will actually fix X. If you're a professional and you need Y to do X because your profession is X. And you don't buy Y and you keep complaining about how annoying it is to do X. You are not actually a professional.
Scott: Usually that's a situation where this problem should have been solved by adding the feature of that accessory to the original thing, right?
Rym: Well, yeah, there's a lot of nuance there.
Rym: Or it might be like, I mean, in the 90s.
Rym: Or even actually not that long ago.
Rym: Want to edit video?
Rym: Well, here are your options.
Scott: It's like saying, man, driving this car sucks.
Scott: I sure wish it had brakes.
Scott: Well, why didn't you buy brakes?
Scott: It's like the car should include brakes.
Rym: Yeah, but what about, say, I want to do chroma keying, but it's 1920.
Scott: That doesn't exist in 1920.
Rym: Well, actually, it kind of did.
Rym: Really?
Rym: Yeah, but it was not done much the same way we do it now.
Rym: But similar things could be done.
Rym: Chemical processes and such.
Rym: I was reading a lot about that stuff.
Scott: I guess you could do something with a completely black background and light only the front things and then run the film through again.
Rym: Yeah, or you could probably do masks and all sorts of stuff.
Rym: That's what I'm saying.
Rym: Yeah, automate a mask by overexposing one part all the way up.
Rym: Then you have the mask and then you can re-expose.
Rym: All sorts of nonsense.
Rym: So anyway, I was editing the antenna videos, you know, the Patreon thing, and a bunch of PAX videos and everything.
Rym: And I keep having to shuttle and jog around the videos.
Rym: And I'm doing what I always do.
Rym: I'm futzing around with the mouse and keyboard and back and forth.
Rym: And it's just not that fun.
Rym: And then I remembered that jog wheels exist.
Scott: What's your mouse sensitivity?
Rym: It's not a matter of that.
Scott: You can set your mouse wheel.
Scott: How many clicks is a click?
Rym: Oh, no, it's not that matter.
Rym: I can click one frame at a time.
Rym: The difference is a nice jog wheel.
Rym: Like at RIT in the labs, we had like editing consoles.
Rym: Imagine like a big fucking wheel with a lot of weight to it.
Rym: You can sort of spin and slide.
Rym: It's really comfortable to use.
Scott: Does your mouse wheel unlock and spin like woosh?
Rym: This one does not.
Rym: I have another mouse that does.
Scott: I feel like you just wanted to waste money on something fancy.
Rym: No, because I remember editing video with a jog wheel and with a shuttle ring around it.
Rym: And it was just a lot faster.
Scott: You're in that much of a hurry.
Rym: Yeah, actually.
Scott: I feel like that isn't something that's so much of a pain that the mouse wheel's no good.
Rym: Well, I got to the point where I have a lot of video to edit that involves a lot of like the Utena stuff, especially now, is mostly me jogging around inside of a bunch of like whole episodes of Utena to find individual frames and like exact
Scott: cut off points.
Scott: I mean, there are definitely specialized tools to make things easier that are useful.
Scott: But I feel like that is a borderline, you know, not necessary.
Rym: You've never really put together...
Scott: Well, it's a borderline garlic press.
Scott: That's all I'm saying.
Rym: You've never put together a complex video.
Rym: Look at the timeline of all these stupid Utena things you'll see.
Rym: But anyway, I thought, hey, maybe, you know, a long time ago I looked for these things and I didn't buy one because they were all thousands of dollars or they were just a mouse.
Rym: Like there was no...
Scott: No, you can buy just a wheel now.
Rym: Yeah, so I went around looking online and most of the wheels...
Scott: I've actually seen some Kickstarted at some points.
Rym: Yeah, and I researched all those and basically what I discovered is that there are a few things that are super good, but they're still expensive.
Rym: There's things that work pretty well, but they're not better enough than just a mouse to justify spending any amount of money on them.
Rym: And then I found one thing that was $80 and it appears that everyone else who edits video, even like professionals, pretty much used that one.
Rym: And I asked around and everyone was like, oh yeah, that one's great.
Rym: So I bought it and it's going to make my editing life a lot easier.
Scott: You're going to have fun playing with a knob.
Scott: At least there's one thing you can say about buying that garlic press, well borderline garlic press, not quite as bad as a garlic press.
Scott: That makes it kind of okay and that is you can play Breakout or Pong with it.
Rym: Yeah, actually, the ulterior motive, I want to see if I can play Kaboom with it.
Scott: You can play Warlords with it.
Rym: I might be able to set it up and then we can add some Atari games to our panel at night.
Scott: Anything with a dual purpose gets, you know, gets a pass.
Rym: But the other thing is I actually finally bought a new phone.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Rym: The Sony Xperia Z5 Compact came out in America with every LTE channel that I care about.
Rym: Legit, like.
Rym: I can buy it for real, not some gray market nonsense.
Rym: I can buy it basically direct from Sony on Amazon or B&H or whatever.
Rym: And I did my last cursory research.
Rym: Apparently Marshmallow came out and they all upgraded just fine.
Scott: But does it have any weird stuff or is it pure unadulterated?
Rym: So I really dug into what Sony does because of course it's weird stuff.
Rym: There's only one line of phones that doesn't have any weird stuff.
Rym: And the Sony stuff is... Well, like Nexus phones.
Rym: Yeah, I looked into also the new small Apple phones and I'm not going to wait for the unicorn to come out because my Nexus 5 is a little hardware compromised.
Rym: I was kind of counting down the minutes before it actually does die.
Rym: And the fact that this thing is waterproof, I've been complaining about how there's no good small phone forever.
Rym: And while this is not a perfect phone, it is literally the best Android hardware on the market in the entire world today, full stop.
Scott: So you bought the least smelly poop?
Rym: Yeah, I bought the best Android hardware.
Scott: So I just buy the gold, Jerry?
Scott: Gold.
Rym: Yeah, so this is an experiment because if it's good, if it works, if my feeling that having a small phone with good hardware is better than the alternative, then I was right all along.
Rym: And if I'm wrong, I can resell it for almost as much as I bought it for and just buy the iPhone 5 SE whatever when it comes out.
Scott: Apple's doing this thing now where you sort of pay for your iPhone every month and you can upgrade your phone every year.
Rym: So just always have the current iPhone.
Scott: You just always have the newest phone and you get Apple Care forever also is like free.
Scott: Instead of paying 100 bucks a year for whatever.
Scott: So if anything happens to it, you're fine.
Rym: So actually the main thing was because it's waterproof, that's increasingly a problem for me.
Rym: Like I kind of need a waterproof phone.
Scott: Well, the iPhone is actually more waterproof than you would expect.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Scott: It's not super waterproof.
Scott: Apple don't advertise that fact, but it's they keep making it more and more waterproof every release.
Rym: Yeah, but they don't get the like certification.
Scott: They're not going to say it's waterproof because they want to fuck you if you get it in the water.
Rym: Well, also they don't want to deal with the edge case of, yeah, it's pretty much waterproof.
Scott: They actually said iPhones are waterproof now.
Scott: People would be dumping that shit in the swimming pool and be like, hi, bro.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So I'm getting my new waterproof phone.
Rym: I'm still not going to throw in the pool.
Rym: I'm still not going to shower with it.
Scott: I'm going to take it in the ocean.
Rym: Actually, it says specifically no salt water.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: There is a fully waterproof version, but I don't need that.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway, but knowing it, especially because my, my nexus five, you know, it's kind of damaged because I dropped it on those rocks in Hong Kong and it works fine, but it has a hole right in the bottom that water could just get in.
Scott: Isn't that where the USB goes in?
Rym: USB goes down here.
Scott: Not on the bottom.
Rym: The front is cracked.
Rym: Like where the screen, cause that's where I hit the rock with it.
Scott: Why are you doing that?
Rym: Because I was running in the mountains and I needed a GPS.
Rym: so I didn't get lost cause I'm in fucking Hong Kong and I had literally, it's like a little island.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So I literally the day before the trip or gotten my new nexus five because my nexus forward finally died and the nexus five for like five bucks a dozen in Hong Kong.
Rym: So the nexus five was just a little bit bigger than the nexus four.
Rym: So it wouldn't fit in the armband that I put on when I ran with it.
Rym: So I had to carry it.
Rym: So yeah, I don't like big phones.
Rym: So this is it.
Rym: Either you're, I'm going to talk about how great it is to have a small phone again or Android is dead.
Rym: You're going to find out in about a week cause the phone arrives tomorrow.
Scott: All right, so I got, I got an open event.
Scott: It's, you know, I don't know if someone's probably gonna give me shit about this, but anyway.
Scott: Ooh, all right.
Scott: I've always given people shit who have pains and I'd be like, I don't have any pains.
Rym: You know, that is true Scott, because many times when you've had a pain or I've had a pain, if I have a pain, I'll just take an aspirin and I'll be fine.
Rym: If you have a pain, you'll bitch about it, but you won't take aspirin.
Rym: You'll just sit there bitching about it.
Scott: Uh, yeah, but I usually don't have pains.
Scott: And I also tell people like, you know, like people got back pains and I'd be like, Hey, I just hunch over.
Scott: I never have any pain.
Scott: Look at you standing up straight hurts all the time.
Scott: You shouldn't stand up straight.
Scott: Just hunch and be comfortable like me.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: That's just because your back's messed up because you've been hunched for so long.
Rym: Right.
Scott: Now suddenly of course the comeuppance that was expected came sooner than expected.
Rym: Back pain?
Scott: My back hurts.
Rym: Upper or lower?
Scott: In a weird, it hurts in one spot, like on the left in the middle.
Rym: Left in the middle, like just south of your shoulder blade?
Scott: Uh, a little, I mean quite a bit south, but not super south.
Rym: Cause you know that every study says that the cure for lower back pain is fuck you.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: There's just not that you're done, but there's nothing you can do about it.
Scott: It's not really lower.
Scott: It's in the middle.
Scott: But yeah, I mean, I know that the, there is no care for back pain.
Rym: Why don't you get some chiropractic homeopathy?
Scott: No, I'm not going to do that.
Scott: Uh, yeah, it hurts.
Rym: All the time?
Rym: Like you go to a doctor?
Scott: Uh, I didn't go, I mean it only started hurting like maybe halfway through two days ago.
Rym: Oh, maybe it's an acute pain.
Rym: Maybe you just like, it still hurts though.
Rym: Moved it a weird way.
Rym: It changes.
Rym: We're humans.
Rym: We're over 30.
Rym: The reality is sometimes you wake up and something just hurts for a few days.
Scott: That's what I'm saying.
Rym: Like I can't tell if I'm hurt because I hurt myself anymore or if I'm hurt because I'm over 30.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know.
Rym: Cause sometimes one day, like a month ago I woke up, my elbow, my right elbow just hurt.
Rym: And I kept hurting for like two weeks and then it just stopped hurting.
Rym: So all I could think was, well, I guess that was pain, like injury and not old.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So anyway, so it started hurting.
Scott: I went to bed, I woke up and hurt more and I said, Oh, why is it still hurt?
Scott: Uh oh.
Scott: So then I took one dose of Tylenol and it made no difference.
Scott: Right.
Rym: I would, I would go, you know, most people use other drugs.
Rym: I actually still use aspirin 90% of the time if I take a pain medicine.
Scott: So then this morning when I got to work, right, it was like, you know, I was moving pretty slow.
Scott: So for the first time my entire life, I went into the closet at the office and I took, instead of acetaminophen, there was also ibuprofen, ibuprofen is my number two, man.
Scott: So I took, I think it said to take one, I took one that also did nothing.
Scott: So, uh, but then I guess I took it at nine in the morning.
Scott: How long does it usually take to work?
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: Like an hour, 40 minutes.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: It definitely didn't work because I was hurting the same amount until like maybe three.
Rym: And then it stopped hurting.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean it didn't stop hurting, but it hurts less now than it did at nine, but it didn't change really at all until three.
Rym: So what was one, the actual dose, how many milligrams did you take?
Scott: It said to take one.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Scott: On the bottom.
Rym: I read the instructions.
Rym: You're using unitless measures.
Rym: One what?
Rym: One ibuprofen.
Scott: One pill from the bottle of generic orange stuff that was in the closet at the office.
Rym: Like how many milligrams?
Rym: Like you want 600 milligrams of grifenicin, but you want like 60 milligrams of pseudo ephedrine.
Scott: I mean, I can go look at it again tomorrow, but I don't really care.
Scott: I took the recommended dosage of one and nothing had, nothing affected my pain until three.
Rym: And it still is definitely uncomfortable, but from what I've read, back pain is one of the things where unless you get dangerous painkillers, they really don't do anything for it.
Scott: That makes sense.
Rym: Other pains like you had a headache, like half a dose of aspirin.
Rym: That thing's gone.
Rym: Unless it's migraine.
Rym: I'm saying if you did, if, if somehow the, uh, the overmanage got a headache, then anyone's got a robot body.
Scott: I mean, I've, you know, I've been waiting one patiently, but you know, the clock's ticking here.
Scott: I need the robot body a little sooner than expected.
Rym: It's just, it's always interesting that you're a very pro robot body yet you won't use existing body technology to make yourself feel better.
Rym: Like if I'm sick, I'll just take whatever drugs fully aware of the side effects.
Rym: because why feel pain?
Rym: Why feel discomfort?
Scott: Here's your problem, right?
Scott: See if you take drugs, I've only got this biological body and odds are it's all I'm going to have.
Scott: It's not, we know what the side effects are of taking some drugs, you're going to fuck up this biological body.
Scott: and then what Scott, how was the aspirin going to get a robot body, right?
Scott: I don't have to worry about fucking up a biological body.
Rym: Scott, have you ever like tried to flash a bios and just shit's broken?
Rym: now you're going to flash your butt bios and your butt's just going to like fall off and have an error code on it.
Scott: I got a robot body.
Scott: It's like you're set.
Scott: You can just go.
Scott: I don't give a shit.
Rym: I'm going to get some butt malware and I guess butt malware is just food poisoning.
Scott: I'll just reinstall my whole OS from scratch just like I do with my computer.
Scott: My computer has a lot less problems than my biological body does.
Rym: My, you know what?
Rym: I was, I was going to say, yeah, I agree with you.
Scott: I can take care of a, of, you know, technological body.
Scott: I can't really do my, even doctors who are specialists.
Rym: You know, if I go to the Scott, the only reason you bring me a broken computer.
Scott: And you bring a broken body to a hospital cannot restore that broken body to perfection, but I can restore that computer to right Scott.
Rym: So here's one up on you.
Rym: I'm going to bring you a computer from 34 fucking years ago.
Rym: Restore that shit.
Scott: I can.
Scott: I got two GS in my closet.
Scott: It works great.
Scott: It's better than your computer.
Scott: works better than your brand new computer.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: It's not going to render any video anytime soon.
Scott: If I spend a little money on eBay, I can make it work so good.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But you know what?
Rym: The other thing is when you take, when you take your computer to the computer doctor, he just pulls out all the shit that's broken and just replaces it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So that's why it's great to have a robot body.
Rym: When I broke that rib at magfest a couple of years ago, no one like, that's why biological bodies suck.
Scott: And I don't want one.
Scott: If you could just, you know, do instant part replacement without any problems,
Rym: but Scott, you know what it's like, you know, when you got a raid and one of the discs dies, so the equivalent of taking some aspirin, like if you could just stop using the drive and just not have access to that data until it rebuilds, or you can let it start rebuilding and keep using the data.
Rym: The danger is minuscule negligible, but you have access to your data.
Rym: So if I got to say a headache, like just headache happens, I could either suffer through it for no reason or take an aspirin to not feel it.
Rym: And as long as I remember that, Hey, Rym, you had a headache, you don't feel it now, but you're basically turned off that error warning.
Rym: You acknowledge that error in the alert console.
Scott: You might fuck up your stomach with that aspirin.
Rym: Uh, well, I don't seem to have that problem.
Rym: That's not, everyone has those problems.
Rym: And if you're going to have that problem, take ibuprofen instead, you just still have that problem.
Rym: Take Tylenol.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, Tylenol is definitely my go-to because I feel like Tylenol causes more systemic damage than either aspirin or ibuprofen causes damage to what the liver, the liver, which in someone who doesn't drink is mad strong liver is ready for beaten.
Scott: My liver is like not done any work ever.
Scott: So it's ready for all kinds of acetaminophen clearing action.
Rym: Liver does way more than deal with alcohol.
Rym: Alcohol is a relatively minor part.
Scott: If I have to compare, right?
Scott: If I'm going to, if I have to go to battle with one of my internal organs and I can send either my stomach, my liver, or if I have to go to battle with an internal
Rym: organ, I'm going for the appendix, gallbladder, something I can just fucking cut out and get rid of.
Scott: Just fire it.
Rym: If you've got a bad ram steak, you just pull it out and you're good to go.
Scott: Maybe my liver is going to win more battles and has more hit points than the others.
Scott: So if I'm going to do some damage, I'll take it in the liver.
Rym: We get what?
Rym: I'll allocate.
Scott: I'll allocate my three right torso damage to the liver.
Rym: Just don't worry about the crit chance.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I'm not going to get a crit chance on the liver.
Scott: My stomach though, might get a crit.
Scott: and then, you know, bad news.
Rym: So I got a tech news, which is one of those funny tech news.
Rym: is it's, it's the classic line of didn't know X existed until Facebook announced they're shutting X down.
Rym: So a bunch of my coworkers were flipping out because they're like, Oh my God, Facebook shut down parse.
Scott: And I was like, well, they didn't shut it down yet.
Scott: They're going to shut it down shutting it down a year from now.
Rym: Uh, Oh, slash that's funny.
Rym: It's for those working in the ass business as a service.
Rym: So parse shut down is going to shut down.
Rym: And so I didn't know what parse was, but the headline told me immediately because what they, what it basically said was Facebook never wanted to host apps to begin with.
Rym: They literally bought it.
Rym: So developers could use the Facebook login full stop.
Rym: They bought it.
Rym: It's one of those situations where a large company like Facebook bought another company's thing to literally get one of its features and fuck all the rest of that nonsense that came along with it.
Scott: So this, so parse was this thing that sort of started to solve like this one small problem and they over engineered it and ended up building what is known as infrastructure as a service.
Scott: So basically let's say you're writing like an iOS app and you know, you need some sort of backend.
Scott: that is not in the app itself.
Scott: Like maybe for example, you're making a video game and you want to store a database of high scores, right?
Scott: And you don't want to use like Apple game center.
Scott: You want to have like your own high score database somewhere.
Scott: Or maybe you want to have your game players like log in and have a friends list and you know, do these sorts of things.
Rym: Now the traditional way to do that was you have hosting in the sky somewhere and you were done and you write an application and you put the, you host the application on some servers and that application probably has a bunch of like component applications.
Rym: Like you write your application, but then you've also got like my SQL running behind it and Apache and a bunch of nonsense.
Scott: You actually build a web service of some kind or an internet service.
Scott: And there's a whole Linux server, an application, you write one and you run it.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But on top of an entire Linux server on a hardware, right?
Rym: And then a little revolution was servers as a service or you know, like an Amazon instance.
Rym: So you run a whole Linux server.
Rym: It's just virtualized.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: You don't have to worry about the actual, what Scott's talking about is way beyond that.
Scott: What parse does is basically you don't have to write an application or run servers or do anything.
Scott: They pretty much just provide a generic web user interface, customizable infrastructure.
Scott: So you can just be like going to make a high score list.
Scott: You just go to parse and be like, well, username, high score, login password, you know, do this, do that.
Scott: And now you can write your game and in the game that you write, you know, while you're writing your iOS code and see see objective C or what's the other thing that they made?
Scott: Uh, you know, that Swift, right, you just, you just include, you know, the parse library and now you can use the parse API to communicate with this infrastructure.
Scott: Now you don't have to build Linux servers.
Scott: You don't have to write an application.
Scott: You can do anything.
Scott: You don't have to set up databases.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: You just, I mean, Amazon has a bunch of this stuff too is your infrastructure.
Rym: Like you can use, you can like, you can run an Amazon instance and run like Postgres on it or you just use Amazon's database.
Rym: There's no server.
Scott: We use parse at work, but actually the only thing we use it for is to send iOS notifications.
Scott: We don't use it for anything else so we can replace it with something else.
Rym: Yeah, there's a lot.
Rym: I think there's a notification thing on Amazon.
Rym: you could actually just use, uh, maybe.
Scott: But you know, there's plenty of alternatives.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But yeah, uh, Facebook shutting it down.
Scott: And I guess, you know, it really bothers me that there's like a market for a lot of these things.
Scott: because on the one hand, you know, this all really started with like the Heroku, which is like, it's one thing to sell hosting, right?
Scott: Cause that's all Amazon is really doing is selling hosting.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, well, except I don't have a data center.
Scott: I want to pay to use computers in your data center and I don't really care what CPUs are in them.
Scott: I just want computers that run.
Rym: But that's not super scalable because then you still have to make your application like deal with multiple servers and all that nonsense.
Rym: You have to monitor that shit, dude.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like a lot of these things, it gets to a point where it's like, it's one thing to pay someone to take care of something for you.
Scott: It's another thing to pay someone to, so that you don't have to know something, right?
Scott: It's like people use Heroku so that they could write a Ruby on rails app without having to know anything about databases or Unix or anything like that.
Scott: And so there is way too much and getting way too little.
Rym: So there is a counterpoint there though, like a lot of the Amazon stuff, like especially use like the elastic beanstalk or like some other like basically spinning up code on the fly.
Rym: So if someone like uploads a video to your web server and then it automatically spins up, however many threads it needs out in the cloud somewhere to do like the transcoding or whatever.
Rym: So that way you can scale automatically and only pay for your load.
Scott: You can also do that no matter what.
Scott: Because spinning up.
Scott: You can just do that with EC2 instances.
Scott: You can say, you know, cloudwatch, if CPU usage on any of these machines gets too high, launch another machine with this AMI.
Rym: Yeah, so that might take.
Scott: Elastic beanstalk just does the same thing.
Scott: Even if you use elastic beanstalk, you still have to know about Unix and computers.
Scott: You're not outsourcing your knowledge.
Rym: Yeah, but you're outsourcing having to scale on a per computer basis, like not outsourcing having to know anything.
Rym: Exactly.
Rym: I've noticed just in my industry, you know, finance, there are companies that use services like all this Amazon nonsense because they realize that it has a scaling or a feature.
Rym: There's something it does that is useful to them, but they know how to do that thing on a server.
Scott: People who use parse for like its full infrastructure as a service.
Scott: People do that because they don't know how to make an infrastructure.
Scott: They don't know how to set up an administrator, a Unix server or write an API or use a database.
Scott: And they just want to make a web, an iOS app or something and not have to know any or.
Rym: Or they use it for a rapid time to market to get a thing that works.
Rym: And if it gets big, they'll deal with replacing that with real infrastructure later.
Rym: Why waste effort if you just want to see if the thing's going to work?
Scott: But this is why you get things like the node JS.
Scott: It's like people learn JavaScript and HTML and CSS, and they don't want to have to know anything else.
Scott: So let's just well, we'd rather do a bunch of work and develop this whole node JS thing so that we can also write JavaScript on the server instead of just learning, because that's even though that's more effort, they don't.
Scott: for some reason, people like against learning, they would rather do a whole bunch of work to use a language they already know in a different way than just learn something new.
Scott: Hey, if someone else does that work, but you're it's basically someone else programming language in the world.
Rym: on the server also, it's a great idea, at least even the people who are node evangelists are like, yeah, don't do any serious processing on that thing.
Rym: And I'm like, so what?
Rym: So you've got a backend and a backend and a front end now, two of which are JavaScript.
Rym: Why?
Rym: Why can't your JavaScript front end talk directly to your job or whatever back?
Scott: Seems like there's so many, you know, all the hotness is now.
Scott: these days aren't new things.
Scott: They're just people reinventing the wheel in different ways so that they don't have to learn the existing ways to do a thing.
Scott: It's like, I don't want to have to learn how to make an API.
Scott: I just want to.
Scott: I'll just use parse.
Scott: I'll pay money to avoid learning.
Rym: Yeah, but that's the thing.
Scott: I'll do a whole bunch of work rewriting, you know, making JavaScript work on a server so I don't have to learn Python or Ruby or C or anything like or go.
Rym: So today, randomly, I was we have like a Matlab thing I'm working on.
Rym: So I wanted to.
Rym: I wanted to make a web server thingy just to kind of try some stuff out because I had some rest interface in the backend.
Rym: So I spun up Flask and that totally just worked immediately.
Rym: And it was pretty cool.
Rym: And I had recently done some node stuff and the comparison between working with the two was stark, to say the least.
Rym: But there is a difference between the people who are doing what you're saying, who use services like this to avoid knowledge versus people who use it because they understand what it offers and have a reason.
Rym: I think the latter is probably more successful, but also more rare.
Scott: I also, you know, even if you have a valid use for parse, like you just want to get something up quick and you're going to replace that part later, like you plan to replace it later anyway.
Scott: I really don't like, you know, on Amazon, we only use things, at least I only use things that can be swapped because they have a standard API.
Scott: For example, if you use Amazon RDS, it's just MySQL or just Postgres.
Scott: You can cancel it and just use a MySQL server and you're good.
Scott: If you use Amazon SES, which is their email service, well, we just talk to it using SMTP so we could replace that with like postfix or sendmail like tomorrow.
Scott: Yeah, but if we were to use Amazon, I don't know what's one of the weird things they have.
Rym: Like Elastic Beanstalk is one of the weirder ones.
Scott: Well, no, you use like Amazon simple queue service.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Scott: You can't just swap that out for RabbitMQ or ZeroMQ because it has its own API, so you'd have to recode a whole bunch of stuff to switch away from that.
Scott: It's not using a standard AMQP interface.
Rym: There's a more fundamental thing, though, is if the company that provides your ass infrastructure, I'm going to start calling it that from now on, is not a company that sells ass.
Rym: Do not trust it with your ass like Amazon.
Scott: Don't trust anyone with your ass.
Rym: Amazon is an infrastructure.
Rym: as a service company like that's like that, like AWS, like that is like that's I consider Amazon just be a hosting provider.
Rym: Yeah, but I but all that, like at least they provide that stuff as a primary business.
Rym: So it's not the worst idea to build a business on top of it.
Rym: But Facebook primarily provides racist uncles.
Rym: So I don't I wouldn't really build my ass infrastructure on top of racist uncles.
Scott: Just don't use, you know, if you're paying for someone to do something for you technologically, it should be something that you can swap out that you pay Linode for a Linux machine while you can just swap it out for your own Linux machine.
Scott: And if you decide not to take that advice, you develop your thing on Parse using the Parse API, you're wholly dependent on Parse's continued existence.
Scott: You can't just swap it out.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: See also people who use unpublished APIs of larger companies.
Rym: Yeah, don't do that or do it and just realize that you literally built your business on top of a, I don't know, collapsing pile of sand and rotten wood.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So, you know, once in a while someone comes out with like a chat bot that's like, whoa, it's the new impressive chat bot.
Scott: Wow.
Scott: And it's slightly more impressive than the previous chat bots and talking about Turing tests and A.I.s and stuff.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then people forget about it.
Scott: It's cute for a few days.
Scott: The end.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Well, apparently in China there is a new chat bot called Shao Ice.
Scott: I can't tell.
Scott: I think it's Shao Ice.
Scott: Anyway, this chat bot, you can just chat it up on a Weibo, which is like, I guess, Twitter or Facebook of China.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And apparently like it's in Chinese.
Scott: You can't you can't talk to it unless, you know, Chinese.
Scott: But this article all about it has a lot of transcripts from it that are in English.
Scott: They translated.
Scott: You can see how amazing it is.
Scott: And, you know, it uses the same sort of like, you know, you know, machine learning that has been all the rage these days.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: This thing, I think, is notable in that it is it is not just one step ahead of the previous chat bot that was exciting, which I guess was Eliza maybe or something.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Well, so there's a side conversation.
Scott: I actually have this chat bot is maybe like five steps ahead of the previous chat bot.
Rym: I have a bunch of articles saved.
Rym: Actually, I want to do a main like a show on this in the future.
Rym: Of the reverse uses of chat bots.
Rym: There are chat bots that are designed to predict what you would say to people so we can respond automatically for you on social media and be indistinguishable from what you would have said anyway.
Rym: That's the real awesome and scary shit about chat bots.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But anyway, this chat bot is, you know, it's just like this person to talk to and is at least five steps ahead of any previous chat bot I've seen.
Scott: So I think developments in this, you know, pass the Turing test area are perhaps accelerating.
Rym: Oh, not just turned.
Rym: I think machine learning had a recent subtle acceleration because Go wasn't solved.
Rym: But there's that A.I.
Rym: that basically no human can beat now.
Rym: Like people were saying that wouldn't happen in our lifetime and it appears that it already happened.
Scott: Well, people are just taking the Google stretch.
Scott: You know, Google recently opened up their what are they held to the name?
Scott: the stupid thing?
Scott: I keep forgetting the name of it.
Rym: Oh, yeah, because I just read the article and we were talking about it the other day.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You know, their machine learning thing that I'll probably remember the name of later in the show.
Rym: I can go find the article on the go thing because I was arguing with someone on YouTube about it.
Scott: Basically, Google's strategy has always been to replace the fact that, like, look, we can't code the logic of a brain.
Scott: Let's just get so much data that it doesn't matter.
Scott: And that's the strategy these days.
Rym: And that's work.
Scott: I mean, look, chess is not just get so much data that we don't have to think of a fancy algorithm because that's too hard to do.
Scott: It's much easier to just get like 10 terabytes of data and do a dumb ass algorithm.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, like, look, chess is not solved yet.
Rym: Humans cannot beat machine learning at chess.
Rym: Full stop.
Rym: That's why you never hear about human versus computer contest anymore.
Rym: Humans cannot win ever.
Rym: Go hit that same point.
Rym: Now, allegedly, like go.
Rym: Humans have nothing to add because humans just can't do it anymore.
Rym: Humans have no more contributions to the world of go.
Rym: Except among other humans.
Scott: I don't know if that's true yet, but it's almost true.
Rym: Well, it's basically that A.I.
Rym: is getting tested now.
Scott: But if you were going to draw a line on the timeline of history and when that became true, we're probably underneath the line somewhere.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So maybe there has been an increase.
Rym: Maybe I should start checking on like the current state of machine learning.
Scott: So there was actually Google put up a free machine learning course and I went and I watched like the first YouTube video.
Scott: And that is definitely not a course that I think they lied about.
Scott: the prerequisite knowledge that was required because the guy basically asked you a question and he didn't.
Scott: It's one of those teachers that I hate, like my 10th grade chemistry teacher who asked the question before teaching you anything.
Scott: They asked the question and then they answer it afterwards.
Scott: And it's like, fuck you, teach me.
Scott: And then ask me dumbass.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: it's like, what's one plus one?
Scott: You're like, what the hell is plus?
Scott: And then afterwards, like it's two.
Scott: This is what plus is.
Scott: And it's like, go fuck yourself.
Scott: I can't sit through this.
Scott: Teach me what plus is, you know, show me one plus one, then ask me two plus three.
Rym: That's how you teach.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Well, maybe I couldn't learn machine learning from that machine learning course.
Rym: There's something ironic in there somewhere.
Scott: I had to.
Scott: I have to find another source of learning machine.
Rym: So actually talking about learning, this is a total tangent.
Rym: But there's a bunch of research kind of recently, you know, the idea that different humans have different styles of learning.
Rym: that might be all bullshit.
Rym: There might be like objectively superior ways for people to learn.
Rym: And people who learn by other methods are just worse at learning overall.
Rym: And people who like some like if you have someone who's good at learning and someone who's bad at learning, the person who's bad at learning might do a little bit better with an alternative method.
Rym: But the person who's good at learning will do objectively worse, like far worse with that same alternative method.
Rym: And there's a whole bunch of studying recently around how humans learn.
Rym: There might be some objective truths.
Scott: I think it pretty much just comes down to do you want to learn?
Scott: If you want to learn, you're going to want to learn.
Rym: No, actually.
Scott: So you're saying that people can learn really well.
Scott: who don't want to?
Rym: No, there are people who want to learn but can't.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: That's and that's the most probably the most tragic thing in the world.
Scott: But I think if you don't want to learn, you ain't going to learn no matter what method.
Rym: Human learning is probably just some complex and fuzzy machine learning.
Scott: So you just you get enough data.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I mean, we're just like fuzzy logic nonsense machines.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So I found this video and then I realized it was APIC guy.
Rym: We featured his some of his stuff in the past.
Scott: I wanted to use a few of his videos for things of the day, but I don't want to use the same guy so much.
Rym: Exactly.
Rym: Especially because a lot of the ones that of his that are my favorite.
Rym: Well, anyway, this video actually kind of stood out.
Rym: He took one of those like crapo APC like backups with like the lead acid battery, like, you know, here's your UPS to keep your computer going for like five minutes after the power goes out.
Rym: And he drills it apart and talks about how to make it a hundred times better and how poorly made these things are.
Rym: And it teaches you a lot like if you are young and you might go into IT and you might need to know about like these, like in data centers, like why DC power and power buses and like AC and all like that world and why it actually matters to know about that stuff.
Rym: This video will pretty much summarize everything you need to know in that regard about why maybe we don't actually want AC power within our data centers.
Rym: I mean, pretty much anything modern runs on DC power.
Rym: It's just DC power is hard to distribute.
Rym: AC power is kind of shitty at moving anything other than like a heater or a motor that spins.
Scott: I mean, usually in a data center at the you know, on each rack, you've got, you know, an AC to DC converter and all the computers take DC.
Scott: Right.
Rym: No, usually you've still got.
Scott: you have little power supplies in each rack.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: You have a PDU that distributes the AC power to all the power supplies that are done suboptimal.
Scott: So it is and even Google and Facebook and the really big data centers doing it that way too.
Rym: So some data centers will use direct DC power, but it is such a fucking pain in the ass to deal with that stuff.
Rym: Oh, it's almost.
Rym: it ends up being cheaper for a lot of people to deal with all the problems of AC.
Scott: But I feel like so many power supplies is like so many more points of failure.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Welcome to the world of data center management.
Rym: You want to learn the whys of this?
Rym: Go to college for like five years anyway.
Rym: So this video is fascinating if you don't know about this stuff.
Rym: And even if you do know about it, like a lot of a lot of people think if they have like a UPS that the computer is running off the battery and the battery is just constantly being charged.
Rym: That is not how most shit tier UPS is work.
Scott: No, the battery just sits around.
Rym: But the way this guy modded this one, it does work that way now.
Rym: And it's way better.
Scott: Wouldn't the battery, though, like lose its life?
Rym: It's lead acid batteries.
Rym: They don't lose their life ever.
Rym: Really invincible.
Scott: A lead acid battery can just keep getting recharged and used forever.
Rym: Why do you think your car battery lasts forever unless you break it or something?
Scott: Car batteries don't last forever.
Rym: They last for long.
Rym: God damn.
Rym: They last longer than any lithium ion battery you're ever going to see.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: Anyway, this video is great.
Scott: So way back in the day, like the 80s, there were these computer learn how to, you know, these computer learning books.
Scott: And maybe you've recognized them.
Scott: If you see the cover, they are published by U.S.
Scott: Usborne Children's Books.
Scott: They had books such as Machine Code for Beginners, Computer Programming.
Scott: They also had books that had like listings like here's a program in basic type this into your, you know, ZX Spectrum, and then it'll run and you'll be able to play an adventure game.
Rym: I used to get magazines.
Rym: A lot of magazines had like basic programs in them.
Rym: So I didn't have a computer.
Rym: So I was always desperate to be able to type them into something.
Scott: So Usborne has two modern computer books to teach kids about computers.
Scott: Those books are Code for Beginners Using Scratch, which is this really cool MIT sort of learning computer language thing.
Scott: It's kind of fun.
Scott: And another book called Lift the Flap Computers and Coding.
Scott: But all them old books from the 80s, they have them on their website.
Scott: You just click and you see them.
Scott: They're just there.
Scott: They have a copyright notice.
Scott: And the way the copyright licenses is that they own the copyright.
Scott: It's not Creative Commons.
Scott: You can't redistribute these PDFs on your own.
Scott: But as long as you come to their website and click, you can get a PDF and use it all you want for yourself.
Rym: I kind of want to go there and copy paste some old basic programs into it.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: if you copy paste out of a PDF into a, you know, I could do it old school.
Rym: I could do it old school and literally just type the code in.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, come and take my Apple 2GS and we'll type the code in.
Rym: Maybe we should.
Rym: That'd be there.
Rym: Let's let's we should make a Let's Play video where we do that.
Scott: The problem with my Apple 2GS is not that it's broken in any way, is that I only have five and a quarter inch floppy drives and five and a quarter inch floppies.
Scott: You can get a three and a half inch floppy drive for it and use three and a half inch floppies.
Scott: I do not have those and they are not the price they are on.
Scott: eBay is not really worth it to me.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: We'd get like a few weeks worth of entertainment that we'd probably not use it ever again.
Scott: And the best method of getting software into one of those is a method I have available, which is I plug USB cable into my computer, then I have a little converter and then it turns into a modem cable.
Scott: And then I go to the Apple 2 and I say, hey, Apple 2, you're getting a phone call, take all the data you're getting from the phone call and run it.
Scott: And then on my computer, I say, hey, computer, see this file I downloaded from the Internet that contains Apple 2 software, send it over the USB cable ATAT.
Scott: I also have another method, which is where I download a file of Apple 2 software and I turn it into a WAV file because, you know, a lot of them were just on cassette tapes or whatever.
Scott: You know, modem is just audio, too, right?
Scott: Doesn't matter.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And then I take a headphone cable from my iPhone and I plug it into the in the microphone hole on the Apple 2 and I press play on the wave file and turn the volume all the way up.
Rym: I still have.
Rym: well, I don't have many more.
Rym: My mom probably has them.
Rym: I have cassette tapes that have programs.
Scott: I can even do it by opening Safari on my iPhone and typing in a URL of a WAV file and pressing play and download something from the Internet over the Wi-Fi directly into my Apple 2.
Rym: So in the moment we were just at Pac South, three panels.
Rym: I have video of four panels.
Rym: One of them is already on YouTube.
Rym: I was scared yet.
Rym: A discussion of horror and games with Chris Straub, Dave Allen from Penny Arcade, Alex Stacey from Loading Ready Run and Alana Pierce from IGN or Peace, I think she said.
Rym: But the rest of the videos from Pac South, other than this one, will not be up until I upload the antenna episode 14, which I am editing fiercely as fast as I can with your with your knob.
Rym: The knob is going to come tomorrow.
Rym: Oh, my God.
Rym: I might just video myself using the knob.
Rym: I'm kind of excited about the knob.
Rym: Rym loves fiddling knob.
Rym: I really should have bought that knob before, but the knob used to be way expensive.
Rym: It's actually.
Rym: So get this.
Rym: The knob was cheaper.
Scott: How long is he going on about his knob?
Rym: I'm going to go talk about it.
Rym: once I get the knob, I can do a let's play of me using the knob.
Rym: So much because remember, we have a Patreon and we have a goal.
Rym: And if we hit that goal, you're going to get a bunch of videos of how I do GeekNights.
Rym: Like here's a video of me editing like the Utena video, more money than you.
Rym: Don't give him so much video of me playing with my knob.
Rym: You're not going to be able to deal with it.
Scott: You don't want that.
Scott: Don't give him your money if you're already giving your money.
Scott: Stop.
Rym: I got a very tender.
Scott: make much better use of that money.
Rym: I just got a very tender thank you.
Rym: That was addressed to both of us in the Patreon campaign.
Scott: Don't do that.
Rym: I'm someone who is very happy about GeekNights.
Scott: No, don't.
Rym: Very, very proud to be contributing to our cause.
Scott: That person has a problem with priorities in life.
Rym: Otherwise, we're going to be a MAGFest like next weekend.
Rym: Like that's coming up real quick.
Rym: I mean, yeah, yeah.
Scott: Two weekends from next weekend.
Rym: Not this weekend where we have nothing but next weekend.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: We're going to be on between the two of us, like seven goddamn panels.
Scott: I don't know which ones I'm on.
Rym: I don't remember which ones I'm on.
Scott: Can you make an itinerary for me?
Rym: I'm going to show up and I'm going to go to the staff room and I'm going to.
Rym: I'll just be like, John St.
Rym: John, let's wander in kind of drunk and be like, so where do I have to be?
Scott: Yeah, I need an itinerary.
Rym: Point me at the room and I'll show up.
Scott: I need someone to give me an itinerary because I don't know.
Rym: At least we're doing the same panels that we did at PAX.
Rym: I said the Atari one.
Rym: We can just totally change it up because it's just the Atari one.
Rym: We can do whatever.
Rym: So I think we'll change some games.
Rym: If my knob works, we're going to talk about some kaboom.
Scott: You're going to bring your knob to magfest.
Rym: I'm bringing my knob to magfest if it works for kaboom.
Rym: OK, we'll see if it works for kaboom.
Rym: So you might have noticed me bitching on Twitter, which is kind of ironic.
Rym: And the whole I mean, rest in peace, Twitter was trending globally for a while.
Rym: But basically a while ago, as you all know, Twitter added that lightning bolt that you click on by accident sometimes.
Rym: And it has a bunch of ads and nonsense in there.
Rym: And Twitter has been hinting for a while that they're going to get rid of the chronological timeline.
Scott: Haven't we talked about this before?
Rym: I think I've bitched about it, but we've never really talked about this a hundred times.
Scott: I don't really understand why it has to be a main bit.
Rym: I don't think.
Rym: Do you have a better one?
Scott: No, but all right.
Rym: There we go.
Rym: Put up.
Scott: I still feel like it's a rerun bleh.
Rym: If you hand me something better, I will gladly take it.
Scott: I can just go home.
Scott: That'd be better.
Rym: So this issue is interesting for one reason to me.
Rym: And that reason is it's coming out of a fundamental problem that I think a lot of tech companies or at least companies that use technology in a very like social media open format are going to run into increasingly where the investors or the people with stock want their money back.
Scott: Well, this is why.
Scott: So, you know, I hate Silicon Valley bullshit, right?
Scott: But it seems to be the way to make a company these days.
Scott: You know, the way to make a company in the 90s was you made a company and then you IPO to get money.
Scott: And if you have your money comes from an IPO, they expect you to be profitable.
Scott: And you know what?
Scott: Those companies weren't.
Scott: So when they went under, it caused a big old crash.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Nowadays, the way to do things is, oh, we'll just instead of IPO, we'll get VCs to fund us.
Scott: And then the VCs like buying lottery tickets and they know it and they don't give a shit for whatever reason.
Scott: But you don't have to make any fucking money.
Scott: The VCs just want you to become like big and popular so that you have a better chance of like getting bought so that their investment pays out.
Scott: And then if whoever bought you, well, fuck them.
Scott: I don't care.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And now it doesn't ruin like the whole market because you're not even on the market.
Scott: But companies like Twitter, they eventually IPO or something.
Scott: And then, oh, we actually have to make money now.
Scott: We actually need a real business like none of these tech companies are real businesses that make any money or do anything valuable.
Rym: Qualify that by the fact that Twitter makes one and a half billion dollars a year.
Rym: And apparently that's not enough.
Scott: It must cost a lot to have all those computers.
Rym: Yeah, because all those employees ask you everywhere.
Scott: Also, it's just that even when you become a public company, they expect your profits to keep increasing.
Scott: So even if you do manage to profit, you know, from some mechanism, they expect you to go more and more and more and more.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Like look at GoPro.
Scott: GoPro went public and the stock went because it's like, whoa, this is clearly a really popular fucking thing, right?
Scott: Everyone's buying these GoPro cameras everywhere.
Rym: Counterpoint.
Scott: And again, while I am up and GoPro still profits, they sell plenty of cameras, but they're not doing any better than they used to.
Scott: So the stock went down.
Rym: So a lot of people make the mistake.
Rym: And again, I am not giving investment advice.
Rym: Just got to make that clear on GeekNights.
Scott: You will never hear legal or investment advice.
Rym: Ever, ever.
Scott: But unless a lawyer or investment professional comes on and says otherwise, but you won't hear it from us.
Rym: When a company like GoPro that's been around and you think, wow, that company is really doing well when they IPO whatever price the stock is.
Rym: When it IPOs, it takes that into account.
Rym: It's got to do better than that from that GoPro.
Scott: I think IPO at something like 20 or 30 or something went up to like 90 at one point.
Scott: And now it's like 15.
Rym: And I never bought GoPro stock because I'm not stupid.
Rym: I would have I would have invested in GoPro if I could have in the early days.
Rym: Chipotle, right?
Rym: Chipotle was like, do you see they closed all the stores for like a norovirus meeting?
Scott: Yeah, whatever.
Scott: It's like, you know, it went up like crazy big.
Scott: And then now that it's like, oh, well, not only is the whole market down in general, but, you know, you know, no one's coming to our stores because we poisoned our customers.
Rym: So, again, I'm not a lawyer and I'm not giving any advice or I'm not making any predictions or anything.
Rym: But the reason Chipotle is down isn't really because of the norovirus thing, nor is it because of the food poisoning thing.
Rym: It's probably because Chipotle's growth is unsustainable due to the fact that minimum wage and things like that.
Rym: All right.
Scott: But that's the point I was told started.
Scott: this whole tangent of these other companies is that Chipotle makes money.
Scott: They're very profitable.
Scott: They're just not making more profits than they used to.
Scott: So even if Twitter profits, even if they make one and a half billion, if they're on the IPO, which is the big mistakes.
Scott: And now once you IPO, you're expected to keep making more profit all the time.
Scott: And if you make less profit or the same profit, that's not good.
Scott: So you constantly, even if you have a successful, sustainable product like Twitter, they have to find a way to make more money.
Scott: So they're going to fuck with it and they're going to keep fucking with it as long as they're a public company forever.
Scott: They're going to say because they have to do if you don't do anything, you obviously can't increase profits.
Scott: You have to fuck with something.
Rym: Now, there is another way to go.
Rym: Like some companies just pay dividends out of the stock and then people are happy with that.
Rym: I got some stocks, but you have to keep.
Scott: you can't even if you have to keep making money.
Rym: You don't have to make money.
Scott: You have to keep doing something.
Scott: you have to keep making money, like even if GoPro was giving up big dividends and kept having solid sales.
Scott: They still have to make a GoPro five, a GoPro six, a GoPro seven.
Scott: You know, they had to keep doing something.
Rym: Well, they have to keep selling things or doing something that generates money.
Scott: They can't.
Scott: But they can't just stay still and do that.
Scott: Sell the one camera for all eternity.
Rym: Well, maybe you could.
Rym: Depends how good that camera was to be some fucking amazing camera.
Scott: Yeah, of course.
Rym: Even then, it'd be too amazing.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: You can firmware flash this camera and it gets more megapixels.
Rym: Yeah, it turns out the iPhone one is the same as the iPhone seven.
Rym: You just it's just and it was all just padding inside of that.
Rym: But the problem with Twitter specifically is that I don't think anyone ever had any idea how they were going to make money off of it ever.
Scott: Well, Twitter was one of those accident companies like Flickr where they were originally making something else and they made Twitter by accident off a side project and then it became more successful than the thing they were actually doing.
Rym: I mean, I didn't even adopt Twitter super early.
Rym: I adopted it relatively early, though.
Scott: Yeah, relatively.
Scott: But you know, when I was in Costa Rica, pretty much like a few weeks where it's like Twitter.
Scott: Oh, that's some fad thing.
Scott: And then a few weeks later, it's like, oh, things still around.
Rym: I. Yeah, but now they need to make money.
Rym: And I feel like no one in the company actually, at least the people who make the decisions, like the business people, I don't think any of them use Twitter.
Rym: I don't think any of them like have any idea what Twitter actually is.
Scott: No.
Scott: And remember, Twitter's different things to different people.
Scott: That's part of the problem.
Rym: Yeah, but I feel like what they want Twitter to be is a push feed of ads and celebrity nonsense at subscribers who consume it and they make money off of the people paying to push that feed.
Rym: Right.
Scott: Well, when you have a company, right, you know, you usually what you want to do when you have a company and make more money is listen to your customers.
Scott: And customers are the people who give you money.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So if you're Twitter, the people who are tweeting and reading tweets are not your customers.
Scott: The customers are the people who are giving you money.
Rym: So who's giving you money right now?
Scott: People are buying your data and people are buying ads or the people who gave you money a long time ago when Twitter makes decisions.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They are really changing Twitter to serve the interests of those people.
Scott: And the only thing they care about in terms of the people use Twitter, the users who are not the customers, is will we change something to make so many of them leave that it will actually make the customers upset?
Scott: Right.
Scott: So it's like they don't actually give a shit if they piss off the users and they like.
Scott: they redesign Twitter.
Scott: And there was a rabble and now the rabble is gone and everyone still uses Twitter.
Rym: Well, because they didn't actually do it at the time.
Scott: You can go listen to GeekNights from then.
Scott: We definitely talked about this.
Scott: People are just complaining because they hate change.
Scott: But this isn't really a change.
Scott: Just like bullshit, you know, whatever.
Scott: I think it actually looks better now.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: No one cares.
Rym: But what they're talking about today, like the recent thing, like it's fundamentally different from when like, oh, Facebook moved a button and now you're all freaking out.
Rym: Right.
Rym: This is more like Facebook became Myspace.
Rym: Like they literally changed what it is that it's like if you change in the skin of a game versus changing the mechanics of the game.
Rym: And well, the other kind of side problem is that with a lot of products, like, for example, TV or especially advertising, the customers actually want like their target demographic, like the people they want to target that they're paying to target.
Rym: They actually kind of want dumb people, like they kind of want people who aren't that discerning.
Rym: And the like there is.
Rym: so there's a situation where you'll have a person who uses your service, but the customers don't care about that person like me personally.
Rym: I don't see Twitter ads.
Rym: I don't interact with Twitter ads.
Rym: Ads don't work on me.
Rym: So I'm just costing Twitter money.
Scott: Like every time I look at you're getting a free service, you're basically getting this communication platform and you're not paying anything for it.
Rym: Every time I search Twitter, I'm just costing them a little tiny bit of money.
Scott: You have to execute a search.
Scott: Their network bandwidth has to send you some data, you know, and you don't pay them jack shit.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Now you might say, oh, but you're providing them content that will make more people use Twitter.
Rym: Yeah, I'm providing content for one thousand one hundred and twenty seven people.
Rym: Twitter doesn't give a shit about the people who use Twitter because I'm on here entertaining them a thousand people.
Rym: That's less than the number of people in the panel room.
Scott: If Rym quit Twitter, their profits would go up by the amount of resources that Rym uses a number of people a lot because he's like a Twitter addict.
Scott: So you'd be like a number of people might even add up to like a dollar or two a year in terms of just electricity.
Rym: If I quit using Twitter, a number of people greater than zero, but statistically less than one would quit using Twitter.
Rym: So I don't matter at all.
Rym: But I feel like my use case of Twitter is the only actually interesting thing Twitter does.
Scott: Yes, you're the only.
Scott: no one else using the same thing in a different way has any validity.
Scott: Only the way I use it is valid.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, obviously that's a real way you use Twitter.
Scott: that is different from the way I use it is not OK.
Scott: Only the way I use it is good.
Rym: I guess my question for you is, what do you use Twitter for?
Scott: I use it for the same thing you use it for.
Rym: So is there any way to make money off of you on Twitter?
Scott: Yes.
Rym: All right.
Rym: How would you if you were Twitter and you want to make money off of Scott's, how would you do it?
Scott: Charge me for Twitter.
Rym: Yeah, I'd pay for Twitter because then I'd be the customer.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: If I'm the customer, it'll do whatever.
Rym: I mean, we both use Twitter because it's a public chat room of all of our friends.
Rym: And it's also a public chat room where there's another public.
Rym: There's a bunch of other public chat rooms nearby and I can kind of listen to all of them.
Rym: So like there's people that don't know me, but I know who they are.
Scott: Twitter isn't perfect.
Scott: It could be better, but it's just all the people that I want to be are on there.
Scott: So and it'd be hard to get all the people that I want to move to something else.
Scott: So even though Twitter, I could probably make a better Twitter on my own.
Scott: A, I couldn't handle that many users without spending a lot of money or without using ass.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Even then, I still have to pay for the ass.
Rym: Yeah, you'd have to pay for the ass.
Scott: Ass is more expensive than, you know, make your own ass.
Scott: Depends.
Scott: And all those people I want to be on there wouldn't come over and abandon Twitter for it.
Scott: So that's really the value of Twitter is, you know, for me is I want to be chatting with those people that I follow and the people that follow me who want to hear from me.
Scott: I want them to hear from me when I have something to say.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But I feel like Twitter, I mean, the ways they've tried to monetize are analyzing and or selling their data, which sure.
Rym: Sure.
Scott: Go ahead.
Scott: Whatever you can.
Rym: I don't really care.
Scott: I mean, that's how you want to collect data about my YouTube video.
Scott: I retweeted.
Scott: Go nuts.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I mean, I pay for YouTube with the data that they get from my videos and the people who pay for red.
Scott: I pay for YouTube directly with YouTube Red.
Rym: Yeah, I don't.
Rym: So anytime you like, if you watch our panel video even once, I get a tiny amount of money.
Scott: Well, how long do you have to watch it for?
Rym: I have no idea.
Scott: I watched it for one second to make sure it works.
Rym: So I actually was looking at the stats.
Rym: The money that the GeekNights' Rym YouTube channel gets is about 50/50 between people who see ads and people who pay for YouTube Red and watch the videos.
Scott: I'd be really curious how many total people out of all YouTube users pay for red and how many.
Rym: But also last month I got about 12 bucks from people who pay for YouTube Red.
Scott: I think the YouTube Red numbers are way lower than the non YouTube Red numbers, but I want to see the YouTube Red hours per person average.
Rym: Oh, I think the YouTube Red people watch a fuck ton of YouTube.
Scott: That's what I'm saying.
Scott: I want to also see like YouTube Red total hours versus non YouTube Red total hours.
Scott: Right.
Scott: There'll be some interesting information there.
Scott: I want to know.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: YouTube Red is.
Rym: YouTube Red is like the perfect example of how to monetize something effective.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Give me Twitter blue.
Scott: I'll pay for it as long as I get awesome stuff like no ads.
Rym: And you know what?
Rym: I pay what?
Rym: Twelve bucks a year for Flickr.
Rym: I'd pay twelve bucks a year for Twitter.
Scott: I pay twenty four.
Scott: I used Twitter made them way more than Flickr.
Rym: Yeah, I might even pay them like a small amount per month, like a couple bucks a month.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Now, the thing is, we we talked about this because someone, you know, a while ago when I found this quote from some advertising guy or whatever.
Scott: But if we when you pay to make ads go away, you're identifying yourself as person with money, which makes advertisers want to pay more to see you.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So then if we pay for Twitter with no ads, someone's going to offer that they're going to turn around and be like, right.
Scott: Like, oh, my God, if we could show an ad only to the people who pay for Twitter blue, I would pay you like a zillion dollars.
Scott: And Twitter be like, oh, OK.
Scott: And then it's like, I'll pay even more money to make them not see this ad.
Scott: Right.
Rym: And it's like, OK, because and even though, you know, a lot some of you work in advertising and you occasionally disagree with me on Twitter and one, fuck you.
Rym: But to the fundamental idea of advertising is that you are paying to force other people to watch something they don't want to see if they want to see it.
Rym: You're not advertising.
Rym: It's research.
Scott: You're paying it to basically like steal someone's a part of someone's life, you know, infest what one or more of their five senses with, you know, sensory inputs that you want to put there that they don't want to put there.
Rym: Because if I want to find out what movies are coming, I might go to a movie and see the trailers because I chose to walk into that room and watch them.
Rym: Or I might ignore the trailers and like come into after the trailers start.
Scott: It's like you are paying to force me to hear something I don't want to hear, see something I don't want to see.
Scott: It's like torture that you bought.
Scott: Yeah, you like someone has a torture device and you rented it from them and chose the the means of torture.
Rym: It's also very telling that 90 percent of the torture that is inflicted upon me is car ads.
Rym: Guess who's never going to fucking buy a car?
Scott: Actually, if I do buy a car and I'd like a Ferrari or some shit and they don't advertise.
Rym: Yeah, or I'm going to either that or I'm going to buy the cheapest possible car because I don't care.
Scott: Or I'll be.
Scott: I'm only going to buy a car from so rich that I can afford like the car and a garage to put it actually and whatnot.
Rym: Funnily enough, I am thinking about buying a car.
Scott: Can you afford a garage?
Rym: So because Zipcar got so expensive, I was actually looking into this.
Rym: And if you and I split a lease on a car and paid for parking, there is a parking spot available at my building to 150 a month.
Rym: So if we if we if we if we are parking for less than 200 a month, it'd be 150 a month at my apartment and a perpetual lease.
Rym: We just like get a new car every couple of years.
Rym: You pay like 200 a month for the lease, which those is 350 a month plus taxes divided by twos.
Scott: Like 200 a month.
Scott: I'm not paying that.
Rym: So 200 a month would be cheaper than for 200 a month.
Scott: I could upgrade my Internet speed to like a zillion megabits and get cable TV that I wouldn't watch.
Rym: It would be cheaper than all the combined rental cars.
Rym: And when we take buses or Amtrak to places that we could more easily drive to combine per year.
Scott: I'm not paying twenty four hundred dollars a year for something I'm hardly going to use.
Rym: Yeah, you're not going to go to Wildwood.
Rym: But not paying $200 a month to go to Wildwood once a year, because I'm going to because if I rent a car to go to Wildwood, I'm charging you for that shit now.
Scott: Sure.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So you rent the car.
Scott: even if the rent a car costs.
Scott: What is it costing?
Scott: Twenty one hundred dollars.
Rym: It'll cost.
Rym: it'll cost like three hundred bucks to get it for the weekend.
Rym: Great.
Scott: That's fine.
Scott: That's three hundred bucks a year, not twenty four hundred a year.
Scott: And I got the same amount of transportation.
Rym: What if we go to Wildwood twice?
Scott: Fine.
Scott: Six hundred.
Scott: We had to go to Wildwood four times for it to be.
Rym: Or we go to Wildwood twice.
Rym: We go we use that car to go to like go to a party and then Albany party and suddenly it's breakeven.
Scott: It had to be like at least once a month.
Rym: So, Scott, here's the magic.
Scott: If we get one, then you're not counting the cost of the gas and the maintenance and the pain in the ass parts and shoveling.
Rym: If you rent cars, you got to pay for that shit anyway.
Scott: Shoveling the snow.
Scott: You don't shovel snow for rent a car.
Rym: No, you don't.
Rym: I could probably use TaskRabbit and pay for someone to come and do it.
Rym: Got to pick.
Scott: how much does that cost?
Rym: Like five bucks.
Rym: Actually, I looked at that because there was someone.
Rym: you could for five bucks, they would come and get all the snow off your car.
Rym: They wouldn't shovel it, but they get all the snow off.
Scott: I need you to dig my car out completely as if it was a rent a car.
Rym: I think that'd be like fifteen or twenty bucks.
Scott: Yeah, well, now I might as well get the rent a car.
Rym: So there's going to be indoor parking for one hundred and twenty five right there when that building finishes.
Scott: One what?
Scott: One twenty five.
Scott: Well, mine is outdoor parking for one fifty.
Rym: Yeah, because it's gonna be a whole parking garage in there.
Rym: But you got to live in one of these buildings to get access to it.
Scott: Oh, I do.
Scott: Oh, you can live in this building and by parking in this is all one complex, even that building that's right there.
Rym: The all the yellow buildings are one big complex.
Rym: Oh, OK.
Rym: But Scott, here's the magic.
Rym: If we get one more person in on this car, OK, if we divide it one more way, like Chase, then it's like one twenty five a month.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Then suddenly it gets good.
Scott: I would pay one hundred a month if I could have a car, maybe one hundred.
Scott: That's like a borderline anyway.
Scott: But yeah, that's Twitter much.
Rym: But so Twitter started selling ads and I started just flagging every ad I see.
Rym: if I use the main because I don't use any of the people keep telling me, oh, use this weird Twitter client.
Scott: I use TweetDeck in Chrome on the PC, which has no ads.
Scott: But when I'm on the iPhone, I use the regular Twitter client, which has ads.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And I use TweetDeck because I'm like setting up all my scheduled tweets and like all my nonsense.
Rym: But I just go to the Twitter website at work.
Rym: Like I'm not going to use TweetDeck at work.
Rym: No, I just use the Twitter website because it's fine.
Rym: I actually see so few ads because every time I do see an ad, I flag it as offensive and Twitter won't show it to me again.
Rym: So what I found is if you keep flagging every ad you see is offensive, eventually you start seeing like the weird ads.
Rym: I started seeing a bunch of ads for like cults like Scientology.
Rym: I started seeing like Mormon ads.
Rym: I started seeing like a lot of weird like like not like homeopathy, but Mormons bought ads and the playbills for Book of Mormon.
Scott: I like that.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: Plus one to Mormons for having a sense of humor.
Rym: That's actually also probably not the worst idea compared to other cults.
Scott: The Mormons, they kill you with niceness.
Rym: Yeah, I'll take the Mormons over Scientology any day.
Rym: But then I started seeing ads for like furry, like cosplay nonsense.
Scott: Stop retweeting furry cosplay nonsense.
Rym: No.
Rym: So a bunch of other people were talking about this.
Rym: You see this and also anime.
Scott: I've been seeing some Twitter ads related to the things I tweeted.
Rym: I saw the most ads for specifically cosplay lenses to stick in your eyes.
Rym: I haven't seen any of those.
Rym: I saw nothing but ads.
Scott: How many cosplay people are you following?
Scott: Because I'm following one.
Rym: Uh, one.
Rym: Probably the same person you're following.
Rym: So when I started playing those as offensive, I never saw any cosplay or furry nonsense again ever.
Rym: As soon as I flagged one like lens in your eyes, like fake contact lens to make your eyes look like something as if you make a little thing that automatically like keeps flagging Twitter ads as offensive all the time until eventually all the ads are offensive.
Rym: So actually I haven't seen any Twitter ads for a couple of months now.
Rym: So I think I did it.
Rym: Whoa.
Rym: I think I flagged everything.
Scott: Maybe you got to show me how to flag as offensive.
Rym: If you, if you just go to the website and you see it easy on the website, just click on the, how do you do it in the app?
Rym: Uh, I don't know.
Rym: I don't see him in the app anymore.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So I only do it on the website.
Rym: I just click on the X and it's like tweet was offensive.
Rym: Tweet appeared too often.
Rym: Tweet was irrelevant.
Scott: The problem I've had sometimes is I was, I did do a thing for a while where I'd block the account of whoever bought the ad.
Rym: I did that for a long time.
Scott: The problem is, is that.
Scott: Then you get in a situation where you might've actually wanted to see something they tweeted.
Scott: For example, uh, maybe McDonald's tweeted in, you know, made a tweet and then promoted that tweet, but you know, and then you got in your timeline and I don't want to see that shit.
Scott: So you want to, if you block the McDonald's account.
Scott: Okay, sure.
Scott: You're not going to see that ad anymore.
Scott: Great.
Scott: But then your friend retweets a funny picture of grimace and some fry guys.
Scott: And now you can't see that shit.
Scott: Cause you blocked all of McDonald's, even though that wasn't an ad.
Rym: Pay attention advertisers.
Rym: See the difference between the two.
Scott: I mean, it was an ad because it was from McDonald's, but I chose to see it.
Scott: You know, I wanted to see funny grimace because I didn't follow the McDonald's account.
Rym: I followed my friend who my trust and my friend showed me that thing.
Rym: If my friend retweeted everything McDonald's did, I would stop following them.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: That's why Twitter works.
Scott: You follow the people you care about and maybe McDonald's tweets on like the 25th anniversary of my kids.
Scott: It's probably the 30th anniversary, but you know what I'm saying?
Rym: But the problem with the Twitter ads is that as far as I can gather, they did not make money.
Scott: No.
Rym: So Twitter seems to want to make money.
Scott: You were buying ads, you know, because you're evil.
Scott: Would you buy ads on Twitter?
Rym: No, probably I would, because you can probably get them real cheap right now.
Rym: I probably would buy ads on Twitter.
Rym: Probably buy a shit ton of ads on Twitter.
Scott: It's going to be a waste of money.
Rym: You could have spent that money on something useful, but I'd be buying ads to get people who are too stupid to block ads, maybe that's the whole point.
Rym: I'm going after those people.
Rym: If I want to go after people like me, I would do press releases about my product and hope that the product was something that Rym cares about.
Scott: I see so many companies being successful without any marketing whatsoever, uh, that I feel like it's, you know, there's no reason to buy ads.
Scott: If you can just, just put your effort into your product, they might have marketing, they don't have advertisements, right?
Rym: There's a, there's advertisements are at one tool in the marketers toolkit.
Rym: But so now I feel like what Twitter is trying to do with this change that may or may not be coming.
Rym: I mean, it was leaked that it's happening is instead of having a guaranteed feed and remember Facebook used to have a guaranteed feed too, where if I follow Daryl Surratt, I'm guaranteed to see everything he tweets in my timeline when he tweeted it.
Rym: And if I tweet something, I know that every single one of my followers, all thousand of them, except for the ones that muted you.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Which there's a few, I assume.
Rym: Uh, did you mute me?
Rym: Is that what's going on here?
Rym: But they, they at least could see it if they wanted to.
Rym: Facebook shed all over that idea, and now if you say something, it's kind of random whether or not everyone who follows you sees it.
Rym: They may or may not.
Rym: If you want to guarantee you, they see it, you got to pay.
Rym: And I feel like that's the model Twitter wants because they feel like Facebook makes money with it and they can't come up with anything better than that.
Rym: Because the new system is basically instead of a, just a timeline of everything, everyone, you know, tweeted an algorithm that decides what you might like based on what's relevant.
Rym: And they're really trying to brand Twitter to be that moments tab that no one clicks on.
Rym: Like who is the person who clicks on moments?
Rym: Like I'm going to click on it right now.
Rym: What's in here.
Scott: They must have data for who clicks on it, but it's not me.
Rym: You know what it is?
Rym: It's just a shitty newsfeed here.
Rym: Leonardo DiCaprio and Lady Gaga, something, something at a lunch.
Rym: Really?
Rym: That's, that's like the top thing here.
Rym: Oh, and a riot.
Scott: And shouldn't this be, I mean, shouldn't this be using the things that Twitter knows about you to show you things that you want to see.
Rym: Tell me about Kanye and Yeezy or something.
Scott: Uh, figuring out what ads to say, figured out enough about Ram that they knew that they should show him cosplay related ads and furry related ads, but they couldn't figure up enough about Ram that he doesn't know that to know that he doesn't know Yeezy is.
Rym: nor do I give a shit about Leonardo DiCaprio and Lady Gaga schmoozing at a luncheon 19 minutes ago.
Rym: So that literally ruined sweater.
Rym: if it turns into this and it ruins it in subtle ways, because if you're, if the, the stuff I see is what Twitter's algorithm thinks will make them money, that is literally opposite of what I actually want to see, which right now is my friend Kat Small complaining about jet lag.
Rym: Uh, Joshua AC Newman, starting a Patreon.
Scott: Shouldn't you be doing what you always do and tell people, there's no such thing as jet lag.
Rym: Uh, well, no, there's not no such thing as jet lag.
Rym: I'm just immune to it.
Rym: I am a hundred percent am.
Rym: Uh, Andrew complaining about Deadpool.
Rym: Someone making a joke about druids.
Rym: This picture of pretzel.
Scott: We should send him into space and then wait for it to be like, you know, new in his time and then have him land where it's midnight in the, after like 10 days in space.
Rym: Scott, I've done that many times.
Rym: I've flown to like Hong Kong and lived there a week and then flown right back to New York.
Rym: Emily has seen me land and be totally fine.
Rym: And then let's go out to dinner and he's secretly sleeping on the inside.
Rym: I'll get tired sometimes because I was on a plane for 25 hours, but no, that's not what jet lag is.
Scott: Oh, that's not what jet lag is.
Scott: Then I don't have it either.
Scott: Cause I, all I do is get tired.
Scott: Sometimes it's what do you, what is, what is jet lag?
Rym: So do you do like if your time zones, like if it's, if it's night where you are now, but it's morning where you left from, do you wake up at 3 a.m.
Rym: and can't go back to sleep?
Scott: No.
Rym: Then that, yeah, that's jet lag.
Rym: Do you get hungry at the wrong time, but then not be hungry when you should be able to eat and feel nauseous when you try to eat.
Scott: the timing might be that I don't get nauseous, no, but the timing of hungry and this might be a little off that first day, like when we got to Australia, I think it was like a weird time and that
Rym: is actually a symptom of jet lag
Scott: and, but then it's like, you know, by the second meal, it's I'm a nun that
Rym: I might actually experience that except I'm always hungry anyway.
Rym: So I'm always hungry.
Scott: So I'm way hungry right now.
Scott: I'm actually fading.
Rym: I am so fucking hungry.
Scott: Like I don't have any energies right now.
Rym: So yeah, in some Twitter might try to monetize their platform by literally making it a shitty version of Facebook.
Scott: If anyone wants to help me make the replacement Twitter or is making the replacement Twitter and needs me on their team, I have the perfect design for it and I know how to code it.
Scott: I just don't want to put all that effort in.
Scott: So lend me your keyboard.
Rym: Lend us your ass.
Scott: Lend us your keyboard.
Rym: Ass and your effort.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion, news, and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, gaming Tuesdays, anime comic Wednesdays, and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution.
Scott: 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but on like those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: The patrons this week, in order of the amount of money they give us are Nicholas Brando, Rebecca Dunn, John R knobs, the second Amanda Duchette, James David White, Christian Koontz, Jess, Sam Cordery, mechanical mind, William Eisen rose.
Rym: You expected the next name to be yours, but it was me, D O Clinton Walton, my steady.com.
Rym: Phil Ulrich Renee from New Zealand, Robert Lee, Ryan parent, drew up open Lander, rare Lavelle, Brian Sidroni, Rochelle Montanona, Finn, Eric silver rod.
Rym: And then he placed a single finger upon his mustache.
Rym: Kinetic man, Aaron series, Chris midkiff, Chris Knox.
Rym: It was a dark and stormy night.
Rym: Daniel Redmond, Chris Haddad, Doug Schneider, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: Uh, we had a week of skiing, me and Emily.
Rym: And before that was packed south, I have the first video from PAX South, the horror panel I was up out.
Rym: Fear not while I have the video for the rest of the packs panels, none of that is going up until the next Utena episode.
Rym: Episode 14 is up and I'm literally about a third of the way through putting that thing together.
Rym: So stay tuned.
Rym: I think it'll be up in the next week or two.
Rym: We also just recorded the February Q and a, so that's going to go up or the January Q and a. that's going to go up real soon, probably tomorrow Wednesday, and I will very soon also open the submission form for the February Q and a, but for now I leave you with something that I forgot existed and now it is stuck in my head.
Rym: It may be my thing of the day on Wednesday, but here it is.
Rym: I defy you to not get this stuck in your head.
Rym: My boy making pickles is easy as pie.
Rym: Just watch what I do.
Rym: Then you give it a try.
Scott: This is the problem.
Rym: And this is the push them.
Rym: Just go, go into the jars.
Scott: How simple it is for those jars to get full?
Rym: Just a pull on the pull 'em and a push on the push 'em And the pickles go into the jars.
Rym: Tra-la-la, the pickles go into the jars And now you know all there is to be known.
Scott: I proudly pin you with a badge of Jill Pickle-Pickler, junior grade Pickle away, young fellow Happy pull 'em, happy push 'em.