Rym: It's Thursday, December 22nd, 2016.
Rym: I'm Rym, I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights Tonight.
Rym: Shazam!
Rym: And actually we're talking about Christmas, I guess, and Festivus and all that.
Rym: You'll see.
Rym: It's a show.
Scott: Let's do this!
Rym: Scott forgot his news while we were doing the opener.
Scott: I remember it again.
Rym: So, I've got my new computer up and running, like for real, and I know I keep talking about this.
Scott: It's a computer.
Scott: It adds one and one the same as the old computer.
Rym: I experience something that I always forget about, because unless you're managing a lot of servers that are basically personal servers, like if you manage a data center, you don't really give things clever names anymore, you pretty much give them functional names that are derivable from what they do.
Scott: I just imagined a funny comic, right?
Scott: Here's why I can write comics if I can't draw them, right?
Scott: There's a guy, and he's going on Newegg.
Scott: He's on a computer.
Scott: He goes on Newegg, right?
Scott: And he's got a keyboard and a mouse, and he's looking, and he pulls up the listing, and it's for ENIAC.
Scott: And you look down, and the keyboard and the mouse are plugged into UNIVAC.
Rym: But the thing that always paralyzes me...
Scott: I hope I got the order of those computers correct.
Scott: I'm pretty sure UNIVAC's older.
Rym: I think so.
Rym: I don't remember offhand.
Rym: You know what's funny?
Rym: I took a class on that at RIT.
Rym: We took a class on computer history.
Rym: But got to name your computer.
Rym: Though what's interesting is in the old days, like when you installed Windows or something, it would be, well, depending on how old you go, there's an older days where this wasn't a thing, and then it was a thing mostly when you had like Samba and NetBIOS, like I'd have a NetBIOS name for shit.
Rym: Got to name your computer.
Rym: And it's something that only matters to people who are a little bit nerdy and technological because if you're just some sort of muggle, your computer's name is probably just your first name.
Rym: apostrophe-esque computer and networking just kind of magically makes that show up in places and you don't think about it that much.
Rym: But normal computers have a host name and a Linux server has a host name or something.
Rym: So I had to name this new computer.
Rym: And it's been a while since I built a computer.
Rym: Both laptop and desktop are like 2009 era-esque.
Rym: So is the HTPC.
Rym: So I had to name it.
Rym: So I started thinking about what I have named computers over the years because I haven't had that many.
Scott: Like I can't count work stuff.
Scott: I didn't name all my computers ever.
Rym: I named every computer I ever built.
Rym: The only computer that didn't have a name was the first computer we ever had.
Rym: The 486 was literally just called the 486.
Scott: I don't think I named them until college or Beacon.
Scott: I don't even remember the names I had in college.
Rym: I remember a lot of them.
Rym: So the computer before this one, the new one, was Kusanagi.
Rym: The one before that was Tochiro.
Rym: And the one before that was Ryoko.
Rym: And then I had also names for Tachikoma for a while.
Rym: Every computer I've ever had has had an anime-related name because I've been a weeb since 4th grade.
Rym: But then I dug a little deeper and I realized that also with basically no exceptions if you know anything about Tenchi Muyo every one of them was also a sort of sci-fi anime name in particular.
Rym: And a bunch of them were either Cyberpunk-y or Lady Matsumoto-verse.
Rym: So I've just doubled down.
Rym: Matsumoto-verse forever.
Rym: That's just what I'm going to use to name my computers.
Scott: You can run it names quick.
Rym: Luckily I don't build computers that often.
Scott: You'll run it names quick.
Rym: Well I could use derivations or I can do names of ships like the Arcadia.
Rym: I could use that for stuff.
Rym: So the new computer's name is Emeraldus and the reason I bring this up is in the old days when you start the computer the first time it's like, "What's this computer's
Rym: name?".
Rym: Windows 10 doesn't actually really ask you that.
Rym: You actually have to go out of your way to give it a real host name way after you install shit.
Scott: I name all my computers and currently my current system is always after a fictional robot of some kind, right?
Scott: So my desktop computer that I've had for four going on five years is Hardac, which is from Batman the Animated Series.
Scott: This giant, enormous computer.
Scott: That was a two-parter.
Scott: I think he even had a repeat, but he came back in some more episodes.
Rym: I will look that up.
Rym: I don't remember.
Scott: It was the best episodes of Batman the Animated Series, by the way.
Scott: And my iPad is Genos, who is the sidekick of One Punch Man, who's a cyborg.
Scott: And my phone is Haro, which is a little ball in Gundam.
Scott: that's a little robot.
Scott: You know, it bounces around because it's like a sidekick kind of thing like a phone would be, right?
Scott: You know, whatever.
Scott: I forget what the HTPC is.
Scott: Oh, my NAS is, I think, which is the detective guy from the Astro Boy slash Pluto.
Scott: Yeah, Pluto.
Scott: Detective guy who's also a robot.
Rym: You got to name your next computer, Bruton.
Scott: You know, those are all available names.
Scott: If you want robot names, you could do only Astro Boy robot names because there's so many robot names.
Scott: I think my previous desktop was Danuba because in Phoenix, the manga, in the second part, future, there's the, it's sort of the Logan's Run one.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: And there's the two, there's the computers around the world that basically run these sort of paranoia Logan's Run cities and one of them that starts the new, the intercity nuclear war is Danuba and it's the coolest looking one.
Scott: It looks like a darkology from SimCity 2000.
Rym: Yes, Hardak came back.
Rym: So Hardak is in Heart of Steel part one and two.
Rym: That's what we remember.
Rym: He comes back in a third episode, his silicon soul, late one night, a group of criminals break into a warehouse owned by Cybertron where all the surviving items in the factory are kept, including Hardak.
Rym: Obviously, not recognizing the Hardak icon, they open it and from inside, Batman emerges.
Rym: I don't remember this episode.
Scott: I do remember that now.
Scott: There's basically a robot Batman and Hardak's in it.
Rym: I don't, I feel like I remember this title card with this like robot hand coming up, but I don't know if that's a shazam.
Scott: I just remember the title card with Hardak itself.
Rym: Yeah, but that's, that's not from that.
Rym: That's from the original Hardak and Hardak two.
Rym: Right.
Scott: Anyway, those are like the best episodes of Batman.
Scott: It's good stuff.
Rym: I don't know though.
Rym: The cool and Luke one is pretty good too.
Scott: Uh, I mean, if you want to talk about second best episodes, there's the one where like he has to go to Japan and then fight the guy in the volcano area.
Scott: Oh yeah.
Scott: He learns kung fu.
Rym: So yeah, name the new computer and I pre-ordered the one terabyte crazy drive that's going to come like right away in the new year and then it'll be complete.
Rym: Hmm.
Rym: And it's good times.
Rym: So I got any news?
Scott: I have more news.
Scott: no one will care about but me.
Rym: It's the lounge.
Rym: You can talk about anything.
Rym: So kpop, right?
Scott: No, but you're close.
Rym: Oh, jpop?
Scott: No.
Scott: In 2012, I watched the show running man.
Scott: It has nothing to do with the running man of Arnold Schwarzenegger.
Scott: Right.
Rym: And I like that show.
Rym: I feel like I should have watched more of it.
Scott: They've made an episode I think every single week since 2010.
Scott: The show is six years old, right?
Scott: But you know, the show has like incredible international.
Scott: It's weird, right?
Scott: Is that somehow Korea manages to make a lot of things that are internationally popular but not as popular in their own country.
Scott: Like there's a new kpop group called card that oh my God has dudes and girls in it.
Scott: They've done that a few times, but it's the only active one I know of right now and their song is way good and like.
Scott: if you go on the internet to English speaking communities it's like people are so into it like oh my God, this is the best.
Scott: But if you go like the Korean people don't give a fuck.
Scott: and it's like oh my God, what's wrong with you?
Scott: But anyway running man like about a month ago, my favorite member of the show left because he's like all right, I've been on this for six years.
Scott: That's enough of that, right?
Scott: But the rest of the people kept going.
Scott: they kept going.
Scott: But then there was a whole bunch of drama and I don't want to spend time talking about the details of the drama because it doesn't really matter and it's not that interesting.
Scott: The point is the show is going to end for end for real.
Rym: Oh man, that finale episode is going to be off the fucking hook.
Scott: Originally there wasn't going to be like a finale.
Rym: What?
Scott: Yeah, it was weird dramas you can read about on the internet if you want.
Rym: I'm curious because that show that's the kind of show that is designed to have like the finale that is remembered for all time.
Scott: Well, I mean, so here's the dramas then.
Scott: So the show had seven, you know, I guess for it started off with a different number of members, but it quickly solidified to the seven core members and it was like.
Scott: the appeal of the show really is that they were sort of like a family together.
Rym: Oh, the old cast is going to be together in a new show now.
Rym: The old cast is going to be together in a new show supposedly.
Scott: Maybe we'll see about that anyway.
Scott: But yeah, you can't trust any of these news because they change every day.
Scott: But what happened was is somebody leaked that two of the people were getting kicked off the show and this other famous guy who's not a bad guy was going to be added in and they were going to do something new, like a season running man to or something.
Scott: But those two people who are on the show, they didn't hear that first from anyone right.
Scott: They heard it from the news first.
Scott: They were right.
Scott: And then it was like, oh, they're pissed now.
Scott: And oh, the other guy is not going to join the new show.
Scott: And and then they're like, you're just going to kick us out.
Scott: And so now I guess the latest news I heard was that they're just going to keep doing the show.
Scott: The two people who, you know, were pissed are going to give all their remaining salaries from a running man to charity to be like, look, we're not just staying for the money's right.
Scott: We're staying because of loyalty or whatever.
Scott: And then they're going to end in February.
Rym: There's a lot of stuff.
Rym: So apparently over recent term, the viewership had been dropping.
Scott: If you're just driving for years because the show itself, the content of the show was not really, you know, staying up to previous, you know, demand up to previous quality.
Scott: I mean, that double of seven episode, like but part of it part of it was because, hey, the show is six years old.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's a physical activity show that's every week.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: An hour long to us.
Rym: We have coming up with a half hour show to do literally anything.
Scott: So it's not just ideas that they were having trouble with.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, you know, you do the same thing.
Scott: People want some of the familiarity of the stuff they already like.
Scott: It's sort of like the Nintendo thing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Do we just make another Metroid or we do something new?
Scott: It's like people already like that.
Scott: But if we keep doing the same thing, it gets old.
Scott: We need to keep keeping it fresh.
Scott: But also the show is physical in nature and these people are getting old.
Scott: They were six years younger when the show was zero years old and they were into it.
Scott: They were running around, you know, like and really trying hard and, you know, with the physical activities.
Scott: And now it's sort of like they've been doing that for a day a week or two days a week for six years.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like that's pro athlete levels of getting beat up on a not pro athlete.
Scott: People, you know, they you can see like they're all injured and they can't run as fast and they do less physical things now.
Scott: You know, so it's like you can't you have to get all new people.
Scott: If you got old people who were young, people would be like, Oh, well, fuck that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: These are my people saved by the bell.
Rym: The new cast.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: You can't do that either.
Scott: So it's like they're in this really hard place, especially since no one in their country is watching it as much anymore except for like kids and whatnot.
Rym: So I can't really tell.
Rym: It's hard to suck this suss this out, but as best I can tell while its viewership had been dropping, it's still the number one show on that network on the network.
Scott: Yes, but it's not.
Scott: It's nowhere near the number one variety show, let alone number one show period.
Scott: The number one Friday show is still Infinite Challenge on the other channel.
Rym: Well, it's infinite.
Scott: Infinite Challenge didn't end, but Infinite Challenge lost members to various scandals and things and whatnot.
Scott: It's not a bad show, but I just Infinite Challenge had started earlier.
Scott: It's 10 years old.
Scott: So when I discovered these things, it was already so old that I couldn't go back and watch all of it.
Scott: And I don't even think it's all subtitled from the very beginning, though it's reliably been subtitled for quite a few years now, though.
Rym: So as you guys might know, I talk about how I bought new skis.
Rym: I want to talk about it a little bit.
Scott: You're going to shush all of them?
Rym: So I went skiing.
Rym: Last year was a horrible ski season because I think El Nino messed stuff up, so it was warm and there was no snow anywhere.
Rym: It was crazy on the East Coast.
Scott: Did you see a DJZ bed when you were skiing?
Rym: I did not.
Scott: You didn't end up in the hospital where he's hanging?
Scott: I think he's actually out of the hospital now.
Scott: I was doing okay.
Rym: Actually, I didn't fall down.
Rym: Well, I didn't have any accidents because I went skiing for the first time this year with my new skis and there was a bunch of snow at Hunter Mountain.
Rym: A lot of snow, which is not common on the East Coast, especially in December.
Rym: We don't actually get good snow until the end of January, early February.
Rym: The ski season, winter is actually weird here compared to a lot of the rest of where I have skied in the past.
Scott: It wasn't.
Scott: It used to snow.
Scott: I lived in Connecticut in New York my whole life.
Scott: It used to snow here in November and December.
Rym: Hunter Mountain, you're not skiing in December unless they make the snow.
Scott: In Connecticut, I remember a Halloween where there was snow.
Rym: Yeah, but I also remember in Beacon, a Christmas day where I got up, put on shorts, no shirt, and went for a run.
Scott: That was a decade later.
Rym: Yeah, but I do remember that one morning because I was running and all the Christmas lights were still up and it was Christmas day and I just had this moment of like, "What the fuck?
Rym: What?".
Rym: I actually ski a lot and I'm pretty good at it.
Rym: I'm not a professional skier in that no one pays me for it and all that, but I ski difficult technical terrain and I, in the near future, want to go heli-skiing and do some off-pis stuff with guides on the West Coast.
Rym: I bought new skis.
Rym: finally because I've used the same shitto skis for...
Scott: You didn't say they were shitto when you bought them.
Rym: What I said was the same thing I say about everything.
Rym: I follow my own advice and this is proof that that is the good advice.
Rym: because what's my advice on everything?
Rym: If you don't know why something's better, buy the cheapest version of that thing.
Rym: Don't buy anything better than that until you can articulate what you need it for.
Scott: I got this crazy mixer here for GeekNights.
Scott: I can articulate what I need a $100,000 camera for but I can articulate why I need a mansion.
Rym: I guess it adds justification.
Scott: I can articulate why I need a private jet and a spaceship.
Rym: But you also have to have the memes.
Rym: But think, when we did GeekNights, we started with that fucking Logitech stick mic and then I bought that crapo Behringer mixer and then the bigger one.
Rym: If we had bought this mixer back then, we would have been morons.
Scott: Did that mixer exist then?
Rym: Mixers like it did, but actually I think you had to buy a mixer like this but then you had to buy a firewire card to stick into it.
Rym: This thing came later as the integrated firewire.
Scott: I remember ones that came with PCI cards that you would put in the computer and had a million cables coming out and you connect that to the mixer.
Rym: Weird old days.
Rym: So like microphones, right?
Rym: We bought those Radio Shack microphones and then we were like, "Okay, we're doing this
Rym: serious.".
Rym: We bought the SM57s because they were relatively cheap and while there were microphones that were way more expensive and ostensibly better, I could not come up with any way they would actually help us doing what we were doing.
Rym: And now, you might have noticed that we both use different, better microphones because we had a need and we learned and we were better and we had money and there's reasons to buy them.
Scott: Nah, I don't think there's a reason to buy these SM57s.
Scott: just fine.
Rym: Well, the thing is I needed to have more than two microphones for when we had people on the show and I needed the two SM57s to be able to be used for the room.
Rym: I got that weird mount to do a stereo to record the room because boundary mics kind of suck.
Rym: They're not the best for some of this stuff.
Scott: You didn't continue to waste money.
Scott: You're not buying any more money.
Rym: I'm not buying a better microphone than this thing that I'm using right here.
Rym: Even though two of you recently were like, "Why don't you guys use one of those fancy condenser
Rym: microphones?".
Rym: One, this is a condenser.
Rym: It just doesn't look like what you expect it to look like but this is the same kind of condenser.
Rym: Anyway, I went to a ski shop 10 years ago, more than 10 years.
Rym: God, it was a long time ago.
Rym: I said, "I haven't skied in 10 years.
Rym: I want to start skiing again.
Rym: I want to buy skis.
Rym: What skis should I
Rym: buy?".
Rym: He reached over and he pulled some skis out and put them in front of me.
Rym: I said, "Why
Rym: these?".
Rym: He said, "Because they come up to about your
Rym: nose.".
Rym: Then I said, "What's the difference between these and those blue
Rym: ones?".
Rym: He said, "The blue ones are blue and they're $300
Rym: more.".
Rym: I asked what's better about them and he said, "If you can't tell me what's better about them, you have no business using
Rym: them.".
Scott: That's a good shop right there.
Scott: You don't see a lot of shops like that these days.
Scott: Then I needed boots.
Rym: Same shop.
Rym: I was like, "I'll get ski
Rym: boots.".
Rym: He was like, "Do you want comfortable
Rym: ones?".
Rym: I was like, "Is there a reason why I wouldn't want comfortable
Rym: He handed me some boots and I said, "Are these
Rym: comfortable?".
Rym: He said, "They're comfortable
Rym: enough.".
Rym: I spent like $300 total on skis and boots.
Rym: I skied all the way up to Black Diamonds, like crazy skiing on cliffs and through glades.
Rym: I was starting to hit this plateau.
Rym: I was having a problem where I'd ski really dangerous, difficult stuff, but I'd see other people at my skill level skiing much more smoothly and in control.
Rym: I started to feel like maybe I suck at skiing.
Rym: Maybe there's something I'm missing here.
Rym: I finally decided to do a lot of research and learn more about modern skis.
Rym: I bought modern skis based on Ski.
Scott: technology has improved that much in 10 years.
Rym: Binding technology actually did get better.
Rym: The bindings I have now are way safer than the bindings I had previously, which are way safer than the bindings I had as a kid, which are infinitely safer than the bindings of the 70s and 80s.
Scott: Aren't the bindings of the 70s just like two ropes?
Rym: No, that's like 60s.
Rym: 80s ones are like these giant plastic bricks.
Rym: You look at them and you're like, "Ah, that's
Rym: 80s.".
Rym: They look like they're from the 80s.
Rym: I bought these crazy fancy super stiff skis.
Rym: I talked to ski experts and shops and they were like, "You're good, right?
Rym: These skis will fuck you up if you don't know what you're
Rym: doing.".
Rym: Not to belabor the point on the details of skiing because I don't think any of you guys really care that much.
Scott: It's a sled you cut in half and put on your feet.
Rym: Here's an example.
Rym: When I'm skiing on a very steep cliff, I want to be able to carve, meaning I want to be able to traverse across the cliff and then turn on one side of the cliff and traverse across again.
Rym: You don't want to just go straight down the cliff.
Rym: Sometimes maybe if you're doing a ski jump, but I don't want to go straight down the cliff because it's also covered in rocks.
Scott: If you're doing a ski jump, don't use those really long skis.
Scott: Ridiculously, comically long, like a clown ski.
Rym: Or if you're racing, but it's complicated.
Rym: I actually got slightly shorter skis based on the advice of experts.
Rym: When I was a kid, I actually skied on way longer skis than I ski on now.
Rym: I got 167s now.
Rym: Basically, I bought super pro skis that are rated for experts and I upgraded all my shit and I took them out skiing.
Rym: I had some trouble at first.
Rym: Didn't seem so great.
Rym: I started skiing, right?
Rym: It doesn't feel great.
Scott: It doesn't feel that fun.
Scott: There were new skis that just went on the bunny hill to make sure they worked?
Rym: No, I went right to the big stuff.
Rym: But not the crazy stuff.
Rym: At Hunter Mountain, I went to Hell Gate.
Rym: The black diamond that goes down the front of the mountain.
Rym: The basic, regular black diamond trail.
Rym: I'm having trouble with them.
Rym: I'm trying them out.
Rym: Remember how to ski?
Rym: And then I thought about the experts and why I bought these skis and I said fuck it.
Rym: And I went to the crazy cliff trail and I just jumped down and skied as fast as I could.
Rym: Holy shit.
Rym: These skis are amazing.
Rym: But the reviews were kind of right.
Rym: They kind of suck if you're going slow.
Rym: If you're going fast, they give you this level of control that I've never had before.
Scott: It's like an F1 car.
Scott: If you go slow, it doesn't work.
Scott: You have to go fast enough to heat up the brakes because if you don't heat up the brakes and heat up the tires then you won't be able to stop and you won't be able to go.
Scott: You can't drive an F1 car around the track at like 60 miles an hour.
Scott: It won't work.
Scott: You need to go 100, 200 miles an hour.
Scott: That's how it's designed.
Rym: But the moral of this is I do not waste money on stuff.
Rym: Sometimes I waste money on stuff.
Scott: You waste money on a lot of stuff.
Scott: But when it comes to expert equipment or specialized equipment you will at least have an excuse to where nobody can argue with you and tell you that you wasted money.
Scott: Even if you may have you can justify it to yourself and others with words.
Rym: And that is a very important skill to have in life.
Scott: But you still wasted money.
Rym: So I didn't though.
Rym: I got Atomic Black Eye Titanium Arc XTO-12.
Scott: That sounds like words to make room spend money, Ski.
Rym: But I bought last year's model brand new for 50% off.
Scott: I bought last year's model bicycle brand new for like 25% off.
Rym: The moral is just that advice that we give is totally legit.
Rym: Buy the cheapest thing that will do the job.
Rym: Learn as much as you can from that thing.
Rym: Like I was skiing Crazy Black Diamonds on skis that are not made for that.
Rym: And as a result, I really understood what I was doing when I got on the bigger stuff.
Rym: Like it was worth it.
Rym: It was the time.
Rym: That is the way to live your life.
Rym: Buy the shittiest office chair possible or the best office chair possible.
Rym: You'll notice I'm still sitting in my Aeron and Scott's still sitting at home in his human freedom.
Rym: Human scale freedom chair with the optional headrest.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day!
Rym: I present to you the Scott Forgot his thing of the day!
Rym: My thing of the day is Shazam!
Rym: This movie!
Scott: No!
Scott: The movie doesn't exist!
Scott: No such movie!
Rym: I kind of think the people who think Shazam exists are actually just racist and confuse the actors.
Rym: because I remembered people said Shazam's not a movie.
Rym: And the first thing I thought was, "Bullshit!
Rym: I saw that
Rym: movie!".
Rym: And then I googled for it and the answer was, "Oh no, I'm thinking of
Rym: Kazam!".
Scott: See, I remember Kazam definitely.
Scott: I didn't see it.
Scott: But I remember seeing commercials for it, right?
Scott: But I have a vaguer memory of Shazam.
Scott: I sort of remember like I don't remember a movie like some of these people are like, "Oh yeah, I worked in a blockbuster and I had it on VHS and there were two copies and everyone kept checking it in and out and I had to watch it over and over.
Scott: and I definitely remember this movie.
Scott: It totally existed.
Scott: I don't remember a movie.
Scott: But I do remember Sinbad the Comedian in a pirate genie sort of setting on TV doing something like a TV commercial or something of the sort.
Scott: And that's all I remember.
Scott: So when people say, "Oh yeah, this movie with Sinbad was a genie named
Scott: Shazam!"
Scott: It's like it matches enough things else in my memory that it sort of falsely pieces them together, these true things into a false thing.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But I guess for me, I immediately thought that was Shaq, not Sinbad.
Rym: And then I looked it up like, "Oh
Rym: no!".
Scott: I didn't think that was Shaq not Sinbad, but I said, "Oh yeah, there was Kazam and Shazam, I
Scott: remember.".
Rym: The important thing is as a kid, I remember that Sinbad was not funny.
Scott: Sinbad the Comedian?
Scott: Not funny.
Scott: I don't remember any of his comedy at all, but I remember him you know.
Scott: I remember him fondly, but I don't think he was funny.
Scott: I don't remember him being a bad guy, but I don't remember watching him on purpose.
Scott: I remember jokes about Sinbad more than jokes told by Sinbad.
Rym: Kind of like how in the future we might remember who Jimmy Fallon was just because people make fun of him for his Boteau's comedy stylings.
Scott: Right, well that's what I'm saying.
Scott: At this point even, there are more people remember more jokes about Seinfeld.
Rym: Kids who grew up in the 70s who's in the 70s and 80s remember Ishtar because that was the default name of a bad movie that Mad Magazine would use whenever they wanted to talk about a bad movie.
Rym: None of us have seen Ishtar.
Rym: Well, I have, but no one else has.
Scott: You can see it if you want.
Rym: You don't want to.
Scott: Why not?
Rym: It's not a good movie.
Scott: How bad could it be?
Rym: It's just really, really, really unremarkable that movie.
Rym: So anyway, the thing of the day is actually, I'm just trying to stall to give Scott time to remember his thing of the day.
Scott: No, I got it.
Scott: Alright.
Rym: There's a video of a driver in New York City who keeps his dash cam on, which if you're like an Uber driver or whatever, you really should do that.
Rym: I mean, I do that on my bike, on my commute.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But I guess his thing is trying to hit as many green lights in a row as possible.
Scott: Yeah, if you're really bored, your job is driving, shouldn't you be doing something like that?
Rym: This guy exceeded all expectations, and this is a video, both a sped up one and the real-time uncut one to prove he's not cheating.
Rym: 240 green lights in a row in motherfucking Manhattan and not at like three in the morning.
Scott: So he just knows the timing of the lights and how to hit them.
Scott: And he's practiced so much.
Scott: He's got skills.
Scott: Also, if I need a cab, how can I get this guy specifically?
Rym: More trucks are out at night.
Rym: A lot more Uber cars are on the road.
Rym: I was hoping to push my goal up to a large number, like 500 green lights, but I'll settle for this.
Rym: No stopping.
Scott: Smooth.
Rym: Mostly smooth sailing.
Scott: Any block in the box and like running the yellows?
Rym: He's a little aggressive to catch some lights.
Rym: Slows down a little bit to like wait for something to turn green when it's off in the distance.
Scott: So it's red in the distance, but he's still moving.
Scott: He doesn't completely 100% stop.
Rym: Can't just stop.
Scott: But he gets down to like 0.01 miles an hour and creeps.
Rym: Actually, he keeps a pretty good clip.
Rym: It's a pretty impressive video.
Rym: I didn't watch the whole thing.
Rym: It's 26 minutes long.
Scott: The DOT should check this video out and they could figure out some stuff.
Rym: It's not as exciting as that other video, the guy who raced the lap around Manhattan.
Rym: I think we used that as a thing a day a while ago.
Rym: So what do you got?
Scott: So, Rym, you had El Parrot when you were a kid, right?
Rym: Yes, Dusty the African Gray who could mimic my voice perfectly and would sometimes yell, "Mom, I'm
Rym: home!"
Rym: randomly during the day freaking my mom out.
Rym: Dusty was a good bird.
Rym: Well, he is a good bird.
Rym: Dusty will outlive all of my adult relatives.
Scott: Like everyone who was an adult when I was a kid.
Rym: Dusty's out in Arizona.
Rym: Dusty will outlive my mom pretty much guaranteed.
Scott: Then what?
Rym: Then my brother's gonna take her.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Then what?
Rym: Well, if she also outlives my brother, I guess I'll take her.
Scott: Your brother's younger than you.
Scott: Yeah, he is.
Scott: You're gonna be dead first.
Scott: So I guess don't buy a parrot unless you have children.
Rym: If you get a real parrot, one, you gotta treat them like a kid.
Rym: You can't just leave them home alone.
Rym: They'll go crazy.
Rym: You have to play with them every day like they're a real human being.
Rym: They're as smart as a two to three year old human.
Scott: But anyway, so this parrot, someone has one and it says stuff because that's what they do.
Scott: This one says something way awesome that I've never seen any other animal say.
Scott: It's a 15 second video.
Scott: Enjoy.
Rym: It's actually real good.
Rym: So Dusty did a lot of stuff like that but I won't tell those stories right now because it spoils the video.
Rym: You just watch the video.
Rym: You'll figure out what's going on real quick.
Scott: I mean the title of the video.
Rym: Yeah, but when you see the title, like the video comes up, you're like ah, makes sense.
Rym: In the meta moment, the Book Club book is Rebecca.
Scott: Kindle says that I have how much time left.
Scott: The thing is I can't trust the Kindle time because like I'll read for 15 minutes and the time will go down by like an hour.
Scott: It says I have five hours and 45 minutes left and I'm at the beginning of chapter 13. so who knows.
Rym: It moves around on me too, partly because like I'll be reading on the subway but then I have to transfer and I just like walk with it open, not reading the page for a while and that like messes up its calculations I think.
Rym: Like I can't really trust that number.
Scott: I'm at the beginning of chapter, what'd I just say, 13.
Rym: I'm only a couple chapters in but I'll burn through it pretty quick.
Scott: It says I got less than six hours so I could probably, I'll be done reading this by the end of the year.
Rym: It's still fucking me up because I remember a lot of this but I don't clearly know if I've actually seen the movie or if I'm just remembering pieces of it and other movies altogether.
Scott: Well after we finish the book, we'll watch the movie again.
Scott: I've only seen the movie like two times and not recently, not since like maybe Beacon or earlier.
Rym: Oh dude, if I saw the movie, I was single digit age at most like six to eight years old is when I saw it.
Scott: Oh no, definitely the first time I saw it I was definitely at least two digits in age.
Rym: I watch a lot of awesome horror movies and such as a little kid.
Scott: It's not a horror movie.
Rym: It's pretty lugubrious though.
Scott: It's a Hitchcock movie.
Scott: It's lugubrious and it's suspenseful.
Rym: It's also really, really...
Scott: It's not suspenseful in chapter two though.
Rym: Well, you know what?
Rym: Chapter one and two are interesting in that they're so far, you know, no spoilers obviously, there's like this deep undercurrent of dread of like, we're avoiding thinking about the thing that happened.
Scott: that casts a pall over the rest of our lives.
Scott: Right, yeah, the flashback.
Rym: Like everything's just very nice and the dream and everything's just very sinister.
Rym: and you're like, what the fuck happened to these people?
Scott: It is sinister.
Scott: It's not a feel good movie.
Scott: It's Alfred Hitchcock movie.
Scott: You think Alfred Hitchcock isn't going to pick up like Bambi?
Scott: Bambi's sinister too though.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: So yeah, we're going to be at MAGFest coming up real soon.
Rym: We're between Scott and I. We're on six panels.
Rym: It's going to be good times.
Rym: PAX South.
Rym: Nah, it's coming.
Rym: Not too long after that.
Rym: We're going to be doing at least one panel.
Rym: I'm really excited about MAGFest and we'll hopefully see you there.
Rym: So yeah, I guess Christmas is coming up where we celebrate the birth of Shazam.
Scott: We've definitely done many holiday episodes.
Scott: We have not.
Scott: You deleted them.
Rym: So, you know, we did them, actually we talked about Christmas in the review we did of that movie Shazam.
Rym: So, I noticed looking at the archive of GeekNights that last year around this time, like September or October we did a show on Thanksgiving as a holiday which reeks of the situation that happens to me and Scott all the time where we'll rack our brains for a show idea and then one of us will have a dumb idea like,
Scott: "Hey,
Rym: what are we going to do a show on?
Rym: I don't know, submarine
Rym: sandwiches.".
Rym: And the other one will inevitably say, "We've definitely done a show on submarine sandwiches in the last 16 years of our
Rym: lives.".
Rym: And then it'll turn out that no, somehow that topic never talked about, never did it, never happened.
Rym: And I feel like that happened with the Thanksgiving episode last year and I feel like there's an untapped well of holiday-related episodes that we could fill a lot of Thursdays with.
Rym: So, yeah.
Rym: Christmas is coming up.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: It's Christmas.
Scott: We've done, I think, two Halloween shows maybe.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: When I searched for Christmas in the archive, I found an episode that started promising.
Rym: It was like, "Tonight on a very special Christmas episode of GeekNights, we review Hotline
Rym: Miami.".
Rym: And I think we actually recorded it on Christmas Day.
Rym: So, Christmas as an adult, like the way I had this holiday season is interesting because I've actually sort of resolved over the years.
Rym: I very rarely travel anywhere on Thanksgiving or Christmas anymore.
Scott: Why would you?
Scott: It's a pain in the ass.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: And I've tried to convince everyone in my life who really wants to see me on Christmas to sort of defer that and like, "I'll visit in January" or "I'll come in like
Rym: October.".
Rym: Like, we'll shift the holiday so I don't have to actually travel on Christmas.
Scott: It doesn't matter what arbitrary day you see someone.
Scott: If you see someone every year, it's like,
Scott: "Okay.".
Rym: But you gotta get people on bar because you always have like the grandma who's like, "But it's
Rym: Christmas.".
Scott: Get bent, grandma.
Rym: You did dick, grandma.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: So, once again, I'm just staying home and maybe I'll even go.
Rym: in fact, I think I might go skiing on Christmas.
Rym: That's actually not a bad idea.
Scott: Is it open?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: How many people are gonna be skiing?
Rym: Maybe a lot.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I've never skied on Christmas Day, I don't think.
Scott: On Christmas, I go to the movies and eat Chinese food.
Rym: That's what I usually do.
Scott: That's how a non-believing Jew do.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And how I also believe in Jew do.
Rym: Or like you and me and Jews or something.
Scott: Because those are the only things that are open on Christmas.
Rym: We'll go hang out and get some, we'll get those, what was that, the Arab, the lamb dish covered in those spices that we got at that Chinese place.
Scott: Oh, that's open on Christmas?
Rym: That place is definitely open on Christmas.
Rym: I remember that dish had a weird name and it had more spices on it than you could, it was a ridiculous amount of spices on that lamb.
Rym: But it was pretty good.
Rym: So yeah, Christmas now is, like Christmas Day is barely at all a holiday for me.
Rym: I guess I wake up and I sort of think in my head the like end of Ebenezer Scrooge's Odyssey, like it's Christmas, it's Christmas.
Rym: But then I just like play video games and dick around and eat some Chinese food.
Scott: Yeah, the main problem with Christmas is that if you're not celebrating it and you're not with people and even though there's a few things open I guess like skiing and Chinese food and movies drugstores, sure is that not very few people are like that, right?
Scott: At least, you know, per unit space.
Scott: So you're usually like you know, alone-ish and cold-ish, right?
Scott: It's in the winter.
Rym: And like you log into Overwatch or Counter-Strike, no one else is online.
Scott: Yeah, there's not a lot of people.
Scott: there's not a lot of people making content on the internet.
Scott: so even you think, oh, there's people on the internet and they are but the people actually making stuff aren't working, right?
Scott: You're not gonna get new posts on like your websites or you're not gonna get new content in your video games.
Scott: You just gotta play your existing stuff, you know, new stuff is not happening.
Scott: whether you observe the holiday or give a shit or not you know, as long as you live in a part of the world that does like we do, it's sort of like, alright, it's Christmas but I do enjoy the like two weeks before and the week after Christmas.
Rym: and just like the Christmas music is playing and there's lights and everyone's like I mean, other people, right?
Scott: Including me, I hate that the Christmas shit shows up too early.
Scott: it's like it's not even Halloween yet and they're putting the lights on the tree and I'm like, oh, fuck you, get that shit down.
Rym: Yup, like Black Friday is literally the earliest that is even defensible in my opinion.
Scott: That's not, it's barely defensible, right?
Rym: Defensible at all, it is indefensible to go before that.
Rym: But at the same time It's a war crime.
Scott: If Christmas is 12 or fewer days away if it's like December 13, 14 If it's 13, 14, 15 like, I can't deny you.
Scott: Also despite whether you know, what the lyrics are there are many Christmas carols that I do not find annoying and in fact enjoy that many other people do not enjoy.
Rym: Oh, Scott do we talk about Christmas music right now or do we do a separate show on that in the future?
Scott: I'm just saying is that there's a lot of people, even Goyim, who are like hating on Christmas music.
Rym: Yeah, you know what though?
Scott: I'll hate on Christmas music if I hear it in September Sure, but it's like you know, I like a Burl Live.
Scott: I'll take all the Burl Live you're gonna send me.
Scott: I don't give a shit.
Scott: I'm an atheist Jew and you give me all the Burl Live you got.
Rym: Today I was walking down the street and I heard that holly jolly Christmas song.
Rym: That's Burl Live.
Scott: Yeah, I really like that song.
Scott: It's a great song.
Scott: Feliz Navidad, people are like so angry.
Scott: It's like, no man Feliz all the time.
Scott: Give me some more Feliz.
Rym: Navidad today but Feliz every day.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: Alright, Scott what are your top three Christmas songs?
Scott: Top three?
Rym: Top three.
Rym: No particular order.
Scott: Number one is the easiest so we'll go three, two, one.
Scott: Alright.
Scott: Three, John Lennon.
Rym: Yeah, so this is Christmas and Happy New Year.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: Two Thank God it's Christmas Freddie Mercury.
Scott: Number one Christmas is Hollis Run DMC.
Rym: So, despite being not just an atheist but kind of like one of those angry militant atheists like, you know I can't associate with them.
Scott: they're so bad.
Rym: I'm angry militant in the like.
Rym: atheism is the thing that actually I am mad about.
Scott: I definitely do not believe in God but the thing that people who are in an atheist community all the other things.
Scott: Misogyny and fedoras.
Scott: All the other things that they're into like Islamophobia and I'm not into that.
Rym: Yeah, you say you're an atheist dude with a but those are the guys like burning down Christmas trees.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: no, I'm down with the guys who put out the Satan display on the town lawn.
Rym: I'm pro them.
Scott: I'm down with the people who put like the Festivus pole on the town lawn.
Rym: Yeah, or the like.
Rym: it's a nativity scene but like it's Obi-Wan and a bunch of stormtroopers.
Scott: Oh man, it's so hot.
Scott: Yeah, it is.
Scott: Right, but like the neighbor like in the behind my apartment has like I guess they're actually religious.
Scott: they got like an infledo nativity scene.
Rym: That feels really middle class Americana.
Scott: Well, they're definitely.
Scott: it's kind of sad looking but it's also kind of cute.
Scott: but the super realistic nativity scene at the catholic church across the street that's kind of creepy.
Rym: Yeah, I just got I grew up and went to a catholic school.
Scott: Yeah, it's like the nativity scene at the church is creepy but the infledo one kind of looks like a halloween decoration and plus it's got three kings.
Scott: It's like dude I don't give a fuck about Jesus but three kings.
Rym: but I actually I actually really like some of the like very Swedish hockey jersey three kings.
Rym: very stoic and serious Christmas songs like Oh Holy Night actually might be my favorite Christmas song.
Scott: Not into that.
Rym: I like that song.
Rym: I like Silent Night too.
Rym: Mostly not into that because I like it on a pipe organ and basically your list after that.
Rym: but yeah but it was so alright fine.
Rym: if I can't use anything on your list I'm gonna go with Holly Jolly Christmas.
Scott: Yeah, it's number four.
Rym: Yeah, that's my number three then.
Rym: I'll use that.
Rym: I like that song a lot.
Rym: It's been running through my head all day.
Scott: You know another one.
Scott: I like that.
Scott: everyone else hates Yeah?
Scott: Rockin' Around the Christmas Tree.
Rym: Ah, fuck that song!
Rym: Fuck you!
Scott: Fuck that song!
Scott: People hate that song but you know what?
Scott: It's got that little guitar part where it goes.
Scott: I like that.
Rym: Scott, you you know what it is?
Rym: You know what this is like?
Rym: It's like if you see someone who doesn't know anything about computers they have a computer and they use it but they don't know anything about it and they're just like man that internet explorer is just like the most amazing athlete like I've ever run.
Rym: Like it's great.
Rym: That is how I feel when someone says they like Rockin' Around the Christmas Tree.
Scott: One that song is not rock.
Scott: that song is just like... Who said it's rock?
Scott: I just like the song.
Scott: Then what?
Rym: It's just like straight eighth notes and terrible lyrics.
Scott: Don't give a shit I mean all the songs have terrible lyrics Most of them.
Scott: What's your best?
Rym: What's your favorite Christmas movie?
Rym: that's not the ironic.
Rym: it's not actually about a Christmas.
Rym: It just happens to occur on Christmas.
Rym: Die Hard.
Scott: So not Die Hard?
Scott: Yeah not Die Hard.
Scott: So what counts as a Christmas movie?
Scott: I guess Christmas has to.
Scott: Does Nightmare Before Christmas count?
Rym: Damn it.
Rym: Yeah probably.
Scott: But that's not my favorite.
Scott: I'm just asking if it counts.
Rym: I think it counts.
Scott: I'm not picking it.
Rym: I think it might have to have Santa in it.
Rym: At least implied.
Scott: It has to have literal Santa?
Rym: Or at least an implied Santa.
Scott: So I can't pick.
Scott: It's a Wonderful Life?
Scott: Which I like?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: It's a Wonderful Life.
Rym: It doesn't have the implied Santa.
Rym: Because most of those movies I guess I'm thinking about Christmas specials.
Rym: They always have the implied Santa.
Rym: Like who left this package here?
Rym: It must have been.
Rym: And then the credits roll.
Scott: I can't pick National Lampoon Christmas where the cat burns down the tree or whatever.
Rym: So because so the ski bus that I take sometimes.
Scott: It shows that movie because that's a very appropriate movie to show on a ski bus in December.
Rym: One of them shows.
Rym: There's multiple buses I can take.
Rym: One of them shows the regular vacation movie until it's December and then they show the Christmas vacation movie.
Scott: I feel like that's like the most appropriate movie to show when someone's skiing.
Rym: However there's a better more appropriate movie.
Scott: I know one.
Rym: Better Off Dead.
Scott: I don't know what that is.
Rym: But how did?
Rym: you're the same age as me.
Rym: At least younger people have an excuse.
Rym: That's the.
Rym: I guess you had to be born in like 81 or 80 to remember that movie.
Rym: It's about a guy who's gonna die skiing.
Rym: It's a comedy.
Scott: Oh he's gonna die skiing?
Rym: Well it's a dark comedy.
Rym: It's hard for me to really explain the plot.
Rym: It's kind of absurd.
Rym: We'll just leave it at that.
Rym: Better Off Dead.
Rym: I'm curious if any listeners have seen that movie.
Scott: If I ran the ski bus the movie that I would show.
Scott: Die Hard?
Scott: No.
Scott: Would be James Bond The Spy Who Loved Me.
Scott: The best skiing scene in the beginning.
Scott: The best skiing scene in any movie of all time.
Rym: The thing is though a lot of people are like it's hipster ironic bullshit.
Scott: Maybe I'll watch that shit when I get home.
Rym: To say that Die Hard is your favorite Christmas movie but I think it actually is my favorite Christmas movie and I still can't make a good argument to myself as to why it doesn't count.
Scott: I mean you know if you told me like if I got a choice of like a whole bunch of Christmas movies to watch right and I'm just saying which one do I want to watch?
Rym: So here are all the Christmas movies.
Rym: I typed best Christmas movies.
Rym: Google just gives me a list here.
Scott: Love Actually.
Scott: That's a great movie.
Scott: Scrooged.
Scott: Muppet Christmas Carol though.
Rym: A Christmas Story.
Rym: I think it's just overplayed.
Scott: No I think a Christmas story is not only overplayed but also overrated.
Rym: Once again fuck you you're rocking around the Christmas tree and you hate for this movie.
Rym: What's wrong with that movie?
Scott: I'm not saying it's bad I'm just saying like I'm not into it.
Rym: I suspect you're just oversaturated from the fact that that movie is everywhere.
Scott: I've only seen it like one time.
Scott: Wow really?
Scott: I noticed that it's played a whole bunch like back when I had TV.
Scott: it flipped through the channels and you'd see it on all the time but I'd only see it for like a second and that had no effect on my opinion of the one time I saw it completely.
Rym: Before it became a thing where like networks would air marathons of it, it was actually my family's tradition to watch it every year on Christmas Day.
Rym: Home Alone.
Rym: A Christmas movie.
Scott: Home Alone was okay when I was a kid and now is not good.
Rym: As a kid I really like.
Rym: for some reason this movie would make me laugh hysterically but watching it as an adult it's basically soft core torture porn.
Scott: It's not a good movie.
Rym: Like it's a torture porn movie.
Rym: Straight up it is just these dudes get tortured dangerously the end.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: It's a Wonderful Life.
Scott: A+ movie.
Scott: Elf with Will Ferrell.
Scott: Never saw it.
Rym: So I saw it.
Scott: Also I don't think he's funny.
Scott: And other things I've seen him in.
Scott: I know who that is actually.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: A thing that's happened to me is that whenever I see there's a movie that has Will Ferrell in it I kind of assume it's gonna be just like basic shitty movie.
Rym: And Elf is actually a shockingly good movie compared to my expectations of that movie.
Rym: I saw it under duress and I enjoyed it in the end.
Rym: Like I did not regret seeing it even though I attempted to avoid seeing it.
Scott: When I was a kid the movie that was on the pay movie channels was the Santa Claus.
Rym: Oh.
Rym: That's on the list right here.
Rym: Right after National Lampoon's Christmas Vacation and Nightmare Before Christmas.
Scott: And back then it wasn't the worst.
Scott: Like it was.
Scott: I remember it being better than I expected but I don't remember it being good enough to where.
Scott: like.
Scott: I liked it and wanted to watch it.
Rym: I remember seeing it as like kind of a body horror movie because he started getting fat and he couldn't stop it and it just felt horrifying.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: He actually like became Santa for reals.
Scott: Like the spirit of Santa inhabited his body.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: That was Tim the Tool Man Taylor too.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You know what I really like?
Scott: I like you know the Rudolph with the claymation.
Rym: Oh.
Rym: That's good stuff.
Rym: The Bumble.
Rym: Muppet Christmas Carol.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: That's what I'm saying.
Rym: White Christmas 1954.
Rym: Never seen that.
Rym: Irving Berlin.
Scott: I don't know what the hell that is.
Rym: It's Vista Vision.
Rym: It's one of those old Rosie.
Rym: Alright.
Rym: Bing Crosby movie.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: I've never seen it but it's one of those like ultra wide.
Scott: I never even heard of it.
Rym: Let's see.
Rym: Miracle on 34th street.
Scott: No.
Rym: You don't like it?
Scott: That's a Macy's commercial.
Rym: It's a part of Americana.
Scott: The new dog.
Rym: No.
Rym: We're not talking about that new Grinch movie.
Rym: Though the original animated Grinch.
Scott: Animated Grinch is fine.
Scott: It's okay.
Scott: Whoa.
Rym: Wait a minute.
Rym: So now there's a new contender for me because I always say my favorite Christmas movie is Die Hard and that might be true.
Rym: I forgot until just now that Gremlins is actually technically also a Christmas movie.
Scott: I guess if you count Die Hard you gotta count Gremlins.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But I mean I like Gremlins-ish but like.
Rym: I haven't seen Gremlins since I was a kid.
Scott: If you give me a Die Hard DVD and a Gremlins DVD it's not even a difficult choice.
Scott: No.
Scott: Not even difficult.
Rym: In fact I think any Die Hard even later ones comes over Gremlins.
Scott: I don't know about that but.
Rym: Well I haven't seen Gremlins since single digit age so I gotta watch it again.
Rym: Oh Charlie Brown Christmas.
Scott: Is it pretty good?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Just like whole jingle all the way.
Rym: No.
Scott: It's not as good as Great Pumpkin though.
Rym: Great Pumpkin is way better.
Scott: Which is not as good as Garfield.
Rym: Christmas with the cranks I did not see.
Scott: I don't know what the hell that is.
Rym: A Very Bill Murray Christmas which I've heard mixed reviews of.
Rym: I didn't actually see.
Scott: Never seen it.
Rym: They remade Miracle on 34th Street.
Rym: Oh no.
Rym: 34th Street.
Rym: What the fuck?
Rym: They did.
Rym: What's going on here?
Rym: They remade it.
Scott: It's the 90's version yeah.
Rym: Wow I didn't know that existed.
Rym: I feel kinda dirty about it.
Rym: Earnest Saves Christmas.
Scott: Nope.
Scott: 1988.
Rym: Nope.
Rym: If I recall correctly I think that one scraped in the bottom of even the earnest barrel.
Scott: Look there's not that many.
Scott: You ran out of Christmas movies pretty quickly there.
Rym: Home Alone 2.
Scott: It's a real short list.
Rym: While You Were Sleeping.
Rym: also Christmas movie.
Scott: I don't even know what that is.
Rym: Lethal Weapon is listed.
Rym: Part of it takes place on Christmas.
Scott: Sure whatever.
Rym: It's listed next to Die Hard.
Scott: Sure.
Rym: I guess Trading Places takes place on Christmas.
Rym: Batman Returns takes place on Christmas.
Scott: That is more of a Christmas movie than Die Hard is for sure.
Scott: No question.
Rym: Actually yeah.
Rym: Remember Rare Exports?
Scott: Did you watch that with us?
Scott: I didn't know what the hell that is.
Scott: Oh.
Rym: Well you didn't come right?
Rym: We went to Chase's house.
Rym: We watched that shit.
Rym: This is a horror movie set in like the Scandinavian wilderness.
Rym: It's in this movie is a Christmas movie except the conceit is Santa Claus is probably real and he's treated like a monster from a classic horror movie.
Scott: But isn't he going to be nice to everyone and give them presents?
Rym: No.
Rym: It is horrible.
Rym: This movie is like you're ultra violent like it is.
Rym: it's like deep homage.
Scott: Why isn't Santa giving everyone presents?
Rym: You've got to see this movie Scott.
Rym: It is legit good.
Scott: Alright whatever.
Scott: It's a good Christmas movie.
Rym: Or Halloween movie.
Rym: It's one of those interchangeable.
Scott: Does Edward Scissorhands take place on Christmas?
Scott: Part of it.
Scott: I guess it's in the winter.
Scott: I definitely remember scenes with snow.
Scott: I only saw it once when the year it came out.
Rym: I also saw it the year it came out.
Scott: Which was when?
Scott: 1990.
Scott: So I was eight so I remember nothing.
Scott: I remember him cutting bushes in the snow and being in a house and people were scared of him.
Scott: and that's about it.
Rym: We went to the theater and as a kid my main memory for the movie was why the fuck did he give him Scissorhands?
Rym: He had perfectly good hands right there and that bothered me the whole movie as a kid.
Rym: Christmas town the bishop.
Rym: Oh Mickey's Christmas Carol.
Scott: Mickey's Christmas Carol is not as good as Muppet Christmas Carol.
Scott: But Scrooge is like the best at being Scrooge.
Scott: So I wish they would make a Muppet Christmas Carol and bring over Scrooge McDuck to be Scrooge.
Rym: That might be peak.
Rym: Scrooge McDuck like that was like that.
Rym: Ebenezer Scrooge is kind of legitimately terrifying.
Scott: That's how it should be.
Scott: You want to talk about a good Christmas movie?
Scott: The old Christmas Carol movie.
Scott: The real deal.
Scott: The black and white.
Scott: That's the hot shit.
Scott: None of those new garbage ones.
Rym: So we were thinking about doing a Christmas special like the Bill Murray thing.
Scott: Like the crunchy roll thing.
Rym: We'd be sitting here and we'd be like ding dong.
Rym: what's that?
Rym: Who's here?
Rym: Oh it's I don't know Gerald from anime world order.
Scott: There's actual fucking Santa.
Rym: In the neighborhood.
Rym: And then like play a recording from him and we're just fucking lazy and didn't do that.
Scott: Yeah we're not doing any work.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I thought we were going to live stream it.
Scott: I still can't believe we haven't done a holiday show ever.
Scott: Ever.
Rym: We did Thanksgiving once.
Scott: Facebook is adding live audio streaming which is interesting that no one else does that.
Rym: I saw that.
Scott: We could do shout cast.
Scott: We could have done shout cast in the 90's too right?
Scott: I mean that still exists also.
Scott: But how are people going to find that shout cast and play it?
Scott: Are we going to put some weird shout cast player in our website?
Rym: All over the Facebook thing because I feel like we can generate content on a thing like that with the rapidity that allowed like the YouTube people to get big in the early days.
Scott: I mean you could just find some ways that when we're recording the podcast on our Facebook page a live audio thing shows up.
Rym: I think I would need a Facebook account to actually set that up.
Scott: Yeah you need a Facebook account and then I give it permission to access the Facebook app.
Rym: I've never had a Facebook account in my entire life.
Scott: I'm not giving you mine.
Scott: It's like I could give you just permissions for the app but you need.
Scott: you can't just log in.
Scott: You can't log in as GeekNights.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: You need to log in as a user who has permission on the GeekNights page.
Rym: Well I guess they made a Christmas Carol again in 2009?
Scott: I mean I assume Christmas Carol.
Scott: With Jim Carrey right?
Scott: I assume Christmas Carol gets remade like a thousand times.
Scott: There was a Christmas Carol production at the Boys and Girls Club near my apartment that was running all month and it was supposedly like sort of a creepy cool one but I didn't get over there to see it.
Rym: Jim Carrey.
Rym: This looks horrific.
Scott: It probably is.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Alright.
Rym: So I actually have a lot of nostalgia for like old Christmas.
Rym: but when I was a kid it was interesting because Christmas really just it was literally never religious.
Rym: It was just.
Rym: I had a materialistic and specific desire to get a ton of presents because I did not have any way.
Rym: like I couldn't just get NES games.
Rym: I did have money.
Rym: so I would get NES games primarily on Christmas.
Scott: I had Hanukkah.
Scott: We had eight days of presents and my mom would hide the presents in the basement and then after dinner you light the candle then she goes down in the basement and comes up with the presents for that day and we would go in the basement during the week and we couldn't find shit.
Scott: And we were searching hard.
Scott: like if we're kids you think we're smart enough to find something right?
Scott: I don't know how.
Scott: I mean there's a bunch of junk in our basement.
Scott: but man we couldn't find jack shit down here.
Rym: Maybe they weren't actually down there.
Scott: Maybe sometimes you think like aha she's putting like under her shirt and then going down there.
Rym: Alright Scott you wanted the pro move because I actually I do know the secret of how most parents in America solve that problem.
Scott: I mean we were looking like in the washing machine behind the washing machine in the clothes in the.
Rym: you know a lot of families in America have more than one car.
Rym: all the presents are in the trunk of the lesser used car.
Scott: Yeah no so but I mean like one year.
Scott: so here are notable episodes from presents from the basement right?
Scott: That I just have a clear memory of right?
Scott: One year she was like oh I got a present for all of you together to like share right?
Rym: That's always that's sometimes a danger sign.
Scott: Alright and I'm looking through like the Toys R Us catalog right?
Scott: You know the circular or then there was the big book.
Rym: The big book was the one I go through that with a highlighter.
Scott: Oh yeah but it's like if you're looking through that Toys R Us and I'd be like hmm what here is appropriate for everyone.
Scott: and keep in mind Sarah Rubin was eight years younger than me at the time and could like barely walk.
Scott: so I'm like what is good for all three of us right?
Scott: And one of the things that I thought might be possible was Mr.
Scott: Bucket because he was in the catalog.
Scott: Mr.
Rym: Bucket.
Scott: You ever saw Mr.
Scott: Bucket?
Rym: I'm well familiar with Mr.
Rym: Bucket.
Scott: Yeah so it's fun.
Scott: and I was right when Mr.
Scott: Bucket came out.
Scott: So Mr.
Scott: Bucket definitely wasn't hidden anywhere else but the basement because where the hell was she gonna?
Scott: how was she gonna sneak him into the basement?
Rym: You remember that horror movie that the AVGN made with Mr.
Scott: Bucket right?
Scott: But the point is Mr.
Scott: Bucket fucking sucks.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: It was like he played with it in the kitchen immediately.
Scott: and then we're like alright that's the end of Mr.
Scott: Bucket.
Scott: good job.
Scott: Yeah there was always that like Why'd you buy that garbage?
Scott: I could have told you not to.
Rym: Like as a kid there's always that like crazy adrenaline rush of oh shit there's presents.
Scott: I mean because there was no internet.
Scott: so just new things period were like a miracle regardless of what they were.
Rym: Like when a new Simpsons episode like the night when Simpsons episode was on like whole family gather round because.
Scott: Oh my god something's going to be on the TV that's never been on the TV before ever.
Scott: Whoa.
Scott: Because now I could just if no one ever made anything else ever I could watch YouTube and see new things for the rest of my life.
Rym: I could just watch all those Christmas movies that we just talked about.
Scott: The other notable episode from the basement.
Scott: right yeah comes out of the basement and this is box and they take the wrapping paper off the box and it says like Macy's on it's like is this some kind of clothes folded up in here or something?
Scott: right you know.
Scott: but then you take off the Macy's lid.
Scott: it's a rectangle box like it's going to have clothes and then there's a bunch of tissue paper in there and you take off the tissue paper.
Scott: NES game reveal Mario 3.
Rym: ah damn.
Scott: The golden of all goldens the platinum item had arrived that Mario 3 right there.
Rym: That was one hell of a year because you had to choose between Mario 3 and Zelda 2.
Scott: I took Mario 3 all day.
Rym: yeah no regret.
Rym: so there will always be that sort of crash though like around 1pm on Christmas day when everyone's laying around and like you sort of touched all the toys.
Rym: and now you sort of you're almost bored like you're looking at all this stuff and you're like so which one do I interact with?
Scott: now?
Scott: see that's the thing.
Scott: when you get one thing a day that's not a problem.
Scott: but you know what is a problem?
Scott: you get your Christmas shit.
Scott: you wake up in the fucking morning and there it is and you're not going to school.
Scott: so you got all fucking day to burn it all out to play Mario 3. right I got Mario 3 and I played it and after it's already after dinner it's already like 6 or 7.
Rym: we'd be up at like 4.45 in the morning to start opening shit.
Scott: so I get this Mario 3 run upstairs and I play Mario 3 and then I go to fucking bed and then I wake up and maybe I can play like one level and then go to school.
Scott: yeah and I'm in school all day.
Scott: there's no.
Scott: Hanukkah doesn't cancel school or anything right in December it's cold and I'm in school all day just like.
Scott: gotta get home and fucking play Mario 3.
Scott: Jesus Christ what the hell am I doing here?
Rym: this is a problem.
Rym: yup our problem was like well I remember one year we got the Super Nintendo.
Rym: that was a big goddamn deal.
Rym: and the problem was we got every launch game too F-Zero, Mario yup, RPM Racing which is a truck game.
Rym: it was actually an okay game but we had to share it.
Scott: I mean only F-Zero and Mario are the ones you care about but we had to share it.
Scott: sure you can play Mario 2 people.
Rym: yeah but couldn't play F-Zero 2 people.
Rym: nope not the original F-Zero couldn't play pilot wings with 2 people.
Scott: oh right pilot wings.
Rym: and even worse.
Rym: later when we got the super scope there's only one of those.
Scott: you don't get 2 super scopes.
Scott: I mean we gotta say Genesis but Sonic 2. that was the one that came with Sonic 2 not the one that came with Sonic 1. it was the redesigned Genesis so someone could be Tails.
Rym: I guess I guess I guess that was a Christmas show.
Rym: it wasn't a Christmas special it was a Christmas show.
Rym: this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Rym: remember GeekNights is not one but 4 different shows SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience but unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night
Rym: and the Patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights in order for the amount of money they give us on the continuing basis are Alan Joyce, Rebecca Dunn, Nicholas Brando, Heidi McNichol, Amanda Duchette Construction Noises, Ivy Thay, MyStady.com, William Eisenroz, Jeremy Miner, Chris Reimer, and Thomas Hahn Christian Koontz, Rod Order Doesn't Matar, It's Only Important That First and Last Good God You Ok, Sherman Van Horl, Iggy Kid, Roy Lavelle, James David White, Rochelle Montanona, Superboy.
Rym: and then the winged Hussars arrived Aaron Cerise, Brian Fisher, Sailor Vista, Carl Hanratty, Famous Knock Knock Joe, Matthew Smith, Don Schleicher, Jared Thompson, Joshua Joestar, Tyler Eller, Sean Yeager, Sam Cordery, Clinton Walton, Ren from New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, Drew Openlander, Brian Cedroni, Kareniff, Redacted, Chris Midkiff, Chris Knox, Daniel Redman, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer, and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: We didn't do a Christmas special but we talked about Christmas.
Rym: We're thinking about doing a kind of Christmas special variety show.
Rym: I don't know if we'll just wait and plan it and do it next year, maybe we'll do it randomly over the next couple weeks, we'll figure it out.
Rym: But we've got some vague ideas.
Rym: That might be one of the things we spend a little bit of the Patreon money on down the road We might make a legit, cheesy Christmas special, because that might actually be fun, as well as a relatively constrained project, but anyway We're seriously on like six panels at MAGFest.
Rym: If you're at MAGFest, let's hang out, let's play games.
Rym: It's going to be awesome.
Rym: And now I leave you with Want to show old Santa Claus that I Believe.
Rym: Silent night The stars are bright The fields are white with snow Christmas trees are waiting Lights are turned down low Tinsel shells and tinsel bells reflect.
Rym: the Firelight's hue Seems to whisper softly.
Rym: There's just one thing to do.
Rym: I'm hanging up my stocking.
Rym: Tonight is Christmas Eve.
Rym: Want to show old Santa Claus that I Believe.
Rym: Want to see his reindeer Come dancing through the snow.
Rym: Hope their bells will wake me up so I will know What you get for Christmas?
Rym: Now I lay me down to sleep upon this joyful night.
Rym: Angels will watch over me until the morning light.