Rym: It's Tuesday June 7th 2016.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights tonight the grind.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: And also if you are hearing now from us that PAX West badges went on sale.
Rym: They're already gone.
Scott: I mean the thing is I mean this obviously every time they go on sale you have the same discussion on Twitter that you have Every time they go on sale.
Rym: right yeah in fact I almost want a catalog.
Rym: if the same people make the same arguments year after year I think they do.
Scott: it seems like they do anyway, but yeah just to to reiterate every you know what we say every year.
Scott: number one There's an article where they interviewed Robert coup and said everything that we always say.
Rym: I will link to it.
Rym: It's on geek wire because it's literally like Today.
Rym: everyone who tweeted at me It was like why don't they just X like?
Rym: there is literally an answer in this article where Robert coup is like listen We thought about that.
Rym: Here's why it doesn't work and People.
Scott: the main thing I want to address though is that some people were?
Scott: Scoffing or laughing at me for saying that I would quit my job To get packs tickets and go to packs.
Scott: well if my job said sorry we're not giving you vacation time for packs or if I?
Scott: The packs tickets went on sale during a meeting and I walked out and then they got mad at me I just give him the finger.
Scott: It's like he was doubting me, but it's like no.
Scott: There's what is the point?
Scott: I don't want to go to work.
Scott: the reason I go to work is so that I can do things like packs.
Scott: if you tell Me I can't go to packs.
Scott: There's no reason for me to be at work.
Scott: That's the reason I'm there.
Scott: So if you tell me I can't go I'm gonna quit the job first.
Rym: now at the same time it is at least fair To as some of the criticism pointed out to at least acknowledge that that is the privilege of the fact that we're wealthy tech.
Scott: guys If you can't go to packs period if you don't have this privilege packs is expensive Even if there are plenty of packs tickets and no one wanted them and you just get them.
Rym: so guys Here's the two tickets for four days.
Scott: for me right cost like three hundred dollars plus hotel nights.
Scott: for four days It's $200 a night for just a one bed hotel room plus get to Seattle.
Scott: right.
Scott: so this is already a multi-thousand dollar Endeavor just to go.
Scott: so if you can afford to go to packs in the first place Then you're already a very privileged individual, and that's not really.
Rym: in fact.
Rym: We talked about that at length because it's actually a kind of rough topic for people in the member that Why no one will game with you panel.
Rym: and we talked a little bit about how.
Rym: there's a lot of games like a lot high-end PC gaming.
Rym: unless you've got enough money to buy some fucking like giant video card you can't even come to the table.
Rym: Yeah, like that's the reality of the world it sucks.
Rym: But at the same time if you really want to go to a packs and prime so hard to go to guys pecs out Like pecs out is so cheap So easy to get tickets to.
Rym: the only things that are missing from packs out that you get in Seattle are Seattle itself.
Rym: I really like Seattle like there's stuff to do there like sales a really good place with lots of food and The expo hall is kind of baby, but you know what the expo hall is the least interesting part of packs.
Rym: Yeah, and Everything else at Pac South is 100% as good as PAX Prime only yellow.
Rym: Yeah, like the tabletop is actually better than packs.
Rym: prime because you can actually get a seat.
Rym: It takes a couple days for the badges to sell out so you can just like no It did there did.
Scott: I don't think they sold out at all.
Scott: They but they're on sale now.
Rym: I think Friday and Saturday matters.
Rym: Let me see.
Scott: Let me see anything is sold out.
Scott: I think you just buy a ticket.
Rym: I'm gonna check right now cuz I had.
Rym: I've never bought a ticket to any packs.
Rym: at least that I needed to.
Rym: Yeah, you can totally just buy bad guys.
Scott: I won whenever the demand is way lower than the supply.
Rym: So guys Pac South 2017 go buy a badge now.
Rym: It's in the end of January.
Rym: It's a pack.
Scott: even if you live and say like Portland, Oregon, right where you'd slut me you could drive to Seattle Maybe and cheaply you're gonna have to pay to park your car and the hotel.
Scott: It will literally be cheaper for you to go to Pac South might be more expensive to go to Pac South from Portland.
Rym: Cuz I tried to go to Portland after packs to lecture that other thing.
Scott: I tried to think of the place that was closest to Seattle, but you still needed a hotel.
Rym: But seriously, we live in New York City.
Rym: It is cheaper for us to go to Pac South in San Antonio fucking Texas than it is to go to Pac's East in Boston.
Rym: Yep, like they are very close to each other in terms of actual total cost Just go.
Rym: that is terrifying.
Scott: but Pac South is the seat especially all you people with the sour grapes about not getting tickets to prime.
Scott: Just go south.
Rym: No, no one got tickets to prime.
Rym: No one.
Scott: Yeah, no one not all the thousands of people that are gonna be there.
Rym: No, cuz there's PAX West.
Rym: there is no packs, bro.
Rym: But here's the other secret and I'm not gonna put this in the text even though it's common public knowledge.
Rym: I feel like all these reward people who pay attention a little bit.
Rym: guys if you really really want to go to packs and For some reason like it literally is a many hundred dollar markup to buy a badge from the few scalpers who have them Buy a badge to PAX dev.
Rym: It's only 400 bucks.
Rym: And if you're a student at a university It's like 250 bucks.
Rym: And if you buy a badge to PAX dev you have the right to buy a four-day pass to PAX Prime Even if it's sold out right because they basically allocate a PAX Prime badge per PAX dev badge.
Scott: Of course, you need a legit reason to go to packs day.
Rym: Yeah, no wait, I mean you.
Rym: if you're a student if you have any interest in making games you can go.
Rym: I mean, I've gone to all but one of the packs devs.
Rym: They're really really fun.
Rym: Like I like going but the only danger of going to PAX dev is Seriously, like you can't fucking talk about it.
Rym: Because if you reveal the things that aren't pretty like allowed to be revealed from PAX dev because it's sort of a closed Dev is a secret place.
Scott: right if you go there if you reveal any information that you learn there to the public or the press
Rym: without permission from the people who Gave you the knowledge that
Scott: you're not supposed to you Run the risk of being banned from all packs is forever, which is like the worst thing in the universe.
Rym: I'd rather go to jail for a moderate to short amount of time then.
Rym: But otherwise like PAX dev is just like a really focused packs like imagine a packs That there's still people.
Scott: the problem with PAX dev though Is that even if you save money compared to the price of scalped prime badges?
Rym: You have to pay for those extra two hotel nights But if you're one of those people who lives kind of local then it's actually not that bad.
Scott: Oh, if you're if you're local that man, you should be going right?
Scott: I guess I take more days off of work but I mean I'm quitting my job to go to pack.
Rym: and well you might not want to go to dev like if you're really don't care about making games and Money is an issue really like.
Rym: don't go to PAX dev because if you don't have a student discount it is like 400 bucks Yeah, but but still that's way cheaper than like normal professional conference.
Scott: All right, so packs badges one and sell yet again.
Scott: Let's move on.
Rym: Yep, but it's interesting because literally this morning in a serendipitous moment There's an article an op-ed on the New York Times that I it opened.
Rym: I opened it by the Hamilton guy Yeah, and I opened it because I was thinking packs badges go on sale any day.
Rym: as you saw on the forum I was trying to predict when they would go on sale.
Scott: Well, there's also.
Scott: a few days ago former Ticketmaster CEO also former executive at Twitter wrote a big article about the same topic.
Scott: Yeah in a different news outlet.
Rym: So there's two reasons I bring this up.
Rym: one It's called stop the bots from killing Broadway and basically take every complaint everyone has about the badges for packs and All the things that Mike and Jerry want to do with packs because they don't want to reward people who have more money as much As they can.
Rym: it's the exact same article just about Broadway and about Hamilton and It's sort of a reminder to all the kids who were super butter about Packs or Dragon Con or New York Comic Con or all these conventions where it's hard to get badges.
Rym: Welcome to every other fandom on earth.
Scott: Well, I think there's a more underlying problem here.
Scott: Right that maybe may not be true.
Scott: I have no evidence to you know, it just seems like it may be true, right?
Scott: Yeah, and that we've arrived in a society.
Scott: We're going towards a situation where many many more things are Abundant and some things are infinitely abundant at least in the privileged United States society.
Rym: Yeah, like if I want to listen to a particular song.
Rym: Legality aside it's infinitely abundant.
Rym: I can just go download it, right?
Scott: so first of all, people are saving money not buying a bunch of CDs and stuff, right and People, you know, there's there's certain experiences that have become so common that they've lost worth, right?
Scott: So I think that people who are the kind of people who pay for experiences are over there, you know They're more there.
Scott: They're Overvaluing right.
Scott: you're overvaluing something like a convention or a concert right or a sporting event.
Rym: You make a good point.
Rym: think about this.
Rym: if I spent say I used to spend a thousand dollars a year buying music CDs Cuz I'm really into music and then I just start pirating now.
Scott: I've got a thousand dollars a year Even if you know this a it might be that you have more money But it be.
Scott: it might be because of just the way people's lives are.
Scott: so internet that when there is a high-quality In-person thing that just the value of that in terms of what it gives you in your life seems like greater, right?
Scott: You're willing to pay more for something like that because you know, it's like yeah, right, you know.
Scott: people look at packs like the concerts are cool, you know are Better than they used to be or people want to go to them more than they used to just because of the way our culture Is now right, you know.
Scott: So because of that there's more demand for them than there was before.
Scott: people are more interested in Concerts now than they were then.
Rym: I think there's even another thing drawing demand or because we've been going to pack since 2008 And back then you could just buy a badge like way late in the game Like you could just show up at the door and buy a bag.
Rym: Yeah, we didn't go early enough like oh six oh seven because we couldn't yeah We couldn't afford to or or we weren't willing or able to make the sacrifices necessary to go.
Rym: This is one of my few regrets.
Scott: mistakes are made.
Rym: I should have at least gone to o7.
Scott: I could have made it work could have gone to o7 for sure.
Scott: We probably could have even gone to o5 o6 if we really wanted.
Rym: You know what if we'd stopped going to like Otakon earlier, we definitely could have done the packs like earlier.
Rym: Yeah, but there's I think there might be another thing going on because Hyperion, you know positive this problem and a bunch of other books We've read over the years like culture books even positive problem.
Rym: Remember, there's one culture book where there's an event that happened a long time ago and the light from the explosions of that event Is about to hit this big orbital.
Rym: so there's gonna be a concert in at the orbital and sure you could do the VR and like see the concert and it'd be Totally fine like over the culture equivalent of the super space internet, but because it's only going to happen once ever People suddenly decided they put value on for real being there and there's only so much space like even the culture can't conquer basic physics.
Rym: So this post-scarcity society redevelops currency just for this one concert mmm, and The internet, you know, like when we used to go to PAX is like even game.
Rym: like most gamers I talked to had never heard of PAX Even in like oh 809 even 2010 like PAX East.
Rym: a lot of people lived in Boston Didn't know PAX was there but were otherwise gamers.
Rym: I feel like the internet being more ubiquitous and like Generation Z or whatever like getting old enough to really use the internet like the younger kids.
Rym: They just know what's up.
Rym: Like they look online and they see Oh markiplier is a guy I'm a fan of and oh, he's at this thing packs and then they learn about packs.
Rym: So there's way more eyeballs independent of if the demand from any individual eyeball went up.
Rym: like think about all the people to this day who are anime fans who live in fucking Baltimore and Don't know that the best and biggest anime con except for anime.
Rym: Boston in terms of best in the country is basically like down the street From them.
Rym: It's in DC now will be Anyway, yep.
Rym: You got any news?
Scott: I do have a news about something we saw at PAX Which is radio ball in a deep and distant future.
Scott: Finally, this game is announced for being released on July 12th.
Scott: I got missed a mistake.
Scott: it.
Scott: I thought it was June 12th, which is this Sunday.
Scott: I got all excited, but no, it's a month from Sunday.
Scott: Yeah, July 12.
Scott: So we're gonna go to Connecticut.
Scott: We're gonna come back and then on Tuesday It'll be on Steam for $9.99.
Scott: is gonna be the price to play video ball.
Scott: That is a great price.
Scott: I'm gonna be buying and playing that game on July 12th.
Scott: So look forward to it.
Rym: Scratch is so many inches that I've had for a long time.
Scott: because we should have a streaming video ball party.
Rym: We should work.
Rym: I mean you.
Rym: we just form a team and just try to compete.
Scott: We need a third person for our video ball team.
Rym: Let's get good and then we'll host tryouts for who can be our third.
Scott: we or we can just play two people.
Scott: team.
Scott: that there's You know one on one two and two and three on three.
Scott: Yeah, I think we wanted three on three I feel like is the real mode.
Rym: We did that Atari game design panel at a bunch of packs as in other places and we've been I've been really thinking a lot About these like simple like very direct competition ortho games like Atari style and I feel like that genre really needs a huge Renaissance for just starting to get like video ball is one of Many games
Scott: she knows even out yet.
Scott: I know dude release that.
Rym: yeah I mean, it's interesting how like I don't pay attention to certain games.
Rym: But so like there's these specific games shapes and beats and video ball that every packs I've seen the actual hella is coming out rare very very soon like oh man days away.
Scott: This is the cyberpunk anime bartender simulation visual novel type game.
Rym: Yep Oh my god, but these games I see him every year every packs and I walk by and I go up to these people and I'm Like dude, just give me the game.
Rym: I don't even care if it's done.
Rym: Just I'll give you money.
Rym: How much money is do you want already pre-ordered?
Rym: Yeah the trouble is because my main news is that overwatch is also out and And So there is I think every single person I know except me is playing this game, right?
Scott: Holy shit every person I know every nerdy friend.
Scott: I have even like my sister is playing this game, right?
Scott: It's like every single person.
Scott: I didn't you know, I knew this was gonna be a big game when it was You know having boobs and Blizzard was making a tf2 type game.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: a lot of people were confusing this and battle-born because they look very superficially.
Scott: Anyway, but like I knew the Blizzard is making a tf2 type game.
Scott: I knew it was coming out soon.
Scott: I actually got the the beta for like.
Scott: there's a beta weekend, which I got.
Scott: I download installed it and didn't play it.
Scott: And then like I knew it was gonna be a hit because it's a Blizzard game, you know.
Scott: But it is a like the biggest hit I've ever seen like so even when tf2 came out.
Scott: It wasn't like Everyone was.
Scott: this is literally I do not know any nerds who are not playing this.
Rym: So it's interesting because except me team fortress 2 was supposed to be the successor to.
Rym: you know I'm fortress the throne of team fortress team fortress classic weapons factory Mega TF like that kind of game real game.
Rym: team fortress 2 was supposed to be like the modern version of that and it was Except you go back and listen to our show about it.
Rym: It was kind of baby mode.
Rym: It actually wasn't that fun Unless you like.
Rym: even if you got like if you got really good the game was just not fun anymore.
Scott: Yeah, they put way.
Scott: they put all the effort on the aesthetics and pretty much got the best aesthetics in a shooter ever But sacrificed the actual game and then they went down Hat Road.
Rym: and but it wasn't just Hat Road It was game affecting hats right before Hat Road.
Scott: It was bad.
Rym: but then once the Hat Road that was like the last nail in the coffin and I remember this rush where everyone got really into It partly because I'd been talking up this game for as long as it was possibly in development.
Rym: Remember that site TF to like Rym weights.
Rym: Yep, every event in history Rym weights.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So it finally came out and it just was deeply unsatisfying and had all these problems and within about a month I was just done with it.
Rym: Like I just didn't care anymore.
Scott: It's an overwatch seems to be significantly more skill based.
Scott: So it doesn't seem like it's at the level of like actual super quake, but well, actually it's pretty close.
Rym: So here's my.
Scott: are you flying around like ridiculously?
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Yeah, it was like quake one fast.
Rym: It's about as fast as quake two Really?
Scott: Yeah, how are all these people playing it?
Scott: Are they like just like?
Rym: most people are fucking awful at it?
Scott: Are they just like dying instantly to people who are like going so fast.
Scott: They can't hit them?
Rym: the beauty is shot it by people and so many people are playing and It's six on six And the matchmaking is really good.
Scott: Blizzard is the only people have good matchmaking like.
Rym: I'm Legitimately impressed with the matchmaking and how close these games end up.
Scott: Yeah, Blizzard is the only company with decent matchmaking technology.
Rym: So all that together means that there is room for people like the skill level of people.
Scott: Oh, you're never.
Scott: you're never in a match with any gods that are gonna crush you.
Rym: You might be in them occasionally But it's pretty rare.
Rym: and because it's not like the old days where a match was an hour long like this shit ends real quick If one team is just that much better and then they rematch you so you're not playing with them again.
Rym: So if I had to compare it to one of the games that it succeeded it is actually closest to weapons factory.
Scott: It's like a million different things to do.
Scott: Yes, and you have to bind like a hundred keys on your keyboard.
Rym: So remember how Team Fortress 2 distilled that down to like.
Rym: every class has like a few weapons and a power.
Rym: Yeah, this one distilled it even further.
Rym: But unlike Team Fortress 2 where the powers are all kind of samey and bullshitty The powers here are way different like dune level different.
Scott: So in mega t so it's like a. it's like MOBA where you have your four Yep, so here's an example.
Rym: in old weapons factory Which was the height of that genre weapons factory?
Rym: for quick to?
Rym: Weapons factory quake 3 was slow and kind of crappy and like lot like people went back to quake 2.
Scott: What?
Scott: no the only weapons factory is the quake 2 one.
Scott: There's no there was no other weapons factory.
Rym: Well, there was a the the quick grappling hook.
Rym: the quake 3 weapons factory was made by the same people who made the fourth Supposed Indiana Jones movie and all those Terminator movies after the second one and I think they tried to make some matrix movies.
Rym: It's really a shame that those guys all died anyway, so in weapons factory Here's some of the classes and then I'll compare them to overwatch classes.
Rym: There was the gunner.
Rym: the gunner was super slow.
Scott: Yeah, didn't you have like the crazy like minigun?
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Now the gunner was a woman like.
Rym: the models are all way different.
Rym: It was this big buff woman.
Rym: She had a chaingun.
Rym: Well, she had three chainguns.
Rym: cuz this game had you had like a different weapons factory right different ammo in each one.
Rym: One chaingun is that you can run at normal speed and it's the normal chaingun.
Rym: one chaingun fired like did twice as much damage But you're real slow.
Rym: and it also made a bunch of like lens flaring effects.
Rym: So people would like see where you were and then one of them was crazy ridiculous bullshit strong But you couldn't move while you were firing it.
Rym: They all that class also had a pod.
Rym: you could stick on a wall and when you stuck it there It's shot out a laser as far as it could and just sat there.
Rym: if anyone touched that laser Instant death.
Rym: and that laser disappeared after like 30 seconds or so.
Scott: So it's like it's a long time.
Rym: Yeah, but then there were other things but to like widely disparate powers.
Rym: So there's a character in overwatch called bastion.
Rym: He's a robot.
Rym: He has a regular machine gun.
Rym: when he's running around one of his powers is shift into now I am just a turret mode much like the gun I see.
Rym: Yep, but his other power is he can heal himself Instead of shooting but you can't shoot while healing yourself.
Scott: Nope.
Scott: It's a hide some way.
Rym: But meanwhile, there's another character.
Rym: Remember that laser.
Rym: so symmetra is a character who has like this weird close-range weapon.
Rym: She can leave little turrets around that stop that hit people and slow them down and do increasing damage over time like tribes - she can Also throw down a teleporter.
Scott: Okay, that's a tf2 thing.
Rym: Yeah, so in weapons factory the engineer could build a sentry and a teleporter.
Rym: in this game There's one character who can make sentries and another one who makes teleport.
Rym: Yeah, and they so basically it's like they took all the core ability made a lot more character choices, right?
Rym: I mean, well, there's actually fewer character choices than weapons factory.
Scott: Really when I see pictures of overwatch, it's like a hundred freaking characters about the same compared to like tf2 Where there's only like a handful?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well tf2 is way limited.
Rym: weapons factory had more like weapons.
Scott: You think are they gonna keep making more characters like a MOBA until eventually there's a screen with like a million rectangles?
Rym: I don't think so.
Rym: They have said it's never gonna be pay to win.
Scott: when you play competitive Do you have to like draft characters like a MOBA?
Scott: you can you can match?
Rym: So basically each team just picks their team.
Rym: It tells you if you're the attacker of the defense and show you what the other people are picking.
Rym: No But you can change intramatch.
Scott: So it's like oh you can change in the middle of the game Yeah, so when you're dead, you just be like, nope.
Rym: I'm gonna be diva now.
Scott: Okay, so like any?
Scott: yeah, okay Yeah, so can you let yourself on purpose to switch?
Rym: Ah, you might have to go do it in the environment I don't know.
Rym: if there's a Yeah, you can fall.
Rym: there's no falling damage, which is more like quake, but you can just jump off the edge.
Rym: You can jump off the edges.
Rym: Okay The maps have a lot of nooks and crannies and nonsense and they're real big.
Rym: Like.
Rym: basically that tribes big no, but they're like weapons factory big if not bigger.
Rym: They're bigger than counter-strike Yeah, yeah, but like in weapons factory the marine had like a grappling hook to fly around Rockets and Could leave these little mini centuries.
Rym: so they took the centuries away gave that to another character.
Rym: The rocket character can just fucking fly like crazy has concussion rocket.
Scott: It's a rocket jumper.
Rym: just actually fly so you can.
Rym: you can tribes to fly and you have a boost rocket jump.
Rym: That has a cooldown time and you have a concussion grenade.
Rym: You can also use the rocket jump with if you really wanted to and you just have rockets.
Scott: All right, so they do give you a lot of stuff to work with.
Rym: So you you have the same almost the same number of options as Team Fortress 2 but they're all so different and so Satisfying to play that it is the closest game to this I can possibly describe is weapons factory.
Rym: This is literally the successor to weapons factory for quake 2 wholly and thoroughly So.
Rym: I play it every day for at least a few hours and my friends list is huge.
Rym: I can always get like six friends to play together the boys like.
Rym: everything just works great.
Scott: Everyone's playing.
Rym: Even if I play by myself I use like I'd say about 70% of the games I get into just by myself are good.
Rym: And the way?
Rym: the matchmaking world?
Scott: I think there's some things I've heard.
Scott: for example, they're aggressively banning cheaters.
Rym: So that's like yeah if you get so if you get caught cheating, you're just banned forever period.
Rym: you're banned for life And they keep information about you.
Scott: So if it looks like people have tried all sorts of ways to like like buy the game again And they just keep getting rebanned no matter what people have tried.
Scott: I've read that somebody I don't know if this is true somebody rebought the game with a different account and a different credit card and a different address and put it on a different computer right and Then they went through like a VPN so that they wouldn't know where the person was playing from and after playing for a few minutes They were rebanned.
Scott: I don't know how that's technologically possible, but good job Blizzard.
Rym: So yeah, they are so serious about anti-cheat and They seem like they're also pretty see like while they don't have the same like counter-strike thing yet.
Rym: We're like I get people banned from counter-strike all the time.
Rym: But it is like if you make a group and play by default.
Rym: You're in a voice chat just with your friends and you have to opt into the team chat.
Rym: So it's like our four friends and then you go in as a group.
Rym: It'll find two randos or group of two and stick them in your team and then start the match.
Rym: Everything about this game is great and there is room for people who have never played an FPS before.
Scott: that Yeah, cuz you're gonna get match makes with other garbage players like, you know, everyone is.
Rym: oh so even better.
Rym: It includes a mode where you can practice against a eyes.
Rym: includes the mode You can just walk around the maps and check it out.
Rym: It includes a mode where there's a special map that has a bunch of enemies doing different things.
Rym: Like it's like a giant playground where you can just practice.
Rym: And it has a tutorial like the original half-life 1 tutorial that literally teaches you how to have to walk.
Scott: Yeah to aim tracer runs on screens.
Rym: Like I'm gonna run over to the right.
Rym: now watch me.
Rym: You're not looking at me.
Rym: Look at me.
Rym: turn use your mouse and look at me.
Rym: This game is so good.
Rym: Now it's it's good because people who don't have like.
Rym: I have this history with games like weapons factory Where I was kind of obsessed with them and this is what a team fortress 2 was supposed to be for me.
Rym: So I'm like prime.
Rym: this is like it's like if someone made a new advanced wars Rym just starts playing this game But people who have never played FPS is before are getting into this game equally strongly.
Rym: That says a lot.
Rym: this game is Possibly the best FPS in the genre since weapons factory.
Rym: for quick to know.
Scott: there have been a lot of competition.
Rym: really Well, also the people who may also tribes to the people who made it said straight-up games like action quick to where they're like primary Inspiration sure like they know what's up.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, you know, anyone who's making an FPS knows about these People because they don't follow up on what they write.
Scott: what they know right is they?
Scott: you know They think they're smarter than the.
Scott: you know, the old good stuff It's like.
Scott: no, all you had to literally do is take action quick to and change the graphics to make the modern.
Scott: You don't have to do anything else, but yeah, we'll clean it up a little bit.
Rym: I think they know better like an action quick to or in a weapons factory Like.
Rym: you had a lot of options that were just like way inside the Pareto frontier like not worth using.
Rym: Yeah, and this game is everything is extremely well balanced characters are hard counters for each other And I'm gonna play it pretty much right after Scott leaves the apartment.
Rym: In fact, our friends came out this weekend.
Rym: They brought their computers so we could land party play the game all weekend.
Rym: And we did.
Scott: you could have just played from their house.
Rym: Well land party.
Rym: What's different also how you get just hard to go a few days without oh the other thing.
Rym: Even my old ass computer runs it fine like a surface pro for you can play.
Scott: I mean blizzard games run and everything.
Rym: That's how they do right even runs on Mac But like this seems to even run on my laptop.
Rym: like this game runs real graphics down Yeah, but not that not as far down as you think.
Rym: it's kind of like Counter-Strike Go where it's.
Rym: they take a lot of shortcuts in the rendering So it looks great, but they cheat to make sure it'll work on your video card.
Rym: Yeah things of the day Cuz.
Rym: I'm so into overwatch.
Rym: So there's a thing it does Where after every game like one you can vote for people like commend them like you did a good job like it shows like the four Top players based on various heuristics.
Rym: I mostly vote up whoever was being like support or healing or like help me out.
Rym: But they also do a play of the game where the game tries to Algorithmically decide what like the craziest or most important moment in the victory or whatever happened in the game was and it's like Overwatch play of the game and sometimes it shows a really epic moment.
Rym: Sometimes it shows me as Trobjorn literally just dying and then I'm laying there dead while my turret kills a bunch of people.
Scott: Right, so it detected that you got a bunch of kills at that moment.
Scott: So I thought that was the play of the game.
Scott: But really it was your turret getting a bunch of and I was just literally laying.
Scott: it shows you because you're the one who was Doing the killing and the cameras too dumb.
Scott: the camera should focus on the people getting killed not the person doing the kill.
Scott: Well, we'll see.
Rym: cuz the thing is it also.
Scott: camera also should try to get the killer and kill II in the in the same.
Rym: Well, it's even more than that.
Rym: You don't want to necessarily have it always be whoever did the most killing in a clever way because sometimes the play of the game Is well, it's a kills per in a short burst Five kills within like ten seconds.
Rym: Sometimes the play of the game must like
Scott: someone
Rym: use their resurrection power cuz like the team got wiped except for the healer and they Like raise the whole team on the spot like at a critical moment and then everyone's there and they win like there's the moment that won the game or like the play of the day.
Rym: basically and It blizzard appears to be because the algorithm seems to be changing.
Rym: They I think they're putting a lot of effort and trying to tune that thing to where it'll find if not the best play at least always something that's very satisfying to watch and Satisfied.
Rym: like.
Rym: I got to tell you it's pretty rare because you know, there's 12 people.
Rym: It's rare that you are the play of the game But when it happens you feel real cool unless it's something dumb like you're lying Like I'm lying there dead in my turds doing all the work which has happened a few times.
Rym: So the other thing that's happened is that people are using the play of the game Aesthetic to make wonderful memes like there's one guy that the demolition guy like there's grenades and things everywhere.
Rym: His power is this he basically spins up this Mad Max tire full of explosives and then drives it off to blow up on somebody.
Rym: So people made an overwatch play of the game that shows him like ha ha ha and then it cuts to a real clip of A monster truck tire just like rolling down the highway and then eventually hitting someone.
Rym: so the meme of an overwatch player and then a real-life event that somehow evokes that player is Something that has been thoroughly amusing me of late.
Scott: Hmm so It's summer which means and also in video game land these steam summer sales coming up soon.
Scott: You know get your Gabe end videos ready.
Scott: Yeah, it's a money raining down.
Scott: But here on steam There's actually a game that's on sale right now that you can buy.
Scott: this game cost you 54 cents because it's usually 99 cents And it's 45% off.
Scott: And this game is called summer sale.
Scott: Experience summer sale without losing money while you lose 45 54 cents.
Scott: But yeah, it's the game that simulates the steam summer sale.
Scott: It's a candy box, but 54 cents.
Scott: I say award this person for their great humor.
Rym: It's funny how it took me Several seconds when Scott told me to click on the link.
Rym: I'm looking at it.
Rym: I'm like steam summer sale, but is this just the same?
Rym: something like it took me a minute to realize?
Scott: Oh, it's on steam steam page.
Scott: It's a steam game page for a game called summer sales.
Scott: No dog.
Scott: It's steam summer sale.
Rym: Okay, what took my brain a minute to figure that out and then it was legit funny even after I explained it to you.
Scott: Could you click on the thing at the day?
Scott: Like you still might be like.
Rym: So in the meta moment, the book club book will be Oryx and Craig by Margaret Atwood.
Rym: I am plowing through the last wheel of time book Scott.
Rym: I know everything about that tower.
Scott: now Tell me all the tower stuff.
Scott: No, tell me no tell me the tower It's.
Rym: it's actually real complicated and how complicated could it be?
Scott: Oh this snake people.
Scott: they have powers.
Rym: It would take me about 20 minutes to actually explain what the deal is.
Scott: I got time.
Scott: It's just less time than it take me to read 14 fucking books.
Rym: It didn't take me long to read those books less than 20 minutes.
Rym: But that but don't you also want to know about like the Dragons?
Scott: there used to be dragons.
Rym: Well, what about them?
Scott: They're dragons.
Scott: They have wings.
Scott: They breathe fire.
Rym: What's up with the taint?
Rym: Like what is that?
Rym: Why taint?
Rym: What do you say?
Rym: is that voice?
Rym: and Wren said really lose Theron?
Rym: Yeah Let's just say that a bunch of stuff went down.
Scott: isn't he just like inhabited by the spirit of lose Theron or whatever?
Rym: It's just the book series.
Rym: The only way to act like it's literally faster to read the books than to read the wiki.
Scott: Yeah, but it's not faster than the 20-minute explanation.
Rym: Yeah, but that would just be to explain the tower.
Rym: Anyway, I'm gonna be done with those books.
Rym: I'll know everything there is possibly to know except I'm not going to read.
Scott: I was at the bookstore and saw a supplementary appendix type.
Rym: Yeah, so I was about to say I'm not going to read that Because I looked into it and there are apparently some inconsistencies.
Rym: if you look at that in addition to the books and Also, I don't care about the actual power ranking of all the guys to die literally numbered from most powerful to least powerful Literally every single one in the entire series.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: There are a lot of them.
Rym: Let us say But yeah, Oryx and Craig Margaret Atwood though with the way the American politics are going I feel like the Handmaid's Tale might be a more relevant one to read.
Rym: But we'll do Oryx and Craig because that's what we said we'll do.
Rym: Kinetic count is coming up that stay tuned for that.
Scott: That's actually scarily soon.
Rym: Yeah Otherwise, hopefully we'll see you at PAX Prime If you're cool, yeah.
Rym: And if not, seriously buy tickets to PAX South like we'll be there.
Rym: PAX South is great and you can just buy them.
Rym: now You just go click and you'll have badges.
Rym: You can just go click and have a hotel.
Rym: That's like a one-minute walk away from the convention.
Scott: It'll be warm.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So if there's one thing that I complained about a lot At least up until about a decade ago when I didn't give it yet anymore is grinding in games Like I have.
Rym: there was a time in my life when I actually think my stupid kid brain enjoyed it.
Rym: yep, like leveling up in Final Fantasy 1 when I was in elementary school felt like it was a very productive thing and like I would really Like like I'd like I'm gonna go I'm gonna fucking get that silver sword and I'd be walking back and forth Fight like two ogres go to the inn.
Scott: Pokemon Pokemon was the turning point for me.
Scott: Like when I started playing Pokemon, I was like all grind and I didn't even notice it was a problem.
Scott: It's just like we.
Scott: this game is amazing.
Scott: And then before I beat it, I was like Walking back and forth back and forth killing Pokemon back and forth back and forth kill a Pokemon and it was like this sucks Fuck this.
Scott: Yep, and that's what I you know, I realized.
Rym: so we started thinking about that because it's it seems like a really simple topic.
Rym: But if you really broaden it What is grinding?
Rym: because that actually means very different things depending on the kind of game you're playing.
Scott: Yeah, there's so many other grinds out there besides the.
Scott: you know, most people JRPG grind.
Scott: Yeah, most people just think of the RPG grind like you.
Scott: you do the same thing over and over again Usually mindless tasks in order to you know increase numbers in order to do other things right like Fire Emblem.
Rym: You can be clever and beat the game low-level or just kill a bunch of people and the numbers will be high and then You don't have to solve the puzzle.
Rym: You just have the rabbit girl and the night guy just marry each other and then they single-handedly kill literally fucking everyone in the game.
Rym: Yeah, didn't even make anyone have kids because kids are useless like.
Scott: but there's such a wide variety of grinds out there.
Scott: Right, there are grinds of the candy box variety where you just wait you do literally nothing.
Scott: It's not like you have to keep fighting bad guys and do random encounters Like you.
Rym: there's there's the alternate candy box grind where you actually have to keep clicking As much as you want.
Scott: even less mindless then.
Scott: it's even more mindless than an F in our JRPG combat.
Scott: It's like you literally you just click you just do some Completely manual no thought task over and over again, but there's also some grinds where you actually do a complex test, right?
Scott: Think about something like a rune factory or a harvest moon.
Scott: It's like every day You got to check the plants and walk around town and maybe go on an adventure and you got to do all these things.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: in a more reason Pokemon the third time all my berries were dead.
Rym: I just fuck it.
Rym: I never grew a berry again, right?
Scott: It's like there's so many things you have to do some of which require like actual thought and like planning out your garden Like what are you gonna plant where and when?
Scott: and like.
Rym: this is actually a lot of stuff to do But the planning is the only thing that matters.
Rym: the doing is mine, right?
Scott: But it's like but then you have to push all these buttons and you have to do it Oh every single day of the game because the game has days right?
Scott: It's like there's a complex task.
Scott: It just takes a long time To do all these things and that's how you progress is by you know Sticking to do you know having discipline and keeping doing this thing over and over again.
Rym: Where most people seem to get really mad or at least start to have opinions about grinding other than just like why'd you do?
Rym: Your stupid grind and don't shame me in my mindless entertainment is with MMOs.
Rym: Because at least in a JRPG like if you like to grind you just grind.
Rym: if you don't like to grind you just cheat And skip it and who cares?
Rym: but in an MMO You have to grind in order to get better in order to level up.
Rym: But by you grinding you now become more powerful than other people.
Scott: But you had to spend time and effort or at least so someone else for example pays money to do To do because I level up instead of spending time.
Scott: That's not fair.
Scott: I had to spend time Yep.
Scott: Now if it's a non-competitive, it's like did you enjoy what you did?
Scott: Yeah, but then don't.
Scott: why do you even fuck about what other people did?
Rym: Yep Cuz I like it like Borderlands is even a better example of this.
Rym: Borderlands is a single-player game or a like local friend or remote friend co-op game.
Rym: Yet if you want to play at the same level as your friends You literally have to grind just so the numbers are arbitrarily at the same level or it's not fun.
Rym: And if you choose not to either the game sucks for you or it sucks for your friends.
Rym: and when people suggested Why don't you let people just pick their level?
Rym: The amount of butthurt coming from people who thought that was somehow unfair to them on the internet was ludicrous.
Rym: Right, I suspect that overlaps heavily with people who like ready player one, but I digress.
Scott: so so why does?
Scott: why is grinding a thing?
Scott: Right.
Scott: So here's the deal.
Scott: Sometimes when you play a game, right?
Scott: Let's say you go out and you play Soccer, right?
Scott: You play soccer you.
Scott: the more you play soccer You get better at it, right?
Rym: There's an edge.
Rym: Well, there's a touch case But this varies a lot.
Scott: this isn't like a guarantee to get better, right?
Scott: I mean, there's plenty of kids out there playing soccer like and they're super into it and There's all.
Scott: they're not becoming like fucking Ronaldo, right?
Scott: Even the professionals They're not.
Scott: you know.
Scott: It's like how many kids out there playing hockey and how many of them are Wayne Gretzky?
Rym: Well, I think none of them.
Rym: like I ski and I always get better.
Rym: Emily started skiing after me And she'd continuously got better at a pretty steady rate but but I've known people who have skied as long as me and Basically hit this plateau and literally never got better, right?
Scott: There's a people seem to have a limit that they hit to where they can't get better without doing something different.
Scott: Maybe they need extra help or more alert.
Scott: They hit, you know limits where without something extra mixing things up They can't improve.
Scott: even with more practice people seem to also get better at different rates.
Scott: there are two people who start doing the same thing at the same exact time like two kids take piano lessons at the same time and After a week later They've practiced the same amount and one of them can play twinkle twinkle little star and the other one still can't.
Rym: well Scott that happened.
Rym: It was in two ways.
Rym: Like we both got Street Fighter 5 You played it a little more than me and then a month later video wasn't the same amount of practice.
Rym: Yeah But because I put a little bit less practice in that just snowball now was Fox and then the opposite.
Rym: remember we both bought Harmonicas and then a month later.
Rym: I was like to turn around.
Scott: you were like and that's - I didn't practice Because I had no discipline.
Scott: well, okay, I didn't want to do it So I didn't enjoy doing it.
Rym: and then you just got you got to mesmerize by that cool guy with his video.
Scott: At least it was only five bucks.
Scott: Yeah ever cost anyway Right.
Scott: So when you're playing a video game, right say like Street Fighter, right?
Scott: If you want to get better at Street Fighter guile doesn't level up.
Scott: You have to level up.
Scott: It's the same as playing soccer or tennis, right?
Scott: You have to get better at it.
Scott: You the human being right has to get better at the game.
Scott: So some people based on their skill level They might not be a person who's good at something like Street Fighter or because Street Fighter is fucking Impenetrable.
Rym: with all this nonsense and no good tutorials follow Daryl Surratt on Twitter if you want to see some details of that lately.
Rym: Right, you can't.
Scott: you just can't get better without learning secret information that even the pros can't answer my fucking questions that I have for Them right about the game Shit like that.
Scott: So, you know you get frustrated with something like that when you play say a JRPG.
Scott: It doesn't matter who you are.
Scott: It doesn't matter what your skill level is.
Scott: Right, as long as you're at this minimum level of confidence Which is pretty much any human being who's literate and knows how to use a controller, which is everybody I know pretty much.
Scott: if you just keep playing you don't get the human being you doesn't improve at all Right, but your character in the game There's.
Rym: the numbers just fucking go up and the illusion you of progress.
Scott: you feel as if you you get the same emotional feelings that you that in satisfaction and gratification you get from Actually getting better and achieving mastery at something without actually achieving mastery anything.
Scott: It's like practice that's guaranteed to work and guaranteed to always make you better.
Rym: Oh, I think it was.
Rym: I think it was Dave Riley on fast karate But he because he was talking about ready player one which is why I referenced it before and he pointed out that ready player one is almost like a celebration of Someone who spent their life like.
Rym: instead of someone who spent their life like getting good at weapons factory or tennis It's someone who spent their life getting good in quotes at grinding out potions in Final Fantasy 11.
Rym: Mm-hmm And like.
Rym: that's the kind of person who is into that book because it's the illusion of progress But actually it's just a candy box in practice Right.
Scott: So if you make a game like this the game will be really satisfying to a lot of people because you know They play it they're doing some kind of thing that is somewhat fun and interesting But they keep getting rewarded for what they do like a rat in a you know, a Skinner box constantly getting bits of cheese,
Rym: right?
Rym: It's like actually we give them cheese and a non constant rate.
Rym: They'll act even more crazy for it, right?
Scott: I mean, it's like that, you know and it's like.
Scott: it's like hey, you're fighting all these, you know Skags and scag gold scag.
Scott: But if you do that enough eventually you get like cheese in the form of crazy ridiculous weapons And your level goes up and now you feel super powerful.
Scott: But really all it means is that skags change into a different model in a different part of the map But you're still doing the same fucking thing.
Scott: It's just the numbers are bigger and it looks cooler.
Rym: now There's.
Rym: this is where already.
Rym: this is why I like.
Rym: doing this as a panel or a show is already sort of complex single-player versus multiplayer.
Rym: There's completely different discussions.
Rym: a single-player game like Deus Ex human revolution or even like the old system shock Like your dude levels up in the course of the game, right?
Rym: And in laws gives like Symphony the Night like you level up your shit in the core for the course of the game.
Rym: Yeah in a single-player game while you are leveling up as a person or else you won't be good at the game.
Rym: the Escalation of the numbers and the powers and the other things adds to that like they complement each other both to make the game feel Very expansive but also to sort of like unlock more abilities as the game goes on.
Rym: So that sort of grind like in a single-player game can be used to make a game more immersive more effective like sure the crazy axe takes more human skill to use in days of root dawn of DS Dawn of Sorrow.
Rym: that one the crazy axe at the end, but at the same time Leveling up to get that axe like getting the axe feels really good too Even though I know I kind of just ground it out.
Rym: It was like this good balance between grind and satisfaction and because there's no competitive element You don't have to do it.
Rym: who cares?
Scott: Now when there is a competitive element you get all sorts of problems, right?
Scott: For example, if there's a game where you can grind like save MMO But you can grind on your own and then you get into a fight with someone like maybe a Diablo or something.
Scott: It's like whoa You played the game for 30 hours and I played it for 10 and now we're gonna fight even if I'm better at you than At this game you or just have bigger numbers than I do because you put more time into it.
Scott: We might as well just automatically give the trophy to whoever has already spent the most time and not even bother playing.
Rym: Yep, no amount of skill can overcome the loot or gear or level difference in a lot of these games, right?
Scott: It'd be like, you know if you imagine if you were a baseball player professional baseball player and you go and you you know You get your bat and you go up to the plate and the pitchers out there and you're like what the fuck is that?
Scott: And he's got like a tiny tiny golf ball.
Scott: He's throwing.
Scott: it's like where the fuck he has to throw baseball.
Scott: What's up with this bullshit?
Scott: And it's like actually he's been playing baseball for like 20 years.
Scott: So he's allowed to throw this ball.
Scott: Yeah And it's like.
Scott: that's fucking bullshit, right, you know, it's like what he ground out in the league for so long.
Scott: He gets this but you know, it's like and then when the guy gets up to bat He's got like this giant metal bat.
Scott: that's got like a rocket on the back of it.
Scott: It's like what the fuck is that?
Scott: He's like, well, actually he's been in the league for 15 years.
Rym: So it's baseball simulator 1000, right?
Scott: He's allowed to have that even though the rookie has to have like a tiny stick and has to throw a beach ball.
Rym: now It gets even worse.
Rym: cuz remember how we just talked about when you're.
Rym: you know When you when you use this mechanic to grind something It's partly because it either augments or replaces the actual progression of the skill of the human.
Rym: So the human transfers the progression of the character unto themselves.
Rym: So they feel like they accomplish something.
Rym: So now if you let someone shit But if you let someone else skip the grind by paying money Then the player who grounded out Feels cheated even if they have no logical reason to feel cheated because they feel like their accomplishment was literally just taken from them
Scott: Because it
Rym: was really.
Scott: it's really just you know Truth-telling right?
Scott: They couldn't handle the truth, which is that you fucking wasted your time.
Scott: You spent hours to change numbers in a database that could have been changed with a single line of.
Rym: but that's the danger of using character progression to Substitute for human progression.
Rym: the more you use that the more the truth will hurt the people who play your game.
Scott: But the other thing is that you could almost argue that like hey, we're simulating what in the real world You actually do have to grind things out to get better at them, right?
Scott: It's like you don't get better.
Scott: It's something like miraculously.
Rym: So see this is where it could be used for good if you like.
Rym: Counter-strike actually does this really well and Overwatch actually does something similar.
Rym: So a counter-strike.
Rym: There's the real ranking the competitive ranking.
Rym: But there's also this bullshit rank that just goes up the more you play.
Rym: So the fact that there's two ladders there to like ranks for your character Means that the people are pros like they know that the one is just bullshit.
Rym: They only pay attention to the real one, but everyone else Even like they're playing counter-strike and they're getting better at whatever rate their human brain and body get better at.
Rym: but the game Gives them this sort of like separate indicator of you've been playing it a lot.
Rym: So like you're getting better like it ranks you up ranks you up.
Rym: that causes people who might otherwise get discouraged or quit because they Don't recognize their own progress Which is a real problem if you have good matchmaking because you'll always feel like you're at the exact same skill level forever Unless you have some context to show that you're not Like.
Rym: imagine if right matchmaking was perfect You would always win 50% of the time forever.
Rym: You would never feel like you got better at the game Unless you could zoom out watch a video of you playing the game be like, oh wow, it's Neo vs.
Rym: Neo.
Rym: Okay So You can use this mechanic like counter-strike does to encourage people to keep playing the game which will then cause them Most of the time to get better while at the same time have a separate ranking system for the pros that actually matter to them
Scott: Mmm,
Rym: so there are ways to use this for good not just for evil.
Scott: Well, there's other situations where it's like.
Scott: is it grinding or is it not right?
Scott: So look at something like all the mobas out there.
Scott: whenever you play a MOBA you got to level up in that MOBA.
Scott: Right, you know that they're always like everyone starts at level one every time the game starts.
Scott: So it's not an unfair thing where it's like.
Scott: I've been playing mobas for 30 years.
Scott: I got to start with level 20 guys like everyone starts level one and we level up as we play the MOBA and then when we start another round everyone's level one again.
Rym: but See, that's all.
Rym: that's like a versus Stateless grind.
Rym: so it's like a competitive grind like you know what?
Rym: You know what has the exact grinding?
Scott: is that it's like who can grind the best?
Scott: It's like who can grind the fastest.
Rym: Yep, so you and so it's again.
Scott: There's actually a it's.
Scott: it's actually almost not a grind.
Scott: It's like you're testing this skill of who.
Scott: can you know?
Scott: Do these tasks better than other people and then we're just not going.
Scott: you know you were at any time.
Scott: You can like sort of like actually try to fight the other people and see who's better and there's actually some skills to that, too.
Scott: But you know if somebody was better at one part then you're not gonna be able to beat him at the second part.
Scott: So they minion.
Scott: they beat you at game a you know Come after you in game B, and you'll be in screw.
Rym: Dominion in a way does the same thing.
Rym: the mechanics of playing Dominion are Minimal in terms of the actual play of the game But the real game is you look at the state you look at your opponents like all the cards that are available.
Rym: You come up with a strategy of how am I gonna grind out victory points to win this fucker?
Rym: and then separately?
Rym: There's the execution which gets harder over time like you got to keep track.
Rym: like how many of those cards do I have in?
Rym: How many cards are in my deck?
Rym: is the total?
Rym: is it time to start?
Rym: DPT Yep, and MOBAs is the same way.
Rym: you're like.
Rym: you're both like the competitive.
Rym: like there's a there's this morass You have to fight your way through.
Rym: Everyone picks a strategy and a path as a team to fight their way through it And then you're eventually gonna bump into the other team.
Rym: Whoever got a little bit further as a huge advantage still sort of a problem.
Scott: because let's say I'm really good.
Scott: Let's say you know I'm a person where I'm.
Scott: actually I'm not.
Scott: but let's pretend that I was the kind of person who was really good at like Combat in the MOBA, right?
Scott: so you give everyone characters that are all the same level with the same amount of gold and shit and I just kill everyone because I'm just so fucking good at this game.
Scott: But if I'm not good at that first part and I get into a situation We're like, I'm level 7 and everyone else is like level 10 I just get blowed up because I'm not good.
Scott: the first that grindy game ends up becoming You know more important than the combat II game.
Scott: It's like even it doesn't matter how good you are the second one if you can't do the first one.
Rym: So the grinding game is actually more important Which is interesting because you look at the pedigree of MOBAs and they sort of come out of this idea.
Rym: You know Warcraft 3 basically.
Rym: so they come out of this idea that you know.
Rym: There's a bunch of goons and basically it's just competitive.
Rym: Everyone stand there and level up until someone's leveled up a little bit more than someone else.
Scott: All right Then I can go and fight you because I'm stronger than you.
Scott: watch out here I come like.
Rym: obviously the modern MOBAs have gone Way beyond that but that's kind of the core mechanic.
Scott: It's still the core mechanic.
Scott: There's other.
Scott: they layered a whole bunch of stuff on to it to make the different parts more interesting Like, you know, I know the heroes of the storm is like events on the map and all this kind of.
Rym: you know It's all kind of things going on But there's always a danger if you have that kind of progression in a game then things like build orders like Starcraft style Matters so much that not memorizing those just you can't even come to the table.
Scott: Mm-hmm Where to get the payoff from the game is just too fucking time-consuming, right?
Scott: so let's say I go to the store and I buy something like Final Fantasy 21 and It's I paid money for this.
Scott: It's full of all these videos and all the story and this carries so much stuff in there, right?
Scott: And I want to experience a whole bunch of it.
Scott: But in order to experience a whole bunch of it I have to spend time pushing a bunch of buttons mindlessly before I'll get to the next bit of it.
Scott: It's like that's fucked up, especially in a single-player thing.
Scott: Imagine if you went to the store and you bought Lord of the Rings on DVD and after 15 minutes And the first movie it stops and it says hey you want to see the rest of the scenes?
Scott: Well, you can't see them unless you push this button for like an hour and then we'll show you the next scene in the movie.
Scott: It's like fuck you I paid for this.
Scott: I just want to watch the whole fucking thing right now and of course like here's.
Rym: here's so Final Fantasy 4.
Rym: Here's a not really a counter example, but a more nuanced example.
Rym: That game is random encounters and boss fights.
Rym: Yeah, it also has very limited resources.
Rym: so I mean you could grind out like I'm gonna skip this part but you could like fight random counters and grind out to like Level up and get infinite money and then go through.
Scott: but I just go just hang around near a town Keep going to the inn if you're not willing to do that.
Rym: There is a skill a pretty significant and interesting skill game there I actually enjoyed as a kid and I played Final Fantasy 4 again like five or six years ago And I actually enjoyed it despite that grind.
Rym: now I got a little sick of the grind at a few points along the way But the idea that for example, I gotta go into the Silf cave to get the thing It's like this ordeal of all right.
Rym: how what resources do I need to bring in like how many potions do I actually need to bring in to deal with this?
Rym: and Then each encounter is a puzzle of.
Rym: do I fight it if I do fight it?
Rym: What is the optimal path through this particular encounter?
Rym: Right because it is my resource right.
Scott: if you grind it less and you want to get the game done quicker You can save time by you know going in with less, you know less levels less potions less.
Scott: You know now this where you can spend more time up front getting more potions And then it'll be a breeze to go through the cave, but you know you spent more time on it.
Rym: Yep, so the other thing the original Final Fantasy 4 did was that the boss fights were fucking Disaster parties like they were so hard at that the trick like figuring out the patterns and the tells and figuring out how to beat The guy was actually like more powerful than grinding up to a certain point.
Scott: Yeah In order to in order to level up enough to beat a boss without Trouble like with like just a wrecking Rubicon without actually knowing his deal.
Scott: They were just so powerful that you couldn't really do that without spending an inordinate of time.
Scott: You had to learn like aha on this boss You have to use reflect after he wiggles and then he'll spell will bounce back at him And you'll kill him really easily.
Scott: we had to figure that out.
Rym: So also Final Fantasy 4 American kids tended to turn this off But in the basic original Japanese mode.
Rym: Combat was actually semi real-time and all the time you spent like in windows and menus like thinking and clicking around Bad guy just kept doing yep.
Rym: He just kept attacking so it was really like oh shit.
Rym: What do I do?
Rym: No, no, I used the potion on the wrong person.
Rym: fuck ah.
Rym: and That made the game actually really stressful and skill base.
Scott: Compare this to Final Fantasy 1 where as soon as you get to elf town where the silver sword is you walk around outside That town until you can afford to buy yourself a silver sword.
Rym: Unless you're on Awesome games done quick with like some memorized random seated route You're gonna go get the silver sword before you try to beat astos.
Scott: Yeah, you're getting.
Scott: and you know what if you got two fighters you're getting fucking two silver.
Rym: So yeah, you are fuck.
Rym: that shit was 8,000 gold by two silver sword.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, it doesn't matter if it takes you two hours walking around outside that elf town You're fucking doing it because if you don't and you try to go in the next place without any silver swords You're not killing shit.
Rym: There's also an interesting.
Rym: You know you're killing the white mage Survive but in when like when I was a kid like I would play Final Fantasy 1 and beat it About once a year and like I knew my path through the game and I just go through the motions again.
Rym: Like I knew my strategies.
Rym: I had the strategy I came up with that I did like easily 20 times in my childhood where I go all the way up until I could get the airship Having only beaten one fiend.
Rym: you have to beat at least one fiend to get that far.
Rym: Then I would go around and do everything in the game Except beat the four fiends.
Rym: then I'd go back and beat all the fiends real easily.
Scott: Yeah, cuz you'd have all the shit, but like and it was weird because I did similar stuff in Zelda 1, right?
Scott: So in Zelda 1 there's not grinding in Zelda 1. right and you can be.
Scott: I could beat Zelda 1 and like Maybe under an hour.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I don't know what the maybe that's.
Rym: you could grind out.
Scott: I can tell the world.
Scott: I don't know what the world record is.
Scott: I might be getting the time way off but I can beat Zelda 1 very quickly.
Rym: You could grind out multiple times in a day grind out coins and then buy the blue ring before you do anything, right?
Scott: So that's what I end up doing is like if there's things that are if there is equipment available to me, right?
Rym: I will go around and get like every.
Scott: I'll get bombs.
Scott: I'll get them all the heart containers.
Scott: I'll get a blue candle I'll get a blue ring.
Scott: Like I will get everything I can get before going into dungeons.
Scott: Yep as a kid I would fuck I would go get that rat because I know right I know where the.
Scott: You gotta get the raft in dungeon 3 but I would go anything 3.
Rym: get the raft come out get the heart container Then go back in and beat the boss.
Scott: Okay, but it's like I would usually go to dungeon 2 because dungeon 2 is so coin rich.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: and then I like wouldn't do dungeons.
Scott: I would just get all the free coins that are in this, you know secrets to everybody.
Scott: Because like once you get the coins from level 2 you can buy the blue candle You can secret to everybody then you can get the blue ring.
Scott: then you can you know buy bombs.
Scott: you can buy everything, right?
Scott: You're getting bombs from a blue octorok or blue moblin.
Rym: Anyway, even way early I'd go into the dungeon and get the magic book because while everything else that dungeons unbeatable And when you're the magic book is right there at the job He's going to get it.
Scott: you can sneak in and get it.
Rym: Yeah, and then as soon as you get that wand That's a white sword.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Well, I get the white sword.
Scott: I don't need the one.
Scott: I never use the wand really except for fun.
Rym: But yeah, but the wand once you have fire is a white sword that shoots all the time, basically, right?
Scott: But you know.
Scott: So it's like I get all this stuff Before actually going to do the dungeons.
Scott: and the dungeons are so easy because it's like dude.
Scott: I'm in dungeon 3 and I guess what I'm getting.
Scott: I got a ring and a white sword.
Rym: I somehow was a kid Legitimately enjoyed Grinding through Final Fantasy 1 once a year.
Scott: I enjoyed leveling up pokemons.
Rym: So you can't even just say like even I know people who are adults though enjoy leveling up pokemons Yeah But I'm saying that is a that that is a legitimate aspect of gaming that I cannot deal with anymore.
Rym: No But as a kid I did deal with and I know people who still deal with.
Rym: so it's a Part of gaming that can be used for good for bad for evil.
Rym: Like it is a very nuanced topic.
Rym: Mm-hmm So maybe we should do a panel on it.
Scott: Yeah, don't waste your time.
Scott: Yeah We're only gonna live so long.
Scott: How much are you that?
Scott: how much of the limited short life?
Scott: Do you have?
Scott: do you want to spend press an a go and fight fight fight?
Scott: Yeah I mean the one thing I can how much time you wanna play Dragon Quest?
Scott: Kill slime kill slime kill slime.
Rym: when I would beat Final Fantasy 1 once a year was like second grade when my life was a blur of Video games and family events and I don't know what else I did in my entire like childhood I got
Scott: to say the Dragon Quest is the most disappointing because like those games are like.
Scott: Everything is so good about them except for the grinding part But the grind is so bad.
Scott: if I could play a Dragon Quest without grinding That would be like the most glorious thing cuz you could shoot slimes and it's like there's so much stuff is you know?
Rym: Oh, man, what's also interesting though is like I my favorite AGD cues recently are Like the Final Fantasy 4 one where they it's just fun They did a speedrun of Final Fantasy 4 No grinding in case you didn't know new listeners.
Scott: Rym is a big Final Fantasy 4 fanboy.
Scott: It always has been.
Rym: yeah I Was like for whatever reason that game.
Rym: just really I guess it was the perfect storm of Like.
Rym: I was in the anime already When Final Fantasy 4 came out or two in the United States.
Scott: and finally six is just better, right?
Rym: Uh, I like them both equally actually for very different reasons.
Scott: six is just better.
Scott: I'm not saying four is bad I'm just saying six is better.
Rym: I think I could.
Rym: I could.
Rym: Moore's for is probably is easily the second best For actually almost has a more at like the fat the moon The fact that you go to the moon and the core of the earth I mean, he found a fantasy legend through.
Scott: your dad is a stealth bomber.
Scott: You're not gonna compete with the moon does?
Rym: the final lesson three wasn't actually a Final Fantasy game.
Scott: I know it doesn't matter.
Scott: Your dad is a stealth bomb.
Rym: Also Final Fantasy legend one.
Rym: you're in a tower of searching for heaven and remember how you find heaven like right away.
Rym: Yeah, no that game is good - yeah Legend - was a lot like Final Fantasy 6.
Scott: actually, I wish I could stream those games.
Scott: It's not easy.
Scott: Uh emulator Yeah, it sucks.
Rym: But maybe ah, maybe I should.
Rym: I could play those games again cuz while they're grindy They're also more way more puzzling those games and they're also shorter.
Rym: Yeah, and as a kid like I couldn't get past some parts that I had a lot of trouble with.
Rym: I think my adult brain would just not have trouble with that.
Rym: I beat one in three and ever beat - - is actually - as though there's a lot of fourth wall breaking like there's one moment Because it has a lot more cutscenes than one in three.
Scott: I never even played - I don't think so.
Rym: at one point There's this whole plot where like your dad ran away like, you know That's a fancy trope of like your dad's dead and your mom like he's a self bomber.
Rym: Yeah Well in all the regular games your dad's dead like it or both your parents are dead.
Rym: in Final Fantasy legend games Your parents aren't actually dead.
Rym: There's just some bullshit going on with them.
Rym: and the Final Fantasy legend - your mom's like your father ran away and I don't know.
Rym: and You keep finding people who look like your dad, but they're not your dad and then eventually you find your dad.
Rym: He's kind of a schmuck.
Rym: but there's a scene like there's a lot of cutscenes where you like come up to a door and then it like shows you what's going on in that room and it's like the mini like the minor bosses of the game and they're In there and they're like making their evil plans and there's a bunch of chests and then you're like, oh fuck I'm gonna fight them I'm gonna open those chests and then your theme music starts playing and then the bad guys like oh shit That's their theme music.
Rym: They're here and the three guys literally open the chest.
Rym: There's badass items in them.
Rym: They take the items and they just run away and then you come into the empty room like well shit Yeah, oh I would be remiss also just not mention Chrono Trigger.
Scott: right Chrono Trigger the key there and a lot of other games do.
Scott: Also is that even though you've got a grind a bit right you there's no random encounters.
Scott: They don't force you into the grind, right?
Scott: It's like you can grind to your own.
Scott: you control when you're gonna do it and when you're not it's like oh I'm just gonna not go bump into that bad guy and I won't have to fight him right now and you can sort of still do the things you want to do when you want to do them and Only grind when you need to grind or want to grind the exact amount you want Final Fantasy.
Scott: It's like you might just want to walk back to a town right now and it's like no here comes some begging Yep, which could be used to be terrifying.
Rym: like as a kid I remember once I was I got the floater and I came out of that cave and I'm like, holy fuck I'm gonna get the airship.
Rym: I'm gonna do it.
Rym: I'm gonna do it, but I didn't have any tents.
Rym: Mm-hmm And let's just say I didn't make it back to town.
Scott: Did you have a cabin?
Rym: Uh, no, of course Kevin that's some rare luxury son.
Scott: He said you have a tense.
Scott: You never know.
Scott: Yeah might be already on Kevin Let the house.
Rym: house was good.
Rym: Oh As long as it's not sweet home.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Rym: It's actually recorded at night and the patrons for this episode of GeekNights in the amount of money that they give us on a continuing basis are Alan Joyce Rebecca Dunn Nicholas Brando Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette James David White Christian open parenthesis cuts my state.
Rym: e.com.
Rym: Sean Heyworth William Eisen rose Jeremy minor Spartacus Spartacus Spartacus Iggy kid Matthew Smith shart Avishon Jojo Joestar Tyler Eller Don Schleich Clinton Walton Sean Yeager Ren from New Zealand Robert Lee Ryan parent drew open letter.
Rym: rare Lavelle Brian Sidroni Rochelle Montanota Finn Eric Silver on and the infinite sadness.
Rym: kinetic man Aaron Cerise Chris midkiff Chris Knox flame dark fire Sam Corddry Daniel Redmond Chris had odd Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: That the episode we just did is actually a preview.
Rym: We said one of the panels we submitted for Pax prime is called the grind and we're basically just going to talk about all those concepts in much more detail and with Citations.
Rym: the other we submitted remember designing game rules.
Rym: Well, we're sort of rejiggering that panel to focus specifically on writing board game rules.
Rym: So it's gonna be like 60% the same panel But with more examples, we're gonna drop the video game aspect and focus a lot more on the game design aspect.
Rym: So we'll see which.
Rym: if either they Schedule for Pax prime if somehow they schedule neither and it's the end of an era and we don't get to speak at Pax Then we bought tickets, so we'll be there anyway.
Rym: So yeah, see you there.
Rym: and now I leave you with something Particularly interesting and Try keep track of how long it takes you to realize what's going on here.
Media: theory that energy equals mass times the speed of light.
Media: e equals MC squared Okay.
Media: Now if you take that formula and we think there's a lot of mass, right?
Media: Okay, if you collapsed all the mass down into the universe, so there is no space between the mass.
Media: Do you know how much mass there is in the entire universe?
Media: You think you're a lot of mass right?
Media: I'm a lot of mass right.
Media: this building Okay Well, the whole universal mass can be consolidated down into the size of a bowling ball.
Media: That's all there is in the whole world and the universe.
Media: So how much mass are you?
Media: That's right an infinitesimal amount.
Media: So if you take that formula e equals MC squared you can almost cross out Mass.
Media: so the formula ends up being energy equals the speed of light.
Media: Okay, and that's why the vision system is so important because we have lots of photoreceptors that receive light.
Media: But when Hanuman died he the scientist didn't fall in his camp okay, and The pieces of the puzzle didn't fit well together.
Media: So God and his infinite wisdom sent him another Einstein called Stephen Hawking's.
Media: Okay, Stephen Hawking's gave us the string theory and what he discovered is that there are other Energetic particles in the universe and they're shaped like little you ease and what they do is they work by vibration.
Media: So our body is so wonderfully designed.
Media: We have light receivers and we have ears String vibratory.
Media: they pick up vibration.
Media: So if you add it to that theory Einstein's theory of relativity we have e equals MC squared that mass is crossed out almost and strings vibration.
Media: But that still doesn't tell us the whole picture.
Media: because what is a cell?
Media: Right, okay, so a cell has Cell wall cell membrane cytoplasm.
Media: Is that mass?
Media: Not very much really right.
Media: So what are that?
Media: What is that?
Media: You can break down the cells into tiny pieces of energy called electrons protons Neutrons, right Okay, so the whole body has an infinitesimal amount of mass, but what is the remainder?
Media: Energy?
Media: So I am energy.
Media: you are energy.
Media: Okay.
Media: Now if you go to study physics Energy cannot be created.