Rym: It's Monday April 18th 2016.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight Crypto ransomware and why it can really only fuck you if you're dumb.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Oh my god.
Scott: It's warm.
Rym: Yeah And then it was cold.
Rym: It was warm and it was cold that I thought it was summer.
Rym: then it snowed and In fact, I didn't even do.
Rym: usually there's a bunch of stuff I do to my bike because I like I grease it up in the winter because I do use it occasionally.
Rym: You know salt and all that nastiness.
Rym: so I put heavy grease on and then I switch it for summer grease in the spring.
Rym: I hadn't done the switch up yet because the weather had been coming and going but it was so nice today I was like fuck it and I just bike to work anyway and halfway through the bike ride Of course squeaky squeaky squeaky squeaky squeaky.
Rym: So I've stopped and bought some teflon and lubed it up and it's it's spring now and we bike to work every day.
Rym: I feel real good.
Scott: hmm So I'm sure at this point in time was like 2015 2016. now.
Scott: It's 2016.
Scott: Yeah, people have heard like this babymetal thing that's going around Right.
Scott: Yeah, and because I internet I knew about this a long time ago.
Scott: Right as I know tend to know about a lot of things in advance because I internet so much But I usually what happens is I'll be like man.
Scott: There's this thing.
Scott: I knew about it before you.
Scott: I'm so cool like a hipster But in this case, I was so wrong.
Scott: I was the wrongest that you could be All right.
Scott: When I first saw babymetal, which was like they're actually I think they started like way back when they were in like middle school.
Scott: And at that point they were in middle school.
Scott: They were really small and they didn't have a band or anything.
Scott: It was actually the sort of like an offshoot of like a regular old idol group or whatever Right and when I first saw it, it was pretty much just oh, yeah, that makes sense.
Scott: It's a weird Japan thing.
Scott: I've seen those like a million times.
Scott: I mean how many Japan things like that?
Rym: I mean, that was the era where weird Japan was just like an even regular old pop culture, right?
Scott: It's like you always see up.
Scott: There's another thing that's weird from Japan.
Scott: They combine two things that hadn't been combined before or they took something from someone else and redid it, right?
Scott: Yeah, so it's like okay.
Scott: They made an idol group that happens to have metal music in the background.
Scott: That's a cute one-shot thing, right?
Scott: You know.
Scott: and then you know, I saw it again and I'm like, oh maybe like two years ago I think maybe one or two years ago.
Scott: I saw it again and I'm like, oh, I guess that kept going that thing, right?
Scott: It's still not really a big deal, right?
Scott: You know, it's it's you know weird thing.
Scott: It's not commonly known It's just some you know, it's just a j-pop idol group.
Scott: That's not good.
Scott: It's like perfect blue only it's metal right big deal Right, so and they you know, they were like, I know that they opened when like Lady Gaga had this weird tour in 2014.
Scott: I think that was like the art pop tour the art rave or something because crayon pop opened for that and like she originally wanted Crayon pop to open for the whole thing.
Scott: I think couldn't.
Scott: so babymetal opened for the other ones, right?
Scott: And I was like, oh, I guess they're still around right, but I didn't really care.
Rym: is where this is going, right?
Scott: I didn't care or like them at all, right?
Scott: So then of course recently I'm sure now everyone knows who they are because they performed on Colbert's show Which used to be Letterman show which has a history.
Scott: actually if people aren't aware of letting weird acts perform Yeah at the end of the show like going back to like PB Herman and even earlier, right?
Scott: It's like a lot of people became famous You know in the United States because they were their weird-ass act was able to perform on that show Regardless of who is hosting it, right?
Scott: So now everyone knows who they are.
Scott: So because they came back again and like this is like.
Scott: I've seen them now multiple times over the years.
Scott: I was like why like I was like, why are they still here?
Scott: Right?
Scott: This is like a one-shot gimmick deal, right?
Scott: Isn't this a gimmick?
Scott: How is this gimmick continuing to last?
Rym: Well, is it a gimmick if you're the only one?
Rym: I mean, it's not.
Rym: they're not quite guar level of like having the legend of Krauser happening there.
Scott: That is how I was wrong because after they appeared on Colbert.
Scott: I said, why are they still here this gimmick?
Scott: Why is this not gone?
Scott: This one this one-shot deal, so I looked into it Secretly without me noticing.
Scott: for these past two years They have done something that I didn't realize could be done, right?
Scott: And that is they are not what I thought they were.
Scott: I thought that they were a Japanese idol group that happened to have metal music in the background.
Scott: Right, you know of their regular idol songs and whatever.
Scott: right that is not what they are.
Scott: Babymetal is Actually a completely legit metal band that happens to have Japanese idols.
Rym: Wait, so you'd never listen to them like you?
Rym: never no no.
Scott: No, it's not.
Scott: I mean, it's not the music that is legit, right?
Scott: first of all when they got a band to back them up instead of just like a recording that helped a lot because The band that backs them up known as the kami band Right the god band is like literally.
Scott: they went around Japan.
Scott: I got like the best drummer.
Scott: the best guitar is the bit like the best people that they could find Right and they made this band like the drummer used to be in the blue man group and the bassist is like this.
Rym: Used to be in the blue man group is not a significant.
Scott: It's not easy to be in the blue man group.
Scott: You got to be talented to be.
Rym: I'm saying there's a lot of them like.
Rym: there's a lot of skilled percussionists in the world.
Scott: He's really good, right?
Rym: I'm not saying he's not.
Scott: the bassist is some crazy six.
Rym: There's a lot of big man.
Scott: There are many yes But anyway, right.
Scott: so they got like the totally like the sickest band that you could get of Japanese musicians or whatever.
Scott: But like if you go online and look for performances that aren't say on late-night American TV It's like they've been performing it like Gigantic music festival in the UK with like a hundred thousand metalheads and shit, right?
Scott: And I realized watching this that like oh my god This was the secret that all the other Japanese shit has not been able to do right.
Scott: It's like if you look at like you go to the complex store For example, right and you see the manga and the manga is separate right?
Scott: It's not with the other comics.
Scott: It's Japanese comics, it's Japanese first and comic.
Rym: Oh, I see we're going with this.
Rym: So they were just popular among metal people but not as a Japanese weird thing just as metal.
Scott: Yes, every metal band has a gimmick right, you know Blind Guardian has a Lord of the Rings gimmick, right?
Rym: What was Metallica's gimmick?
Scott: No, they don't have a gimmick.
Scott: That's their game.
Scott: They're the only metal band that doesn't have a gimmick.
Scott: AC/DC has like the schoolboy thing going on You know, it's like market machine.
Scott: supremacy has the Commodore 64 thing going on.
Scott: You know every.
Scott: you know, Ramstein has the ridiculous stage things going on flaming penises.
Scott: Every metal band you can think of has some kind of gimmick, right?
Scott: This is a baby metal is a completely normal metal band right of Relatively moderate to high quality and that just has and their gimmick just happens to be Japanese high school girls Right, and I realized all the other Japanese stuff that can't break in right is because it's all the other cool Japan shit, right?
Scott: It's because it makes itself Japanese first instead of what it is first.
Rym: Like we've always said, you know, not that it's not Wednesday But with anime just take a show.
Rym: that would be you know appeal to a demographic and just put it on.
Scott: So this is so.
Scott: it's the fact that they're still there and they're that as big as they are I didn't realize just how big they were is proof right that the things that we've been saying all along are True and would really work if you were smart enough to try them.
Scott: and apparently whoever runs this shit there at baby metal incorporated Knows what the hell they're doing.
Rym: Are they actually baby metal incorporated?
Rym: Did you just call them that?
Scott: because it's some.
Scott: it's some like something entertainment company.
Rym: I just wondered if you're like baby metal incorporated because that's literally what they are technically call.
Scott: I mean baby metal is probably making all the money that they make now.
Scott: Yeah, I can't imagine the Like.
Scott: they were the other idol groups.
Scott: they have whatever.
Scott: I can't imagine they're making a lot of money, right?
Scott: Yeah So actually they have some crazy world tour going on now, right which is why they were performing and whatnot.
Scott: because they guess their second album came out at the beginning of April or whatever.
Scott: and So I was like, oh I wonder where this world tour is going.
Scott: The world tour is ending and like some extravaganza at the Tokyo Dome like later in the year
Rym: I'm not going to that
Scott: it's gonna be in New York on May the 4th May
Rym: the old Star Wars day
Scott: and it was sold out something like oh, oh well stub hub.
Scott: I went on stub hub and you know what?
Scott: It was cheap.
Rym: Oh, do you get tickets?
Scott: I bought one ticket.
Rym: I guess I'm fine.
Scott: Maybe we should go.
Scott: I figured why not?
Scott: Yeah, it was like Okay, I'm not going to Hong Kong.
Scott: It's on Wednesday and it's like four blocks from my office and it's like well Why be alive if I'm not gonna go?
Scott: it's right there Also get tickets and it's at the.
Scott: it's at you know, I guess it's not it used to be.
Rym: is it seating or like GA?
Scott: It's GA.
Scott: So it's that ensure making sure it's at the PlayStation theater, which used to be the Nokia theater.
Rym: Oh be I know where that is.
Scott: Yeah, I think we saw Blind Guardian.
Rym: We did see Blind Guardian there, right?
Rym: So like that was that that was one of the Rym is an old man.
Rym: concerts cuz we went and it was great.
Rym: There was the front rivers mosh and whatever and we all went to the back and sat in those seats.
Rym: I just enjoyed the concert sitting there enjoying the music.
Scott: I got new earplugs - I haven't used them yet.
Scott: Yeah, but yeah.
Scott: So like I've been sort of like once I realized what I had missed.
Scott: right that's sort of and it's all on Spotify by the Way all their music.
Scott: so that sort of occupied my brain for like a whole day As soon as I realized what I had not paid attention to and was wrong about.
Rym: So in terms of occupying people's brains This is most people are associating what I'm about to bring up with games the video game industry all that But it is equally associated but less talked about in tech and almost every modern profession that involves coding technology art anything and while this is not specifically technology it is Really important to talk about and it's also so close to all these issues.
Scott: and oh this guy.
Rym: Yeah this guy Okay, so it's like yes.
Rym: We know this is not technically technology, but it's too close to home and Never before has there been an individual person who so exemplifies these toxic fucking attitudes Like I.
Scott: can I mean well this?
Scott: this is something that is a constant rumble which with occasional spikes, right?
Scott: But this is the largest spike in this discussion that has ever occurred.
Scott: so far despite me constantly trying to make it spike I haven't been able to do so.
Scott: I guess you need the troll to make it spike and not be smart beavers.
Rym: Well, I think part of the reason it's spiking is that Alex st.
Rym: John the shithead we're talking about to talk about is in Relation to John st.
Scott: John.
Rym: No who is amazing.
Scott: Oh, he's a video.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: the video game aspect brought in the extra community power and not just the up because the last spike was the Second biggest spike was the EA guy.
Scott: Yeah, right and he was.
Scott: that was also games that I haven't seen.
Rym: a lot of spikes in this just in pure technology area and I think it's partly because Game development like people assume and expect both publicly and privately that it's awful.
Rym: But this is more whispered in technology.
Rym: Like you don't have nothing.
Scott: It's whispered.
Scott: I think it's just.
Scott: you know, I think it's technology.
Scott: people like it.
Rym: I have okay, so I'll put it this way I have never seen someone who has a slideshow of the presentation He gave on how to hire people.
Rym: that literally spells out.
Rym: It'd be like if the Communist Party in Soviet Russia legit was like.
Rym: here's the slide on how we will oppress the work.
Rym: Here's the slide on how this is just animal farm Like it is.
Rym: so the deal is Someone.
Rym: Dean Takahashi just wrote this article which was pretty smart.
Rym: He's basically like look he's okay guy.
Rym: Yeah He's like look video games have a problem and that we have perpetual crunch like due to poor planning and poor expectations and exploitation.
Rym: We expect video game developers to work 70 80 hour weeks when there's literally no reason for it to be that way.
Rym: no, and Alex st.
Rym: John on venture beat decided to write an article in response to that.
Rym: what I'm reading from is Rami Ismail who wrote a response to Alex st.
Rym: John's response to Dean Takahashi Where he basically eviscerated this guy, but the gist of the article was that?
Rym: People in Video games but you can apply this orthogonally tackle obviously need to work Crazy hours and not have hobbies outside of their work and dedicate their entire lives to their job or else They've fallen victim to the.
Rym: what is it?
Rym: the wage slave attitude?
Rym: Uh-huh that and he goes on and on about how you should feel privileged to work like this.
Rym: All you're doing is pushing a mouse around.
Rym: you're not doing real work.
Rym: So why would you?
Rym: why do you feel like you should have to only work like 40 hours?
Rym: Why do you feel like you should go home and see kids?
Scott: Because I'm not a loser like you as a life.
Scott: Yeah I have things to do beside if I only work because I have to not because I want to.
Scott: there's not my fault that you have nothing in your entire life other than work that fulfills you and you're a pile of human garbage.
Rym: and he's basically arguing that the idea of work-life balance is a myth and that you Cannot exist in the games.
Scott: It sounds like someone who has no life and just wants no others to have a life because that makes him feel bad.
Rym: It's a it's a lot like Like, you know, we gave Cliffy B a chance when he gave that keynote at PAX.
Rym: I was like, you know what?
Rym: I'll listen.
Rym: I'll hear this guy out.
Scott: I mean, I listen to David Jaffe.
Scott: Listen, it could be.
Scott: Yeah, maybe he's better than David Jaffe stuff.
Rym: That is true.
Scott: That doesn't say he's good.
Scott: He's a less smelly poop of the same flavor.
Rym: He's pooping is.
Scott: they're both poops.
Scott: One of them is like a diarrhea and one of them just some turds.
Rym: But Cliffy B's didn't really come out until later when unrelated to that keynote But he said a bunch of crap online.
Scott: We're like, okay He seemed at the keynote like he knew better and he was trying but he just couldn't hide it.
Scott: Yep, he couldn't hold it in but him too like this.
Rym: they have this like ridiculous idea of how tech workers should live their lives and they're sort of building this narrative to try to almost demonize people who have social lives or
Scott: because they don't want
Rym: to work 40 or 50 hours a week tops and do other things in the rest of their time and It wouldn't be that much news except that because of this teardown of it Everyone's talking about this.
Scott: finally I've been trying to get people to talk about this for a long time.
Scott: Because all you see on the startup things are people glorifying the you know, eat ramen, you know live in a startup house Get paid with.
Scott: you know lottery tickets kind of culture and I'm every place that calls me to try to hire me has that Culture and I say oh fuck you, right?
Scott: And that makes it pretty hard to find any place to work besides where I'm working.
Rym: Exactly because
Scott: like even though this guy seems like a like a you know, a crazy evil person Why if he's so crazy evil wide and he's you know, like a rare case of this crazy evil How come every single tech startup is act is doing basically what he says even if they're not writing the articles that he's?
Scott: Alex St.
Scott: John is writing this.
Scott: someone who Runs the place has his attitude because all their people are working a ridiculous hours and not having lives.
Scott: Yeah, I mean basically if you have I went to interview at a place.
Scott: there are people.
Scott: they had a fancy kitchen.
Scott: People were cooking and eating dinner in there as like a group like it was a family and it's like whoa Get the fuck out of here.
Scott: No way.
Rym: Am I working here now I could see situations I know you wouldn't do this But like if I owned a company or if I really cared about something like.
Scott: so He's this guy Alex St.
Scott: John owns a company.
Scott: He really cares.
Scott: he expects his workers to care as much as he does.
Rym: I don't think he actually really cares because reading everything he's written It feels a lot like Cliffy B's stuff where these are like the rent takers in the industry who aren't actually Personally contributing that much.
Scott: No, I mean people who managers don't contribute much.
Rym: in general They do I think in well-functioning organizations.
Rym: But like the problem is like in video games people expect like, uh You're gonna have to work like crazy hours for the last eight months of game development.
Rym: Like no that means you fucked up Wave way earlier in the project and now you're choosing to pay that cost with the lives of your workers Instead of just by pushing out deadlines, you know, whenever we talk about like Project management, especially in software.
Scott: We always talk about the space shuttle.
Scott: Yeah, and we're like, yeah, we're not building the space shuttle What the fuck do we care right?
Rym: Oh, yeah, because you had that article about how they built the space shuttle.
Scott: Yeah, there is actually an article I read recently that was like here is actually the software process They use to write the space shuttle software and I was like, oh now we know exactly how they do it.
Scott: And it's like well, it's not agile.
Scott: No, it's fuck.
Scott: No, it's not agile.
Scott: and also Now I know exactly to what extent I never have to go.
Rym: You know, what sucks doesn't really suck that much.
Scott: but also if you're building something super serious like a space shuttle Why aren't you doing what they do?
Rym: So in my industry, you know Wall Street crap Is the space shuttle.
Rym: so I have some projects like some things that don't matter that much.
Rym: so yeah agile Let's just push out a bill Let's go.
Rym: and there's other things where I will personally spend like six months Writing a spec like a giant book of the Bible that says here's what this thing needs to do And here's how it needs to be architected.
Rym: That is like 100% like the stakeholders have signed off like the regulators like everyone is like.
Rym: this is exactly what we're building.
Rym: We understand it a hundred percent and then we build it.
Rym: not everything I do needs to be that way But that's kind of orthogonal to this point.
Scott: So I want you all but the point is that if you do that kind of stuff, right these management hours Issues aren't an issue, right?
Scott: It's it right.
Scott: That's how it's related.
Scott: It's a matter of you care building things the right way and not you know Doing some agile nonsense bullshit.
Scott: then, you know exactly how long things are gonna take you People and divide the labor properly.
Rym: you might be wrong, but there's a big.
Scott: it's gonna be way less off than eight months of crunch.
Rym: There's a big difference between oh shit We're falling a little behind.
Rym: can we work?
Rym: everyone work one extra weekend and work fine And then I'll give you all vacation after the games out versus yeah eight months of 80-hour weeks.
Rym: Oh, and we're still behind.
Rym: so But I really want all of you gaming industry taking serving to read Every word that this jackass road because you need to understand that this is like this is exactly What the people who ask you to work late day after day are thinking in their heads.
Scott: I also want to just remind people the reason that these people can get away with this attitude is Because people agree to work for them and people who do work for them don't unionize and don't assert themselves.
Scott: Right, if you go and someone like asshole like this is trying to hire you I don't care how badly you need a job say fuck no, right?
Scott: I mean, would you rather be?
Scott: I mean if you're unemployed?
Rym: There's a level of privilege there Scott in that I pretty much get a job anytime I need to.
Scott: if I Was between even if I couldn't get a job I would just.
Scott: I would rather work at Starbucks than work at some ridiculous asshole place like this, right?
Scott: I'll just move out of my apartment rather than destroy my entire life for someone else.
Scott: What's the point of being alive?
Scott: What is the point of being alive if you're spending all your time?
Scott: Just sacrificing all of your meant your you your young years your years of youth that you're able to work, right?
Scott: Giving a hundred percent of your entire mental capacity to this other person for their garbage, whatever the fuck it is.
Scott: So I would rather just be poor than do that.
Rym: It goes way beyond that and that it really illustrates the sort of tech bro bullshit.
Scott: And if everyone has the attitude I have Then those people won't be able to force anyone to do that anymore because nobody will agree to work for them.
Rym: You really need to look at the slides that this guy posted.
Scott: I looked at those slides.
Scott: Yeah, if I was at that presentation, I'd go buy tomatoes and come back.
Rym: You don't recruit and retain male engineers.
Rym: you recruit and retain Wives and girlfriends.
Rym: if the wife or girlfriend is unhappy the engineer is gone.
Rym: the paycheck goes to her.
Scott: You didn't let me finish about putting the rocks in the tomatoes.
Rym: But like he even has his advice where's the thing that?
Rym: like?
Rym: Here it is?
Rym: be on the lookout for the I'm quoting this guy.
Rym: be on the lookout for the holy grail the undiscovered Asperger's engineer and then what follows is literal advice on how to find someone with Asperger's syndrome And trick them into ruining their lives to make your company profitable.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: This is literally what your jackass boss is thinking and trying to do.
Rym: Yep So I look forward to the continued just general disc.
Scott: These are the people who venture capitalists give lend money to instead of lending them to someone like me Because they'd rather have some asshole.
Scott: have the money to make the world a shittier place.
Scott: Then have me go to the beach and make a better the world a better place by not bothering anybody.
Rym: yep, that's why I'm very very happy in some regards to the Decisions I've made in my life in terms of the places like the plate.
Rym: the last place I worked All my bonuses and everything were in lottery tickets.
Rym: You know what that lottery did not come in but you know, that's a shock.
Rym: But they paid me enough money to make rent in the meantime, and I only worked 40 hours a week.
Scott: Yeah, well this guy's doesn't sound like the guy in a guy who's gonna pay enough cash.
Scott: He's looks like he's a lottery tickets only.
Rym: Yeah, I get I get job offers.
Scott: I actually read something interesting today.
Scott: We're like There's some sort of like Wall Street is souring on certain companies like say Twitter who pay their employees with lots and lots of stock And not a lot of cash.
Scott: Yeah, it's starting to cause some issues Like do you actually have any money to pay these employees?
Scott: Are they gonna let you know?
Rym: Well, but so it's interesting because retention in those spaces is a big problem, but it's interesting in video games.
Rym: Retention is a problem because people get burned out and ruin their lives and just quit and disgust Eventually like after I hit a bottom like they hit rock bottom and someone tells them to quit and then they finally do because they're going Crazy, but I mean, it's a grasses
Scott: on ants.
Scott: It's a grass is always greener thing, right?
Scott: You're working at some job where you hate your co-workers But you have a life and you get and you know you get money and you look at this game job and maybe it pays more and you see all these cool co-workers because they're all Game people and you're like, oh man that what a better life that is.
Scott: Yeah you know you see the grass is greener you look at the things you don't have and you see that game job and it has The things you don't have now.
Scott: so you move to it and you don't realize the parts that were worse.
Rym: But see that's the difference.
Scott: the guy that I have the priorities in order.
Scott: Your life is number one priority.
Scott: The only reason that you are working is because you could need to work in order to live.
Scott: if we had diamond age We wouldn't work But at least in other industries starch like we wouldn't work.
Rym: finance and a lot of technology.
Rym: the people Usually make a lot of money and while they're still ruining themselves.
Rym: They at least have a giant salary the whole time But in games you don't even get that.
Rym: So if you're gonna burn yourself out and make these very poor decisions at least do it on Wall Street Because then at least you'll be making.
Scott: I know someone who works for Bloomberg, right?
Scott: And they don't tell me how much money they make but they've told me how they make a lot of money and they're planning to retire very very early like 40s early I was looking at.
Rym: so actually Bloomberg has a job posting that is literally.
Scott: Bloomberg pays really really well.
Scott: I know I know they actually and it's not like it's not.
Scott: um, it's not like some miraculous culture.
Scott: That's like the best thing ever, but it's actually a pretty it's an okay culture over there, right?
Rym: They don't make people work ridiculous And they have all sorts of luxuries in the bag repeatedly like whispered in my ear by people who are probably afraid that I would quit my current job.
Rym: how Boring and horrible it is to work at Bloomberg.
Rym: and I think they're afraid that I might just one day be like, you know What let's go work at Bloomberg.
Scott: Yeah, I mean everything I know about it is like it's you could work at a lot worse places And you get paid a lot and you can retire early.
Rym: So you got any news.
Scott: Yeah, so lately there's you know 360 video which is when you have a YouTube video where you can drag and look around.
Scott: Right has been coming a lot hotter because there's a lot of cheap cameras Now that you can buy that are basically two wide-angle cameras back-to-back on a stick.
Rym: Yeah, the old days really like make a rig and then stitch it all.
Scott: now They've got like GoPros doing a thing where it's like four GoPros all together, right?
Scott: I saw a guy the other day Biking and he had one of those.
Rym: you had one of those who's biking around like fight.
Scott: I yeah, why not?
Scott: So it's actually these things are getting cheaper and cheaper to get to make the 360 videos which are kind of fun.
Scott: You can do cool things with them, right?
Scott: I saw a music video that was made with one where all the people in the music video were like standing around it.
Scott: So you could like look at the different band members, right?
Scott: Like look at the guitarist over here and then you turn around and look, you know And you can see what someone's doing when like they're not the center of attention, right?
Scott: And then I've seen stuff for like, you know someone goes in a tour of a city and it's like you're on the tour bus and you can look around and that the different Sites on your own by clicking and dragging the mouse.
Scott: So 360 a video is it's okay With VR doing head tracking it's even better.
Scott: right because then you don't have you don't have to keep clicking and dragging and stuff Right, you can sort of naturally look about and that feels like you're in a place that you're not and that you know, that's cool.
Scott: But thing with 360 video is that until now?
Scott: It's just been recorded, you know, and then you take all the cameras and combine the data after the fact and then upload it Right.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: YouTube is now adding a feature for the first ever I've ever seen Live-streaming 360 video.
Rym: the example they show is already perfect because it's not just video.
Rym: It also has the three-dimensional audio.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So imagine like the example they show is there's a jazz concert live For a million people and every one of you every member of the audience is sitting on the middle of the stage Just with a band playing for them and you can just look around and hear all the audio.
Scott: Yep, so Live-streaming 360 video it's like man.
Scott: I need some to subscribe to some channels and get some alerts of when people are going to be doing 360 live streams in various.
Rym: Awesome guys, I want the NHL to put this rig in like the best seat at MSG.
Scott: Dude, you could take the 360 cameras.
Scott: They're so small.
Scott: You could put a wide-angle lens on the front of someone's helmet and on the back of someone's home.
Scott: Oh, you could be lies lie during the game Be Somewhat like the quarterback or whoever at any sport, right?
Rym: I just want to be in the crowd.
Rym: I just want to be sitting in the best seat at MSG and you need to look behind you.
Rym: Yeah I'll look behind me and see like whatever drunk I have.
Rym: you could take it just before.
Scott: they could be like eight 360 cameras is like in the stands and you just pick which one you want to watch the game from.
Rym: Yeah couple that with an oculus or something.
Scott: It doesn't write in the stands.
Scott: You can look behind you and be like, oh who's fighting?
Scott: If the drunk attacks the right make the home viewing experience the same as the stadium experience.
Scott: You could actually get rid of stands entirely one day and just play sports in much smaller spaces and just have 360 cameras like around the edge of the.
Rym: I've been thinking about this a lot and I've been talking to people who work in VR companies a lot.
Rym: and the Spectation I got stuff we'll talk about on a Tuesday show.
Scott: right the 360 thing makes spectation a big deal at anything that's not you know, just forward-facing right?
Scott: think about like You know, I work for Broadway comm.
Scott: there's a lot of Broadway shows where you're not just looking at the stage the whole time Right, you know like in cats the cats come out in the audience and in Phantom of the Opera They got the show Scott.
Scott: Here's the one here comes over the top.
Rym: There's something you probably forgot about this but there's.
Rym: Remember what we used to watch Penn and Teller's shows and stuff and all that like a long time ago and how they always talked About how the the best form of magic like the most amazing thing to see is the close-up magic Which is hard to get because the close-up magic is someone as good as like Penn Gillette Literally sitting in front of just you messing around and doing a trick in front of you.
Rym: You could have people doing close-up magic to these rigs I mean, but I don't see.
Scott: you're how that really enhances it that much unless part of the magic trick is behind you.
Rym: Well, it's not just looking out at you.
Rym: It's that you've got this sphere of Your sort of present.
Scott: use a wide-angle lens facing forward the whole point of the 360 camera.
Scott: We already have 180 cameras.
Scott: It's not a big deal.
Scott: The whole point of the camera is that something behind you is going on, right?
Scott: There's a reason to look around if it's close-up magic.
Scott: You're only looking at this person right in front of you, right?
Scott: it's.
Scott: I don't see how it's.
Rym: so you discount how Powerful the effect is if you move your head a little bit and the world moves correctly.
Rym: yeah, like that effect is very profound in humans because of our Biology and how easily tricked our brains are.
Scott: there needs to be things in all 360 degrees.
Scott: 360 degree camera to be worthwhile.
Rym: I mean even this concert.
Rym: what's gonna be directly behind you?
Rym: some other jackass watching the concert?
Scott: Well, that's what I'm saying, though But see how that's.
Scott: the example is not a normal concert.
Scott: how often in a concert are you in the middle of the bed with?
Scott: music coming from all sides Right.
Scott: Imagine if every human being could like say shrink themselves to be really small.
Scott: What we wouldn't make a symphony on a stage.
Scott: we would have a symphony surrounding you facing inwards.
Scott: it would sound way better.
Rym: Arrangements would have to be changed a little bit.
Rym: actually.
Scott: I think you just have it, you know, it depends how many people you had, right?
Scott: It's like you'd have like one violin equally spread out in every direction or maybe like, you know Like you get like, you know how they have the in New York City in a lot of places like the whistling bench And the whistling arches and set it up like that.
Scott: So like even though the timpani is in the corner You can hear it on all the sides whistling basically effectively, you know, cuz you don't need four timpani's right?
Scott: That's a little ridiculous.
Scott: Like oh fuck me.
Scott: I can't hear anything else.
Rym: Things of the day.
Rym: So if you didn't know Pyongyang in North Korea a place you should not go ever don't go there.
Scott: Maybe one day you can go there like you can go to Cuba now It has a subway right but do not go there until I say you can go there.
Scott: That's because by the time I say you can go there.
Scott: It'll definitely be safe to go there.
Scott: So only recently were foreigners ever allowed inside Pyongyang subway except like one station The shiny the shiny one that looked good and had actors in it.
Rym: So this is a photo journal with a lot of pictures.
Rym: This is basically the first group of foreigners who have ever been allowed to see the entirety of the Pyongyang metro system Every stage.
Scott: people actually use it.
Scott: or is it just for show?
Rym: I think people actually use it.
Rym: but remember the people in King.
Scott: I remember hearing it was just for show and that like they saw people like oh no That was I think was the regular train station.
Scott: They got off the train because they came in the train from China or Russia or whatever.
Scott: Yeah, and then when they got off at the train station, there are people about the train station But there weren't any trains other leaving or arriving other than the one that they had just arrived on.
Scott: so there were no reason for any people to be in that train station.
Scott: that.
Rym: but when Yang is sort of like the Propaganda city so it like people live there the privileged few or I guess the most trusted or best-looking or whatever.
Scott: I'm sure their lives are not great when there's no foreigners around.
Rym: but this is a lot of photos and they're Fascinating just from all the subway stations.
Scott: It looks like every other photos I've seen in North Korea before but these you've never seen inside of here.
Scott: I haven't seen those particular ones, but they the propaganda looks the same.
Rym: It's all the most interesting notes about this.
Rym: Later works their trains work one the trains themselves look straight out of like East Germany.
Scott: Yeah, like Cold War it takes Dracula.
Scott: It's a lot harder for him to get around those trains.
Rym: And two in almost every photo there's at least one if not multiple people Given the photographer the fucking death stare like people are not happy that this person is there.
Rym: It is side-eye after side-eye after side-eye.
Scott: Maybe it's just because they have to act while that person's there and they can't.
Rym: well I press.
Rym: I posited another idea that if you live in North Korea You are told your entire life that foreigners particularly Americans are the reason your lives are filled with such terror and privation.
Scott: And why are they allowed in your country?
Scott: so you just murder them on site.
Rym: you see one being escorted around by North Korean security forces for whatever reason and It'd be like if
Scott: I don't know today If I saw someone being escorted around the city by the security forces usually the security force is in the city You're just sort of standing there, you know doing their jobs doing nothing.
Scott: Yeah, if I saw them escorting someone I'd probably rubberneck a bit and be like, oh who did they arrest him?
Scott: For what reason it's got?
Rym: what if a bunch of people who just looked like Nazi Hitler's.
Rym: We're walking around taking photos in the subway suddenly and there's a bunch of cops Just like walking them around and guiding them and no other context.
Scott: I'd assume that the cops are keeping me from killing them Which is probably correct.
Rym: This is a fact in fact.
Scott: that happens in the United States like when the KKK people like, you know Get a. you know a thing like a license to have like a rally or something, Illinois Nazis, right?
Scott: The cops have to be there no matter how much they hate him - you know because they got to protect them from.
Scott: you know The smart people.
Scott: that's how it goes.
Scott: You know, it's the cops aren't approving of them.
Scott: It's just if you have your protest.
Scott: that's anti KKK and the KKK protest.
Scott: the cops will protect you from them.
Rym: Also So I got you got a thing of the day.
Scott: I do have a thing of the day.
Scott: so There was that new Godzilla movie that came out in the US a while ago year or two ago.
Scott: It's been a while actually, but the new Godzilla movie is directed by He deiaki.
Scott: I know don't?
Rym: I saw Twitter Flipping out about that trailer.
Scott: Did you watch the trailer?
Rym: I did not.
Scott: well, that's my thing of the day.
Scott: So we're gonna watch it now.
Scott: So this trailer Basically, I watched the trailer and I said wow You didn't even need to tell me this is directed by Anno.
Scott: In fact, I didn't know until after watching the trailer and I noticed while I was watching the trailer Like there's a scene in the beginning where some glass shatters and when the glass shattered I'm like that really looks like a building falling apart and say Akira or even jelly.
Scott: That particular way they animate the buildings smashing but done in live-action Right, and then there was a scene where the tail there's a lot of tail action Right where the tail goes over these Japanese buildings in the street and the camera pans across the right.
Scott: and I was like That really seemed like you know that what which angel had like the whippy arms?
Scott: Oh, yeah And I'm like it really feels like that scene like I feel like I've seen this shot before That's and then when I saw Godzilla, it was a really scary Godzilla, right?
Scott: But he's got those t-rex arms and they were extra t-rex arms like yeah And I was like that reminds me of when I watched how we hono and the person who was the actor who was playing on Oh was doing a Godzilla impression and had that exact same body language.
Rym: I gotta finish that show.
Rym: I
Scott: wonder if that person saw I know doing a Godzilla impression and stole that body language for his acting and I know also put his own body like his idea of how Godzilla's
Rym: Blue blazes and think it was funny and then
Scott: I don't know but it was definitely the same body language in both blue blazes and This Godzilla
Rym: or Scott.
Rym: is it possible?
Rym: That's just Godzilla's body language I think.
Scott: I think that you know that Godzilla's body language is that but it's like it's.
Scott: Has it has like this flavor right the seasoning of it?
Scott: The raw material is still beef but the seasoning is definitely the seasoning of the crazy guy.
Scott: So I'm gonna see this shit as soon as it gets English subtitles good or awful.
Rym: So in the minute the booklet book will be Margaret Edward Oryx and Craig.
Rym: I'm biking to work every day.
Rym: So god, I don't want to read anything anymore.
Scott: I'm about to start it.
Rym: Yep I'm pretty much done with.
Scott: that was only like there's only like one manga sitting on top of it.
Rym: I learned a lot of stuff about Randell tour and stuff happened.
Rym: So I'll move on to another book for a while and let that said good.
Rym: We're going to be at PAX East this weekend.
Scott: Yeah, so don't expect a show Wednesday.
Rym: No show Wednesday.
Scott: Yeah, I'm good Thursday.
Scott: I'm getting on the bus tabletop Monday.
Scott: I'm coming on the bus back.
Scott: I'm gonna be working in the tabletop night shift.
Scott: So that is the time to come and play some games.
Scott: when I'm not there to play games with you and beat you I will On the night you want to lose it games.
Scott: feel free to play games at any other hour.
Scott: If you want to win the games play at night when I can't play with you.
Rym: I will be working the VR lounge.
Scott: That's a shame.
Scott: That's gonna be handheld lounge.
Rym: It's the weird Department.
Scott: It's handheld lounge - I think I'm trying to do the circuit.
Rym: my goal Is to do everything.
Scott: I mean, that's your excuse now.
Rym: Yeah, I've got every I've always got every year.
Scott: It's the way to make yourself feel good about working in a shit department every year in the forum.
Scott: regret Not just being tabletop all the time like smart people seems like more work than other.
Scott: table top is great.
Scott: It's the best department.
Rym: Main events is real fun.
Rym: live streaming was fun before.
Rym: I didn't get to sit in the room anymore back when I got to be Pax 2 on the video all the time, but when you go to Pax if you're not working, where do you spend most of your time?
Rym: Playing games in tabletop.
Scott: So what's the difference?
Rym: not playing games and walking around being a presence?
Scott: sure Being a presence is good.
Scott: You can tell people how to wit you see go up to someone and they're playing Carcassonne and they're about to put the towel In a real dumbass place and you're like, whoa.
Scott: Well, what the fuck you do right there.
Scott: put it over there.
Scott: Don't let him finish that Cathedral.
Scott: You gotta aim a road right at the heart.
Rym: on Sunday 3 30 p.m.
Rym: Arachnid theater.
Rym: We were doing Atari game design.
Scott: We've done it before me.
Rym: I think thing is we've never put it on YouTube so you can't see it.
Scott: Why didn't you put on YouTube?
Scott: You record it like twice.
Rym: Yeah, I'm gonna do it again.
Rym: Maybe we'll see.
Scott: we didn't do good enough the other times We did except the Atari video.
Rym: We didn't record the Atari video.
Rym: We didn't actually video anything.
Scott: I thought you were doing that with some ODB now DB.
Rym: Yeah OBS, but the second time we didn't even record it ODB should retire.
Scott: Pretty sure he's dead.
Rym: So Pax is gonna be awesome.
Rym: We're gonna be there.
Rym: We'll see you in Boston.
Rym: Yeah, also on the patreon I did put up.
Rym: we hit that goal.
Rym: so the first episode of GeekNights ever the beta with commentary remastered is in the patreon for the backers, but publicly for anyone to listen to.
Rym: I put just the Commentary because I listened to the whole episode and I did about 16 minutes worth of commentary.
Rym: and Scott I said there's something in the commentary.
Rym: We recorded a bunch of stuff before the first beta episode.
Rym: I don't remember this to you know because in the episode at one point We say something like well We like, you know, we listen to what we recorded yesterday and blah blah blah.
Rym: But I'm literally listening to the first audio file we ever made as far as I can remember must have lost one.
Rym: I get the impression we recorded a bunch of stuff in the alpha and maybe we just agreed to delete it.
Rym: Like I don't remember.
Rym: I just wondered.
Rym: you remembered that.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I went to go to my backups recently to find some software.
Scott: I wrote in college and I found everything.
Scott: and so if your backups are not as good as mine.
Scott: That's not my problem.
Rym: 2005 it was October 11th is the first GeekNights.
Scott: You're the one who backed up all these things.
Scott: Not me.
Rym: Yeah, no, I'm saying but we called it the beta.
Scott: also since I'm not paying for the patreon I don't have these.
Scott: I can't get the files.
Scott: You can listen to them.
Rym: You can listen to them.
Scott: I'm not paying you any money.
Rym: No, you can leave.
Rym: got the backup.
Rym: You could just listen to the file.
Rym: You even know the fucking URL.
Scott: I thought y'all I thought you found one that was even older.
Scott: that wasn't at the URL.
Rym: Oh, yeah, I can give you that one.
Rym: Okay, then you just don't get.
Rym: let's do a remastered unless you pay.
Scott: Oh, no remaster It took me a while.
Rym: It was hard to remaster that shit.
Rym: It was actually really hard to remaster that shit and let me tell you smells like ramen.
Rym: I am Really pleased with how well I was able to remaster that audio because if you hear what it sounded like originally It is almost unlistenable.
Scott: Does it smell like ramen?
Rym: Yeah, Emily's cooking in there.
Scott: Is it ramen?
Rym: I don't know It's food.
Scott: It smells like some food cooking.
Rym: Anyway, anyway So there's been a lot of stories about ransomware or crypto where lately to the point that I feel like we should at least explain A little bit about what the deal is there.
Scott: Well, I mean, this is something that just sort of.
Scott: this is one of those things that escaped being a show topic because it's just So common and so sort of like.
Scott: it's never like spikes, right?
Scott: It's always just like.
Scott: there's always one once in a while and you tend to just sort of it just like a fact of life.
Rym: Well, it also wasn't that common until the last few years like so if you took definitely been happening more.
Scott: But it never happens like a whole bunch in a very short period of time.
Rym: It's also one of those things where we always said years and years ago Why doesn't someone just do this with a virus like why don't you make some money?
Scott: Someone is yeah Viruses in the old day were harmless pranks and fun or some of them would just like destroy your computer.
Rym: But then they then they got to the point where people make viruses that would like literally just like ruin all your data delete random Files like literally destroy your life.
Scott: and then we got to the stage where viruses and malware wouldn't actually do any that they would Monitor you you borrow your CPU cycle send spam with your computer do all sorts of other things.
Scott: That would basically just make money and let your computer keep running and hope you keep using your computer Because as long as your computer keeps working you keep it turned on.
Scott: they make more money by using it Maybe in like a zombie army to do SPL or who knows what.
Rym: now what's interesting is even in that era Very rarely did they try to steal like credit card numbers or things like they.
Rym: just they did like spam bots or whatever.
Rym: And then we entered the air after that where most malware was literally just trying to steal your credit card number.
Scott: Yeah, I know your bank account number and now credit card numbers aren't even worth a lot of money on like the evil black market Right.
Scott: Yeah, it's like you can just buy credit cards.
Scott: It's a. you know passports physical ones are worth a lot of money, but that's hard to steal with its software.
Rym: So Ransomware, I think part of the reason it had a big up-and-coming like the reason we're seeing it is the best way to make money.
Rym: It's only a way to make money because bitcoins are still worth some amount of money.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: if you wanted to make a ransomware before Bitcoin Mmm, someone's got to send you the money somehow and that's tough to do.
Rym: Yeah, what are you gonna do?
Scott: We're gonna be like yourself.
Scott: You're gonna do the old.
Scott: are you gonna do old suitcase briefcase of money next to the trashcan thing?
Rym: Yep, mail the mail cash to this p.o box.
Rym: Like you're gonna get caught.
Scott: good luck with that.
Rym: It's a lot of work You might cause.
Scott: no point allows you to hold people's stuff for ransom and then get money from them in the form of bitcoins Without the police finding you.
Rym: so the most basic ransomware and then we'll talk about cuz Scott was like How could you get gotten by this if you're not dumb?
Rym: and the answer is you really can't.
Rym: yeah but there are ways to make ransomware dangerous even to relatively smart and sophisticated people and we're seeing it get really Sophisticated in a hurry.
Scott: So basic ransomware is as such you get some sort of virus Because you did something stupid like a download an email attachment or you went to a shady website and clicked on something shady.
Scott: No, it's already exe from download.
Rym: calm now It is possible to get these things through, you know a zero-day exploit where there's nothing you could do, right?
Scott: That would be but still is zero to exploit wouldn't be on google.com It would be.
Scott: you went in your your unpatched browser right on or on the zero day.
Scott: There is no patch yet But you visited a shady ass website except running the zero day like some legit websites have hosted this through their ad networks You can also run.
Scott: you didn't have ad blocker, right?
Rym: It's a dumb person but What they do is they get on your computer and then what they take all your files and start encrypting them.
Rym: They have a little private key locally.
Scott: Yeah, if they run something that's basically just like true crypt the thing that you would normally use to encrypt your hard drive.
Scott: But they just start encrypting your drive.
Scott: So they look like my document like everything still works because when you double click on a file it decrypts it.
Scott: You might not notice it is slower, but you might not notice how it being slower because your computer is pretty fast Yeah, and then once it's encrypted It pops up the screen and it's like alright, dude I encrypted all your shit.
Rym: send, you know one Bitcoin to this address Within 48 hours or I'm deleting the private key and your data is literally unrecoverable Mm-hmm.
Scott: See if they just deleted all your stuff it would you would first of all, you'd notice immediately.
Scott: and second of all How could they ransom you like?
Scott: Oh, we'll give you your data back.
Scott: It's like it's already gone.
Scott: But by encrypting all of it It's like aha.
Scott: We have basically taken your data hostage and now you must pay us into Unencrypted because to pot if you find the key after we delete the key.
Scott: Good luck with that.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Now if it's well written because there's been a few instances recently where smart people who are doing you know Basically doing white hat hacking right?
Scott: You could just first of all if they use that method, right?
Scott: They haven't deleted the key yet.
Scott: You could unplug the computer real fast.
Scott: Take the drive out, you know connect to the drive find the key that's on there somewhere And then use it to decrypt your stuff.
Scott: Now.
Rym: What if the key itself is encrypted?
Scott: It's right, but it's still.
Scott: it's easier.
Scott: The key would be encrypted with something like AES Right.
Scott: So that's it's a symmetric key and not a public-private key.
Scott: Yeah, because they even know it.
Scott: even though it's very difficult to crack It won't be impossible and most likely I can't imagine it being such a complicated, you know You would be able to eventually rescue your if your data was important enough to decrypt.
Scott: You would you would do it and if it wasn't important enough.
Rym: you who cares right now It may I mean not talking about us But a general like.
Rym: think about a normal person using their computer and suddenly it's like hey dog all your files What do you do?
Scott: You don't even know how to get a Bitcoin and send it.
Scott: So you're fucked.
Rym: Yeah, so actually these ransomware's usually provide very clear instructions on how to buy bitcoins where to buy them.
Rym: They provide helpful links documentation Some of them have helps and facts.
Scott: I mean you could really if you've infected the person's computer this much you could really just Like do everything automatically for them and just be like enter credit card info here to buy the Bitcoin Yep, and then they click OK and then here's it can be alright.
Scott: and then I'd be like, oh, thanks for your credit card info.
Scott: No, I'm just buy all the bitcoins I want with it.
Rym: I would make one where once you give the Bitcoin to be like.
Scott: Yeah, just kidding ten more bitcoins I would be like you'd have to type.
Scott: I'd be just like, you know You type the credit card in now just buy coins up to your credit card limit and give them to myself the end
Rym: And then not even decrypt the guys and
Scott: then sell your credit card number to somebody to to make an extra buck.
Scott: But these are highly effective and if you put stop if you stop the payment, then I'll remove the re-encrypt your computer.
Rym: But they're highly effective if you don't have proper backups and why I say backups not Redundancy because you have a raid.
Rym: these things are.
Scott: we did a show about this a long time ago So you can go listen to that.
Scott: We're talking about the different levels of backing up, right?
Scott: And it's nothing.
Scott: no information in that show despite it being really old has really changed, right?
Scott: If you have your data backed up like if someone gave me ransomware on my computer today and was like We're gonna be encrypted all the hard drives in my computer and there's a lot of them.
Scott: I'd be like Okay.
Scott: So what are you gonna do?
Scott: Oh, no, there's a bunch of games.
Scott: I installed.
Scott: I can't get those from Steam again.
Scott: Oh, there's a bunch of other apps.
Scott: Okay, what?
Scott: what file is on there?
Scott: They can't give it.
Scott: all the things that I've backed up are backed up in like two different cloud services and my NAS.
Scott: Even if they could access my NAS and encrypted.
Scott: that is like, okay, I've got it in the cloud still You can't access that.
Rym: If your NAS is mounted they can and they will.
Rym: actually they'll mount every file system and encrypt it.
Scott: Sure, go for it.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: I got my cloud backup.
Scott: You can't get there.
Rym: Yep I literally dragged my entire two terabyte NAS up to Amazon cloud drive every month.
Scott: I got the whole thing.
Rym: I just do a snapshot of it.
Scott: It's like, you know, you can't right?
Scott: so then if someone did this to me I'm like, alright, it'd be a pain in the ass, but it won't be a big deal.
Rym: But so even if it got me in the middle of a workflow like say I have 40 gigabytes of video from Scott on an SD card and I've copied it to my local hard drive And we haven't uploaded it to the cloud yet.
Rym: Yeah, or like I just started uploading it to the cloud drive, but the ransomware has infected me already.
Scott: I'm holding the SD card.
Scott: I guess the ransomware could get the SD card walls If the SD card is still plugged in.
Scott: Oh, no, we lost a panel video.
Scott: the end of the world.
Rym: It's totally worth a Bitcoin not so then it comes down to what are you willing to pay for that data?
Scott: Or I'm willing to pay a dollar for this panel video.
Scott: It depends.
Rym: if it was a good panel I'd be willing to pay up to like 50 bucks.
Scott: That's all you.
Rym: One zero, but think about so.
Scott: it's other thing is that it's you know Paying terrorists is not a good strategy because that encourages them to continue if they if no one's getting paid off of it.
Rym: But that's why these ransomware is tend to ask for a Significant amount of money but not a huge amount of money.
Rym: They never asked for like hundreds thousands of dollars.
Rym: They're always like 50 bucks hundred bucks.
Rym: Yep, you're gonna risk like every photo you have of your kid for a hundred bucks Mmm, so fuck up.
Rym: I mean what's very interesting?
Rym: Is that this ransomware has started to get a little more widespread and that they're starting to get into?
Rym: Enterprise environment.
Scott: so it may forget shouldn't the enterprise environment have backups?
Rym: Yeah, but if the backup is mounted or mounted by accessible from the computer it'll encrypt that too.
Scott: I mean usually even if you have a shared drive that everyone has mounted that's usually backed up somewhere else Right up to the cloud or to another storage machine or something.
Rym: So I guess I haven't seen an example of this yet.
Rym: Now.
Rym: I've seen some pretty sophisticated one.
Rym: So a lot of these to Force you to be able to basically to force you to just pay.
Rym: They will give you like a one-hour countdown like yo, you've got an hour.
Rym: You're not sure what we've encrypted.
Rym: You've got an hour to pay the Bitcoin.
Rym: or we delete the key like that kind of thing like literally counting down in front of you.
Rym: Some of them will do that.
Scott: I'll just unplug the computer.
Rym: So if you unplug the computer, maybe they've already deleted the key, but the key was transmitted to the overseas server.
Rym: They won't send you a copy of it unless good for them.
Rym: Good move Yeah, so you could make this stuff really sophisticated.
Rym: if you want to be really clever You'd have to.
Rym: I mean you could probably make one that would Encrypt all the files and keep encrypting all the backups you're taking.
Rym: if it had a way to do that, right?
Scott: That's the thing is if you take backups You know frequently right enough if the ransomware is dormantly encrypting things for a long enough time eventually your oldest backup Right, eventually all your backups are encrypted too and you don't realize it now.
Scott: That would which is why you need to test your backups and make sure they work.
Rym: Yep, and almost no one does that Nope, and when I did that.
Rym: I do that at my previous company.
Rym: when we did that We'd find a bad backup every now and then which was good because if we never found a bad backup I'd be worried that we weren't actually testing
Scott: the thing that does our database backups also Not only does it MySQL dump but also loads them into a database to make sure they work.
Rym: Yep But the ransomware is I think going to explode on the scene increasingly because it is actually.
Scott: it's already big tech people.
Scott: It was there then it was you know.
Scott: Now it's like an everyday thing.
Scott: It's an everyday thing for tech.
Scott: people soon Expect to see it getting all over everybody who doesn't know what the fuck they're doing.
Rym: I've seen it hitting hospitals.
Rym: I've seen it hitting like big companies.
Rym: internally where you know, even if you've got a pretty good company There's always the trade-off between how much you lock down your PCs versus do you trust your employees?
Rym: If you trust the wrong person malware up is oh that guy had access to the backups.
Scott: Oh, well, it's not even that.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: if you know, even if your employees computers are way locked down and shit, right?
Scott: You don't let them install stuff.
Scott: Hopefully that would prevent the ransomware from getting them in the first place.
Scott: But if it doesn't because of some zero-day nonsense Maybe that person just has bad habits.
Scott: and like they're in accounting and they saved a bunch of Excel sheets on their hard drive And that's it.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't back them up and you can't make them back them out.
Rym: It's funny.
Rym: You mentioned that.
Rym: so one of the examples I just pull up a ton of like exactly your whole company needs those Excel sheets That are encrypted.
Rym: I pulled up all these examples from the read from just recently just so I'd have like interesting points.
Rym: There's the pet your ransomware, which is targeting HR departments in Germany specifically And because it's looking for that kind of situation of the HR person has a bunch of spreadsheets that they keep locally.
Rym: They back it up occasionally like they're not stupid, but it's not automatically backed up.
Rym: It's a thing just like on their PC Mm-hmm, and it goes one step further than just encrypting.
Rym: it Crashes your PC into a BS OD suddenly once it's done and then when it tries to boot up It's encrypted the master boot record and all your data.
Rym: Oh So they take that drive out and mount it on a Linux machine or something, yep Because zero days exist you pretty much cannot prevent 100% of the ways this could get a computer.
Rym: the only way to absolutely protect yourself Ransomware is to have good reliable automated backups and Redundancy.
Scott: see me know what that's actually like.
Scott: that's actually kind of okay, right?
Scott: Because you think about it a lot of other things like we're just gonna blow up your hard drive.
Scott: It's like if there's a zero day, you're just fucked.
Scott: Yeah, but something like this It's like oh, you know what backups are something you should be doing anyway.
Rym: But if you didn't you're basically paying a tax to a terrorist to get your photos back.
Scott: I mean, they're evil for sure.
Scott: I'm not gonna say ransomware people are good, but at least they actually give you the files back.
Rym: Sometimes yeah, no sometimes I found another example where there's a. there's a brand somewhere that had a bug in it So it actually wouldn't decrypt the files properly.
Rym: It would just give you gibberish.
Rym: But but someone like inspected the code and it looks like it's literally just a bug.
Rym: So from what I can gather the guy who wrote the malware I thought the person who wrote the malware released a patch because they felt bad.
Rym: Oh Okay, yeah They refunded the money of anyone who paid who fucked up like who lost their data and they released a patch.
Rym: So if they hadn't like if they still had the messed up data, it would fix it for them.
Rym: So, you know what?
Rym: There's a little bit of honor left among thieves like the tiniest bit.
Scott: We are punishing people who don't make but maybe it's just a huge campaign to get everyone to make backups Except I used to advocate for that in mid in high school.
Rym: I was like why don't I just write a malware that just nukes your computer and Just gives you and it fills your computer with nothing but pamphlets on how to have computer security?
Scott: Sure.
Rym: Yeah This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Rym: It's actually recorded at night And the patrons for this episode of GeekNights in order of the amount of money.
Rym: They give us in the continuing basis are Rebecca Dunn Nicholas Brando Alan Joyce Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette James David White Christian.
Rym: My girlfriend's last name is Kunst Kunst Jess mystady.com.
Rym: Sean Hayworth mechanical mind.
Rym: William Eisen rose.
Rym: Jeremy minor Spartacus.
Rym: Spartacus.
Rym: Spartacus Kimmy.
Rym: bachelor kajar tavishan.
Rym: Just your show.
Rym: show your star Tyler Heller Don testing your memory.
Rym: She like I remember you Sean Yeager Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Robert Lee Ryan parent drew openlander rare laval Brian Cedroni Rochelle, Monta.
Rym: No, no.
Rym: Finn Eric silver on can't melt steel beams.
Rym: Kinetic man Aaron series Chris mid.
Rym: give Chris Knox the North remembers for Sam Corddry Daniel Redmond Chris had Todd Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas, huh?
Rym: We literally just recorded the March Q&A.
Rym: So submissions are open for the April one and will actually record it before the end of the month.
Rym: for once It was ten questions and they were actually pretty good.
Rym: I think it was a good episode that we did.
Rym: We're not gonna do a show on Wednesday because we're heading out early Thursday morning to packs.
Rym: So instead I'm gonna put it that up and Expect a whole bunch of patreon content right after we get from packs because there's no more Convention stuff for us to do until Connecticut and then PAX Prime and packs awesome.
Rym: all that biz.
Rym: So now I leave you with something strange.
Scott: In the 26th century mankind faces an epic struggle for survival.
Scott: the forces of nature have spun wildly out of control.
Scott: Oh Mighty cities have crumbled and the dinosaurs have returned to reclaim the earth.
Scott: In this savage land one man stands alone Jack ten rank defending humanity in a world gone mad a world where only the strong survive a world of Cadillacs and dinosaurs.