Rym: It's Wednesday November 29th 2017.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm scared, and this is GeekNights tonight descending stories showa genroku rakugo and double suicide.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: so it's that time between the food holiday and all the other food holidays and What that means for Rym in the Rym household that I eat a lot of root vegetable.
Scott: Rym household Could be the Emily.
Rym: well I'm saying that it follows me and that it's not the bunny house and it really is the bunny household.
Rym: I come home and I go into the bedroom and movie stand in the middle of the room.
Rym: He just looks at me like you're bringing me my food But I'm saying that this is a problem that any household of which I am a member.
Rym: the problem follows me.
Rym: The problem is I had a lot of root vegetables roasted like celery ac and parsnips and Yeah celery root, okay, you've never seen that right?
Scott: would you eat the root of a celery?
Scott: because it's delicious When you could just eat a celery.
Rym: have you ever had roasted celery ac?
Scott: I could just eat celery though.
Rym: uh Roasted celery ac is literally possibly my favorite non potato root vegetable.
Scott: I thought you liked this early thing.
Rym: I like that too.
Rym: I thought I call anyway.
Rym: The problem with these was that I'm prone to farting.
Rym: on occasion as people who know me may know You think you're prone to fighting.
Scott: well Let me show you something.
Rym: Well.
Rym: Let me show you when I eat these kinds of foods.
Rym: Let's just say that it goes from being funny to being a problem And I will leave it at that.
Rym: This is what happens when Scott forgets his opening bit.
Rym: You're getting farts from me.
Rym: So you got any news on this comic?
Rym: Pretty much all comics today except for one movie.
Scott: right.
Scott: well.
Scott: You know basically a whole bunch of comic stuff is going down.
Scott: You know as a because you know there's.
Scott: the big news is that's been going on Pretty much constantly for the past feels like month.
Scott: I don't know exactly how long.
Scott: Basically every bad dude who sexually harass people is finally getting called out and shot down which is awesome.
Rym: We need this to happen even though It's a lot of people who are near and dear to a lot of like fans of things.
Scott: But I don't give a fuck every time I don't get.
Scott: it's almost like the more beloved someone is the more satisfying is to see them go down hard.
Scott: Yeah like even if mr.. Rogers went down, I'd be like I.
Rym: Yeah, well I mean if he did something.
Scott: I don't there's no way.
Scott: no I would bet my life Bet all.
Scott: I've been every penny.
Scott: I have Mr.. Rogers was totally good and not evil in any way, but anyway What's the saying?
Scott: so of course you know when you're a nerd.
Scott: we all know that in the nerd communities Right there's definitely a lot of bad dudes and and the nerd people have big online Presences more than other communities, right?
Scott: I'm sure like some bad dude in the I don't know What's a community magic the gathering?
Rym: Oh, it's the same problem there the bread baking community, right?
Scott: I'm sure there are many you know evil sexual harassing bakers out there, right?
Scott: Running bakeries taking advantage of the you know female apprentice bakers.
Scott: now I'm sure that exists, but there's not exactly a huge online presence of baking other than bread.
Scott: it and bread.
Scott: It is just like hey check out my bread.
Scott: It doesn't talk about the bread industry.
Scott: It's not at the level of there's Twitter bots going after people talking about this right anyway, but you know comics industry Right game industry you know very all these places have big online communities.
Scott: You know someone in the magic.
Scott: You know this drama going on a magic the gathering community right now Right such-and-such.
Scott: anyway What's going on as a result?
Scott: right people are not just getting called out for sexual harassment, but also for Sexual assault also, but pretty much any affront.
Rym: well right any upfront anything I've had a crime against just basic morals.
Scott: anything that is anything that is indecent or Distasteful is now being called out.
Rym: so well I think you've both indecent and distasteful.
Rym: deeply describe what we're about to talk about
Scott: right, so this is dude And his name is CV Cevalski, and we may have talked about him in the early days of GeekNights because it was around that time 2005 2006 ish that I was aware of this individual because I was buying comics.
Scott: and CV Cevalski is a dude who's like Some.
Scott: what he has things in common with me.
Scott: He's like a white dude from Connecticut.
Scott: Yeah, he works.
Scott: You know he works for Marvel Comics.
Scott: I enjoy comics Basically the same person basically no, but he's a madweeb right?
Scott: He wasn't one of those people that was like you know like like.
Scott: I would hear him talk on podcasts or see like the comics that he was writing or reading or whatnot.
Scott: and it's like Oh this person is actually a weeb who has legit knowledge about manga and such and isn't just like you know Someone who only likes Naruto or whatever or is pretending to like manga in order to promote it, right?
Scott: You know you see those people were like faking it and those people were like actually legit, right?
Scott: So he's basically a weeb that worked at Marvel Comics and actually his jobs were at Marvel were often related to his You know manga knowledges and such.
Rym: And now that So the news is you may know him by a different name and not realize it.
Scott: well Oh, so the the first news is that the he is now Editor-in-chief at Marvel Comics, which if you don't know is the number one creative job You can have at Marvel or DC is to be editor-in-chief.
Scott: I guess same thing at Shonen jump or any comics publishing place.
Scott: right if you're the editor-in-chief You're the number one creative person.
Scott: you're like the person who has to talk at the conventions.
Scott: It's like anyone above you only cares about money or is like a Disney exec or something, right?
Scott: You're in charge of the comics.
Scott: if it's in the comics.
Scott: It's your responsibility, right?
Scott: All the other editors writers artists are all under you.
Scott: It's the big job, right?
Scott: You finally after so many years I mean he's been there since at least 2005 when I just you know pride before then Worked his way up to that job.
Rym: now you'd think if he's a weeb Then he would be able to push toward Fixing some of the most egregious problems that are specific to floppy Marvel comics.
Scott: I know he.
Scott: there is actually some chance that he's gonna you know, do some good things that a you know Weeb manga type loving people like us who will appreciate like he you know He could.
Scott: you know, it's more likely that he will push Marvel Comics in a direction that we appreciate Than any previous editor which is why this is all such a shame.
Scott: such a shame that way back in the day Well, not too far back but backing up the
Rym: 2000s, which actually is a terrifyingly long time ago I
Scott: actually remember this and when it was brought up again I like I have this vague memory and now that the truth is out.
Scott: It's so clear, right?
Scott: There was a time when there was like Marvel manga verse and like some other Marvel comics that had like hints of you know, manga ness in them, right?
Scott: And I remember seeing some comics around that actually seemed it like.
Scott: it was a time where they were like getting Japanese creators to work on Marvel Comics, right and it was like ooh, and I remember seeing Plenty of you know, Japanese names on Marvel Comics Which came out of nowhere?
Scott: It was like suddenly they you know, they're like, oh man.
Scott: Manga is the hot thing I guess you know.
Scott: and that was the time when you know media play was not yet dead, right?
Scott: And there's you know, manga was the boom was happening.
Scott: So Marvel is jumping on that bandwagon a little bit and I remember seeing some names there that were not.
Scott: You know the names of known creators almost like perhaps Akira Yoshida, right?
Scott: so apparently Akira Yoshida is actually The current editor-in-chief of Marvel Comics CB Smolski fat white guy from Connecticut.
Scott: Yeah, so Uh Yeah, so on the one hand right people got to understand using a fake name to create things is in general a thing that has always happened for a very very long time and is acceptable in the right Circumstances.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: There are a lot of reasons someone might do that.
Rym: They might be writing say smut I need to separate it from their non-smut persona in case they want to get certain kinds of work down the road.
Scott: They might be actually, you know writing for some other author like you're writing a book but actually it's all gonna be published under like this one author's name and you're getting paid like a lot
Rym: of those pulp books that You might really
Scott: go to the grocery store and there's like a thousand spy novels all by the same name.
Scott: It's like no no, no, those are by like 20 different people.
Rym: It sucks and it's sad.
Rym: but a lot of people who are not white dudes will often use a. That makes them seem like a white dude.
Scott: to avoid that basic latent racism in the consumption of media in the u.s Right, like if you you know, you're gonna send your your pitch to a whole bunch of publishers and they racist.
Scott: but they're like And your name is you know, very foreign to the United States.
Scott: they might look it over or be prejudiced towards it.
Scott: So you said you change your name to some much more spellable and pronounceable name.
Rym: Do is make up a fake name of a minority when you're a white dude And then use that to gain some sort of advantage in your work.
Scott: Yeah You're trying to basically gain some sort of like cultural credibility.
Scott: right that you don't got Yep, and that is not okay, and he done dude that yep, and I guess he only did it for a year.
Rym: But it doesn't seem like he really apologized in depth.
Scott: I don't think he understands like.
Scott: he doesn't know what he did like he.
Scott: it's sort of like.
Scott: he knows that it was bad But he doesn't understand how bad right?
Rym: I was young and I even had a lot to learn back then.
Rym: it wasn't that long ago.
Scott: See, here's the one thing people gotta understand.
Scott: is actually someone made an app that will help you Apologize at least specifically for sexual harassment and assault but in general Right when you apologize.
Scott: first of all I got to talk about people who apologize who don't need to apologize.
Scott: people like say They're sorry when they didn't do nothing like you know don't do that right.
Scott: do not do that.
Scott: only Apologize if you actually hurt someone.
Rym: and if you did hurt someone well only apologize if you did something wrong Not just if you hurt someone right.
Rym: punch a Nazi.
Rym: I'm not apologizing.
Scott: well, no you apologies are for when you hurt someone you didn't mean to hurt someone and You regret hurting them.
Scott: you wish you had not done that and you need to make sure and you're letting people know this right and What you got to do to make a quality apology?
Scott: It's real simple number one.
Scott: Do not make any excuses in your apology.
Scott: Yeah, if you make an excuse you're not apologizing Right.
Rym: you're passing the buck right.
Scott: you must make no excuse.
Scott: the saying you're young and night nut that's an excuse.
Scott: You cannot make an excuse.
Scott: you just got to say I was bad.
Scott: I didn't do it Yep, and number two you got to try to fix it in whatever way you can and obviously you'll never hundred-percent fix anything because time Only goes in one direction, but you just got to do your best and people still might not forgive you.
Scott: That's okay Because you've done a bad thing.
Scott: They don't got to forgive you for shit.
Rym: Well.
Rym: Yeah, there's a. there's a very fine point there.
Rym: That's just because someone apologizes does not mean that the aggrieved party is under any album.
Scott: I'm sorry that like I murdered your whole family.
Scott: I hope you can forgive me.
Scott: I didn't make any excuses.
Scott: I'll try to make amends.
Scott: I will you know Try to fight crimes and also give you money, and you're gonna turn into Batman.
Scott: I'll do things to make up for my heinous ways and That doesn't mean you have to forgive me.
Scott: I fucking murdered your family.
Rym: Yep, right That's how we got the budget where we could undo that.
Rym: That's a whole different ballgame.
Scott: Oh, we just I mean if we could undo murdering the murdering wouldn't be wrong would it?
Rym: no Of course it seems like in free market it ends up being what anyway what it?
Rym: yeah You didn't read the culture book that gets into that actually.
Scott: yeah, all right, but the point is Apologize properly also your editor-in-chief of Marvel.
Scott: now people are gonna be yeah If you're about to get promoted to a job of visibility And you have any sort of skeleton in the closet I would suggest either How big or small I'm to either get the skeleton out of there, or don't get promoted.
Scott: just decline.
Scott: I'd be like no.
Scott: I'm good.
Scott: I'll stay at my second tier job.
Rym: Yep, you could.
Rym: now I guess there is a third way.
Rym: if you're evil If you go to the moon if you are confident you can hide that skeleton Forever.
Scott: you can't hide the skeleton.
Scott: the internet exists.
Scott: It is the ultimate skeleton finder.
Rym: Yep I mean in the modern world you can't make up a name because Anything I know about following Rym on Twitter is the internet is great at finding skeleton especially if the dancing You don't understand what a golden age this is.
Rym: for me the age of the skeleton has come I mean to share.
Rym: So in other news that's at least a little bit less Depressing.
Rym: if you weren't aware the breadwinner came out And you can totally go see it in a theater if you live in a real city.
Scott: So if you do not know right there was a studio of animation named cartoon saloon, and they made secret of cows Which you haven't seen.
Scott: why haven't you seen it?
Scott: Yeah?
Rym: It is.
Rym: it is One of the best movies like that that I'd ever seen in terms of just actually came out a scary long time ago.
Scott: Yeah, I did but anyway, but it's an Irish animation studio called cartoon saloon.
Scott: It's like the premiere animation.
Scott: it might be like the biggest animation studio in Europe.
Scott: They're like I even know over outside of US or Japan or Canada where else you know.
Scott: I was like I don't know a big animation studios from other places.
Rym: They make good stuff and most people if they know about them.
Rym: They know about Tom Moore specifically.
Scott: Tom Moore directed wrote that movie right.
Scott: he was like the creative drive behind that and then Due to the success of secretive cows which is like a labor of love that probably didn't make a lot of money They made song and a sea which song is basically a perfect movie like.
Rym: I literally can't really fault any aspect of it.
Rym: It's one of my favorite movies.
Scott: That was also Tom Moore and whatever but cartoon saloon, then it's like well.
Scott: What are they done since then?
Scott: well?
Scott: They are working on that wolf movie on a wolf movie the wolf walkers Which is used to see the trailer, and you already know that they made it.
Scott: It's probably gonna be oh my god.
Scott: It is a 100%.
Rym: just go see it.
Rym: Don't even don't.
Rym: we don't even need to review it.
Scott: Just go talk about it before or after because you're gonna see that anyway.
Scott: But you know make a little money on the side.
Scott: It's just a little collaboration work with a couple other Studios here now.
Rym: This was just Purdue.
Rym: Tom Moore was one of the producers, but this is directed by Nora Twomey mm-hmm I don't know.
Scott: I'm sorry.
Scott: I don't know how to pronounce your name Nora Yep, I also do not know but the breadwinner.
Rym: We saw it in the theater And I don't really want to give a full review to it primarily because you should just go see it.
Rym: Like most of what we might say is Moot because you're just gonna go see it.
Rym: however you need to see it because one is beautiful - it is deeply Touching and it will make you cry.
Rym: And Three it's a movie that needed to be made and needs to be seen because a lot of people Despite the fact that the u.s.
Rym: Invaded Afghanistan and tore down the Taliban and like left this chaotic realm behind.
Rym: It's about the people of Afghanistan And it's beautiful.
Scott: so the story of this movie is that you have this you know family living in Afghanistan And they don't got a lot of monies But you know their
Rym: host rise of the Taliban But not out of like the people who like the older people in the movie were in Afghanistan before the rise of the Taliban
Scott: before you know Russia and before yeah, right.
Scott: so anyway You know their life isn't great, but you know they're a family, but you know Muslims.
Scott: You know especially this very strict You know I guess only the very strict Taliban type ones who are you know even more sexist than any sexism You're gonna find in the United States right?
Scott: you know women.
Scott: women can't go out in public.
Scott: There are.
Rym: there are communities like that that are Christian in the United States.
Rym: I'm sure there are some of those weird towns upstate.
Scott: Oh, yeah, I'm just talking about you know average United States, right?
Scott: You're not gonna find that on New York City Street, right?
Scott: Yeah, well the point is that even the Hasidic Jews who are real bad in this regard are not that bad?
Scott: Oh, there's slightly less under the Taliban still way bad.
Rym: something very specific was that women were basically not allowed to do anything on escorted.
Scott: Yeah, you basically can't go outside.
Scott: You're supposed to stay in the house and be owned by your husband or brother or father or closest male relative And that's that's your life.
Rym: and something happens to this family and this young girl Has to dress as a boy to be able to do simple things like go out and buy food for her family.
Rym: mm-hmm and It goes on.
Rym: so I she's the breadwinner.
Rym: and what it's really about is the sort of The resilience and storytelling in history of the Afghani people who have dealt with regime after regime and What proxy wars the Cold War though throughout all this history?
Rym: It's sort of the story of how those people have continued to survive and make do and how there are both Like there are good and bad people in all these situations.
Rym: And I don't really want to say any more because seriously you should go see this movie.
Rym: It's fantastic, and it is currently still in theaters.
Scott: if you live in a real city It's not gonna be in every movie theater.
Scott: It's but you know if you live near a populated area It will be in the artsy theater.
Scott: I mean the thing is if you can't be for some reason you live in a boonies place or another country or somewhere where you?
Scott: Can't see this easily.
Scott: It will probably be streaming Downloading you know within a year within six months even maybe who knows right the secret of Kells end song of the sea.
Scott: you Can both like.
Scott: I think now they were on Netflix for a time But I think now if you want to see them legally you got a pan Amazon Yep, but you know I think they're like five ten bucks something like that.
Rym: What was interesting though is when we went to see it.
Rym: usually when we see a movie like a cartoon saloon movie like song of The sea or like any anime movie in New York It's like the same set of weebs show up every time like I don't know any of those people, but I see him Every time I see one of those movies in the theater.
Scott: Yeah, they'll always be like we went to the showing of ghost in the shell arise.
Scott: Oh look who's here.
Scott: Oh, we go to the showing of Satoshi kano.
Scott: look who's here.
Scott: It's the same weebs again.
Scott: Yeah, the New York weebs would go to anytime something is screened.
Rym: It was fascinating that I did not see those weebs in the theater for this, but the theater was still full.
Scott: Well usually when you go to we usually go like children's film festival screenings.
Scott: Yeah, those are usually full of like a whole bunch of families of kids and stuff.
Rym: Right, but if you go to like a Ghibli that isn't part of that or like any edge It's just.
Rym: it's just leaves all the way down.
Rym: mm-hmm not weebs.
Rym: the weebs did not seem to be the primary draw for this movie No, even though the weebs should probably all see it.
Rym: So yeah, go see this movie.
Scott: all the human beings should go see it probably.
Rym: So in some other news that I don't go too deep into Anime NYC as you know happened.
Rym: It was the sort of first new anime convention.
Rym: That's real in New York City.
Scott: We would have been there if not for PAX Unplugged yep, and it seems at least judging by social media people I know who went there and other things it seems to have been worth a subway ride to go to.
Scott: so if it does not Collide with anything next next year I will probably go to it.
Scott: yep.
Rym: So I think at this point unless this reliably overlaps with PAX Unplugged every year Which hopefully will not then I think anime NYC is going to become the sole anime convention that we perform at Because I can take the subway to it and as much as I love anime Boston because it's a fantastic anime convention It's just too much of a pain, and there's too many packs as we have to deal with now.
Scott: Oh By the way the next anime season is gonna begin in like early mid January so that means we got to do our Judging.
Scott: it's maybe late December when I'm not working.
Rym: we have to do another judge anime by its cover.
Scott: We're gonna do it for reals cuz I'm excited.
Rym: I'm they're going well.
Rym: I'm really happy with our judge.
Scott: everybody's cover one is going well.
Rym: well if you take account the ones we did at old anime Boston.
Rym: yeah, we videoed.
Scott: yeah, we're gonna keep it up though.
Rym: Yeah but anyway things Of the day.
Rym: so many of you listening to a Wednesday GeekNights are probably Creative in some way like you try to make games or you make art or something.
Rym: But I noticed there are a lot of people if you're not you should be who like make some art and make some games but then they see Professional stuff like triple-a stuff, and they feel inadequate.
Scott: Yeah, that's it that was made by a whole team of people who had a zillion dollars and worked for a very long time.
Scott: So I cannot compete with that.
Scott: the fact that you can even come close to that with some Adobe shit in your apartment Is a miracle.
Rym: so this video is a full panel like an hour-long panel from a convention.
Rym: But what it is is the basically creative directors of overwatch taking you
Scott: through course your favorite how
Rym: they made overwatch, but they show a lot of the early art and the early gameplay and You should see what overwatch looked like for more than a year of an entire team working on it.
Rym: And then you will feel a lot better about how much progress you're making with your own art.
Rym: Holy shit was it just like t-pose stick figures shooting garbage at each other Without animations for a long time?
Scott: yep It's already got so everyone at least ever.
Scott: a lot of nerds know all nerds should know that in Disney World land I don't know which one both.
Scott: Maybe there's like a secret restaurant that only like you know Special people get to go to.
Scott: it's like this something club.
Rym: Yeah, just like where Walt Disney would eat right one of those velvet ropes if pretty much any Culture.
Scott: and the thing about velvet ropes is that you know having a secret club.
Scott: if you actually want to do something secret No one knows about it because it's actually a fucking secret club.
Scott: right, but if you've got what usually when there's a club That's you know fancy for rich people only like they want a status symbol that they must use a velvet rope.
Scott: That's a let.
Scott: You know it's there to let you know.
Scott: you can't come in to make themselves feel better about keeping you out Right.
Scott: yeah, it's no good for me to you know have a secret club right if I want to You know rub my ego.
Scott: I got to put a velvet rope and have a bouncer at the door who doesn't let in schmucks.
Scott: Why?
Scott: why do they have the schmucks out there in the first place?
Scott: Why don't they let them in so that the people inside feel better about themselves and feel cool?
Rym: should we make a velvet rope at?
Scott: Arkhan yes, yes, we should.
Rym: if you pay Some people just give a special.
Scott: anyone who's not I'll just anyone who's not that guy can come through the velvet rope.
Scott: That's an inverse velvet rope the velvet ropes at the front door anyway however.
Scott: So yeah everyone knows about this Disney World restaurant.
Scott: I forget the name of but anyway, I learned today that in Japan.
Scott: There is a secret Nintendo bar Called 84 right.
Scott: so it's actually not that secret.
Scott: It's just in a hidden place, and it's not advertised.
Scott: and the way to get in is basically have someone who already can already a member Brings you there and then you keep you go enough and that you prove that you're not some fanboy who like screams and goes nuts when you see other cool people and You go enough times And you know you taught you have a conversation with the owner and some other another member and they decide yeah This person's chill, and then you're now a member and you can now bring new people and so forth.
Scott: so it's not super secret.
Scott: But it's secret enough that like people don't stumble into it randomly because like it's probably not on the street It's in like a location.
Scott: You could only go to if you knew where to go.
Scott: and the people who go there are you know a lot of Nintendo employees or Pro wrestlers or mangaka or other somewhat famous people Are the frequenters of this establishment.
Scott: so and what we have here is we have an article that a let me know this place Exists even though I'll never go there my whole life.
Rym: two tons of photos of the inside.
Scott: It's pretty cool Yeah, and the photos the inside show all the awesome stuff They have there.
Scott: because you know the place.
Scott: we should carry me a moto goes to get a drink.
Scott: It's probably gonna have some cool shit, and it sure does.
Scott: yeah It makes you want to open up a secret place, but I don't know how to do that.
Rym: look at that.
Rym: We gotta have money.
Rym: someone's gonna have money.
Scott: I don't have money.
Rym: Yeah, we have money.
Scott: one of that money Money to open a place.
Rym: so in the matter moment the booklet book was the fifth season.
Rym: You should read it cuz we did our episode on it.
Rym: I'm gonna pick my new book real soon after I finish a bunch of other stuff I'm working on.
Rym: we have a lull where we're doing real GeekNights episodes until January And then we got to go to PAX South.
Rym: I feel like we just had.
Scott: we're going to magfest first.
Rym: We did just have a pax.
Rym: We have so many paxes.
Rym: I'm literally losing track of them.
Rym: It's it's starting to be a problem.
Rym: I had to like make a spreadsheet to keep track of which paxes I have like sent our panels to or bought a hotel for?
Scott: did your enforcer paperwork?
Rym: Yeah, cuz now I had a lot of enforcer paperwork now.
Rym: I'm employed in like multiple states, and it's a pain in the ass to be honest.
Rym: Yeah So we will be at both magfest doing a ton of panels and playing a ton of games and at PAX South we're on Friday January 12th at 4 p.m.. In the Bobcat theater.
Rym: We're doing a brand new GeekNights panel talking to me balancing games.
Rym: So we're gonna talk about like half done how to stand on a seesaw.
Scott: Maybe a little less than half done.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, I think it'll be a good panel.
Rym: I'm feeling good about it.
Rym: I got a. it feels like the kind of panels we did like a decade ago where We have a looser structure to the slides and a lot more anecdotes and a lot more give-and-take instead of the like hyper-structured ones we did for a while recently where we have like 70 slides and like a very strict order of what we talked about
Scott: anyway.
Scott: Yeah, but you should go onto the internet and find us in all the places.
Scott: go to YouTube go to my youtube go to Rym's YouTube Instagram.
Scott: we got a GeekNights Instagram like what I've been trying to do is anytime.
Scott: There's like we do a thing as GeekNights like go to a convention or about whatever I try to like take a photo put it on the Instagram and people seem to like that.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Yeah, what is that like something?
Scott: I don't understand.
Scott: is general phenomenon is like you know you post up on Twitter Whatever what you know once in every little day or two that you know and people care a little bit.
Scott: But if you post like a selfie like you get likes like everybody.
Scott: yep It's like why I don't?
Scott: I don't like that.
Scott: my like pattern doesn't follow that.
Scott: I like things that are like oh If some post a selfie, I don't necessarily Automate auto like it.
Rym: I like a lot more things and the reasons I do are actually a surprisingly complex heuristic when I try to think about how to explain what I like and what I don't like.
Rym: Well what I click the like button on versus what I do not click the like.
Scott: well basically for the rest of December I don't have a lot to do.
Scott: so I'm doing a lot more in the streaming and possibly you know shorter video photo making department.
Rym: I was thinking which did you bring the SD card for the panel?
Scott: I think so these in my bag somewhere.
Rym: Yeah, well tiny it's hard easy to lose those things because we did at PAX Unplugged The kind of event that we've done like three or four times ever.
Rym: We did him at like PAX Prime and PAX East and East.
Rym: we did him in this normal sized room and a prime.
Rym: We did him in a room.
Rym: That's about the size of this GeekNights' room right here.
Rym: It was a tiny room that's hidden that no one knew about and For the first time we actually videoed that kind of event.
Rym: so it'll be interesting to have video of that kind of like Weird event that people could only experience if they went to a packs and knew about the weird event We were doing and we're gonna try to put that on YouTube which will be interesting.
Rym: Gotta figure out how to edit together all the b-roll we got and everything.
Rym: But anyway, uh Other than that right ahead of Wikipedia open up celeriac.
Rym: Guess let's talk about this manga.
Scott: Yeah, so I think it was last time we animate Boston.
Scott: We did the judge anime by its cover.
Scott: One of the anime was about rock who go and that's all we knew about it at the time because you were judging it by The cover.
Rym: now if you do not know rock ago is a traditional form of I'd say Japanese stand-up comedy.
Rym: But they don't stand up and sit down sit down comedy.
Scott: Yep But it's not as you always comedy.
Scott: It's it's storytelling but usually comedy.
Rym: It's a sort of Ritualized and formalized form of storytelling that has its own tropes.
Rym: Yeah, and it's own its own memes effectively, right?
Scott: We basically we found out at least I found out about it.
Scott: We went to Otakon one year and they had this guy come who was like a professional rock ago performer But he did it in English in English Which not too many people in the world do like.
Scott: maybe was he the only one.
Scott: if not, there's not many.
Scott: I think we were single digits.
Rym: Emily and I were actually looking for more of it because we rock ago.
Scott: Okay, was I was we were our friend invited us one-to-one recently, but it was not a good time.
Rym: Let's just say that there is not a lot of rock ago.
Scott: That is not in Japanese But if you speak Japanese, you can go to Japan and just like watch rock ago all fucking day real cheap.
Rym: Yep, in fact, I learned about that from the last two pages of this manga.
Scott: Anyway But anyway, so but that one time that I saw rock ago in person It was fucking hilarious and hysterical and oh my god is amazing.
Scott: It was really impressive.
Rym: like this manga We're gonna talk about there's a thing.
Scott: It's like a person sits there on a little cushion and you look all day All they have is like a fan and like another thing.
Scott: What's the other thing?
Scott: They have seems like there's a few things They could have I don't know Like a few objects that they use to help tell the story, but you know, the fan is the primary one.
Scott: But they don't stand up they just sit there and just using facial expressions a variety of voices, you know gestures They like bring that a whole story to life.
Scott: It's it's really, you know, like an excellent acting and storytelling the skills.
Scott: It's almost like a puppet show where just your body is the puppet and your voice.
Rym: Yeah, what I would say is that in the well a puppet show also uses the best right.
Scott: not always I'd say not always.
Scott: I'm just saying there's a lot of skill crossover between Puppeteer and Rakugo performer, right, but it's also.
Rym: it's one of those also acting it's you know but it's also one of those art forms that sort of self reinforcing and that because it builds up this repertoire of Rakugo specific tropes.
Rym: Those can then sort of feed on themselves and provide this like even further meta layer of storytelling.
Scott: I've anyway all of I've experienced in Rakugo is that it is a very positive and awesome thing is a Great, you know a piece of like really Japanese culture.
Scott: That is awesome.
Scott: And I enjoy it and I like it.
Scott: So I saw this anime about it and I'm like damn I should watch that but I didn't even though it was on Crunchyroll.
Scott: And then the manga came out and I'm like, oh, I'll just get that instead.
Scott: So I got the first volume of manga and I read it and then I said hey Rym Read this if we could do an episode and he actually read it.
Scott: Oh my god.
Rym: Well one Rakugo.
Rym: I mean, duh Yeah, and also it was short.
Rym: Volume one was yeah, we only read volume one full disclosure.
Rym: Yeah, but written by a Haruko Kumota, I don't know I don't know.
Rym: I never heard of them before but published by Kodansha Which usually it's I guess the interesting thing is that it is ostensibly a Jose manga So it's aimed ostensibly at middle-aged women.
Rym: Okay, which I can see Sure based on the story, but the story seems pretty good because it's actually got a bunch of elements.
Rym: There's sort of interweaving but it's very human like if there's nothing really fantastical about it or anything.
Rym: and The short version of my review before we go to get into the details is that I'll read volume two.
Scott: No, okay, you can read volume two.
Rym: I would keep going with this.
Rym: I thoroughly enjoyed it and I feel like though I have not seen the anime.
Rym: I think I would prefer to just read the manga because I don't know if anime could add much and the reason for that is that a big part of the way this manga is Put together is that it never really goes through a full rocker go performance.
Scott: You don't actually see a lot of rocker go happening like they talk about.
Scott: it'd be like even one piece.
Scott: You didn't see the fights.
Scott: You just saw like oh love you went to fight someone and then afterwards It's like well, you really kicked his ass.
Scott: Yeah, you know, they don't show a lot of the rocker go in the manga.
Scott: Just you know, they give you a sense like ah someone is performing.
Scott: This is the thing they're performing.
Scott: They're doing a good job.
Scott: They're doing a bad job, you know, this is the mood of the of the situation But it's only be like a couple panels.
Scott: It's sort of like the inverse of no down make on table that music And it was able to spend like I think showing you the whole musical performance played the whole song Everyone's crying in real time.
Rym: But reading the manga was not actually that satisfying unless you know the music that well And if you don't then you're gonna miss a lot, which is why the anime is a little bit.
Rym: Yeah, I'm actually plays the rock Mon and off and you hear it and you feel it.
Rym: and they do a good job.
Rym: but here with rocker go Actually doing the performance I think would take away from it because The manga does a good job of sort of showing like one frame of the person making one face than making a different face or like a few of the words or like a few of the plot points of the rocker girl story.
Rym: they're telling give you the gist of it and then Instead it just gives you an impression of how powerful that performance was Unless your imagination run away with
Scott: is using animation I don't think or even just filming a rocker go performance with a camera as opposed to sitting there in person.
Scott: You know, it's sort of like watching a Broadway show just on video, right?
Rym: If you say it's the same like I don't know what to say to you, right?
Scott: It's like the power is taken out of it.
Scott: So I don't think it's possible or at least extremely extremely difficult to capture rocker Go performance by animating the actual the performance, right?
Scott: Even if you got a rocker go person to come in and do the voice acting for it It like it wouldn't come across.
Scott: so even if you were trying to pretend like whoa that person did a great job But you as the viewers who just watch that same performers wouldn't feel that they did a good job.
Scott: So it wouldn't work.
Rym: Yep, right cuz whenever you have like if initial D showed just like really bad car animation as Opposed to really bad people animation initially would not be worth watching.
Scott: Anyways, so the plot here is sort of different from other, you know, typical anime plots like say an initial D Where oh, there's someone who's secretly the master.
Scott: It's like no there's someone who's already the master.
Scott: There's another master who is dead.
Scott: The other master who is dead's daughter lives with the master who is still alive who seems to believe that the alive master Caused his dad.
Scott: living with someone who you believe murdered your father, which is already like, okay Doesn't make a lot of sense and there's definitely something up with him.
Rym: Yes, he has Yakuza connection, right?
Scott: Even though he is a master of rock ago He's not like you usually think of like a wise master like someone you just you just look up to them.
Scott: They're great like a. you know, it's a lot of characters like that.
Scott: and then yeah, right where it's like crazy bunta.
Scott: Yeah, crazy bunta.
Scott: It's just like there's not any negative thing about them.
Scott: It's like they're just the master.
Scott: It's like no.
Scott: this master who's still alive while he's amazing at rock ago seems totally shady and untrustworthy.
Scott: Well, I guess all but he's also complex.
Rym: what I appreciate is that all these characters that we know of in this manga are More complex and human than I typically expect when I pick up some random comic.
Rym: Yep, and their motivations are reasonable in so far as you can read them and Like this guy acts in a complex manner like he doesn't always react the way you would expect but you watch it usually boots of reacts Exactly the way you would expect.
Scott: he's just a trope character.
Scott: He's a wise old master.
Scott: the trope There's no the characters in this are not tropes of any kind.
Rym: So, uh, the main character.
Scott: They're not cliche.
Scott: The main character is really weird.
Scott: It's a random dude who just walks up to the master on the manga.
Scott: This is really disjointed.
Scott: I think actually I really don't like this cuz it's like do like.
Scott: it's such a bad setup.
Scott: You're like what the hell's going on.
Rym: I like it because Does the stir?
Rym: it buries the lead the the main characters.
Scott: nice that it's different But it's it's like yeah, you follow the rules of storytelling for a reason.
Scott: It's like you just threw me in.
Scott: I don't know what the fuck's going on here.
Scott: But basically there's a random dude just goes up to the master on the street and is like make me your apprentice.
Scott: and the master Has never taken an apprentice before.
Scott: and he does.
Scott: and that's like literally how it starts like page one.
Scott: Yeah, it's like I don't know who this guy is.
Rym: You don't know this masters, you know, nothing in multiple of the characters there's this buried lead of.
Rym: she thinks he murdered her dad and yet So little is known about that situation that it's sort of like.
Rym: it sort of strikes you My father.
Scott: it's like you have a father.
Scott: this isn't your father.
Scott: Well, yeah it's like.
Rym: and then like the more you think about it the more concerned you get about what this story is actually about.
Rym: and The main character is the craziest one because it's like yeah.
Rym: Well, I guess he was in the.
Rym: he was in jail All right, he got out of jail.
Rym: What it?
Rym: what were you in jail for and what was his answer?
Rym: He says like I don't remember.
Scott: Yeah He kind of just like brushes it off and tries to move past that but meanwhile a bad dude from his past comes and tries To take him back to a life of crime.
Rym: I do like how that situation resolved.
Scott: I was actually my favorite part of the thing.
Scott: That was a real good moment cuz it's like oh what's gonna happen here?
Rym: Yeah, so, uh, I don't know what else we could really say other than that I like it and I want to continue reading it.
Scott: I mean, it's not.
Scott: I mean I like it but it's like hardly because so I get a pay.
Scott: I don't think I'm gonna pay money because it's sort of like.
Scott: it's you know, it's just the disjointedness of the story.
Scott: It's like it was hard to care about the characters too much.
Scott: It's like, you know, some of them are cool like the you know, the master or whatever.
Scott: But it's like I can't care about someone.
Scott: you didn't build you or grow me on you Just threw me in.
Scott: and then you know the connections between parts of the story.
Scott: It's almost like I mean obviously was probably released in some magazine one chapter at a time.
Scott: Well, obviously the master to tell where the chapters are cuz suddenly it's like what we were doing this now.
Rym: Clearly the live master and the dead master were in a romantic relationship Yeah, and clearly the alive master sees something of the person who is dead in this dog Conrad Kraling like Main characters why he's agreed to take an apprentice after never taking one before.
Rym: but then he isn't actually an apprentice He's basically just a pet.
Rym: and then the way the story I like how the main care the main character is the only one.
Rym: Yes, the main character somehow is gaining actual Rakugo skills yeah, and I don't know what the old man's game is No, and I don't know if he has a game or if he is also an impulsive person.
Rym: He got game Yeah, but I liked it.
Rym: and if you are interested at all in Rakugo It does a good job much like no dame cantabile or the wine one drops of God It will teach you about Rakugo.
Scott: That was actually my second favorite part was as a part where someone describes like how the theaters where you go to watch Rakugo work Almost like they.
Scott: it was an advertisement for Rakugo, which I guess the manga partially is Yeah, but it's like oh that was very informative.
Scott: And now I've actually learned a whole ton about Rakugo, which is the thing I was interested in anyway, and anytime you learn more about something you're interested in you'd feel them pretty good Yeah, but as a result It does the thing.
Rym: that usually is a fault in a lot of manga where it'll leave Japanese words in many conversations Untranslated in romanji and then have a note like this is what that word means Which usually
Scott: has a decision of the American publisher, but English this
Rym: specific case Because these are all like sort of Rakugo specific words that are subtly different from
Scott: say you couldn't translate the word Rakugo to something else that wouldn't work.
Rym: Like you're gonna change like you're gonna change like the name for the special Rakugo theater to just the Rakugo theater Even though like that there's sort of a lot of meaning built into it.
Rym: I'm not saying go full nakama like a lot of people like to but this Particular manga seems to do it in a way that is acceptable.
Rym: Whereas I would not accept that from other kinds of stories.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night.
Rym: and the patreon patrons for this episode You think nights are Ellen Joyce Heidi McNichol Amanda do shed a shimmering ruby obelisk hanging in the sky.
Rym: my state calm Jeremy minor Anyone.
Rym: but if I'd like to find six car monorail charts option, you know, I never ever wonder why we're here.
Rym: Semper Fi bitch Matthew Smith Chris Reimer Joe sure Joe star Rebecca Don Ren from New Zealand captain shingo Akasi Finn Daniel Redmond Nicholas Brandau Shervin von Horrell Don Schleich Rochelle, Monta, Nona Drew open Lander Chris Knox Chris midkiff rare Laval Clinton Walton sailor Vista Ryan Perrin Brian's Adroni 421 creations Thomas Hahn Sam Corddry Sean Klein James David White and Sean Yeager.
Rym: That or reordering of the patrons really messed me up more so than I expected.
Rym: But yeah, stay tuned for some steamed hams in your future.
Rym: And now I leave you with something that has nothing to do with steamed hams The rate ourselves hate ourselves viciously Just for a kick we knock you Oh.