Rym: It's Thursday, February 16th, 2017.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, we're talking about lunch.
Rym: Scott keeps dropping something back there.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So yeah, we're live streaming this one video, because as you guys might know- Because you got nothing better to do?
Rym: No.
Rym: So, well, partly, I've been trying to like set up my live streaming such that if I'm in some game and I want to live stream it, I don't have to do anything.
Rym: So I got like a light and all these cameras, and I like upgraded all the equipment.
Scott: My problem is I always try to get fancy, right?
Scott: If I do it a PC game, I could just use a webcam, but it's like, no, I want to get my- Dude, this webcam is pretty baller, C920.
Scott: I want to get my real camera going on, right?
Rym: Yeah, look at that.
Rym: That looks pretty good, right?
Scott: If I'm sitting on my couch, I want to get my country man in there with my wireless.
Scott: It's like I keep wanting to hook up more stuff, and that's why it takes a long time to set up, and then- That's why, because I got this all set up already because of the mixer.
Scott: That doesn't mean that's not going to help, but then the other thing is like- Why?
Rym: I just plugged the country man in there.
Rym: I could just plug it in.
Rym: It just works.
Scott: And then if I set all the stuff up, and it's like, well, I could just leave it that way, but it takes up so much room.
Scott: It's a big mess.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: So I take it all apart.
Rym: So yeah, it's Thursday.
Rym: Talk about whatever.
Rym: So I was looking at Google, looking for news that might have happened, and I saw Great Wall trending, and I was like, "Wait,
Rym: what?".
Scott: I mean, it's not the Chinese Great Wall, but it is.
Rym: Yeah, well, sort of.
Rym: So there's this movie, if you don't know, that is called The Great Wall.
Scott: I only know about this because someone sent me the trailer, and I watched it.
Rym: So I saw the trailer before Rogue One, I think.
Scott: Oh, I didn't see it then.
Rym: I think I saw it then.
Rym: I saw it in the theater.
Scott: I saw Rogue One on Christmas.
Scott: The trailer for this wasn't out yet.
Rym: Well, first, I saw this trailer where the whole crowd is like, "What the fuck is this movie?
Rym: What is this
Rym: about?".
Rym: Like, at first, we all thought it was based... You know those movies they make from crappy, light teen, young adult fiction novels?
Rym: Like I guess Hunger Games was pretty good, actually, even though it was from those.
Rym: But like Maze Runner.
Scott: I didn't watch any Hunger Games.
Rym: Yeah, the movies were pretty good.
Rym: But like Maze Runner, those kind of level.
Rym: I thought it was going to be like that, but then it seemed weirder and weirder, and then we used power suits, and at the very end of the trailer, the logo came up, and we figured it out, and it was literally like a dark and gritty Power Rangers reboot.
Scott: I mean, the point of this Great Wall here is it's a movie where white dudes save China from demons on the other side of the Great Wall.
Rym: That's why they built it.
Scott: So if you are... It's like an alternate history where they built the Great Wall to stop demons instead of Mongolians.
Scott: I don't know if they're trying to say Mongolians are demons.
Scott: I like Mongolia.
Scott: It's pretty cool.
Scott: But anyway, so if you're a normal person, this seems like a cool idea.
Scott: that's original.
Scott: But if you're a nerd, a real nerd who knows real nerd things, you'll know that this is L5R, the Legend of the Five Rings, or it was a giant wall, which was the Great Wall, basically.
Rym: Even though that game was mostly like Japanese-esque.
Scott: It was everything that was stereotypically Asian samurai kung fu, etc.
Scott: My honor.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And on the other side of the wall was literal hell, which is not only a trope you see in L5R and, I guess, this movie, but also even in things like Wheel of Time, where if you go too far north, it's awful, right?
Scott: It's like, don't cross this line, this bad stuff on the other side.
Rym: I remember we were playing that L5R game.
Scott: We're the clan that defends the good part of the clan.
Scott: But I mean, in Wheel of Time, it was the people who lived in the northeast, right?
Scott: They defended the rest of the land or the society from the evil demon stuff that lives on the other side of their castle or whatever.
Rym: They're just next to Mordor.
Scott: Mordor is the same thing, there's a big giant wall and the bad guys are on the other side of it, right?
Rym: Of course, the bad guys are kind of also defending that wall, like it's kind of, anyway.
Scott: Right, but anyway, this is just another one of those, there's a wall with bad guys on the other side.
Rym: But even the styling, like the way they draw the armor and this color style and all the weird color grading they're doing, it even looks like L5R art, like the legit art in the role-playing system and such.
Rym: But yeah, as far as I can tell, this movie is just white dude appropriation times a billion and I can't imagine wanting to actually see this movie.
Rym: And even worse, when I saw the trailer in the theater, the CG actually looked bad.
Scott: So I read a story somewhere that's like, people watch the trailer and saw some extra awful CGs in it and they pulled the trailer and put out a different one or something because it was like- I wonder if I saw that one.
Scott: Someone did some lazy action in the trailer, right?
Scott: You know, a little rush job.
Rym: Oh, this is a savage review of this thing.
Rym: Savage.
Rym: Outside of the romantic quipping between two characters.
Scott: Oh, this is someone who saw the whole movie?
Rym: The dialogue is aggressively simple.
Scott: I mean, it's not summer yet.
Scott: Isn't this a summer blockbuster type thing?
Scott: Why are you putting this shit out in February?
Rym: February blockbuster.
Rym: What else is going on in February?
Scott: You could put out like, you know, the romantic movie for Valentine's day or whatever.
Rym: I'm sure that movie also came out.
Rym: What movies are even in the theater right now?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Still Star Wars because everyone has.
Rym: Let's see.
Scott: Just go to Fandango.
Rym: I'm just going to have to see if Google will just tell me.
Rym: Movie times, movie in Manhattan.
Rym: All right.
Scott: Oh, Lego Batman is the big movie right now, actually.
Scott: People said it's pretty good, but I imagine it's just as funny as the- I thought, you know, other people liked- I saw the Lego movie and everyone else loved that, and I was like, man.
Scott: I thought it was okay.
Scott: So I was like, man.
Rym: Why is it auto scrolling?
Rym: That's weird.
Scott: So if people love Lego Batman- There you go.
Rym: That's like a legit critical movie.
Scott: That's been out for a while though.
Scott: That's not new.
Rym: But it's still in the theaters.
Scott: Sure.
Rym: Why is this auto scrolling?
Rym: That's weird.
Scott: Your mouse is broken.
Scott: Nope.
Rym: It's just this one website.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Lego Batman Fist Fight.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: I don't know what that is.
Rym: 50 Shades Darker.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Whatever.
Rym: John Wick 2.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Rym: There you go.
Rym: Did you ever see John Wick?
Rym: Nope.
Rym: John Wick is fantastic, and I highly recommend.
Rym: if you're the kind of person who likes the kind of movies that I like, you'll actually really like John.
Rym: If you like The Matrix, you'll like John Wick.
Rym: If you like The Raid- Wait.
Scott: So if you like Blues Brothers, you'll like John Wick?
Rym: Probably.
Rym: I think the overlap between the people who like those two movies is pretty good.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: A Dog's Purpose.
Rym: Split.
Rym: Rings.
Scott: Is Rings a sequel to The Ring?
Rym: Actually, yeah.
Rym: I think it is.
Scott: Coming out of the TV.
Rym: First you watch it, then you die.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: It's almost two fucking hours long, too.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: Wow.
Scott: I mean, it's a horror movie.
Scott: It's cheap to me.
Rym: So yeah.
Rym: Don't go see The Great Wall.
Rym: Go see John Wick.
Rym: Go see the actual Great Wall.
Scott: That'd be awesome.
Scott: I want to go there.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Actually- Can you ride a bicycle on The Great Wall from end to end?
Rym: I won't get to go.
Rym: Not all of it is the part you're thinking of.
Rym: Not all of it has that flat part on the top.
Scott: Oh, really?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Only the most fortified sections do.
Rym: Other sections are basically earthworks.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Also, they've faked it.
Rym: They've cemented over a lot of the top of it for structural reasons.
Rym: There's a lot of problems with The Great Wall.
Rym: Not looking so good.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Too many demons attacking.
Rym: Well, I've got ... Oh, I pulled it up on the stream, but I showed it to you.
Rym: I've left it in the other room.
Rym: Funnily enough, because we're talking about The Great Wall, maybe that's why I thought about the movie, I had on my desk a minute ago, and it's currently sitting on my.
Rym: This Is Fine dog.
Rym: I have an actual piece of the Theodosian Wall from Byzantium.
Scott: Well, it didn't last too long, did it?
Rym: That wall lasted a long time.
Rym: It's still there.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Scott: It's not ... You can get right through.
Scott: No problem.
Rym: You can climb inside of it.
Rym: You know who's living in it?
Rym: Homeless people.
Rym: Homeless, dangerous, armed homeless people who threatened me with bodily harm if I did not vacate the inside of the Theodosian Walls.
Scott: I guess it's well defended.
Rym: So you got any news or anything?
Scott: So this dude, this is gaming news, but whatever, there's plenty of gaming news.
Scott: This dude, he pre-ordered Nintendo Switch, just like me, which is coming in two weeks.
Scott: You know, I'm glad I didn't wait in the line at PAX South to play something that's going to be at my house in two weeks, but he just got it in the mail early, randomly, by luck.
Scott: I guess whoever he ordered it from mailed it to him too early.
Scott: They got it in stock and they weren't supposed to ship him.
Rym: Oh, someone messed up.
Rym: Someone might be in trouble.
Scott: Someone fucked up.
Scott: So he got one and he posted a video online of all the menus and stuff, you know.
Scott: So way to go.
Scott: Awesome.
Scott: Now we know.
Rym: Did he get games too or just the Switch?
Scott: I mean, he didn't.
Scott: The video is not that long.
Scott: It's like I would have been post.
Rym: I would be live streaming 24/7 like I'm here.
Scott: No one else can compete with you.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You would instantly get all the followers on Twitch.
Scott: Like I have the Switch.
Scott: I am on the Twitch.
Rym: You know what I do?
Rym: I do a let's play.
Rym: I just sit there and be like, guys, what do you want me to do?
Rym: What do you want me to click on?
Rym: Let's go.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Want to see some settings?
Scott: I get the software update.
Scott: I go to the eShop.
Scott: I buy the games.
Scott: I need to load it up.
Scott: I mean, they might shut down your channel, but it's like I just go for it anyway.
Scott: I'd be like, deal with it.
Rym: It'd be worth it.
Scott: I keep switching different YouTubes.
Scott: I'd set up my own streaming.
Rym: You'd be switching?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I'm going to do that, though, once the Switch comes, I'm going to go home and plug it in and stream it up.
Rym: I was going to sit on your couch and join you.
Scott: There shouldn't be that much competition on March 3rd because who else has the technology to do this is going to do it, pre-ordered the Switch on Amazon, et cetera, et cetera.
Rym: I would, but I'm actually going to be in London, so I won't be around.
Scott: That's a shame.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I wasn't going to even pre-order the Switch.
Scott: If you live in New York, if you can get to New York City on March 3rd and you want to come play Bowerman.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Let me know.
Rym: I guess the weekend after that was PAX, and then.
Scott: Oh, wait.
Scott: Wrong convention.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: You may recall some time ago, I did a thing of the day that was YouTube comment reconstructions.
Rym: These are.
Scott: Oh, it was like people saying YouTube comments.
Scott: You ever seen these?
Scott: I think I'd barely, I half remember this.
Rym: They're artistically done.
Rym: I almost feel like I should play a clip, but they're.
Scott: You're good.
Rym: So they're artistically done, black and white, like good acting, like really good acting.
Scott: It's like the old guy.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: It's like rest in peace, Nelson Mandela and the other guys just like nodding along.
Rym: You're a good actor and Bruce Almighty.
Rym: And then the other guy just like slowly raises his eyebrow and starts looking up at him.
Rym: Like, please, please tell me that you are trolling.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: So that was a series.
Rym: They did several, many episodes of this.
Scott: Why are you reusing an old thing of the day?
Rym: Well, because I won my everything of the day was one of these, like one episode.
Scott: And now you think of it as all the rest.
Rym: No, I think of the day is the series finale occurred.
Scott: Oh, they're done.
Rym: They the final episode is a final episode in every regard.
Rym: It is not to spoil, but basically it's the two actors, the main guys sitting in like this garden and they're having a conversation about how like freedom of speech is so important and I can swan like Obama, get out of my emails and trolling people.
Rym: And meanwhile there's a cowboy hunting them down with a wanted poster and the cowboy is slowly like reciting the terms of service of youtube out loud as he stalks them.
Rym: And it is quite a finale.
Rym: This series is must watch youtube.
Rym: Like the fact that they only have, they have under a hundred thousand subscribers is kind of sad to me.
Rym: This stuff is like a internet.
Scott: I like how it's dead parrot channel.
Rym: They do a bunch of other stuff too.
Rym: This is just like one thing they did.
Scott: All right, so there's some people in Astoria where I live and they made good morning Astoria, which is a parody of, you know, morning shows like the today show or a good morning America or whatever.
Scott: But it's, it actually has a little bit of like actual truth in it, but also mostly jokes.
Scott: But then there's actually like, once you get towards the end of it, there's like an actual like, you know, musical performance, which is like legit.
Scott: And then that's most of the rest of the, the end of the show, but like a pretty good job for, you know, like we could do this, but like not as good as they could.
Rym: No, I was about to say not as good as they could.
Scott: So I mean, if you live in Astoria, you'll understand more of this cause it's a lot of neighborhood jokes, but also, you know, some general jokes that anyone would laugh at.
Rym: They're like two full production quality levels above us.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Cause look like he's still close to the green screen.
Rym: Like you can see the shadowing.
Scott: No, that's actually like a thing they printed out, I think.
Rym: I don't think it's a green screen because I could have whatever it is.
Rym: He's too close to it.
Scott: At some point the camera moves and it's like, it looks like they just printed out on a big board or something.
Rym: That's pretty common.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: But yeah, you can, you can tell he's close to it.
Rym: The thing is we'd have the same problem because they're in, they're just in their apartment.
Scott: They're like, you know, and then the musical performance, they literally like take the camera, go down the stairs, go out the front door and the guys are outside with the music right on the sidewalk.
Scott: It's like, it's that, it's that sort of thing, right?
Scott: It's like, I got a lot of that like public access vibe plus youtube vibe plus.
Rym: no look how much better it looks when they're outside in the sunlight.
Scott: plus like an SNL like actual professional improv kind of vibe only has like 600 views.
Rym: A story is not exactly the most happening place in, you know, I just feel bad when something that is clearly good is not well known.
Scott: It's going to get some more views now.
Rym: I hope so.
Rym: All, all, all 11 of, whoa, there's a lot of people watching the street, all five listeners who know about his story.
Rym: There are 11 people watching this live for some reason.
Rym: Eleven people.
Scott: They don't watch me when I play a stream video game and 11 people don't come.
Rym: I get, I've gotten as many as 30 watching me play overwatch, which I don't know why.
Rym: I don't comment.
Rym: I just kind of sit there staring sullenly at the screen as I lose over and over again.
Scott: I keep trying to comment cause I know it's boring as hell when I'm sitting there doing nothing and I'm not getting it.
Rym: What's up gamers?
Rym: Welcome to my Minecraft stream.
Scott: Not like that.
Scott: I usually try to like talk about like the design of the game.
Scott: Like, Oh look, this part of the game is poorly designed.
Scott: Oh look, this part of the game is well designed.
Scott: And if I know about the game, I'll be like, Oh, you know, like I know about this game.
Scott: Let me tell you what I know.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: The problem is that requires the game.
Rym: I know.
Rym: Like I was saying, if I do sieve five.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Like I can talk forever.
Rym: Like here is exactly how this mechanic works out of us.
Rym: But if it's sieve six, I'm like, I guess I'll build a Hansa.
Rym: cause I guess I just sit there like reading text on the screen for five minutes.
Rym: That's fine.
Rym: This has got seven.
Rym: I'm giving this it's 18th.
Rym: Like here we go.
Scott: You didn't even watch it.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I'm confident in it.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: I am confident in it based on what I saw here.
Rym: So in the meta moment, the book club book is Dune.
Rym: The Dune.
Rym: D-U-N-E.
Scott: We're doing it.
Scott: Not the video game Dune.
Scott: Not the movie Dune.
Scott: The book Dune.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: Not the board game Dune.
Scott: And not any of those other Dune books.
Scott: Only the original first one.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: Because I've never read the whole thing.
Scott: It's by Frank.
Scott: How you been?
Rym: I know a lot about Dune, but I'm really interested to see one, how many nerd references do I miss?
Rym: because I don't realize they're from Dune to, uh, is the book at, will the book grab me with my adult sensibilities in a way that it did not when I was younger, middle school Scott could not get past much of Dune, but three more important.
Rym: will my like exposure to things like the Prince of nothing make its density feel sparse.
Scott: Well, I mean, look, you know, wheel of time was another famous nerd thing.
Scott: Not quite as famous as Dune, but out there, uh, a lot of stuff.
Rym: Like now I know the Heron.
Rym: Like I learned the Heron blade is from that Heron spear is better.
Rym: Heron spear is better.
Scott: Herons.
Scott: I mean, Heron anything is like, if I ever make a game that has like equipment in it or something, the Heron, whatever is like the highest level of stuff.
Rym: The problem with the Heron's blade was that it kind of Peters out and there's way bigger stuff later.
Rym: Like they work it up so much and it's like, oh yeah, everybody, you meet like 20 people who have them, but the Heron
Scott: spear
Rym: was used once in before the books and I feel
Scott: like it
Rym: being used again is going to be the end of the Prince of
Scott: nothing.
Scott: I mean, like, look, like King Arthur is like, you got like Excalibur, right?
Scott: And it's like, first of all, there is nothing better than Excalibur lying around anywhere.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: What about, well, yeah, the only thing wrong with Excalibur is like, he gets it right a fucking way from the lady of the lake and then he's always got it.
Scott: and that's pretty much it.
Scott: It should be like, they should tease you with the legend of Excalibur, like, you know, it's out there.
Scott: It's a Chekhov's gun.
Scott: Someone's going to get it at some point, but don't get it until the end.
Rym: Oh, no.
Rym: So, oh, he's got Excalibur.
Rym: Great.
Rym: Now I got to go find the Holy grail.
Rym: That's way more important.
Scott: They spend the whole fucking book on the Holy grail.
Rym: I'm thinking about the movie once.
Scott: a future King is the real deal.
Scott: All others are not the real deal.
Rym: He should have stayed with the geese.
Rym: That was a way better life.
Scott: I also would have stayed with the geese.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: That goose girl shitting on everybody.
Rym: Hanging out with the goose girl.
Scott: Making a big racket.
Scott: They didn't even guns then.
Scott: So what are you going to do about it?
Rym: Also like geese got culture.
Rym: Like they're talking about like visiting their aunts and uncles and all their like dinner parties and nonsense.
Rym: Like I remember the geese have a surprisingly modern culture.
Scott: Also, you know, uh, Merlin pretty much like, you know, Merlin backwards.
Rym: I feel like living backwards is not the best way to live.
Rym: It is.
Rym: So yes, the previous book club was Rebecca.
Rym: The episodes up.
Rym: You should read that book.
Rym: If you didn't read it, you should also watch that movie if you've never seen it.
Rym: And then you should listen to our review where, uh, if you want late crit, go somewhere else because other people have done that way better.
Rym: We just talk about the book from our own perspective.
Rym: Uh, we're going to be live at PAX East 2017 doing a panel called play dirty to win on Friday at 6pm in the bumblebee theater.
Scott: Such Phil.
Rym: I've been doing some, uh, research for this panel.
Rym: Like a lot more than usual.
Scott: I think it reeks of effort.
Rym: It does.
Rym: The slides are looking good.
Rym: Uh, I learned a lot about formal heuristics and uh, I got some stuff.
Rym: The gaze heuristic is the tip of the iceberg.
Scott: Nobody cares.
Rym: Fast and frugal failure of heuristics is the order of the day.
Rym: Uh, so, uh, I guess we never talked about lunch.
Scott: Also known as crab people ideas.
Scott: We got nothing else to talk about on Thursday.
Scott: Send your Thursday show ideas that anything that in the world that's not that we a haven't done.
Rym: B is not technology, is not games, is not comics, anime, manga, reviewing things you haven't seen, general protest packs versus board game geek convention.
Scott: That's just like news.
Scott: that's not even tennis.
Rym: How tennis is awesome.
Rym: That's gaming, but that would be a good Tuesday show.
Rym: Sure.
Rym: Like we're talking about why tennis is what, like a nearly perfect sport or a perfect game at least Thursday ideas Thursday.
Rym: The day that could be literally anything is the hardest goddamn day.
Scott: Sure.
Rym: Well I guess.
Rym: So I suggested we do lunch and Scott said, I feel like we already did it.
Rym: Uh, not only have we not done lunch, but we have not even done brunch.
Scott: I'm pretty sure we have.
Rym: Nope.
Rym: In fact, the only, if I search for lunch, I find one punch man.
Rym: That's an a bunch of dwarves and Mike Tyson's punch out.
Scott: the hell is a bunch of dwarves.
Rym: I'm going to find out to that and GeekNights burning dwarf.
Rym: Oh, we talk about, remember when you ran that burning door fortress game?
Scott: That was a good game.
Rym: We just tell the story of that.
Scott: and why did we do a show like that and something so shitty?
Rym: and then we used it as a segue into remember project Dorf.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't go anywhere either.
Rym: I hear it.
Rym: Get hub.com.
Rym: A fresh.
Scott: There isn't even really, I mean that's probably still there, but it never got to the point of code that ran, I think seven years ago.
Rym: you added some basic documentation, fixed a color bug.
Scott: Uh, does it even do anything?
Rym: Oh no, you didn't.
Rym: Lack of cheese made the last updates.
Rym: This is a may 6th, 2010.
Scott: does it even run or do anything?
Rym: I know there's all this stuff in here.
Scott: Sure.
Rym: It's just python.
Rym: I can, I should, I should go like, should.
Rym: you guys should download this repo and like run stuff and see what happens.
Rym: Here's random movers.
Rym: Here's some python code.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Here's a random mover.
Scott: I can't imagine anything will happen.
Rym: Any random mover, a mover that moves randomly between adjacent nodes.
Rym: Mine.
Scott: Mine.
Scott: Good times.
Rym: Anyway, so I feel like lunch is an okay show because lunch is the forced meal where you don't, like.
Rym: I feel like lunch is the meal you have the least day to day control over where like what you eat because you're always at work or something.
Rym: Like you're very limited.
Rym: You're not going to go far.
Scott: I think it's the most important meal.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Cause I can skip breakfast.
Rym: I usually do.
Scott: It's like, you know, even if you eat a breakfast, it only gets you so far, you know, through the day before you lose an energy.
Scott: And then it's like, you got to rest of the day.
Scott: You got to make it through.
Scott: You must eat a lunch.
Scott: It's like, you can even skip a breakfast and just sort of get to lunch and you could like, you know, you can skip dinner and go to bed, but you, you can't skip lunch.
Scott: It's like, it's like you won't, you'll just fall asleep in the afternoon if you don't eat lunch.
Rym: So for one, I have a philosophy on lunch and I decided this, you know, back when I did not have a lot of money
Scott: thinking too hard about life here,
Rym: lunch, lunch can be cheap or it can be expensive, but I made a conscious decision back when I was working at IBM, even, and you know, I didn't have a lot of money.
Rym: I didn't make that much money back.
Rym: I felt like I was making a lot of money till I realized I was not, but I made this very conscious decision to always have a great hot lunch or at least a great lunch every day.
Rym: And I decided back then I was willing to spend up to $15 a day.
Scott: It's a lot of money.
Rym: It was a lot of money.
Rym: Like I thought about that.
Scott: I save a lot of money by just like making peanut butter and jelly sandwiches and not paying $15 every day.
Rym: So for a while I tried to go cheap and I can buy expensive stuff.
Rym: I would make lunches.
Rym: I would eat like pizza cause I was where my office was in, uh, basically Yonkers.
Scott: So if you take the money that I do not spend on alcohol, coffee and expensive lunch every day, only some days, why live?
Scott: Because then I could spend that money on luxurious items, which I do.
Rym: But I may, I re.
Rym: I thought about this real hard cause I was eating these kinds of crappy lunches and just saved my money.
Rym: But when I worked at IBM, the culinary Institute, basically like their students ran a cafeteria on the campus and you could get cheap food there, but you could spend about 1395. give or take and get like a legit amazing lunch, like a big one, like this giant ass gumbo.
Rym: It was always something fancy.
Rym: It was different every day.
Rym: And I thought long and hard and I decided that adding up $15 a day over the course of my life, five days a week, the sheer joy that that gave me, the good feelings, that sense of comfort and food was worth that money.
Rym: I was willing to spend that money.
Rym: Like if it were a monthly subscription that guaranteed five meals like that every week for the rest of my life, as long as I kept paying that monthly fee, I would have paid it.
Rym: And I've continued that philosophy to this day.
Rym: I have a great lunch no matter what.
Scott: All right.
Scott: I save money.
Scott: and I mean, thing is peanut butter and jelly is not a bad lunch.
Scott: I get a fancy jelly, which costs like $5 for a jar that lasts like a whole week, a loaf of bread.
Scott: That's like $3 that lasts a whole week.
Scott: So it's $8.
Scott: And then bulk at bulk, amazing peanut butter from Amazon is like more money, but that lasts you like months.
Scott: So it could last you like peanut butter or crunchy, whatever you feel like.
Rym: You don't care.
Scott: I mean, preference is really not a such thing as bad peanut butter except for Peter Pan brand, which tastes disgusting.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Any peanut butter that tastes like edible oil from a non peanut.
Scott: But like Jiff, Skippy, even those are.
Scott: even those are mass brands.
Scott: They taste good.
Scott: Fine.
Scott: Peter Pan is just the one that tastes bad.
Rym: The grocery store by my office has the dump peanuts in a thing and grind your own peanut butter.
Scott: I mean, a secret.
Scott: If you go to Publix Supermarket, which is in Florida, it's like the stop and shop of Florida.
Scott: If you go to the deli counter where you get meats, they will actually have peanut butter back there that you can get by the pound.
Scott: And that is like incredible peanut butter.
Scott: It's secret.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: So what do you have for lunch on a daily on an average day?
Scott: Usually peanut bun.
Scott: I make two sandwiches.
Scott: I just make them at my desk and it costs almost nothing.
Scott: Oh, yes.
Rym: You leave the components at work and make the lunch there.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: The grocery store is right next to work.
Scott: I'll just walk when the bread runs out.
Scott: I walk over and buy a bread.
Rym: I never did that for lunch, but I did that for snacks.
Rym: Like I would go to the grocery store and buy like all these snacks and just like stock my office with them.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: We have a. we have a mini fridge just for our department.
Scott: I load it up.
Scott: Oh, but I mean, that's not I don't do it every single day.
Scott: For example, you know, let's say I run out of bread and Pax is three days from now.
Rym: I'm not going to buy more.
Scott: Why would I buy a loaf of bread that I'm only going to eat half of and then we'll be stale when I get back from Pax.
Scott: I just going to eat out three times, you know, and what I eat out is I don't eat the same thing two days in a row.
Rym: You have that weird upset.
Rym: You'll do that a restaurant.
Rym: So you're like, I had Mexican food yesterday, so I can't have it today.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: That's crazy.
Scott: It's not crazy.
Rym: But what if that food is good?
Scott: So right next to my office, same food two days in a row.
Rym: So right near my office is Takahachi Bakery, which is like a legit Japanese style, like Tokyo Street Bakery.
Rym: They have great, like simple lunches.
Rym: I will eat there three times a week.
Scott: I mean, I'll eat at the same place.
Scott: I just won't get the same thing.
Scott: Like as a place near me, I go, they got this really good pasta.
Scott: You can get there.
Rym: So you can have enchiladas for lunch on Wednesday and then you could have like a chimichangas on Thursday and that's okay.
Scott: Are they different enough?
Rym: Chimichanga versus enchilada.
Scott: Yeah, I guess it's different enough.
Rym: All right.
Rym: What about soft tacos versus hard tacos?
Scott: It's not really different enough.
Rym: What about soft tacos versus enchiladas?
Scott: Depends.
Scott: I mean, I definitely wouldn't get the same filling.
Rym: How different do the toppings on a pizza have to be to count as different?
Scott: I mean, pizza is pizza.
Scott: You got only pizza two days in a row.
Rym: There is a really good pizza place by my office, too.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Well, I mean, it's one of the like a hundred places called little Italy, but it's actually we got all kinds of like everything.
Scott: We don't have amazing places near me, but we have like these everything places.
Scott: But the thing is the everything place.
Scott: like you can go there and get a pizza.
Scott: That's a one person pizza with anything you want and they make it in like this brick oven and everything.
Scott: And it's like, even though it's an everything place is way good.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Amish market is kind of like that, too.
Rym: Like they have like this giant like counters, get stuff from.
Scott: But like their sandwiches and stuff are legit like there's all these everything places, which is like the default lunch in New York City.
Scott: And I got tons to choose from, but some of them are good.
Scott: So whatever.
Scott: Just because you're just because they're serving every it's like a cat.
Scott: It's like a cafeteria, basically.
Scott: But it's not.
Scott: It's a public cafe place.
Rym: The problem is when they're like the good ones are like, I'd say a third of them are the good ones, but the rest are like not ideal food to eat.
Scott: The other thing is that one by Grand Central, there are actually tons of amazing lunch places that you can for real cheap, even in tourist town where I am.
Scott: But you got to sit down.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And even though it'll be way cheap, but it's like, do you have time to sit down and get this way cheap, amazing lunch?
Rym: I will make time a lot of times because I'll work and I'll be working and then when it's lunchtime, like I'll just go away for an hour or so and like sit down with the book.
Scott: The other thing is that a lot of places that aren't, they don't have like, you know, they're not designed to walk up and take food away, but you still can.
Scott: So like there's like a sit down, there's like a noodle place like Kung Fu something.
Scott: It's always way crowded with a line out the door, but I'll just walk in and instead of saying like, can I get a seat, I'll just be like, hey, I want this.
Scott: And then I wait outside and then when it's done, they come out and hand it to me in a bag and I go back to work.
Scott: And it's like, I didn't have to wait, you know, forever and you know, people are still waiting to get a seat, but it's like, I got this sit down food, you know, see, I got time.
Rym: The problem is most of the places I like to eat lunch, they often have seating.
Rym: So like you can take away or sit down, but the sit down is a hundred percent full.
Rym: unless I eat at 11, maybe 1130, which luckily I usually don't eat breakfast.
Scott: I'm hungry at 11 or 1130.
Rym: I eat lunch at 11 almost every day, like 1115 I start getting hangry and by 1130 I'm dead.
Scott: If I get a, if I eat a bagel or English muffin, then I won't get hungry till like noon, but if I don't eat breakfast, I just like, you know,
Rym: unless I bike to work, then I'm desperately hungry immediately when I sit down and I'm also hungry at 11
Scott: I'll get bagel on the way to work.
Scott: So it doesn't happen.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I don't do that.
Scott: If I bike, well, I'd get a bagel and then bike now I'll buy first and get a bagel from a street car.
Rym: Actually, you know, it's a pretty good breakfast.
Rym: Not that we can't talk about breakfast is the, uh, the breakfast sandwich is Starbucks.
Rym: Like actually not that bad.
Rym: No, it's like, it's, it's pretty like, it's not that different from what you get at one of those everything places.
Rym: No.
Scott: No.
Rym: So, uh, are there any good places?
Rym: Like where do you go when you want a good lunch?
Scott: Good lunch.
Scott: There isn't a lot of good lunch near me.
Scott: I'm in the touristy area.
Rym: There's a, there's, you know, there's the, which is like fancy burgers.
Rym: I got shippers, which is also burgers.
Scott: There is a shippers I go to, but I go there so rarely.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I, my rule is I cannot go there.
Scott: What am I going to shippers every day?
Rym: What the hell am I going to be like 300 pounds milkshake and a burger and some onion rings.
Scott: There's a Chinese place I can go.
Scott: That's like, you know, it's sort of like, um, something famous, whatever.
Scott: And all the Chinese people go there and you wait in a line and then you choose like three things and they put it in the plastic thing, you know, and there's different things every day.
Scott: You know, there's a, there's a, there's a sort of higher level, more expensive, fancier everything place where you can get like, you know, even more of everything, but they got like sushi or Korean foods and like the, if they make you pasta, it's like almost like fancy restaurant pasta, but they charge as much as the sit down restaurant would for a pasta dish.
Scott: So it's like, what's the point?
Rym: I could have just like, I have my coworkers like they, they, they go, like they order together and they go to Sophie's like a lot.
Rym: I do not like that place.
Scott: What is it?
Rym: It's a chain of Cuban food ostensibly, but it feels and tastes, you know, those places that are ostensibly one kind of food, but they're really just a Chinese place.
Rym: Like Americana style Chinese food cooking, like oily, like it's Chinese restaurant sharing kitchen with thing that is not Chinese restaurant, but cook kind of the same way, kind of tastes like that.
Rym: And it's kind of cheap and not that good.
Rym: And the meat's kind of bad because I had a coworker before who always wanted to get the Papa John's.
Rym: Oh my God.
Scott: Like you wanted it so much that hopefully, hopefully he'll get half off tomorrow.
Rym: He'd be like, so yeah, guys.
Rym: You want in on Papa John's?
Rym: And if people weren't into it, he would offer to pay for everyone just so we'd have an excuse to order his Papa John's.
Scott: Why don't you get good pizza with the fuck?
Rym: He doesn't work here.
Rym: He doesn't work there anymore.
Scott: New York city.
Scott: What the hell?
Scott: Even a Papa.
Scott: John's is in business.
Scott: We keeping it in business all by himself.
Rym: Maybe him and the Rangers.
Scott: Why does he love it so much?
Scott: The Rangers don't help them in business.
Scott: They put them out of business.
Rym: I wonder if they have insurance on that.
Rym: Like every time that happens, like they get pretty sure.
Scott: Even with the discount, uh, that you're, they're still making money on those pizzas.
Rym: Well, they have to be, those pizzas can't cost more than a nickel to make every.
Scott: I've never seen someone who actually was going to order it.
Scott: Everyone just jokes about ordering it.
Scott: So I can't imagine.
Scott: I don't think anyone even buys the pizza at the discount.
Scott: They're probably the day after.
Scott: they're probably just selling all the pieces at normal price.
Scott: No one's using that code.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Right.
Rym: Or you imagine there's some furtive Rangers fans, like they put on an Islander's Jersey and kind of like sunglasses and sneak in and order some Papa John's.
Scott: You just order online and you use the code and you get it, but you have to be in the area.
Scott: You can't do this at like, you can't order it at a Papa John's in California.
Scott: Won't work.
Rym: Papa John's had a time and a place.
Scott: Also isn't the guy Papa John like a shithead?
Scott: I've heard he's a bad dude.
Rym: I have heard that too, but I don't know for sure.
Rym: What is it with pizza places and bad people?
Rym: Cause you also got, uh, Godfather's also bad.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But, uh, there was a place and a time for Papa John's and that was if you needed pizza after midnight and you don't live in a real city, remember RIT, they delivered till what?
Rym: 2 AM.
Scott: So the best is if you're on a trip, you can get like a super luxurious lunch.
Scott: That's when you like, when you go to packs or something like, but sometimes when you're on a trip, you can't get luxurious lunch and you end up getting like concession stand lunch to hold you over for luxurious.
Scott: You know what it is?
Rym: It's the, there was time now, Twilight zone situation where you finally have the excuse to like sit down at the restaurant, like the nice one and order from the lunch menu.
Rym: But there's a convention.
Rym: That's why you're in town in the first place and the restaurant's full and you can't sit down.
Scott: Or are you going to like leave the convention and lose an hour or two of your time to eat the lunch?
Scott: Or are you just going to like snack and do whatever you can to hold out until dinner?
Rym: Thus the power of magfest and the power of PAX Prime.
Rym: The fact that those kinds are four days means I don't feel so bad about sitting down and having a lunch somewhere.
Scott: Being 24 seven at a magfest helps for that a lot too, but the best is if you're traveling and it's not some sort of convention, you're just on vacation, right?
Scott: It's like when we were in Australia and packs was over, it was like, Oh, every day, just every three meals a day, three restaurants, three lunches of awesomeness.
Rym: We get the big brekkie every morning and then at lunch you get like a pot meat pie of some kind.
Scott: Oh, we should go back just to go back to the top on your hockey place.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Cause, cause I couldn't go with Emily cause.
Rym: that's in Melbourne and we were in Sydney, but it looks like I'm going to PAX Australia.
Scott: How do you know?
Rym: Because I have to go.
Rym: So the second PAX Australia I went to was right after this finance conference.
Rym: that's in Sydney.
Rym: The same thing's happening again.
Rym: So I'm going to fly to Sydney.
Scott: So this year it was too far apart.
Rym: last year.
Rym: This year they were like two and a half weeks apart and I could not justify spending more than a month in Australia.
Rym: And even beyond that, I was not going to fly to Australia, fly home, fly back to Australia.
Rym: Like can you imagine doing that?
Scott: No.
Scott: Why would you do that?
Rym: Yeah, exactly.
Rym: So this time it looks like I can fly to Sydney, uh, spend like a week there doing work stuff, take like a weekend vacation, fly to Melbourne, do work stuff for like one day vacation for a few days
Scott: packs,
Rym: and then either fly to Singapore into a conference or just fly straight home.
Scott: I kind of want to go, but we said we'd go to Essen in 2018.
Rym: Oh yeah, well you could do both.
Rym: Do packs awesome 2017.
Scott: But I could go somewhere.
Scott: I've never been though.
Scott: That would be so much better.
Scott: A tropical place.
Rym: Thing is, if you go back to a packs AUS, you have to do Melbourne and a different place in Australia.
Scott: Tropical, uh, coral reef.
Rym: Yeah, or at least Sydney.
Rym: Like at least go to Sydney.
Rym: Sydney's way different.
Rym: You probably like Sydney.
Rym: Sydney's more like New York in a lot of ways.
Rym: Just less peace smell.
Scott: Let's go to coral reef.
Rym: Yeah, you can go to the coral reef.
Rym: Of course it's bleaching.
Rym: There's less of it to see.
Scott: I'll go see it before it's all bleached.
Rym: You had to head up to Brisbane, hang out on the beach.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, I mean, if I'm going somewhere, I might as well go to the beach.
Rym: So there was for most of, you know, I actually don't like Chipotle that much.
Scott: I like Chipotle.
Rym: There was a time when that became my go to lunch because it was cheaper, but it was plenty of food and it would fill me.
Rym: And it seems to correlate with if I bike to work every day, once I've been doing that for more than a few weeks, like I'm way hungrier all the time than I used to be.
Rym: And Chipotle is one of the few meals I can eat over lunch quickly that will satisfy that like weird deep craving for calories.
Scott: Chipotle is great because for like eight dollars, you get a ton of food.
Rym: You get like fourteen hundred calories encased in the size and shape of your stomach.
Scott: And you can get all sorts of different stuff.
Scott: You can get.
Scott: the best thing is get the bowl, but ask for the soft tacos on the side.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You can get meats mixed in.
Scott: you like I want the chicken and I also want the beef.
Scott: Give me half and half.
Rym: I decided a long time ago, I'll only get the sofritas.
Rym: I'm done with the meat there.
Scott: I do sofritas, but sometimes they also have chorizo now, which I have not been since they got the chorizo.
Scott: You haven't been in a long time.
Rym: I stopped going to Chipotle because that is way too many fucking calories.
Rym: Even for me, most of the time.
Scott: You got it.
Scott: You see, I don't get the guac mixed in, which costs more over the guac.
Rym: You got to get the guac.
Scott: The guac counts for most of the calories.
Scott: Yeah, but guac's real good.
Rym: All right.
Rym: I think it's still like over a thousand calories.
Rym: If you get the minimum possible burrito, if you I will get.
Rym: my default at Chipotle is the white rice, the black bean, it's got the flour tortilla by itself.
Rym: I don't three hundred.
Rym: The chorizo is another three hundred in the bowl.
Rym: I get the bowl with the tortilla like that.
Scott: OK, now I get the bowl.
Scott: The default my minimum, right?
Scott: The thing I usually get is bowl white rice, black bean, sofritas.
Rym: All right, wait, I'm going to do this now to get the bowl.
Rym: Uh, OK.
Rym: Sofritas.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: That's good.
Scott: White rice, black bean.
Rym: Black bean.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The pico.
Scott: The hot.
Rym: Pico's good.
Scott: The hot salsa.
Rym: The red one or chili one.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I actually like the tomatillo green one more.
Scott: I mean, one of them, right?
Rym: Don't get the guac.
Scott: And then.
Scott: Cheese and lettuce.
Rym: Cheese and lettuce is the pro move.
Scott: Right.
Rym: That is.
Scott: How many calories?
Rym: Six hundred and thirty five calories.
Scott: That's not bad.
Scott: That's a good lunch.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: That's a lot.
Rym: OK.
Rym: It is two thousand four hundred milligrams of sodium.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Yes, it is.
Scott: I see.
Scott: Now click on the guac and see what it goes to say.
Scott: Add your guac in there.
Rym: My guac.
Rym: Uh, eight hundred and sixty five.
Scott: It's two hundred calories of guac.
Scott: That's a thousand, though.
Scott: If I'm super, super hungry, you get the chips and guac and I'll get chips and guac extra.
Rym: that the chips and guac is like eight hundred calories by itself.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You're supposed to share it.
Scott: But hey.
Rym: No, no one shares that.
Rym: If you have two people, you get two orders of that.
Rym: That's how we roll.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I just don't do the Chipotle anymore.
Rym: It's still.
Rym: it's too much food unless I'm biking to work.
Scott: It's so convenient and also delicious.
Scott: And eight dollars.
Scott: So convenient.
Scott: It's like anything.
Scott: It's like so cheap, but way better than things that cost more.
Rym: Even with their pipeline, like how fast they are.
Rym: The two Chipotle's near my office have like a 15 plus minute wait to order their Chipotle's near my work.
Rym: There's there's two within walking distance or two with a walking distance.
Scott: there are lines when you go in, but you're out in five minutes.
Rym: I have waited in that line.
Rym: That line goes like 10 to 15 minutes on multiple occasions.
Scott: Your line must be even longer than ours.
Rym: But that's only if I go after like twelve, fifteen.
Rym: Seems like most people eat lunch like twelve, thirty, one thirty.
Rym: So by eating lunch at eleven thirty, it's kind of hacks, like no one's around, like I could just sit down.
Rym: Everything's fresh.
Rym: You can't go before eleven thirty or most places don't actually have all their food out yet.
Rym: Like Takahachi, like doesn't have all the lunches like the soup's not done.
Scott: See, like here's a good example.
Scott: Right today.
Scott: I ate the last of my loaf of bread, right?
Scott: So tomorrow I'm probably going to get like I'm going to get like maximum luxury lunch tomorrow.
Rym: I'll go all out.
Rym: What is what is all out?
Rym: Because all out for me is I go to Zaytzeff, which is like a fancy burger joint.
Rym: I'll get like a burger, fries and a beer and like a dessert of some kind.
Rym: I mean, I'll sit there for like an hour and a half.
Scott: All out could be anything.
Scott: I choose the place and then I just, you know, whatever place I choose, all out mean a waiter.
Scott: It could be.
Scott: Who knows if I got time.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But I choose the place and then I get, you know, the entree, some, you know, a side and a drink and, you know, like I max it out.
Scott: I get the most delicious possible things and, you know, then I don't have to eat dinner until like eight and I don't eat much dinner.
Rym: Yeah, well, I guess it's easier.
Rym: The thing is living alone.
Rym: I remember like it's very hard to cook a satisfying meal because normally a good meal has like one main thing, like a main side and then a secondary side or a salad or something.
Rym: But if it's just one person, it's hard to like make all those things in a sustainable, not wasting food.
Scott: I just make a blue apron.
Scott: I only eat half and I put the other half in the fridge.
Rym: The blue apron is good about that because it's main thing side thing and it all only needs like one set of cooking implements.
Rym: Actually, if I like on weekends, you can do like blue apron, lunch, dinner, cook one for lunch, cook the other one for dinner.
Rym: The next day, lunch and dinner again, just flip them.
Scott: Nope.
Scott: You can't eat the same thing.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: You won't die.
Scott: If I make a blue apron and I have half leftover, I'll eat it for lunch or dinner two days from then.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: Not one day from then.
Rym: So are there some things you would eat for lunch, but you have no way to get them generally like sushi.
Rym: Like I would eat sushi for lunch, but there are no sushi places that have good sushi that will deliver.
Rym: There are only sit down restaurants that are expensive nearby.
Scott: when I originally, I mean, I'm in New York city in the touristy area.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: If there's any kind of food I want, I can get it.
Scott: I can get any.
Scott: you've named the country.
Scott: I could get the food from there, right?
Scott: It might not be the best because of the neighborhood I'm in, but I can get it right.
Scott: I can get anything from like, you know, a burger to astronomy, sandwich to Indian food, the Chinese.
Scott: I can get anything, but it might not be the top quality in any category.
Scott: The thing is there are specific dishes that I cannot get.
Scott: For example, when I first, I can get Japanese food, no problem, right?
Scott: There's like multiple choices.
Scott: I can get bentos, I can get ramens, I can get whatever.
Scott: But when I first started working there, there was a place called Teriyaki boy, right?
Scott: And you could go in there and you could get basically in what was a giant styrofoam cup, like larger than a cup noodle cup, but like the same shape basically, but big, you could get a kitsune udon and a cup.
Rym: Oh.
Scott: And that was like, that place went under cause I think they jacked the rent up on him and it hasn't been there in like, like maybe seven or eight years.
Scott: It's super long time.
Rym: There have been a succession of like three different banh mi places that were open and then were closed near my office.
Rym: Now I can get udon.
Scott: No problem.
Scott: I got like multiple udon noodle choices.
Scott: There is no kitsune udon at any of these places.
Rym: When I worked in midtown, there were, there were not one, not two, but three places that all had kitsune udon right next to my office.
Scott: For me to get it, I would have to walk a distance or take a subway and like, there's no one who'll deliver that, you know, there's plenty of udon, just not that specific udon.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, I can't get that even though I want it.
Rym: I really like it.
Rym: They also remember they discontinue, oh, the, uh, the pat walking paths and city, all park and ever realized that our deck.
Scott: Whoop, whoop.
Scott: Exciting.
Rym: OK.
Rym: And I was looking at the map for lunch.
Rym: But anyway, I remember when they discontinued the bowl noodle kitsune udon.
Scott: It was not bowl noodle.
Scott: It was separate.
Rym: It was there kitsune udon bowl.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: There is a. there is one kitsune udon instant that's left from another brand.
Scott: I haven't actually tried it.
Scott: It comes in a red bowl.
Scott: I haven't tried it.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Maybe we should try it.
Rym: Maybe I'll buy one because then I could bring a few of those to like a magfest for like quick lunch.
Scott: because, yeah, the convention lunch is like it's the bowl kinds you pour in the hot water.
Rym: Close the lid.
Rym: That is perfect for like magfest when you don't want it because you can't eat it.
Rym: Any lunch places.
Rym: They're completely full.
Rym: Oh, you know, I go all the time, not all the time, but when I'm really hungry now, instead of Chipotle, go go curry, go go curry near me, I'd be going there.
Rym: There's a go go curry near me.
Rym: I eat there.
Rym: My rule is I can never eat there more than once a week, no matter what.
Scott: There are some.
Rym: that is a lot of food.
Scott: There are some places near me that have opened up like in the past year or two, like the melt shop or like a little beat.
Scott: But it's like they have good food, but it's way overpriced and too expensive.
Scott: There's also a lot of food carts near me that are way good.
Scott: You know, the food trucks come over and some of them are like top notch.
Rym: I used to do the food trucks.
Rym: The only reason I've stopped is that the food trucks are a bit of a walk away and they actually had way longer lines and way slower service than the places actually in buildings near me.
Scott: It depends on which one and which day and stuff like that.
Rym: Well, they're all over by World Trade Center because there's no restaurants over there.
Scott: They're like for me, they're one block away.
Rym: Yeah, there's like a 10 minute walk to get to where they are.
Rym: Yeah, I used to city bike over there when I have city bike.
Rym: That was like the best use of city bike is city bike to a different lunch place that expands the feeding area.
Scott: But even like the really popular ones that are always there, they got like a routine and they, you know, they zip things along.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: Like this is one.
Scott: This guy is it's called like steak freak, even though it's not really a steak place.
Scott: It's more like, you know, like noodle bowls and stuff.
Scott: It's really good.
Scott: He's got a big long line, but that line moves.
Scott: And what the way he does it is you're waiting in the line and you'll get up to the front of the line.
Scott: And if he's only makes like two or three things at a time.
Scott: So if you're like the fourth person and they're too busy, they go up.
Scott: just wait, don't order yet.
Scott: And they finish the people they got and then they start making for you.
Scott: And it actually moves along like you could be.
Scott: I've been like the 10th person in line and only had to wait like 15 minutes from from, you know, getting in line to walking away with food.
Rym: Yeah, I guess the trouble is all the food trucks near me, they go to a place where there aren't lunch places.
Rym: So they're actually the only lunch place.
Scott: These are actually in front of a bunch of lunch places that you deal with it.
Scott: And there's just so many people that it doesn't matter.
Rym: Yeah, I kind of almost miss working in Midtown because while the food's more expensive up there, I had a lot more variety of options.
Rym: Like I have a similar number of options downtown, but they're from a narrower band of kinds of food.
Rym: And also, there aren't any good places near me right now.
Rym: I don't think there's one around.
Rym: to see if there's one right now.
Scott: Sure, there are.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway, by me.
Scott: All right, let's go.
Rym: By me.
Rym: Let's get it done.
Rym: You're hungry.
Rym: Yeah, you're talking about lunch.
Rym: All right.
Rym: I guess that's the end of that.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows, SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights in order.
Rym: The amount of money they give us on continuing basis are Alan Joyce, Rebecca Dunn, Nicholas Brando, Heidi McNichol, Amanda Duchette.
Rym: Great job, Emoji Ivy fame, MyStating.com, William Isenrose, Jeremy Minor, Lisa Needs Braces, Dannel Plan, Lisa Needs Braces, Dannel Plan, Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn, Christian Koontz.
Rym: Moage is what brings us together today.
Rym: Moage, Dead West, Oangeman, Shervin Van Horl, Roy Lavelle, James David Wright, Rochelle Montanona, Superboy, a Patreon patrician's patronizing patronage, Brian Fisher, Sailor Vista, Matthew Smith, Don Schleich, Jar Tovjian, Joshua Joestar, Tyler Eller, Sean Yeager, Sam Cordery, Clinton Walton, Ren from New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, Drew Openlander, Brian Sidroni, A Rodent of Unusual Size, Redacted, Chris Midgiff, Chris Nock, Daniel Redman, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: Hopefully all my travel will not be impacting any of the Ignites that is coming up and Rims-Rants and all that bit will be returning with gusto this weekend, especially.
Rym: And some of you might've noticed, ConnectiCon panel submissions are open.
Rym: Also, if you plan to do a panel and you did not get a comp badge already because you have not yet been a panelist at ConnectiCon and you want to only come to ConnectiCon, if you are accepted as a panelist, let me know.
Rym: I can give you a link that will let you book your room despite not yet having a badge because they're hiding the room blocks unless you're already a, uh, already have a badge and I have no control over the situation, but I'm here for you.
Rym: I will help you.
Rym: But anyway, now I leave you with something.
Scott: Baza promised me a pretty penny for your head, Princess Toadstool.
Rym: Your nose.
Rym: Breathe through your nose.