Rym: It's Tuesday January 31st 2017.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: That's good.
Rym: And this is GeekNights Tonight.
Rym: we're talking about potion explosion.
Rym: It's okay.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Good PAX South as always but as I was leaving PAX South I dug the pisser.
Rym: Yeah, one of the crowning achievements of my life is that I was able to start a chant of Good chunk of the audience at the omega-thon finale at PAX and that chant was just piss piss piss.
Rym: Without context.
Scott: that sounds horrible, but what a sad life you had if that's the crowning achievement.
Scott: But the dude.
Rym: so basically what?
Rym: the dude who failed to win the omega-thon last year.
Rym: he just happens to have the handle rug pisser.
Rym: and Because he failed to win the omega-thon finale He gets to be in a mega not again.
Rym: and as we've noticed if you make it to the finale and fail You're pretty much gonna keep making it to the finale until you succeed.
Scott: I'm we're trying to figure out.
Scott: is a?
Scott: are people losing in the finale on purpose?
Scott: because just getting the second place Guarantees you to come to the packs and beat omega-naught?
Rym: Yeah, and then one year if you want to go to Australia just decide to win.
Scott: you win and then but then you're dry.
Scott: your days Of omega not are over right?
Scott: It's like you can just keep going to the same packs over and over and over and over Remembered more being an omega not over and over.
Scott: or you can go to PAX Australia or wherever whatever it packs You want.
Rym: one time Rym won the omega-thon?
Rym: 2019 great or Rym was an omega not finale 20 years in a row.
Scott: or is it that there are certain people who practice the games that are announced But then they can't deal?
Scott: their natural gaming skill is low so they can't beat the final secret game that they didn't it was like.
Rym: remember when Lou when a friend of ours tried to Rig the DDR tournament freshman year at RIT by rigging it.
Rym: There was this there was a gentleman of Distasteful demeanor who was super good at DDR with his fanboy pistoning and He was good at it primarily because he just memorized a hundred percent.
Rym: So The president of the club at the time made the finale of the tournament Custom arrows that no one had ever seen before hoping that someone with raw skills could beat this person.
Rym: Mmm, so It might be a situation like that.
Rym: These people do not have raw skills necessarily or at least not a breadth of skills required to be able to make it through all those baby rounds and be good at like crocodile or air hockey or at
Scott: least the omega-thon was air Hokey,
Rym: which I guessed every year for so many years.
Scott: We guessed that we wanted that we wanted it to be that and we guessed it would be that for years and years and years.
Scott: And then we completely forgot about it because it was so clear that it was gonna be some Nintendo switch game.
Scott: Not only was packs out the premiere of the Nintendo switch for people to who weren't Nintendo.
Scott: On the stage they had red and blue packs sticks like I'm and it's like it.
Scott: the stage looked like a switch controller.
Rym: Remember the year when they set up.
Rym: it looked like there was a pinball machine because they had a drape over it and then they Pulled the drape off and just a pile of shit.
Rym: They're like, no.
Scott: Yeah, it was not what you thought It was there.
Scott: It was clever.
Scott: But yeah hockey that's fine.
Rym: The best part about it was that neither one of them was good at air hockey at all.
Scott: They got slightly better at air hockey to make it entertaining rugpister.
Rym: However, I love you, dude But you did not exhibit the capacity of learning that Mancey did or maybe he wasn't losing intentionally.
Rym: Maybe I mean, I'm gonna say if I got to the Megadon finale Probably lose several years in a row.
Rym: cuz I'm pretty sure if you're skilled enough.
Scott: I mean consider this right.
Scott: you're up against someone who's also good at games out of packs, right?
Scott: It's a game.
Scott: You don't know.
Scott: unless you get lucky and it's a game.
Scott: You're already the master of right like.
Scott: oh look it happens to be kaboom.
Scott: Right.
Scott: unless that happens You basically got a 50/50 shot.
Scott: So what are the odds of tails three so far for rugpister?
Scott: three tails in a row?
Scott: That's that can happen.
Rym: counterpoint though.
Rym: Oh She's surprising percentage of the games are games that we just happen to be really good at.
Scott: We happen to be good at a lot of games and they pick lots of old games.
Scott: Oh, they also pick lots of physical arcade type games that we are fans of.
Rym: However, I'd like I'm not good at crocodile like.
Rym: I would add trouble.
Rym: No Flicking not great.
Rym: No, I mean pitch cars.
Rym: I did really well, but even in pitch cars I basically have three settings.
Rym: fucking miss entirely don't move at all fly off the table.
Rym: Those are my three settings.
Scott: I mean if it wasn't for that one really hard part we put on the pitch.
Scott: It's like I'm really good at the pitch car As long as there isn't something above my skill level.
Scott: like if everything's within my skill level like I'm great.
Scott: It's same thing with like rocket league.
Scott: if we did if we had rocket league where everyone is stuck on the ground and you could Only jump and not rock it up into the air.
Scott: I would be like the god at rocket.
Scott: He's so good, right?
Rym: So, yeah packs happened and we'll talk.
Rym: I mean most of the stuff we saw we'll talk about.
Rym: we're not do a whole show on Packs, but cuz we go to.
Rym: a lot of packs is now.
Rym: but panel went well saw a bunch of good games.
Rym: We'll talk about them as we play them more and review them.
Scott: way too many games.
Rym: I think the game that stuck out the most was captain sonar.
Rym: like.
Rym: we played it enough.
Rym: That game is a fucking like.
Rym: that game is perfect.
Scott: I mean, we know that yeah but new.
Rym: we exposed a lot of people who hadn't actually played it to it and Pretty much everyone just wanted to keep playing it all night.
Rym: We had to like cut him off like cut that IV off and make him go do something else.
Rym: It was good times.
Rym: We played that Serlin what fantasy strike?
Scott: Yeah, that's what we expected it to be.
Rym: Oh, it looks like when we went it's a FPS on FPS.
Rym: when it's a fighting game That is just the rock-paper-scissor of hitting the buttons without having to do the combos Rims.
Rym: real good.
Scott: I mean anyone's real good.
Scott: It's not about you were real good.
Scott: I only have one first four matches.
Rym: Oh, yeah, no you won the first four rounds of a first of five.
Rym: But I want I came back and won all the rest because I chose the most complex character to date solely because he won.
Rym: he's his owner which that's kind of like to play but - he Has a power and his power is just fucking saunter past the other character.
Rym: That's it.
Rym: Just walk by a bit of a shit-eating grin.
Rym: and when I saw it I was like, that's my character.
Rym: and then Scott looked at me said room.
Rym: That's your character.
Rym: He's my Voldo.
Scott: I just I read the instructions for the character that I want to be the fish man.
Scott: But the fish man is not in the game yet.
Rym: He's not yet her or the gambling pan.
Scott: I read the instructions for the Rockman and I played as the Rockman and it said yeah If there's a projectile you can smash it.
Scott: so I did and you could just smash my project.
Scott: But then I'm like, well, how do I need to get close?
Scott: because I'm a throwing guy.
Scott: How do I get close?
Scott: So the way to get close it said was to slam on the ground like Kirby stone mode Which worked and knocked rims ass down.
Scott: then it said after you do that get close to this button.
Scott: So I did and I did get close.
Scott: But then the timing of it was such that when Rym woke up from me getting close Hit me and if I tried to jump over the projectiles it to get close without just smashing him infinitely.
Scott: Oh hit me.
Scott: But I could not figure out from the instructions how to get close without getting hit if I wasn't.
Rym: or it was this like great Paper-rock-scissors cuz we're both learning the game like we're no shit about it.
Rym: So like basically if I mess that up at all Scott would get a little too close and I take like three damage.
Scott: Yeah, it's so great.
Scott: It doesn't have like this, you know health bar That's like, you know Just you know that it's like you take X number of hits period and some moves do two more than one damage But most and some Blocks.
Rym: Yeah, like my dude didn't have as many Scott's had more cuz he's a heavy.
Scott: I'm a giant Rockman.
Rym: Yeah, basically Zangief but it's Like touching it a little bit and watching people play it.
Rym: It appears like it is going to live up to what they intend it to be.
Scott: Yes, we can get the experience of playing the top tier fighting game action without having to be able to you know Move buttons move the trick joysticks and push buttons real fast and precisely.
Scott: cuz like I when I see but not not so simple And stupid as dive kick, right?
Scott: Yep better than granted.
Rym: I really like dive kick - yeah sure, but this replaces dive kick.
Rym: This is just like cuz and it's more.
Scott: it's more of a real game.
Rym: Like when I play dive kick, I think oh man right fighting games.
Rym: And then I'd like maybe I play the most recent Soul Calibur at a PAX.
Rym: I'm like, oh right fuck this.
Scott: The problem is I went to go get fantasy strike and it's like you had to get it by patreon.
Rym: Yep Which is fine the patreon.
Scott: the way it works.
Scott: if you pay five dollars a month You get it with like five characters.
Scott: and if you pay ten dollars a month you get it with like seven characters.
Scott: It's like what the fuck is this bullshit?
Scott: Just I'll give you even $50.
Scott: Just give me all the goddamn.
Rym: Here's here is a use For the GeekNights patreon the first official use.
Rym: I've never used any of that money.
Rym: people again I can just redirect that money into other people's patreon Mm-hmm, and then if they don't double dip They don't take the fee like twice as far as I can tell.
Rym: so I could spend some of our patron money to send to Fantasy strike so we can then play the game and talk about it.
Scott: But it's feel I mean that's I'm just saying that's way too much money to be charging for that game.
Rym: This is like this is funding the development of the game.
Rym: You're subscribed to the patreon saying yeah I want this game to actually come out.
Rym: Well, I'm just gonna wait until it's released But I think I'll back it because I want to get good at it now.
Scott: Yeah, I think I'll be fine.
Rym: Yeah But yeah, we played a lot other games.
Rym: We'll talk about as time goes on.
Rym: Nintendo switch was there and I don't.
Rym: I still don't understand the people who stand in line because the line was like three hours To play Zelda.
Rym: Yeah, like I always wanted to go to that line and ask everyone in line.
Rym: Just two questions one.
Rym: Did you pre-order a Nintendo switch already?
Rym: and two?
Rym: Did you pre-order this game?
Rym: You're waiting in line for three hours at PAX to play.
Scott: I did.
Rym: I think the answer to both those is yes.
Rym: What the fuck?
Rym: Like?
Rym: why packs is no only so many hours?
Rym: you spending three of those hours in that line?
Scott: Well, they're always like oh I got my DS.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Oh, yeah Always got something like oh, I'm doing something in the line.
Scott: I'm making friends in the line.
Scott: It's like but with three hours, it's like is you're gonna play Zelda for 15 minutes.
Scott: Is that really worth it?
Scott: You could be.
Scott: you know The opportunity cost compared to what you did not take you guys much more than three hours to play that fucking train game you played.
Scott: Right, you could have played this train game.
Rym: That's three hours long and epic could have played like three captain sonars Even like intense ones.
Scott: right and you can't do that at home a month from now when the switch comes out.
Rym: Yeah, but suffice it to say PAX South is My third favorite packs and Australia is cheating because it has the bonus of being in Australia.
Rym: So if you don't count the Australia, it's the second best.
Rym: packs Like you can't go to prime go to eat go to South before you go to East Especially if your tabletop II it's cheaper.
Rym: Yeah, and speaking of packs.
Rym: I think there's some other news.
Scott: yeah, the the packs you should really go to if you're Tabletop II is the brand newly announced PAX Unplugged.
Rym: it's in Philly.
Scott: We knew it was coming and couldn't talk about it.
Rym: I've known for so I'm just like sitting on this knowledge.
Rym: It's like wanting to talk about it.
Rym: Yeah, well, you know one news because we don't know how it's gonna go down yet.
Scott: Well one news agency Put their story up too early.
Scott: Yep But basically as far as we know the only thing wrong with this pack is it's gonna be in Philly Which is good because it's near us but bad because it's the worst city there is.
Scott: But Yeah, it's gonna be packs in all ways.
Scott: It's good.
Scott: I heard is just well.
Rym: It's always except the focus is tabletop, right?
Scott: This is just rumors, right?
Scott: But from what I have gathered it is a full packs the Omega thon.
Scott: You know the keynotes the panels the tabletop, right?
Rym: But imagine but the keynote is tabletop twisted.
Rym: the omega-thon is tabletop game, right?
Scott: It's not going to have Console free play.
Scott: It's not going to have the PC zone.
Scott: It will not have in the x-ball hall, you know Anyone selling video games?
Scott: unless there may be video versions of board game.
Rym: I assume there won't be a concert but I could be.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know about a concert but it's going to have mad RPG and mad dice and mad Meeple and mad all that biz.
Rym: so the worries extra.
Rym: there is a fear that it might take a cue from Traditional tabletop cons meaning shitty ones and do some of their biz.
Scott: Yeah, I don't think it's gonna be like those now.
Scott: Here's the problems with it.
Scott: Number one.
Scott: It is the same weekend as BGG con which is in Texas far away And I don't really care about BGG con.
Scott: but a lot of tabletop people do.
Scott: But I think most of them are like the grog nard BGG types that probably aren't going to packs anyway.
Scott: But it's the industry of tabletop can't really go to do conventions at once.
Scott: Publishers are gonna have to choose.
Scott: but danger.
Rym: number two It is also the weekend of the new anime con in New York City the big one
Scott: the one that is made by the people who made the New York anime festival and Are now on their own doing a new thing and it could be a good anime con.
Scott: I got hopes for it, but And the packs came second.
Rym: So it's sort of unfair to bail and I like I already committed GeekNights to anime NYC like handshake.
Rym: like I we will be.
Scott: It's like they're announcing this packs way too close to when the packs is happening.
Rym: We might literally have to split up and Scott will go to our shit at packs and I'll go to our shit and anime NYC.
Scott: Yeah, I'm going to the packs for sure.
Scott: yeah, I did not commit to the anime NYC even though I really was basically planning to go to it and expecting to go to It and totally on board with it.
Scott: Yeah, but then a packs appeared on top and it's just like I didn't officially commit.
Scott: So I can go to the packs without guilt but not without like.
Scott: just regret that.
Scott: why did they have to do it this way?
Rym: Yeah, cuz like this anime con is basically.
Rym: if any anime con could be the packs of anime cons It's this one.
Rym: Like if this one can't do it.
Rym: No one can.
Scott: it's the.
Scott: it's a week before Thanksgiving 2017 November 17th through 19th.
Rym: Yeah, so we'll let you know how that all goes down I would probably bail on the anime one, but I like.
Rym: I shook hands.
Rym: I'm not I can't like.
Rym: I didn't sign a contract but be a dick.
Scott: move So and shake no hand.
Rym: But if we split up it also means something very important because Scott realized that he's been.
Rym: you know Fat lady Scott realizes he's been to 20 paxes.
Scott: I've been to 20 paxes.
Rym: I don't count pegs dev.
Rym: because that's just part of that's not a but even not counting back dev.
Rym: I've been to 21 paxes.
Scott: fine counting pegs dev.
Scott: I went to 21.
Rym: It's not counting max dev.
Rym: I've been to like many bags, but I Skip.
Rym: you skipped one more pack sauce than I did.
Rym: Yeah, but if I don't go to this PAX Unplugged we're tied again.
Rym: But I was ahead before.
Scott: so I think I definitely counts as a real bag.
Rym: That does Yeah, this is all like exciting news.
Rym: We'll see how this all goes.
Rym: But anyway things of the day.
Rym: So a cloud over packs.
Rym: the whole time was that of course like the Republic is falling all around us and all this nonsense happened.
Scott: And well, they haven't shut down the GeekNights yet.
Scott: They have not.
Rym: we're still here.
Rym: we are broadcasting from the end of the world maybe but Unrelated to all of that just like you guys on the gold records in his face Unrelated to anything that might be going on politically in America right now.
Rym: My thing of the day is really unrelated.
Scott: you wouldn't have said anything.
Rym: My thing of the day is a succinct YouTube video.
Rym: just if you're gonna make a fist Because you're gonna punch someone.
Rym: Here's a basic video on how to make a basic fist good enough to not break your hand.
Rym: So if you happen to need a fist for whatever reason I recommend you watch this video.
Rym: And if you're not gonna watch this video in the very least don't put your thumb inside your knuckles.
Rym: I was thumb on the outside.
Rym: If you're on the outside hit with the first two knuckles.
Scott: don't bend your wrist like if you're not at least You know Competent at fist making I suggest not doing it.
Scott: It's one of those things like yeah, you probably shouldn't use a drill press if you haven't been trained.
Rym: Yeah, I imagine a video of the whole hog spinning with you on it and really not happening, right?
Scott: If you want to make fists, yeah You can watch this video.
Rym: if you feel like you need a fist like I just I suggest that you know how to make a fist That that's my thing of the day.
Scott: What was my thing today?
Rym: Cuz I got more fist stuff.
Rym: you who is trying to convince me that there's no punching in taekwondo anyway, it's about kicking.
Scott: so Take two things combined right like take a pen.
Scott: Yeah, you take alright, so first game number one the hearthstone.
Scott: Game number two the rhythm heaven.
Rym: now rhythm heaven is so mashup rhythm.
Scott: having a game that I don't actually like playing that much I played it for like 10 minutes and I was like, oh this is cute and then I didn't need to play it anymore.
Rym: I like those pony mashups with it more than I like the game.
Scott: So here's a hearthstone mashup of that, you know with rhythm heaven.
Scott: But the thing about this one is is not.
Scott: it's not particularly remarkable except in its dramatic production quality.
Scott: It's like whoa.
Scott: The production clock value on this is like insane for what it is.
Scott: and also the name of the YouTube account On which this is posted is piece of sheet as in piece of a sheet of favor As in poop and it's a piece of toilet paper.
Scott: It looks like to make it even more funny.
Scott: Ah, I don't want to subscribe.
Scott: I like I don't care what videos they post.
Scott: I'm subscribing to.
Rym: piece of sheet thing is you know?
Rym: It was like remember we found car bot the people who made all those like Starcraft shorts.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, same thing like you.
Rym: find an account like this.
Rym: just subscribe.
Rym: He's only.
Rym: this account only has 77 subscribers.
Rym: I'm the 78th person to subscribe.
Scott: Yeah What's up with that?
Rym: video needs more views like I have panel videos that have more views than this.
Rym: guys get it up there.
Rym: Ah, the first comment on my fist video is that's not a fist that shit.
Rym: so, okay In the moment the book of the book was Rebecca we did it.
Scott: it's done Let's do it.
Scott: What's the new book club?
Rym: I gotta pick the next book club.
Scott: It's your turn.
Scott: I'm gonna pick something.
Scott: I got a whole pile of books.
Scott: You want me to pick one?
Rym: So I'll warn you cuz I never actually read doing all the way through.
Rym: So I kind of am leaning toward making it Dune.
Scott: I thought about that.
Scott: Yeah as I read Dune I've think I've said this before.
Scott: I read Dune way back in the middle school But I only started reading it because I was like and stopped reading it and all of them is.
Rym: I know a lot about Dune Partly from reading wiki's partly from playing games.
Scott: I know having conversations I know a lot of proper nouns from Dune and things of that nature because of a nerd and when you're in it's an important Nerd thing.
Scott: and that was the justification for making What's it called wheel of time.
Scott: oh the book club book like I know like and will will you know?
Rym: Well adult Scott like Dune more than middle school Out there have heard, you know fears the mind killer like that whole thing and didn't realize it was from Dune.
Scott: I didn't know that was from Dune, but I've heard it before.
Scott: Well now you know, I know that spice must flow is Dune?
Rym: Yeah, you know, I know it's Jesser it are.
Scott: I know that's a some old ladies in Dune.
Rym: They're not all old.
Rym: You just thought you got that impression from the art in the board game.
Scott: That's correct.
Scott: Yeah I like the board game a lot.
Scott: I like the board game way more than I like.
Rym: Yeah, everyone knows the Baron Harkonnen.
Scott: I know that's a bad dude.
Scott: Yep I mean, he's the Baron and no one's a Baron who's a good guy, right?
Rym: There are no good Barons that I can think of.
Rym: Nope, there might be an old like German Baron or something in somewhere.
Scott: Rym Rym is a bad guy.
Scott: He likes to put barons on people but that's a bad Baron.
Rym: What about very much housing?
Rym: Is he good?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I just know that Baron munchausen is the name of a Baron.
Scott: I don't know anything about him.
Rym: What do we need to make the?
Rym: do we need to make the GeekNights like anyway?
Rym: that maybe I'll let's see bear All right.
Rym: So Barons are one step below Viscounts and one step above Baron nets and hereditary Knights.
Scott: So that's actually way low.
Scott: It's like Here's the full ranking Lord Count Baron Baron's way down there.
Rym: All right, I'm gonna go from the top to the bottom Emperor King.
Scott: Yep Archduke.
Scott: Oh, really?
Scott: I didn't know there was Archduke Duke or Grand Prince.
Rym: they're the same level.
Rym: is Then Prince?
Scott: they're putting in extra levels here.
Scott: No, no Prince.
Scott: Yeah, what?
Rym: no, so yeah, so Duke and Prince at the same level.
Rym: Yeah Prince Duke sovereign Prince Marquez marquee though that whole like count the marquee disown marquee marquez count.
Rym: They're all account in power.
Rym: No, okay count palatine is different.
Rym: So marquee is above count Then Viscount then Baron then Baronet then Knight then Esquire then gentleman then fuck you Which ones of those are Lords and which one of them aren't Lord's fuck if I know.
Rym: All right, gentlemen, gentlemen, I'm trying to figure out.
Rym: how do you how you become a gentleman have?
Scott: what level Do you have to be to be a Lord?
Scott: Cuz Lord is like a whole bunch of them right like all the counts and all the bears Gentlemen was used by anyone who could not claim a real title.
Rym: All right, so Baron Baron Baron Baron old French baron Latin borrow during the ash cameras.
Rym: Okay This Wikipedia article is way too long for me to decide whether or not the majority of barons are good or bad.
Rym: So I'm just gonna let it be they're bad.
Rym: Otherwise if you were at PAX South and you saw our panel on grind mechanics and games Guess what video of it from paxi prime is on YouTube already.
Scott: Just watch that one.
Scott: How about that?
Rym: Look at that.
Rym: Look how fast we got that.
Rym: see that panel.
Rym: Follow all our stuff on the internet.
Rym: We have YouTube channels.
Rym: We got Twitter.
Scott: We got an awesome How we have more followers than piece of sheep.
Scott: We haven't which is so wrong.
Rym: We have an awesome new forum that you guys should be using.
Rym: it tests to sell secure.
Scott: It's not that.
Scott: it's not that awesome It's just new.
Rym: It's pretty awesome.
Rym: Yeah Now the old old owners better but then when he upgraded the vanilla I kind of got worse.
Scott: I liked it better than this one.
Rym: I like the old vanilla better than this one But I like this one way better than the new vanilla.
Rym: Yeah, and I like all of them better than the PHP BB.
Rym: We never well guess.
Rym: we technically ran one the old days whatever Zeebs and all that.
Rym: Mm-hmm the pre GeekNights forums Mm-hmm.
Rym: What if anyone remembers those?
Scott: Yeah, all ten people.
Scott: Yeah, we're in the game.
Rym: We ran on there for like a month and then it died out.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Any other meta?
Rym: I think that's it Mm-hmm.
Rym: All right, we're gonna be at PAX East doing a panel on I think Friday at like 6 p.m.
Rym: I'm not sure I got a check but we're doing a Brand new updated like rewrite of that old how to win panel.
Rym: It's called how to play dirty to win.
Rym: You want to fucking win games to the point that your friends won't play games with you anymore.
Rym: That's the panel for you.
Rym: If you want games to not be fun anymore.
Scott: If you're not cheating You're not trying this.
Rym: this panel how to get as close to cheating as possible without actually cheating Mm-hmm, and I think the panel.
Scott: I'm gonna talk about all the things that Rym likes to do Like look at your opponent's eyes to see where they're looking to figure out where they're gonna make their next Dark conversations.
Scott: to distract people don't shuffle the hand of Citadel cards And you pass to the next player and hope they don't shuffle it either and then look at it carefully.
Rym: They pick a card memorize an off-forgotten rule of the game and have a perfect pedantic knowledge of it and let other players Misinterpret it tactically and then interpret it correctly when it's time.
Rym: That is how you win games.
Rym: and then I think the panel I'm gonna put in for prime is just cheating.
Rym: Like if you're gonna cheat, let's talk about what cheating is.
Rym: I like week.
Rym: So now we've got grinding winning losing cheating quitting.
Rym: It's the five fact of one word panels.
Rym: We're out of her at that and I can't come up with any more.
Scott: anyone got any ideas for game panels Especially if they're a one-word idea.
Rym: Yeah, and don't say gaming.
Rym: So I saw people tweeting about this game Like I. people kept reading pictures of it.
Scott: I had heard about it I had seen the box and then I had seen a news that said it came out on iOS and Android.
Scott: I think Android like just the other day I'm think it's five bucks to get the digital version and then I sit down in packs out.
Scott: It was like the first game that hits the table and we played it two times Yep, and that's enough to fully review it.
Rym: I have 100% understanding of the quality of this game.
Scott: so you sit down and you see this game and you go holy shit.
Scott: your first impression if you're is this is the greatest game You've ever seen because it's got this little cardboard Like potion machine that you construct and you dump a bag of marbles in it and they come down like fucking bejeweled.
Scott: only It's in the real world and not a video game.
Rym: Yeah, and you like take marbles out and then marbles fall down and you make combos.
Scott: It's like whoa.
Scott: This is like crazy like that in its own is like the funnest coolest thing.
Scott: It's like better than fucking mousetrap like holy shit.
Rym: This is amazing Despite the utter simplicity of the the rest of the game around it that can see.
Rym: it was enough to where I actually had fun Playing this game Whereas if it had a less clever conceit I would have quit in the middle of the game and said eh right like you see this mechanism and you're like this gonna be Good, let's do this.
Scott: And then you play.
Scott: Okay, you play the game and it's sort of a Average game.
Rym: So here's my first observation about the game.
Rym: Is that if you because usually someone's gonna teach you the rules, right?
Rym: What I found is that most people who have played this game because I talked to a bunch of people at PAX Who have played the game because just because they played it before?
Rym: Nobody had the timing questions that we had.
Scott: Nobody gave a shit like all the question cuz it's such a simple game It's like a family game, right?
Scott: You wouldn't even think to ask these kinds of questions such a basic game.
Scott: But we asked those questions and then when we grabbed the rule book They didn't answer in the rule book nor did they answer.
Scott: and board game geek.
Scott: So no one on board game geek even asked the questions we were asking.
Rym: So some of the questions we asked I did discover were answered in the rule book, but in obtuse ways.
Rym: But they were consistent.
Rym: but some of them I don't think were answered in a consistent way.
Rym: that would satisfy me.
Rym: And you might say but it's a simple game.
Rym: It must not matter.
Rym: It actually would matter a lot.
Rym: it matter a lot because the bejeweled part they're like.
Rym: make a combo is 100% of the game.
Rym: like if you are smart and capable of seeing the best possible combo on the turn That's it.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: the only skill based thing in the game is looking at that pile of marbles in the machine and Figuring out the most optimal way to get the most marbles to come out of it in one turn like
Rym: already like When you put the marbles back on the thing in the middle of your turn Matters a lot and the rules are vague and they say like you can't like you have to do it randomly and you can't direct Them.
Rym: but I could legit like do better at the game by pay holding my marbles in a certain way and dropping them So that the black ones fall into the channel.
Rym: I just opened and Continue my combo.
Scott: They really need to change the mechanism.
Scott: Such baffles needs.
Rym: it needs a tower on top of the mechanism.
Scott: All it needs is on top of the mechanism.
Scott: instead of dumping the marbles into this flat surface with a bunch of holes at The end it should be in more ever use marble madness like a marble race.
Scott: Oh, yeah There was the one piece that was basically a funnel and the marbles would enter into and spin and spin needs that and then it Would go into the hole in the middle.
Scott: Just put one of those on top to feed.
Scott: in that way you put the marbles they spin and spin and spin and spin and They go down one at a time Completely out of any human control into the potion thing.
Rym: Yep But the game really just comes down to like.
Rym: the rest of the rules are ultra ultra simplistic and it feels like the designers And I don't know.
Rym: there's three designers Castelli Crespi and Silva and they haven't done games I particularly know about but I feel like they came up with this cool conceit and then design.
Scott: I came with the simplest game that they could attach to it.
Rym: It is literally just.
Rym: you pull them are?
Rym: you pull a marble off and Then our two marbles.
Rym: I forget.
Rym: you pull one marble and then any combos that get made with colors You also pull those off until you don't get any more combo.
Scott: So if there's blue red blue you would take the red marble Which you now have.
Scott: now the two blue marbles hit each other and two marbles of the same color handing each other makes them explode.
Scott: So you would take those two blue marbles and any other adjacent blue marbles vertically only and you take those and then if that Results in two marbles of the same color smacking into each other in that empty space you just created you would take those and so on and the most you could take would be an entire vertical column.
Scott: if they just Happened to luckily be arranged in such a great way that never happened.
Scott: But you can get a lot of marbles with good arrangements.
Scott: Then you take those marbles and in front of you you got two potions and the potions need Certain colors and certain numbers of marbles to complete.
Rym: so this one needs three red four black and a blue.
Scott: So you put the marbles on the potions to try to complete them and if you complete them You get them and then you take new ones.
Rym: each of the potions is a type that has an effect.
Rym: They're like cards you can use once yeah Things like and basically you drink them to do stuff.
Rym: the action on your turn where you pull a marble is the only time you Get combos.
Rym: so all the other options will let you take more marbles.
Rym: But movement of marbles will not generate further combos from right.
Scott: so for example is a potion that you can drink to take one Marble, but nothing explodes when you do that.
Rym: or take two marbles next to each other that are different colors.
Rym: Yep, stuff like that Reuse the boat.
Scott: take as take as many marbles as you want from the bottom horizontal row But no two of them can be the same color.
Scott: so basically that means Get a red a blue a yellow and a black because there's only four marble colors.
Scott: Yeah, you're not gonna use that and see you're getting four out of it.
Rym: blow up all the marbles of one color in one row Mm-hmm, and then you also have a tiny pool of three.
Rym: you can basically keep three extra marbles around.
Rym: yeah
Scott: in case you get like A ton of red and your potions don't need a bunch of red right now you could put three Marbles and store them in the side area like a sidebar and that way when you get a new potion Then you can move those into there And you won't get.
Scott: you know you're not wasting the marbles.
Rym: so the potions are all worth varying victory points.
Rym: basically they do this.
Rym: They do they all do things.
Rym: They're all equally powered.
Rym: But the more the potions that take more marbles are generally worth a lot more victory points And the game end is actually really weird and fiddly so.
Rym: basically the game ends.
Rym: There's these Chivo's achievements and the achievements are like get three potions of the same type or get one like five different kinds of potions Each time.
Rym: if you accomplish that you take one of these achievements is worth like four points.
Rym: once all of the achievements are taken the Game ends after everyone gets equal number of turns.
Rym: but that that doesn't feel super satisfying and Really the way the game goes is you gotta make two fucking potions every round or you lose right?
Scott: So that's the number one problem with this game is that you cannot catch up.
Scott: Yeah, you have two potions in front of you right and it's very snowball.
Scott: e as soon as you finish potions You now have these powers that make it easier to finish more potions And then you when you finish those you get powers to help you finish more potions.
Scott: But you can never ever no matter what there's no way to finish more than two potions a turn.
Scott: every turn you start with two Potions in front of you and the best you can do is to finish both of them.
Scott: You can also only finish one or fail and finish zero of them.
Scott: So the best you can do is two potions a turn no matter what if you don't do two potions a turn and someone else Does how do you catch up to them if they cuz now not only?
Scott: Would you have to basically hope that they fail and you succeed in order to catch up?
Scott: But they have more completed potions already available to them with powers that will make it easier for them to continue Getting to a turn every turn.
Scott: So as soon as you fail to get two potions on a turn and stop someone else hasn't failed yet you may as well just quit because you can't beat them now and One of the potions is an attack and this is the end.
Rym: one of the ambiguous ones We're basically lets.
Rym: you can steal someone else's pool.
Scott: You can steal their their side marble.
Rym: It's like explain what the fuck it means by that.
Scott: It just says steal and we came up with like Four different ways that could go down And says you can use a potion at any time on your turn even as soon as you finish it.
Scott: So I finish a potion right and then it's a stealing potion.
Scott: I use it and I steal marbles in someone's pool, but my pool is full.
Scott: Am I allowed to do this?
Scott: Do I have to put the stolen ones into my pool?
Scott: Can I put them directly onto my other potion that isn't finished yet?
Scott: Yeah, I've already done the part of my turn where I'm finishing a potion, right?
Scott: Am I allowed to finish a potion then put more marbles in the other potion and then finish that one or do I have to?
Scott: Put you know is my turn to strictly take marbles put marbles finish potions.
Scott: Is it that sequence or not?
Rym: I think and it's not entirely clear the game like the potion stuff probably needs to be a little more complex.
Rym: but more importantly the game would be an interesting game of skill if it weren't a game where anyone who's smart can literally look at the board and Trivially calculate the best possible combo they could make.
Scott: here's how I think the game should.
Rym: I would have a timer.
Rym: You get 10 seconds to take your turn, right?
Scott: Here's the first thing that I would do.
Rym: and if you are if you're holding marbles at the end of your turn when the timer Runs out they explode and you lose them.
Scott: Here's What I did the two experiments that I would do first if I wanted to make this game better.
Scott: Experiment number one is what you just said, right?
Scott: You want to take exactly the right number of marbles like punish people for having unused marbles?
Scott: Right.
Scott: The second thing I would do though is fuck you two potions a turn, right?
Scott: There would be some potions just out there and on your turn make them.
Scott: on your turn You try to you take as many marbles as you can Right by a comboing and then try to get finish as many potions as you can of the available.
Rym: Here's how to make that better.
Rym: you if you have extra marbles, you must put them into the pool potions But if you don't finish one of those potions, they make it easier for the next guy.
Scott: The biggest combo might not be right But the point is just a whole bunch of available Potions and on your turn you take as many marbles as you can and try to finish as many boys as you can who draft The potions like splendor.
Scott: you could do that.
Rym: Here's of increasing power.
Scott: drafting the potions is good.
Scott: Also this is
Rym: then you have pads Like if you're falling behind go for a bigger potion because you make the bigger potions have bigger powers, too
Scott: Right, you could basically make this a lot like splendor of machi karo where instead of just take coins as your turn It's you know, there's a little game for taking the coins and if you play that game, well, you can get more coins Right.
Scott: So that's the first thing I would do.
Rym: to make things better is the most easy thing to do.
Rym: just like your turn is X seconds and like 30 is the most I give and just do what you can make you shit and You bet you'd better not be holding any marbles when the timer hits zero Mm-hmm, I cuz.
Rym: then it's not a stare at the board for a minute to figure out the perfect combo.
Rym: It's shit.
Rym: What do I do?
Rym: Uh, I need black running out of time.
Rym: Fuck it BAM.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: That could be a much better game.
Scott: There's a lot of things you could do to make this game better.
Scott: The game is but the mark the marble part is really cool and you get that when you if you buy the game you have The one-time fun of putting together the marble machine.
Scott: Yeah, which is a little fun project.
Rym: But so minutes like it's a it you know what if you have kids like if you're a family a great kid This is like this is a but a plus game super great kids game.
Scott: compared to like Candyland garbage This is like holy shit.
Scott: So good.
Rym: Yeah a kid who plays this is gonna be way better at like but you'll type Elementary even middle school.
Scott: This is like an a-plus game like holy crap But for adults is like a suit.
Scott: are smart about games.
Rym: It is.
Rym: I see this pattern a lot.
Scott: It is a like if you're like You know if you're not super hard into games if you just sort of you know Regular into games and you have like kids and you gonna play with them.
Scott: Yep You know then you were great for you also competitive in Candyland for you, but it's just.
Rym: it's this almost design pattern of Really solid core conceit.
Rym: everything else is lazy ship it.
Rym: Yep, and This just this fits that perfectly, but I've enjoyed it.
Rym: I never need to play it again.
Rym: the expansion adds nothing.
Rym: the expansion I can see.
Rym: potion explosion.
Rym: The fifth ingredient is just a fifth ingredient and apparently it's just a wild card.
Scott: You can just go buy a sack of marbles of a fifth color like buy some white marbles and there you go.
Rym: There's probably new potions and as prob I assume there's got to be some potions that require the wild card.
Scott: sure, but yeah Whatever.
Rym: It's okay game.
Rym: So I got to say you could buy worse.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Rym: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce Rebecca Dunn Nicholas Brando Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette construction noises Ivy Faye my stady calm.
Rym: William Isen rose Jeremy minor.
Rym: Somebody once told me the world is gonna roll me.
Rym: I ain't the sharpest to Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn is a false statement.
Rym: I see a little silhouette of a man Sherman Van Harl really Val James David Wright Michelle, Monta.
Rym: No no Superboy Abraham link says Aaron serious Brian Fisher sailor Vista.
Rym: I am NOT throwing away my shot.
Rym: Matthew Smith Don Schleich jar topics and Joe Joe Joe star Tyler Eller Sean Yeager Sam Cordray Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan parent drew open.
Rym: Lander Brian Sidonie Sidronie Remember when we married all of us redacted Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel Redman Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: So yeah, we're back and we're bad and we're only doing one more episode this week.
Rym: And then I'm gonna be off on my ski trip.
Rym: So Hopefully as long as I don't die We will have good pictures and stuff from the ski trip and after next week GeekNights will resume with its normal Regular old schedule, but anyway for now post packs.
Rym: You should be real happy that we did an episode right after we got back from packs.
Rym: That's because this was such a good and energizing.
Rym: packs packs out.
Rym: That's so great.
Rym: I look I'm gonna go to it someday.
Scott: But here is something Fuck what you heard.
Scott: It's what you hearin What you hearin?
Rym: Listen, this is what you hear it.
Scott: Listen.
Rym: This is what you hear it.
Rym: Listen X go give it to you.
Rym: fuck.
Rym: wait for you to get it on your own.
Rym: X go deliver to you.
Rym: knock knock open up the door.
Rym: It's real it did not stop my problem.
Rym: stainless steel.
Rym: go hard getting busy with it.
Scott: But I got such a good heart that I make a motherfucker wonder if you did damn right and I'll do it again.
Rym: Yeah, I am like so a gospel.
Scott: it break bread with the enemy.
Scott: no matter how many cats are.
Scott: break bread with a break.
Scott: Who's sending me?
Scott: Bitch.