Rym: It's Wednesday, July 26th, 2017.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights Tonight Castlevania On Netflix.
Scott: The not anime.
Rym: The Netflix one.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So my whole life, I don't like wearing shoes.
Rym: Like that's just a thing I really would rather does not have shoes on but at the same time I don't want the bottoms of my feet to be covered in poop, shall we say.
Scott: I just don't like wearing uncomfortable or painful shoes.
Scott: So I always wear the most comfortable shoe.
Scott: I don't wear an uncomfortable shoe ever.
Rym: But the most comfortable kind of foot covering is Probably the sandal.
Rym: The high quality sandal.
Rym: I'm a big fan of wearing the sandal.
Scott: The most comfortable shoe covering is a sneaker that is extremely squishy and light.
Rym: But that is not optimal if it's hot outside.
Scott: I don't really have a problem of overheating feet.
Rym: It's so much more comfortable.
Rym: Like if I'm wearing sandals, I could even get away with wearing pants instead of shorts.
Rym: That's how profound a difference that is.
Scott: I don't have this problem.
Rym: Also, the sandal is just chill.
Rym: It's airy, your feet are hanging out there.
Rym: They get tanned like the rest of you.
Scott: I don't have this problem.
Rym: Anyway, I really like sandals.
Rym: I'm really particular about my sandals because I don't like flip-flops.
Rym: I think they're...
Scott: No, I hate any any sandal where the thing goes between your big toe and your next toe.
Rym: But that's because it literally is like a glove on your foot.
Scott: No, no, no.
Scott: A toe shoe is fine at least in that regard.
Rym: It's a glove on your foot.
Scott: If you are using this Spoke that goes between your big toe and your second toe as a means of keeping the shoe on the foot It means you sort of have to squeeze those toes together a little bit.
Rym: You have to walk with a weird game Which I read articles there.
Rym: there is evidence that walking long distances and flip-flops causes specific harm, right?
Scott: There is it.
Scott: well to you, you know, a podiatrist wouldn't recommend it, right?
Scott: Yeah, it is not comfortable.
Scott: It is Painful.
Scott: A flip-flop is pretty much only an emergency device to cross a short distance on a hot sand and then remove them.
Scott: Or to like go out to a garbage chute Sure, like walk out into a hallway to go into a shower that might have a fungus in it.
Scott: Perhaps a shared locker room type environment shower because pool shoes are kind of garbagey.
Rym: I used to use pool shoes and those are not great.
Scott: I don't know if they make those anymore.
Rym: If there is a place in the world for Crocs to exist it might be that shower situation Yes, but no other situation.
Rym: No other situation.
Rym: but anyway My issue is that I want if I wear sandals I want my foot to be basically completely exposed But it has to have the three straps two in the front and one around the heel.
Rym: It doesn't go around the heel.
Rym: It's worthless because you still have to walk weird to keep them on your foot.
Scott: See I don't have this problem.
Scott: I have the sandal with just two straps.
Scott: I don't like it, but it is right.
Scott: Essential there are many sandals that do not have the third strap.
Scott: that will like fall off your foot, right?
Scott: Yeah, the point is no matter what the mechanism I know I don't care about a specific mechanism or whatever But it has to be a saddle that is securely remains on your foot on its own So that you do not have to adjust your walking or your foot position.
Scott: You can just walk the same way.
Scott: you walk in a tied shoe.
Scott: Yep, right and This is why I like the three straps and my two strap just stays on just fine.
Rym: I can walk normally in it But so the difference is I can walk in the two straps just fine.
Rym: But if I run or something comes up if there's a chance it'll pop off.
Rym: I guess try to run it in your sandal.
Scott: There's a possibility.
Rym: with the straps You can just run.
Rym: But anyway, I bought some Birkenstocks because they seem to be like the only brand that hipster brand three straps Sandals anymore.
Scott: You can buy them from funny a brand.
Rym: Yeah, so no on Zappos.
Rym: They're there were almost no three strap sandals.
Scott: Anyway, like not I'm sure them.
Rym: so five years ago in April.
Rym: So a little more than five years ago I bought some Birkenstock sandals with the three straps hipsters.
Rym: only today Five plus years later have they worn out enough to where they are no longer wearable.
Scott: Aren't they supposed to last like a lifetime or whatever?
Scott: They have some kind of warranty.
Scott: Isn't that why the hipsters are all into them like?
Scott: I don't know they were just they were break them in over the course of Years like like why?
Rym: no, they broke in basically immediately.
Rym: They were fine.
Scott: It's that get last forever your whole life.
Scott: You wear this way.
Rym: I never encountered any that.
Rym: but I basically I buy.
Rym: they could be blues brother on me like every part of them failed at once and I look cuz I could have gotten before.
Scott: I like Because you wanted to buy a new sandal.
Rym: No, actually I don't like new sandals because I like the like.
Rym: collected grease of my foot over five years makes it like like it Perfectly is formed to my feet.
Rym: Yeah, no, but They blues brother.
Rym: They completely fell apart and I looked it would cost me from even like one of those crap.
Rym: Oh cobblers in like a subway station 40 or 50 bucks to resold them.
Scott: Aren't you supposed to take into the actual Birkenstock company?
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: you have like award.
Scott: There's like a thing they do there.
Scott: It is like that's their mystique or whatever.
Rym: I've never.
Rym: I didn't even think I I didn't encounter that.
Rym: I just I had these sandals.
Rym: I wore them out because I used the hell out of this and googling five plus years.
Rym: so cobblers like 40 50 bucks to Resole them.
Rym: but I can just buy brand new ones for only a little bit more than that and thus get around all the issues The fact that I've beaten the heck out of out of the years.
Rym: So I think I'm gonna buy new sandals every five years for the rest of my life.
Rym: Maybe when I'm old it'll be ten years because I won't walk around as much.
Rym: We'll see.
Rym: So anyway, it's Wednesday, it's comic day, it's not sandal day.
Rym: We already did an episode on shoes a long time ago.
Rym: So what's your news?
Scott: there was tons and tons of huge news from the San Diego comic.
Rym: like Matt Groening is doing a new show and Ready player one like people are flipping out about how bad that thing is.
Scott: I mean, it was so weird, right?
Scott: I it felt like when ready player one was a new hot thing that we were the only ones going.
Scott: But now everyone's going in.
Rym: Well, I think what happened?
Scott: everyone learned from us.
Scott: Is it where they were the?
Rym: someone else described this in detail in a Twitter conversation?
Rym: But to summarize because I think they're dead on it most it became really popular because it was in that loot crate or whatever.
Scott: Is that really the reason it became popular?
Rym: This I haven't been able to verify.
Scott: really evidence of this I have Back, we're like living in Beacon even and like some, you know listeners told us to read this and I heard it was one Of those things, you know You know how I do that.
Scott: when I see something getting lots and lots of buzz and people can't shut up Then I go and check it out like Madoka Magica.
Rym: That's why we check that out exactly people.
Rym: I read the whole goddamn book way back that I Think I mean I quit in the middle of Dragon's Gold Serpent silver chimeras copper and yet you finish this.
Scott: I mean, it was very easy and quick to read.
Scott: it took me like a couple days, but Scott it diminishes the soul Not really At least now no one can tell me all you haven't read it.
Scott: I could.
Scott: now I can I can freely swing Scott stick of judgment.
Scott: And anyone who says did you even read this?
Rym: I'll say yeah read the whole fucking thing Piece of garbage, but basically what they said was that When it suddenly got really popular The only people who were talking about it were the kinds of people that it was aimed like.
Rym: the demographic It was perfectly suited for Were the people who were doing all the reviews and all the talking.
Scott: the impression that I had back when I read it in those Days when is getting buzz was that everyone in the world seemed to be in freaking love with this thing except me.
Rym: and then now Regular people tried to read.
Scott: look at Twitter now, and it's pretty much.
Scott: I have seen just only negative.
Scott: I've not seen a single Positive comment.
Scott: the only positive comment is I was I was talking to a nerd that I am Only slightly acquainted with in person, and I was like yeah, that sucks.
Scott: They were like why?
Scott: And then that same person also.
Scott: I think they subscribe to loot crate and also That's two strikes.
Scott: and also we went to the Lego store, and I ogled like that Apollo rocket and didn't buy it.
Scott: They actually bought like three Lego things one of which is ninja go You know actually it's really good.
Rym: I haven't been to the Lego store in a long time cuz I think I would just start buying Lego.
Scott: The only I was at the Lego store.
Scott: the only thing you want at the Lego store is the Saturn 5.
Scott: It's only $120.
Scott: the problem is it will not fit in your apartment.
Scott: you need to find someone else to keep it for you.
Scott: But it functions perfectly like the little Lander pops off turns around and docks the other way All the stages.
Rym: if I had a three-bedroom apartment there'd be a room.
Rym: that was the rabbits and Lego room And that's all they'd be in there.
Scott: a rabbit's Lego.
Scott: safe.
Rym: I think we're average actually have a hard time biting Legos cuz they're real, but they're real powerful.
Scott: I'm not worried about hurting the rabbit.
Scott: I'm worried.
Scott: We're hurting Lego.
Rym: The Lego would be up on tables.
Rym: I think my train table it falls down and then I feel I mean rabbits are experts at biting things.
Rym: I feel like they could bite them and come out unharmed.
Scott: We'll see.
Scott: you want to swallow them But basically yeah.
Rym: But when I gathered there was this wave of people like all the early waves of people who were reading that book.
Rym: We're like the kinds of people who would love that completely non introspective like regurgitative Pablum aimed at the most pandering of panders the people who go woo.
Scott: when the woo game happens at a convention.
Scott: I mean there's no who wait in line for swag in the packs dealers room.
Rym: There's that screenshot.
Scott: someone keeps waiting line for an anime con dealers room to open.
Rym: this screenshot has hit my feed easily 40 times.
Rym: Covers to comic books and it's just like one page for ready player one and it's just literally lists of proper nouns from Wikipedia from the 80s Mm-hmm.
Rym: Also as people pointed out like none of that stuff was things that like women made.
Rym: it was no like black music.
Rym: It was just like white boy music like there.
Rym: There's a lot.
Rym: there's so many problems with ready player one and I think just recently because the movies being made People who aren't that Demographic looked at it and said what's going on in here?
Rym: What's this?
Scott: Yeah, the funniest thing is the people distributing that.
Scott: that I guess tirade of About porn that the author wrote.
Rym: Oh, I didn't.
Scott: I saw that You know, basically reminding you what kind of person the author of ready player one is.
Scott: Which is disgusting.
Scott: Anyway, so Yeah, anyway, here's some real news from San Diego comic-con.
Scott: So back in the day There was vertigo comics.
Scott: right vertigo comics is a was a an imprint which means it's really DC Comics.
Scott: It's the same exact, you know company.
Scott: But they put a different label on it because this ain't Superman and ain't Batman, right?
Rym: It's other stuff can't scare the Superman people away, right?
Scott: So they just put a different label on it and it's managed by.
Scott: it has different its own editor its own staff and stuff and They work separately right with their own label, but money wise their own the same part of the same company.
Scott: so vertigo still exists, but The thing is back in the day.
Scott: the editor of vertigo the person in charge was this woman and Karen burger burger burger I don't know if the G is hard or soft.
Scott: It doesn't matter And she was responsible for publishing Many of the greatest American comics ever.
Scott: right?
Scott: we're talking V for Vendetta We're talking Sandman preacher fables fucking Why the last man?
Scott: Like fucking everything.
Rym: it's good stuff in here right?
Scott: vertigo comics was like the greatest, right?
Scott: It's like you.
Scott: if vertigo came out with a new book Like I would just get issue number one just to see what it was because if they're publishing it's probably something good, right?
Scott: So what happened is I don't there's some drama or whatever.
Scott: she was kicked out and or left and she she disappeared and Since then vertigo has just been like publishing nothing like.
Scott: they still exist.
Scott: they still put books out, but a lot of them are just reprints and garbage that no one really cares about.
Scott: and Like they're still in the catalog, but they're effectively.
Scott: they may as well be dead right.
Scott: it may as well not exist anymore.
Scott: That's sad times right.
Scott: but image comics since then has been publishing all the good shit like the sagas and the Descenders of the world right.
Scott: things that may have been Vertigo in if they had been published 10 and 15 years ago are now all at image, right?
Scott: But this gives us a problem because without vertigo There's not really a lot of competition for image.
Scott: right you got Marvel in DC or doing underwear perverts only right Japan.
Scott: those publishers are in a different country.
Scott: that IDW which used to do good stuff is now sort of like only doing licensed stuff right.
Scott: ponies Transformers yeah, I chose they just got Sonic the Hedgehog from Archie which and actually that stuff is generally actually pretty good.
Rym: But it's not this kind of calm.
Scott: that stuff raised IDW from being sort of an indie tiny publisher to being like big-time publish.
Rym: Yeah, right actually I really want to read mask.
Rym: Sure, I just haven't yet.
Rym: I've been busy go for it.
Scott: They'll probably trade soon.
Scott: Yeah so all anything that's like a licensed nerd property that's not owned by Disney or Warner DC is over at IDW.
Scott: right.
Scott: all the Hasbro things all that stuff.
Scott: So the only other really big American comics publisher.
Scott: You know that's the super big right There's like some medium-sized ones like boom and stuff or your mouse guards and things like that.
Scott: like you know what whatever.
Scott: But you know is Dark Horse and Dark Horse is mostly doing mangas Hellboys, I think they have like alien Buffy the Vampire Slayer Those sorts of things right and they just sort of quietly over there on the side You know doing their thing not getting a lot of attention, but now big dudes.
Scott: Karen Berger Who ran vertigo back in the day has signed up with Dark Horse and they're gonna make Dark Horse burger books first of all Totally deservedly.
Scott: She just gets her name on the fucking job right what that that means?
Rym: seal of approval slash Endorsement, right?
Scott: So this is actually not new news.
Scott: We knew this is coming like some months ago But now at Comic Con they actually announced the like the initial books that are coming out.
Scott: So they got Hungry Ghosts by Anthony Bourdain the cover alone.
Scott: All right, the chef Anthony Bourdain, which is I guess I know that that's the name of a famous chef.
Scott: I don't know anything else about it.
Scott: I just know that that is the name of a famous chef person and it's about food.
Scott: But yeah, you can tell by the cover.
Scott: The only name on the cover that I care about is Paul Pope.
Scott: like one of my favorite artists of all time He like he doesn't do a lot of stuff like anything he does.
Scott: He's like Midas touch of artwork.
Scott: And now that you can tell his artwork from like 10 miles away like no one draws like him anywhere.
Rym: Is that just him Maya from my eccentric family?
Rym: I don't know with his our ramen shop in hell.
Scott: The other thing that is interesting is The seeds right by and the senti and David Aja, so I know who David Aja is.
Scott: That's a familiar name I've heard before right?
Scott: So that's gonna be really interesting.
Scott: You've got this thing called the originals, right?
Scott: So the originals is has the artists from Watchmen not Alan Moore Who's probably who know what the hell he's doing?
Scott: Rolling around it's a mud somewhere.
Scott: I don't know One of those retired and retired do who knows what he confirmed.
Rym: he's retiring from comic books last year.
Scott: sure, whatever No one cares your old man.
Scott: But Dave Givens the other Watchmen guy is starting a series called the originals and the cover looks like Fucking Watchmen art because it's the same fucking guy.
Scott: Yep You got this thing Madahari, I guess it's about the real Madahari.
Scott: I don't even know.
Scott: and this other thing called Incognito Renaissance, which looks like mafia do incognito.
Rym: It's a very specific period thing I couldn't tell from.
Scott: it's hard to read that word that I've seen.
Rym: this one in particular has been getting a lot of buzz in My feed lately.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I'm just looking at the knee like.
Scott: I don't know who Matt Johnson and Warren police are but that doesn't matter Because I know Karen burgers, I'm gonna buy all of these books issue number one to see which ones are legit.
Rym: So we basically just outlined a bunch of GeekNights episodes that are coming up.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much any.
Scott: well, we'll probably do one episode all number ones.
Scott: Oh, yeah, and then so forth right.
Scott: and then like when I'm sure these won't be the only books this imprint publishes.
Scott: Right these they're gonna figure out which ones succeed which ones fail which ones are limited which ones keep going forever, right?
Scott: And new ones will come up.
Scott: But this is like, you know comic book publisher to watch.
Scott: if it has this name on it from Dark Horse It's worth at least checking it out.
Rym: Yep Just the covers all these alone.
Rym: I'm interested.
Rym: if I saw these at some comic-con and I didn't know anything I'd probably pick them all up.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So really quick news because this this like shockingly happened and I saw Twitter freaking out about it.
Rym: I guess United Airlines Just randomly started telling people trying to fly home from San Diego.
Scott: comic-con isn't United Airlines the one like every airline?
Scott: Yeah, every single airline has bad stories about it in the news all the time But United is the one with the most bad and most frequent bad story.
Rym: Well, so I would say that spirit is still a worse airline by every measure.
Scott: I mean probably but it doesn't.
Scott: it's not in the news for being.
Scott: it's just generally bad.
Rym: But I've been boycotting United for most of my life because but majority of the times I try to fly with them.
Scott: Yeah, we're like Spirit Airlines is just generally shitty.
Scott: That's like taking a Greyhound bus.
Scott: It's just generally shitty.
Scott: but United has specific horrific incidents that are frequently newsworthy.
Rym: but in this case, they basically started telling people that the TSA said you can't check comic books and you check bags and That was egregious enough to even the TSA Which is an organization that I despise with literally every fiber of my being.
Rym: even they were like No, that is not true WTF.
Scott: this is probably just one relatively low-ranking employee doing a thing at that one Airport in San Diego from you know just like meh just Because who knows why they thought of doing this, but they just did for whatever reason.
Rym: all these nerds showed up at the airport And I have sort of that.
Rym: there's a buried lead in this story.
Rym: I'll get to in a second Mm-hmm, but I guess a buried barb is a better a better way to put this but all they had all these signs.
Rym: comic-con attendees remove all books from check bags and A lot of people go to comic cons buy a lot of fucking books literally like bring extra luggage and fill.
Scott: That is nothing but books.
Scott: Yeah hundred percent book.
Rym: My barb is simply Why are you buying so many comics at a comic-con?
Rym: They're not cheaper there.
Rym: This isn't like Silver Age Silver Surfer at Wizard World from a discount bin.
Scott: Well, the thing is actually if you actually unless you're getting weird exclusive signed, I guess but how many?
Scott: So if you're the kind of nerd who like is like you're only care about comic books.
Scott: You don't.
Scott: and you like the floppy shitty kind right or even the trade paperback kind.
Scott: if you go to comic conventions and you're buying stuff that isn't brand new and Is Super old or rare, but it's just sort of like, you know Like a trade paperback that came out two years ago, and then they made too many copies and didn't sell them all.
Scott: It's like if you try to buy those online They're not gonna be like two dollars, but at the convention, there's some comic store that's dealing there.
Scott: That's just oh my god, please.
Scott: I want to get rid of this inventory and they're selling it for $2.
Scott: Yep, so if you buy a large quantity of that stuff You can reach an economic point to where the price of your comic-con badge the travel the hauling and if you're actually gonna read It all of course.
Scott: So but I'm in the play.
Rym: I can spin that back around.
Rym: if you had to fly to get to San Diego comic-con That threshold is significantly higher Mm-hmm.
Scott: You have to save at least the $50 that you Extra checked bag.
Rym: also books ain't light and there's limits on how heavy bags can be.
Scott: indeed I was.
Scott: it's probably cheaper for the $50 of the checking bag.
Scott: You could probably spend $40 at the FedEx.
Rym: so my only guess is what actually happened here is that Someone maybe was trying to troll comic nerds and worked at United.
Rym: That's possible purposefully Misinterpreted a TSA guideline to do this to cause havoc for the lulls.
Rym: That's my guess.
Scott: Oh, there's definitely possible.
Scott: There are lots and lots of incidents where Individual employees have the power to do something but they're you know, the thing happens.
Scott: It's you know No one knows no one outside knows why or how or who and it's just like it causes a bigger deal.
Scott: then You know any that the person who did it thought would it would cause.
Scott: now right and then he's just like oh shit.
Scott: And then once it becomes a deal the coal company finds out about it and now you're fine.
Rym: Yeah but anyway things of the day what he got?
Scott: so Hockey comes in many varieties and we enjoy almost all of those varieties.
Scott: the field kind The deck kind that guy he's okay.
Rym: the ice kind Yeah, roller hockey is the only hockey I played any serious amount in my.
Scott: so it's rather difficult for a normal person To play a lot of these kinds.
Scott: right ice kind is the hardest even though it's the most common.
Scott: Not only do you need to know how to skate but you need a venue.
Scott: you know how to skate backwards.
Scott: You need to have ice I need to have equipment.
Scott: It's like it's a rich person's game.
Rym: No I would argue polo.
Scott: skill wise I guess polo is more expensive because you need a fucking horse and a horse cost more than hockey.
Scott: equipment skill wise has to be maintained.
Rym: ice hockey is way easier than roller hockey because roller blades like that not really designed for that playing that sport.
Rym: the way hockey gets played doesn't work the same way, but anyway.
Scott: But roller hockey is least eat a more accessible.
Scott: if you want to just try.
Scott: you see roller blades are cheaper.
Scott: You don't need ice you know right.
Scott: you know the equipment is less.
Scott: It's a street right, but the point is almost all varieties of hockey except sticks no regular shoes on feet and nets with a ball is Really inaccessible right so?
Scott: There was a type of hockey that I just discovered today.
Scott: I want to play this real bad I'd never seen before and this type of hockey is a little bit less accessible than The other kinds.
Scott: right.
Scott: then say just ball feet and whatever.
Scott: I'd have to buy a few things But it is not out of the reach and does not most importantly does not require any skills of skating or rolling or anything like that And this is soap hockey.
Rym: it requires balance.
Scott: basically make a giant Rectangular slip and slide.
Scott: you know a slip and slide is rectangular But it needs to be wider than that.
Scott: right a big wide slip and slide.
Scott: and rather than having water rushing down it You make it flat and cover it in soap liquidy soapy water, so it's fucking slippery as hell.
Rym: And then just try to play hockey with that.
Scott: you put two tiny nets balls and plastic sticks And you get out there, and you play hot and you fall on your ass as Grover Just pointed out ankle injury the game.
Scott: Yes, it is ankle injury the game, but that's fine.
Scott: Oh, I'm fine with ankle injury the game.
Scott: I am.
Scott: I am just not as let's safer than skiing.
Scott: it's even safer than I can in this.
Rym: I would argue This is way less safe than skiing.
Scott: listen the chances of being injured doing this way higher than skiing probably higher than skiing Safely I agree, but if you have an injury skiing You're probably going to break a leg or crack your head open.
Scott: if you have an injury With the almost guaranteed injury of doing this is like spraying your ankle.
Scott: big deal.
Rym: I feel like cracked heads are a real possibility.
Rym: lost teeth.
Rym: I Fight.
Scott: I think those are really unlikely.
Rym: Running on slick surfaces swinging sticks around I think you sort of shuffle.
Scott: if you try to run.
Scott: It's not gonna go well for you.
Rym: I still want to play it.
Scott: Absolutely would play this.
Scott: if anyone wants to donate a big flat lawn doesn't mind it getting ruined by soap and being covered and trampled upon.
Scott: And I'll go.
Scott: I'll get the nets and sticks and balls and Amazon if you take care of the rest.
Rym: so I've been following a lot of different YouTube channels talking about like archaic technology mostly from the 60s 70s 80s and Tech mode is pretty good, but this video is really interesting because there's an area of technology I've been very interested in myself lately and that is Think about a task that you do today with computers basically and then realize that The task itself was done by professionals before computers were widespread and then try to figure out how the hell they did it.
Rym: Like how did a sound board work before you could just have like wave files on a computer?
Rym: like how did a DJ just make a particular sound play suddenly by hitting a button?
Rym: and The answer is for many cases from the 60s through the 90s have lots of tapes Yeah, but even though some tapes aren't that accurate.
Rym: They don't have like cue points at least cassette tapes Don't like standard cassette tapes.
Scott: No, they had fancy tapes like DAT tapes and shit.
Rym: No, so DAT tapes didn't solve this.
Rym: they use something called a broadcast cart machine.
Rym: Okay, and the tapes are spooled the same way.
Rym: that eight tracks are All right, and the base of the main reason these were important was that they'd play forever.
Rym: You never.
Rym: you could not rewind them, but you could always play them forever in a loop.
Scott: Oh, it would go back to the beginning.
Rym: Yeah, you know how that works.
Rym: You ever see like an endless tape and what how those work?
Rym: Yes, so cuz all eight track.
Rym: you realize eight tracks are all like this, too.
Rym: You could never rewind an eight track.
Rym: You can only play forward Yep, and eight tracks actually did have eight tracks and there was a predecessor the four track.
Rym: I had an eight track system that I played with a lot as a kid and I kept repairing because it broke.
Rym: So I actually know a lot about eight tracks.
Rym: But anyway Broadcast cart is the way like if you were at an event or you were a DJ and you needed sounds and jingles and things To be able to be queued up.
Rym: the difference between any other tape mechanism of the era Was that it could be.
Rym: it could start playing and stop playing nearly instantly Which is not like ever trying to pause a VCR at the at an exact spot.
Rym: It's actually real hard.
Scott: So did you like preset it with start and stop points or something?
Rym: You can manually start and stop it and it's like instant and it also has a mechanism for the machine queuing up The next sound.
Rym: that's on the tape couldn't you also?
Scott: I mean, this is probably not the best way to do it.
Scott: But it's possible right.
Scott: just it says this tape is a loop.
Scott: You get a really short tape that plays a tiny loop over and over and over again and it's always playing and you just turn It down on the mixer and then when you want to hear it, you just mix it up and mix it down.
Rym: I mean, yeah, I've you can die.
Rym: Oftentimes at an event you'll do a loop track like that.
Rym: And this the one that.
Rym: so in this video they have a giant track tape that he finds That's like super super long and he basically when it's really long.
Rym: He repairs it to figure out what the hell was on it Mm-hmm and the machine to play it.
Rym: Yeah, this channel is all about having the machines for this nonsense.
Rym: Okay, but yeah, that is the thing that some people would do.
Rym: but this is a really interesting video talking about the very like Challenging problem of doing that kind of thing before computers existed that we got to just take for granted now.
Scott: Hmm I guess you could also do it with vinyl if you knew the exact spot to put the needle.
Rym: you put it Take it off real fast But you have to be really skilled Ah, but also vinyl doesn't really start playing immediately cuz you're gonna get that scratch noise when you put the needle down.
Scott: Yeah, yeah, you would that's right.
Rym: Yeah, no one use vinyl for that.
Scott: They have nowadays.
Scott: I've heard that there are some record players that will use a laser and not a needle to like optically read the Record, so I learned about basically means it's a CD at that point Except worse quality because vinyl is not actually that high fidelity.
Rym: Jesus do not even fight me.
Scott: I don't understand why people are so hyped on vinyl.
Scott: even still I keep seeing like in my Twitter feed.
Scott: occasionally Someone's like, oh man bought new vinyl.
Scott: I'm like what the fuck.
Scott: and if and if your argument is you're like a record company starts producing more vinyl It's like people it's garbage.
Rym: if you're into the cool old technology like the weird old tape stuff is way more interesting.
Scott: This is cool, but we're not gonna buy any of these ever.
Rym: Though also, uh, I would point out that the end run of analog cassettes like the height that technology got to before they're obsoleted by CDs is Nearly indistinguishable from CD quality.
Rym: if you got like Dolby s going on.
Rym: Mmm It's just the CDs sort of displaced that too quickly.
Rym: Mmm.
Rym: But anyway, I digress otherwise them at a moment.
Rym: the book club book is The fifth season season.
Scott: so not winter not spring not summer not fall.
Scott: What smart other season.
Scott: smart is a month Season another season the fifth season by nk jemisin.
Scott: It's like the hottest shit fantasy novel going on and I'm gonna read it as soon as I've finished reading about that.
Scott: They're unholy consult.
Rym: Yep, and there's nothing but games.
Scott: They are perpetuating in the arc of Gogara in the shadow of Golgothar off.
Rym: The arc of man is having knives used on it.
Scott: That is how it be.
Scott: that is happy quite literally princes of not much and less Horses being broken left and right man.
Scott: He who breaks horses is actually broken less horses than everyone else in this book so far.
Rym: Yeah, I'm disappointed.
Scott: not one horse broken by the official horse breaker But many horses broken by others who wouldn't even know how to break a horse.
Scott: They're mere mere amateurs compared to the true master of horse breaking.
Rym: Otherwise the next convention we're gonna be at is Pax West Mothership packs the real the ticket.
Scott: I just remembered I in my bag over there in the other room.
Scott: I have Tickets to the real pack.
Scott: Oh they came the badges not the stinking ones.
Scott: You don't need the ones you need very badly badges.
Rym: Yes, you definitely need badges.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: They are in the mail.
Scott: They have arrived.
Scott: don't lose them because you're not using them for a few more weeks.
Rym: But we will be there on Sunday, which is the third of the four days.
Rym: We're gonna be there on all of the day But we will be there on Sunday doing a panel on rage quitting and butthurt rage and all those sorts of topics And I think it'll be fun.
Rym: It's gonna be awesome and also something very important.
Rym: Yeah, also one of our friends and listeners of the longest time the row row is Literally was a listener who when we said hey, we're gonna be at a PAX Isn't that cool?
Rym: back in 2008 where we were still you spring chickens She picked us up at the airport didn't serial kill us and drove us to our hotel and now after so many packs is She has been accepted as the Omega knot.
Scott: So that means we're gonna be going to every not just the final omega-thon round as usual But every round unless row loses we're making sure we'll just be going to the last round.
Rym: like I'm gonna make a shirt.
Scott: We're gonna make a lot of shit.
Scott: So you should if you want to see us come to the omega-thon round and also help us cheer for a row.
Scott: So she win.
Rym: so let's get right.
Scott: as I mean that would make this packs like even more epic than usual.
Scott: It's already like up a level, but she win.
Scott: that's like up.
Rym: Well think of it this way if she wins One that means that I'll she'll go to PAX Australia.
Scott: We're all gonna go to back.
Rym: So yeah, but to the the after packs feast.
Rym: while it will not be in the most wonderful bathroom that we've ever seen it'll be somewhere.
Scott: and Imagine we'll go to the fancy restaurant instead of the regular restaurant.
Scott: We'll go to the fanciest place we can find.
Scott: Yeah, it'll.
Rym: it'll be a feast of celebration like a place that caused mad money Mad money the meat.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: So yeah.
Rym: So if you didn't hear Netflix made a four episode TV series animated of Castlevania 3 is it Castlevania 3 really curse of Dracula?
Rym: you didn't did it.
Scott: I thought it was just Castlevania generic.
Rym: So you didn't notice a la card and Sifa The only person we didn't see that we need to see to make it fully Castlevania 3 is grant and I assume he's gonna be there.
Scott: I thought the next season.
Scott: I thought they can't.
Scott: a la card isn't until like PlayStation He should.
Scott: did you ever play Castlevania 3?
Scott: I didn't beat it.
Rym: Did you ever?
Rym: did you ever get a character other than Trevor Belmont?
Scott: I don't think so.
Rym: You realize the whole shtick with that game was that you run into Sifa a la card and grant Depending on the routes you take through Dracula's castle.
Scott: and I think I had to go back and play Castlevania 3 because All I know about Castlevania 3 is a. it's a lot like Castlevania 1 style not Castlevania 2 style.
Rym: Oh, there's a big it.
Rym: actually it's a kind of a hybrid of the two.
Scott: There's a big hullabaloo about the audio in that game.
Scott: Japanese cartridge had a much better Soundship and better.
Scott: amazing incredible music considering was an NES game.
Scott: Yeah, and the American cartridge had crap music by comparison.
Rym: So Scott although pretty good by comparison to other crap NES games You can play as all these different characters and there's different ending.
Scott: I guess I'm gonna go emulate and beat Castlevania 3.
Rym: then I don't think you will.
Scott: you don't think I will.
Rym: Castlevania 3 how hard could it be might be the hardest Castlevania that was ever.
Rym: It cannot be.
Rym: Castlevania 1 is also.
Scott: I'm gonna play the Japanese version because I want that better Japanese version is easier by most accounts.
Scott: I just want the better audio.
Rym: What uh, uh, well your emulator do that.
Scott: Yeah, why not?
Rym: Well, you sure will Yeah, make sure your emulator supports that weird chip.
Scott: It will definitely support it.
Scott: What year is it?
Rym: Anyway, I can't believe you did.
Rym: So yeah This is literally one of the first times in human history That a television show or movie was made based directly on a video game and it was good.
Scott: Why did they choose?
Scott: Castlevania 3 specifically.
Scott: so I was not say Symphony of the Night or Aria of sorrow or any of the other Castlevania.
Rym: so I thought there'd be a short answer to that question.
Rym: It turns out there's a very Long answer to that question.
Scott: should we answer this long question or should people just go to the internet and read it for the?
Rym: If you want me to tell you I'm literally on the Wikipedia page.
Rym: Just read it.
Rym: But this summarize it the The production of this Castlevania series had a long and torturous path.
Rym: There's no upside down castle yet.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah this came out in 2017, right?
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: so I'm just gonna read the first sentence of the summary of how this came to be and you'll see why it's hard to summarize.
Rym: quote in March of 2007. ten years ago Frederator Studios acquired the bravest warriors acquired the rights to produce an animated film adaptation specifically of Castlevania 3.
Scott: why does this have anything to do with this current?
Rym: because that is where this current thing came from?
Scott: It's not a completely brand new deal Like this up the old remains of this.
Rym: this Literally, you know hard it was for this to get made.
Rym: it got stuck in development hell like twice All right.
Scott: Anyway, so this new this Castlevania 3 animated adaptation looks a Lot like what people would say is anime even though we know there's no such thing as look like anime because anime comes in
Rym: Evoke that especially if you look at stills from it that very specific feeling of late 80s and early to mid 90s Violent away views.
Scott: It looks like vampire hunter D or demon city or ninja scroll.
Scott: It looks like those anime style.
Scott: That's the visual style.
Scott: It has right but it is written by Warren Ellis a Credible great writer author of many works such as trans metropolitan fell Next world, what else is he written?
Scott: That's really good.
Scott: Those are the big ones that I can think of.
Scott: Yeah But Warren Ellis is usually if you see his name on something that means good writings are here.
Rym: read this comic and it was general.
Rym: It was a pretty big International production involving a ton of different studios and production companies and people
Scott: but not Japanese people Which is why it is not anime, but it doesn't matter if it's anime or not It's an animated work and I don't really give a shit about if it's anime or not.
Rym: Yep Though I will say while the stills so so heavily evoked those 90s OAVs as does the story and the violence.
Rym: But and I had this very specific and odd reaction as soon as I was watching it a few minutes in I Really was reminded of the way a on flux was Animated in terms of like the way the camera would move and the way the characters
Scott: not if you mean not a lot.
Rym: Yeah It doesn't move much and there's just the way the faces looked in the way the characters sort of look past each other instead of At each other.
Rym: so I got this really strong like rain or a on flux vibe just from that.
Scott: Yeah and the dialogue is all that like very stilted like only saying what needs to be said sort of feels like there's a like a Millisecond too much pause in between people talking to each other.
Scott: and yeah But the thing is.
Scott: that's the way those 90s things like Ninja Scroll felt when they were dubbed.
Rym: This feels too easy.
Scott: This is original English language.
Scott: This isn't some Japanese thing.
Scott: That was right.
Rym: This is but if it feels like watching the dove of vampire hunter D, right?
Scott: It's a little bit.
Scott: the voice acting is a little bit better than that.
Scott: There's like if one of the voice actors like a famous person, right?
Scott: What's his name?
Rym: Oh Richard Armitage.
Scott: Yeah that guy.
Rym: Yeah, the voice acting is good.
Rym: However, the script is a little bit.
Rym: People say fucking piss a lot for just because yeah Like it was it feels like the kind of language that some dubs of those old anime OAVs Is.
Scott: the original dialogue isn't translated.
Rym: however, I was reading this interview with the producer of Castlevania and It's very telling what they drew from because basically the anime seems like the person medium for Castlevania.
Rym: You mentioned ghost in the shell and ninja scroll and other interviews.
Rym: what anime creatively informed this series?
Rym: And the answer is and I quote vampire hunter D was an early reference.
Rym: Yeah space pirate Harlock for the use of color Oh Berserk as an example of what to do.
Rym: There's a lot of berserk going and the CGI reboot as an example of what not to do.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, no, there's definitely a lot of berserk going on in this year in this year show for sure.
Rym: Uh, I really liked it.
Rym: I mean we're gonna talk about it in depth.
Rym: It's only four episodes.
Scott: So it's four short episodes.
Scott: just watch it.
Scott: yeah, it's not.
Scott: I'm not gonna say it's like it's not great, right but it's like if you have Netflix and you're a nerd and you're like a vampire or you like anime or you like violence or you like.
Scott: it's like it's worth Your 80 minutes of your life.
Scott: Yeah, cuz it's not that long.
Rym: I enjoyed the hell out of it.
Scott: I didn't enjoy the hell out of it, but it was like, all right.
Scott: So the plot is basically if it was, you know, if it wasn't Castlevania, it might have been like man.
Scott: So spike speak, I think the fact that it is Castlevania puts it over the phone.
Rym: and tonight spike Spiegel reincarnated as Trevor Belmont Fine meets a wizard girl and they go into a dungeon to wake up Ellen Chazar from Escaflowne.
Rym: You go fight Dracula exactly.
Scott: That is the plot.
Scott: Well, the actual plot is that Dracula was Dean his usual self.
Scott: his castle reappeared once every whatever number of years.
Rym: Dracula's a chill dude.
Scott: Relatively well, I mean he's not super chill He's an evil vampire dude But he's not like destroying the world or anything Right, and then some lady comes to visit him because she heard that he's got mad science Which he does because he's like fucking immortal and he knows shit.
Scott: that beginning scene is my favorite scene and in the dark ages People don't know shit, right?
Rym: Yeah, she shows up and she's like the peasants are all dumb.
Scott: Castle is like a fucking cave of wonders full of awesomeness and she's like she convinces Dracula like hey Let me have your science.
Scott: and he's like, alright, you're hot.
Scott: I'll go with it.
Scott: Yeah, cuz I'm still a dude even though I'm an immortal, dude.
Rym: Well also it was interesting because she shows up and she's clearly not afraid of him.
Scott: She doesn't know she's a woman of science.
Scott: He doesn't know that Dracula is all like vampire and shit.
Scott: She just thinks he's a rich old you know dude who lives in a castle full of science.
Rym: and that aspect of it is really interesting because there's like a big part of the plot.
Rym: is that Dracula vampires because they're long-lived have science they have light bulbs and things.
Rym: Yeah, and it's cool how like Trevor Belmont remembers all the you know The knowledge of his family and he talks a lot like did you see those strange implements and blah blah blah, right?
Scott: That's the.
Rym: that's the legend of what's inside Dracula's castle.
Scott: But the world is clearly in a dark age has much lower technology than the vampires.
Rym: I mean, it's what 1400s right people in Wallachia.
Scott: It's like the towards the end of the Middle Ages in the United States.
Scott: Yeah in the real world Europe.
Rym: Now here's the real question does Dracula's castle Travel through time such that that is that precursor technology is actually his future technology?
Rym: did vampires independently invent electricity?
Scott: and all this because they live a long time and they're bored or Live a long time and they're bored because if it was time-traveling he'd have like, you know Internet in his yes Or was there a precursor?
Rym: Civilization and the memory of that is all that remains.
Scott: Also think.
Scott: part of it is that in the past there were times when Dracula's castle appeared because it's reappeared so many times that there have been times when it's appeared that you know Dracula has had like, you know, huge armies or slaves or who knows what.
Scott: we're building things.
Scott: Yeah It's like the castle was made at some point by a whole bunch of people that Dracula had forced to build.
Scott: he didn't build it By hand on his own but the very beginning of this he was a king right his account at least he had people.
Rym: But it seems like in that initial little bit because this like this whole backstory is like a minute of screen time Right just to set the stage.
Rym: because and I'm glad they did it because if you don't give some sort of reason Dracula's just this like bad bad guy.
Scott: I mean like Symphony the night where it's like What is a man?
Scott: a pile of secrets?
Scott: Hahaha Dracula?
Scott: All right now try to kill me.
Scott: the ends like go go go.
Scott: It's like why I don't you know anything about you.
Scott: It's like all right, I guess I have to kill Dracula cuz he bad he Dracula yep, but uh from the first like 10 minutes this show Dracula Kind of justified not fully justified by.
Scott: so the issue it right.
Scott: So what they do is they basically give Dracula a Refrigerator reason for being evil, right?
Scott: They take his wife murder his his wife.
Scott: So now he mad right?
Scott: It's the old fridge scenario.
Scott: No It's like all right.
Scott: You have your reason you're you're you know, but also rope reason.
Rym: But the church drag that murdered his wife way more evil than Dracula, right?
Scott: The difference is though is that Dracula's vengeance cuz he's so powerful is Way over the top.
Scott: It's like yeah, not only is he taking it out on the church.
Scott: He's killing all humans.
Scott: Kill all humans.
Rym: It implies that he's only gonna kill all the humans in Wallachia.
Scott: That's pretty much all humans.
Scott: No, it doesn't feel like there's anything outside of.
Scott: will I get in this?
Scott: in this Joe I mean there has to be the whole world.
Rym: I mean, I don't.
Rym: I don't know how closely the castle in your world is set in the world.
Rym: Yeah But basically he even gives them a sporting chance though He comes back and he's like I'm gonna fucking kill you all in one year.
Rym: So leave or make your peace.
Rym: I'll be back and the bishops like.
Rym: he's not coming back and it's not really a spoiler But there's this great coming back.
Rym: exactly when he said he would where the bishop is literally giving mass and he's like.
Rym: Dracula said Almost one year ago to this very moment that he would come back and kill us in one year and we're still alive.
Rym: He didn't come back and then the sky starts raining blood and a whole bunch of vampire hunter.
Rym: D happens all at once.
Scott: Dracula's like here.
Scott: I am.
Scott: I promised I'm here.
Scott: Listen I was you know, yep.
Scott: I'm Dracula.
Scott: I got time.
Scott: a year for me is like a second.
Scott: That's like.
Scott: I'll be back in a minute guys.
Rym: I'm gonna pee and come back but it basically takes all the like.
Rym: the formal story that like could be gleaned from Castlevania 3 takes those bits and pieces and gives them just enough interesting context to drive the story forward without Like ruminating too deeply on the details of the lore.
Rym: like it you get impressions like the Belmont family Are all like mysterious and have powers and the shit.
Rym: You're the only one left and because the the church turned on them to the church basically fucked everything up in this.
Scott: Well, that seems to what always has another trope right is like there's a there's a some good people's but they're like.
Scott: You know their job is to fight the evil.
Scott: But now the evil has been gone for so long that now those they seem like crazy be like the mandate and the prince of Nothing exactly.
Scott: It's the same exact thing.
Scott: So basically the mandate Belmonts here.
Rym: Actually, it's very close to that because the Belmonts like the speakers and the vampire It's a. so the speakers the Belmonts and the vampires all know how the world works and are smart and then the regular people Don't know shit.
Rym: The church is actively evil and regular people are the dumbest beings who have ever existed.
Scott: other medieval peasants Yeah, but it's not fair to them.
Scott: They didn't have opportunity for education.
Rym: That is true.
Scott: But this show really single school in this show.
Rym: This show really goes out of its way to hammer into your head how dumb the normal people are in this world, right?
Scott: I mean, well, the first thing is this science lady who comes to Dracula's castle and she's like yo.
Scott: People in this world are really dumb.
Scott: They won't listen to my science.
Scott: If only I could science them I could save them.
Scott: Yeah, cuz they're also Dracula's like.
Rym: alright science away.
Scott: Yeah Everyone's so done.
Rym: There is a scene That because the show is only four episodes It's a high percentage of the total dialogue spoken and it is a long debate about the logistics and punishments for sheep-fucking.
Rym: yeah, and Like that scene you think it's gonna be a joke and it just keeps going and going and they they're really talking about this.
Scott: Is that the one in the tavern?
Rym: Yeah, yeah with with the really ugly guy the less ugly guy the stringy ugly guy and the bartender who looks like the bartender from Cowboy bebop the tavern scene.
Scott: I think only exists to introduce Trevor, right?
Scott: He's the quiet guy.
Rym: I think it also exists to introduce the culture of those peasants.
Scott: Yeah, he's the.
Scott: he's the quiet guy.
Scott: It's all these tropes, right?
Scott: He's the quiet guy sitting in the back of the tavern not saying anything, but he makes all these vehicle faces all the time.
Scott: All the disgruntled peasants make a ruckus in there.
Rym: Yeah But He really like he'll almost it.
Rym: it doesn't really hurt the show But sometimes he makes kind of a stereotypical anime face and that doesn't really fit.
Rym: the rest of the way The face is usually drawn.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: But anyway, the highlight of the show for me is Actually the action scenes.
Scott: Oh, so sword fight the most sort for animation and most of the show is middling.
Scott: to average There's a few times where it sort of looks kind of man.
Scott: You know a little weirdness and the way things move.
Scott: during times when things don't move much they move a little bit They move weirdly right but when there's action scenes They put in like super effort into them to where they're not quite as good as like say the fight in episode one of cowboy Bebop or something like that where it's like majestically animated.
Scott: they're close, but it's still like a wow Situation like the one where they takes the dude's eyeball out.
Rym: Oh that whip You said you said something.
Rym: cuz you watch it before me.
Scott: I specifically remember this one part where he was.
Scott: it was a shot of Trevor and he was whipping right now And it was showing basically him from his shoulders up his arms in his head And that was the whole taking up the whole frame and he was whipping like with both hands whip whip whip Right or it looked like he was whipping with both hands.
Scott: It might have been one hand whipping back and forth and I could tell that for like one second of animation His whipping movement looped like three times and I was like, how long are they gonna loop this whipping animation?
Scott: and then as soon as I thought that at the speed of thought it changed to a Different whipping loop and then changed to a third different whipping loop.
Scott: So they normally someone doing cheapo animation would have had one loop of whipping.
Scott: now, right?
Scott: They animated three different ways of whipping right for like three seconds like whip whip whip whip whip whip and then a different whip whip whip and I was like Oh, they actually like it could tell like ooh, it's visually interesting.
Scott: What is happening?
Scott: Yes.
Scott: He's just whipping.
Scott: There's nothing happening in the story other than violence to like the there's.
Rym: so there's a bunch of vampire hunter D Like things getting kind of have violence.
Scott: But like this applies.
Scott: this same principle applies to all of the action scenes.
Scott: with like especially.
Scott: we just fight in Alucard.
Rym: Well when he fights that dirt priest right away and he's be whips to knock the dagger out of his hand Yeah, and then you see the guy dude's finger just like land next to the dagger and you're like, ooh.
Scott: And then he think he makes a funny comment about the thing.
Scott: Yeah, he does if I remember correctly then he whips the other guy's eye out and he's like, well, yeah I was when he whipped the eyeball.
Scott: I was like, oh pie may steal your eyeball.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Oh, I think the best fight though Was the Alan Shehzar fight?
Rym: Yes, because that because the way Alucard moved was great.
Scott: Yeah, cuz I mean and his sword is Appropriately weird and right.
Scott: he moves in a way that is appropriate for him to move and he also floats around a lot.
Rym: Yeah,
Scott: you know, it's like ooh, they didn't just make him, you know do boring stuff and
Rym: I also like how it did they
Scott: do as he needs to be,
Rym: you know, how Dune has the that the moment of There's a conflict that would be boring in any other thing and then the characters just talk and then the situation is resolved.
Scott: He just talks to Alucard and is resolved.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: It's like Alucard's like.
Rym: I'm not Dracula.
Scott: I'm Alucard.
Scott: Yeah, okay I'm the son of Dracula.
Scott: Oh and I want to kill him.
Scott: Are you know, I guess I'll believe you because You don't look like Dracula to me.
Scott: You're not killing me and biting me right now Which Dracula totally would.
Scott: he would just kill us right now.
Rym: So I don't he might not.
Rym: No, it depends we did.
Rym: I don't think we've personally pissed Dracula off.
Scott: I'm pretty sure if someone went to visit Dracula at that time when he was pissed.
Rym: You don't visit Dracula right after the church murdered his wife.
Rym: You can't let him be.
Scott: They're gonna visit him.
Scott: they're just gonna visit him with like whips and crosses and holy.
Scott: I like how all.
Scott: that's another thing.
Scott: they usually When you have something based on a video game you sort of shoehorn the game mechanics into it In an awkward and kind of Blair way like a whip is was probably the lowest.
Scott: I'm having a whip as his weapon.
Scott: Okay, right, but it's not like he didn't whip a wall and have a meat come out But like which he's not.
Rym: ops that was guarding Sifa cuz that have that's in the game, right?
Scott: That's perfectly fine.
Scott: But the example was actually the holy waters in the game.
Scott: It's not like.
Scott: it's not like it would have been lame if he Hit a candle with his whip by accident and found a holy water behind it in a vial and then threw it.
Rym: Find some wall meat right.
Scott: that Super lame corny hackin eatin bad instead.
Scott: what they did?
Scott: He's like.
Scott: there was a point at which he was like you Priest man.
Scott: go get water from the well and bless it and bring it back and then he tossed it on something.
Scott: It's like I don't seen where he's worked in the holy water from the game to make it still, Castlevania But not in a way that's corny and video gamey in a way that just makes sense.
Scott: You're if you never played Castlevania, you wouldn't think anything of it wouldn't be awkward Hadn't played Castlevania?
Scott: and a dude hits a candle with his whip and holy water comes out.
Scott: You're just like.
Scott: what the fuck is this shit?
Rym: But it also draws from the fact that like in the in the story itself or a guy finds a meat in a wall of A house.
Rym: the Belmont family knows things.
Rym: their primary power is their knowledge and their bloodline which hasn't really been gotten into yet.
Rym: Yeah, I don't know if it'll get into that.
Rym: We'll see.
Scott: Castlevania bloodlines.
Rym: See you get some Simon Belmont.
Scott: Oh, yeah the best one.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, Simon might be the most powerful Belmont.
Rym: until the new era I was reading I was really is Richter stronger.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: I don't know any.
Scott: I don't know enough about Castlevania lore.
Scott: I just played Castlevania games.
Scott: I haven't played all of them, but like I don't know the lore because I don't pay attention to that I just kill Dracula every time and explore his castle.
Scott: I know the horn it for as evil as drag.
Scott: I know the three.
Rym: I played as a kid when I was obsessed with this stuff, which is Played on the DS.
Scott: I don't know the lore of and I played him.
Scott: Well those I Was I know nothing about are like the GBA ones which I tried to play and couldn't and just because of technology reasons couldn't Get.
Rym: I am confident.
Rym: You will not beat Castlevania 3.
Rym: I never beat it in my whole life.
Rym: Really we Gonna be alright Zelda too hard.
Rym: I can do it whenever the weather's bad like in the next several like whenever we feel it.
Rym: Let's both live stream ourselves playing Castlevania 3 and idly and just see who like if either one of us beats it Because as a kid I never beat it.
Scott: I mean I'll use.
Scott: you know if I could use save states and cheat if I have to.
Rym: I won't use save states.
Rym: That's too much cheating.
Scott: The thing is when you die you go back to beginning, right?
Rym: Uh It's a hard game.
Rym: It's a real hard game.
Scott: It can't be that it's.
Scott: it's beatable.
Rym: It is I would say it's like five times harder than Castlevania 1.
Scott: I'll watch a speedrun and copy it.
Rym: Oh, yeah, I just watched a speedrun of it and Jesus The Japanese version I think I can be.
Scott: I can beat the Super Nintendo one.
Rym: I think the Super Nintendo one because he can dangle dangly.
Scott: My favorite move whip dangle.
Rym: I like the Super Nintendo one.
Rym: I feel like as many three is a way way harder Hmm.
Rym: I I usually tried to get grant cuz.
Rym: I did better as grant I think but Grant will see you probably in the second season.
Rym: Uh say if you enjoy Ultra violence like vampire hunter if you like 90s violent animes if you like vampires.
Scott: if you like Castlevania Then you have and you haven't.
Scott: I wouldn't pay for Netflix just for this.
Scott: I would pay for Netflix for this and little which academia TV that I haven't watched yet.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, definitely but um, I Wouldn't buy Netflix just for this.
Scott: but if you have a Netflix and this is probably worth your 80 minutes of your life You know, yeah
Rym: and I why you're
Scott: eating dinner or something
Rym: and it's go we literally watch it while we were eating dinner and I Will because they already got they already renewed they're gonna do.
Rym: it's three parts.
Scott: So three episode parts at the end of the fourth episode you're it's not.
Scott: the end is definitely like oh, okay There's a lot more to do.
Scott: It's almost like the first four episodes.
Scott: is really the intro?
Scott: Oh, yeah, it doesn't even get into the meat of anything.
Scott: You don't even go to Dracula's castle, which is the most disappointing part because that's it's Castlevania.
Scott: It's not Dracula Vanya.
Scott: Yeah, it's like I want to see castle action.
Scott: I care about the castle more than care about any of the characters.
Rym: I really I really want to see a la card bust out though because he had the best dialogue.
Scott: I think yeah I want to see them like go into like different rooms of the castle and fight all crazy different shit like a room with floating.
Scott: But that's it.
Scott: If it keeps up at this room with like some you know, all the different crazy bosses within the castle There are only eight more to see the mess with the Frankenstein monster.
Rym: So eight episodes at this pace should be definitely be worth watching.
Scott: I would.
Scott: if I were them what I would do is I'd have them get to the castle in one episode and then the remaining Episode should be monster of the week within the castle.
Scott: and then the final episode Dracula.
Rym: now They hinted.
Rym: it appears that the first one they tried to just be like set up does the exact story of Castlevania 3 But they didn't commit to ending the way Castlevania 3 ends.
Scott: Well, I mean Castlevania 3 ends.
Scott: Congratulations.
Scott: You were the winner.
Rym: you killed Dracula.
Scott: Good job.
Rym: So maybe they will manage.
Rym: maybe Dracula, but it'll actually end.
Scott: I'm pretty sure it'll end in such a way that gives you a nice Closing and leaves it open to there where they can make another series Either based on another one of the games or directly continuing from this and making up some new stuff.
Rym: I would like to see them because I like this enough to where.
Rym: as long as the next eight episodes are as good as this It'd be cool if they just started doing short vignette series like that from different eras.
Scott: Do with Castlevania because you don't.
Scott: Dracula's castle only appears once every whenever.
Scott: yeah, so there isn't like.
Scott: you don't have to follow Continuity.
Scott: you have to make the continuity be like the continuity.
Rym: You must have moto style continuity.
Scott: There's so little connection between the different ones because there's so much time between them.
Scott: It's like alright.
Scott: well, it's a new person named Belmont and the only people that are still alive are like a la carte and Dracula and Dracula's castle appeared.
Scott: you have to kill him.
Scott: There's.
Scott: everything else is brand new every time and the castle changes every time.
Scott: Yeah, it's like alrighty, then I guess you don't need to.
Scott: and it's like, you know, the vampire people are so old They don't remember.
Scott: they don't have to bring up anything that happened in like a previous one.
Scott: It doesn't even matter.
Rym: I feel like Simon's quest could actually turn into a really good one.
Scott: Well, I think the problem with a lot of the first one and Simon's quest is that there's not a lot of characters.
Scott: It's pretty much a Simon on a lonely man quest and really hard to turn the lonely person quest Into any sort of TV or movie.
Rym: this one Castlevania 3 specifically has the team up.
Rym: Yeah, because we know there's gonna be one more person on the team when they find grant.
Scott: That's why it's hard to make like a Metroid movie because it's like, you know, and you make a movie like alien.
Scott: You need to have all these people around Ripley to die.
Scott: She doesn't just start out alone.
Rym: Yep, Chris Castlevania 2 at least he goes town to town.
Rym: It could be like every town has its problem.
Scott: Yes, you can do that.
Scott: Yeah, but he's gonna be you pick up friends.
Scott: Can we leave up stuff?
Rym: Yeah, but you could set it up to where he picks up friends and none of them make it to the next town.
Rym: like hell.
Rym: When he comes out of the north everyone everywhere he goes he picks people up in town and he's the only survivor at the next town.
Rym: That's how I'd do it.
Scott: Not bad.
Rym: But yeah, you know terrible nights curse having.
Rym: But no this thing like it's really simple.
Rym: It's really short.
Rym: It's well done.
Rym: I enjoyed the hell out of it.
Rym: I think my mom would actually really like it.
Scott: My mom she I guess she didn't tell me turn it off.
Rym: Who suggested that I watch vampire hunter D when I was a kid, my mom loves vampires more than you know.
Scott: Yeah, we do.
Scott: I only casually like enjoy a vampire because you know, I'm a nerd.
Scott: I like a vampire.
Scott: My mom loves a vampire shit.
Rym: She like and rice book reading, you know I read interview with the vampire and that's the only one that I read.
Scott: I didn't even read that one.
Rym: It was pretty good as a book.
Rym: The movie was not great.
Rym: The book is pretty good.
Scott: I tried to read the actual problem.
Scott: I tried to read the actual Dracula once and I only got like a few chapters in.
Scott: yeah And then I read something else and then I forgot that I was reading Dracula.
Rym: But I mean this is what I like as a kid.
Rym: if you'd shown this to me when I was in fourth grade I want to love the shit instead of vampire hunter D. Yeah, I would have been so obsessed with this you would.
Rym: I would have dressed up as Trevor Belmont in Halloween Like I would have gone.
Rym: this would have been.
Scott: the senator is definitely a younger Scott who fucking loved the shit out of like say Ninja scroll.
Scott: Yeah, who now is a sort of like man and just girl.
Rym: but vampire hunter D I still really enjoy even though come vampire hunter D unlike this Doesn't actually have a conflict because vampire hunter D is the story of oh, no, there's a problem.
Rym: How will D surmount it?
Rym: D wins because he's more powerful.
Rym: Oh, no, they trap D. What will he do?
Rym: Oh D is actually more powerful than you thought.
Rym: Oh, no, here comes Dracula himself.
Rym: Oh D is actually more powerful than Dracula the end.
Rym: I feel like there'll be actual conflict in this.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and make comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Rym: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette and Thomas on my state e.com.
Rym: William Isen rose Jeremy minor.
Rym: Life and death and love and birth and peace and war on the planet earth.
Rym: a genuine bonafide.
Rym: electrified six-car monorail Nicholas brand out captain Chinguac asi Rebecca Dunn the terrible secret or space for two one creations.
Rym: That's because there we're fighting each other Shervin von Horl rare Laval James David White Rochelle, Monta, Nona Superboy I paid five bucks to make room say pickle sailor Vista Matthew Smith, Don She liked Kajar Tovish and Jojo Joestar Shawn Yeager Sam Cordery Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin Drew open Lander Brian Sidroni Finn Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel Redman Sean Klein Chris Reimer And Thomas Hahn.
Rym: yeah, I Really like Castlevania, and I hope it does well.
Rym: Like I said you tennis stuff is coming.
Rym: We were getting our pipeline going again now that we're Shifting some of our convention responsibilities shall we say.
Rym: but anyway now I leave you with.