Rym: It's Monday November 13th 2017.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I am Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We're talking about the IME Vulnerability that you probably don't know about.
Rym: that definitely affects your PC.
Scott: Can we just talk about IME in general?
Scott: Yeah, probably Let's do this.
Rym: I guess the problem is it's kind of a complex Thing to talk about because a lot of people don't even know it exists.
Scott: I was just talking about what it is and not worry too much about this specific.
Rym: Well, I guess we'll talk about what it is and why.
Rym: it's why you should know what it is.
Scott: Let's go on to the other parts of the show first.
Scott: All right, so main bit does not come first.
Rym: So I ran.
Rym: Emily and I. we ran a race yesterday But it wasn't our usual like 5k running races that we run with the normal like NYC runner type thing.
Rym: Longer shorter.
Rym: I was the same 5k cuz that's the like.
Rym: that's the default race for most people.
Rym: But we ran it.
Rym: it was like a Rangers thing, oh you actually did that thing.
Scott: Yeah Oh, I didn't realize it was yesterday because they kept advertising it so much during every game.
Scott: And I think I said one time like oh, I guess you could do that.
Rym: Yeah, and we told you actually did it All right, we can?
Scott: I kept saying like are you faster than lunguist?
Rym: So a few of booze booze Nevis actually came.
Rym: boo Nevis Yeah, and a whole bunch of retired Rangers like yeah famous ones the people who are playing did not come.
Scott: Yeah, I get they could have used some exercise.
Scott: then I'm gonna play until Wednesday.
Scott: Why don't they show up?
Rym: cuz they're asking boo about VCs teeth?
Rym: They gone Do forgot one of them.
Rym: they found one in his live.
Rym: Yep Like he spat and only one came out and they're like, where's the other one?
Rym: and it was in anyway, that's all gross.
Rym: but yeah, so we ran the race.
Rym: it was actually super fun and uh When the Rangers are involved as opposed to just like the running clubs There's a lot more hullabaloo around it because there's a lot more money involved Say but it was actually a pretty good race and I came in 15th overall.
Rym: Okay out of like a thousand people actually who was in first place?
Scott: boo Nevis.
Rym: Yeah None of the Rangers people were in like anywhere near the front runners.
Rym: They all started at the front.
Scott: But I mean, you know boo Nevis is like, you know, he doesn't only play in the AHL He's on the New York Rangers a professional athlete getting paid plenty of money.
Scott: How come he's not faster than you?
Rym: I don't know if he actually ran you.
Rym: Okay, but a bunch of other people ran and they did not finish at the top.
Rym: Well, they're old So I ran.
Rym: my time was like 21 13, which is pretty good for someone my age.
Rym: What's fascinating to me?
Rym: Is that I was I think 15th overall.
Rym: I was 14th overall in Men because the woman like the fastest woman actually was faster than me.
Rym: She got a really good time.
Scott: I saw she's an athlete of some game.
Rym: She looked at.
Rym: she finished like right ahead of me and She ran at a steady pace like the entire time and I could not catch up to her despite.
Rym: She's probably
Scott: looking at you like this woman passed me
Rym: but they posted video and I can see I actually like sprinted and passed a whole bunch of people right at the end, but I was like eighth in my age group and All the people who ran faster than me ran way faster than me in my age group meaning I could do better.
Rym: It's not just old man Rym.
Scott: It's Rym needs to train harder Or you're not a professional athlete and they are.
Rym: uh, no I think they all.
Rym: it's kind of like, you know Those people we know who biking is their primary hobby as opposed to one of many hobbies Like.
Rym: they only have one hobby and it's biking.
Scott: Listen DNA only gets you so far.
Scott: You might not be able to be any fast.
Rym: I'm pretty happy that I can run like 14 15th overall in a moderately big race.
Scott: How many people are in the race?
Rym: like eight or nine hundred thousand?
Scott: Mmm, did they charge you money to be in the race for their charity or what?
Rym: Yeah, but all the money went to charity.
Rym: So it was.
Rym: it was garden of dreams.
Rym: Yeah, it's like health care thing.
Rym: They split it 50/50.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Garden of dreams actually does good stuff.
Scott: It's okay.
Scott: Yeah, you could do worse.
Scott: You could also do better.
Rym: you could do a lot worse than garden of dreams.
Scott: Yeah Better - you could do a lot better.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So yeah got some tech news.
Scott: Yeah, so, you know, I don't know about anyone else right but for many years now, you know I'm pretty.
Scott: you know, I know a lot of people out there are like full Google full Amazon full Apple full Microsoft, right?
Scott: Whatever.
Scott: I sort of spread my bones out a lot.
Rym: You do I am full Google though I am like a hundred percent double down on Google Google some Apple some Amazon some Microsoft.
Scott: I use a little bit everything.
Scott: Oh Whoever the best one is.
Rym: so I did split because I was using Amazon's cloud storage like not that not the server-side stuff But I was using the Amazon like Backup like cloud.
Rym: like these are facing cloud backup.
Rym: I'm gonna stop using it because they ruined it and now it is too expensive for what I do.
Scott: Anyway, so But for many years, you know as a result of using things like Google inbox and such right?
Scott: I've used the Chrome browser primarily Yeah But why?
Rym: because I the reasons why I used to use I used to you'd be pretty hardcore Firefox and the reasons I switched to Chrome Mostly centered around the fact that I am so Google and Google works just better in Chrome.
Scott: Well, cuz I mean I was using Firefox when it was Phoenix.
Scott: Yeah, right when the style of the time You know, I'm a belt right and the reason I switched to Chrome in those days is simply that it was just faster, right?
Scott: It was a time period where Firefox, you know got.
Scott: originally Mozilla was this one program that had web browsing email Composer and those groups all in one app and it was slow as balls.
Scott: they made Firefox which is just the web browsing part of Mozilla and then they removed all the crap from it.
Rym: and a lot of people a lot of Neck beards fears were that if you took all that nonsense out of a mainstream browser No one would do any of that nonsense anymore.
Rym: They were kind of right.
Scott: Well, I mean for composer to make web pages not necessary.
Rym: Yeah, right and BBS is like, I'm sorry I know you but that tech is dead.
Scott: It was dead.
Scott: Didn't use it when I had it.
Scott: message boards were dead and then Thunderbird.
Scott: people stop using that.
Scott: cuz never uses webmail or something Right.
Rym: Yeah, I'm amazed when I run into someone who has a heart an email client.
Scott: That's like using pop except for except for Outlook and Exchange.
Scott: Yeah, you know, anyone has an email client.
Rym: Yep Like using Outlook like.
Rym: that's a marginal use case at best anyway.
Scott: So for many years, it's like I'm my computer at work.
Scott: For example, I have Chrome for my normal personal stuff And then I'll do my work in Firefox just to have a separate browser.
Rym: I know the same thing at work.
Scott: I know that you can actually open Chrome and have like two different chromes that have two different profiles But in practice that the user interface of that didn't work so well.
Scott: I'm like I would click on links and they'd open up in the wrong Chrome.
Scott: Yeah, because Chrome is your default browser But it doesn't know that.
Scott: like aha when I click on a link in an email and outlook I want it to open in these in the chrome with this profile when I click on a link.
Rym: Also a big part of that was in my previous job.
Rym: I was basically the social media like marketing manager so I'd be tweeting and like doing social media stuff on behalf of the company and I wanted an Extra layer of Rym.
Rym: It's Firefox.
Rym: Don't tweet that like skeleton shit from that account.
Scott: Yeah, anyway, so I just use Firefox for work and plus, you know at work, you know I don't want to use the ad block because we have ads on our site at work that I gotta see.
Scott: Yeah But I don't want to browse anything at all without an ad block ever.
Scott: So I only use it to visit our own sites.
Rym: also be wary because I add blockers.
Rym: depending on how you do it have Access to data because they're an application that's actually inspecting content.
Rym: So it ad blockers in a way will sidestep SSL TLS.
Rym: So instead, okay, they can they see the content.
Rym: be wary of that I digress but if you're doing stuff for work, like you work at a real company Don't just run ad block without knowing what it's doing.
Rym: if you're accessing corporate stuff with it Oh, yeah, just saying but I mean corporate stuff.
Scott: You don't need to block ads on exactly.
Rym: so that's why again, I use Firefox for work stuff and I use Chrome for like right life, but What's happening right now is Firefox finally, right?
Scott: They've done this many times where they're like, oh we got a new update.
Scott: It's actually faster and better.
Scott: I got new update.
Scott: It's actually faster and better but no for reals this time like not even joking.
Scott: actually for reals Not boy who cried wolf.
Scott: There is a version of Firefox.
Scott: It was it was it's set in stone.
Scott: you can get it right now as of this podcast on Monday night, but it's called what quantum it officially releases tomorrow.
Scott: It's Firefox 57.
Scott: I tried it out.
Scott: It is Faster than Chrome no question.
Scott: I'm on two Windows computers.
Scott: that and a Mac and a Windows computer.
Rym: that I tried You is because quote the faster web browser in quotes in the modern era has meant as much to me as people who like Worry about the cast latency on their RAM.
Scott: No, no, no.
Scott: No, this is like Faster in terms of benchmarks.
Scott: I can't say what I can say.
Scott: Is that like without any sort of benchmark tool whatsoever?
Scott: You type URL into this site you push enter it appears you go to Safari or Chrome or whatever and there is a note You can.
Scott: there's the visual noticeable delay in rendering Right and also the responsiveness of the page while scrolling up and down moving about clicking to go to the next page, right?
Scott: It feels like you just got a new computer with a fresh install when you use this Firefox.
Scott: So at least that is my experience on two completely different computers.
Rym: So it does lose the Google Direct integration stuff that Chrome has which is a big part of how I use Chrome.
Scott: Yeah, you lose the Chrome sync big deal.
Scott: this Firefox sync It does the same thing.
Rym: part of it too is that I use the notifications but also I use a hardware token for my two-factor and That only works with Chrome right now.
Scott: Nothing.
Scott: I do only works with Chrome.
Scott: The only feature that I would lose by going to Firefox is that Chrome has a feature where you can be looking at a web page on Chrome on say your computer.
Scott: Open up Chrome on your mobile device and then be like show me my links that are currently open in tabs on my computer And then click on one to open it.
Rym: That is a good feature too that I imagine I will also lose if I go to this Firefox.
Scott: You didn't even know about the feature and you've never used it.
Rym: Actually, I've been poking around with remember how Windows Phone used to have features been around for years By the way, have a thing that integrates with Windows.
Rym: like you can say hey Windows There's my Windows Phone and do like a lot of that kind of stuff Because Windows Phone is dead.
Rym: You can just do that with Android now.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway, and it kinds kind of cool I've been playing with it anyway.
Scott: Yeah, there's nothing that I use like.
Scott: I even stopped using Chrome because Chrome on iOS is just worse than Safari.
Scott: So I just get even though I was losing that one feature that I used occasionally Safari on iOS just so much better.
Scott: I only have Chrome installed on iOS because for some reason Jackbox only works in Chrome on a not Safari.
Rym: So I got some stats from this article.
Rym: right now Chrome is 60% of desktop browser usage.
Rym: if you told Rym and Scott when we were in college that any non Microsoft browser would be that percentage I would not believe you because the world has changed a lot.
Scott: Well, no, I mean I. when Chrome came out and Firefox came out and was called Phoenix.
Scott: I started using it.
Scott: I know that that was the shit I don't.
Scott: I didn't know.
Scott: I did know - but I didn't know at the time if we'd get non nerds to use it.
Rym: But that was what I'd expect.
Rym: I thought that cool is definitely catching on big time.
Rym: I always thought that corporations would never let people use non Microsoft browser and then the revolution happened and pretty much most companies force you to use Chrome or Firefox.
Scott: In fact, there was a time is a funny story.
Scott: The RIT library had a little stage in it at one point I don't know if it's still there.
Scott: Oh And you could sign up to do talks there and I was like so I figured out how to sign up but I signed up.
Scott: I'm like, ah, I know I'll go in there and I'll do a presentation about Phoenix and get people to use it because people don't fucking know and they this is RIT.
Scott: They definitely want to know.
Scott: and yep, right.
Scott: and then so I sign up and I'm like, yeah I need a projector with a VGA cable so I can you know.
Scott: Demo this shit and a laptop because I didn't have one at the time.
Rym: Yeah You could check laptops out from the library, right?
Scott: So I show up and the projector is not there and I went to the library desk.
Scott: I'm like, where is it?
Scott: They're like, we don't know Mm-hmm, and then I looked around and there's all these people studying and it would be super awkward to suddenly do a presentation to people Studying.
Scott: I thought they would like set up chairs facing the stages Schedule.
Scott: so I just left and no one said anything.
Scott: I never heard.
Rym: I mean the only Alternative is to do what I did at that anime con long ago when one person showed up to my panel is just loudly start Doing the panel.
Scott: I mean, I I would have been fine doing that but I couldn't demo Phoenix without.
Scott: I Needed those necessary equipment.
Scott: I couldn't just do it by talking.
Rym: So the article was what's interesting.
Rym: the other statistic Let's see quote if you're already a Firefox user You should receive an automatic upgrade when it launches November 14th.
Rym: So tomorrow tomorrow Chances are you're not a user.
Rym: Yep, 13% of desktop users using Firefox.
Scott: Well, I hope just try it out if you know if you're one of those people who left Firefox or you know Maybe you're concerned, you know concerned about like privacy and stuff like that.
Scott: Listen, Firefox is no no skin in any games where Google Microsoft Yeah, Apple all do.
Scott: Apple is really good on privacy though You know, they're at Google's not trying to make Google's making money off eyeballs Mozilla's making money off nothing.
Scott: Yep, one thing though if you clean install Firefox Go to the settings and make sure you change your default search engine from Yahoo to Google.
Rym: Yeah You know though it's.
Rym: I'm just glad this is happening because Whenever one of anything starts to run away with the game.
Rym: It's always dangerous And I'm glad that there is competition again here.
Scott: Yes, I think I'm gonna switch away from you know, make Firefox my personal browser and then use Chrome for the work browser.
Rym: I'm gonna hold off again because I use hardware two-factor.
Rym: Oh, yeah, and I can't like I don't have to like.
Rym: I can use the Google off app.
Rym: I actually have two different ways to do two-factor But I prefer to use my hardware token and that does that.
Rym: don't think that'll work with the new Firefox anytime soon.
Rym: So in other news, this isn't purely tech But it's an interesting thing that you that you should bear in mind because we've talked about this a lot.
Rym: but Advertising, you know, we just mentioned adblock.
Rym: The biggest danger with the fact that we're all moving to these models like Netflix where people pay for ad free content.
Rym: Is that?
Rym: Advertisers are desperate to do anything to advertise to someone who they know has enough money to pay not to see ads We've talked about this before where it's like, aha the people are buying ads for and it's free content.
Scott: But that means the people watching don't have any fucking money.
Scott: You're paying to make ads go away.
Scott: Oh, those are people who have money.
Scott: We really want to show ads to them.
Scott: They have enough money to make ads go away.
Scott: That means they have money to spend on stuff.
Scott: if we advertise to them we can get some of that money.
Scott: Yep, and now this is when you're a company like Netflix.
Scott: It's like uh These advertisers will pay even more money for us to show these ads to the people who are paying to make the ads go Away, what do charge more money to the people who are paying to make ads go away show.
Scott: Yeah, that's why you know Hulu there is still like a few shows that like, you know I don't watch any of those garbage shows, but you still see ads even if you pay to make ads go away.
Rym: so the needle shifting again toward the advertisers because Amazon is apparently developing a Free ad Supported compliment to Prime streaming video.
Scott: Well, that's not.
Scott: that's not them paying to show ads They're not who are paying for prime.
Rym: They're not putting ads in the stuff You're already paying for though.
Rym: Apparently they have done that a few times.
Scott: No This is if you don't even have Amazon Prime you can watch Amazon Prime streaming video with ads on it for free.
Scott: That's all this is.
Scott: So apparently I didn't notice the opposite of what Hulu did Hulu's like.
Scott: Well, if you want to see any Hulu's now, you got to have an account and pay Amazon Prime's like.
Scott: oh well You know what?
Scott: Now you can watch Amazon Prime video, even if you don't have Amazon Prime.
Rym: So apparently Amazon has that.
Rym: I'm gonna quote this here Amazon put ads inside NFL games that people were seeing on Prime.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: So I have twitch prime which gets rid of all ads.
Scott: I was watching the rocket league world championships yesterday.
Rym: the rocket league people put their own ad in.
Scott: there were ads as part of the stream on Twitch.
Scott: that we're not.
Scott: they were not of twitch ads using.
Rym: so that's one important thing.
Rym: It was not allowed to fucking do that.
Scott: The event was sponsored by twitch.
Scott: yet I'm pretty sure that's against the twitch terms of sir.
Scott: Yeah, you're not allowed to do that on Google I know which doesn't get a cut of those ads, you know, they're.
Scott: they're sponsoring this event.
Scott: I wonder what was up with that, but I was pissed when I saw an ad that I could not get rid of.
Rym: Yep, and the danger here.
Rym: The reason I bring this up is that any time a Company starts to edge back into the free supported by ads model That is what is on the verge of really fucking up the games industry right now.
Rym: Regarding these free-to-play games and their loot boxes.
Scott: if that becomes that's a gambling issue not an ad issue.
Rym: No.
Rym: but if there is a model that is the shitty model and a company realizes that Way more people are willing to go the shitty way than the good way.
Rym: They'll if they'll edge that way.
Rym: So if Amazon decided that they can make more money by having only ad versions as opposed to paid versions They would do it.
Rym: all these companies would.
Rym: so right now Netflix seems to be the only hardline company and We'll see how this all goes.
Rym: It doesn't matter cuz yeah But anyway things of the day.
Rym: so I want to point out Scott came to me and he said and I quote My thing of the day is only a picture.
Rym: Yep now I have done similar things in the past and all I could say to Scott was imagine if the Situations are reversed.
Rym: and yeah, hi.
Rym: and you and I said these words to you.
Rym: What would your reaction be?
Scott: I would say Rym what kind of thing a day is just a picture?
Scott: your thing a day is probably crap.
Scott: My thing a day is gonna be way better.
Scott: Yeah, and here we have a case though Where the picture that is my thing of the day.
Scott: It's actually a tweet with a picture in it.
Rym: Yeah My thing of the day is this tweet.
Scott: Yeah, and I go Rym I gotta think of this just a tweet basically really just the picture in the tweet.
Scott: But I care I'll bet money that not only is it better than anything in the day that you'll come up with But it is also that you will admit it is better than anything in the day that you come up with.
Scott: This is so good But yeah, it's someone's Halloween costume from the nation of Japan.
Scott: They are cosplaying as Dad.
Rym: It's so usually there's the situation in cosplay where sometimes someone has a really clever idea and they execute it the minimum Possible way to make the joke and the opposite side is the amazing costume that's very well put together But it's a thing that I don't know about.
Rym: like it or it's not a joke Yeah, or it's like just it's a beautifully done character from a game.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: Mm-hmm great This is both well executed and high concept, this is a very high concept.
Scott: It gives me some inspiration for costumes of my own that I will not do Talk about doing and not actually do.
Rym: Chris typed death in the stream because that's what we're talking about And Google flagged it as possibly offensive and I had to manually approve the death threat the word death.
Rym: Yeah, I should report him for making death threats.
Rym: get him banned from Google.
Rym: I Should write.
Rym: So my thing today is just this music video that I stumbled upon called a float.
Scott: is it better than my thing a day?
Rym: I think it's equal but different.
Rym: Oh, look at this owls guys.
Rym: It's a good owl, right?
Scott: That's a good owl.
Rym: That's that is the kind of.
Scott: why is the owl also a lighter?
Rym: The owl is not only also a lighter but it's also a day like laser spewing death machine.
Rym: The owl basically saves the day in every situation.
Rym: This is music video.
Scott: I like cute owls though.
Rym: Yeah, this owl is cute.
Rym: He spins his head.
Rym: He pops up all the time and it is just this music video about space pirates and pulp sci-fi animated nonsense and the music video is just really good and the song is really good and I think you should just watch this.
Rym: That's all I got to say about it.
Rym: Anyway in the meta moment the book club book was the fifth season by NK jemisin and I have now read the entire trilogy.
Rym: So if that was fast, uh All I want to say is that I have posted some thoughts the the end of the thread in the book club in the in The GeekNights forum, which you should join because the GeekNights forum is pretty fucking baller.
Rym: But you just join it.
Rym: use a link to it on our website.
Rym: It's great, but we're talking about the book and
Scott: Our website is front row crew calm by the way Yeah
Rym: And community dot front row crew calm is our new forum which is pretty warm
Scott: dot front row crew calm is the old forum which Is locked in read-only mode for eternity and is slightly broken but still readable.
Rym: Yep, forever, but in the bottom of the thread about the fifth season We're starting to talk about the full trilogy a little bit edging into spoilers, but without spoiling it spoiling anything at all.
Rym: I will say that people who have I can see why some people were not satisfied With the second and third books in terms of what the mysteries actually were and what some of the answers were.
Rym: I am Satisfied.
Rym: I am really happy with knowing what the deal is with the Guardians knowing what the deal is with the evil earth.
Scott: Well, it's good to know that I'm gonna get know what the deal is.
Scott: It's not some secret of space that will never be revealed.
Rym: There are some things you don't learn the full deal, but it's totally fine.
Scott: This is not the cool things like snake people.
Rym: now seriously I like all the things you care about.
Rym: I guarantee our answer to your satisfaction and The direction those answers go are a little bit ghost in the shell mmm and a lot Evangelion.
Scott: well, those are two things.
Scott: I like yep.
Rym: I am so 100% happy with the way this trilogy ended.
Rym: I have nothing but positive things to say.
Rym: if you like the first book.
Rym: in the evening I spoke plug cookbook club.
Rym: You should just read the rest of the books.
Rym: They're great and I'm gonna pick the new book soon I'm gonna.
Rym: I got.
Rym: I'm really really tempted to pick that new translation of the Odyssey.
Scott: How long is?
Rym: uh, you know exactly how long the Odyssey is.
Rym: It's the Odyssey.
Rym: We've both ready.
Scott: What's that?
Scott: What's the new?
Scott: why is it?
Scott: The translated newly any different than an older translation.
Rym: When was the last time you read the Odyssey?
Scott: the pop-up book?
Rym: Okay, so I've been hankering to read the Odyssey again for like a decade now, and I just haven't okay home.
Rym: But there is apparently this new translation of the Odyssey.
Scott: Why is it better in?
Rym: it's better in the same way that or different.
Rym: the newer penguin Translation of the Count of Monte Cristo was better.
Rym: It's more colloquial and modern and it takes appropriate liberties with the translation of specific words and themes To make it a more modern flowing reading while maintaining everything that's good about the Odyssey.
Scott: two different ones if you choose that.
Scott: So we're not gonna be able to compare two different.
Rym: I am also not going to reread the old translations I have may have read.
Scott: I will compare it to the pop-up book though.
Rym: Yeah, God that pop-up book is so good.
Scott: I just saw it the other day cuz looking at my shelf.
Rym: I can't.
Rym: the Cyclops and the sphere that pops out is so good.
Rym: That is a choice.
Rym: pocket pop-up book.
Rym: So I'm leaning heavily toward picking this new translation of the Odyssey to learn about the journey of this complicated man.
Rym: But I could be swayed.
Rym: I got some other books that I'm thinking about.
Scott: it isn't a definite picker It's not a definite pick.
Rym: So I am soliciting comments.
Rym: do will you read the Odyssey if you have never read it?
Rym: read it before if I pick this?
Rym: Good modern translation because if you've never read the Odyssey What's wrong with you?
Rym: That's like required high school.
Rym: How do you not know about?
Scott: Cyclopses and sirens and yeah No all that cool shit.
Rym: and also the fact that Odysseus is kind of a shithead and kind of a jerk.
Scott: Listen people like jerks.
Rym: Yeah, but he is like.
Rym: he does good things, but he also does really shitty things.
Rym: He's kind of a shithead, and it's just most people who read it don't seem to get that out of it.
Rym: And I if you've not read it I want to find out if you think Odysseus is as much of a shithead as I think he is all about bro side.
Rym: Well yeah Poseidon is the biggest piece of shit, and I'll never say that out loud to his face cuz he'll fucking drown me Poseidon seriously like you're cool.
Rym: We're cool right like I'm just joking.
Scott: Okay, so actual metamoments.
Scott: this weekend is PAX unplugged.
Scott: it is a PAX that is exclusively tabletop.
Scott: We will be there doing a thing about Carcassonne.
Scott: You can read the schedule yourself.
Scott: Yep, if you're not already going it might be too late.
Scott: I don't know what Saturday is.
Scott: so it's in Pennsylvania in Philadelphia.
Scott: Don't need you want to go there except for packs.
Rym: Saturday's sold out the um the three.
Rym: oh there are still three-day badges.
Scott: interesting interesting anyway.
Rym: Other thing oh, and there's a thing I noticed.
Rym: there are kids specific badges for Sunday.
Scott: Are they free uh?
Rym: Yes Sunday only.
Rym: We're gonna talk about that on a Tuesday show cuz I didn't notice that.
Scott: I don't know whatever.
Scott: But yeah pegs up like the tabletop.
Scott: only packs is in Pennsylvania this weekend.
Scott: the first one ever will be there After that the beginning of next year.
Scott: the first two weeks are mag fest followed by packs out boom boom.
Scott: That's how it's gonna be we're gonna be at both.
Rym: We are definitely doing panels at mag fest because like they're in and it's mages and almost guaranteed packs out.
Scott: panel.
Rym: Yeah, we're probably doing panels at pecs out, but I never say guarantee.
Rym: Hey, cuz I do not have a contract tax.
Scott: East 2018 badges just went on sale.
Scott: I think Saturday is sold out.
Scott: It's a four-day con though you could go like Thursday Friday Sunday, maybe I don't know.
Rym: yeah And if you don't have oh yeah, only Saturday is sold out.
Rym: if you don't have a hotel You're probably super fucked because you're gonna have to find a host.
Scott: well.
Scott: You can get a hotel.
Scott: Just it will be far away.
Scott: Yeah, that sucks, or I think a lot of people just driving instead.
Scott: look at that.
Scott: It's like Thursday Friday Sunday.
Scott: You can buy these easily not even sold out.
Scott: Oh Saturday completely sold out.
Scott: Yeah, I guess a lot of people see PAX East as a one-day.
Scott: You know expo Hall experience, but if you are actually a packs person you can experience a whole lot of packs.
Scott: You know the real way.
Scott: and just you know buy a scalp Saturday badge from somebody yeah.
Scott: Or skip Saturday and enjoy Boston.
Scott: you still get three days of packs Which is as much packs as you would have gotten last year caveat, and you'll still see the beginning and the finale Saturday.
Scott: this is what are you missing?
Scott: Panels on Saturday.
Rym: you're missing the crowded as day in the expo halls.
Scott: what I hope our pattern panel is not Saturday But also well I hope it is gonna be the crowded as day X East is in April.
Rym: so the odds of it being a Ridiculous hottie and nightmare escape of bitter cold are slightly lower slightly slightly.
Rym: It's Boston, but it means you might be able to go enjoy Boston because last year You would not have gone out and enjoyed Boston cold.
Rym: You'd have hidden around a fire for the entire time.
Rym: So yeah, let's talk about this Intel thing.
Scott: okay a lot of ground to cover here Alright, so you got you got to explain so people can understand this right.
Scott: There's a thing that came into existence in the late 2000s.
Scott: the people sorted knew about in theory But Intel kept it a secret.
Rym: you see articles in like really deep nerd places saying hey There's this thing called IME.
Rym: Do you know about it?
Scott: mm-hmm, but basically nowadays?
Scott: In more recent times like the past you know a few months more beans keep getting spilled about it and the truth comes out.
Scott: Here's what it is the Intel management engine.
Scott: right and in theory right.
Scott: it has a good intentioned existence.
Scott: Right you have a computer.
Scott: It's got a CPU.
Scott: That's really complicated right.
Scott: and you got this operating system that nominally Manages the CPU and the scheduling of processes and everything else.
Scott: right.
Scott: so the operating system handles all the CPU biz and everything else Is talking you know through the operating system and whatnot right?
Scott: But there are some things That perhaps even the operating system shouldn't be trusted to manage right.
Scott: so for example power management.
Scott: Right operating systems aren't really always that good at putting the computer to sleep for example Yeah, or waking it up when the from on LAN, or you know these sorts of things right?
Rym: It's like.
Rym: I'll give you an analogy.
Rym: This is not relevant to CPUs But in hard drives a solid-state disk right.
Rym: so when you put data on a solid-state disk You have this interface with the disk, but inside the disk it has its own hardware and software.
Rym: That is managing where the bits actually go.
Rym: Because one the OS and the users shouldn't don't need to know that you just need the data to be there and two if the OS was gonna manage that it might fuck it up because there's a lot of internal details that are complicated and The manufacturer of that hard disk knows better than you.
Scott: yep So this Intel management engine?
Scott: right.
Scott: the truth that we have learned about it is now this right.
Scott: so basically it is an operating system.
Scott: It's Minix right which is an OS.
Scott: it is and is now because we have discovered that it is What the Intel management engine is based on.
Scott: it is actually the most deployed?
Scott: operating system on earth.
Scott: Minix is basically a super Intel chip since like 2008 or 9 has it whether you're running Windows OS X Whatever.
Scott: you got that Intel management engine because everyone's using Intel CPUs.
Rym: now We're not gonna get too deep into the details of Minix because it has a story.
Scott: It's an open-source Unix operating system that can be really small yes But the way that the way to put it Minix Min.
Rym: It is not a light or stripped-down version of Linux.
Rym: You know its own thing.
Scott: it is a POSIX Unix II operating system That is just really tiny and if you wonder what POSIX is that is out of scope for this podcast anyway.
Scott: So How we're like?
Scott: well wait a minute.
Scott: I'm running Windows.
Scott: how does this other operating system?
Scott: How does this?
Scott: how does this work right?
Scott: how exactly does this function?
Scott: I'm trying to explain it to someone who doesn't know anything about how CPUs work.
Scott: So basically you know on your computer You could become root and you're allowed to do things that you're not allowed to do and you're not root.
Scott: you got to type in Your administrator password or whatever.
Rym: Use some sudo right.
Scott: push the yes button when Windows says hey you want to be administrator right now It's like yes right up CPUs actually have that same kind of thing right?
Scott: the x86 Architecture in particular has what are known as rings.
Scott: now.
Scott: originally back in the day There was just ring zero and like rings one two three.
Scott: I don't think anyone uses one and two anymore.
Scott: I think it's pretty much three zero.
Scott: And then they added all these negative ones like negative one negative two negative three right yep And for what it's worth as an IT major?
Rym: Well, I like I never really did assembly programming in RIT.
Rym: clearly not and yeah of course not.
Rym: that's not a requirement of IT.
Rym: But the things I know and learned about like It's CPU architecture are on a higher level than this and I've never cared about how memory is actually protected, right?
Scott: So you got basically almost.
Rym: I just assume like the OS does that it is protected.
Scott: I don't care how almost everything in a computer right is pretty much just writing on reading memory from locations Right.
Scott: so like oh you want to you know talk to the network card.
Scott: well the network card Probably has some memory location and when you you know move memory to that location then the CPU sends that data out.
Scott: You know instead of writing it.
Scott: so I say RAM You know it writes it to wherever the network card is and that's how you send on the lowest level.
Scott: Talk to other things in the computer is by reading and writing data from addresses, right?
Scott: It's how you talk to the RAM.
Scott: It's how you talk to anything right yeah.
Scott: So if you're running an assembly program and that assembly program is that ring three where the normal user programs run And you try to say yo CPU yeah see that memory location.
Scott: I want you to write these bits there.
Rym: No windows is there.
Scott: yeah, it's like Dude, that's like yeah, that's that's where the Linux kernel is a memory.
Scott: You're not allowed to write to that spot and the CPU itself Depending on what you're doing will stop you from reading or writing memory to different locations based on what ring Of security your assembly instructions have permission for now.
Rym: this what Scott just said is the very important distinction because an operating system Will protect things like if I try to mess with files or something that I'm not supposed to or install software.
Rym: The operating system has all these controls But if I installed a different operating system Then the controls might be different.
Rym: right not exist.
Scott: so your operating system And you know Linux kernel whatever you're running windows is running at ring zero Which is when you when you become root, that's you're running at ring zero.
Scott: right you have permission to access all the devices And do all the user stuff.
Scott: that even stuff users can't do.
Scott: yeah You know all everything is open to you.
Scott: basically as far as like a user of a CPU is concerned a human being But it rings negative one negative two negative three.
Scott: There's all sorts of stuff going on that the operating system can't mess with.
Scott: the computer is just built into the hardware.
Scott: Right the code that is running you know firmwares and whatnot to manage power and CPU stuff And whatever else.
Scott: Intel decides that the operating system shouldn't mess with it just happens right?
Scott: so this Minix operating system When you turn your computer on turns on puts its in has a little bit of RAM that only belongs to it.
Scott: So a piece of your RAM is like locked away.
Scott: if you tried to write code that was like read from that RAM.
Scott: Right If you tried to read data from that memory location And you're running your code as root on your normal operating system Right you would just get back a bunch of F's or you know an arrow.
Scott: who knows what would happen?
Rym: But it does actually.
Rym: is your RAM chips or just have its own embedded storage?
Scott: No, it just.
Scott: it just.
Scott: it's an operating system running on your computer, right?
Scott: It doesn't have any.
Scott: like the code of it is stored in the CPU Northbridge Southbridge.
Scott: No.
Scott: They don't know where it is.
Scott: actually It's.
Scott: I think it moved into the CPU itself like this code in there.
Scott: But it you know it it.
Scott: it's like a normal program.
Scott: It loads into memory when the computer starts in your RAM.
Scott: if you could use a super Microscope and look at your RAM while it's functioning and read the zeros and ones and look at the electrons You could read the program in your RAM after it loaded in there, right?
Scott: And then how does it run?
Scott: it sends assembly instructions to the CPU to be executed.
Scott: those assembly instructions?
Scott: Just run it.
Scott: ring negative three and can do whatever the fuck they want.
Rym: So if you were able take these bits in this part of memory I don't care if it's protected by anything and move them over here, right?
Scott: So under normal circumstances if someone roots your computer, right and they become root they can do.
Scott: they can run assembly instructions at ring zero Which would give them permission to basically you're already boned right there.
Scott: They're at turning on your webcam.
Scott: They're reading all your hardware files in your hard drive.
Scott: They're doing everything, right?
Scott: But if you can run assembly instructions on a computer at ring negative one negative two negative three Right, then not only can you do all those things obviously which much greater difficulty because you're gonna have to.
Scott: it's like redirect.
Scott: You're working on the assembly level trying to figure out like alright where in memory is this webcam?
Scott: Let me try to talk to it with assembly.
Rym: Like think of it like if you were trying to hack someone's hard drive by poking wires Into the side right with a voltimeter, but it listening out what's going on.
Scott: If you can do it It's worth doing and it's definitely within That the capabilities of a single human being let alone an organized group with money.
Scott: now It can be done easily especially since the IME has access to like the network card.
Scott: They could just upload your data download your data all kinds of stuff.
Scott: And here's the real problem.
Scott: Is that your code?
Scott: That's right.
Scott: You know, let's say you write an anti a virus checker.
Scott: that's running as what root?
Scott: You can't even see this shit happening.
Scott: You can put a root kit on someone's computer running at this low level.
Scott: that is undetectable Completely undetectable.
Scott: You wouldn't even know.
Scott: the only way to know that anything's happening Is that you somehow very closely examine the CPU and notice the hot.
Scott: the CPUs didn't execute my instructions Executed some other instructions for a second and then it went back to executing my instructions.
Rym: So think about that.
Rym: you could have a perfectly clean Windows OS.
Rym: that is literally not.
Scott: you can have a motherboard and a CPU That have been compromised.
Scott: Yep, and that physically it's like.
Scott: well, what am I gonna do?
Scott: burn them now?
Rym: these kinds of problems have been a problem in the enterprise world for a long time because When you're managing servers like real-world like practical examples, you often need out-of-band ways to control things.
Rym: so there's a lot of ways to like control a computer from the outside like from a special network or a special connection or a Special card you stick in that could do similar sorts of things and securing those as a big part of corporate stuff, but This is that built into every computer Automatically not
Scott: just built into a special server.
Scott: Imagine if you're able to compromise the management engine of say a server farm.
Scott: You would not simply spy on them.
Scott: you would simply take their computers and start mining coins because you could basically schedule all the CPU cycles for yourself and None for whatever software is actually running on those machines.
Scott: so suddenly all these computers are not doing that.
Scott: basically all appear to be easily be frozen because they just stop executing the Instructions that the operating system wants to execute and they're executing some other instructions and you can't even see what's happening.
Rym: You can even I guess be clever and have the OS be a minimally responsive and just make it think that it's got plenty of Space like spending plenty of capacity.
Scott: You could just you could you could draw you could send some fake screenshots to the Looks like something's happening.
Scott: Nothing's actually happening.
Rym: So this kind of problem like people have always talked about it like Scott right people have.
Rym: for a while people have been like hey Do you know this IME thing is here?
Rym: What if someone like whoo-doo-doo?
Scott: Yeah, it's always been this theoretical but known threat, but only like super hardcore.
Scott: crazy security nuts were like I'm getting an open-source computer with open-source hardware because I can't.
Scott: I can't stand the the threat of this Intel management engine the government.
Scott: They got my computer Yeah But you know They probably do like.
Rym: it was theoretical.
Rym: in the same way that if any of you are our age or young or older You might remember tempest vulnerabilities.
Rym: tempest was the idea and it is gone now.
Rym: But the idea was that with old monitors CRT's cathode ray tubes the things that are literally obsolete now You don't have to worry about this because they basically acted like big antennas.
Rym: There's a lot of reasons why theoretically if someone had a monitor you could get the same monitor And if you use the right kind of signals processing and other antennas you could pick up the electricity.
Rym: That was being like the waves the data that was being sent to the monitor.
Rym: the same way a radio could pick up sounds from the radio struck to the images and there were Real proof-of-concept implementations of these kinds of vulnerability.
Scott: right like imagine your neighbor has a monitor and some antennas and then suddenly that monitor is showing everything that your monitor is showing and The ultra nerds who were crazy about this.
Rym: if you ran like old PGP you could literally Display, you know, they had a reader built in that had like quote-unquote tempest secure display.
Rym: So you could read and it was basically notepad, but it was like gray with darker gray text to help limit the ability of a tempest attack, which was 99% of theoretical.
Rym: back then.
Rym: Only ultra nerds cared about this.
Rym: It was not a reasonable attack vector, right?
Rym: But it was there right.
Scott: so the Intel management engine is mostly a concern to people because a you know While it does some things to manage your computer in an honest feature adding way It's like you don't really need it.
Scott: If you just removed it You wouldn't even know that it was removed as long as your computer turned on.
Scott: you removed it in such a way that your computer Still turned on.
Scott: you would.
Scott: only you would only miss it if you were using like Motherboard power management features or something like.
Scott: you might not even know it's gone.
Scott: But meanwhile its existence creates this theoretical threat by which somebody could totally own your computer And you would never know the government could actually mess it that all the computers that have Intel chips everywhere.
Scott: It's totally shady and it's totally closed source mystery.
Scott: No one knows what the hell's in there except Intel people and they've kept it a secret for this long.
Rym: and the extra danger Is that because we know that it's minix.
Rym: it means that fairly arbitrary code can run on this thing.
Scott: Yeah, no longer do you have to write.
Scott: so, you know, it's like ah, it's minix.
Scott: We can just write some minix apps to run on this thing.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah anyway, so recently There was an actual for reals vulnerability discovered in this.
Scott: That's the most threatening one yet.
Scott: There have been a few in the past that were related.
Scott: I think there was a ring negative to one a couple years ago in 2015.
Scott: I watched a video about where they use this like memory remapping thing with like HCI or something the weirdest or I forget what it was, but it was a really weird thing.
Scott: but and it really wasn't a Like it could get you but it wasn't.
Scott: you wouldn't have to worry about it too much Right, but this is basically a USB thread.
Scott: So and it's totally legit use a thing called J tag, which I always forget what it stands for Joint test action group.
Scott: All right So J tag is basically this sort of universal connector protocol kind of thing for debugging hardware, right?
Scott: So let's say you're working on a circuit board with it with a CPU on it and you got to debug that CPU like one instruction at a time.
Scott: you plug in something to the J tag port and you plug that into your actual computer that you're writing code on and Now you can debug the instructions running on the CPU on this little tiny board, right?
Scott: That's the kind of thing you J tag for.
Scott: so just about every circuit board out there that has a CPU That's you know Made by a company has some sort of J tag connector for you for people to develop and debug things happening on the on the board.
Scott: so They discovered an Intel management engine vulnerability where you buy a USB device.
Rym: Right because I guess the management engine is access to USB which and this is a consequence of the fact that USB Universal serial bus that's what stands for I'm pretty sure.
Rym: Yes Is has become the universal bus?
Rym: So anything that would have been done in a proprietary or different way for this kind of like IO that isn't network IO has all become USB.
Scott: So now you can quite Realistically create some software put it on a USB stick Plug it into the USB port of any computer with an Intel chip that has the Intel management engine Which is effectively all of them or almost all of them.
Rym: and then what use J tag to get access to IME?
Scott: and now You that computer is your computer and no amount of reformatting the hard drive is gonna make a difference.
Rym: so what's even funnier is I saw this tweet and I think they already deleted it, but USB right you plug it in and you can unplug it.
Rym: Mm-hmm It's actually pretty trivial to make a USB physical device that once you plug it in a little hook comes up.
Rym: now You can't unplug it.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: There's no way to remove it sort of physically removing the actual you could.
Scott: I mean if someone did that's like on the front port on my computer.
Rym: It's disabled the front port.
Scott: Well, I could disable the front port or I could just open the computer and cut the wire that goes to the front port.
Scott: Plug the front port from the motherboard, but if you go into the back port, I'd have to like pry.
Scott: You know, I had to like use pliers or something and yank it out now.
Rym: Here's why now again I don't know the full details of this vulnerability Like how.
Rym: all we know is that it's a proof of concept.
Rym: that seems legit.
Scott: The point is if you put the hooks in for somebody who get pliers you it's the time It takes to own them is already passed.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: The hooks are mostly just funny.
Rym: Yes, but here is a like from my perspective the kind of Vulnerability that makes like the kind of practical use of this kind of vulnerability that makes it terrifying.
Rym: So I have this like jelly comb mouse right for my laptop.
Rym: It's this like cheapo wireless mouse as USB dongle.
Rym: in it you plug the USB dongle in it's just a wireless mouse.
Rym: That's how a lot of like mice and things work these days.
Rym: Because of this vulnerability if I were say China as a state actor and I had a company that I had compromised that was selling cheap USB Wireless mice the dongle I might pull the vulnerability in there that would trigger JTAG to take over IME And then use that solely for the purpose of compromising random number generation when people are generating a cryptographic key.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know why you're so racist against China But I see no fun.
Scott: Russia's Russian state actor the US government I mean judge a state actor right is like what's stopping like just logitech from delivering a bunch of shitty mice?
Scott: You've seen you know Lenovo.
Scott: We've seen Sony with their right, you know big real companies not just knockoff crap.
Scott: Oh stuff right.
Scott: real things that you would buy at Staples could theoretically be Compromised and have evil spywares in a US.
Scott: Buy a USB stick from like SanDisk right.
Scott: obviously none of these companies that I'm mentioning have had any of these things happen.
Scott: This is all theoretical right, but the most trustworthy things you can imagine buying and plugging into USB port Theoretically could have some sort of thing.
Scott: and then your computers are owned.
Rym: Yeah, and it's owned in a way that is literally impossible to detect right now.
Scott: yet, so you can't detect it.
Scott: But there have been many people recently Figuring out and getting really close or close enough To solutions to removing IME from your computer.
Scott: so you do something and now your computer doesn't have IME anymore Just has some blankness and your computer still boots.
Rym: now again to all the things we're talking about.
Rym: assume That Intel is not a malicious actor.
Rym: Yeah But if you are at the point where your legitimate threat vector Involves Intel itself being directly compromised either you're a paranoid nut job, or you are a super serious for real James Bond style spy and One of those is more likely than the other.
Rym: yes, you've got to trust someone.
Scott: Mm-hmm I mean you know you gotta also have a good chip at some point.
Rym: But that's kind of why I mentioned you know when I said China or Russia like they have a state actor.
Rym: I'm not worried about a company like Logitech being directly corporate malicious actors.
Scott: Not too much.
Rym: but I am worried about Say the US government going to a company like that and saying we are forcing you to do this and also you'll be arrested if You tell anyone I'm more worried about or like what is more confidence at the factory.
Scott: Oh, no, yeah, what deploys something is way more common.
Rym: this happens kind of often.
Rym: USB stick like company does a promotion and gets a USB device that gets outsourced to a company.
Rym: that company Itself is not corrupt.
Rym: They're just lazy and someone hacks that that manga factories network and just gets malware injected into.
Scott: Suppliers are for all the chips and that perfectly boring Logitech mouse You just bought who knows like something could be on there and the mice work just fine.
Scott: So they pass QA and then people plug them in don't even know anything's wrong.
Scott: And then next thing you know everyone about this mouse.
Scott: This is a computer is infected with like the most evil Magic and you wouldn't even know.
Scott: you could not know for years right this Intel management things.
Scott: It's like nine years and we're starting to figure stuff out here because hardware is so complex and the shit is so low-level That you know, it's real hard to figure shit out.
Rym: Yeah, there could already be stuff We didn't even know and I'm in the long run in terms of catching these sort of things earlier.
Rym: It's It's really hard to say because a lot of the neckbeards will argue that yeah back in the old days I got a full schematic of the like my processor when I bought a computer.
Rym: and it's like yeah because your computer was a 286 welcome to the modern computer had 10k breath.
Rym: Yeah, like you could make a physical Explains what's going on inside of that chip?
Scott: You could draw all the bits onto a piece of paper and keep track of them with a pencil.
Rym: So this is all just interesting.
Rym: That's really all we have to say right now.
Rym: Just be aware that all this exists.
Rym: and uh I don't know I'm curious if anyone out there is actually in the kind of situation where this is a legitimate threat that threat vector that you actually Care about directly, right?
Scott: I mean, you know It's just something to be aware of when you see all the talking going on and the only recommendation I can make to you is to always update your shit, right?
Scott: Don't do anything.
Scott: That's not trustworthy.
Rym: Don't plug in random USB devices that you find on the street, right?
Scott: And also we I have.
Scott: there's a thing you can buy online.
Scott: I have it's called a USB condom with and it's exactly what it sounds like.
Scott: and basically what if I put my exploit in?
Rym: there There's a tiny chip.
Rym: You don't know about.
Rym: did you take it apart and see?
Scott: no, okay You got to trust somebody.
Scott: Yeah so and what it is is basically it's USB on one side and USB on the other side.
Scott: and if you're gonna charge your Device because hey, guess what?
Scott: You're fuck.
Scott: I guess my iPhone doesn't have an Intel CPU, but a lot of fun phones.
Scott: You know their phones out there with Intel CPUs, but not just phones any device to the Intel CPU right now just computers.
Scott: You know you plug in you're gonna charge something with USB and you don't trust the USB port at the airport or where that Starbucks or wherever the hell you are, right you plug your USB cable into the condom and then the condom into the charging port and that basically blocks all data and now only Electricity is coming through to charge your device.
Scott: so now you can trust that you're only charging your device and you have not been compromised by That USB port that you decided to get a charge from at wherever you are and that is a good thing to have.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Rym: It's actually recorded at night And the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce Heidi new nickel Amanda duchette a shimmering ruby obelisk hanging in the sky my stady calm.
Rym: Jeremy minor a genuine bonafide electrified six car monorail Shawn Yeager Matthew Smith Nicholas Brando captain Chinguac asi Rebecca Dunn for to one creations.
Rym: No, I never ever wonder why we're here.
Rym: semper fi bitch Shervin von Horrell rare Laval James David White Rochelle, Montanona Superboy Rym says something funny here Sailor Vista dodge like chart office and Jojo Joestar show Sam Cordery Clinton Walton run from New Zealand.
Rym: Ryan Perrin drew Openlander Brian's Adroni Finn Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Han.
Rym: Still busy times, but this weekend is PAX Unplugged and within a month of that things once again calm down.
Rym: But PAX Unplugged is gonna be pretty great and I hope we see you there.
Rym: But now I leave you with Malo Oh Oh.