Rym: It's Thursday August 3rd 2017 I'm Rym I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights' night.
Rym: We're talking about a big bike ride.
Rym: We did upstate the Harlem Valley rail ride biking.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: So my work has been like you know officially we get free breakfast every other Thursday, but I guess Unofficially, but anyway we seem to get on the.
Scott: on the Thursdays where there's no breakfast We're getting free lunch, and the lunch is always from somewhere different.
Scott: so today the lunch was free barbecue.
Rym: Oh from where?
Scott: from crabby old Dallas barbecue.
Scott: And this place is not the worst But I mean it's one of those things where it's like They brought in this food, and if I was gonna go to a barbecue place I would never go there pretty much ever.
Scott: There's no reason to be to ever go to that place.
Rym: But I went there like once or twice in my life for zero dollars.
Scott: zero money.
Rym: for zero money.
Rym: I'll eat some barbecue chicken and cornbread right?
Scott: I got fried chicken.
Scott: I got rib.
Scott: I got cornbread.
Scott: I got bean.
Scott: I got shrimp.
Scott: you got beans and cornbread shrimp ease And then there were even salads that no one ate.
Scott: It's like there was so much food.
Scott: It was crazy.
Scott: It's like I had to use like three wipey things on my fingers.
Scott: For dessert I'm gonna eat vegetable And for breakfast tomorrow probably gonna eat nothing.
Rym: I basically skipped lunch.
Rym: just cuz I wasn't super hungry cuz I had a big dinner and I like haven't done enough exercise since the bike ride, but Because of that I was so hungry when I came home that I ate an entire ice cream sandwich like right before you arrived.
Scott: Great yeah, but uh it was interesting to see like what different people chose to eat from the barbecue.
Scott: Like a lot of people were taking the fried chicken covered in buffalo sauce which was not looking great Whereas I took the.
Scott: you know they were the messy kind of ribs.
Scott: Yeah But it's like you know.
Scott: some people were like sitting there with a plastic knife trying to like cut off one rib And I'm like no no no no no I just grabbed the whole.
Scott: They were like.
Scott: you know they were like set.
Scott: they were already pre-cut.
Scott: It's like you know sets of like four rib four rib four rib.
Rym: So you take four.
Rym: you just tear it apart with your hands and shove it into your maw.
Scott: I had to make.
Scott: I was very difficult at my desk trying to like not touch my keyboard.
Scott: Cuz how often you eat barbecue at a desk with keyboard and a mouse yep And then the whole office smelled like barbecue sauce.
Rym: The problem is having just read that person nothing.
Rym: all I can think about is like the grease on my fingers and getting everywhere.
Rym: Mmm, cuz that grease.
Rym: yeah bad news.
Scott: We'll see.
Scott: we'll see what we get for lunch two weeks from now.
Rym: Yeah yeah, my actually worry is turns cuz my company.
Rym: we moved offices to the fashion district and like 7th Avenue and And It's like we're a software company and literally everyone else in our fancy building is a fashion company with like Designers on max designing dresses and things get some dresses.
Rym: I'm getting a lot of weird looks from people like the kinds of conversations.
Rym: We have in the hallway and It's just.
Rym: it's interesting to be in that building.
Rym: I think we're literally the only non-fashion company in this gigantic.
Scott: Is that place?
Scott: then cuz plus.
Scott: I think if you're a fashion company in that building you get like tax breaks or so from what?
Rym: Being
Scott: in particular I don't
Rym: know anything I don't know for sure but I heard cuz I you know I overheard all the stuff about setting this office up that a lot of those incentives are going away or went
Scott: away
Rym: and cuz fashion like the incentives are not gonna be there like they used to be.
Rym: so there's big pressure for Companies that are willing to pay a lot more money to move on to 7th Avenue now.
Rym: But I don't know cuz I don't know a lot about real estate.
Scott: So yeah, but yeah, that's the thing.
Scott: people It's like.
Scott: why did all these businesses go in the same district?
Scott: Well, it's like.
Scott: sometimes it's just you know convenience like.
Scott: oh, there's the you know, I don't know a bar.
Scott: It's like well people hang out here at night So I'll put more bars here and then all the nighttime people hang out in this area.
Scott: No, and then that's how we get more business by being all in the same area, right?
Scott: We make a red light district or something.
Scott: Well, like look at you have a company that's like indoors like you're designing fashion or something.
Scott: Why would you be?
Scott: What's the point of being physically near someone who does the same thing, you know, I guess deliveries and you know Well, also remember that district.
Rym: if you go to the side streets off of 7th Avenue It's all that like you there's all those shops that are little or literally just like.
Rym: do you want to buy an entire?
Rym: Bolt of a very specific fabric.
Scott: Well, that's right.
Scott: Some places like a wholesale place will be like, aha I'll open up near these other guys like all you know, this way electronics manufacturers all in Shenzhen, right?
Scott: We're all near each other so that they can all get stuff from each other.
Scott: I'm putting together a circuit board.
Scott: I can go to the guy who makes Ram and I can go to the guy who make course even look like it in our Right here, there's two bouldering gyms like a few blocks from each other.
Rym: That makes no sense because they're just competing with each other except the thing is they're both completely full like over capacity.
Scott: I guess the demand is just too high.
Rym: you could probably build two more bouldering gyms here and they'd also be a capacity.
Scott: Anyway, the point is there was actually in the in the district the fashion district at least as well as many others.
Scott: They specifically give tax breaks and other, you know incentives to be there And that's what creates the district in the first like the diamond district and all these.
Scott: I don't know if the diamond district is that way but the fashion district there definitely were some kind of like, you know incentives Financially, like if you're making a fashion company and you you've put your office somewhere else.
Scott: Yeah, you're gonna be losing money.
Scott: The only thing that's driving up free money.
Scott: I'm not the most fashionable dresser, but I'm far from the Kilt and the toe shoe guy is not an and floppy old man hat is not the most fashionable.
Scott: Hawaiian shirt is Concede you don't set really.
Scott: I didn't know.
Scott: I thought that that was like peak like Like the height of all fashion.
Rym: I am NOT the bottom either because we have seen the bottoms.
Scott: Well your clothes are at least washed when they're when you leave the house, but also I don't dress that way like for work.
Rym: I'm usually wearing like a decent collared shirt like a Henley or something Like.
Rym: I dress up a little nicer.
Rym: usually though if I bike to work, I'm just in like biking gear because who cares?
Rym: but Pretty much everyone in this building who doesn't work for my company is like fashionable to the point that you're like well, like you.
Rym: look at him like wow and Everyone is like that in this building.
Rym: literally everyone dude walked in and this dude was wearing like stiletto heels and He had like these sort of tight jeans that cropped short and then he had a jacket like a sport coat and a Henley.
Rym: That's what he had on and that sounds crazy.
Rym: If I tried to wear that I look like a moron.
Rym: this dude looked tight.
Scott: Why don't you ask that dude like hey?
Scott: You're like the most fashionable person.
Rym: I've seen make me like you.
Scott: You tell me what to buy and he's gonna be like.
Scott: he's gonna be like.
Scott: this jacket is $1,000.
Scott: You're like Like oh and you're like, why are you wearing it?
Scott: It's like I don't pay.
Rym: yeah Because the $900 jacket looks like garbage.
Scott: He's like it's $1,000 for you.
Rym: So there's some really important news.
Rym: You remember the scary stories to tell in the dark books.
Rym: yes, the ones that had that.
Rym: pretty much everyone who was born between like 1978 and 1984 had these books as a kid and they're really like crappy ghost stories.
Rym: Like they're not good ghost stories They're not even scary.
Rym: Nope, but the art in these books was like Terrifying to kids.
Scott: Well, this is black and white really creepy draw.
Rym: But it had like this really like thin line like creepy Cthulhu.
Scott: Did you find info about the artist?
Rym: No, I know all about the artist Stephen Gamel.
Scott: Okay So the deal is.
Rym: the books got republished in the 2000s and there was an uproar Because they replaced that art because I thought it was too scary with some bullshit.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So the news is and this was posted today.
Rym: This is brand new news.
Rym: They're finally due to hate like crazy demand from basically my generation.
Rym: They're republishing these books in their original format with the original arts.
Scott: I just have the books.
Scott: like it's anyone.
Scott: I also have the book.
Scott: anyone wants them.
Scott: I know exactly where they are.
Scott: I will sell them to you for money.
Scott: Are they worth a lot?
Scott: I have the trilogy in the.
Rym: I think Literally everyone born between 1978 1984 has all those books.
Scott: There's three of them because we got them in the last.
Scott: they're gonna be released on the Kindle or something now.
Scott: But I feel I'm not gonna buy them or read them.
Scott: But I feel like I would gladly sell my old ones for money.
Rym: if I were ever going to make a horror video game I would hire this artist like him no matter what at any cost.
Rym: Cuz these books like the art is what made them great.
Rym: I was terrified.
Rym: the one in particular in the first one Harold that story the one I got a fear on the screen that probably scared me the most as a kid because I had a wrestling buddy and I also had a my buddy and I was afraid between this this and child play that they'd Wake up and kill me one day.
Rym: Mm-hmm and I was a for there's one page in the first one where you're like you're reading this story and you turn the page and On the inside page when it comes around there's rotted skull lady.
Rym: And I did and the problem was because I turned the page.
Rym: I was touching the skull lady when I turned the page and I remember as a kid.
Scott: I dropped a book.
Rym: wash your hands Yep, don't turn the page shriek.
Rym: wash your hands And then take the page and show to your brother because he's younger than you.
Rym: So This is a big deal and I'm glad it's a I feel like there's.
Scott: only everything old is cut is already been.
Scott: Is there anything left that hasn't been like re-released or remade from our generation yet?
Scott: Huh?
Rym: Care Bears didn't get a gritty reboot.
Rym: sure Teddy Ruxpin didn't come back.
Scott: I don't think pretty sure Dean ever went away.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I don't know much about Teddy Ruxpin anymore.
Rym: I definitely heard his name recently But yeah, so I'm pretty excited about this.
Scott: was it?
Scott: maybe it was the creator pet.
Scott: I know that was Paddington Bear's creator I think passed away.
Scott: Oh I don't know.
Scott: I don't really know the difference between the two.
Rym: They didn't make a new David the gnome.
Scott: I Don't know.
Scott: How do you know they didn't?
Rym: I assume they didn't.
Rym: I'm looking at right now.
Rym: So what's your news?
Scott: So there's an article on the Guardian that was actually quite fascinating.
Scott: It's written by a guy named.
Rym: Oh, they're rebooting it.
Rym: They're rebooting David the gnome Weinstein companies doing what's the year on it - this articles in 2015?
Rym: All right Spy kids reboot and David the gnome are rebooting.
Scott: Uh-huh All right.
Scott: Anyway, so this article is written by someone named John Ronson, which is the most porn name I've ever heard.
Scott: But anyway, it's an art because obviously people aren't making too much money with porn anymore because internet right is killed the mark.
Rym: If someone wants generic porn, there's probably literally an infinite variety.
Scott: for all intents and purposes This is article here about you know, the business of making bespoke porn where someone you call them up You tell them what porn you want to make.
Scott: they you know, they give you options of like actors and you know stuff.
Rym: So I'm pretty sure that's how two girls in one cup got made.
Scott: They try to make the porn as specific to your you know request as possible and send it to you Which is I guess, you know, if you're really into something weird go for it.
Scott: But this article is interesting not for the porn part, right?
Scott: which is actually pretty much they like don't even really talk about porn.
Scott: much in the article is because it's pretty much what you expect like.
Scott: Oh people have a fetish.
Scott: they call them up.
Scott: They get porn man.
Scott: All right, whatever right, but the weird stuff is This one guy for example was sending in books of stamp collections and
Rym: we must show you stamps man
Scott: and Was like I want you to make a video of like, you know Someone stamping on like stepping on these and like destroying this book of stamp collecting and they're like why it's like, you know There's nothing porny going on in the video.
Scott: Well, it's porny for someone sure But this basically it's just like a. you know a foot stepping on this collection of stamps and totally ruining it.
Scott: Oh, yeah Mess up those stamps and it goes into this thing.
Scott: finally find out like what the deal is.
Scott: it was one, dude Basically who apparently in Iceland I think it was there was a. that sounds about right.
Scott: It was a fad.
Scott: for a period of time where everyone is super into stamp collecting and I go a whole street was just like full of stamp collecting shops right and stuff and This person apparently is caught up in that fad much like beanie babies, right?
Scott: So there's like basically the guy who has a closet full of beanie babies.
Scott: This is the guy who has a big huge stamp collection is just like why why do I have this now?
Scott: So he sent all his different books of stamp collections to like different people to have them.
Scott: It was like more than one bespoke porn maker got this request And they already able to find the guy and question him.
Rym: I guess it's hard to tell the line between just a bespoke film and bespoke porn.
Scott: Well, I mean, I think if you're making bespoke porn, right?
Scott: You're basically, you know Just what was there between you and anyone else who's making bespoke film.
Scott: is that you're willing to make a film of anything true?
Scott: Someone who's making bespoke films only isn't willing to do certain things, right?
Scott: But if you're bespoke porn maker Well, you can make a video fucking anything.
Scott: It doesn't matter.
Scott: So if you don't care about like the artistic merit, and I'm sure they don't do like the worst job in the world But you're not gonna get an Oscar winner from them now, right and as long as it's gonna be short.
Scott: They're not making you something that's like hours long.
Scott: You know, I'm sure there's some kind of limit, right?
Scott: But if you want a bespoke film, it might be cheaper to call the bespoke porn people for it.
Scott: You know, even though it's non-poor and they'll be like, okay, that's easy.
Scott: I think it's like we're willing to like do all this other crazy shit like, you know, whatever.
Scott: So we'll definitely do your step on a book video or you know, whatever it is.
Scott: We don't care.
Rym: There's one guy who want us to buy a van and have my wife and a couple of other girls drive around in it for A week and smoke cigarettes in the van and pee in the van at the end of the week drive the van into the desert And blow it up and he sent them pictures of the van.
Rym: And I. the best part is his quest like their question to this person was and I quote why that particular van?
Scott: Hmm, he's got it.
Scott: Maybe that's a van from like that the guy had in college or something.
Scott: You know, it's just.
Scott: it's got to be the right van.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Let me drive my van into your heart.
Rym: So you didn't watch enough Steven Universe, you know, that's actually in like episode like two or three like that's at the beginning.
Scott: Well, I mean, I only saw the dead.
Scott: I know the dad has a van.
Scott: I only saw the episode like one.
Rym: well now Harlock is in the show.
Rym: Actual captain Harlow a character became Harlock in a spaceship with the crew dressed like Harlock having Harlock space battles.
Scott: You haven't even watched captain Harlock.
Rym: I've seen some of it, but I didn't watch the opener.
Scott: You haven't watched the show.
Scott: I think I even know what the plot is of the show captain.
Rym: Harlock is a Humble space pirate.
Rym: is he fight fights under his own flag?
Rym: Who's he fighting?
Scott: Like if I know it's you don't know shit.
Scott: No, what do you know?
Rym: He's a space pirate fighting under his own flag For Nostra Liber dad.
Rym: so in some other news This I guess it could be technology news but it's just sort of like a PSA because I've had to explain this to a lot of people professionally over the years, but Fonts are just as copyrighted as anything else.
Scott: They're super.
Scott: more so even and the people who make because make.
Scott: you know The people who make fonts a good fonts not easy to make if it's a quality font It takes a lot of effort to design and make.
Scott: and the people who make them, you know Since they put in so much effort they I mean regardless of what you think about intellectual property law as a concept Which we've talked about a trillion times.
Scott: The law is at least in countries where it's enforced like this one.
Scott: You can't just go using a font for whatever you want, right?
Scott: It's like you can make a word document and print it out at work and it's not a big deal.
Scott: but if you like make a website and you're like a Commercial business of the website and you use some font on your website You have to have the rights to do that.
Scott: you print out newspapers and sell them on the street.
Scott: If you're using a font in that newspaper, you better have the rights to use that font.
Scott: Otherwise it gets complicated.
Scott: if someone sees they're gonna come after you.
Scott: even if you make you know buy a font.
Rym: usually the licenses will have clauses that limit like can only be used for print runs of less than 10,000 per year or can only be used in these circumstances but not in video.
Scott: that's on broadcast TV like it actually has a lot of consequences for the performance of websites because for example, if you use something like Adobe typekit, which oh, yeah, it gives you access to a zillion fonts legally.
Scott: you got to pay for it.
Rym: It comes with they don't send you the file.
Scott: No, you have to basically, you know put this complicate to do it legally, right?
Scott: You could obviously to pirate the font but to do it legally the way they want you to is you include this code on Your website that like loads up the font and delivers it to the customer If assuming they don't have it on their computer and if it somehow doesn't work it uses a font from the person's computer.
Scott: But anyway, the point is all of this like rights checking stuff really slows down the website when you're like look just a load of font.
Rym: Oh, yeah, I changed the fuck as I get when I set up our.
Scott: my Good, we could have just had a world where people go like font equals.
Scott: You know HTTP colon blah blah blah blah dot TTF and they just download fonts.
Scott: but we can't have that world because People are so and you know people who make fonts or so.
Rym: and there's also the thing recently where the use of a font in a document proved that said document was forged because that font didn't exist in the year the document purported to be from.
Scott: It's like a mug.
Rym: There's like a big thing with the brema.
Scott: I said I just use the text file, bro Yeah, use the text file.
Scott: You wouldn't have a font.
Scott: Yeah,
Rym: but well But anyway, so this is a sort of article that talks about this and how there's some big money and big damages here And all you really need to know is that just because the font is in like an application that you have Doesn't mean you actually have the legal right to use that font pretty much anywhere.
Scott: Yeah You might like use the font like making a logo in Photoshop and it's like you have a zillion fonts in Photoshop.
Scott: You get one from typekit into Photoshop.
Scott: Yeah But you can do just by clicking and you have it now And then you make a logo with it and then you use that logo and now your logos Your famous trademark and then the person who made the
Rym: font sees
Scott: that in your logo
Rym: In your trademark like go lawyer
Scott: up.
Scott: now, they're coming for your monies.
Scott: I mean if you didn't pay for it properly in the beginning they coming for you.
Rym: Yeah Fonts are complicated and also you might wonder well I don't people just use those free fonts because there's a lot of fonts that are basically public domain suck mostly like
Scott: the high quality unique or You know perfect fonts that don't have like, you know these minor typographic issues.
Scott: You don't even think about it.
Rym: ones that are really really polished are like made by Apple or but the best fonts are the ones that you literally like.
Rym: they're so good that you look at a website or like you look at a thing and it just looks good and you can't really even articulate why and then you look at something else and the font is So similar, but it looks wrong and you're like.
Scott: you can't tell why but the typographic people can tell why.
Rym: yeah I can't tell why but I can tell look what looks good or bad because that expertise is what helps them make good fonts.
Rym: Yep, cuz I've actually I Scarily enough.
Rym: I've been doing a lot of like legit graphic design lately, which is weird But that's what I like.
Rym: I know my way the hell around in design and illustrator now more so than I want to.
Rym: so in some other news a bunch of articles were Running around about this lately, but it seems like this is legit.
Rym: Okay, a lot of people are younger than us Literally don't know that broadcast TV exists.
Scott: Why would they know they never watched it?
Rym: they never.
Rym: most people seem to think when when we switch from analog to digital most young people who basically noticed television who were like 10 15 years younger than us when they came of age, they just had cable probably and internet and Broadcast TV was gone.
Rym: and very few people except people who actually relied on broadcast television mostly in rural areas Bothered upgrading to modern digital antennas.
Scott: I think even people who do live in rural areas right in the years between like, you know 2017 they all got satellite dishes.
Scott: satellite just used to be a giant enormous thing.
Scott: We had a satellite only just just for HBO.
Scott: That's all we got the only thing affluent people could get and only if they were willing to put some giant ass dish out.
Scott: But you know what?
Scott: once there was DirecTV and Dish Network with the small dishes Everyone around the world who wasn't like in a very populous area that had You know cable all got dishes.
Scott: and if you go to places that are even populous highly dense The populated areas if they don't have the infrastructure to actually wire everyone up with cable.
Scott: Just everyone's got dishes.
Scott: You go you go like India.
Scott: It's like dishes everywhere.
Rym: It's actually crazy like when I was young even like the reason satellite receivers those big ones appeared.
Rym: was that in the old days?
Rym: Television shows even like proprietary like special stuff or premium stuff was broadcast to the local networks Unencrypted via satellite.
Rym: So if you just got a dish and pointed it into the sky You basically got the equivalent of free cable.
Rym: So people were buying dishes and like stealing TV.
Scott: Also, there weren't as many satellites up in the sky helping out with this.
Scott: Yeah, right It's been since then a lot of rockets put a lot more satellites up there to help Have satellite TV.
Rym: They only started encrypting this stuff because nerds were basically watching TV for free or seeing shows before they were even released.
Rym: like all sorts of nonsense was going on And cable.
Rym: like I remember when cable came to my neighborhood as a kid cable used to be a ridiculous luxury.
Scott: The point is TV with no commercial point is people younger than us, right?
Scott: So we're at least a few years younger than us did not?
Scott: we're not conscious.
Scott: at a time when Broadcast television was used right pretty much at all by anyone everyone had a cable or a dish or was the kind of person didn't have TV and Broadcast TV is still out there.
Scott: You know, it's still a thing.
Scott: It's.
Scott: it's I think in Japan.
Scott: It's still like a huge thing, too.
Rym: Yeah, it's in other countries even but the US had such a cable culture and US TV culture is pretty like like I've Doing that anime openers panel.
Rym: Like I learned a decent amount about like how Italian TV works as mother countries.
Rym: US TV culture is like really weird and not many other places are like the way US like stuff worked out.
Rym: No for a lot of reasons, but another come out of this story.
Rym: Is that half the articles about this are clearly like planted by marketing companies to push an agenda?
Rym: Because I like some of these quotes are just obviously so fake like it's kind of awesome.
Rym: It doesn't Helping them out by spreading their message because some of the articles are legit and just talking about the technology.
Rym: But basically what seems to be happening now is people are buying antennas who previously didn't know broadcast TV existed.
Scott: Is this really happening or someone just writing articles saying it's happening?
Rym: No, it's definitely happening.
Rym: to antenna sales have actually risen Mm-hmm for the first time like since ever.
Scott: it's interesting because you see things coming out like this.
Scott: I almost considered it the YouTube TV.
Scott: Yeah You pay a very small amount of money to YouTube every month and then they will just YouTube.
Scott: they will suddenly on YouTube.
Scott: is your local TV stations live and you could even like, you know roll back and DVRs to some extent.
Scott: I don't know exactly People are doing it.
Rym: It seems mostly to watch sports.
Rym: Yeah, that's what I was gonna do with it Which doesn't help me because I want to watch Rangers which would probably be blacked out anyway.
Scott: No, that wouldn't be on broadcast.
Scott: That would be on You know, yeah MSG Network and not but you can watch football Yeah, and then you know Fox CBS whatever.
Rym: but so yeah, basically if you didn't know There is TV that's digital that's just in the air and if you buy like a $10 antenna It'll just be on your TV.
Scott: assuming that you're close enough to it, you know broadcast thing You'll no matter where you are.
Scott: You're gonna get at least one station.
Scott: Yep, you know where I lived in Connecticut growing up.
Scott: we had because we were so close to New York, but also, Connecticut To CBS to Fox to NVC to every two of all the major station I had one better plus local stations that were you know syndicated and stuff.
Rym: I was in the in Michigan in the Midwest.
Rym: I got US channels Detroit.
Rym: I also got the suburban channels because the Detroit channels were like way powerful and I got all the Canadian channels from Windsor.
Scott: Oh, wouldn't Canadian channels be using like different technology though?
Scott: No, okay There's the same because I'm pretty sure if you take your channel, I remember Channel 9 TV to like, you know somewhere else.
Scott: It might not work not just NTSC pal, but you know other types of differences.
Rym: Well, let's not get into UHF and VHF and all that nonsense, right?
Scott: Which I know the UHF has been sold off.
Rym: It's all that stuff's gone.
Rym: We're now using it for I actually know a lot about it because this is how old we are.
Rym: We learned about this at RIT and my wife one of my first IT classes.
Rym: it was like literally like we learned like how the electrical signals work in like Ethernet and like exact like the details of like fiber encoding and broadcasting coding and radio encoding and all that nonsense and Literally everything I learned in that class.
Rym: literally everything is obsolete and basically not used anywhere anymore.
Rym: Mm-hmm, so I can tell you all about differential Manchester.
Rym: But that's not what modern Ethernet uses.
Scott: It's someone's job to like make sure this is broadcasting still works And it's like.
Scott: would they even know if it's soft working is even as if no one's watching it.
Scott: Yeah, how much energy are we using on broadcasting?
Scott: You know TV and radio over the actually no way less No one is listening to.
Scott: the old method radio towers is still really powerful.
Scott: Yeah, the multi kilowatt radio towers and what they don't even know.
Scott: if anyone's listening How do they know based on how many people call in when there's a contest?
Rym: but the other crazy thing was back then because Like the world was old and archaic they would always everything we saw.
Rym: they'd be like tonight at 7 o'clock 6 Central The Simpsons.
Rym: they had to take into account the fact that they covered multiple time zones with a broadcast In a way that does not matter.
Rym: in the modern era stuff usually just comes on at midnight For the next day on Netflix or whatever.
Rym: but anyway things.
Rym: So first I learned that you know what Harlock fights wine.
Rym: He is the destroyer of wine.
Rym: He drinks a lot of wine sure yeah, but anyway.
Rym: So I found this video kind of randomly and it was really fascinating.
Rym: you know old medieval looking buildings or like old germanic buildings Like the second floor is actually like wider than the first floor like you see that a lot in old towns sometimes I know you're like.
Scott: I've seen it.
Rym: And if they go higher like every higher floor is always bigger than the floor under it to the point that it's kind of ridiculous.
Scott: I've never seen one.
Scott: I'm sure that exists, but I can't.
Scott: I mean I've definitely know the thing where the where the it was like little sort of like.
Scott: you know triangular Struts and this.
Scott: like all this the second floor sticks out sort of like there's a balcony But the balcony is on the inside.
Scott: so but I never seen anything like continue going up like upside-down pyramid.
Rym: So why do you think that is like?
Rym: why do they build buildings that way?
Rym: What do you think?
Scott: They were bad at building buildings.
Rym: uh No, actually if they were bad at building buildings They wouldn't have done it that way.
Rym: so try again cuz I had an idea that I was super wrong about.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: What do I know about architecture?
Scott: nothing nothing.
Rym: it was because castles looked that way and it was the defensive thing.
Rym: and this video is Basically like no none of you know shit about our defending a little wooden house.
Scott: someone who said it on fire there It's done.
Scott: I always assume a defense that castles did it for a defensive reason and other buildings did it to look like castles Uh-huh, but I never thought about it to even come up with the reason.
Rym: I thought about it a little.
Rym: so this video goes into extreme detail on why medieval buildings are built that way.
Rym: And it's not for the reason.
Scott: I thought and it actually makes a lot of sense, and it's really interesting It makes a nice little tiny tiny place to hide if the rain is falling.
Scott: Oh, yeah, actually you haven't invented the awning yet.
Rym: It also means people in upper floors emptying the chamber pots will get them further away from the base of your house.
Scott: Is that the reason?
Rym: uh no?
Rym: There's two reasons.
Rym: one reason is structural.
Rym: the structure is actually better that way which seems crazy.
Rym: But then there's a bunch of diagrams explaining why?
Rym: Like that it's actually better to build a wooden house that way.
Scott: why don't we build houses that way anymore?
Rym: Because we use very different building techniques like the kinds of houses We build are not the kinds of houses They used to build anyway.
Rym: this is just.
Rym: this was like.
Rym: I was surprised at how interesting a video about this very specific and Minor detail of medieval architecture was but it ended up being really interesting.
Rym: It's like 20 minutes long.
Rym: There's a lot to say which is terrifying.
Scott: Alright, so we you know we're gonna talk about this in a minute We spent the weekend and like upstate New York biking or whatever.
Scott: so I was thinking about the upstate New York boonies areas.
Scott: But and in high school you would go with the youth group We would go to these conventions and the.
Scott: our conventions were held in the Paramount Hotel in Parksville New York, so I was like alright you pointed that out.
Scott: like any time We've been even within like 50 miles and you'll be like hey, right well by the time I was in college I think shortly after the last time I was there in the late 90s it burned down and that was the end of it.
Scott: But we drove past it a few times in the RIT days because it was on the way to wherever we were going.
Rym: every time You'd be like a ram.
Scott: You know we took the other road instead of 90.
Rym: I mean, you know what that is.
Scott: that's right.
Scott: It's like it's basically a lot like the hotel from the shining.
Scott: Yeah big and it's you know back in the day you got to remember way back like well You know my parents age Right.
Scott: the Jews from New York City in the summer would go up to the Catskills and spend their time basically their whole summer almost in these either bungalow colonies or Big giant luxury hotel places, and this is where you had like all the great comedians
Rym: You ever hear of the borscht
Scott: belt Borscht
Rym: belt comedy?
Scott: right all that stuff was in these kind of places right?
Scott: you know dirty dancing that movie Was in one of the hotels up there one of the fancier ones that had ice skating and shit, right?
Scott: but you know the Paramount was one that still existed in the late 90s before it burnt down and I Was like I was thinking about it again because we were you know we were upstate, New York even though We were way east of where this is.
Scott: yeah.
Scott: So I googled it, and I'm like.
Scott: I wonder if there's any new info.
Scott: so I went to Google Maps And I saw up.
Scott: no it's still the same satellite image and the street view car still hasn't been on that road.
Scott: I still can't see anything better But I can still see what's there which basically looks like a crazy Mashed up nonsense building with a rundown pool outside of it.
Scott: but I found this interview, but I guess the guy who owned it for maybe a few years ago like 2010s and This interview is really fascinating from somebody who spent time in that hotel.
Scott: I went to it like four or five times.
Scott: It was very interesting to read with.
Scott: this guy had to say about it, and it makes me think Maybe that fire was not no accident Insurance fraud in his way out of that hotel.
Rym: But the hotel was like a hundred years old at that point right like it was old.
Scott: It was like the most crazy Like we got lost every time we're in that hotel And we would like we try to walk like figure out our way around it.
Scott: It was like a Resident Evil situation only we couldn't remember.
Scott: We ended up in places that were like under construction Just like open to the air and really weird and then we entered like it.
Scott: you'd go down a hallway And you'd be like in a different building like it was.
Scott: so many additions added to it And they're all different.
Scott: and it's like all the doors were red and the carpet was different in this area And there's these ghost girls who are trying to murder you.
Scott: the banquet halls.
Scott: We ate luncheon.
Scott: We're just like enormous like the biggest friggin like hall you've ever seen like so like tables and chairs like it's Super-far.
Scott: you could have a wedding for like a thousand people in there.
Scott: probably It was insane how big this place was.
Scott: and then like you know we would go and hang this that we did most of our Stuff in this like downstairs like kind of area that had like a stage and a huge dance floor and a bar And an empty cigarette vending machine because that's how old the place was.
Scott: They still had those but most of the people staying there when we were there that weren't you know?
Scott: for an event like ours We're like hunters whereas back in the day like that was a happening place people were going there just to go there Which is crazy to me.
Rym: like think about how different the world is like.
Rym: would you go to a hotel?
Rym: Just like somewhere not that far from your house and just stay?
Scott: people do it today but they do it either on hotels that float or Hotels in tropical places.
Scott: Yeah, I'll do it in hotels that are like Nearby.
Rym: usually they do it like like the Gaylord is kind of like a modern.
Scott: People are going to do this kind of thing.
Scott: they'll go to a hotel, but they're not going to the hotel.
Scott: to go to the Hotel it's that there's attractions in the area right and the hotel is just a place they sleep.
Scott: We're now back in the day.
Scott: there weren't attractions right?
Scott: it was the hotel built Attractions so that you would come to it and that it would provide you everything in the one place.
Scott: It would be like you know people do have resorts in the tropics that hotel that.
Scott: what's.
Scott: also attractions in the same place Casino food what you know pool beach whatever.
Scott: This is the same idea only in the woods.
Scott: only the idea of it not being tropical has sort of become not popular.
Rym: Yeah So uh in the meta moment the book club book was Frank Herbert's dune And we read it a while ago, and we're done in the episodes up, and you can just listen to it.
Rym: So yeah, we're done.
Rym: We read dune.
Rym: It was what it was.
Rym: you can if you want to know our thoughts on it You can listen to this episode.
Scott: so the new book club book is the fifth season not winter spring summer or fall.
Scott: It's not another kind of season.
Scott: By NK jemisin, this is like the hottest you know fantasy sci-fi author right now.
Scott: So and this is like I guess the first book you're supposed to read from this author's.
Scott: that's what we're gonna.
Scott: Do yep other the metamoment stuff.
Scott: I've actually gotten a lot of people applying to the forums recently.
Rym: Oh welcome.
Scott: No, I accepted none of them because there's a when you fill out the form to join the forum There's like a fill a field.
Scott: that's like reason for joining and a lot of people write something like Discussion or one person wrote I want to make friends who play csgo and someone else wrote something else right.
Scott: and It's like some of these things are clearly not something a human would write or something a human ignored the field and just typed in Whatever or a human who would write.
Rym: that is not someone I want to talk to necessarily.
Scott: If you want to have your application to join the forum approved you must write something in there.
Scott: That proves to me Reading it with my eyeballs that you actually are like someone who knows that GeekNights is.
Scott: you could write something like you know?
Scott: For example some people have written.
Scott: I was in the old forum making an account on the new one and it's like that's clear right.
Scott: or some people have written been A listener for a long time.
Scott: It's like oh clearly.
Scott: You know what GeekNights is yeah But if you have an email address from Ukraine and it says you know want to talk to like-minded people.
Scott: That's not enough.
Scott: I'm gonna decline your registration.
Rym: Please try again, but you should join our forum because if you're listening to this podcast I guess there's something that you like here.
Rym: So you might as well meet other people who like the same thing.
Rym: and our forums actually pretty great.
Scott: And it has activity every day has the right amount of activity every day.
Scott: Yeah, there's a discussion thread for every episode So it's a good place to go To hang out with.
Scott: you know us and other people who are dumb enough to listen to us.
Rym: So the other thing is that you might know the prince of nothing series.
Rym: our Scott backer Just has been a thing with us for a long time.
Scott: since as long as GeekNights has existed This has been our fantasy series.
Scott: Yeah, that is not the greatest fantasy series But we are super obsessed with it because it is the most GeekNights.
Rym: Yeah, it's uh It fits us real well.
Rym: a lot of its aspects, and there's reasons.
Scott: not all of its aspects, but enough.
Rym: But we just finished the last book.
Rym: so or the latest book.
Scott: so Appendices.
Rym: I'm gonna.
Rym: I'm reading the appendices like all night tonight.
Scott: I got to work on.
Rym: I'm reading the whole thing cuz the appendices I love.
Scott: the one thing I love about these books is that well one appendices glossary one is apps But the other two have actual stuff.
Rym: But the fact that every book has like a glossary at the end and the same thing will have a definition In every book, but in every book that definition is expanded More and more based on things you've learned along the way.
Scott: What's great is if you go online and look at other fans of these books they notice particular things.
Scott: they notice that an unusual number of Moderately important figures in the world all died in this same year according to the glossary.
Rym: I noticed that in particular that can't be a coincidence.
Scott: what happened?
Scott: it happened in a dirt.
Scott: that year happens to fall between It's the year of the tusk in between two of the books when you know An area of time that we don't get a lot of information about.
Scott: yep, so what's up with that?
Rym: Well, I noticed too that there's a lot of people who died in the year that the book we just read takes place.
Scott: There's also Quite a few like errors that have been pointed out by people online like someone's eye color changes from book to book.
Scott: Yeah like that.
Rym: so You know Scratchy stuck sort of itchy struck the same rib twice and yet two distinct notes were sounded.
Rym: That kind of complaint.
Rym: There's an hours.
Rym: go back our AMA where he was answering a lot of questions too and for a couple of me was like most of All my questions.
Scott: He was like he wrote RAFO which means read and find out.
Scott: yep I'm just like we're at a heron spear.
Scott: I thought I was gonna have my heron spear in this book, and I didn't get it, and he's like read and find out.
Rym: yeah But that's good.
Rym: There's the three answers.
Rym: It gives her basically.
Rym: No you didn't read the book closely enough or No, that's a really clever thing you notice, but that's not intentional.
Rym: or read your book dude.
Rym: There's more book coming.
Scott: Don't die before you write this book.
Scott: How old are you?
Rym: Yeah?
Rym: I feel like he's doing okay?
Scott: We'll make it.
Rym: so uh yeah We did this bike ride, and it was pretty great, and I feel like well We have we'll get all our bike talk out in this show.
Scott: Yeah, the whole show on this.
Rym: so Scott convinced me to do this.
Scott: right.
Scott: so what happened was is you know my biking friend?
Scott: Told me last year hey I went in this bike ride Where you take the train upstate to somewhere in the boonies and then you camp on a field and then you wake up in Bike all day and you come back and there's awesome food And they support the ride and there's awesome rest stops and awesome scenery.
Scott: And then you come home on the train, and I'm like that sounds crazy fun.
Scott: I would like to do this yep.
Scott: So this year I was like oh, it's spring again.
Scott: that thing sounded so fun that I didn't forget about it.
Scott: I will ask oh hey, Katie.
Scott: What was that ride?
Scott: Oh, it's the Harlem Valley rail ride, okay?
Scott: So I go in and register for it.
Scott: once we decide I'm gonna do it right I'm not gonna do it alone, but once I figured people seem like it's gonna happen I just registered yep, and then I got a phone call that was like hey You're the first person to register it.
Rym: I'm like really I registered the Thursday before.
Scott: yeah apparently I'm real dumb for registering early even though it turned out great.
Scott: But most people register for these bike ride things that like close to the last second as possible because they want to check the weather Right which makes sense.
Rym: there was.
Scott: I like biking in the rain like I don't mind if it's regular Miles in driving rain, and I don't have to be anywhere, and it's not so slippery.
Scott: I'm gonna fall over and die or something right, but you know obviously I prefer it not to be raining.
Scott: Yeah, but apparently she you're showing me this other bike ride that was like nickel-and-diming everyone charging like extra money for rain Insurance and extra money for like extra stuff.
Scott: Really well, so there's a thing that Ride is very reasonable.
Scott: I paid what like $75 something like that.
Scott: I just covered everything yep, and I could ride any distance I wanted.
Rym: and but so like I bike a lot like as a kid like I was a mountain biker And I'm kind of getting into mountain biking again.
Rym: like I. biking is a big hobby of mine, but it is far Far from my primary hobby.
Scott: It's not like.
Scott: it's not my primary hobby But it is if it is warm, and I'm not doing anything, and you know it's not raining or something.
Scott: I do that because My other hobbies I could like play video games or do it.
Scott: I could do that anytime.
Rym: You can only bike when it's nice out.
Scott: biking is you know it's not my number one But it's close to the top and it's definitely my number one thing I do outside.
Scott: so if it's an opportunity to be outside it becomes the number one priority to do Because when it comes winter I do it zero at all.
Rym: But it's interesting because I've never done like a big bike ride with people whose primary hobby is biking before.
Scott: Yeah, and I'm definitely not gonna ever care about bike racing.
Scott: This is just a you know bike around and enjoy the scenery and some people are doing it for fitness or training reasons But no one's.
Scott: there's no reward for coming in first.
Scott: They don't buy.
Scott: you know my reward was.
Scott: it's not like a dinner like 40 minutes before you right?
Scott: I was real hungry, but it's not like one of those things.
Scott: they hand out medals to everyone even if no matter where you finish.
Scott: Right it's absolutely not a competition anyway it's literally just come out and you can go on a bike ride that is much longer and Interesting that you could normally go on by yourself with added safety and comfort.
Scott: so at you know with with company.
Scott: Yeah, that's the big thing is like I could just take the train up there and go on this bike ride whenever I wanted to.
Rym: Yeah, I have the route now.
Scott: Nothing's gonna stop me, but I would not have people waiting at farms to hand me food or Put porta potties to pee Someone.
Rym: we're kind of going the same pace and we talked for like five minutes.
Rym: Then one of us would just pull ahead and that was that I met like 20 or 30 cool people just like Biking next to them and almost every one of them started the conversation in a way.
Scott: you all have biking in common Yep, but pretty much all of them like Pete someone who bikes and cares about biking that much is a good person.
Rym: pretty much every one of them was like So what happened to your?
Rym: what happened to your bike?
Rym: because I wasn't using?
Rym: I was I Think I would might have been the only person on the long ride who didn't have a road bike.
Scott: We weren't on the long ride.
Scott: We're on these 72 miles.
Rym: It has a whole bunch of there's a century, right?
Scott: So this is there's a super short ride.
Scott: That's pretty much just on the rail trail and I saw.
Rym: I looked at the people who are on the three short.
Scott: It was like it was like children and they pretty much all had like mountain bikes and hybrids and like it's like the fun ride For kids and you know family type ride, right?
Scott: Then there's like, I don't know what it goes in between.
Scott: but then you start to get to like medium ride like 50 miles Which is like, okay, you're gonna bike but you're not super serious about biking, but you can do it, right?
Scott: You know, you'll enjoy your whole day bike in 50 miles.
Rym: But there were four at the top that are like the big ones.
Scott: So he did 72 which we died at 72 because that's what else is doing.
Scott: Yep I did 72 because I was like, hey, which one are we doing?
Scott: We're doing 72.
Scott: I Well, that sounds good and I did it because you were doing.
Rym: I thought about doing the centuries.
Rym: I've never biked a hundred.
Scott: I felt like I could do the hundred like it would take.
Scott: I would finish it Obviously it would take me a couple hours more than the 72.
Scott: Yeah, but it had.
Scott: daddy two giant hills.
Rym: Yep Now there are two versions of the century that a normal one and then a leg save and they had one with five Fucking giant hills.
Scott: I climb over a hundred.
Scott: challenge you climb over a mile.
Rym: Yeah, people were doing that one when they started rolling into the camp at the end.
Rym: They looked like grim death.
Scott: Yeah, there was.
Scott: these are people.
Scott: so there was one person who did the challenge?
Scott: who was you know?
Scott: A friend of the friends we went with.
Scott: so I didn't really know them.
Scott: Yeah, and they finished that challenge when we were on the train home and they but they only started one hour late You know, they they they're supposed to start it at seven.
Scott: They started at eight and these were people who are super serious.
Scott: I met a lot more serious and fit than we are who.
Rym: there's a point where people who failed on the century Could cut off and join the end.
Scott: Yeah Before if you don't if you don't finish if you're not far enough along they force you to turn at a certain point like no.
Scott: And also I think one of the monster hills was closed for some mysterious reason.
Scott: I heard rumors about like a lost hiker.
Rym: Yeah, I googled like brat could not find even the slightest mention of anything like that.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know what the deal was But I mean small town news, right?
Scott: But one of the hills was closed for some reason that was out of the control of the people organizing the ride now.
Rym: so on one hand I thought oh I should do the century because like No lie, like I bike a lot and I run a lot and I'm pretty like I can.
Scott: I can just like bike.
Scott: 40 Miles after work on Friday would not even a problem.
Scott: I'm like a hundred if I'm biking all day With nothing else to do but bike and I don't have to stop and I have rest stops and all the support.
Rym: I could definitely Do a hundred because normally I do self-supported rides meaning like I have a backpack with like everything I would need if I.
Scott: this is like now I have to carry anything But I get all the luxury of if I was carrying stuff, you know what I had?
Rym: I had a. I had an emergency pump one tube a patch kit and one water bottle And that's it.
Scott: I had two water bottles and a tube and a co2 cartridge and some allen wrenches.
Scott: Yeah, my entire levers entire entire levers and that's all I had.
Rym: Yep But on the side my human body and so the 72 was like the cut like it seems like everyone above that in the entire Ride I saw one person other than me who was not on a road bike.
Rym: One and I was looking for him and everyone I talked to was like, oh man Something happened to your bike.
Rym: like everyone like assumed that I like broke my bike and was using my backup bike and they were like Shocked that I ride that far on a hybrid.
Scott: Hmm.
Scott: You can do it.
Scott: Yeah, it was it trimming.
Scott: It's just maybe less comfortable and less efficient.
Rym: possibly It's definitely less efficient because you know gearing is different all that stuff.
Rym: But at the same time I'm actually more a mountain biker than a road biker to this day because I spent most of my life Doing mountain biking.
Scott: I'm sure you know what the thing is like.
Scott: I only had to.
Scott: my goal was to just.
Scott: you know It's not a race.
Scott: I didn't care how fast I went and I pretty much assumed that I would go slower than everyone else because I don't bike for Fitness or try and it seemed like other people were actually trying to go fast to at least some extent.
Scott: Yeah, where is it when I ride my bike?
Scott: I basically if I feel like oh This is like hurting or I'm gonna be out of breath I slow down and I just make sure that I'm always like.
Scott: I mean, I don't really I'm personally relaxed at all times.
Scott: So I'll go super ridiculous slow as long like if it's up a hill I just like ah this feels great.
Scott: So even if I'm climbing the steepest hill I'm just like ah, so it was interesting.
Scott: I was way slow compared to other people But I mean I finished what compared to Rym who runs and climbs daily.
Rym: You were like minutes after me.
Scott: I was 30 minutes after you and that doesn't include like the fact that I stayed at rest stops longer than you did because I was Going on well.
Rym: for so for hanging out talking to people Supported rides are the best because like every 10 or so miles there was a rest stop with like water and Gatorade Gels and food and you could just relax.
Rym: So I waited for like we had a group of people like we met.
Rym: all these cool people were hanging out like friends of friends or whatever and I would like wait for some of them at each stop before I went away and I Think it was the third to last rest stop or I just stopped waiting for people and just tried to power through to the end As fast as I possibly could.
Rym: Yeah, I would not had no interest in going as fast as I like that feeling So like on that first big climb, like I pushed myself up that hill.
Scott: Yeah, so my goal was to a whole bunch of people come.
Rym: I was really cuz I don't like.
Rym: I'm not super in biking.
Rym: I was actually kind of like weird.
Scott: Well, first of all your bike had way lower gears.
Scott: I probably could have gotten up the hill on your bike.
Scott: Oh, yeah, but even though it's heavier than mine.
Rym: But I was not in that lowest gear for a lot of those climbs.
Rym: cuz I was go I was going as fast as I could use my lowest gear often and didn't give a shit.
Scott: Because my goal is basically cuz these I never stand up.
Scott: I saw a lot of people.
Scott: they stand up.
Rym: I want a steep climb like standings.
Rym: great.
Scott: I never stand.
Scott: why my goal is not staying why I just standings.
Rym: a perfectly valid technique.
Scott: I just don't stand right and then weird.
Rym: I mean, I don't walk.
Rym: That's my thing.
Rym: I will never walk.
Scott: I'll see him.
Scott: I usually I would never walk.
Scott: but that hill was just at such a steepness that in my lowest gear While I was sitting I could not turn the pedal If I push pull push pull and just really get up.
Scott: if I stood I could have gotten up easily if I had.
Scott: You know, you know knowing that the hill is gonna be that steep I probably could have maybe done a zigzag or something.
Scott: cuz it basically comes.
Scott: you turn a corner and there it is and I saw Someone else walking and I'm just like, oh well, but I only walked up the one hill.
Rym: I did not walk at any point and I also did not run into trouble at any point.
Rym: cuz there's one section way near the end Where the road like the trail was real shitty and covered in gravel.
Scott: That was the shitty part.
Rym: Yeah, but the funny thing is because I was on a hybrid.
Scott: I was just like whoosh didn't even think about it Have too much problem with the gravel but I had to really look at the ground to avoid.
Rym: I saw four different people get Flat tires like on that one spot.
Scott: I didn't get a flat tire, but I was basically at that part.
Scott: I was chillin with some people who were on a tandem bike.
Scott: Oh And I was just.
Scott: I was like, whoa awesome tandem bike Whoo, and then suddenly they stopped and they're like just behind me.
Scott: So then I stopped and I'm like, whoa, you guys are right.
Scott: and then I realized Everyone else was turning off the gravel on onto the rail trail again.
Scott: And I'm like, oh they know if I didn't if I hadn't noticed them stopping I would have totally missed that turn-off right there.
Rym: Yep, I almost followed it way toward the end.
Scott: It's all.
Scott: the directions are painted on the ground, but they don't paint on the gravel.
Scott: Yeah, the paint was on the pavement off to the side.
Rym: I was I was following this guy for a while Like I was just kind of.
Rym: I wasn't like drafting him But I was like following him because you can you can think less and focus more on the scenery if you keep like someone else Who's going at a good pace for you?
Rym: Just like in your peripheral vision.
Scott: So I like to follow someone because if I'm by myself I'd every now and then I'm like like There are a lot of times where I was alone and there wasn't a direction on the street for a long time and you had.
Scott: Then one would come.
Scott: you have the cue sheet, right?
Scott: I didn't.
Scott: I lost my leg right away.
Scott: I have mine but never had to check it because every time I thought I might have been lost someone appeared or some direction appeared on the ground or direction from a previous year that was faded was on the ground and then I when I got to the end on Strava the map exactly matched a hundred percent Super accurately the map on the website.
Scott: It even said exactly 72 miles.
Scott: Yeah, 72 point.
Scott: Oh, I was like damn That's some accurate map.
Rym: right there My Strava says seventy two point four in the end and I looked.
Rym: there's a spot toward the end.
Rym: The only time I stopped outside of rest off the entire time I pulled my bike like to pee in the woods twenty or thirty feet down this like driveway and then walked into the woods Peed forever.
Scott: I just peed on the side of the road.
Rym: I went.
Scott: I went off the road even though I the thing is like I peed at every rest stop But at that I had to pee again because I drank too much water.
Rym: Yeah, well at the end like I was getting pretty tired.
Rym: So I drank a lot of water and that was a mistake.
Scott: I wasn't tired.
Scott: I was like when I got to the end I was like, ah, I'm into the end I was tired, but in that long flat section near the end, I tried to go fast.
Scott: Well, I didn't actually was surprising.
Scott: is that even you know, obviously I was you know more fatigued.
Scott: I didn't feel like tired and like I need to go to sleep.
Scott: My body was clearly more fatigued closer to the end because I had biked already seventy miles.
Scott: Yeah, but when I got in the rail trail itself, it was covered in shade and the pavement on it was different for some reason.
Rym: Oh, yeah I just started going faster there on the good parts that were technically rail trail.
Scott: I was just going faster while still being comfortable because I think of the shade and the pavement something about it was just like Oh, you can go faster here because it appears the pavement on the street was I guess, you know, not as good.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: So the cool thing is like.
Rym: all the other people we were with are like way more like biking is their main.
Scott: Yeah, I mean Katie was like I biked every weekend this summer.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't do.
Scott: I didn't hang out with my non Viking.
Rym: I don't think I'd ever biked more than 60 or so miles in one go ever.
Scott: The thing is they also I think they did this program in New York that the New York Cycle Club does called the SIG Which has like different groups a B and C and it's a free program.
Scott: but like they teach you how to group ride for serious the a group is like.
Scott: We teach you how to like form pace lines and we'll kick you out if you're too slow and stuff, right?
Scott: But they did the B one I think which is why they knew to like have these clips to hold their cue sheet on their Handlebars like they learned all this stuff there that we didn't learn.
Scott: But I went to the website cuz like they kept trying to push me to do it.
Scott: like Scott You should really do the SIG.
Scott: Oh, you should do it.
Scott: I went to the website to check it out last year the first first of all.
Scott: It's a 10-week thing or 12 and you have to do every week.
Scott: You can't really miss it or else you get kicked out.
Scott: The very first week of it last year was the PAX East weekend.
Scott: Well, and it's just like.
Scott: well and it's also like it starts in March at the beginning of March when it's cold.
Scott: Yeah, you gotta buy some you know, like equipment to go bike in the cold.
Scott: Otherwise, you're gonna quit.
Scott: Yeah But yeah, that's that's why you know, I think that's where a lot of them met or whatever.
Rym: Yep but in terms like I Realized pretty well on that a lot of the people on this trail like not just the people were hanging out with but like everyone I talked to along the way.
Rym: biking is definitely like their primary or sole hobby, but specifically this kind of biking No one I talked to it ever mountain biked and no one like all the jargon about like trail riding or single track.
Rym: like no one.
Rym: Any what I was talking about?
Rym: They only do this.
Rym: I remember I two different people.
Rym: I ended up sort of like.
Rym: they were curious.
Rym: I just explaining in detail like how mountain biking works like yeah You don't clip in you just put your feet on and they're like terrified of that and it was just.
Rym: It's interesting to see these people have a very narrow and deep Hobby because I pretty much you're just like.
Rym: I'm not super deep on anything and I'm just all over the place on everything.
Scott: I'm sure those people have other hobbies besides bike.
Scott: Yeah, but they're just.
Scott: they're just way more into biking No, but only this kind of biking like I do.
Rym: all kinds of rice.
Scott: The thing is they care about.
Scott: a lot of those people care about.
Rym: as a kid.
Rym: I used to like BMX biking.
Scott: I don't care about biking itself.
Scott: Whereas for me.
Scott: It's like yeah, I do enjoy biking But I'm like I was looking at the scenery more than I was trying to you know Check the time or worry about my body's health or any of that nonsense, right?
Scott: I'm just like whoa cuz like you.
Scott: go out to.
Scott: this place was Millerton, New York and the surrounding towns.
Scott: It's like farms.
Scott: There were a few places very definition of bucolic and pest or there were a few places where their houses next to each other But there was a lot of trees.
Rym: There's one spot where it like you get to the top of this mountain and it's like it says it was a slog to get Up there and we finally get to the top and then you kind of come over the crest and then there's a spray paint.
Rym: That says two miles straight down fly But along like right around there There was another spray paint.
Rym: that said look at an arrow to your left.
Rym: in case like you're so focused on the ride You look to your left and it's like the most gorgeous Farmland.
Scott: like there's a pond in the distance horses and cows Mostly horses up there, but then later on cows indoor cows and more cows all the goats All the rest stops seem to be in cooperation with certain farms.
Scott: It's like you go and you stop it like the horse farm and the people who run the horse farm were out there running the rest up.
Scott: one of the rest stops is way better than the others in a misting tent and That's the one with ice right?
Scott: It had ice.
Scott: The other ones didn't have ice.
Scott: This one had ice.
Scott: So and one of the rest ups is sadder than the others and they're like the bare minimum amount of stuff.
Scott: I should have skipped that one.
Scott: But yeah The actual camp place where you like start is like the baseball field of Millerton is like the town park.
Scott: I guess that's where we camped.
Scott: You don't have to camp.
Scott: a lot of people stayed in hotels.
Rym: like the vast majority of people Live in the area and drive.
Scott: in the vast majority people just drove there Sunday morning got out and biked whereas we had went there Saturday woke up and biked Going there and camping is definitely the superior method.
Rym: Yes There aren't that many people camping and it's like this really chill vibe and when we woke up in the morning is like there was Awesome breakfast.
Scott: Yeah, it wasn't like the greatest breakfast ever, but it was like band camp breakfast.
Scott: The bagel was way better than streetcar bagel.
Scott: Although it wasn't greatest bagel ever.
Scott: It was free Of course, right every note and like they were actually making like French toast there, which is way good.
Scott: The bacon was really sad.
Rym: sausage was good though.
Rym: I should eat more of that sauce.
Scott: But and then when we got back afterwards just bbq, yeah, it was really.
Scott: it wasn't the kind of barbecue I had for lunch today, right but it was like it was pretty good.
Scott: It's like, alright, I got a sausage and onions And the thing is like it like they do all this stuff to like help you out.
Scott: It's like when we arrived on the train to get there They were there with a van because we called them Yeah Take all
Rym: of our
Scott: stuff except our bikes so that we could bike on the rail trail to get from the train in Wasek to Millerton and then when we had to go back home to New York They put our bikes in a pickup truck put us in a van and drove all of us to the train station.
Scott: Like for nothing.
Scott: just like, you know, that's just what they do and it was super organized and they actually took care.
Rym: Yeah, like getting the bikes like everything.
Scott: everything happened on time perfectly.
Rym: They exhibited the PAX tabletop enforcer mantra make it fit Yeah and they made it fairly.
Scott: this operation is like actually only run by two people and I guess everyone else was just like volunteers or staff of some kind helping out.
Scott: but like there were so many people helping out this vans driving around checking like if you You would you would like biking and you'd see nothing for like miles.
Scott: But if you stopped and waited a van would eventually just drive by like and like be hey thumbs up.
Rym: You're good.
Scott: Yeah, like you need something from us.
Scott: It's like a whole van full of help.
Scott: They were just driving everywhere.
Rym: I'm glad I didn't have trouble cuz actually my front tire is still the original tire from when I bought this bike and it's pretty Original tire original tube, I bought that bike some time ago.
Scott: But yeah, you know regardless of your biking athletic skill, right if you live in New York You can go to this specific ride.
Rym: It's where unless it's gonna rain that weekend I'm definitely doing it again.
Scott: rise by the fun, you know based on where you live I'm sure you can find rides similar to this.
Scott: Just don't do one in like.
Scott: I don't know Colorado or Vermont or some places made of mountains Switzerland.
Scott: Do it someplace.
Scott: that's at least mostly flat ish.
Rym: an interesting sort of side point Is that the websites like good in some ways like.
Rym: it has a lot of info like there's a lot of stuff here But it also lacks all the like really pertinent details.
Rym: that only means God seemed to care about Like everyone else like bike community just trusted like oh, yeah, it'll work.
Rym: It'll just work out.
Scott: But I think that they've a lot of people done this before.
Scott: Partly there are hundreds of people doing.
Rym: you know how my hobby has failed conventions.
Scott: Yeah, like Opposite this is run so professionally like even the first packs we went to.
Rym: I was like reading every detail on that website like okay It's in this building.
Rym: It starts at this time.
Rym: Get my badge will be here because of this like I'm so like and this.
Rym: it was just like yeah I just show up in camp and I'm like, well, when can I show up?
Rym: and it turns out it doesn't matter to show up.
Scott: Apparently some people show up early on Saturday bike on Saturday and then bike on Sunday.
Rym: Yeah, I think next year I'd show up like a Several hours earlier on Saturday, but not like crack of dawn.
Rym: get there like late afternoon.
Scott: You could do like some you know, like a nice 20 30 mile pre-ride.
Rym: Yeah, maybe play some bocce or something.
Scott: Yeah someone was playing some people.
Scott: I Think this family had brought a game that I hadn't heard of that.
Scott: I looked up and it's called Something ladder with the bolo's.
Scott: you basically have a bowl It was like three sticks Vertically and you have a bolo which is two balls with a rope attached to each other and you're trying to Throw it and get it to catch on the the thing.
Scott: So it looked really fun But you should have brought some cub Because I planned like.
Rym: I didn't plan like.
Rym: I didn't actually like commit until like right before.
Rym: So I bought my like.
Rym: I registered on Thursday Which I think was the last day to register before the price increase.
Rym: like if you did it the day Oh, if you do day of it's a hundred bucks and then 75 I thought I'll maybe I'll stay at a motel and I was like, oh, no, that's stupid.
Rym: So I had to go like buy a tent.
Scott: you didn't have to buy a tent you could just borrowed, you know The tent I was in was a two people tent.
Scott: you could have stayed in that.
Rym: Yeah Well, I asked you like how big a tent?
Rym: I didn't know that you were like, I don't know and I can't trust that I'm not gonna risk it.
Scott: Okay, you know you just like buying stuff.
Rym: No, I didn't need a tent cuz I do plan to do some camping.
Scott: I just borrowed my friend and I do have.
Rym: my mom has all my old like camping and tent stuff and I thought maybe I want to mail it to me and like Emily's parents have like a hurled stuff, but I went and bought cuz they're not that expensive like a modern backpacking tent.
Rym: Holy shit has that technology gotten better in the last 20 years?
Scott: Yeah Despite not like.
Scott: I was afraid I haven't put together a tent in so long and any tent I've put together has not been Complicated or was old-style.
Scott: I had I put together my friend.
Scott: I was worried about breaking it because it wasn't my tent and it was no and it's like with no instructions whatsoever This expensive tent belonging to my friend that I was afraid to break.
Scott: I was.
Rym: I put it together perfectly from the first try just like boop Yep but no instruction was up in like 30 seconds and the rest of the time was me fucking with it and like Making sure cuz I wasn't convinced.
Scott: It was like whoa It's that was really easy and not a problem at all
Rym: and we could see stars but like basically I didn't own any modern equipment because I haven't done like serious camping since I was a kid and all the stuff that I own through my family is old enough to where the technology is vastly superior today like my Hiking backpack is an external frame, which is like a monster by modern.
Scott: I think I have a sleeping bag that I used in the desert from the year 2000.
Scott: Yeah, that sleeping bag is probably garbage.
Rym: I went looked at modern sleeping bags like the world changed Yeah, but I didn't buy a sleeping bag cuz I don't need like.
Rym: I'm not gonna do winter camping ever again No, so it's I enjoyed.
Scott: it was a little bit colder than I thought but it was still warm enough that I made it.
Rym: I bought a sleep sack, which is basically like a tiny sleeping bag that you can stuff in like a really tiny space But it only works if it's like 50 degrees or more like below.
Rym: that it won't help you Mmm, and it was actually really cheap like I got it on a sale at REI.
Rym: But basically I went like bought this stuff and now actually I might do a camping trip like right after packed.
Rym: So it's kind of good that I got this.
Rym: The only problem was that I have the sleeping pads.
Rym: Like you don't want to sleep on grass directly.
Rym: usually even in a tent like that's not comfortable.
Rym: So I needed like a sleeping mat and I had to silence got one.
Rym: But the ones I got are pretty big because they're like the luxury cover.
Scott: Yeah, this is one.
Scott: an Amazon is green.
Scott: that goes way smaller.
Scott: I'm gonna get up cuz.
Rym: this is the one I'll bring to like feed Nuri's house.
Rym: So I'm gonna sleep on their floor Yeah, but I'm not necessarily or like winter camping because it's crazy insulated, but not carrying that like on my backpack.
Scott: Yeah other funny things the people we were with they were all they spent like the whole time having the same conversation About this creepy dude.
Rym: Oh my god I got.
Scott: it's like all they could talk about was his creepy, dude.
Rym: Well partly cuz Scott they has the gnosis of like creepy dude lore.
Scott: Well, they they were in you know They did some biking event with this dude, right and afterwards the dude I guess messaged them all like in succession like trying to ask them out
Rym: Yeah,
Scott: and then of course now here at the biking event all of them are together and they're like We all got messages from the same creepy dude.
Rym: really one of them was reading an email out loud and Scott's like there's warning signs There I'm like, that's creepy dude.
Scott: So that was that was a funny story.
Scott: another funny story was.
Scott: I don't know were there any other funny stories.
Scott: I was like trying to think like, you know, you think you do something like this like weird stuff.
Scott: What how?
Scott: there was this really awesome dog that I thought?
Scott: Oh, yeah that like but that austere Was like an enormous dog sitting at the end of a driveway that I buy a nine I described and I was like.
Scott: It was like he really guarded the driveway, but he like wasn't?
Scott: you know, it wasn't misbehaving.
Scott: It's like whoa, that is like the awesomest dog right there.
Scott: Yeah There were horses, but they didn't bother anybody.
Rym: Well, they came over like bothering people for treats and when no one gave him a truth, they're like and they just left.
Rym: They're like no one's giving me an apple.
Scott: What else happened there?
Rym: I mean it just was fun time hanging out with a bunch of strangers swapping stories.
Scott: There was a music guy at the end.
Scott: He was actually really like quite a good musician, but was too loud.
Scott: So it was hard to talk when you're hanging out as loud as like other kinds of it was like it was a metal concert Loud.
Scott: it was just slightly difficult to talk to each other, you know hanging out at the end loud.
Rym: Yep It's partly.
Rym: it's very usually the circles.
Rym: I hang out with with strangers are more on the gamer or technology side Very rarely on the sports side because most of the sports I do either do solo or I do with friends.
Rym: like most of my Biking is alone self-supported or me and Emily's self-supported.
Rym: and like skiing I mostly do by myself like I only on ski trips with other people other than Emily like twice a year tops.
Rym: And this year like it was like I know it like I imagine doing all the other sports that I mostly do solo With all the people who do those sports and I think that would actually be fun.
Rym: That's enough time.
Rym: just do other stuff.
Scott: Oh, oh, that's right.
Scott: The other thing is so we all had to take our bikes on the train.
Scott: The Metro North trains I measure North was not ready for us.
Scott: on the way up.
Scott: It wasn't really a big deal because there weren't that many other bikers on our train But on the way back because like everyone arrived at different times taking different trains But on the way back is pretty much like everyone.
Scott: there are two trains going back Basically and most of us are on this six o'clock train Like 50 bikes we like filled the bed.
Scott: They you know The MTA technically has rules about like eight bikes per train or you per car or something like that.
Scott: It's not a high number but like we friggin it was crazy.
Scott: We filled the back of this Metro North train with bikes and all the seats and doctors were pretty not cool.
Rym: It like they want to know.
Scott: they you know, they they allowed it.
Scott: They were just.
Rym: they were definitely annoyed by it.
Rym: You know
Scott: it was a hassle for them and
Rym: then a lot of the people who got on the train later because the train complete basically completely Filled because this is like all the people who did upstate crap on a Sunday coming back into the city and the train shows up Basically full of bikes and though so the funniest thing actually on the way there We were on the train right and like we do our transfer and everything and this old man like I'm Away from everyone else by myself because I I talked to the doctor and I just like put my bike like in the empty car.
Rym: That was roped off and that was way pleasant.
Rym: But as I'm leaving this old man who was sitting there with Scott and then we're with the bike with the other bikes He goes the conductor.
Rym: He's like, how can you let this happen?
Rym: The conductor is like what?
Rym: and he's like Why are there bikes on this train?
Rym: They're in the way.
Rym: It's rude.
Rym: They're getting the seats and he's like this guy was so pissed that there were bikes on the train.
Scott: We'll just get pissed by things that are out of the ordinary and make them angry.
Scott: And then when we were in the talk about this literally all the time is the old.
Scott: This is the thing that is talked about the most.
Scott: Why do we need to keep talking about it?
Scott: There are people in this world who are dumb, angry, averse to change, averse to newness.
Rym: But the fact that he said anything that is unroutined The exact words he said were to the conductor.
Rym: How could you let this happen?
Rym: That's the kind of thing you say when like someone gets hit by the train or like a gunfight breaks out.
Rym: That's not something you say because you saw a bike.
Scott: The people are fragile.
Scott: Yeah Something's out of the ordinary.
Scott: Oh my god.
Rym: But no, this was super super fun and I really like biking and I think I had to replace my clip shoes because the toes Like the clips are fine.
Rym: Like everything's fine, but my toes I've almost broken through the front of the shoes.
Rym: I think I've just worn them out from using them for so many years.
Scott: Mine are like the problem with mine.
Scott: There's nothing wrong with them, but it's like they're the right length.
Scott: but They are Things like super super tight Purpose.
Rym: I ordered like five from Zappos.
Scott: I did the same thing and the ones that were one size smaller.
Scott: My toe was like bumping up against the front.
Scott: Ah, you know why I kept the ones that I have But I think I might have to just buy like a different brand next time if they can't get narrow ones or something.
Scott: Yeah, you know maybe next year.
Rym: I mean my one pair is sort of like I might get a pair that's less walkable But just more like biker.
Scott: Also my helmet which is only a few years old and it's still you know It's still perfectly great like the fuzzy stuff on the inside is all like destroyed.
Scott: So I'm like, I don't want to buy a new helmet.
Scott: They're not cheap and there's nothing wrong with this one.
Scott: But so I wonder if I can just get replacement Cushion parts for the inside.
Rym: I was about to type in to find out how often Bike helmet should be replaced because there's probably some like specific guidance on there.
Rym: Yeah The recommendation searches for how often are.
Rym: how often should you change your oil?
Rym: it makes sense.
Rym: How often should you shower?
Rym: How often should you poop?
Scott: You should poop like once every day or two.
Rym: Yeah 1.5 times a day on average I feel like is a good metric.
Scott: Yeah, I don't need to Google for this bike helmet.
Rym: All right, how often should you replace a bike helmet?
Rym: Five years.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: I don't think mine is five years old.
Scott: Mine is Three years old I want to say.
Scott: Yeah, I don't.
Scott: I think mine might be only two or three years old at this point.
Scott: I bought it recently.
Scott: One that I replaced was well over five.
Scott: Yeah, the one I replaced might have been like nine or ten years old.
Rym: Yeah, oh this side is funny.
Rym: helmets.org.
Rym: When should I replace?
Rym: When should I replace my helmet and has a list of questions?
Rym: Did you crash?
Scott: Yeah, if you place it if you crash the helmet helmets are one use.
Scott: if they get hit by something you have to replace it.
Scott: It won't protect your head a second time.
Rym: But the second the second question is did you drop it hard enough to crack it?
Scott: I've dropped it but not hard enough to crack.
Rym: Is it from the 70s?
Rym: Replace it.
Scott: No, it's not.
Rym: Is the outside just foam?
Rym: Replace it.
Rym: Does it not have a certification sticker in it?
Scott: It has the sticker and the outside is still plastic.
Scott: Does the plastic actually help?
Scott: I think so.
Scott: Or is it just decorative?
Rym: So the plastic?
Rym: I think Because I from what I know the the PVC or whatever that like the actual part of the helmet the part of the helmet that matters the foam is destroyed by UV light Like it's weakened over time.
Rym: That's the main reason.
Scott: The plastic is protecting it.
Rym: Yep I don't think the plastic does anything else structurally.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Maybe it forms like an initial like.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I don't know about helmets.
Rym: I just replace my helmet every few like four or five years.
Rym: Mmm.
Rym: Yeah, biking This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Rym: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette and Thomas on mystati.com.
Rym: William Eisneros Jeremy minor Life and death and love and birth and peace and war on the planet earth.
Rym: a genuine bonafide.
Rym: like five six car monorail.
Rym: Nicholas Brando captain Chinguacos.
Rym: see Rebecca Dunn the terrible secret to space.
Rym: 421 creations.
Rym: even if we were to pull out today and if they were Come to come take our bays.
Rym: Shervin on Horrell Roy Lavelle James David White Rochelle, Monta Nona Superboy.
Rym: I paid five bucks to make room.
Rym: say pickle Sailor Vista Matthew Smith don't you like?
Rym: it's art obvious in Joshua.
Rym: Joe star Sean Yeager Sam Cordray Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan parent drew open-lander.
Rym: Brian Sidroni Finn Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas on working on the antenna show.
Rym: Just give me time.
Rym: I got it.
Rym: I got to put like the pipelines together.
Rym: We just got over court some stuff and it's coming.
Rym: You'll get one at some point probably shortly after packs.
Rym: but anyway now I leave you with a Dream Who's gonna love you baby?