Rym: It's Monday July 24th 2017.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I was good, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We're talking about passwords Hunter - was it hunter?
Rym: - or hunter five whatever that old.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: So it's been a long time since I've talked about stu leonard on this show.
Rym: Yes, you know once we stopped living upstate like don't go to stu leonard as often.
Scott: well I mean so.
Scott: when I was a kid we went and I was like a special deal right like Stu leonard was the fancy grocery store.
Scott: before there was Trader Joe's or any other fancy place, right?
Scott: It was pretty much supermarket and stu leonard was another thing.
Scott: It was completely different.
Rym: It was like the IKEA of groceries and when I worked in Yonkers I literally worked like right next to the one there.
Rym: So I would stop there on the way home to Pekin like right once a week.
Scott: Well, but it was only one of when I was a kid.
Scott: There's only one in Connecticut and then they open a few more.
Scott: There's still not that many.
Scott: you only can go to it if you're in New York Connecticut kind of area.
Rym: most important part about stu leonards is that turkey chili?
Scott: But anyway, you mean the chicken chili with beans whatever what it was it was.
Scott: Oh, that's I guess That's what I'm gonna eat cuz that's in my fridge.
Scott: So, you know, I haven't been to one since in like super long time Because I don't have a car.
Scott: I used to when I would drive from Pekin to Connecticut I would pass by the one in Danbury off 84 But I haven't been to one in so long.
Scott: So I went to one yesterday no Saturday and The Yonkers one and it's pretty much the same as it was was before, you know They had all like the same foods that they've always had that gorgonzola salad.
Scott: Oh that gorgonzola salad Pretty much everything that they.
Rym: you know, I just make that salad now.
Scott: Yeah, but they sell like the full filet mignon.
Scott: It's like they sell everything they always sold.
Scott: I didn't notice a lot of new stuff there.
Scott: You can still scoop pistachio nuts on the scoop, right?
Rym: I saw you're in some of those pistachios, but obviously you wouldn't bring this up if there wasn't something different.
Scott: Yeah, so the thing that's two letters is most known for which is the reason it was a special occasion to go there when I was a kid in the 80s 90s.
Scott: whatever is that?
Scott: the store is full of animatronic shit like like five nights at Freddy's.
Scott: yeah, pretty much like, you know, the Confederate dog and Singing right and the.
Scott: You know This the milk carton singing and the Chiquita banana singing and the cow that you push the button and it goes move And all that stuff.
Scott: so the one in Yonkers, I'd actually never been to that one before but that's the one we went to and It had way less Animatronic shit, I guess that's better than I've been in the past.
Scott: The only thing that was in there was a singing tree from Poland spring water The the dog and cow singing with the banjo and the right the Civil War dog and cow.
Scott: and There were a few of those, you know, like monkeys that keep flipping over a bar over and over again The bars in this video right here, they didn't have the cow that goes moo and you push the button.
Scott: They didn't have the singing milk cartons.
Scott: They didn't have any of that stuff.
Scott: So it's like I think the most of that stuff was always at the original Westport, Connecticut location.
Rym: I feel like that is like the 90s mall animatronics era, but it was before the 90s.
Scott: this stuff, right?
Scott: It was you know.
Scott: And then it's more like Stu Leonard is more like a Casa Bonita with the diving.
Scott: It's like it was.
Scott: they had a unique thing that only they had But that thing has been toned down in these other locations.
Rym: Well, there's only two alternatives.
Rym: I'm not sure what's changed in the many years since I've been there with animatronics because it amusement parks at malls And I guess it's do Leonard's.
Rym: there's only two ways animatronics can go.
Rym: either they get scaled back over time because that's ancient archaic technology or They become decrepit and I guess you can keep maintaining him and scaling them up.
Rym: I feel like yeah, I have an expert person I feel like there is no interest in the world that I feel like animatronics are a dying art that will just disappear.
Scott: So I think it actually you know It seems like it, you know, the one kind of logic is like they have it because it's quirky, right?
Scott: Just because no and then you get rid of it because we're spending money on this thing.
Scott: that obviously isn't increasing our business It's just costing us money, right?
Scott: But I think in the day of internet You actually want to have that thing because it gives you a reason to go to the grocery store.
Rym: Ah, but you would.
Rym: that's not just you know Fresh direct you would craft it a little bit differently then you would want to craft it in such a way that People there would have a reason to do Mimi nonsense around it and she read it around.
Scott: I think it just makes your store into a. you know, you get tourists to come to your store Which is a regular grocery store.
Scott: The thing is about Stu Leonard is that even back in the day Even if you lived close to it, it would be weird to use that as your everyday grocery store Because you got to walk along this path with very little opportunities to cut across Like IKEA where you have to go along the path and see everything.
Scott: It's like that You can't just go in get an egg and come out.
Scott: You got to go through the whole store and pass all the things And if I recall correctly when we would go we would buy a lot of nonsense But our path.
Scott: the other thing about Stu Leonard's is that you only when you go there you pretty much only buy Stu Leonard brand Stuff because that's the reason you're going there is to get stuff that they have that no one else has.
Scott: You don't go there to get like brand name stuff because they overcharge up the ass.
Scott: Big time is like you go in there and it's like oh bag of chips $5.
Scott: and then you go over and it's like oh another bag of chips for $5.
Scott: But these are stews made in store daily kettles sweet potato chips, and it's like if you buy some Lays It's like alright.
Scott: I'll give you a fucking $5 or a bag of giant Chips, but them lays for $5.
Scott: You can shove that where the Sun don't shine The Sun don't shine in my mouth.
Scott: So Not putting lays in my mouth.
Rym: So anyway in the news is a bunch of like little news is that I think are worth Mentioning?
Rym: and I think first off is that this is a little bit old.
Rym: But it's probably moderately important because if you're not aware There's a lot of ways to encode video like if you then the like you might look at the extension.
Scott: It's a lot crazier than and like image encoding.
Scott: because you know, you have a JPEG.
Scott: It's named JPEG.
Scott: It's you know, the file extensions map one to one.
Scott: Yeah with the kind of file But with videos you have containers and encoding and you are you cloud it and code the audio and the video with two different codex.
Scott: Yeah, and you can do all sorts of crazy combination.
Rym: Usually there's lots.
Scott: this is why things like VLC are not, you know are important?
Scott: because they get that shit playing right what?
Rym: and there's lots of ways to encode video and one of the more recent like pushes forward is h.265 and all the stuff under that.
Rym: but Hulu Netflix and Amazon are at least working together Ostensibly to use a royalty-free format that they're calling AV one that should perform similarly if not better than a shot to 65 But more importantly quote will be licensed under royalty-free terms for all use cases.
Scott: that's extra important because They want people to make devices and software that lets you watch Amazon Netflix and whatever.
Scott: So let me say unless if it's just one of those services people aren't gonna have an incentive to implement it.
Scott: But if it's like oh, this is the thing that every service is using.
Scott: We better create decoders for this and put them in all of our products.
Rym: Well, like I have a camcorder that'll record a.
Scott: now if you start up some other video service And you don't use this codec You might find that people can't use your service because that your videos don't play.
Scott: It's not
Rym: just that though because one of the biggest reasons why a lot like there's been so much trouble especially say in the 90s and early 2000s was that To make any codecs better you just be violating someone's patent Mm-hmm, and there was basically no way to innovate in that space.
Rym: and even big companies.
Rym: But they'd have sort of this mutually assured Destruction of equal and opposing patents and they'd sort of just come to this unsteady Cold War truce.
Rym: So open codecs Basically remove the primary source of friction for a lot of the media industry.
Rym: So unless you're Sony in the old days you have a vested interest in removing that friction Because it'll help your competitors, but it'll also help you and you'll all just make more.
Scott: The other thing is that all of these companies with the big big video game like YouTube and such right?
Scott: They use so much fucking bandwidth.
Rym: So even if they can get so much CPU as well That's like.
Rym: that's not a trivial concern.
Scott: But the point is even a small savings a tiny savings like of a fraction of a percent Multiplied by all the videos they have and all the videos they send out will save them More money than you have in like a day.
Rym: If they
Scott: team up to improve codecs with more brain power they can make a bet even better codec that squishes things even smaller without losing quality and Thus all of them will save even more money Whereas if they just worked on their own codecs individually, none of them would be as good.
Rym: The all use cases part is probably the most important part because my camcorder at least one of my camcorders It has a uses AVCHD like.
Rym: that's the thing it uses But old and crappy.
Rym: Yeah, but that it was the state of the art when I bought that camcorder.
Scott: Yeah, it has its uses still.
Rym: Yeah, it does but and I have other cameras that use other codecs or have different options.
Rym: But most of the cameras I own have notes buried in the manuals that came with them Saying things like you have a license to use this list of codecs for home personal use only Technically you can't use these these transitionary formats from a lot of Consumer or prosumer devices in a commercial endeavor and most people don't worry about those things don't think about those things.
Rym: But technically like by using that camcorder in certain situations like in a monetized video on YouTube If I may or may not have been violated it's because you Transcoded it in Adobe Media Encoder before you put it on YouTube and then you're not even using that codec.
Scott: YouTube is how do they?
Scott: Even know what codec you use because YouTube is then using its codecs to deliver.
Scott: They don't even know what the original video was uploaded with.
Rym: actually I remember researching and they can't.
Rym: they only YouTube could tell them it's actually really debatable What counts as personal use and whether or not like use in the camera and then transcoding counts or not?
Scott: And
Rym: basically, it's just a nightmare that
Scott: just words that lawyers wrote somewhere, you know Because that's how they do and it doesn't actually count and no one's ever tried to fight or and if they did they probably get it appears
Rym: a lot of that is because the Licensing fees and royalties for these codecs were much less if you were restricted from using them in commercial capacities.
Rym: The idea was that they charge the people who sell the studio camera way more money for the license But they can't charge that much for like dumpy thousand-dollar camcorder, right?
Rym: well, there's also countries where like Europe Europe is like has a war on video.
Scott: a Camera that can record video longer than 30 minutes is considered a professional video camera So and there's an extra tax on professional video equipment there.
Scott: So all these cameras that could otherwise record forever But for no reason have artificial limits in them there that forced them to only record 29 minutes and 59 seconds in a single video.
Rym: One has that per GX.
Rym: one has that problem.
Scott: you have to push the video record button again.
Scott: Yep, you know the Sony a7 which is like one of the top video cameras has that limitation everywhere in the world, but the Panasonic gh5 I think has that limitation nowhere in the world.
Scott: the gh4 they made different versions for different parts of the world.
Scott: You know every all these all these crazy things.
Rym: Pretty sure there's only one version of the gx-1 and it had the limitation everywhere.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, it's not a video camera It's a camera that has video because every camera has video in the year 2017.
Rym: Yeah I am thinking about just buying a legit studio camcorder because they're not actually that much money.
Rym: and Especially if we do our convention and all that stuff we're talking about one of those would be way useful.
Rym: So I'm looking into that.
Scott: do whatever you want.
Scott: So is your money?
Rym: there's some other.
Rym: well, it might be the patreon's money.
Scott: That's my beach money.
Scott: Don't touch that.
Rym: So in other news you might have seen that there was a Pokemon go fest and if you didn't see that well good job.
Rym: I'm glad you avoided it.
Scott: There's a convention for a single game Pokemon go that single free to play zero skill game.
Scott: That game is big enough still that they could have a convention and get people to show up.
Scott: and not only that.
Scott: but they had Smaller not super, you know There's only one event in Chicago was actually endorsed and supported by Niantic the company that makes You know Pokemon go.
Rym: but there were other sort of semi official Maybe real events around the world all the same time and it was a disaster for the reasons that like I don't know how Professionals everywhere especially like nerd professionals at a game company fail at this.
Rym: they it's sold out like right away.
Rym: So they had a long time between when they sold their stupid tickets and when the event happened To plan for this and at no point did anyone say hey What's gonna happen if all these people show up in a park and try to use their cell phones?
Rym: and yeah, nothing worked.
Rym: No one could.
Rym: no one could play Pokemon go Pokemon go fast all the events that they had.
Rym: they had to fake the results because no one could actually play at all And because it was in a park they couldn't even do the kinds of things that like big convention centers or sports arenas do because those usually involve having Wi-Fi antennas up in the sky pointing down in limited cones.
Rym: You'd have to get you know Deployable equipment and spread it around but the the method that is the most effective at giving a large Numbers of a large group of people in a small area service won't work if you can't put the antennas above them.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: this I've seen these things like I've seen like AT&T deploy these at like events is basically a box.
Scott: Yeah has a generator in it But it also plugs in and it has this big stick coming out the top with a little thingy on it And you basically bring a whole bunch of these to like a music festival or whatever.
Scott: Right and they set them up all over the place.
Scott: now it actually works But you have to tell them this is happening and they did not so they could have like that.
Scott: You know if they were smart they could even like called like Verizon and t-mobile.
Rym: I think there's a difference though.
Scott: I've gotten like a partnership and a sponsorship.
Scott: There is a very important difference.
Rym: Unlike normal events This is an event where?
Rym: Literally everyone is going to be using a lot of data on their phone the entire time.
Scott: you think people are using a lot of Data on their phone or all the entire time in a music festival.
Rym: I don't think 90 plus percent of them are at any given moment for the entire concert.
Scott: No, but the number of people the music festival is much larger.
Rym: Usage is being bigger than most music.
Scott: How big was this thing?
Scott: I had another website actual number on turns.
Rym: Well, it's only one day event.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: The point is I'm pretty sure right.
Scott: They tell them how many people they could have handled it, right if they call them They just didn't even think about it or do anything because they're morons.
Rym: I actually don't think they could have handled it because of how much data.
Scott: I think it's definitely possible Because of how much data.
Scott: that game is just a fire festival situation.
Scott: people don't know how to run an event because there's so many things involved in running an event that you you need this Extremely large body of knowledge to handle all these different areas from like first aid stations.
Scott: You know fucking toilets.
Scott: You got a handle, you know, there's vendors.
Rym: No, but here's.
Scott: so here's the other thing.
Scott: So much shit, you got a handle Stuff.
Rym: they didn't even handle the basic stuff.
Scott: They literally right just like fire festival.
Rym: It was like well, no fire festival was a scam.
Rym: that wasn't a matter of not.
Scott: I'm just saying people running an event who don't do all the things necessary to run the event because they don't know all the things necessary To fire festival didn't even do anything.
Rym: that was just a scam.
Scott: I'm pretty they did some stuff.
Scott: It was just a mega.
Rym: an event wasn't even prepared.
Rym: So like all they're like all their stuff like the rooms you could render over were just fake like it was just all fake.
Scott: I don't think it was a hundred percent fake Pictures of stuff.
Rym: Yeah, I read a lot about the event.
Scott: Also the tumbling con with it with the with the On ball pit.
Rym: Oh dash con was.
Rym: it was what you're describing.
Rym: it's just a better example.
Scott: They're all the same.
Scott: They're all.
Scott: it's basically an event.
Scott: It doesn't have all the things an event needs but you're missing.
Scott: how the thing is if you have it a big event if it's big Enough if you're missing even one thing you just ruin everything Everything.
Rym: so there were four our lines to get in because they never at any point considered How they would get all these people into the park.
Rym: no one that they knew the exact number of people would show up and You can calculate how many people get through a turnstile at a time and they literally just Couldn't even make that happen Didn't
Scott: even think about it because they had no event running experience and they didn't hire someone to help run the event or anything Like that - that would say hey, you know You need to think about how to get the people in the park Like it doesn't you know, if you've never done something it doesn't cross your mind the things involved in it.
Scott: It's true for everything in the world.
Scott: Someone goes into like a wood shop and they never made or anything out of wood before.
Scott: they just start doing it with no Experience or studying or knowledge or preparation or help from anyone and there's gonna be so many things they overlook.
Scott: They're just gonna make this fucked up thing throw it out and learn some lessons and start again.
Scott: but if that first time you do it is In some practice piece of wood where you don't care.
Scott: It's the real deal with thousands of people.
Rym: That's a big fucking problem.
Rym: The thing is from what I can gather they did have professional event people.
Rym: I think it's just even people in this profession.
Scott: find out who those people are and don't hire them for your event because they're fuck-ups.
Scott: but the moral is.
Rym: there's a real fundamental moral here and the moral is Don't ever make an event that relies on cellular networks or Wi-Fi full stop Because if you're at a large gathering of people you must assume that the internet will not work.
Scott: And if you are hosting a large gathering of human beings You must assume that it will be an internet dead zone.
Rym: Even if it's in like the middle of Tokyo or something The Penny Arcade Expo did once an omega-thon finale that involved Wi-Fi just on the stage and it couldn't work.
Rym: It could not work and they knew exactly what they were doing.
Rym: if they can't make it happen No one can.
Scott: however that convention center now has perhaps the best conventions that are Wi-Fi I've experienced.
Rym: However, the method that it uses to provide that is a method that literally cannot be deployed in outdoor arenas.
Scott: It can if you've deployed many many boxes that have long tall sticks on them that aim down Which I don't think has ever been deployed.
Scott: that system is a music festivals.
Scott: I've seen it with my own eyeballs.
Rym: No, so that this is a thing.
Scott: they have that.
Rym: Did you read the paper?
Rym: We linked to on the BCEC system.
Rym: It's a stationary system.
Scott: It's not the thing you're thinking of for music festivals and is a you can deploy Something that will give everyone service.
Rym: Are tightly targeted to some shockingly small geographic areas inside of the BCEC.
Rym: Anyway, don't if you went to Pokemon go fest I don't know what you were expecting because it's what could possibly have happened.
Scott: I mean if you're a sad person who's so sad that you're playing Pokemon go like that?
Scott: You deserve what you got a Pokemon go fest.
Scott: Maybe it'll teach you to not waste your life playing Pokemon go.
Rym: Well because well, I mean it has its purpose that it got some people to walk around outside.
Scott: I feel like I want to make a bad game that gets really popular.
Scott: get everyone to come to an event and then use the Whole event to be like look this whole thing was a trap guys.
Rym: That's just the plot of the wave.
Rym: only with Nazis Mmm, that's exactly the plot of the wave.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So in some other news that people are shockingly mad about Microsoft is killing MS paint.
Rym: So what a lot of people are really mad about this is another.
Scott: there's a new paint thing in my in Windows now that just old paint is also there Although nothing more than update to Windows is removing MS paint.
Scott: So, you know what right now if you're upset about this is what you do.
Scott: paint is one file.
Scott: paint that exe.
Scott: Even if you don't save your copy of paint that exe it is readily available on the internet.
Scott: So I'll not a copy of paint dot exe.
Scott: put it like on your fucking desktop or whatever and just double-click on that Motherfucker whenever you want some paint.
Rym: So the most amazing thing is I was reading comments on reddit slash dot.
Rym: people are actually mad about this and the primary complaints are people who claim to use it professionally in their day-to-day work and Yet for whatever reason like never thought to use a real Application.
Scott: paint on point.
Scott: paint on net is free free zero dollars and they make ridiculous arguments about.
Rym: but my computer's locked down So I can't install anything.
Scott: quit your job.
Scott: get to go to her real work.
Scott: Well, if your job requires you to be able to draw terrible pictures and ask IT and say I need to be able to use A paint program in order to do my job.
Scott: I cannot do it without a paint program.
Scott: You've removed MS paint.
Scott: Give me a paint for also I'd realize or I cannot do.
Rym: I realize pretty quickly.
Rym: a lot of the people complaining Don't realize?
Rym: the snipping tool exists and has existed for a long time and they use it what they use MS paint for this.
Rym: I think this is the majority use case.
Rym: is they hit print screen and then they paste the print screen into MS paint And then they crop it because they literally have never heard of the snip tool that's been around for a long time.
Scott: Yeah You know what?
Scott: I do on my Microsoft Surface.
Scott: I take them the pencil and I click the eraser area because it clicks in Yeah, and then this thing shows up on the right side of the screen and one of them says Screenshot sketch or something like that.
Scott: So I touch it and now it has a screenshot of my screen already in a paint thing and I can doodle on it or crop It or whatever.
Rym: I do one better.
Rym: Just hit the windows key type snip.
Rym: Yeah, I did the wrong one.
Rym: But anyway windows key Snip and you get the snipping tool and you can literally just get an arbitrary screenshot Yep, and you can doodle on it.
Rym: Yep, and then I can copy to my clipboard Save it as a file.
Rym: I could even email it.
Rym: I guess like directly.
Scott: Is it what hat people?
Scott: many people learn a way to do something?
Scott: Yeah, as long as it gets the job done.
Scott: people except nerds don't give a shit about efficiency.
Scott: They really don't.
Scott: very few people care about efficiency or learning anything new.
Scott: They have a way of doing a thing.
Scott: They hate learning so they keep.
Scott: they want to be able to just keep doing things the way they do them for the rest of their entire life and Never have to learn anything new ever.
Scott: and that these are the people that I do not respect and would not hire and do not Want to work with ever.
Scott: so I could pretty much do job interviews and just be like, you know Would you be upset if there was a new way of doing a thing?
Scott: or like test someone in some way to see if which?
Scott: Kind of person they are?
Scott: I just hire all that even if they don't have any knowledge or skills.
Scott: if they're the kind of person Who wants to improve their way of doing things?
Scott: I know that that person will be able to do any job pretty much.
Rym: But the other thing is from a like pure just software perspective I think it's probably good because I would rather the OS like this doesn't seem like a necessary function of OS is anymore to have a Drop picked a.
Scott: I wish my my drawing application.
Scott: I think it's I think it's problem that Windows fucking comes with anything, right?
Scott: It's like they pre-installed all this garbage, right?
Scott: It's like you get all the it's like the Cortana and stuff.
Scott: It's like give me Windows that comes with fucking nothing.
Rym: That's called Linux.
Scott: I'm just saying right that's called Linux.
Scott: They could make Windows that comes with absolutely nothing.
Scott: No one wants that.
Scott: I want that.
Rym: I don't even want that.
Scott: cuz how many to you and Steven if you clean install Windows these days Right clean install.
Scott: you have to go uninstalling a bunch of shit like what like nowadays if you install the Windows 10 recently.
Rym: Yeah, I remove some stuff.
Scott: I think they put like the knowledge the Cortana.
Scott: they put like Candy Crush installer OneDrive, please get Microsoft Office.
Scott: annoying thing.
Rym: I don't sell the Microsoft Office thing.
Scott: the whole big fat start menu full ads.
Scott: You got to get rid of.
Rym: Yeah, just let him be there.
Scott: You just let the ads be there.
Scott: yours.
Scott: I time ad block.
Scott: you let ads in your start menu.
Rym: Just let him be so my start menu is up for however long it takes to type the name of the application.
Rym: I'm just saying I just didn't even buy.
Rym: remove.
Rym: Are you that simple-minded that it bothers you that much?
Scott: Oh, you're the person who says block all ads ever is now saying it's okay to have ads.
Scott: Yeah in your fucking start menu Yeah, okay, uh-huh are these actually ads?
Rym: though what is?
Scott: yeah Those are actually all ads.
Rym: by the thought that that picture of GeekNights is an ad there's a lot of ads in there.
Rym: I'm just saying that's not an ad.
Scott: there's.
Scott: there are things in there that are not ads but many of them are.
Rym: but more to The point that ms.
Scott: Paint really only is added in the start menu itself.
Rym: because in the era unless you remove them before internet operating systems like a computer with nothing on it had to be Amusing and reasonably functional.
Rym: even if you never ever put a disk in it installed software.
Scott: No internet.
Scott: Where would you go and get software from?
Scott: you had to go to the store and buy?
Scott: Software.
Scott: and if you bought a computer and you just set it up and you turned it on if it didn't do anything useful It's like it's like an old Apple computer.
Scott: You got to put it in a program, right?
Scott: It's like what.
Rym: but like people would like you needed a bunch of games in a computer because an average family most family members We have no reason to use a computer.
Rym: So you pretty much needed to have amusements built in but nowadays We don't need that.
Rym: But you do need some other things.
Rym: like you still need a web browser to come with the OS.
Rym: it makes sense for a web Browser to get built in.
Scott: it should be Chrome or it should turn on and let you choose which one you want.
Scott: You know rather than including IE that you use actually Windows today comes with fucking two web browsers edge and Internet Explorer.
Scott: Jesus fucking Christ.
Rym: that doesn't really bother me though.
Scott: It doesn't bother me, but it's like are you serious?
Scott: Remember really now?
Scott: and you're just using one of them to install Chrome.
Scott: So for a normal person actually Firefox has improved a lot.
Rym: 90% of what they do on a computer is a browser recently like the past few weeks and the other 10% of it is some sort of like email app and For gamers, it's like steam 20%.
Rym: steam 70% browser 10%.
Scott: me when you guys seem in Chrome like you're done Yeah, what else you need unless you actually do things with your computer.
Rym: I mean, I got audition running Some people have Adobe stuff.
Scott: Yeah, I got OBS running over there.
Rym: But yeah, people are shockingly mad about this and I find that really fun.
Scott: We'll get mad about fucking everything.
Scott: That's how they do every time.
Scott: people get mad about some software changing like Twitter redesigned ravel ravel ravel.
Scott: This did it ravel ravel ravel.
Scott: and I go lol get with the program.
Scott: life is things are gonna change Constantly for the rest of your life.
Scott: if you're gonna ravel every time Just die already like why.
Rym: so another really quick news here Snopes the website that long ago told us whether or not there was rat meat in our chicken nuggets.
Rym: if we were too stupid to Just assume there isn't.
Rym: mm-hmm Appears to be in trouble, but it could be fake.
Scott: I need Snopes to tell me if it's not fake or not, but where would we check?
Rym: How do we know?
Scott: Snopes is still up right now.
Rym: Yeah, you can read this.
Rym: I'm not not gonna we're not news We're commentary.
Rym: my hot take is that I I don't think nopes does not have good I.
Scott: if this is true and it is a hundred percent the people at Snopes are Morons when it comes to fucking computers, we should look at other website.
Rym: looks you have you like that.
Scott: might you have no business?
Scott: running such an important website?
Scott: if you don't if you just Let basically pay someone to take care of all your computer stuff if they lost their DNS Like.
Scott: I really need Snopes to continue to exist because it's an important resource.
Scott: But I have no sympathy for the people who own it losing their livelihood if they fuck up because they fucked up.
Rym: But if they're in so much trouble, how are they about like the people who run their website holding them hostage?
Rym: How have they been able to put the save Snopes banner to donate on Snopes because they still have access to like the admin of?
Scott: Snopes, you know in the CMS Yeah But they don't have.
Scott: it seems like they either don't know or don't like have access to like the DNS the actual servers.
Scott: You know the anything like that, so they can't actually like, you know do any.
Rym: so I got a guess.
Rym: This is an uninformed pure guess on my part.
Rym: I suspect that they are dumb and they did the penny arcade of Accidentally sold their company or accidentally gave someone else rights and that is the real problem here.
Rym: I'm sure I feel like the people who run their website own part of like own the IP in some way to where They are being extorted and it's kind of their own fault.
Scott: I mean if that's a guess doesn't know I mean I Do know is that I don't know anything about the legal aspect or who owns what.
Scott: but the point is if you don't know enough About technology and you have valuable technology people who do know about technology can hold you ransom Yep, and it is not really much you can do about it even with legal resource because they just delete all your shit.
Scott: Then what?
Scott: Yeah, you've got a Law can't bring back the data.
Rym: You gotta hire someone who knows what they're doing But you don't know how to vet the person right.
Scott: what they should do is they should Start by backing up their shit.
Scott: And if they don't have backups, they should scrape that shit.
Scott: Yeah, and then just try to save your DNS.
Scott: if you control your DNS record You can just point it in new fucking servers and you don't need to worry about your hosting company there.
Rym: Just stop paying them, but I feel like if we ever find out what happened back there I imagine it's a really pathetic drama mess.
Scott: just from reading this I can tell you the people at Snopes are not not guilty or not not negligence Yep, and now we're not giving them any money.
Rym: We're not saying that the people Allegedly holding them hostage.
Rym: They might also they might be evil.
Scott: Oh, yeah, but I'm still not giving confident.
Scott: Yes, but I'm not giving any money to incompetent.
Rym: I'd say let's just make Snopes.
Scott: and the problem is the value of Snopes is important enough that someone as soon as this message went Up someone has already scraped it.
Scott: So I am and not worried at all about losing the.
Scott: The Snopes with.
Rym: the value of Snopes is primarily in the investigative journalism and the data not the name or anything else.
Rym: right this point exactly.
Scott: so they could even just start up a new site Snopes - and As long as it's all their trademark then it.
Scott: then they can call it Sin seppone or something.
Scott: Yep, and just host all their recaptured data that they probably you know, and whatever.
Rym: So we'll see where this goes.
Rym: I am NOT donating money until I know what's going on.
Rym: Yes, much as I like Snopes I do not trust.
Scott: donate your money to the Internet Archive.
Scott: instead who will archive Snopes?
Scott: Yeah, and knows about and they know about computers very much.
Scott: They are talented IT professionals at the Internet Archive.
Rym: So this is your news even though you've asked me four times today what your own news is.
Scott: Yeah, I guess I forget.
Scott: so check this out.
Scott: This is some VC garbage startup.
Scott: Somewhere is making like They're making some bullshit.
Scott: That's not gonna work.
Scott: You know typical Silicon Valley nonsense get but what.
Rym: but the what they're doing is Because the kind of thing that could undermine open source consumer software.
Scott: They have this technique that that they are using to which market their shit.
Scott: I'm not gonna say their name because it would market them.
Scott: So what they're doing is step one hire someone who is The maintainer of a popular open source thing.
Scott: For example, they hired someone who is the manager of a plug-in for the atom text editor Which is the text editor that's made by github, I believe and is a very popular text editor.
Scott: So they hired someone who made a very popular plug-in for Adam and then in hiring this person They I guess they couldn't force them to do it But I guess the person did it of their own free will possibly because a bunch of money showed up who knows.
Scott: but this person worked for this startup and Then as after they were hired by the startup They merged in a patch into this plug-in that effectively added what amounts to Advertising for the startup they now work for.
Scott: that would be like if I merge some.
Scott: you know I was working.
Rym: I don't know you were gonna patchy and you merge like you just merge in all these like ads for GeekNights into the comments Of all those modules and scripts, right?
Scott: It's like that's basically what they did.
Scott: the details of this happened.
Scott: At least there's at least two recorded incidents of this and perhaps more Because they only have so many employees right and those employees only have so many existing popular open source projects in their portfolios.
Scott: but Yeah That basically means people are just innocently using this open source project not realizing the person who maintains It was hired by an evil company and modified it.
Scott: and now when they update they get this evil update.
Scott: So yeah now people who actually care about these projects have to go and like fork them Because depending on the license and remove these evil patches and also find people to now be the maintainers because the original maintainer is in The pay of the evil people.
Scott: exactly so and that maintainer you can't trust any software They make ever because they're a person they basically ethics they Lenovo'd at that point.
Scott: Yeah, that person anything that that person works on ever even after this startup goes out of business, which it will Is now a tainted person?
Rym: No, they're doing.
Rym: I trust them.
Rym: It seems like their plan is to do this as far and wide as possible.
Rym: and from a cynical perspective I mean, it's clever because the kinds of people who maintain like these types of open source projects often need the money It's and their salary is way cheaper than legitimate advertise.
Scott: It's a clever technique to market, right?
Scott: It's like who?
Scott: I wouldn't have thought of that.
Scott: but your market you're making tools for developers.
Scott: Right who are the smart people?
Scott: and now you're burning the bridge with the customer.
Scott: But it would be smart if you could use this kind of technique to like Let's say you hired the people who work on VLC.
Rym: I was about to say name into the stuff that normal people.
Scott: Yeah, then the people using VLC.
Scott: Well don't know any better, right?
Scott: It's like oh, there's an ad in VLC now god damn Oh, well, right smart people will stop.
Scott: but most of the people using a VLC don't know better.
Scott: But if you're going for dev tools like the atom text editor or the Python auto-complete Which they also now people who said that shit up for developers, you know better, you know fooling them.
Rym: But it does show a very a power a profound weakness in the open source movement as a whole in that Some projects are important enough to the fundamental fabric of technology and the modern world Like the Linux kernel that there is in that there is plenty of money and funding and people to keep it going.
Scott: Well, also is these kinds of also projects that are large enough like that aren't you know?
Scott: Linchpin on a single person.
Scott: even if Linus Torvalds dies Or Greg koa Hartman dies or turns evil, right?
Scott: It won't affect Linux They will just kick that person out.
Scott: even Linus Torvalds can be kicked out of Linux if he does if he fucks up too much Right, but imagine like so some really important Apache module or some bright work.
Scott: It's.
Scott: the vulnerability is in projects that have a lar Relatively large number of users and a relatively small number of maintainers which could even be one maintainer.
Scott: And then that person that single person becomes compromised in some way and is now, you know they're deploying software onto all these people's computers around the world the thousands of developers and
Rym: It would also be a great way to start sneaking malware in if you were a bad person.
Rym: because the reality is Most people who download open-source software download binaries and run them without thinking about it or a lot of people do curl pipe.
Rym: Exact I mean even if you compile it, did you actually step through the code?
Rym: No, you'd of course you didn't.
Scott: no one does.
Scott: Yeah, you can make a Python module and put it on pi pi and if someone pip installs it You can make a node module put it on NPM Installs it you can make a deb and to put it up somewhere and someone can apt install it.
Scott: and If they don't look before they install you got them.
Rym: But the weakness to installing.
Scott: these are the
Rym: kinds of projects where you know The economy's not great and it doesn't look like it's getting better for the average person which you know Obviously, especially
Scott: someone who's writing software in their spare time for free meaning
Rym: that there's a lot of economic pressure on people who maintain these projects to either quit maintaining them to get a job that pays food money or To take money from this evil company.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So We'll see how quickly this blows up in this terrible company's face And we'll see if there becomes a trend of other people trying to Ransom hostage or otherwise compromise open-source software.
Scott: This company will live as long as it's VC funding keeps it alive And then that'll be it.
Rym: Yeah, just like all other startups I definitely do want to keep tabs on whoever funded this.
Scott: and The point what you should do is look at all the open-source software you use that's actually somewhat important and Go and if it's not a major project, you don't worry about vim, right?
Scott: Right, but it's yeah some plug-in you're using or something.
Scott: All right, go and check.
Scott: Well, you know what?
Rym: What the deal is with it, like I use the hell out of notepad plus plus to this day, that's fine You can trust that right pretty sure I can.
Scott: yeah, you can trust it.
Scott: But like for now, you know check the I guess heritage what you know, the what's the word?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: There's a word for there ends an edge For the provenance.
Scott: check the provenance of yours not an edge.
Rym: That's not the proven edge.
Scott: No, it's not.
Scott: You should know the provenance of all of the the little things that you're installing for free to make sure they're legit.
Scott: Just check them all once and well and then once.
Scott: if you check everything you use now once Then you can now easily check everything you add in the future.
Rym: Another thing is well if you work for a company, this is more important.
Rym: if you are a company that uses open source software Someone's job should be to periodically vet the open source packages.
Scott: You're using Yeah every time and then don't update them without checking again.
Scott: Yeah, also Another general rule that I follow a lot of people don't is just minimize how much stuff you use.
Scott: I see people they got like, you know a million fucking plugins in their vim and the firefox and all these add-ons and it's like I use as few as humanly possible just Because you you know, you you keep your attack surface area down.
Rym: Yeah But anyway things of the day.
Rym: so in case I didn't drag Pokemon go fest enough from a like poor planning perspective this video is a super cut of how bad Pokemon go fast really was.
Rym: it's someone just took actual promotional video that was filmed at Pokemon go fast and it's great because you see these MC's who are clearly professionals trying to Not react to the crowd as a crowd of 10,000 people is chanting things like we can't play and Kind of losing their shit.
Rym: It also interestingly really highlights how bad an idea Pokemon go fest as a Like as a concept was because of how non interactive the game actually is Mm-hmm the fest like you.
Rym: if you watch this video You'll see the kinds of events and the kinds of things they're doing.
Rym: There's no content you can provide to people at an event like this other than like a place to hang out with the other people Who do the thing?
Rym: because the game is not actually interactive in any meaningful way.
Rym: No and You see that by how desperately they had to stretch The kinds of events that they put on at the event and then had to fake the fact that none of the events actually worked.
Rym: Mm-hmm, but to their credit these people Super pro emcees like remember when he fucked up that late show and there's that moment where the two of us look at each other For a second because we don't know what to do.
Rym: That never happens.
Rym: They like power through it to the end bonus points for the fact that they keep trying to coin all this like pro gamer terminology around Pokemon go a Game that has literally zero skill input.
Rym: Mm-hmm they they have these cut.
Rym: they kept these phrases like savage season, which is a Technique you can use to one shot a Pokemon and it's literally made up bullshit.
Rym: and this one guy is like Committed to acting like.
Rym: this is a thing real people say in the real world.
Rym: Mm-hmm It's just fascinating to watch this.
Scott: I mean shit like this isn't new Yeah, but this video is pretty.
Rym: this video is a lot like all those long shots of the ball pit at.
Scott: I got an actual technology thing of a day here.
Scott: So the first RAM today.
Scott: people don't know how RAM today works.
Scott: RAM today at least as far as I'm aware.
Scott: Maybe things have changed since I learned about how RAM works.
Scott: But as far as I know SD RAM that we were using like DDR one It's still the same principle just way way way better.
Scott: It's basically sort of a really fancy circuit breaker with really tiny tiny break Yeah, and then you basically just like the circuit breaker in your basement Imagine just like a bajillion fucking tiny switches now go click click click.
Scott: They're electronic obviously with no moving parts But and back in the day the first ever RAM right?
Scott: How the fuck did it work?
Scott: We had vacuum tubes.
Scott: that wasn't really RAM.
Scott: That was the transistors of the vacuum tubes and the computer would just compute.
Scott: you had the input and the output.
Scott: There wasn't a lot of storage besides a flip-flop, right?
Scott: Which is a register That's not RAM.
Scott: RAM is like an a memory that is external to the CPU That is addressed by the CPU and read to and written from written to and read from right?
Scott: Not a register that the CPU is using to compute.
Scott: the first ever RAM ever Was not the fancy circuit breaker DDR kind we have now.
Scott: It was this thing called core memory Which if you look there's a million videos about this like you can make it yourself Right memory or memory plane and you can make some yourself.
Scott: The way it works is you basically sew with thread Strings a mesh and on the vertices of the mesh are little donut Magnets tiny magnets that are donut shaped and you send electricity through, you know the edges right a lot of the you know, the on the side through these strings and The when you know, you hit certain vertices with the electricity the donuts physically flip around like And from some of the side you can write and some of the side you can read.
Scott: you can flip the donuts and you can read which way the donuts are currently flipped by, you know, seeing what comes out and it was The thing is it was prone to error because physical donut things moving around.
Scott: So it was lots and lots of error correction going on to avoid that and sometimes the computer would crash if those error and you had to start over.
Scott: but you know It wasn't nearly as bad as it was before the invention of this stuff.
Rym: So core memory was extra fascinating because the way you actually made it there were never hand.
Rym: Well, yeah Because there were never efficient machines to make it.
Rym: and lots of people like in the fin during the Cold War like the early 50s their job was to basically knit RAM to using computers, right?
Scott: So here's a video with a guy who worked on the team that made the RAM talking all about it.
Scott: It's fucking fascinating and he has the RAM and he can show it to you and it still works today.
Scott: Just slow as balls.
Scott: Yeah slower than your hard drive with moving discs in it Probably slower than like a 1.44 floppy drive Really slow.
Rym: so in about a moment the book club book was Dune Frank Herbert's.
Rym: we finished it the episodes up.
Rym: go listen Enjoy, we talked about Dune.
Scott: We're probably gonna watch the Dune movie.
Scott: That's supposed to be hella bad.
Rym: Yeah, we're gonna watch the Dune movie and then you it.
Scott: yeah, and then I guess the new book club book is the fifth season Not C's own season right as in a season like spring winter summer fall and then a fifth season after that.
Scott: Oh my god Stupid smarch.
Scott: Yeah, that's a month.
Scott: That's not a season.
Scott: This would be like Falter By NK Jemisin.
Scott: this book is like the hot shit in the sci-fi fantasy Genres of recent years.
Scott: all her books are but this is like.
Scott: that seems to be the main Starting point for this author.
Scott: So that's where we going.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: You can see I already bought it.
Rym: I bought it when Scott announced it.
Rym: He has to update the website and we'll do it Probably after the prince of nothing book comes out.
Scott: Yeah, cuz prince of nothing is gonna come out in tomorrow.
Scott: Yep, supposedly Yeah, and we're gonna read that and then we're gonna start reading this book club book.
Scott: Yeah Otherwise, are you starting the book club book in like three days proud?
Rym: Yeah, something like that.
Rym: I'm pretty much gonna read the prison.
Rym: nothing like probably before that bike ride like on the train up.
Scott: I'm gonna read it in the tent while I'm waiting for the bike.
Rym: Yeah So, yeah.
Rym: Otherwise, I'd like Scott's YouTube channel as a ton of stuff and my youtube channel has a ton of stuff and together They're like the entire cannon of GeekNights video Except for a few videos that are orphaned on an account that for complicated reasons We can't access anymore.
Rym: But I'm just gonna scrape them all out and stick them on my youtube channel just so I can control them.
Rym: Hmm and yeah, otherwise the next convention we're gonna be at is Pax West the real Pax.
Scott: the tickets are in that my friend just got his tickets in the mail.
Scott: Mine might be in my mailbox right the fuck now.
Rym: I booked my flights today.
Scott: Oh, I booked him while ago.
Rym: Yeah, you know what Delta was actually cheaper than jet blue.
Scott: I feel like I've been booking flights too early and I could save money by booking later.
Scott: So I'm gonna start booking later.
Scott: I'm waiting for the PAX South flights.
Scott: I didn't book him yet.
Rym: Probably PAX South is way too soon.
Scott: Yeah, I'm gonna wait.
Rym: I read you is for domestic flights two months for international flights three months.
Scott: I read a few things online.
Scott: I couldn't tell if they were true or not But I figured there's no reason not to at least give them a shot.
Scott: They said 47 days is the ideal time.
Scott: So 47 days before PAX South.
Scott: I'm gonna go try to buy tickets and see that prices I mean, I said alert if they're higher than they were before.
Scott: Oh, well, and if they're lower, oh, okay I guess they weren't lying to me.
Rym: I actually do use kayak mostly because I found that at least for a while.
Rym: I mean, I can't.
Rym: I'm not saying I endorse them and you know those kinds of sites come and go all the time But right now they're the ones I use because I booked a lot of flights And I had pretty good luck with them.
Rym: Like they've never overcharged me and I pretty much always find the best option.
Scott: I've used it before.
Scott: Yeah, in fact, it's a little janky the way it works, but it works.
Rym: Well, the problem is I always have to uncheck EWR cuz I'm not flying out of Newark Fuck you.
Rym: Yep, and I have to uncheck like Gatwick cuz I'm not flying to Gatwick if I'm going to London.
Rym: Fuck you.
Scott: Well, I mean actually, you know if the flight is like serious enough flight and you're saving enough money?
Scott: Never true you can get to EWR not too bad.
Rym: I would have to save at least five hundred dollars before I would even consider going to EWR.
Scott: No, cuz it doesn't cost five hundred dollars to get there back.
Scott: Get to get to Newark.
Scott: It only costs like an hour of your time an hour.
Rym: if there's minimal traffic.
Scott: I know.
Scott: what do you do that my traffic?
Rym: Well the last time I Jersey Transit goes there and all at 24 hours a day Jersey Transit The last time I flew to Newark for a work trip.
Rym: I took a cab actually Fucking cab because the company just set it up.
Scott: for now You can take Jersey Transit to get to Newark 24/7.
Scott: So no matter when your flight is you can get there.
Rym: Also Penn Station so much right now.
Scott: I wouldn't trust that because like it depends when your flight is right.
Scott: if your flight involves a rush hour trip Maybe not.
Scott: but if your flight is like oh get to eat get to Newark early crack of dawn on Saturday.
Rym: It's also just like the times I flown there.
Rym: It just kind of sucks.
Rym: I mean, it's not as bad as LaGuardia.
Rym: Don't get me wrong.
Scott: No, but already is the guard is the worst but at least I can basically walk there.
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Scott: well, I guess okay.
Scott: I'll go here occasionally.
Rym: Third sixty six percent of the time that I have landed at LaGuardia in the last year I have walked out of the airport because transit was fucked and there was no other way out Mmm, and I feel real bad for people who don't have that luxury.
Rym: And actually it's a pretty nice walk.
Rym: like you walk out of LaGuardia and eventually you get on like, you know There's a couple streets.
Rym: You can take.
Scott: I take toward my home when I've landed LaGuardia Usually take a cab home and I've been lucky that that has worked.
Rym: Yeah, two of the times I landed there.
Scott: I have.
Scott: I have now learned how to use the select bus service.
Scott: I'm gonna try it.
Rym: Yeah, the one time I had trouble there.
Rym: The traffic was so bad The select bus couldn't get into the airport.
Rym: I learned how to use like busing so I walked out and I caught the local bus that does kind of the same route from outside the airport.
Rym: Hmm So, uh, yeah.
Rym: So this topic I think is worth.
Scott: I feel like we've talked about this so many times.
Scott: It feels like either in news bits and also we did an episode on it.
Scott: He's already said everything we got to say but but it's important enough that we could say some more.
Rym: also some like some things have legit changed in this topic in the last year like there is.
Rym: There are changes to best practices regarding passwords and the last show we did where we definitely talked about This is the main topic was
Scott: two years ago, which is not that long ago
Rym: But we called it don't share your password and I'm
Scott: sure that in the discussion of passwords We said everything there is to say about pass But I think
Rym: I feel like we mostly talked about all the people who like have they share Passwords with each other which and I think that is a really common practice now
Scott: Do not
Rym: do all the streaming services
Scott: never do
Rym: even though as I say that For a long time.
Rym: We were logging into Emily's parents crunchyroll account because yeah, they shared their password But I just have my own account now because I didn't know that that was not maintainable.
Rym: that a lot of reasons.
Rym: But obviously don't share your passwords don't make your password hunter - but NIST Which is an organization you can the national different standards and technology or something something like that.
Rym: Yeah, they issue guidance for things is a good way to describe them.
Rym: Yeah Technology and science things and they've changed a lot of the best practices around how you should manage passwords.
Rym: So I think we should do a quick refresh on in 2017. how should you deal with your passwords?
Rym: and the answer is not?
Rym: To use a service where you give them your passwords and then they log into your sites for you All right.
Scott: well To give people credit using one of those services like last pass or one pass or whatever.
Rym: those fucking things are Last pass might be the safest one.
Scott: I don't know I don't know which one's good and which one's bad because I don't use any of that garbage, but They're better than the regular whatever, you know, they're better than like doing nothing and doing some crap.
Rym: Yeah, if you're bad at passwords, definitely use something like last pass.
Rym: It's way safer than whatever garbage you're doing now, right?
Scott: It's like it's got its problems.
Scott: I wouldn't trust it, but it's like for your mom.
Scott: It's like if your mom is just gonna like make her password like the name of the pet With like a number after it.
Scott: Yeah, then your mom would be helped by last pass.
Scott: It's still better than that.
Scott: So, okay But otherwise if you actually have anything you care about protecting for real Like your steam account that has thousands of dollars with the games in it.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Do not use this.
Rym: Oh god YouTube in the background is just looping terrifying stew letters animatronics on this tab.
Scott: Okay anyway.
Scott: So the reason that they are bad is some of them are like storing your passwords encrypted in the cloud somewhere.
Scott: So now it's theoretically possible.
Scott: someone could like get your passwords because they're stored somewhere.
Scott: It depends even if your passwords are only stored on your computer.
Scott: They're stored.
Scott: They're written down.
Scott: They're in a place where they can be stolen from.
Scott: the password should not exist anywhere other than your brain.
Rym: So think of it.
Rym: like you're saying you've got 20 keys to all the different buildings you go into on a daily basis.
Rym: what these password services do in the best-case scenario is they give you a box and You put all your keys in that box and then you lock that with one key And then because physical analogues don't work that one key now magically has the properties of all those other keys Meaning if someone steals that one key they can get into all your buildings instead of just the one.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So what should you do?
Scott: well, if you I've said this before in the show for sure, but if you have something super secure and Super important you need the best password.
Scott: There's a thing called dice where and that's what you should use.
Scott: you roll some fucking dice And it brings you up a big-ass long sentence full of words.
Rym: This protects you from random number generator.
Scott: It's relative key logger attacks.
Scott: It's relatively easy to remember.
Rym: Well, I guess not at use key logger attacks, but at create generation keylog attacks.
Scott: It will generate for you an amazing password that is super secure.
Scott: that is relatively easy to remember compared to its secureness and You just remember it and it's awesome.
Scott: And so anything you really care.
Scott: I'm gonna.
Scott: I've been slowly trying to convert every single password to dice Where?
Scott: But you know, I have so many passwords.
Scott: It's sort of an ordeal.
Scott: Yeah So here's other things that I use right now that are pretty good.
Scott: Right?
Scott: So I use a thing called Super super gen pass.
Scott: Oh, yeah So super gen pass.
Scott: the way it works is you remember one password in your brain only right and you might be going.
Scott: Oh, no, I'm typing my password into the shady website.
Scott: But no, I've looked at the source code for super gen pass.
Scott: It's not that complicated.
Scott: There's not that much in there and it's a hundred percent JavaScript.
Scott: It runs totally on your computer and sends nothing anywhere, right.
Scott: and The way it works is you type in your password and then you type in the domain of the website you need the password for and it uses math that I'm not going to explain to combine that one password you remembered with the Domain of the website to generate a unique password for that website And that's the password you actually use on that website Meaning
Rym: even if you're using the same password in your brain and say that website Just stores your password clear text and their server gets compromised.
Rym: the password that was stolen is literally worthless.
Rym: It's not any other website, yep If I can you become.
Scott: you're effectively using the same password in every website.
Scott: You have to remember the one password but You're actually using a different password on every website and all you need is this little bit of code and the domain names To sort of combine the password you remember with the domain to get the real password to log into that site.
Scott: Yeah, now your passwords are not stored anywhere.
Scott: No one can like find your password by like stealing some files or decrypting anything or anything like that.
Scott: They if they break into that website while they broke into that website, but your account is you know gonna be fine, right?
Rym: No, I actually do something very similar, but I just do it in my head.
Rym: I have an algorithm I can follow in my head based on sure.
Scott: It's less mad and mathematically rigorous.
Scott: Of course.
Scott: It's some fancy hashing?
Rym: It is definitely not but I feel like it's sufficient.
Scott: I mean we've talked about it's probably sufficient the level.
Rym: It doesn't take much how crazy you are about passwords and security and all these things Opsack is just what's your level of paranoia and what's your level of acceptable risk versus convenience?
Scott: Another thing I use is called password card.
Rym: password cards are real good.
Rym: I recommend this to anyone who I think is too dumb to use a more technological solution, right?
Rym: So smart enough to realize that they need a solution.
Scott: the way password card works is you go to this website password card and you randomly generate a password card, right and they've made hundreds of thousands of password cards.
Scott: and then you print it out and it prints you this nice little card with symbols and numbers all Over it right.
Scott: and then you go to a website and you need a new password.
Scott: or you got a new account You need a new password.
Scott: You look at your password card and you say which combination of these weird symbols Am I gonna use for the password for this banking website?
Scott: Maybe I'll start at the dollar sign and go down to the right Diagonally and then back up in a v-shape and I'll use those symbols, right?
Rym: Okay I've never gone that complex with my password card usage.
Scott: I'm just saying that's an example Right of something you might do and you remember because the bank website to start at the dollar sign and to go in the v-shape.
Scott: Because whatever you just have to remember that little bit.
Scott: you just remember a smaller piece of information Which is where on this password card is my password?
Scott: Which is easier to remember than the actual crazy password full of symbols and nonsense.
Scott: And then you'd pull out your password card and you look at it and it's like having your passwords written down on a paper.
Scott: But unlike having your passwords written down on paper no one can take the paper and Figure out your password because they take this paper and it's a fucking jumble of nonsense and they don't know where on this piece of Paper your password is.
Scott: it's just a jumble.
Scott: It means nothing to nobody except you.
Rym: if you use it naively It gives people a bunch of low-hanging fruit guesses as to what your past.
Scott: Yes, if you're like, oh well my password to the banking website is start at the dollar sign and go straight down.
Scott: Yep Don't do that.
Rym: But here's the more.
Rym: this is where we're gonna deviate from the shows we've done in the past.
Rym: This in particular is a good case study because it still generates the kind of entropy focused unintelligible passwords that hitherto have been considered secure and NIST has issued updated guidelines and basically the best practices today are to not use Passwords like this and instead to use pass phrases because that way you don't need a token.
Rym: It goes back to being what passwords originally are Something that literally only exists in your brain and only comes out of your brain when you're entering it to authenticate.
Rym: Yep So what?
Rym: NIST has basically been issued a whole bunch of guidelines and these were earlier this year and there's been a lot of debate about it, but the idea is that humans are not good at remembering a random string of uppercase and lowercase ridiculous characters and You'll actually generate more entropy by just typing a very long password that consists of words.
Scott: Yeah, if you just have a ton of lowercase letter think about it, you know, okay, so one character, right?
Scott: You're using 26 letters of the alphabet.
Scott: Okay, uppercase and lowercase and you got eight characters.
Scott: So eight times 26.
Scott: Well 26 to the eighth power possibilities.
Scott: It's a lot of possibilities, but not for a fucking computer.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: no no, no, so You could increase the number of characters you allow.
Scott: allow hyphens question marks plus minus divide.
Scott: Okay, so now it's 40 to the 8th power.
Scott: Okay How much bigger is 40 to the 8th power compared to 26 to the 8th power?
Rym: and you really gonna remember T uppercase V You that weird double s squiggly underscore.
Rym: underscore 9 1 1 8 4 uppercase T.
Scott: You know, what if you want I I I you just take 26 to the 9th power the 10th power the 11th power the 12th power Your complexity is going to increase much much more rapidly than it will allowing more characters, right?
Scott: So just between uppercase lowercase and space you've got 53 characters, I guess, right?
Scott: Yeah, you don't need to include anything else.
Scott: 53 characters to the very long sentence that has you know, five five-letter words.
Scott: That's now 50 something to the 25th power and all you have to remember is a sentence with five words.
Rym: And let's say let's say do you stuff you remember like?
Rym: let's say I'm really into Tolkien.
Rym: So I use a really lot.
Scott: like I use a Tolkien quote You can write looky mighty right and it's like.
Scott: looky mighty is already a great password because it's like a ton of letters.
Scott: But if you write the whole fucking thing, like my name is Ozzie.
Scott: Mandy is king of kings.
Scott: Look upon my works ye mighty and despair.
Scott: That's hella long.
Scott: You can always remember that.
Scott: look I just quoted it and Nobody's guessing that in a million fucking years.
Scott: Yeah, that is super secure password.
Scott: I feel like if there's someone your name is Rym and that's what people are gonna guess Day one, but if you're like guess number if your name is not Rym, no one's guessing that yep.
Rym: So this wants everyone to increase the maximum length of passwords to at least 64.
Scott: that sounds good to me which is perfect now.
Rym: I'd like to see what sentence are you not?
Scott: Yeah, why not?
Scott: 128 256.
Rym: well cuz right now you got a shocking number of sites.
Rym: limit you to like 16.
Rym: Yeah That's awful, which is not enough because actually the passwords that I use today that I algorithmically generate I decided not to use passphrases because so many things I log into.
Rym: don't let me have long enough passwords for that.
Scott: Yeah, that's a super problem.
Scott: That's the number one thing keeping me from a hundred percent dice where besides laziness is a lot of sites I can't because they don't allow my password to be that long.
Rym: So another no reason is to have no Composition rules.
Rym: do not require people to use uppercase and lowercase right now.
Rym: require numbers.
Rym: Do not require symbols.
Scott: think about this.
Scott: if you have it Let's say you have a two-letter password right and you require uppercase.
Scott: Well now you've actually just decreased the possibilities.
Scott: the search space of all legal passwords is now smaller.
Scott: Yeah, you might.
Rym: it's like sure even if you get up to eight twelve That has three digits on it and you have a rule that says no two digits can be the same that it makes it way Easy to figure out your pick combination.
Scott: Yeah, they just removed a lot of possible combinations.
Scott: So even though you might be allowing someone to have a stupid password like password That still forces the person who's trying to guess the password to go through every possible guess.
Scott: They can't just eliminate all these guesses like oh this one doesn't have uppercase.
Scott: Don't even try it.
Scott: This one doesn't have a number.
Scott: don't even try it, right?
Rym: So they basically say have a minimum and have a very high maximum.
Rym: Yep, and the minimum minimum is eight now, which is fine.
Scott: It is good, but I'd make the minimum like 12.
Rym: Yeah, I would make the minimum higher.
Rym: Yeah but 16.
Rym: I'm on this website.
Rym: that I think is a summary of some of the news Guidelines and make sure you allow spaces because that's what allows phrases.
Rym: They say it very succinctly here favor the user.
Rym: Make your password policies user-friendly to put the burden on the verifier not the password user Mm-hmm, and the verifier is not gonna have any more or less trouble with a long quote from Tolkien than it will from a long String of unintelligible characters.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: So, you know the basic dictionary stuff, but the no composition rules is a big problem because so many things require ridiculous bullshit in their passwords Mm-hmm, and that's like.
Rym: as a result I still like my not everyone's following these guidelines.
Scott: In fact few people are following these guidelines.
Rym: I have had let's just say in a professional capacity Large Very well-funded institutions that require this bullshit.
Scott: who has really really awful password practices?
Scott: American Express.
Scott: Yep, American Express forces you to use a tiny garbage password.
Scott: Yeah, it's like for something that should be very very secure.
Scott: your fucking money.
Scott: Don't use American Express.
Rym: So Amtrak for a long time.
Rym: I don't know if it's changed.
Rym: I still use my weird old password.
Rym: there had so many Requirements that I could not make any of the algorithms I used to generate passwords work with it.
Rym: So I basically for a while made a throwaway password and did an email password reset every time I had to log into their site.
Scott: That's not a bad system.
Scott: In fact for a while, that's basically two-factor, right?
Scott: Mozilla was like bullshitty - Mozilla was using was developing this thing that they said I was gonna use but they Closed it because it was called persona?
Scott: I think no.
Scott: and it they closed it because it didn't get enough traction.
Scott: But actually I thought it was gonna be great because basically what it did is it did exactly that.
Scott: it's like oh well password You know email reset is the thing.
Scott: so what we'll do is we'll just when you log in we send you an email you go to the email and click and now You're logged in for as long as the cookie lasts.
Scott: and that's it.
Scott: No bothering with stupid passwords Just email email the thing only if that lets you reset.
Scott: Why not?
Scott: Just let it have it log you in.
Scott: and then it also included some fancier ways to let you log in because the idea would That you would you know open ID was the was now also now dead which would be I had an open ID.
Rym: Yeah, it's tied to a Yuba key that no longer works.
Scott: Yeah Open ID was a thing.
Scott: for a while The old Yuba key until the login with Google login to Facebook login with Twitter Oh off took over instead.
Scott: Yeah But the idea would that be you would be log into.
Scott: you would set up your own sort of off server with you know Sort of open ID way.
Scott: log in do it with the persona and your open ID fashion with the email.
Scott: So no, you didn't even type in a password.
Scott: All you did is you guess you login you did your email you click the thing you're logged in and then when you go to other websites That uses Oh off to connect you in.
Scott: so you never had to have a password anywhere and just log in everywhere with your one persona login at that one place that you completely control.
Scott: Yep, and that never came to be so.
Rym: some of the other guidelines and these are more for people who are developing all systems Never allow people to use password hints nor require them.
Scott: looking at a lot of websites Yep, how you go to win even Microsoft Windows?
Scott: Yeah, you can have a password hint on the screen.
Rym: It made me type something.
Rym: Yeah, I typed the word fuck.
Scott: I just left it there work I just type.
Scott: I forget what I type.
Scott: you said whatever.
Scott: Yeah, nothing.
Scott: Nothing helpful.
Rym: Knowledge-based authentication is obviously a terrible idea.
Rym: This is usually a problem with password recovery.
Rym: Like what was the name of your favorite pet?
Rym: What's your mom's middle name?
Scott: Someone can some someone can find out my mom's middle name so I don't actually type my mom's middle name there I type something else.
Scott: Yep So if someone finds out, you know, they can research and find out my mom's middle name or my.
Scott: you know Pets name or what?
Scott: School, I went to so I always put something else there Which is helpful, but probably the most important one.
Rym: if you run a system Never people never require people to change their passwords and never expire passwords Unless like my work which expires them all the goddamn time.
Rym: Oh my god, don't even get me started about some LDAP nonsense I've been dealing with recently.
Rym: Yeah, but two if you're a user of passwords, which I hope you are Don't just rent the.
Rym: don't change your passwords regularly pick passwords and use them unless you have a reason to change them Like a site was compromised.
Rym: Yeah, if you change your passwords frequently, you're more likely to forget them and have trouble Mm-hmm.
Scott: And if you're more likely to forget them You're more likely to use a less good password, right if you if you have some super long sentence But you type it a hundred times a day every day forever.
Scott: You're gonna remember it forever.
Scott: It's gonna stay secure forever.
Scott: Yep, it's the math means they need like a billion years to guess it until the quantum computer is invented So don't you don't have to change it except for every billion years now.
Rym: I guess the important gist of this is that all the things you should do to make your passwords better are Not really supported by a lot of the things people need to log into Mm-hmm, which is a problem.
Scott: Well a good thing you can do for example is like I was talking before about the login with Google login with Twitter login with Facebook.
Scott: yep, a lot of those places like Google will allow you to have the real deal password.
Rym: Yep, Google password, which is the literally the most important password in the world, right?
Rym: It's a really long password.
Scott: So use those things if you have the opportunity because then even if some website is real shitty and doesn't have good password policy You don't need a password on the website.
Scott: Just log in with Google and since your Google safe your web your account on that site is safe and you're good You don't need a password there.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So the other interesting thing is that I mean we've talked about two-factor before and obviously you should use two-factor wherever possible.
Rym: Mm-hmm because the concept of passwords in a real secure environment is increasingly obsolete Because while it may be a token that only exists in your brain in an ideal world.
Rym: The reality is they are trivially compromised by key loggers malware Hide-resolution cameras.
Scott: It's always possible that someone could still get my password.
Scott: What if like someone's in one of the you know?
Scott: I'm not gonna close my window every time I type my password right.
Scott: maybe somebody in an adjacent building It's a super long zoomy lens and zooms into my fingers and records in slow-mo high def and they see me type in the password.
Scott: it's like there are ways to get someone's password no matter how fucking good the password is if you're Going through enough effort.
Scott: so if something is secure enough and valuable enough that more likely someone is to go through with the effort to get that password and They can get it.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: So that's Starbucks with the security camera typing your password on your laptop.
Rym: Yeah What I say the other day if you live in a building that has a doorman or work in a building as a doorman That doorman probably knows the unlock code to everyone's phones.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: What are you doing?
Rym: You're an elevator.
Rym: You open your phone.
Rym: look at Twitter for the 30 seconds It takes.
Rym: yeah, you might say oh, but I use my phone.
Rym: I use the fingerprint.
Rym: That's even easier to get.
Scott: Yeah, touch.
Rym: Did you touch anything?
Rym: In fact, I only steal.
Scott: you have it.
Scott: I have it set to where the fingerprint will only open it after a very short locking period After a long locking period like I actually put the phone away.
Scott: I need to type up password again.
Scott: Yeah, not some pin not a swipey thing with lines Android actually typing in a real password on the phone.
Rym: Yeah, because What do you touch your phone with?
Rym: primarily probably your thumb or your fingers?
Rym: Your fingerprints are all over your phone and I've seen there's been many proofs of concept of extracting those fingerprints Printing a 3d model on rubber or something and then just open in a phone.
Scott: But anyway, you need the two-factor because someone can get the password.
Scott: But to get the password and to also get a physical thing that you possess in your possession is very very difficult Right.
Scott: Oh they zoomed in with the zoom lens and they saw me typing in the password.
Scott: This is the security camera.
Scott: the Starbucks recorded my password when I was typing it in and they don't have my phone because I own It.
Scott: it's in my hand right now.
Scott: They didn't rob me and mug me.
Scott: Oh the mugger mugged me.
Scott: He's got my phone, but he didn't.
Scott: he's not the same person who stole my password.
Scott: so you to do both things in the level of difficulty there is so high and The things that you a GeekNights listener have are so not valuable that it's so not worth it.
Scott: Yeah, if you have a two-factor you safe, you know you very safe as an aside.
Scott: safe, but so safe.
Rym: one of the other changes is that they have formally Obsoleted the idea of using SMS as a second factor.
Scott: Looking at you looking at you twitch and Fucking Twitter Tumblr Fuck all you dude support.
Scott: Oh off you I have a Yuba key.
Scott: Let me let me use my fucking you know Google authenticator app.
Rym: I have you.
Rym: I could literally plug my Yuba key.
Rym: I have a physical token.
Scott: I plug into USB plug it into your phone.
Rym: Uh, you can if you get the RFID one, you don't have the NFC one You don't have that one.
Rym: I could get that one.
Rym: Actually you can do three factors.
Rym: So there is a way.
Rym: if you have an Android phone It won't work on iPhones because Apple won't let them because a lot of dumb reasons for that.
Rym: But you can get a token a physical like token that has RNG stuff in it with NFC And you use the Google authenticator app on your phone and a password.
Rym: the authenticator app Can't generate the numbers unless you have the RFID token against your phone.
Scott: if I ever have a company everyone has to do that.
Scott: Yeah, that would be.
Rym: that would be like if the company did anything that mattered.
Rym: Yeah I'm not doing that for our convention.
Scott: No, I'm talking about for like the bank or the you know Expensive shit.
Rym: Yep So, uh, but they you can.
Rym: SMS does not count as two-factor right now.
Scott: You might think well, wait a minute.
Scott: Wait a minute.
Scott: What's wrong with having someone just text me the code?
Scott: That's the same as emailing me the code, right?
Scott: No, it's not and this is why I'm using Gmail.
Scott: right in order for someone to get in that Gmail They had a hey Google.
Scott: They need the really good password and the end the Google authenticator app for my phone.
Scott: They ain't getting in there to get my email or they have to break into Google's nonsense.
Scott: Good luck breaking into actual Google and all that shits encrypted on their servers.
Scott: Anyway, yeah, good luck.
Scott: So so SMS one.
Scott: what happens?
Scott: what it's clear.
Scott: Someone sends me a text message.
Scott: It's not encrypted.
Scott: that text message can be spied upon on the network Especially if I'm getting wife text over Wi-Fi or something, right like use an iMessage or who knows what.
Rym: now that is Obscurity because it's like sniffing.
Rym: that kind of traffic is a giant pain in the ass, but it's possible And it's not even that hard.
Scott: and that text message doesn't originate like on some phone system.
Scott: It originates on the internet and then it only hits the phone system like near the when it gets close to me and that whole Area, it's unencrypted and snoopable on the internet.
Scott: All right, not only that But it has been proven that the customer support Services at all of the phone companies in the United States, especially but also probably other places are very susceptible to social engineering.
Scott: I could trivially with what I know about my friend say Rym Call his phone carrier t-mobile, which I know because I'm his friend.
Scott: Yep and convinced them that this phone I just bought is rims new phone and they should begin to send all of rims phone calls phone number and text messages to this phone that I just Bought at the store.
Scott: and that rims phone was lost stolen fell in a toilet.
Scott: something like that seems implausible.
Rym: I had to call t-mobile a while ago because my data plan literally stopped working SMS work, but data didn't and at no point when I was like Changing Sims.
Rym: Did I have to prove my identity to anyone?
Scott: So I'm sitting there trying to log into rims tumblr and it says oh by the way We just texted you a message for off And I go Oh rims using two-factor.
Scott: Let me just take this spare phone Call t-mobile get rims number ported to my phone in ten minutes and then log into team log into tumblr again and Okay.
Scott: Now the OAuth was the message is sent to this phone and I logged in and the two-factor was worthless.
Rym: now the art.
Rym: Some people multiple people when I was talking about this back when this guidelines like the the request for comments period was going on Had a counter-argument and their argument was yes SMS two-factor is insecure But for the majority of people it's one better than nothing and two by deprecating it You're harming all the people who are too poor to have a smartphone You
Scott: Should be sending you you.
Scott: first of all, they're very very inexpensive smartphones available these days that are cheap.
Scott: Yeah, they're cheaper than flip phones.
Scott: like to get a phone that can run the Google off app You don't even need data.
Scott: You can get iPhone one.
Rym: Remember the Google off app does not need data to work.
Scott: You know iPod touch?
Rym: it generates the codes on the phone.
Scott: You can get some old they should.
Scott: Google's just make little tiny things that do the off app.
Scott: That's all they do and to they'd be like five bucks.
Rym: I would argue that Giving someone a false sense of security is way worse than them.
Rym: Just having bad security.
Rym: uh-huh, if you think the door to your house locks and you don't realize that like Literally anyone could open the door and only you don't realize this That's way more dangerous than you being afraid that someone's gonna open your door in any right.
Scott: if you have a door with no lock On it.
Scott: It's like all right.
Scott: Well, at least I know I'm not safe.
Scott: I'm gonna sit here with my shoddy.
Scott: Yeah, but if you have a door you think is locked I'm told no one getting this safe.
Scott: It's fucking Fort Knox and then someone walks the fuck in.
Scott: you're a shoddy across the room.
Rym: now imagine you're pooping in a public bathroom and you think the stall is locked and Someone just opens it and is standing there and pees on you.
Rym: Yep, which happened to a friend of mine at band camp.
Scott: But if you see the lock is dark.
Scott: If you see the lock is clearly not functioning on this stall and all the other stalls are occupied though You can hold that shit close at the finger.
Scott: You got options when you know.
Scott: you got to be in the know so people They got to know.
Scott: if you use the text message off You at least got to let people know so they can hold that close with their finger.
Scott: So
Rym: my advice to you just so we have a moral because we gave you a lot of advice that a lot of websites won't Let you actually do is other than all the stuff like to do
Scott: the best you can do Whatever you can do it to the best of your ability.
Rym: use passphrases that don't expire anywhere.
Scott: You can do things that are relative According to the value of what you are protecting and if something you didn't put full effort into protecting is stolen Oh deal with it.
Scott: That's your own fault.
Rym: And if you're in charge of a system a lot of you work in IT.
Rym: That's probably why you're listening to get nice Monday.
Scott: Follow these guidelines.
Rym: Yes, don't force stupid passwords on your users.
Rym: Don't expire their passwords.
Scott: and if say your boss if some if you have some stupid boss who's making you do something stupid Give them this document.
Scott: show them the guidelines.
Scott: be like.
Rym: this is what the government says to do.
Rym: That's what the DoD probably at least I hope does.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: This is the.
Scott: this is more secure than what we have.
Scott: You just don't know anything about security.
Scott: This is what experts say.
Scott: we're doing with the experts say If you don't think I'm an expert that means you don't value expert knowledge in which case you should quit that job Immediately.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: And in fact, you know what?
Scott: I'm gonna I'm gonna.
Rym: I'm gonna give you some extra credence Scott.
Rym: I'd like this job is legit, right?
Rym: I've been.
Rym: Scott should know security.
Rym: Otherwise like a big website would be in a lot of trouble.
Scott: But I never had a problem.
Rym: one of my formal roles and my current company is doing risk analysis and part of that includes writing and Auditing security procedures.
Rym: I am like I legit am in charge of that stuff for a company and I do it and I research It and you've had zero incidents.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well, yeah, I can say this any incident any incident that has ever happened has been due to someone not following a procedure or Circumventing something and the remediation of course is prevent circumvention or force people to follow procedures But fire people.
Scott: I would have zero tolerance for failing to follow you.
Scott: That's the one thing It's like if I had to work, you know people I whenever I talk about like yeah I was a boss.
Scott: I'd be like a million Lazy time on the beach.
Scott: Yeah, not giving a shit take as much time for lunch as you want right laziest workplace.
Scott: But if we were doing important work that had value the only thing I would be asshole about as a boss would be security stuff.
Scott: Yeah, you fucked up a security procedure.
Scott: I'll just have zero tolerance and fire you because you're a threat to the company.
Rym: Well on the same token, there's a difference between negligence.
Scott: I'd educate you in advance.
Scott: do lots of education up front I wouldn't just you know, but well, there is a difference between Satan negligence and gross negligence, for example Sure, but like if someone just leaves the fucking door open or yeah doesn't lock their computer when they stand up.
Rym: Oh, if someone doesn't like the computer when they stand up goatse is the appropriate punishment for that.
Scott: That's correct.
Scott: But that's also sexual harassment in the workplace, okay What can we use?
Rym: I'm sure I could come up with it up with a appropriate similar punishment a leak spin that doesn't go.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and brand Okay for the logos.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Rym: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons with this episode of GeekNights are Ellen Joyce Heidi McNichol Amanda Duchette and Thomas on my stady calm William Eisendrills, Jeremy minor.
Rym: Life and death and love and birth and peace and war on the planet earth.
Rym: a genuine bonafide electrified six-car monorail.
Rym: Nicholas Brandau captain Chinguac see Rebecca Dunn the terrible secret of space.
Rym: four to one creations.
Rym: That's because we're fighting each other.
Rym: Sherman von Horl rare Laval James David White Rochelle, Monta Nona Superboy, I paid five bucks to make Rym say pickle sailor Vista Matthew Smith Don Schleich Gajar tavishan joshiro jostar Sean Yeager Sam Corddry Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin drew open Lander Brian's Adroni Finn Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel Redman Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: you saw that I uploaded a rims rant to the patreon as an exclusive for the patrons about heuristics.
Rym: Emily and I recorded not one but two rimmly reviews.
Rym: That'll be up in the coming days as we start to get the pipeline going again.
Rym: Stay tuned for a post about the brand new Q&A.
Rym: stay tuned for some updates on some coming.
Rym: Ignites presents you ten episodes and I'm still trying to churn through that backlog of like a hundred board game reviews.
Rym: and now I leave you with Lovely and bright and soft.
Rym: She's a small Wonder a child unlike other girls.
Rym: She's a miracle and I grant you she'll enchant you oversight.
Rym: she's a small Wonder and she'll make your heart take flight.
Rym: Fantastic made of plastic Microchips here and there.
Scott: She's the small Wonder.
Scott: brings love.
Scott: Laughter everyone.