Rym: It's Tuesday February 28th 2017.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott and this is the ignites tonight the princes of Florence Which I've played at least one time.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So I had a light bulb that was out.
Rym: It was actually the last of the halogen spots in the wells in the ceiling.
Rym: over time Every one of those halogen spots kept burning out because I don't know the power is just bad up there or something.
Rym: So I've replaced them all with LED.
Scott: I mean when I removed into my apartment I replaced everything with CFLs, and I haven't really had to replace any.
Scott: yeah But I did replace them even though it's um I didn't have to.
Scott: they weren't great with LEDs because I wanted to yep, but I didn't do that for all of them.
Scott: They're still going.
Scott: so it's sort of like me on two of the CFLs.
Rym: one of them Just started being super dim, so I got rid of it and one of them just burned out.
Scott: I definitely had it one burn out at some point.
Scott: I think it was one that was from Beacon Days.
Rym: Yeah, but I got all LEDs now and actually they're real cheap, but because I was changing that light bulb I thought I should double check all the light bulbs in the apartment And I'm replacing.
Rym: I put replaced like there's a weird bulb that goes in like the bathroom like that is a different bulb from everything I was in the house for some stupid reason but There's this there's two lights in the bathroom and most bathrooms like a new building in New York.
Rym: you get that like top fill light for the bathroom and you get the like the bar of lights above the mirror and I only have the bar lights above the mirror.
Rym: I got both.
Rym: so the top one is like this ultra bright kind of annoying buzzing fluorescent thing and The one I never knew what the one in the mirror was that ever thought about it.
Rym: But I noticed when I was doing my light bulb rampage that the one Above the mirror was way dimmer than I remembered.
Rym: so I decided to open up thinking I wonder what kind of light bulb goes in there.
Rym: and It was the weirdest light bulb.
Rym: I've ever had to deal with except I in doing like studio lighting.
Rym: So I open it up and first off it's t4 lights meaning it's just fucking wires come out of the end of the bulbs Like not even like it doesn't have a mast or a socket or it's just like wires sticking out right - there's like four light bulbs in there and they're all different shapes and There's a whole bunch of text.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: And the text is like listen motherfucker These are not halogen lights.
Rym: do not put halogen lights in here.
Rym: These are not halogen.
Rym: These are xenon.
Rym: Why are they xenon?
Rym: because fuck you we're gonna be weird Mm-hmm.
Rym: xenon as far as I know is only used in two applications.
Rym: Like I never encountered a xenon bulb outside of a spotlight like the kind you'd use in a giant room like at PAX or Headlights and cars.
Rym: Mm-hmm Giant warnings pasted all over the inside of this fixture that I had never opened until today.
Scott: Is there like a model number on the fixture?
Scott: Like you could look it up or something cuz I had to buy a replacement filter for about the hood over my oven.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Scott: so I looked on the inside of it and there was a sticker and I looked it up online and actually I have the most popular possible kind of range hood and I went on Amazon and I just searched for range hood filter and the first filter the most popular filter Was the filter that I needed
Rym: is the grease filter in the top.
Scott: Yeah, that one right which I haven't replaced it.
Scott: I replaced it once and all the time.
Scott: I've lived there Every six months.
Rym: I just soak them in things to remove all the grease and put it back in.
Scott: I hadn't done anything to it since I moved in in 2009.
Rym: So I'll warn you there there's grease You don't know.
Scott: don't think that the person who lived there before me did so either.
Scott: Yeah, so it was quite an old filter.
Rym: I a while ago actually cleaned the grease out of just the innards of that whole range hood.
Scott: Yeah, I don't need to do that.
Rym: Yeah, I went in there.
Rym: There was a Shocking amount of grease like I want to say there was half a pint all told I'm not going in there.
Rym: Yeah, it's in there It's hanging out.
Rym: It's not good.
Rym: Someday.
Rym: It'll catch fire.
Rym: No, but uh, so anyway, uh, It says like 50 watt t4 xenon and a bunch of other shit.
Rym: So I paste that into Amazon like you do and All the results that come up look fine.
Rym: They actually look like the bulbs that are in there, but they don't actually say xenon.
Rym: They just say bulb.
Rym: so I get.
Rym: So I dig around a little bit and every one of these bulbs is a halogen ball.
Rym: The thing that the thing said do not put in me So I can't actually find this bulb.
Scott: So you go like the specialty bulb store in the city I could.
Rym: there's one in Chinatown that I don't know if it's still there But I think I'm just gonna like a Home Depot or that kind of place.
Scott: I'm sure that's close enough.
Rym: Yes, I'm gonna actually go to a place buy these light bulbs and I think I need six of them and the halogen ones They're like six bucks each.
Scott: so hey I'm just looking for regular but like bulbs that are bright, right?
Scott: I think I might need maybe one more lamp.
Rym: Well, what do you want bright like a spotlight or bright?
Scott: I want to make my whole apartment white like, you know Bright when the Sun is not.
Rym: so in terms of this room how much brighter do you want it to be than this room right?
Rym: Brighter how much brighter like twice as bright?
Scott: Well, I see all these shadow areas.
Rym: You don't want to see shadows.
Rym: Not really For your apartment.
Rym: I'll tell you straight up.
Rym: You need three fill lights like three Torsia style or two Torsia and then one like accent spot to get rid of like.
Scott: I already got two lamps.
Scott: I turned them on and it's still pretty dark because those are what CFLs?
Scott: no No, they're just LEDs, but what kind of LEDs?
Scott: just the normal kind the equivalent of a 60 watt regular light.
Rym: You need ones that go up to fill out bouncing off the ceiling in the walls.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: That is the way to go.
Rym: That's why it's torsiers are the things that used to be used for that.
Rym: now There are other ways but all those other ways are weird like that weird woodley one.
Rym: I was showing you on Amazon.
Scott: Yeah, this one the ones I have are just normal.
Scott: they have you know a lampshade around the side.
Scott: Yeah, you can't have that.
Rym: you're gonna have something like this like that weird LED thing just more And you need multiple of them.
Rym: I mean look our living room.
Rym: I got that giant halogen the one that's super hot.
Rym: I would need three of those to actually light that room up fully.
Scott: Maybe I'll get two and put one on either side of the TV and then move the lamp on the left of the TV to The back.
Rym: that's actually not a bad idea because you see I have the big one by the TV in the front.
Rym: I got the two dim ones in the back and that kind of rounds out the room.
Rym: Anyway, it's not light bulb nights.
Rym: It's GeekNights.
Rym: They got any news.
Scott: I do have a news.
Scott: so All the card games that I played the digital card game Hearthstone right netrunner, right.
Scott: the physical card game They're getting big changes are happening or rumored to be happening soon or are happening already.
Scott: They're rebalancing.
Scott: They're fixing the cards.
Scott: There's a new guy in charge of netrunner Hearthstone.
Scott: big changes going on.
Scott: they just Nerf some cards.
Scott: today expansion got announced all kinds of action and card game layers the pirates changes the ladder.
Scott: That's right, but the most exciting thing that I've seen is Someone some dude in the Parliament of one of the best countries this feed Where the Swedish chef is a Brahma?
Scott: And so is the king the king of Lundquist.
Scott: He's also from there.
Scott: The guys in the Parliament of Sweden.
Rym: so imagine Well in the Congress of the US, so just you know, this threat is already locked sure for reasons.
Scott: Anyway, imagine someone in the Congress of the US going on to twitch play in Hearthstone and Talking politics at the same time.
Scott: now I know of a few congressman who I could imagine doing that maybe like Jared Polis from Colorado or something, but Most I'd say 99% would not do this.
Scott: but in Sweden They have a guy who's doing that and he's gonna talk politics while playing Hearthstone And he wants to know about like how to promote eSports is a thing in Sweden And I know there's plenty of excellent Swedish eSports type people.
Scott: It's pretty, you know, they got the counter-strike and they got plenty of good action there.
Scott: so even though Not involved in Swedish politics.
Scott: I don't really care.
Scott: I kind of want to see this dude stream.
Scott: So I wish you know, we could get some of that action going on here and I'm surprised It wasn't Iceland first.
Scott: you think Iceland would be doing this first.
Rym: So the thread was full of Almost nothing, but hate speech and they locked the thread being like quote.
Rym: the number of hateful comments in this thread is too damn high.
Rym: It's cool.
Rym: This guy is streaming, but I'm locking the thread due to people being idiots.
Scott: What kind of hate speech would someone have to say?
Rym: Let's see.
Scott: I'm not one example.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I imagine it all got down.
Scott: It all got deleted.
Rym: Let's see.
Rym: So already liberal in Sweden day means libertarian and there's an argument about that nonsense.
Scott: All right, I don't know anything about Swedish politics.
Rym: So it looks like it's just libertarian arguments.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: It is everything else probably got downloaded.
Scott: It is the internet I mean who.
Scott: I don't even know what the politics of this guy are.
Scott: He could be a crazy conservative nut job for all I know but is still a politician in office playing Hearthstone.
Rym: So I saw most of the comments here actually deleted.
Rym: So I'm pretty sure someone went and just like deleted whatever hateful stuff was in here.
Rym: So a long time ago, do you know when we kick-started this?
Scott: You remember without looking kickstarter was extremely new like brand new Like it must have been the first if not second year of kickstarters existence.
Scott: So I'm gonna say like we were definitely living in not beacon, all right Well, so it had to be 2010 2011. so I'll say this.
Rym: I don't know when the kickstarters started.
Rym: I guess I could go look up when I backed it, but the Anticipated delivery dates was September of 2014.
Scott: Oh, so I was actually way too early on my no That's when it was anticipated to be delivered.
Scott: So that makes me feel like it was kickstart in 2013.
Scott: Maybe I can't imagine they thought it would take more than a year even though they were wrong.
Rym: So, uh, I literally forgot this existed.
Scott: I didn't forget but I got it confused because other things along these lines were coming out true the whole time between 20 whatever and 2017. there were so many other things that I forgot that like.
Scott: no, none of those are this but River City Ransom Underground, which is a legit and Like officially licensed real deal sequel to River City Ransom.
Rym: It is both a spiritual successor and a successor Mm-hmm with the real team like they got the dude and I'm not gonna get into the history of these games.
Scott: Actual people who made River City Ransom 1 also made this game.
Rym: Remember those Technos games?
Scott: It's not some indie people making a clone even though I'm sure some of the people working on it were.
Scott: It wasn't just these people but the actual River City Ransom people worked on this River City Ransom sequel.
Rym: I was as a kid obsessed with Technos games.
Rym: Authentic.
Rym: Because primarily I had some Technos games But because of Nintendo power and the earliest of the internet I would occasionally see pictures of Technos games that never came out of the only ones we had that I know of.
Scott: Wasn't really Technos, but I mean there are games that said Technos.
Scott: we're talking about the ones with the same kind of sprites.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Scott: So the do super dodgeball River City Ransom and I think wasn't crashing the boys right.
Scott: crashing the boys though.
Scott: It's sportsy one Right.
Rym: I remember crashing the boys.
Rym: Anyway, I was I was kind of I rented that game a bunch, but I never actually bought it.
Scott: for some reason I've played that one the least of all the of all those.
Scott: Yeah, but there are many more than those three that were Famicom but not NES released.
Rym: Yep, but it actually Came out and I got a steam code.
Scott: I got a steam key in my email today.
Scott: I was like, whoa, okay Whoa, what's this?
Rym: I guess I can.
Rym: I can log into Kickstarter and put a check next to got it.
Rym: Yep The only.
Scott: I mean, I don't know if it's good or not We're gonna find out real soon because it's River City Ransom.
Scott: We can play co-op and then Rym.
Scott: I got to punch him first before he punches me.
Rym: I just want to point out that when I play co-op River City Ransom with anyone, but you everything's fine.
Scott: Yeah, because you see it's me and you come a guy.
Scott: It's I got a punch sky.
Scott: He looks like a bad guy.
Rym: So I think what it is is that you put yourself directly in front of my fist.
Scott: I didn't shoot you.
Rym: you want to run of my gun.
Scott: You saw me shooting the guy.
Rym: Why are you walking in front of my gun?
Scott: Officer I didn't shoot him.
Scott: You saw walk in front of my gun, right?
Scott: As I was pulling the trigger, you know, that's not on me.
Scott: But uh, I'm real glad this game came out because it takes me like no one else here walks in front of my gun.
Scott: It takes
Rym: a long time to make even a seemingly simple game and it looks like they put the Proper amount of effort into making this live up to the things that we liked about River City Ransom without Replicating the things that made River City Ransom suck because it was a Nintendo game from a long time ago
Scott: like grinding.
Rym: Yeah, they're
Scott: being way too short
Rym: Or way too long depending on what kind of person
Scott: you I saw a speedrun of River City Ransom is way short if you skip the night and
Rym: if you know how to fight all the bosses and like how to make them all appear
Scott: and you don't spend your time like we do trying to buy a bunch of items and you just pretty much grab this the Fist and just go to the end.
Rym: Also, just don't die.
Rym: So you always have a ton of money.
Scott: Yeah Oh, yeah, it's also good, but dying is like they pretty much just buy the stone fist and that's it.
Scott: You don't need anything.
Rym: I always use dragon kick.
Scott: I always like to use acro circus cuz we Suck though.
Scott: It does suck but we Best one was the one that was the point of playing.
Rym: if you're not gonna get a The one that lets you hold a weapon and do that with the weapon.
Scott: and I like to go get some sushi.
Scott: Yeah, I think it's a smile.
Scott: I was a freeze and I like to get to see the butts getting the spot.
Scott: some sauna.
Scott: But it's like most people if you want to speedrun it you can just skip all that.
Scott: Walk walk walk walk walk skip.
Scott: all the bad guys.
Scott: do only point you to punch the punch the bosses with the dragon the stone Fist and the game is over.
Rym: But yeah this game.
Rym: I'm gonna guess that it's gonna be great, but we're gonna find out.
Scott: who knows I don't know.
Scott: I've been burning my stuff like but hey, it's out and that's a lot more than you can say for other games No, which are not out.
Rym: but anyway things of the day.
Rym: This is a compilation video, but it's very important right now because it's a it's a good time and the hockey times Rangers are definitely going to win the Stanley Cup this year.
Scott: What's wrong with you?
Scott: That's wrong.
Rym: Red Wings Yeah, well The Red Wings might be ending one of them one of the more interesting streaks in modern NHL history and that they have not missed the playoffs in my entire.
Scott: They're making it sentient life.
Scott: Definitely gonna make it.
Rym: there is a.
Scott: There is a guarantee Guaranteed to make it.
Rym: they actually seem to have a better shot of getting into the top three of their As opposed to getting a wildcard slot because the wildcard slots everywhere are nuts.
Rym: right now anyway, it's hockey season and One of the greatest things about hockey is the empty net goal.
Rym: One of the best things about hockey is the own goal But one of the best best things about hockey is the empty net own goal.
Rym: So to make that even further only's not there.
Scott: you got an extra person on the ice more than the other team and you score.
Scott: I have the puck and you know, they can't defend all of you.
Scott: It's not like they got past you.
Scott: There's someone who's open cuz you got an extra guy and somehow you put it in your own empty net.
Rym: It's not like somebody snuck past and got it in like Crider seems to do shorthanded to other teams all the time lately.
Rym: But that and the thing is this isn't even just this video.
Rym: It's not just oh.
Rym: They pulled their goalie in the last minute and then they messed up.
Rym: the most of these instances are from a very particular thing.
Rym: that happens in hockey where There's penalties, right?
Rym: so like if you hit someone in the face with your stick or like you stab them with the butt end of your stick or Like all the stuff you're not allowed to do can't do that.
Rym: They will whistle and stop play and give a penalty.
Rym: However, if you are on the offensive meaning you're in the enemy team's zone and you have a chance to score and you possess The puck and the other team commits a penalty.
Rym: They're not gonna ruin your opportunity.
Rym: They'll put their hand up signaling that hey as soon as you lose possession of the puck We're gonna immediately stop play because there's a penalty on the other team.
Scott: So keep playing for now.
Rym: so because you know that the other team cannot touch the puck without play stopping You immediately pull your goalie, right?
Scott: Why not?
Scott: they can't.
Scott: they can't take the puck from you and score because as soon as they touch the puck with their stick That's it.
Scott: Play stops.
Rym: almost every one of these own goals is in that situation, right?
Rym: These are tied games or games that teams were winning up to this point.
Scott: in that situation It can only be an empty net own goal because it can't be a not own goal because if they touch it then it's the Play stops.
Scott: you could.
Scott: only way it could get in.
Scott: your empty net is if you put it there.
Rym: Yeah the I mean unless somehow When the referee dropped the puck no one touched it and it bounced and rolled all the way in.
Scott: Sure, I guess physically that is technically the referee is dropping the puck play is already stopped and the person is in the box.
Scott: Yep, so I can't have a face-off during a delayed penalty.
Rym: This is kind of amazing to watch because there's one where a dude kind of back passes to change lines And the puck just starts like slowly rolling toward the goal and no one notices right away.
Rym: It's good stuff.
Rym: So what do you got?
Scott: Ah, so I was watching the usual, you know, kpop Performances of the week whatever and I'm just scrolling through and I see one that's labeled Hakuna Matata and I'm thinking oh man, this is pretty great.
Scott: Someone I don't know who because it's written in Korean.
Scott: I don't read that shit Has performed a Lion King cover.
Scott: This is gonna be great.
Scott: Let's see who it is and and see if they're any good at it.
Rym: That is what I assume this was.
Scott: so I click on it and out comes this Amazing, dude and his girl with cat ears and some other girl like whatever.
Scott: and I'm like, alright this is clearly not the Lion King and I've never seen these people forever.
Scott: and They have.
Scott: their name is wall worry.
Scott: That's the name of their group Right.
Scott: I don't know all their names, but the dude his name is mr.
Scott: Boombox And the name of their song is Hakuna Matata.
Scott: I guess if you make it one word and take the space out of the metal and put in all caps Then you're not gonna get sued by Disney.
Scott: So whatever and this song and these people are Incredible, I mean is this dude like?
Scott: it's like he's Captain Jack of Korea But also at the same time he's like beatbox champion.
Scott: I heard that he like organized.
Scott: he won and now organizes the beatbox competitions over there.
Scott: This this is our kind of guy and he made this group to sing this amazing song and they're just sort of getting up.
Scott: They're like, we don't give a fuck.
Scott: Let's have a great time.
Scott: And I think they've seen like three performances.
Scott: But in this performance the other ones that seemed like the whole audience was girls and shit like teenagers who wanted to see actual kpop.
Scott: There's that one girl though, and they're all silent but in this performance they seem to have a fan in the audience.
Scott: He's like on full pterodactyl mode And it's incredible even more incredible than the other ones.
Scott: the top comment.
Rym: Oh my god Did any Wells hear someone in the audience scream, right?
Scott: Also the vibes I get from this are like full Eurovision.
Scott: obviously Eurovision doesn't include Eastern Asia where Korea is But maybe that's what the spirit of Eurovision is getting ready because Eurovision is way soon.
Scott: Yeah It's always in the spring and it's already March.
Scott: tomorrow when you're gonna be listening to this It's probably gonna be March where you are and
Rym: this at least reminds me of the older Eurovisions that I liked a lot because some of the newer ones have been a little too sentimental and serious And I'd rather get back to like
Scott: now people the new ride the new Eurovisions Most people are doing like, you know, really powerful Ballads of And it's like I don't mind.
Scott: sure if I don't want to hear that shit Bring me the crazy songs and the wackiness and the you know, crazy costumes and epic sex.
Scott: Come on bring on the good stuff.
Rym: Yep, the like that.
Rym: No one's watching Eurovision Forget that running camera dolly shot.
Rym: They did of spinning around the dude.
Scott: If it's not epic sex, I don't want it.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So I think they should send this wall aries, you know They should pretend to be like, you know, I don't know what country Bosnian or something.
Scott: So they can sneak in.
Rym: So in the meta moment the booklet book is Frank Herbert's dune dune.
Rym: a cuz we never read it.
Rym: find out.
Scott: We're gonna find out.
Scott: find out about it.
Rym: not John Carmack's doom Frank Herbert's doom, which I'm actually finishing the nude 2016 doom because I didn't actually beat it.
Scott: Oh, you didn't beat it.
Scott: Yeah, I beat it under the end.
Rym: now I really like the rocket launcher.
Rym: That seems to be a minority opinion.
Rym: I like the sniper You know, no, I have the assault rifle like max out headshots from a distance.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: I also have done.
Rym: However, it is real stressful to like pick people off from a distance cuz it's do like stuff keeps moving next to you.
Scott: Yeah, it depends on your level of violence.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Is it ultra?
Rym: Of course.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Rym: I'm not a baby.
Rym: I played dunes dunes before.
Rym: Actually, I'm thinking about live streaming.
Rym: it's been a long time, right?
Rym: I'm thinking about just start up doom 2 and just trying to play it on a live stream and see how far I get before I give up.
Rym: cuz it's been a long time.
Scott: I live stream.
Scott: the other day I played Zelda 1 because I was testing out.
Scott: I set up a new live stream setup.
Scott: It is so spice.
Scott: I don't think there's anything wrong with it whatsoever.
Scott: It's so good, right?
Scott: Because I'm gonna stream the switch when I get it Next Friday this Friday, isn't it this Friday?
Rym: Cuz I'm gonna be in London.
Rym: I think it was next Friday will be a pecs.
Scott: I think is this Friday.
Rym: That's gotta be so soon.
Scott: It's a show from Amazon.
Scott: I'm gonna stream Zelda right away, but to get ready I stream the oldest Zelda Zelda 1 and I don't know why.
Scott: I remember that entire fucking first quest and I can't remember like the name of a character in a book.
Scott: But I sat down to play and stream it and two hours later I fucking beat it.
Scott: Whoa, nice I was just like I died a few times and I was careless and I was you know I mean like I was messing with the stream while Octoroks were shooting me like that, but his robes get you sometimes Yeah, the great one boot.
Scott: one time I died this blue wizrobe came up on me and he's just like magic spell magic spell magic spell.
Rym: He did like.
Scott: I only had the white ring at that point the ring and he did like six hearts of damage and I'm like Oh, fuck me.
Rym: Yeah, there's nothing to do about that.
Scott: Yes, if I would have just turned to the right I could have blocked them all with a magic shield, but whatever.
Rym: No, you didn't get a like like to eat it.
Rym: You're good.
Scott: actually I almost got it eaten by like likes Many many many times and managed to escape.
Scott: like every time I'm like, oh well That's the end of my shield.
Scott: and somehow I escaped and still had the shield.
Rym: as a kid You'd always be like, how could the light?
Rym: how could you possibly get hit by the like like like it's so slow I'm gonna get you.
Scott: I managed to it because if you look I pointed this out when I was streaming.
Scott: they designed the rooms in Such a way.
Scott: the room with the like like also has the sword stopping guy.
Scott: So he stops your sword.
Scott: then you get like liked and you can't stab your way out and then when it gets really hard they Put like like sword stopping guy and whiz robe all in the same room.
Scott: You need the shield to block the whiz robe.
Scott: the guy takes away your sword.
Scott: you get like liked.
Scott: now You don't have a shield and now whiz robes on your case.
Scott: Yeah That's how they do.
Rym: I feel like maybe this would be a thing with the new streaming rigs.
Rym: We should start playing old games Like I'll just stream bionic command all the way through till I beat it.
Scott: I said, you know, you should go play bionic man.
Rym: Maybe I'll do the new rear or the old rear armed again.
Rym: cuz I think it was real good like.
Rym: Actually in retrospect like I would never get tired of that game.
Rym: Yeah Not the sequel though.
Scott: That was bad any other meta moments besides packs of the East.
Rym: So we're going to be not this Friday But next Friday in Boston at PAX East 2017 doing a panel at 6 p.m.
Rym: On Friday.
Rym: play dirty to win The leg ain't cheating ain't trying.
Rym: Yeah This panel keeps evolving as I work on the slides and I'm this one's gonna be fun.
Rym: I think I'm feeling this panel a lot.
Rym: It's not the highly technical panels.
Rym: We've done.
Rym: It's more.
Rym: We'll see.
Rym: You'll see My only advice to you is to not follow all the advice we give because you'll be a monster.
Scott: Don't follow that advice.
Scott: He just gave.
Rym: don't do what Donnie don't does.
Rym: does.
Rym: We may or may not do a show on This week Thursday unless we record it right after we record the show because I'm gonna be in London.
Rym: so if any of you somehow are in the financial services industry and are at the EMEA trading conference at Old Billingsgate in London on those buildings gate you're definitely a place.
Scott: that's in London.
Scott: There are no old Billingsgate Outside of the UK.
Scott: I guarantee it.
Rym: I think I'm staying it like I'm staying in Grace Church, which is right near there.
Scott: There's something Shire.
Rym: I will be in London at this conference and I need people to talk to.
Rym: so if you've somehow you're a nerd and you're at this thing Come to my booth and just like saying I'm not even giving a talk.
Scott: You're going you're just standing in a booth.
Rym: Yeah, I'm standing in the booth and going to meetings.
Scott: I ain't even giving a lecture at this one, man You know This is why you got to do have a game like netrunner because then you could meet this like the UK netrunner people when you Go there, but you don't have a thing like that.
Rym: Listeners in the past at like pubs and things just like get a drink and hang out.
Scott: listener is good But you could meet like a whole group.
Rym: Yeah, my game right now is overwatch.
Rym: Yeah Any of you who play overwatch with me if you're in London?
Rym: I'll sneak out of this thing.
Scott: I'm sure there's like a LAN party place.
Scott: You can go to like a PC, whatever.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, it's not you know, Japan where they have a bunch of them, but I'm sure there's at least one in London.
Scott: I'm sure there's at least one in New York City.
Scott: So dude in Australia Is there even one in New York City?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I assume so.
Scott: Is there a New York City PC place?
Scott: Otherwise,
Rym: I've been putting I'm still doing this all our board game reviews separated out as just their own things without all the like dick talk and stuff that happens before and after them and There's a giant playlist these on YouTube and I'm trying to put one up every day until Every board game review we've ever done is out on YouTube and a lot of people are watching these things.
Rym: So spread the love spread them around.
Rym: Also, is that it?
Rym: I think that's it.
Scott: and downtown flushing there's a place called Evo gaming.
Scott: I don't know if it's related to the fighting game championship Play, you know tournament, but I've heard of that place.
Scott: It's got 17 5 star reviews on Yelp.
Rym: Oh And I learned something interesting.
Rym: So two of the things I haven't uploaded yet is I got a review of spot it and our review of that shitty trigger game That they made.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: We did those reviews exactly one year apart on the same day effectively.
Rym: So we reviewed spot it because we found it the next year.
Rym: we reviewed the next and last game We bought from that company because that company only made one good game.
Rym: That game was called spot it.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So, uh See you guys at PAX.
Rym: Maybe I'll see someone in London and now we're gonna talk about the princes of Florence Which is not traders of Genoa, but it's pretty much even odds.
Rym: if you bring up either one of those games in my presence I'll assume you're talking about the other one until I see the game and remember right?
Scott: So traders of Genoa is the game where you can trade anything for anything.
Scott: Yep, princes of Florence is actually just normal euro game.
Scott: Yep, well not a lot of trading.
Rym: It's a normal like older euro game.
Rym: Yeah, cuz it's not real euro game.
Rym: It's not a cube pushing game No, like El Grande, which is even older, but it's also not one of the more modern like crank the machine games.
Rym: It's one of those like really tight euro II like multiple paths to victory.
Scott: every turn You get a couple actions.
Rym: There's like bidding and stuff have a really restrictive bidding system of some kind.
Scott: Yeah, well you go.
Scott: I think it's more.
Scott: it's like a power grid kind of thing, right?
Scott: We go around right like one, two, three.
Rym: Yeah, but it's it's a. it's not power grid in that the bidding is fixed.
Rym: You started 200 you go up in 100 increments, right?
Rym: But yeah Prince.
Rym: so the princes of Florence is a game from 2000.
Rym: So it's 16 years old But it's on.
Rym: it's a Kramer and all rich game, which you may remember from El Grande, which Really holds up as I'm starting to realize as I see people talking about it and playing it again in the modern era.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So, uh, this game is from the line of games that were some of our earliest German euro style.
Scott: Yeah I'm not sure what these games had to do with each other other than that They all came in the same box and had numbers on them and look like the Elia.
Scott: It was the big box game Alia big box like Puerto Rico and a bunch of games all come in the same looking box.
Rym: You'd see these all lined up.
Rym: a game company like it.
Rym: like you've got a millennium games.
Rym: Well, there's one with the mammoths on it Burgundy's actually in that list.
Scott: I don't know about the.
Scott: maybe I don't know but There's others.
Rym: there's also the small box, right?
Scott: But basically all these games can't.
Scott: castles of burgundy all these games come in the same looking box.
Scott: They're the same style Germany.
Rym: They're all numbered but you'll know them in the US because a lot of them were brought out by Rio Grande in the US.
Rym: Right and you got the numbers.
Scott: you can tell by looking at.
Scott: you're supposed to line them up on your bookshelf.
Scott: But what these games have to do with each other?
Scott: other than that, they are similarly complex zero games.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Yeah, like they're not made by the same people.
Rym: What's interesting though is many of them but not all of them and also I have not played all of them.
Rym: Some of them have never as far as I know been released in the US.
Scott: not all of them are equally good.
Scott: It's not something they range from bad to Puerto Rico.
Rym: So but all these like Kramer and all rich games and all these bit like there's there's all these games in this that I all associate together.
Rym: But part of that was that when I got into gaming a lot of these games were in game stores And there were the games that I was playing because other people are playing them.
Scott: Yeah, even in the early 2000s.
Scott: This was out in the u.s.
Scott: Did he do what to call?
Rym: Because that was a series of games that weren't I don't think Wolfgang Kramer made to come.
Scott: Yeah, did he?
Rym: Yeah, he totally did.
Rym: Okay, he did to call.
Rym: in those other games that were the set of three Maya to call and Java.
Rym: Make those all the mask trilogy, okay and Mexico Java to call right.
Scott: Did he make Java and Mexico also?
Rym: That's just a picture anyway, whatever.
Scott: so Prince of Florence.
Rym: so in this game the idea alternate names the increasingly inaccurately named mask trilogy.
Scott: So the you got.
Scott: you're all princes in Florence, right and you have domains.
Scott: Right, you know you got little.
Scott: I guess what would you call my house?
Scott: Yeah, you got houses the place where you live your estate, right and There's awesome people in Florence.
Scott: cuz hell it's fucking Florence, right?
Scott: And you want to attract these awesome people to come and live in residence on your estate Because then you'll be more awesome than them other princes like Rym.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: So pretty much whoever gets the most People living with them right is the winner and that's all the game is.
Scott: so all you do on your turn is you Basically can choose certain actions to try to improve your estate.
Scott: For example, you can add new buildings to your estate, right?
Scott: Like if if I have a nice art studio then all the artists are gonna want to come and stay with me, right?
Scott: Well Rym with his shabby estate.
Scott: Yeah, they don't want to go there.
Rym: Introduce a freedom to your people right.
Scott: if the people who live in my estate, right?
Scott: Like it's it's feudalism.
Scott: right.
Scott: effectively It's not feudalism.
Scott: It's feudalism.
Rym: It's not feudalism.
Scott: I give my people who live on my estate.
Scott: I'm a prince.
Scott: I'm basically the king, right?
Scott: There isn't a king telling me what to do and people on my estate follow my rules And if I don't give them freedom of speech, they got to shut the fuck up.
Scott: But if I decide you know what I want to give the people who live on my estate freedom of speech unlike that heathen Fascist Rym estate when everyone has to shut up all the time People are gonna want to come and stay on my estate, aren't they?
Scott: I think they are because it's a nicer estate than rims estate.
Scott: So basically you got to alternate between improving your estate and then actually getting people to live there.
Rym: Now the actual game like what you actually do.
Rym: if you ignore the conceit of the game.
Rym: That's one area where a lot of the games that are kind of similar and that it's a bunch of Semi unique or very constraining mechanics kind of all cobbled together into a system Mm-hmm, and you're just trying to navigate through the system alongside everyone else.
Rym: It's it's sort of like solitaire except that you interact.
Rym: one because you are acquiring Highly limited resources and two the primary way you get the most limited resources is through a very restrictive auction Mm-hmm.
Rym: So basically on your turn you'll there be an auction.
Rym: So so you put something up for auction for like 200 flooring and then you just go clockwise around the table.
Rym: You either pass forever or increase the bid by exactly 100 flooring.
Rym: So the things that you auction off there's only so many turns.
Rym: you do not play this game.
Rym: You play like seven turns and then it's over.
Rym: So basically you're going to win seven auctions and Take fourteen actions two actions per turn.
Rym: That's it.
Scott: That's the whole game and you got to play, you know You're only only once per turn.
Scott: Can you actually get a person to move into your place?
Scott: So if you want to win I won.
Scott: I had six guys move into my place.
Scott: So on the seven turns available in the game six of them I was able to score a dude and have him move into my estate.
Rym: you could theoretically make two But I don't know if I've ever seen anyone do it.
Scott: I did one a turn except for I think the second turn.
Rym: Yeah, there's definitely a turn.
Scott: I did not do one and so did the person who came in second place.
Scott: Yeah, everyone else did five or fewer.
Rym: So the game is good in that there aren't really other games like it and it is interesting.
Rym: but there seems to be a big point of contention among players as to whether or not the five player very playing the game with Five players is the best option as opposed to four.
Scott: This definitely is one of those games.
Scott: It's very different with different numbers of players because it has the old game Problem of they did not scale up the numbers of things a lot as players numbers changes.
Scott: Yeah, so as you have more players resources become more scarce and it changes the game drastically.
Rym: Well, like three player four player five player Puerto Rico.
Scott: completely different game, right?
Scott: But compared to say power grid where when you have more players and power grid you put up more starting resources So they don't run out and you use bigger maps that you don't fight it You know, you're.
Scott: equally you have as much fighting over space no matter how many players there are Yep.
Rym: So with a five player game the dudes to make the things which is like the primary point economy of the game.
Rym: There are not that many of them and you need them, right?
Scott: You might make an awesome estate But if you can't actually get the guys Cards of dudes in your hand you you know enough.
Scott: I actually had to fight very hard at the end of the game to get one more card So I could actually score.
Scott: I have a final dude to score.
Scott: Yeah When
Rym: we played at PAX what we saw is that the cards that were available were all taken up basically immediately And then as a result, the only way you could ever get another person outside of what was already in your hand Was - there's a card that lets you basically Take a guy that was already played by someone else instead
Scott: and convince him to come to your estate and leave.
Scott: So I convinced the guy to leave rims estate and come to my estate instead to score him Even though you'd already been scored.
Rym: So when you score the guys and this is actually a very interesting mechanic when you get these guys Basically, they have sort of requirements or not really a requirement.
Scott: They got preferences, right?
Scott: The art, you know if a guy has a certain job He likes a certain kind of estate, right?
Scott: If you have an artist studio the guy who's like a philosopher doesn't give a fuck.
Scott: He's like what use is that to me?
Scott: But if you got a library, he's like, oh, baby.
Scott: Yep I like that estate.
Rym: bigger buildings have more people who like them.
Rym: So they're like the tiny building.
Rym: It's only one dude who cares about that place.
Scott: yeah, if you get like the observatory only the astronomer gives a shit.
Rym: everyone else is like, I don't care if you're having a Frickin telescope, but all these other things like landscapes and gestures and all this stuff They like add more points to this.
Rym: So basically when you take a dude, right?
Scott: So it's like if I could go to that place as a library, but this place is a library But it also has three gestures.
Scott: It's like whoa, that place is way more fun.
Scott: I definitely want to go there and everyone loves gestures.
Rym: when you take a dude you basically add up all those factors and you get a number of how valuable that work was and Every turn there's a minimum value that even counts.
Rym: You can't even do it unless you get at least to the minimum, right?
Scott: People get more and more demanding as the quality of estates increases.
Scott: people are like, you know, they got higher standards, right?
Scott: It's like at the beginning of the game.
Scott: All the estates are basically empty.
Scott: So it's like I'll move in anywhere.
Rym: There's a fucking bed and you bring it and you bring that in and he scribbles like on a piece of paper and everyone in Towns like oh my god, that's amazing.
Rym: Right but seven turns later.
Rym: They're like what I've already seen the Mona Lisa, right?
Rym: Yeah for me.
Scott: Yeah towards the end of the game.
Scott: It's like You know if you want me to live in your estate and you know make you some works or whatever.
Scott: I mean you better have like fucking.
Scott: you know people made of gold licking my junk cuz that's what I got now.
Rym: So, you know Yep, so when you complete the work and everyone might complete their works on the turn you get a bonus for making the highest value work, but you pretty much just got a complete one because that is the primary way to get money and victory points.
Rym: and Basically when you complete the work when you do the thing and get the person you choose How much of that you want to turn into victory points and how much of that you want to turn into money?
Scott: To basically continue playing the game and this is the most interesting decision in the game.
Rym: It is not an easy decision.
Rym: No, it's like you score a guy by like 100 floor in more than once right?
Scott: It's like you think okay early in the game You take the coins and late in the game you take just take all victory points and that's not a bad way to go.
Scott: That's the way it works in most games.
Scott: But on the second to last turn of the game.
Scott: I realized aha Next turn I need to score another dude or else I'm not gonna win.
Scott: Yep, if I want to score another dude, I need to win this auction to buy that dude to score.
Scott: Otherwise, I'm gonna basically score zero points in the final turn for nothing.
Scott: So even though I could score this guy for full victory points, that's not enough points to win.
Scott: But if I score him now for zero points and take all money and I use all that money and get a guy next turn I win like the important.
Scott: Oh, no, that's still not enough points to win because I scored zero points this turn.
Scott: I got to somehow get enough points this turn but as much money as possible So that I have enough points to basically make it so no one can beat me But also have enough money so I can win the auction next turn no matter what.
Rym: now independent of that Pretty much everything you do gets you some points at the end of the game.
Rym: And there's all these like sub games that are kind of solitary that you just play right like jesters get you points and buildings get you.
Rym: There's all these things that like add value to the works that you get with the people.
Rym: but there's also things like When you get buildings or these landscape things you put them on your board and you got to play Tetris and there's rules like you Can't build buildings next to other buildings
Scott: unless your builder gets really good
Rym: And you want to have the least empty space at the end of the game Because you have bonus points for that and if you need a building, but it won't fit.
Rym: Well, fuck you that sucks Yep, and on top of all that you have set collection.
Rym: So like if you get enough builders or you get enough forests or whatever, you know all these extra victory points.
Rym: So there's a lot of ways to get victory points at the end of the game.
Rym: so it's.
Rym: you know, a lot of these games in this era had that concept of Everything is worth victory points in some direct way.
Rym: And then there's a machine that also cranks out victory points.
Rym: so you got to optimize the like Placement getting of things while also optimizing the machine.
Rym: the machine tends to be more reliant upon the actions of the other players While the rest of it tends to be more solitary, right?
Scott: the machine is definitely the most powerful way to get the victory points like if you win that you win because if you win it Other people aren't getting points because that's the competitive part, but you have to keep up in the solitaire part.
Scott: Otherwise, it won't be enough points to win.
Scott: But it's all.
Scott: you just keep up in the solitaire and win the machine game Then you're gonna win the whole game.
Rym: So I'm not sure if I believe the five-player version of this game is the best or not.
Scott: I think the problem with It's tough, right?
Rym: it's so tight and so locked in on the cards that a Problem is that unless you've played the game enough to just know like which guys need what and kind of a sense of what?
Rym: You have a little bit of analysis problems And you have to literally look at the list of all the people and all the things those people want and look at everyone else's Boards and you can do a lot of calculation.
Scott: It took me a lot of time, but I won right.
Scott: I did do a bit of analysis.
Scott: I took like I took.
Scott: I took a few minutes to figure out which what exactly what.
Rym: I was willing to do that and I went Up and got a hot dog instead and as a result.
Rym: I had a really bad.
Scott: I only did it once at like the very end of the game because my plan was slightly Disrupted that I had originally come up with because someone else did something.
Scott: Yeah So I basically had to spend an extra like two minutes figuring out what the hell was going I was gonna do and it and it Did it.
Rym: so the problem I had to was that in the last turn?
Rym: I think there were two players in our five-player game who had literally nothing they could do in the last turn to get points enough To matter.
Rym: Yep, and a third player may or may not have been able to affect the game But it really didn't matter because it depended upon what the fourth and fifth players did Because the resources had basically run out on that fifth turn.
Scott: So, you know You could only do something if you were large and in charge in the fifth turn.
Scott: if you played with less players there would still be a bunch of unclaimed resources at that point and It wouldn't be so tight that you know You could.
Rym: anyone would still be in it basically but at the same time the tightness adds a ridiculous amount of tension.
Scott: Yeah without the game going on as long as some of those super tense train like you want games to be tight You don't want to be too tight.
Scott: For example, we did potion explosion We talked about recently and a potion explosion.
Scott: You can only score two potions a turn and if you fall behind You don't score two every turn.
Scott: Well, right but in In Princess of Florence, it's like well you want to score one dude on almost every turn and if you fall behind Yeah, and you can't really score more than one and that's sort of like but it sucks.
Scott: Sometimes you can't even get a guy cuz they ran out.
Scott: Yeah, and that's that's why I had to win that.
Rym: What's interesting though is the game is only seven turns.
Rym: so I enjoy the like severe restrictions and tightness of this game Even though I hate the same thing in Food chain magnate.
Scott: Well, I think it's because even though
Rym: chain magnate is a lot longer and the paths are so narrow And they don't touch each other at all this game every path has a lot of victory points and a lot of ways to Really look at what other people are doing and it matters a lot.
Scott: Well, the game just has lots of decisions to make that are really interesting.
Scott: Like do I?
Scott: how do I split this between victory points and money?
Scott: Which?
Scott: I want to buy that building because that lets me make this guy.
Scott: He'll he'll be attracted to my estate, but the building doesn't really fit nicely in my area.
Scott: So do I try to get a builder first, but if I get a builder first and it's a whole action I won't be able to get this freedom.
Scott: and if I die because I only have two actions If I don't get the freedom the guy won't be as happy.
Rym: and I already have a builder.
Rym: getting another one doesn't help me that much but I could just get victory points for that.
Rym: Right a bunch of builders is victory points.
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Scott: there's a lot of decisions like that That are like, you know, and then once you make one you're locked in.
Scott: not you know?
Scott: You basically change.
Scott: you improved your board.
Scott: for now the whole rest of the game.
Scott: So it's like the buildings I chose early and like the early turns.
Scott: I didn't realize when I was buying those buildings that later in the game It's like oh I need the guys.
Scott: that goes with those buildings so that I can get more Value out of that building purchase.
Scott: if I have to buy a new building That you know if I had to get a different guy and to get a different building That's a whole extra action to buy another building and like a whole nother, right?
Scott: Whereas if I can be more efficient and use them over and over again.
Scott: Then I'll get more value for my action.
Scott: because you're lit seven turns two actions a turn.
Scott: was that 14 actions the end?
Rym: Yeah, right 14 actions and seven auctions right that's all you got.
Scott: so you better choose those 1421 things very very wisely.
Rym: so we knew you know We're talking about the tense decisions the first auction of the game.
Rym: We're all sitting there about to play this game and a bunch of us haven't played it before and even the literal first auction in The game was real tense and got her a real high number.
Scott: Yes, like there's only gonna be seven of them.
Scott: Here you go.
Scott: First one.
Scott: Let's go.
Rym: It's like oh shit Yep, and because the the auctions are restricted It's not like auctions in other games where you can drive it up Strategically you because you really don't have a lot of choice.
Rym: It's just the price will be X.
Scott: when it comes to you right in power grid There's like this three of them and you know, there's gonna be more and it's okay.
Scott: Yeah in this one It's like alright, I'm picking jester and it's like well, that's the jester.
Scott: That could be won this turn.
Rym: Yep, if you don't get it be another jester.
Scott: If you don't win this auction for jester this turn you are at best getting a jester next turn which is a big difference.
Rym: Yep, because every turn things a lot of the things you get are effectively cumulative.
Rym: So getting a jester on turn one way more valuable than getting it on turn two and extra it's it's.
Scott: it's significantly But not drastically more valuable than turn two But it's way more valuable than getting one on turn three.
Scott: And you're playing with four or five people in a seven turn game.
Scott: turn three is halfway through the game.
Scott: basically No, it's like oh I got one at the start of the game.
Scott: when you go in halfway through good job That's like two less uses.
Scott: you got out of it.
Rym: So I feel like this is a style of euro that a lot of you may not have played.
Scott: Yeah, cuz I feel like this is this I feel I think most people haven't been playing euro serious games as long as we have Even though we haven't been playing as long as like grognards.
Scott: We've only been playing since like thousand ish, right?
Rym: And this is probably got settlers in 2000, right?
Scott: So this came out in like 2000.
Rym: So yeah So, uh, I don't I like it.
Rym: I don't know if I want to own it cuz I'm trying to get rid of game.
Scott: I don't think I need to own this game, but it's like if I want to play then you should bring it to Another packs, right?
Scott: So if I want to play a for real euro game that I haven't already played a bunch I would play this a few more times watching us in the stream.
Rym: He's pointing out.
Rym: Yeah, he's right.
Rym: So yeah, cuz Kramer worked with keys ling on those other games and with all rich This stuff, okay Anyway, well to do there's two different all riches, but the third one is not always named.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I don't know why I never I don't.
Scott: I have not paid a lot of attention to these people.
Rym: I don't know a lot about Richard all rich.
Rym: to be perfectly honest I know Wolfgang Kranger because his name was on all the games.
Rym: I played a long time ago.
Scott: Ah I want to go home.
Rym: You want to go home?
Rym: Oh, yeah the capstone.
Rym: So it's an apple.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and my comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the patreon patreons for this episode of GeekNights in order the money money.
Rym: They give us on a continuing basis.
Rym: Ah Alan Joyce Rebecca Dunn Nicholas Brando having a nickel Amanda to shit.
Rym: great job.
Rym: Emoji ivy Faye my state II calm.
Rym: William Eisen rose Jeremy a minor.
Rym: All I want to do is see you turn into a giant woman.
Rym: a giant woman.
Rym: Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: Christian coots to leather to dildos to curry vindaloo to huevos rancheros and Maya Sherman von Horl rarely found James David Wright Rochelle, Montanona Superboy.
Rym: I paid five bucks to make Rym save vague hoots.
Rym: Brian Fisher sailor Vista Matthew Smith Don Schleich jar top vision.
Rym: Joe sure Joe star Tyler Eller Sean Yeager Sam Cordray Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin Wiggum forever Barney never.
Rym: Brian Sidroni a rodent of unusual size Redacted.
Rym: Chris midkiff Chris Knox Daniel Redmond Shawn Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: No show on Thursday.
Rym: See you guys next week with the Monday show.
Rym: I think we got a topic and now I leave you with Hakuna matata Oh.