Rym: It's Monday, November 12th 2018.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: Why aren't there any good Monday shows for us to do?
Rym: Let's do this So this weekend for the second time in a row of two years because when it was the thing Emily and I run races like 5k or whatever.
Rym: It's kind of like a thing That's really easy to do and really easy to organize.
Rym: But the Rangers do one.
Rym: that's like the super charity thing where it's expensive Because all the money goes to like the charity.
Rym: So we run it every year and this year like P on was there and he high-fived us at them surprised anyone was there because they were in Columbus the night before.
Scott: they're in Columbus playing a night game the game back to back game the games over at like 10 Columbus time.
Scott: then they're in New York the next day at the crack-ass of dawn running a 5k with a bunch of just slubs like me.
Rym: But like he was there a whole bunch of like legacy like old Rangers were there and it's always like this fun thing.
Scott: It's nothing else to do.
Rym: It's like 50 bucks, but all the money goes to 50 bucks.
Rym: Yes cheap dude I'm normal.
Scott: do charity bike races.
Scott: They want you to bring thousands.
Rym: dude normal 5k is like a regular race I run in the city.
Rym: Like if you book it in advance, we're talking like 15 to 20 bucks.
Scott: like charity bike races They want you to bring thousands of dollars.
Rym: Yeah foot races It's partly because there's a couple of organizations that have the equipment.
Scott: I guess for running You don't really need.
Rym: well, you need the typical.
Rym: Yeah, you don't need bicycle shit, but all that.
Scott: but the running stuff is reusable, right?
Rym: Yeah, but you know, well that the so you need the electronic things in the bibs Yeah, but those are disposable right.
Rym: and then you need the chip tracking stuff for the splits and the start and the finish.
Rym: But that's pretty much it like you.
Rym: bring it and set it up for a bike thing.
Scott: first Someone has to lay out the course.
Rym: Yeah And the course has to be a lot more tight because on a running race like the course could just be like pretty much any Street anywhere in the city.
Scott: Yeah, the course has to be long hundred miles plus.
Rym: Yeah, our courses are like you got a market.
Rym: our courses are 5k 10k.
Scott: You gotta have rest stops full of food.
Rym: We don't need any rest stops.
Rym: You think the run table with water.
Scott: the ride takes almost all day.
Scott: Not you know, that's what you could do in the morning and then go home.
Rym: 5k takes 20 minutes.
Scott: Yeah, this takes all fucking day.
Scott: So maybe it's the same dollar per minute ratio.
Rym: So what's interesting is I'm getting older and my like short race times are getting worse.
Rym: cuz Like I keep saying on the show 35 ain't 25 and I ain't even 35 But my long distance times are getting better.
Rym: So I tried to push myself.
Rym: I tried to like despite the fact that I'm getting older.
Rym: I actually tried to do well in this race.
Scott: I trained for it and I ran hard to end again.
Rym: I did vomit at the end Because and I'd so.
Rym: the problem is actually I got almost the exact same time as last year 20 minutes 11 seconds.
Rym: I was number four overall in my age group and I was 16 overall among everybody.
Scott: numbers 1 2 & 3 age group also vomit.
Rym: Uh, I saw another person vomit right over the finish line.
Rym: Just like me.
Rym: It wasn't just me But the trouble I have is that these short races to push myself at the end.
Rym: My body is just like Rym Rym your old Rym Rym slow down Jesus Rym god damn.
Rym: But because there's like a sprint at the end.
Rym: But in a long race you just run like the race is so long that running faster in the last hundred yards doesn't mean shit.
Scott: It saves you a fraction.
Rym: Yeah, but running faster in the last hundred yards is the difference between fourth place and third place.
Rym: So yeah, it was super fun and I got the exact same time as last year.
Rym: Meaning I am at best slightly staving off the rad which is of age Mm-hmm.
Rym: That's what I got.
Rym: Okay race though.
Scott: So someone tweeted that Joe his say she if you don't know who that is this the guy who composed.
Rym: Oh, yeah, I didn't buy tickets.
Scott: that concert all the music for Studio Ghibli movies.
Scott: This stuff is real good Was putting on a concert at Carnegie Hall and I'm like, hey, I've been past Carnegie Hall like a thousand times.
Scott: I know exactly where that is.
Scott: It's a famous place.
Scott: I've never been in there.
Scott: Really when have you been in there?
Rym: I saw some concerts in there.
Scott: What'd you see in there?
Rym: like 10 11 years ago I saw a piano concert.
Rym: It was this famous guy to remember his name and he did a rock mountain off.
Scott: He did another thing anyway, so I'm like, oh and I look and the tickets were hella cheap.
Scott: So I just bought him.
Scott: So apparently I found out after buying the tickets that Apparently last week He was performed.
Scott: they were conducting had like the orchestra symphony or whatever and they were doing Studio Ghibli music.
Scott: Yeah, I was like, oh shit.
Scott: This one isn't that is the weebs always sell those out.
Scott: So that one is in the Carnegie Hall is the building.
Scott: it has three different I guess Theaters in it halls three different music halls.
Scott: in Carnegie Hall, right?
Scott: Which is the building?
Scott: this I forget.
Scott: This is the big one, which is what you think of as Carnegie Hall.
Scott: I forget what it's called Is that there's a recital Hall which I guess is for recitals and very small things like maybe one person singing Maybe maybe a quartet maybe I don't know.
Scott: and then we were in Zenko Hall which is like the medium-sized one and it had like a chamber orchestra in there, right and He was performing that he was Conducting.
Scott: What is it?
Scott: Like he recomposed a Philip Glass piece from the 60s and then That's kind of his thing like every year.
Rym: He'll make like a set of new pieces.
Scott: It was like very modern music right this this Lang guy composed to other things even though his size.
Scott: She was conducting all of it and then like after the intermission This really good singing singer came out and this weird-looking but still good at playing Cellist came out and was like sitting on a platform set from everyone.
Scott: Anyway, so that was good.
Scott: But the thing I want to talk about is that before the show We were sitting around eating some ramens right like you do and I go I know and the ticket was a PDF on my phone Because like you do it's no 2018. so I'm like, huh?
Scott: You know that it's like six twenty and the shows at seven thirty.
Scott: and I'm like, when should we go over there?
Scott: Let me refer to the ticket that let me refer to the ticket to see when we should go over there.
Rym: No, you're in.
Scott: maybe it has some info on it.
Scott: Look at the ticket and I start reading it and I'm reading all the fine print on the ticket and eventually I get to some Fine print.
Scott: it says yo You have to print this out on paper, even though it's And I was like.
Scott: what the fuck are you fucking kidding me?
Scott: is 2018 is the famous venue I can go to Madison Square Garden with a barcode up with a QR code on my watch.
Scott: Yep, I went to the World Series with the ticket on my phone.
Scott: I can go to the Game devs of color with a barcode from event, right?
Scott: Right.
Scott: This is fucking Carnegie Hall a world-famous musical venue that people they're like famous jokes about and you need a piece of fucking paper.
Scott: What kind of like.
Scott: they should be fucking embarrassed, right?
Scott: So the story I want to talk about is I'm in Manhattan.
Scott: How the hell did I read this out?
Rym: Yep, because it was this brief era in a distant past where there were a lot of facilities.
Scott: It's a good thing that I checked because more of the fine print also said yeah, we're not gonna print this out for you haha.
Scott: So I went and I'm like, where can I print something?
Rym: and I'm thinking I know where you can print some staples.
Scott: Yep, so I search for staples.
Scott: No, it's closed at 630 on Sunday fuck.
Scott: Yeah, right Sunday, so I searched for Kinko's which is now FedEx office.
Scott: So I searched her FedEx office and I go there and there was one open just a few blocks away.
Scott: I actually known I'd known of his location previously.
Scott: See I could have she.
Rym: I would have just gone to my place of employment.
Rym: That's not that far.
Scott: I'm as far away.
Scott: Yeah, so I go to this FedEx office and I'm like, alright I have a PDF any email.
Scott: How do I print it?
Scott: and I'm looking around and I look at around and I see this some copy a big fancy copy machine And next to it is a little terminal and a sign and the sign is like yo forward your attachment to email address at FedEx comm.
Scott: then we're gonna email you a number and I'm like.
Scott: I know so I do it and I wait.
Scott: worst-case scenario some employee of FedEx goes and sees Joe his size Very and they can get to Carnegie Hall in an hour with that more power to it.
Scott: I'm waiting and I'm waiting and nothing happens.
Scott: So I start poking.
Scott: I emailed I forwarded the email nothing happens.
Scott: So poking the terminal and the terminals like alright, you can get a USB stick.
Scott: I'm like, yeah, no, that's not happy.
Scott: They're like you can log into your Google Drive on this terminal.
Scott: and oh hell no I'm like, I really don't want to do that.
Scott: I Really do not want to log into my Google Drive Terminal.
Rym: that's the equivalent of.
Rym: here is a hole Somewhere.
Scott: it's like I'm gonna type in my Google email and password on the shady FedEx office terminal And then is it even gonna bring up my 2fa prompt.
Scott: my good sir even gonna bring it up.
Rym: my good sir Please present an appendage of your choice into this mysterious hole.
Scott: So I'm like.
Scott: I go to the attachment and I push the button that saves the attachment to Google Drive And I'm like, I really don't want to do this.
Scott: I really would not like this option.
Scott: They also had a Dropbox option and some other options.
Rym: I'd be more like inclined to make a Dropbox account.
Scott: I thought of that as well, but luckily as I'm waiting there It just took some for like.
Scott: it took like almost five plus minutes.
Scott: I get an email that's like here's your fucking code.
Scott: I'm like, oh, thank god.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So I go to the terminal I type the code in I dip my credit card in the in the slot and two pieces of paper Come out.
Scott: and that's how that works.
Scott: You know, it's funny because in the course of my life I've gone through their own like FedEx cloud where the attachment was located and I had to like choose the file on the little terminal.
Rym: But if I think about like printing adventures, yeah, I said they sent me an email today.
Scott: There's like how was the show?
Scott: and I'm like the show was fantastic.
Scott: You should be fucking embarrassed.
Scott: Yeah that I have to bring a digital ticket that I can't bring a digital ticket to your show is a disgrace.
Scott: fix that shit.
Rym: I mean I went from as a child using a RZA graph because the school couldn't afford an actual a coffee machine.
Rym: My school always had a copy yep to going to a Kinko's and trying to Xerox pages from my Dungeons and Dragons Cyclopedia and them stopping me and saying I can't violate the copyrights by doing so.
Scott: it says on the character sheet page Specifically you can copy this one and they didn't age.
Rym: They did wanted nothing to do with it.
Rym: They turned me away and were real shitty about it.
Scott: It's a library.
Scott: never actually bothered you just go nuts.
Rym: Yeah Usually we went for copies of that brief era where there were multiple retail places.
Rym: You could go to print shit and copy shit to the era where who prints anything anymore Like if I print something at work.
Scott: people don't realize most bodegas in New York still will do like fax machine Stuff and print out a thing for you.
Rym: Well partly because a lot of poorer and more disadvantaged people really need to be able to fax shit other places in New York.
Scott: I don't know if people have these and not not.
Scott: I haven't seen them in suburbs a lot But you know the I've seen same-day cash checking places.
Scott: Yeah payday loan places which are usually shady, but there's a place that's actually way useful Which is the get international credit phone card wire money places?
Scott: Those places very often will do fax machine copying printing all that kind of stuff as well.
Scott: And those are good places.
Scott: Thankfully, I think some of them are also payday loan places.
Scott: then they're bad.
Rym: Last time I had to do a fax Was when I tried to buy that house in Beacon and I had to fax a bunch of documents around and I can't fax to You by emailing an attachment to phone number at something that come.
Scott: Yeah, then I'm not faxing.
Scott: So I faxed from a bodega in Yonkers, it's just a warning to you if you buy tickets to a venue you haven't been to before Double-check that it's modern even though it's fucking 2018 and I haven't had a paper ticket for anything since maybe 2013 or even earlier.
Rym: Well here same same deal, right?
Rym: So we fly a lot, right?
Scott: So yeah, I can use.
Scott: I can use a digital ticket to get in a Jersey Transit fucking bus
Rym: so
Scott: I can buy a ticket on my phone for that bus while I'm waiting for the bus and I can't go to Carnegie Hall a world-class musical institution and I had to have it bring a piece of paper.
Rym: so, you know, I fly a lot and one thing I've learned is that The consistency with which e-tickets are accepted at airports if you're not flying to or from New York City It's so low that you're pretty much got to print shit out.
Scott: No, I you I've not had a problem.
Scott: You have not flown nearly as much as I have.
Scott: but what I did have a problem with which is partially just cuz I didn't Fully understand it was I had the passport card that I got way back.
Rym: You can't use that flying.
Scott: I got that when I got my.
Scott: I got that way back when I bought Passport card in America.
Rym: basically means this is useless in 99% of all cases where you would want to use.
Scott: So it's like I got it back when I got my passport.
Scott: cuz I just picked the max option Just like I picked the max option for my new driver's license, right?
Rym: Well, yeah I did the new.
Scott: so the passport card said you can use this to go to Canada Mexico and Caribbean Islands fine print Not on a plane.
Scott: I didn't see that.
Scott: So I try, you know, I had my real one with me obviously cuz not a moron.
Scott: But I was like, I can't use this one.
Scott: They're like, no that's for like on a cruise ship or something yep, but yeah, the passport card is only for boats and land and the They said oh you can use your driver's license to re-entry into the u.s.
Scott: It's like on boats or land.
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Scott: come on.
Scott: What's the fucking point?
Rym: There's no point.
Rym: It's all just garbage.
Scott: Let me use the passport card for everything.
Rym: How about just not need a passport like when I was a kid and I could just go to Canada all the time Like they would just wave us through and not even ask you we were Mm-hmm.
Rym: You got to get back to those days.
Scott: somehow if you vote for Scott for president I will improve relations with Canada so that we don't need that anymore.
Scott: So once they find out that the big hockey fan is president We all good.
Rym: so in some news.
Rym: So another problem of flying around the world a lot.
Rym: Is that basically everywhere civilized except the United States?
Rym: When you have a credit card, it's you can have a chip and pin meaning there's a chip.
Scott: people in the u.s.
Scott: Don't know this?
Rym: and you know a pin and When you want to use your credit card, you have to input the pin.
Rym: math happens to determine its two-factor authentication.
Scott: Essentially, yeah, you put in your credit card in the slot which you did learn in the u.s.
Scott: Recently Yep, but then you actually to type in a number just like you do with your ATM card.
Scott: Yeah, otherwise, it won't fucking work.
Scott: So if someone steals your credit card, they can't go around buying shit.
Rym: But this does not work the same way and there's no signature.
Scott: No don't do any as a debit card Like.
Rym: it's not the same math.
Rym: It's not the same system.
Rym: It's totally different.
Scott: So it actually provides real security.
Rym: so many of you younger people won't know because I Learned recently that most People who are younger than us have never even heard of the idea of a cash advance because they're largely disappearing.
Scott: But basically you only use that in an extreme emergency.
Rym: Yeah, because their interest rates like 40% It's a bad idea.
Scott: But basically remember they used to send you checks fake checks and well not fake checks But like real checks that you could just write to people.
Scott: that would just make a cash advance happen and fuck.
Scott: Yeah,
Rym: cash advances were bad news but old people could do that if they wanted to and the way it would work is your credit card whether you know it or not has a pin and if you have to put that pin in and it basically acts like a debit card the point I'm Making here is that America relatively recently started forcing everyone to use chips instead of the mag stripes But this was ostensibly for security But they didn't actually implement the pin part of that.
Scott: They're basically just using the chip instead of the magnet strip.
Scott: Yes, so the same fucking thing.
Rym: It's not actually in any way more secure And in fact credit card fraud appears to have not dropped at all.
Rym: Nope And even funnier a lot of Americans who don't travel like in Europe as much as I do.
Rym: We'll go to Europe and try to use their credit card And guess what your American credit card even though it has a chip won't fucking work in almost any point-of-sale System that doesn't have a human there.
Scott: like most things the government does that are anti common sense.
Scott: it's usually because someone is paying the Representatives to go against common sense and it's like a lot of the times It's just plain old visible like oh, yeah, that oil company is paying them to deny climate change?
Scott: obviously, right?
Scott: But in this case, it's criminals.
Scott: So that's the ones that they don't make so obvious.
Scott: But I'm pretty sure I'll be willing to bet that credit card fraud Profiteers are definitely paying to make sure the US does not implement chip and pin.
Rym: I don't know who's paying to me.
Scott: I think that sounds like a crazy conspiracy But you know what less crazy than actual crazy conspiracies the crazy people believe, you know, I'd suspect more.
Rym: all the companies that issue Credit cards in the u.s.
Rym: Don't want to have to update their systems because you have to.
Scott: they already just updated them.
Rym: Yeah, and half the places I go in New York still use the mag swipe.
Scott: So only the only place.
Scott: I actually saw the mag swipe even though I was just talking good about them for letting me use my Apple.
Scott: If you want to buy know if you want to buy food at Madison Square Garden.
Scott: All the chip inserts are broken you or something.
Scott: You got to use the swipe.
Scott: Yep, like it's like in 19, whatever.
Rym: So not only the chips basically do nothing and they're not actually the chip and pin that the rest of the world uses.
Rym: the article I'm linking to here talks about how 60 million US credit cards were compromised in the last year and 93% of those were chip enabled.
Rym: Merchants are basically just continuing to use the mag stripes because they don't give a shit.
Rym: Nobody seems to give a shit about this.
Rym: They did.
Scott: what I thought happened was they changed the law so that if you were a merchant and you didn't update your assistant That you would now be liable for any, you know fraudulent like chargebacks and stuff Whereas otherwise, you know Visa MasterCard the bank or whoever would be liable and that would encourage you to Update your shit because otherwise if anything happens in those transactions your big doodoo.
Rym: Yeah, and I'm not actually sure what the status of all those laws and regulations is like I just don't know.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: But the main way credit cards are getting stolen is Actually really sad and it's simply just malware on the point-of-sale systems that are all basically running windows Right.
Scott: It's like you go swipe your car credit card into a Windows machine like oh that terminal thing at the FedEx place.
Scott: Someone put some spyware in it.
Scott: congratulations.
Scott: They can now make a copy of my credit card and go use this very telling that I have like.
Rym: I have a bunch of Credit cards and I have a set of credit cards that are only ever used online and are never used in person.
Rym: I have another set of credit cards.
Rym: They're only ever used in person and never used online.
Scott: I only have one credit card used for everything.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, I want I kept my old credit card because having that ancient line Yeah, I have two ancient credit cards with zero.
Scott: Yeah I just never use.
Scott: but they're not.
Scott: I keep them from expiring and I just use one for everything.
Rym: But anyway my Online only credit cards have to this day Never had a problem because you're not buying from any shady ass websites.
Scott: You're buying from places with nice green locks in the corner and you know, it's the right domain.
Scott: and yeah You're not.
Rym: meanwhile my in-person credit card has been compromised like six times And I'm pretty sure every one of those times was the result of a shitty hotel.
Scott: I got a hotel hotels in my credit card and haven't had a problem.
Rym: Yeah Well, it was fun on a tropical island.
Scott: I didn't get a problem and I used dirt everywhere.
Rym: Oh, yeah Well, I didn't want MmV.
Rym: But the moral of all this is that the chips on us credit cards are you concerned about that?
Scott: I'm a tropical.
Rym: Yeah, basically mean nothing.
Scott: But I checked my statement ever my balance every month and nothing shady.
Rym: So you got any news?
Scott: What was my news?
Rym: the ridiculous fall, right?
Scott: So So this is something where the core idea is a good idea and that is a phone that folds.
Scott: We've had phones that folded.
Scott: my first phone the Motorola star tag great phone.
Scott: Yeah, flip phones in that area, which is great because You can fit it in your pocket.
Scott: But then when you need to be bigger you unfold it and now you have a large device that's easy to use.
Scott: Yeah, but then when you want to put it away and not use it it magically becomes smaller.
Rym: The last phone I had that did that was the palm free where you can flip out the iPhone like the new iPhone X.
Scott: I forget if the S or R is the bigger one But the biggest iPhone the newest biggest one is way too fucking big.
Scott: No hell.
Scott: No, I wouldn't pay for it.
Scott: Even it was like a dollar but maybe it was done But it's too damn big.
Scott: But you know what if that sucker folded in half, I'd buy that right away Maybe even for like $800.
Scott: not $1,000 but $800 right cuz like damn.
Scott: that would fit in my pocket if I fold it in half.
Scott: But and the main thing when I unfold it, it's great.
Rym: Okay, the main reason why I don't want a big phone is that I can't fit it in my pocket.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: That's reason number one.
Scott: So folding solves all these problems.
Scott: So there you've been working a very long time a lot of companies to make a because you can fold every part of the computer.
Scott: We have laptops that fold.
Scott: No, the problem is we have a phone.
Scott: the part that can't fold is the screen.
Rym: That's the only part that needs to be big for most people.
Rym: that are the battery, right?
Scott: So I mean we can make a folding phone where the screens on half of it like a laptop Blackberry with a hinge in the middle.
Scott: Fuck that garbage, right?
Scott: We need to make the screen itself somehow fold.
Scott: We don't want to have like a DS where there's two screens with a blank space in the middle.
Scott: Yeah, we got to make the screen itself fold.
Scott: So they've been working on this technology for a long time and Samsung has apparently succeeded.
Scott: They want to make this phone and this phone Looks like fucking even worse than iPhone one.
Scott: It is way thick and chunky way janky.
Scott: the most telling the rumor is that they want to charge $1,700 for this.
Rym: someone zoomed in on how thick it is.
Rym: Like he's holding it in his hand when it's folded.
Scott: It's so thick that I can't say this.
Scott: It's like a ham sandwich.
Rym: I have eaten sandwiches that were thinner than this fucking phone based on this pay.
Scott: At least it's smaller than a de bella sandwich.
Scott: Yeah, I really wanted to be able to sandwich right now.
Rym: Oh my god I'm hungry already.
Scott: Maybe I'll pick up a bread and some stuff.
Scott: You said those words.
Rym: Anyway, a Primal part of my I'm selling.
Rym: I'm literally salivating now same.
Rym: Okay, so The point is I can't get in New York.
Rym: I'm rich and I live in New York and I can't get a goddamn de bella sandwich.
Scott: I could go to that other place in a story people talk about anyway.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, the point is this phone is garbage.
Scott: No one's paying $700 for this, but I cannot.
Rym: I cannot wait if my current phone could fold over Forward and turn into a tiny square.
Rym: That's one thing.
Rym: This is like if my phone were just twice as big.
Scott: Yeah, I'm hoping that the squid is basically square aspect ratio.
Rym: What the hell.
Scott: the fact that they have succeeded at this though means I'm really hoping that in 5-ish plus years right when Apple makes the folding phone That I have awesome thin as hell folding phone and I'll buy the second generation of folding phone.
Scott: It'll be sweet as hell.
Rym: Here's my problem.
Rym: I know what's gonna happen.
Rym: the folding phones are going to be in their folded state still too big because the market for this is people who Way to be.
Scott: if I wait for the second generation of folding Apple phone, it will not be too big But then it'll get too big in the later versions and I'll keep that one.
Scott: So I'll stick with the iPhone f7.
Rym: It's just look at this screen like who needs a screen That's just wider like that like at the thing.
Scott: Okay, so if this thing wasn't thick if it was nice and thin Okay, then it would actually be okay because what you wouldn't have a tablet it would be your phone and your tablet.
Scott: true but This thing and that's it.
Rym: Most people who want a big phone seem to want it so that they can watch like movies on it.
Scott: even at $1,700 it's cheaper than a phone and a tablet.
Rym: what I don't see here is what the actual resolution is of this screen.
Scott: not good Enough because I mean it doesn't say you gotta have to wait for it to be good enough.
Rym: It's obviously okay.
Rym: So it is a cow good God.
Rym: Okay, Samsung fold is a tiny 4.6 display with a 19 blah blah blah.
Rym: the unfolded mode is a 7.3 inch 2152 by 1536. that's okay.
Rym: That's alright.
Scott: That's okay.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, I'm actually Surprised that they're going with this instead of waiting one more generation.
Scott: I think they have to push it out to make it.
Scott: you know, there's always that first right?
Scott: Yeah, I remember before the iPhone there was that Motorola iTunes phone.
Scott: Remember that thing right at all, right?
Scott: So there's always has to be the one janky piece of crap before the first real thing.
Rym: So I'm not gonna link to this article for my last news cuz it's on Forbes.
Rym: and if you don't know the deal with Forbes There's a reason why it used to be a magazine.
Scott: That was a real magazine even though the guy who runs it is like a piece of shit The guy named Forbes.
Scott: But Forbes.
Scott: now you use a website used to be a website based on the magazine with real articles like a real magazine.
Scott: But now basically anyone can write a Forbes article almost and then whoever writes the article will go around trying to post it everywhere on the internet because they get paid to the end more clicks and stuff and So just cuz something's on Forbes.
Scott: it sort of lends it this credibility of being in a real Magazine.
Rym: mostly cuz and I run into a lot of people who don't know.
Scott: Change their business may as well just be a fucking blog if it's on Forbes.
Scott: It might as well be a medium post.
Scott: It's the same thing.
Rym: Yep So I'm not even gonna say the name of the company because it's clearly an ad for a company that does delivery services within cities.
Rym: but the point it makes and like the data talks about is pretty interesting.
Scott: if True, it's not just cherry-pick data to support that company's business model.
Rym: Yeah, but the point it makes is that in most major cities Transit is where though like bicycles are literally the fastest and most reliable way to get around Almost any major city.
Rym: that is true, which is 100% true in my experience.
Rym: like the state if I'm going to fall Faster than walking you cannot walk faster than it is faster than taking the subway Even if I'm going like way out into Brooklyn from here depending on the distance, right?
Scott: So it's like an ultra long distance.
Scott: No, it's not faster.
Scott: Yeah Like I can and it also depends on where you're going cuz.
Scott: sometimes if I go into somewhere like if I go to Brooklyn the subway To Brooklyn is either like three transfers and a G. Yeah, and then versus a straight shot I was like I can basically taking a super shortcut with the bicycle.
Scott: We're like the train would have to go way fast to go into Manhattan.
Rym: We'll come back or even like far Rockaway It takes about the same amount of time to bike there as it does to take the subway there.
Scott: Well, there's the subway to get to.
Scott: there is very far Rock away.
Scott: Yeah, it's far Rockaway.
Scott: It's named that because it's farther than regular Rockaway.
Scott: Yep It's not named that for any other reason.
Scott: It's actually talking about the distance.
Rym: It's far but it's something.
Rym: just think about that stat because a lot of people isn't gig knives don't necessarily live in cities.
Rym: But the fact that if you have to rank the ways to get around the city in terms of how efficient and fast they actually Are everyone knows I mean, it's was proven a long time ago that a bicycle is the most efficient form of transportation period.
Rym: Yeah ever conceived in terms of energy per Going again until you get to long like very long distances or you like use cases and all this nonsense.
Scott: I mean if there was friction in space You could use a bike but
Rym: there is some economic Evidence of this to like a secondary set of evidence in the sense that I'm not again I won't say the name of the company in this article But pretty much all the deliveries in New York City, like even deliveries of kind of big stuff like anything It isn't UPS FedEx is coming to buy a bike like bike messengers have Exploded again to the point that like there's a million of these bikes around the city both electric and not electric.
Scott: And then the only reason the UPS FedEx doesn't use say cargo bikes To deploy like all the packages small enough to go on a cargo bike is because they would need so many riders.
Scott: They use money even though each individual package will be delivered more energy efficiently.
Scott: Yes more speedily.
Rym: So just something to think about.
Rym: there's a reason why people there
Scott: are places where they do use bikes though Like you know UPS and whatnot
Rym: plus now that New York like the city bikes in New York have been such a big success that They're like they are such an important part of the transit system in the daily commute now that like a city bike outage is Almost as bad as certain kinds of subway outages in certain neighborhoods.
Rym: But anyway things of the day.
Rym: so I Big Clive.
Rym: calm is a pretty great YouTube channel I've linked to occasionally where he'll basically buy like dodgy ass Chinese bootleg electronics on eBay and take it apart and explain why it's so dangerous and terrifying.
Rym: but his channel is great and he goes into all this stuff, but this one is pretty unique because I had never conceived that such an item existed.
Rym: and apparently these are commonly used outside of the United States.
Rym: and Essentially this device even if it works as intended is Terrifyingly dangerous.
Rym: It is a USB flesh-burning pen for ladies Mm-hmm, and what it is used for is to use high voltage burning for people to burn moles off of Themselves.
Scott: Oh, I could use that or burn skin tags off.
Rym: Basically.
Scott: I have a mole.
Rym: Yes so you can buy this.
Rym: you could buy this thing on eBay and even that expensive charge you with USB and Burn the shit out of yourself.
Scott: Isn't that fucking hurt?
Scott: Yes I'm not gonna do it.
Rym: then and this video is great because he just he.
Scott: Can I use it to burn a mole off of you?
Scott: No, so just the fact that this is a consumer item then I get all the fun of mole removal without the pain fire.
Rym: Yeah It even comes with dire warnings about not to use it on like areas of skin larger than a certain amount and the area that they mention as being the line between safe and not safe is In my personal opinion way too big of an area to burn yourself on purpose
Scott: Mm-hmm,
Rym: so and the funniest part is the thing doesn't even actually work and it keeps crashing
Scott: crashing
Rym: cuz it's just.
Rym: it's a Chinese like bootleg piece of shit and Even if it works, it's intended to burn you with an electrified needle.
Scott: Can you just use a wood-burning laser or something?
Rym: Uh, no, this burns a different way laser cutter videos like 15 minutes long.
Rym: You can watch it and see all the detail.
Rym: but warning He uses it to burn a callus off of his hand because he wants to see how it works.
Scott: Why don't you use it to just burn a piece of wood?
Rym: I could do that, too.
Rym: So what do you got?
Scott: so here's a Twitter account story board art B O R E D like you're bored, but it's all one word.
Scott: Oh cute.
Scott: It's some animator of some kind.
Scott: I don't know who this person is because someone retweeted them.
Scott: I think if they're a bad person, which it doesn't.
Scott: they don't appear to be because you know Anyone.
Scott: it's what it could always be a bad person, right?
Scott: I've occasionally Oh cute Nintendo comic oh a Nazi made.
Rym: that's the exact what I was thinking of that fucking Nintendo comic.
Scott: Anyway, this person doesn't appear to be a bad person and they're an animator artist of some kind.
Scott: and here is the tweet art thread.
Scott: My ten-year-old brother wrote a kid's book and I drew the pictures for it.
Scott: It's like an ex-cop store here, right?
Scott: It turned out so funny that we're actually gonna get it made into physical books for us and some friends.
Scott: So not for you listeners.
Scott: Here's the full thing.
Scott: So on Twitter, it's how many posts is this?
Scott: 123?
Rym: oh, this is really good.
Scott: six seven.
Scott: There are seven tweets in a thread and each one has Four pictures except for the last one which only has two pictures and you just go through the pictures one by one.
Scott: And that's the whole children's storybook.
Scott: That is very well illustrated and it appears to be colored in by someone who's using crayon.
Scott: But it's also really good at crayon or making a Photoshop bar brush.
Scott: that looks exactly like a crayon And it's an excellent children's book.
Scott: it's not on the level of.
Scott: I want my hat back but it is Excellent and entertaining for all ages even if you are 90 or 9 so cute In the meta moment.
Rym: the book club book is Space Odyssey 2001 the book.
Rym: We'll read it soon.
Rym: We're also gonna be live.
Scott: I noticed the other day that you know, cuz that the filmstruck websites going down, but it's not down yet.
Scott: it's here till later in the month and 2010 was on there.
Scott: So I didn't visit Europa.
Scott: cuz I follow instructions.
Rym: Yeah, it's like the one rule.
Rym: Also, we will be live at Pax unplugged doing learn and win Puerto Rico.
Rym: I just mostly finished these slides for that and All I will say is the production values are off the charts.
Rym: There's gonna be a great panel.
Scott: You did not do the strategy section.
Rym: No, I didn't.
Scott: I also made some edits in your rule section.
Rym: I wish I well, I'll look at them see what you misspelled.
Scott: governor.
Rym: You wrote governor and not govern or over though I was copy pasting a lot out of a thing cuz I was in a hurry.
Scott: Some other things also.
Rym: Yeah, I also I found a rules clarification That we had.
Rym: we never knew about this rule.
Scott: What rule is?
Rym: oh, I'll share it later And we've never followed it, but I'm confident it never came up.
Rym: Okay?
Rym: So it's one of those situations But that'll be good.
Rym: this will be a good panel.
Rym: and then also the 40 tabletop games.
Rym: You must play the advanced version for the tabletop con where you can assume the people know the biz.
Rym: So this be a good time.
Rym: also packs out.
Rym: this coming up packs.
Rym: The East is coming up.
Rym: I wonder if the packs these badges are sold out yet.
Rym: That's a good question cuz Saturday's sold the fuck out.
Scott: Yeah, they've already went on sale and no only Saturday sold out.
Scott: Oh days are very available for PAX East.
Scott: if you want hotels might not be available.
Scott: But if you want to go to PAX East and on any day but Saturday you can just go and you can maybe get a Saturday badge in the secondary market or something.
Rym: and Enforcer applications for PAX East are live.
Rym: So if you didn't know East is the con that like me and Scott enforce we're there.
Rym: Enforce the night shift every year.
Scott: It's not enforcing it.
Scott: East kind of makes East way shittier.
Rym: Yeah, East I mean East is great, but it is the worst PAX.
Scott: Yeah, like I'm saying, you know I often talk about things being like the least smelly poop and that's when everything sucks But this thing sucks a little less.
Scott: East is like a scratched up piece of platinum.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: yeah, it's like okay It's not the most delicious steak.
Scott: It's the Second most delicious.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Oh, no It's like I got a platinum piece a gold piece and then East is like the electron piece like that's still worth something.
Rym: Yeah, that's still great.
Rym: This is still great.
Scott: It's just.
Scott: it's slightly imperfect compared to the other greats, especially because oh, no I only got a Donatello piece of artwork and not a Van.
Scott: Gogh.
Rym: I mean, honestly, the only problems with PAX East are one Boston.
Rym: Yeah, like Boston doesn't have enough hotels.
Scott: It's cold.
Rym: It's it's cold in Boston doesn't have enough transit.
Scott: The building is a big rectangle.
Rym: actually literally every problem with PAX East is the direct fault of the city of Boston and not PAX.
Rym: Yeah, like 100% so But it's still fun and we'll be there.
Rym: It's gonna be awesome.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So, yeah, we were trying to give up with the Monday shows we do and I realize we almost just did a show on printing.
Scott: Yeah, I feel like we might be able to do something on that maybe but yeah So Monday show ideas are hard to come up with.
Scott: those two reasons right.
Scott: reason number one is that we're not really learning Technologies, it's not like, you know to do a show.
Scott: It's like we could just read Wikipedia to you, but that's stupid.
Scott: Yeah, we need to know something so that we can talk about it for 20 30 whatever minutes.
Rym: Another like minor problem.
Scott: We don't learn new Technologies that much and there aren't new ones to learn that often and we do these two shows like every other week.
Scott: It's like I'm not learning a new technology every other week that I can talk for 20 minutes in depth about.
Rym: Well, also that like my areas of expertise have changed quite a bit based on the work I'm doing.
Rym: like for example, there's new there's a couple of new routing protocols and what's a new?
Rym: I mean from like 2012 2013.
Scott: Yeah, you're not working in routing them.
Rym: Yeah, I don't configure.
Rym: So while I know what those routing protocols do on a high level I Could I sell like OSPF where I can like start drawing the details right now for you?
Rym: And if I tell you what I know about these new routing protocols that you will learn less than you would learn from Wikipedia about Them.
Rym: Yep, like there's even a there's even a new now Non-routable range in IPv4 for a specific kind of net right and things.
Scott: some things I do learn are so incredibly Specific and narrow that they're not really appropriate for a podcast for the audience.
Scott: That's you know, not someone like I could talk about like a specific Function in a specific library and it's like anyone who's not using that library doesn't give any shits It's not it's not.
Scott: so y'all talk about right and also like.
Rym: at this point I am so far removed from the code my own engineers Right that I work on a very high business oriented level.
Rym: now Is one not interesting?
Rym: most of you and two.
Rym: I can't talk about what I'm doing Like.
Rym: I can't just talk about it.
Scott: second reason is hard to come with Monday episodes is because even though Technological change is moving at a more rapid pace than at any point in history right in terms of actual computers consumer electronics these sorts of things developments have that are that are significant and meaningful and Episode worthy have decreased significantly in recent history.
Scott: Well,
Rym: there's like the 20 outs to that though like number one a lot of the things we would previously have talked about on a Monday show around technology in The modern era much more appropriately fit in like a Thursday show Because it's more about the society around the use of the technology and we've started to make that distinction more often than we used to.
Rym: Another part of it is that a lot of the advances in technology While they are Transformative to like like cell phones like battery technology and all that and while they are moving pretty quick The gains from those are being basically eaten by other evolving aspects of technology like batteries got bigger.
Scott: But also we're doing more with the devices of batteries don't actually last long right and it's like if a lot of the improvements to Something it's like okay something was made faster.
Scott: It's like okay.
Scott: Well like there's a new Wi-Fi They're telling me like Wi-Fi.
Scott: They stopped using letters now.
Scott: They were simplifying it.
Scott: They're gonna big Wi-Fi.
Scott: v6.
Rym: dude You know 211 G is still like literally fast enough for everything I do in my house, right?
Scott: But the point is is like I don't know what the differences between them are only that they're faster.
Scott: It's still Wi-Fi.
Scott: You don't notice any difference as a user.
Scott: You don't know which one you're using.
Rym: there are Some differences around how the signals interact such that you can have more density of access points and signals.
Scott: How can you possibly get a GeekNights episode out of all that?
Rym: well?
Scott: Well because again Wi-Fi is now faster.
Scott: if you get a newer router and a new enough device and somehow they link up Well, here's it, but it's way.
Scott: It's faster than your internet connection is you won't notice.
Rym: Well, that's it.
Rym: the impact of a lot of the fast-moving technology impacts like like it's multiple steps removed from the consumer use case.
Rym: like ISPs will benefit from some of these changes, but you using your phone connecting to a Wi-Fi at home There is literally no meaningful difference to you for the foreseeable future.
Rym: Cuz look strip live streaming six megabit up.
Rym: That's all I need to live stream to YouTube.
Rym: They won't even take more than that.
Rym: yep at least for what I'm doing.
Scott: mm-hmm also.
Scott: Even you know they used to be this thing.
Scott: Moore's law where they were like okay every two years Transistor density will double right and it's like well actually we're sort of slower than that.
Scott: It's more like three years at this point And it we're not seeing.
Scott: even even things getting faster are not getting faster as fast as they were five six seven years ago.
Scott: Intel specifically who's like is number one in terms of consumer chips.
Scott: still kinda They've been working on this 10 nanometer Process which means the transistors are 10 nanometers in size supposedly And they sort of have fucked that up repeatedly and evisced all the deadlines And it was supposed to be out this year and this year's almost over now.
Scott: They're saying next year There's a rumor that they're just gonna cancel the whole fucking thing and Intel's like no no no This is why they're in trouble right now.
Scott: well There's and that's why you see things like Apple and Nvidia really gaining on them Apple making its own chips for a lot of its machines and and devices Nvidia maybe making a CPU.
Scott: yeah, they haven't officially announced that but well I can see it coming.
Rym: there's another sort of subtle thing going on.
Rym: There is that when we were talking a lot about computers one like we're buying a lot more consumer like computer shit and building computers more often but to the metrics of Performance were much more straightforward an 800 megahertz chip versus a gigahertz chip.
Rym: the actual impact on your use of a computer for even simple things was Noticeable to a human.
Scott: yeah You guys sit at the two different computers running the same software otherwise configured identically and one of them would be obviously faster.
Scott: You would double-click on an application.
Scott: It would appear sooner right.
Scott: you would run a game You would get.
Scott: one of them would run smoothly and one of them would have lag and not have enough FPS.
Rym: yep.
Rym: But nowadays like my current computer.
Scott: It's running at 4.5 gigahertz It's got your doors for most games even if you crank the settings up pretty high.
Scott: It's like unless you got like a 4 or 5k screen and really crank it up You won't.
Scott: you'll get the full 60 frames whether you got a 1060 or a 1080 or an 1180. right forget gaming.
Rym: Just regular PC usage.
Rym: if not for the fact that I edit 4k video mm-hmm.
Rym: There is literally no performance difference between my current crazy powerful computer and the one I replaced it with.
Rym: that was like five years old.
Rym: Yep, like literally no difference.
Rym: the only thing that's ever used all this computing capability of this modern computer.
Rym: I have is Doing complex effects that can't be done in the GPU on 4k video.
Rym: Like that is the only thing that uses the CPU right and even like cell phones It's even worse like.
Rym: I don't think I have noticed a performance difference in any cell phone I've bought in like six years.
Rym: I literally don't even care.
Rym: What chip is in my cell phone?
Scott: No, it used to be that like the first few iPhones.
Scott: I had 3g for right noticeably kind of slow compared to the newer phones.
Scott: But once we got to six seven it's like oh actually This is just perfectly fine.
Scott: and the new phone?
Scott: if I went to the Apple Store the new phone doesn't feel any faster than iPhone 7.
Rym: yep, it's the last phone.
Rym: I had that felt slow was my?
Rym: What that like LG something for like it was so long ago.
Scott: It's ancient history right, so it's not just speed right It's that meaningful.
Scott: other kinds of advancements haven't really been happening.
Scott: Recently in re in like the past couple two or three years right.
Scott: It's like all right.
Scott: We had fuck.
Scott: like we were talking about this earlier.
Scott: We got phones with a full screen on the front and today We still have phones with a full screen on the front.
Scott: We went from not having any tablets to like here are tablets.
Scott: They're all screen right.
Scott: It's like what meaningful You know.
Scott: big developments are in terms of like.
Scott: the actual features and capabilities of devices.
Scott: consumer electronics and computers are Meaningfully different from how they were a few years ago.
Rym: Well meaningful is complicated because that could be very contextual based.
Scott: I would say I'd use a different word.
Rym: I think transformative.
Rym: right.
Rym: what it were the changes where as like everyone who uses the technology or a wide body of those people Fundamentally change the way they interact with that technology right.
Scott: the clothes I could find is like a folding phone.
Scott: That's the closest thing I could find.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: it's not gonna be good for If it's ever good in this in the span of our like our lives.
Rym: What were the transformative technology moments like?
Scott: Going well when computers suddenly had a hard drive in them instead of all these needing a floppy disk to be stopped in Pentiums like the Pentiums compared to the for having a color screen on the computer.
Scott: well having a mouse that went.
Rym: The difference between a 380 we're old and a 486 like literally changed the world for me.
Scott: going from a modem to a modem That actually was fast enough to load a web page.
Scott: Yeah, not a dial-up modem.
Rym: Yep, Oh Computers that don't actually have good sound to a sound card that you can just buy.
Scott: Wi-Fi is now a thing and I don't have to always have some sort of wire.
Rym: USB USB fucking changed everything.
Scott: I remember Windows 95 support us.
Scott: you have a battery you have a laptop.
Scott: you can take the computer with you somewhere.
Scott: That's not a desk Digital fucking camera.
Scott: yeah We've seen a lot.
Rym: when I was in high school We had a digital camera.
Rym: the entire school share cameras.
Scott: put a floppy disk in the digital camera was not the thing Until like it's actually shockingly recent like even early 2000s.
Scott: It was still film camera even though digital camera was a thing.
Scott: Yeah, it was the kind where you put like a CD RW or a floppy disk into the camera until like you know 2003 4 or 5 maybe right you started.
Scott: we had a real digital camera with compact flash card right.
Scott: that came later.
Rym: But now like internet acts like broadband at least like forget access because there are parts of the world and especially because we're talking about like just sort of our experiences in America where people don't have broadband but Broadband getting faster doesn't benefit the vast majority of users of broadband.
Rym: They're gonna use it the same way they use it today.
Scott: But it drastically affects people who don't have broadband who suddenly need it.
Scott: I read an article recently about.
Scott: I read that same article Kids who live in rural places where there's no broadband at all Can't do homework And they go to the near the school because the school has internet and they sit in like the parking lot using the school's Wi-Fi To do their homework.
Scott: Yeah, that's fun.
Rym: Let's try to step back.
Rym: What was the last?
Rym: technology improvement that was transformative in our lives Because I'm hard-pressed to think of anything other than like the complete sweet Modern live streaming technology like I've had.
Scott: I've had the same sort of device loadout for like a significant period of time.
Rym: I'm still using the same laptop from 2009 and it plays sieve 6 right?
Scott: It's like I've had upgrades to devices But like what transformative change was there between my iPad pro and my mini iPad other than it's bigger and faster?
Scott: Yeah, nothing right has a has a stylus.
Scott: stylus ain't new The like.
Rym: I bought a fancy camcorder to use for gig night stuff like recently.
Scott: You know a thing but 4k video is already like four years old maybe four or five years old.
Rym: so the fancy camcorder I bought is Just cheaper because of like improvements in process and technology.
Rym: It's not better than camcorders.
Rym: I've could have gotten previously.
Rym: It's just cheaper and smaller, but I'm gonna use it the exact same way.
Rym: I would have used one of those other ones if I could have afforded it.
Scott: Yeah, Nancy the gh4 which I had not the gh5 was like basically the first prosumer Camera that had like meaningful 4k recording yeah right into video recording and it came out in.
Rym: We've been using that to record gig nights panels for a while.
Scott: Yeah a long time.
Scott: 2014. yes, I was right like every four or five years right Wow 2014.
Scott: It's only 28 May 2014.
Scott: It's 2018.
Rym: Here's what a video is four years old already But digital video cameras that just work and encode things in Reasonable formats like we tried to record some gig nights panels with that flip camera and those videos were encoded Badly to the point that you could not sink them.
Scott: like GoPros are a thing now.
Scott: But you know the GoPro has basically been perfect since.
Scott: like the GoPro 4. ish Yeah, I think I have the 5 is the 7 out now.
Rym: Yeah a new GoPro came.
Scott: I'm thinking it's not really.
Scott: I think it does 4k 60 instead of yeah 30.
Scott: Maybe I don't know.
Rym: Last gen GoPro cuz I have a GoPro like g2 That I think I gave away.
Scott: Yeah, I think the one I have if you have that one you're good.
Scott: You don't need a newer one.
Scott: Yeah, and this we only need one.
Rym: cuz I need that top-down view or for doing like panel streaming and stuff like.
Scott: it's like there's Been advancements in the drone department, but that's not something we can use.
Scott: Well.
Rym: It's still hobbyist.
Rym: It's not transformative.
Rym: It's been a lot of drone Coupled with camera has been transformative for video and audio and like low-budget film like video Professionals a drone is like now standard equipment.
Scott: Yeah, look at it.
Scott: look at it.
Scott: Look at how many YouTube videos now have aerial shots overhead shots.
Rym: Yeah, that is transformative drone camera drones.
Rym: I will give you that is a transformative technology.
Scott: right.
Scott: look how many things you watch now have like some drone footage Basically like that drone chasing the poor baby bear.
Scott: Usually it's like you know scenery like to sort of set us down.
Rym: But seriously look at a tracking shot from a helicopter from the like late 80s Compared to like a drone I could buy with the cash in my desk right now.
Scott: Like seriously, I just not allowed to fly it anywhere near here.
Scott: if I lived in the woods And I would use a drone more I would get one.
Scott: yeah When we went to the only reason I'm not droning is because I'm in a city and it's illegal to use it everywhere.
Scott: people do It anyway, dude.
Rym: I'm not gonna mess around.
Rym: I showed up the Rangers 5k.
Rym: Do you know many signs there are all over Flushing Corona Meadows Park.
Rym: that just says do not fucking fly our drones here We will arrest you.
Scott: there's one place that you can fly them because next to the the meadow pond There's a little area where you're allowed to fly like model plane helicopter.
Scott: You can fly your drone right there in that spot because it's no different than a model plane your helicopter.
Rym: Yep, I think the only other thing I can say that's been transformative is like in relative recent history we hit these sizes of Solid-state drives to where you can have just solid-state drives.
Rym: and be fine the iPad that.
Scott: the only reason I'm upgrading this perfectly good iPad pro is because this one has 128 gigs of storage.
Scott: and even though Apple overcharges the fuck for storage because they're fucking assholes New iPad pro has an option for one terabyte of storage, which I think is enough.
Rym: I mean I have a one terabyte SSD.
Scott: The SD cards that I put into my camera are 128 gig SD cards.
Scott: I can't have a one.
Scott: edit those on a 128 gig iPad Need especially when a panel fills up the card.
Scott: But if I had the one terabyte iPad I can now record video put it on the iPad upload and edit Which I did on this iPad.
Scott: It was just very difficult.
Scott: So the new one will now make that a possibility.
Rym: No But not much.
Rym: Oh, you know what something's gotten worse.
Rym: Cloud storage solutions for consumers are more expensive and less and more encumbered than they used to be.
Rym: Yeah, well also because the business model there was a loss leader and that doesn't scale.
Scott: It's because you people don't back up.
Scott: if you will backed up as much as they should then it would work.
Scott: The other thing is that people are now The instead of paying for like what.
Scott: was that one?
Scott: the backup solution that was really popular carbon.
Scott: I was that one.
Scott: that was the one that had a flat fee for like unlimited backup carbonite, right?
Scott: People now don't have need carbonite because they just pay Apple like five bucks a month or Google Drive.
Scott: That's where the money's going.
Rym: Yeah for the and that's your automatic automatic back especially if you don't have a desktop computer or like a for-real laptop if you're just living in Apple or even if you do you Could they both have desktop backup solution?
Rym: Yeah Cuz not everyone's weird like me or I need like a 40 terabyte NAS up there for people.
Scott: most people are not backing up A huge bunch of video they record to conventions.
Scott: They're just backing up their photos and their contacts and their few documents.
Scott: I think any you any one their bags any at any one pack, which is God if I did not have video to back up or Many many years of raw photos.
Scott: Yeah, I could get away with just Google Drive or just I could do
Rym: the raw wave GeekNights archive Would fit on like
Scott: a USB stick Yeah,
Rym: like I could just back that I could just put that in like 20 USB sticks and just scatter them around the earth.
Rym: That's my backup.
Scott: Anyway Now there are some sort like in terms of soft self-driving cars.
Rym: I think will be the next like really transform.
Scott: We've already discussed them to death and it also the only news would be ah, they're finally being sold.
Rym: Well, I think there's more to discuss.
Scott: Ah, they finally writing laws about them.
Scott: This is what they say.
Scott: Let's discuss their finer point.
Rym: Well, also the technology isn't actually there yet It's getting.
Scott: it's getting but yeah, we've you know, I think another problem is that if you look at like software, right?
Scott: We've sort of figured out all the algorithms.
Scott: We've figured out all the methodologies.
Scott: There hasn't been a lot of movement there, right?
Rym: There is movement and machine learning and some transformative things are happening there.
Rym: But these are not things that are being harnessed directly by you.
Rym: Yeah, okay.
Rym: Well some of you a lot of you doing this for your job.
Scott: There's a lot of movement in complete bullshit like blockchain nonsense.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Rym: God, I can't wait for those coins to just die.
Rym: That's right.
Scott: So it's like grades like.
Scott: what are we gonna do?
Scott: Nice episode about some fucking bullshit.
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Scott: how many bullshit technologies?
Scott: I know we need real technologies to be invented for us to talk about them.
Rym: Some stuff is getting close like the next gen of VR.
Rym: that oculus go is a big step toward mass-market compatibility.
Scott: It's VR.
Scott: the the current gen of VR is like already been so many years.
Scott: It's like it's like none of this is what was new in 2018 Oculus go.
Scott: No, I'm saying specifically like anything was new in 2018, right?
Rym: Oculus go though.
Rym: That's actually a pretty was it?
Scott: That's the one where it's with the battery in it.
Rym: Yeah, it's.
Rym: it doesn't need a computer.
Rym: It's got.
Scott: It doesn't need sensors, I remember that it should have been a news when it was.
Rym: I was gonna.
Rym: we should talk about it.
Rym: It's yes It's a like.
Scott: we should have talked about it when it was.
Scott: how come that's actually interesting cuz I remember Seeing that news and being like, ah, and I think we had like.
Scott: I had a bunch of travel and a bunch of shit Got in our way, but then like no one else talked about it I know it like it was a news and then it's like I haven't heard from it since.
Rym: cuz it's like.
Scott: I feel like that Hype train should have gone because basically edit that honestly as someone who hates all the VR and his poo-poo it That has everything going for.
Rym: it's the first one that's usable by normal people without doing a bunch of bullshit in your house.
Scott: It's still too damn big on your face, but everything else about it was like, whoa, great job.
Rym: Yeah, like this is the kind of VR I would just buy from my mom or dad and they will not find it till smaller I'm a face.
Scott: Yeah, otherwise, it's like whoa, that is a great advancement.
Scott: Great.
Scott: Great idea.
Scott: Good job.
Scott: Yeah, that is actually huge and makes it way better.
Rym: The only reason I'm not gonna get it is because I have the legit oculus which is better still.
Scott: I'm just waiting for it to be small enough on my face.
Scott: if they make oculus go That's doesn't stick out for my face so much.
Rym: See I don't know about sticking out from the face.
Rym: AR technology is not anywhere near there.
Scott: Well, it's AR technology is getting very advanced.
Scott: A lot of people are investing in it, you know It's only got those animojis showrooms and controlled situations.
Scott: It's like but it's.
Scott: it's not that useful and it's like the cases where it would be useful.
Scott: It's not perfect enough to be.
Rym: voice control I would argue has not been transformative at all But all the investors are desperately trying to make it transform.
Scott: I think there's certain situations where people buy the Alexa or the Google home or the Apple I home Whatever the fuck which one they have.
Scott: usually I think the Amazon was the most popular.
Scott: Yeah, people have those in their house and that's their thing.
Scott: They use it and it works right and it's good.
Scott: But I'm just.
Scott: most people I think are not in the scenario where that's a thing.
Scott: It's like I have a stereo, you know It's like if I had like a room in a house that was far away from all computers or something.
Scott: I might need one or so.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Well, I mean I I would use one in a kitchen.
Scott: But what I found is that if I kitchen was if I had a kitchen that was a separate room I was far away from all of the rooms.
Rym: But I found in practice even like trying to use all these different voice things.
Rym: They don't quite They're not intuitive enough to do the thing I actually need and it is faster to just pull out my phone and look something up.
Scott: The other thing is that I just really despite and maybe it's cuz I'm old but even if no one's around I'm self-conscious about talking to a computer and Computer, please do X and it just happens.
Scott: if anyone is around I'm not talking to a computer.
Scott: But I think if the computer was so intelligent like a person that then well, for example If right now I was that I wouldn't feel bad about it.
Rym: Computer said preheat the oven to 425 like while I'm sitting here, but in the current state of things I don't trust any Internet of Things to have any ability to set the temperature on anything in my apartment.
Scott: If I say computer said preheat the oven to 425 and it said now preheating oven to 425 I would have to go look at the oven to make sure.
Rym: yeah, I wouldn't trust it.
Rym: I also I don't want to be slain in the middle of the night and suddenly here off in the distance.
Rym: It's preheating oven to 550 because someone hacked into my apartments trying to kill me.
Rym: So, yeah that killed an episode.
Scott: I think right but we need ideas for the next Monday episode.
Rym: Tell us what we should do the Monday show on.
Scott: please invent something new or Find something that I actually have a reason to learn.
Scott: that is a significant item that I could talk about for 30 minutes.
Rym: forum thread for this episode.
Rym: Tell us what would you do a Monday show on?
Rym: We're gonna pick the best of those ideas even if it's shitty and we'll do the show on it great.
Rym: So put some good stuff in there.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night
Rym: And the patreon patrons for this episode of good nights are in a somewhat smoother radio voice as I try a different configuration of the microphone Craig Oliver, Ellen Joyce, Heidi McNichol a shimmering Ruby obelisk hanging in the sky Kajara Tovish and my stady comm linky GJ Bantz scooter lonely Roberto Kingsley Shawn Yeager, Matthew Smith Nicholas Brando, mr.
Rym: Strong stretch and four to one creations Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn Shervin van Horr, Rory, Rochelle, Montanona, Superboy, Tripwire, Sailor Vista, Don Schleich, Jojo Joestar, Clinton Walton, Wren from New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, Drew Openlander, Finn, Chris Midkiff, Daniel Redmond, Shawn Klein, Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: If you didn't notice we had some trouble getting stuff on the patreon for a while because we were so busy But there is some patreon exclusive content.
Rym: in the sense that I have posted these slides We're gonna use to teach everyone all the rules to Puerto Rico.
Rym: They're higher production value than my you might expect.
Rym: stay tuned for a bunch of Rimmelig reviews and specials.
Rym: We're finally kicking a bunch of stuff off.
Rym: But anyway now I leave you with something Playing hard to get But I can't understand.
Rym: I see the story in your eyes.
Scott: That night begins to shine.
Rym: Night begins to shine.
Scott: Night begins to shine.
Scott: Dancing.
Scott: the night begins to shine.
Rym: Talk to.
Scott: My heart was racing.
Rym: I took you home In the driving rain had my mind made up.
Rym: I wanna feel your touch.
Scott: When I look at you I see the story in your eyes.
Scott: When we're dancing That night begins to shine.
Scott: Night begins to shine.
Scott: Night begins to shine When we're dancing.