Rym: It's Tuesday October 9th 2018.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight the 40 games You must play.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: So, uh, all I want to say is that I've said this a lot lately, but 35 ain't 25 It's I think isn't 39 ain't 29.
Scott: You know what?
Rym: Third 30 anything ain't 20 anything.
Rym: So I got my first like legit sports injury that wasn't me hurting myself in an accident Uh-huh, and basically I have.
Rym: I probably have plantar fasciate it Basically the tendon on the bottom of my foot is angry at me.
Scott: a lot of people have that.
Rym: Yeah, and you know what causes it.
Rym: the main things that cause it are being really obese because like the weight will just mess up your being a professional athlete, yep, or Or Over training.
Rym: and I thought to myself because I went to the doctor and they were like have you been exercising more than usual?
Rym: And I thought back and yeah, I ran a half marathon literally every weekend for over a month And the doctor was like, yeah, it'll do it.
Rym: So I can still I can continue to exercise like that But I got it.
Rym: Basically what I'm doing is when I'm doing a really long run like 10 miles 20 miles or whatever.
Rym: I And I got it.
Rym: either stop before I get sloppy or I got a run better when I'm tired.
Rym: Mm-hmm and it'll probably go away.
Scott: Yeah, you know a lot of pro athletes have had that you let Manning had it.
Scott: Yeah hockey players had it.
Rym: lots of people get because it's really common is caused by over training usually.
Rym: So either being really really really athletic or not at all athletic and if you're not in one of those two classes It's really hard to get it.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So, uh, yeah, let's get right in.
Rym: you got any news and you geek bites any stuff on this Tuesday gaming.
Scott: Yes, there was this game called interplanetary which is a game name so generic.
Scott: You can't imagine it hadn't been used yet But it hasn't for at least not for a video game that I know of and it was on steam for $4 this weekend.
Scott: Sadly, it's now $15.
Scott: So what this game is is actually so shockingly simple and but I'm surprised has never been done before right?
Scott: All right, so I don't I mean, it's worth about $4.
Scott: I would be sad if I paid the 15, but here's how the game works.
Scott: ready You get a planet around a solar system.
Scott: All right enemies also have planets around the solar system are On your planet.
Scott: you build stuff and you have to build like everything has to be touching a power plant and you have these cities You try to defend Has a circular radius and you have multiple cities and you know.
Scott: and you know.
Scott: You build things like mines to get resources power plants to get energy, you know intelligence Counterintelligence buildings.
Scott: and then you build weapons, right and then it's turn-based But everyone takes their turn simultaneously Everyone's building then everyone fires and then once everyone's ready all the guns fire and they fire like fucking scorched earth.
Scott: but is Not like scorched earth because you're on a planet that's moving and there's gravity.
Scott: So you
Rym: fire stuff off and and then it circles
Scott: and there's a there's a star And there's planets that have gravity and you adjust, you know The and the other thing is like your planet is a sphere Like what if your gun is on that your planet spins and wherever the planets stop?
Scott: That's where you're firing from.
Scott: So you might not be able to aim your gun and you might need to get guns on both sides of your planet So you can shoot in the different direction.
Rym: This looks pretty up my alley.
Scott: The only other thing that's in the game basically is like it's basically that plus a tech tree.
Scott: so it's like every turn.
Scott: you sort of have to decide like am I gonna spend my energy and my read and my Resources that I my materials that I mind up out of my planet?
Scott: Am I gonna spend them on like building a missile and firing it?
Scott: Am I gonna spend it on building new buildings?
Scott: I'm gonna spend it on you know Right and every turn your energy you get X energy per turn.
Scott: your energy output is per turn and if you don't use it You lose it.
Scott: and your your materials is sort of you can.
Scott: you can stockpile them Right, but the other thing about the game.
Scott: there's like really the whole game.
Scott: besides this giant tech tree.
Scott: It's just a giant tech tree where you get better stuff like better, you know weapons.
Scott: Yeah, you know is that a is a little bit of xcom because you have you build defensive buildings.
Scott: I didn't learn this till after many turns Use all your energy firing all your weapons.
Scott: your defenses need use energy every time they block something.
Scott: So you have to just save unused energy at the end of your turn.
Scott: So your defense is actually do something Like block things that land.
Rym: so turn-based real-time turn-based.
Scott: It's turn-based.
Scott: you spend your turn, you know spending resources on your planet.
Scott: Then you line up all your shots and then you push n turn and then all the shots from all the planets fire at The same time and then you take another turn cuz I see it has hot seat.
Rym: This is actually that could be an okay game to play like late at night.
Scott: I think I see it would be intolerable because it would take if you're played to four players like four times as long And if everyone had a copy.
Scott: so at four dollars not bad.
Scott: You got to learn the tech tree.
Scott: also aiming is a huge pain in the ass.
Scott: It's like super like prediction skill-based aiming until I guess you get more advanced weapons that don't need as much skill.
Scott: But that's probably good because gate like scorch the problem Gives you this red line that shows you you like your predicted trajectory.
Scott: Yeah, but that's based on where the planets are now.
Scott: It doesn't give you any hints about where the planets are gonna be and you can sort of be like well This shot is gonna take this long to get there.
Scott: And so it's like if your shot is going slow and taking a long route the other planet's gonna move a lot If a guy's right next to you, right?
Scott: And then the turns end.
Scott: actually like once everyone fires all the planets start moving and they don't stop for the next turn Until all the shots stop moving or there's none left.
Scott: You can actually fire like one shot with a super long trajectory.
Scott: if you want the planets to move a lot before the next turn.
Scott: right, there's things like that going on, but If you like scorched earth, but wish it was way harder and had a tech tree And you want to spend $15 or wait for it to be $4 again?
Scott: Interplanetary is on Steam You know not not a total bad game.
Scott: You know it's a little.
Scott: it's not super polished, but it's definitely unique and Scratches.
Scott: itches that some other games aren't scratching.
Rym: You know what though it also gives me an idea.
Rym: We I feel like we should stream some versus scorched earth Funky, but I will.
Scott: I will Murphy who next Tuesday.
Rym: well, we'd have to play both low-tech and high-tech Cuz.
Rym: low-tech and high-tech are very different experiences in scorch.
Rym: Yeah, I have a floppy disk with it.
Scott: I get scorched earth to run.
Rym: I will figure out.
Rym: I am confident I can get scorched earth to run in - box all right.
Scott: get it get it going And I'll get it going.
Rym: We'll make this happen.
Rym: This will be a good winter project.
Rym: So in another geek bite because there's no way to do a whole show on this.
Rym: But Scott at PAX kept trying to get me to play this trick-taking.
Scott: So who owned it?
Scott: I forget who told me about it, but I think Rowan Jeremy had the game.
Scott: I forget, but anyway someone was someone told me about.
Scott: I forget It was and they're like you got to play.
Scott: this game is to play a trick-taking game.
Scott: So I played it once and I was like all Rym's got played his game.
Scott: Yeah It's a two-player trick-taking and I was busy, and you kept bothering me, and then finally I was like Rym play this game.
Scott: It's like gonna be your favorite game, and he's like no.
Scott: I don't want to.
Scott: I'm like what's wrong with you.
Rym: But I was right though you were right because we finally set down to play it now first off.
Rym: It is a. the important part is it is a two-player only two-player trick-taking game.
Rym: Yeah, that works.
Scott: is it the only two-player trick-taking that works.
Rym: I know of other two-player trick-taking games, but they do not work.
Rym: But it is a two-player trick-taking game that works with like Trump and like that's a full-on trick-taking game.
Rym: It's fun It's enjoyable and more importantly Playing it once.
Rym: I Basically got a perfect score like I've got maximum score and Scott got Minimum score and it wasn't that much.
Scott: it wasn't that bad.
Rym: It was I got a perfect.
Rym: I literally got like perfect score maximum points every single round.
Rym: You know what I didn't get.
Rym: I didn't get all the sevens.
Scott: every single just got very good score I got.
Rym: you know there's the score thing.
Rym: I got the maximum points from that chart Every single round of the entire game.
Rym: I did.
Scott: I took pictures of it on my phone.
Rym: But here's the deal.
Rym: Here's the interesting thing about it.
Rym: the suits like the cards of different face values have different powers but they're symmetric.
Rym: so you know.
Rym: and two You get.
Rym: I'll read this if you take zero to three tricks you get six points because you are humble.
Scott: That's pretty good.
Rym: if you take Seven to nine tricks you are victorious and you get six points.
Rym: If you take ten or more tricks you get nothing because you're greedy.
Scott: What about four to seven?
Rym: you get like one two three if you take in the middle.
Rym: so basically you want to take?
Rym: most but not all of the tricks or almost no tricks and You don't have to commit to either one of those.
Rym: you just got to play against the other person who is the exact same Scoring.
Rym: that's right.
Scott: There's basically you have an odd number of cards in your hand.
Scott: It's like what 13?
Rym: Yeah, I forget how many you draw it's 11.
Rym: I played it once and got a perfect score Point.
Scott: is you have an odd number of cards in your hand so does your opponent?
Scott: you're gonna play all the cards in some?
Scott: order.
Scott: your opponent is gonna play those cards in a certain order, and that's the whole game and You can't possibly take the same number of tricks.
Scott: so someone is gonna get more points than the other person.
Rym: so games like moo and Wizard like all these other trick-taking games scratch very different no matter.
Scott: all the combinations of two numbers that you know add up to the Total right.
Scott: it's like well if I get zero which is great.
Scott: They get 13 Right which is bad.
Scott: It's like it's like if I take one that's good for me And that means they take 12 which is bad for that and so on.
Scott: it's like every possible Combination of two numbers that add up to the total number of tricks.
Scott: one player scores well and one player scores badly.
Scott: There is no way for both people to score.
Scott: kind of me yep.
Rym: And the last piece the odd numbered cards the face values.
Rym: all have powers.
Rym: there aren't that many.
Rym: I'll just read them to you because that really that's the game.
Scott: like seven is the crazy one?
Rym: Yeah, so like one Swan if you play a one and lose the trick you get to lead the next trick.
Rym: anyway Mm-hmm that is way more powerful than people might think.
Rym: no Yeah, the three the Fox.
Rym: when you play this you may exchange the decree card.
Scott: so like the trump card From a cut with a card in your hand which means not only did you change what trump is but now you took that card Into your hand.
Rym: yep, right the woodcutter when you play this draw one card Then discard any one card face down at the bottom of the deck.
Rym: so swap cards.
Rym: Sevens I'll save to last cuz they're great Nine the witch when determining the winner of a trick with only one nine.
Rym: treat the nine as if it were Trump Mm-hmm.
Rym: so nine can just be like yeah, I'm Trump now.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: You have a nine.
Scott: That's not Trump you play it It's now Trump unless the other person also plays their nine which happened a lot.
Scott: And then y'all their nines are just normal nines.
Rym: The 11 when you lead this if your opponent has a card of this suit they must play either The one of this suit or their highest ranked card of that suits That you can see already like.
Scott: hopefully they don't cheat.
Scott: but yeah the 11 like forces them to like either lose a strong card or Use lose their one.
Scott: You know what you can see.
Rym: like these combined They scratch the same itches.
Rym: that like heart scratches when I play hearts with smart people.
Rym: But the seven after each trick the winner of the trick receives one point for each seven in the trick, right?
Scott: So basically if you play your seven The other person is just gonna play a stronger card and take it and get a point.
Scott: if you play a card Less than seven the other person can just play their seven and take the whole trick if the if you're right.
Scott: So if you're leading until the sevens are out, you basically can't lead anything under seven Because the other person will just you play a seven and take.
Rym: so you're in this really interesting situation.
Scott: But the thing is like you want to use those powers on those cards that are under seven the one three and the five.
Scott: But you can't use those powers.
Scott: in course You'll lose a point it because the other prisoners blew out the seven.
Scott: Yeah and score which is those points are a big deal.
Rym: So it has a like like.
Rym: it feels a lot like playing hearts.
Rym: Like that's the kind of trick-taking game It feels like in my brain.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean when you play the game it sort of has these two phases like the first phase of like, you know Where you're dancing around the seven?
Scott: Yeah, once the sevens come out because someone's either forced to make a bad play or someone just makes a good play Yeah, then the rest of the hand is like oh everything comes out now Like someone changes Trump because they think they're gonna take a bunch of tricks.
Rym: But then you know a strategy and you end up making them take all the tricks But the fact that you can go low or high cuz that's the real dance.
Rym: You don't know if your opponent is trying to take a lot of tricks or not.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, okay I take three tricks and it's like I take a fourth trick.
Scott: It's like, alright Well, I'm well on my way to getting the good number, you know, like eight tricks and whatever the good number is No, but then it's like.
Scott: why now I only have crappy cards left.
Scott: Guess what you're taking him now.
Rym: you you you you you you And I cannot stress enough how thoroughly I crushed Scott in the one time.
Rym: I played this game.
Scott: You got it.
Scott: I mean, I didn't win but the crushing was slightly less than you claim Mmm.
Scott: The other thing is that in order to be good at this game You have to be willing to put in the effort to count the cards and memorize.
Scott: I kept a full count in my head, which was I don't put in that effort in any game because I'm lazy Probably be fine.
Rym: this particular kind of trick-taking game is a lot like advanced wars Like.
Rym: it's the narrow set of games that I will go to that effort for.
Rym: Like.
Rym: I won't do that in other games.
Rym: Like I am NOT counting every single point everyone took when I play T&E or Y&Y.
Rym: As much as I want to.
Rym: I'm not gonna.
Rym: I don't even remember what's in the Castile half the time in El Grande.
Scott: I just I just remember like a feel like I'm like every time the Castillo goes.
Scott: I'm like, alright What you know, that's like one time two times three times like uh-oh A lot of people went in the Castillo this around or someone went in there twice in the same Right is.
Scott: I'll just sort of get a feel for like.
Scott: is it big or is it small?
Scott: I won't count all the cubes.
Rym: So in other news PAX unplugged is actually coming up.
Scott: Isn't this meta moment now?
Rym: I'm not.
Rym: I'm just saying PAX Unplugged is coming up in the news.
Rym: Okay, if you're not aware it is the tabletop specific packs.
Rym: It's all full-on 100% regular old packs.
Scott: the schedule is live.
Rym: There's a main theater like.
Rym: there's panel rooms.
Rym: There's Pokemon like tournament league but they play the CCG instead of the GB the Gameboy games.
Rym: it's Yeah, but it's coming up November 30th and Because it's bigger now.
Rym: You can totally just buy badges like.
Rym: it's all packs.
Rym: That's not sold out.
Rym: You can just get a badge and get a hotel and if you live near if you live live within a couple hours of Philly Which a huge percentage of all Americans do it's actually really easy to get to.
Rym: So in 51 days 16 hours 44 minutes in one second, we hope to see you there.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Well anyway things Of the day.
Rym: So what do you got?
Scott: Is it just a photo?
Scott: An old-timey photo.
Rym: Oh, this photo is real good.
Scott: It's supposedly from Russia or something.
Rym: Well, so, uh, yes Imperial Russia, right?
Scott: So the time of the czars That guy has my mustache anyway, the guy in the photo.
Scott: there are some train tracks and A gentleman and some other people bunch of gender arms.
Rym: some of them have plumes.
Scott: Yeah, usually isn't gender arms French people It's that did you read?
Rym: it says special core of the gender harm.
Scott: All right Anyway, so usually you imagine you know train tracks the vehicles that go on train tracks are trains.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Also hand cars like the old-timey things you see like when there's mining where they push two people two guys go Push the thing up and down right to make the thing go.
Rym: I really like those things.
Rym: for some inexplicable reason They were featured a lot in old cartoons.
Rym: Oh, yeah, so like you they just like they felt like common knowledge.
Scott: you saw them in like Western movies and DuckTales.
Rym: Yep, so if you were that if you were a six-year-old, you just saw hand cars all the time.
Scott: Also Looney Tunes.
Scott: Anyway, uh, the point is this guy instead of using a hand car.
Scott: He's got a foot car.
Scott: It's a penny farthing bicycle but instead of tires The it's basically train wheels a big one and a tiny one.
Scott: and then to keep it upright.
Scott: There is sort of this tripod mechanism with a tiny wheel leaning on the second rail And that basically keeps the bike fully upright even though it's centered on one rail.
Scott: It's leaning on the other rail sort of like a sidecar on a motorcycle And this looks way fun.
Scott: I imagine you just pedal this.
Scott: you can't really fall off.
Scott: The hard part is getting up and down onto it.
Scott: But once you start pedaling, it's probably like alright you fucking go Don't need to stop for anything.
Scott: There isn't gonna be a train coming Like.
Rym: it seems fucking awesome a good way to get around if you gotta get around.
Scott: it's like if these existed.
Scott: It's like was it the only one that existed?
Scott: how come we didn't see these more.
Scott: It's like what's the deal?
Rym: I don't know a lot about the history of
Scott: hand cars Like so well known but these are not known
Rym: other than that I do know there is to this day a modern hand car Enthusiast community of people who build their own and ride them on abandoned train tracks and I kind of want to do it.
Scott: I want to do it.
Scott: That's the thing.
Rym: I want to do one time but not make into a permanent Yeah, and I feel like the way to do it is to go between beak it like that long train that goes across.
Scott: I'm sure the best way to do would be to find a hand car enthusiast who knows where to go.
Rym: Yeah Joy, there's got to be a reddit about it.
Rym: so my thing today is you guys know what am I?
Rym: one of my favorite things like one of my hobbies is Just knowing about the idea of sovereign citizens Like those people who are not driving but traveling and if there's a gold fringe on the flag, then they don't have to pay taxes because reasons and There's a whole like thing about them.
Rym: But this video is actually really fascinating because this is a sovereign citizen dude in a courtroom Trying to argue that he doesn't have to pay like he doesn't have to go to jail for his DUI.
Rym: but the judge is a judge who has dealt with these people a lot and He doesn't yell he doesn't freak out.
Rym: He doesn't just have the guy tased or like removing the courtroom.
Rym: He logically like he.
Rym: he listens to the crazy coming out of the guy's mouth and he responds to it directly and Earnestly.
Rym: and the sovereign citizen guy doesn't know what to do.
Rym: Cuz he's like.
Rym: I am NOT the person John Doe I am the.
Rym: I am the entity John Doe.
Rym: what like all this sovereign system nonsense and the judge is like Well, will the entity blah blah blah tell the person John Doe that they are guilty of DUI?
Rym: and Watching this guy like had almost have this realization that he can't actually respond to another human being who actually addresses the words that came out of his mouth is Fascinating.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Like it's the most respect.
Rym: It's the best way to handle something like that.
Rym: if someone's crazy and you're willing to Address them from the logic of their own crazy.
Rym: It's a highly effective way to talk to crazy people, but it's very very difficult to do.
Scott: I got a new plan don't talk to crazy people Yeah.
Rym: But if you're gonna talk to crazy well sovereign citizen crazy people this specific brand of crazy if I was if they heat that sovereign citizen came to judge Scott's courtroom, I'd be like bailiff.
Rym: This is one for you.
Rym: You're back into don't tase me, bro.
Rym: So in the meta moment, we are going to be at PAX unplugged doing not one but two events.
Rym: We're gonna be doing another learn and win session this time instead of Carcassonne.
Rym: We're doing Puerto Rico.
Rym: We're gonna teach everyone how to play Puerto Rico.
Rym: Then we're gonna teach you like legit how to be great at Puerto Rico And then we're all gonna play a game of Puerto Rico everyone in the room.
Rym: It's gonna be a really good time And we're doing a tightened up version of the 40 tabletop games you must play and I'm gonna up the difficulty level a little bit For it because it's PAX unplugged.
Rym: It's a tabletop audience So there's some low-hanging fruit.
Rym: There's no point in telling these people about.
Rym: I gotta up it a little bit.
Rym: get a little more secure a little more weird.
Rym: It's gonna be a good time.
Rym: Otherwise, we're gonna be at PAX unplugged.
Rym: just playing games like the whole weekend is gonna be great.
Rym: Mm-hmm, if you enjoy our anime stuff you may notice that we uploaded.
Rym: finally We did the fall 2018 season of anime.
Rym: We reviewed every anime that has not yet come out or is coming out just now in fall.
Scott: We somehow managed to keep this show going for a whole year.
Scott: It feels like we just like started.
Scott: Yeah No, we managed to keep the show going.
Scott: so if you want to know our Complete guesses about what the net the current season of anime is gonna be like and which shows to watch or not watch Then you can watch this video and then tell us how wrong we are.
Scott: I'll link to see how shockingly right we are because anime are very transparent.
Rym: And I'll link to it because if you really want the full gig night experience Subscribe to both me and Scott on YouTube because a lot of our panels are on my youtube channel and the live streams.
Scott: Obviously you're watching this live stream at least some of you are and we we have a GeekNights' YouTube channel But we sort of like I can log into it kinda sort of me.
Scott: It's hard.
Rym: Don't worry about the YouTube channel.
Scott: It's all messed up.
Rym: Don't don't?
Rym: we were early adopters of YouTube guys, and there's there's complications of that.
Scott: It was G plus his fault.
Scott: Really?
Rym: Yeah, which is dying.
Scott: It'll fix itself now.
Rym: So if you follow us on G plus I'm not updating it anymore because it's going away you don't say.
Rym: but If you some Scott's channel is where judge anime by its cover is but I will link to it here.
Scott: So you can also just go to front row crew comm our official website And yeah, everything is there.
Rym: everything is there including and you don't have to worry about which channels or anything like that Everything is in one place including the new gig nights book club book, which is 2001 is face Odyssey Which I had never actually read.
Rym: I'd only seen the movie.
Scott: Yep So the deal is basically.
Scott: you mean you've heard of the famous very important movie, which if you haven't seen it You should watch that too.
Scott: But I had thought for all this time.
Scott: Oh that movie was based on a book.
Scott: No That is not correct.
Scott: the correct story of what happened is that Arthur C Clark and Stanley Kubrick worked together on a screenplay while Arthur C Clark wrote the novel which came out after the movie.
Scott: and I've never read the novel despite seeing the movie several times.
Scott: So now we're gonna read that novel and maybe we'll see which Odyssey Rym chooses for the next book club.
Rym: Yep, I actually do have something that is reasonably Odyssey adjacent.
Scott: Does it have the word Odyssey in the title though?
Rym: No, and it doesn't work, but it is a Dungeons & Dragons book.
Rym: No I could go do ma.
Rym: Yeah, I mean look off to Monte Cristo.
Rym: He had quite an Odyssey getting home and getting his revenge Spoilers.
Rym: he gets his revenge mostly.
Rym: So, uh, yeah, that is all the meta and we're here right in the main bit.
Rym: So get over to my thing is his Rym's-kraut people.
Scott: I did so.
Rym: as you know We've been doing a panel and even though we have new like we have a new panel that we haven't done anywhere yet Called a rare game mechanics.
Rym: We're probably gonna do it at magfest But we've been doing this 40 table talk games.
Rym: You must play panel a bunch of times because it's really popular and like it's.
Rym: there's a lot of reasons why people like this kind But the genesis of that was a long time ago.
Rym: We were at some packs.
Rym: Was it a Western East?
Rym: I don't remember.
Rym: and then all these game industry people on stage.
Rym: Some of them were smart some of them not so much.
Rym: Some of them were very knowledgeable and some of them were only knowledgeable of games that came out in the last five years.
Rym: It's a better way to put it, but they were basically having the audience Say a game that they think should be in like the top 100 or top 50 games of all time and they would take that and put it somewhere in the list and bump something out of The list and like have a whole discussion.
Rym: and it was a pretty interesting.
Scott: we were waiting for our panel to start and It was like five industry people like journalists and basically they had an existing list from the last time the panel was run And I think the rule was basically like each person on the panel puts a game on the list and takes a game off the list.
Scott: so it was just sort of like this evolving list of Whatever journalists were on the panel most recently, you know And then like I guess they would have.
Scott: the idea was that they would have the panel again and adjust the list every time It was.
Rym: it was okay But one person on the panel was really good and every time it came around to them They were like dance dance revolution, right?
Scott: Every owner strike everyone on the panel was basically saying dumb stuff except for the one guy saying smart stuff That's it was the spy party guy.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: It was his name Alex something.
Scott: Yeah, anyway, the spy party guy was like, you know, everyone else is putting dumb games up on the list.
Scott: It gets the spy party guys like ddr Mean river like everyone else in the room is silent.
Scott: It's like what.
Rym: why are those two weirdos cheering?
Rym: Why are they talking about RAM?
Rym: So we want to do the same panel Originally for all games, but then we've narrowed it to tabletop because tabletop is gonna underrepresented still in the broader gaming discourse.
Rym: but We want to do this panel the 40 games you must play which is way harder because that includes table.
Scott: Yeah, the problem is there's more than 40 kinds of games.
Rym: Yeah You could never narrow it down that much which means we're just gonna have to make a list of 40 games that are representative of Something.
Rym: so to preface this because basically we're doing our homework the kind of research we normally do for a panel as a show To be lazy and do less total work is what's going on here.
Rym: So we're gonna try to make a list today by going back and forth.
Rym: and the important thing is the rules are these a game cannot make this list just because it was the first of something just because it is like Historically important.
Scott: because I think I think what you're trying to do is you're trying to say, okay, there's a category of game.
Scott: Yeah, what is the the the best most important one in that category?
Rym: Yeah, like is there some?
Rym: or in the very least like we say in the when we do the table top version of this panel Is there one or possibly two things we could say about this game that are you that are unique to this list?
Scott: And that way if someone had we're to play all the games on the list that person would have a very broad and excellent Gaming knowledge and skills and such.
Rym: Yep So do you want to go first you want to take turns try to put things on this list?
Scott: Didier?
Scott: So since you said it why It's pretty much I mean and as long as you don't have a disability that rents you from playing DDR DDR is like the ultimate first best rhythm game.
Rym: I'd argue it was the.
Rym: it was the first still the best rhythm game, even though other rhythm games have come I would argue was the first well executed full body rhythm game, right?
Scott: I mean well I mean there are many many rhythm games before that and it has to be fourth mixer later because it wasn't.
Rym: This wasn't that good guys?
Scott: no Well, I mean even third mix was only a little bit good first and second Like if you ever go back and try to play first and second mix.
Scott: Oh, they're awful.
Scott: The arrows basically don't really go with the music.
Scott: It wasn't until third and really fourth mix that they actually started to get the arrows to be on time With the music to have patterns that match the patterns of the song, right?
Scott: So and in fifth and sixth and seventh I mean, they're still good.
Scott: But they started to add ridiculous crazy stuff that sort of took away from the purity and elegance Of fourth, you know fifth mix a little bit even added the holding arrows and stuff.
Scott: It's really fourth mix was the pure elegant and beautiful one and also had the best music Of all of them.
Rym: It was also one of the first arcade games I really saw you know in the dying days of arcades where it was one of those games that would draw a legit crowd of Spectators.
Rym: there aren't many.
Rym: Well now there aren't many arcades.
Rym: But when there were arcades The only games that drew spectators like not like Mortal Kombat like the fighting games because they drew Spectators who were waiting their turn to play.
Rym: DDR drew spectators who were not going to play it at any point.
Rym: They were just watching it Like.
Rym: I don't think there was any good rhythm game before this that used your body.
Scott: No, DD I mean, you know arcades are basically dead and DDR is so strong that on its own Basically caused a minor arcade revival that is still somehow be a little bit stronger than it was after it collapsed.
Scott: Yep, so it's easy.
Scott: It's that's how powerful DDR is.
Rym: I actually am gonna say doom.
Scott: Why wouldn't you say doom?
Rym: because and I'd argue good too because I think doom - actually is way better level design.
Scott: I think you do want to say doom - you don't want to say doom one Yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So the thing is maybe I'll even break my rule because I did.
Rym: I said I didn't want to.
Rym: the first of anything.
Rym: Wolfenstein 3d was not.
Rym: it was arguably not really the first.
Scott: first person you need to actually must play Wolfenstein 3d now, but it was.
Rym: but also I'd argue Wolfenstein 3d is a puzzle maze game.
Scott: Yeah, it's mostly head shooting It's mostly a maze.
Scott: Yeah, it's mostly find your way through the maze.
Scott: It has secret entrances and it has keys and but doing was a puzzle.
Scott: So you just also have to shoot things and not get hurt so that you can live in the maze.
Rym: But doom - was the first like real modern FPS and it was the first Multiplayer FPS that was good.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Well, I mean doom - it was like, okay, you know, it's still a maze But it's more.
Scott: it was less amazed than Wolfenstein and more shooting.
Rym: Yep, also Wolfenstein walls can only be at 90 degree angles, which really limited the game.
Rym: I know a lot about doom - his engine.
Rym: it is Shockingly impressive and this there were so many clones of doom - it's so pivotal to gaming and it's still legit fun to do a deathmatch in doom.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: I mean, it's also an FPS, but it's sort of hard.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: well, you got to pick just like.
Scott: I don't want to pick more than one 3d FPS Yeah, and it's sort of like.
Scott: well counter-strike is a mod.
Rym: I was gonna say counter-strike if I didn't say doom - but it's like or how even half-life 2 single-player.
Rym: This is the crab people.
Rym: We're just workshopping the panel.
Scott: You know, they're pretty much.
Scott: I think you got to play that because doom is still a 2d FPS, right?
Scott: I think you got to play at 1.5 Right.
Scott: You got to play like 2.5 D.
Rym: You got to play.
Scott: Uh one of the premier 3d FPS is which is pretty much just like counter-strike and Like counter-strike is quake 3.
Rym: How are you?
Rym: counter-strike is Fundamentally different because do drives - doom was like deathmatch multiplayer Like it had a very did.
Rym: there's a lot of things it was doing that were very distinct from what counter-strike did.
Rym: Yeah, counter-strike wasn't really a deathmatch.
Rym: No doom didn't have teams in the modern sense.
Scott: No But I'm talking about.
Scott: you have to have the experience of the real 3d FPS.
Scott: true aim with the mouse and move with the WASD Yeah, and also jump and it matters doom is so fucking fast.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: All right your turn Uh Super Metroid.
Scott: Oh, yeah, you could say Symphony of the Night, but actually, you know, I mean there I think Metroids a better game and a more replayable game Even though the map is maybe smaller than Symphony the night.
Rym: I wouldn't say Metroid one because that game is deeply flawed.
Rym: No, like it's a gets good for its time.
Scott: It is still maybe the best game there is.
Scott: Yeah, period And also definitely the best.
Scott: Metroidvania and you know Symphony of the Night is like, okay You could argue that one instead maybe but it the Symphony of the Night is more like RPG.
Scott: ish It has these RPG elements that take away from the pure and elegant met.
Scott: You know only Metroid elements of Super Metroid.
Scott: Yeah, it doesn't have RPG nonsense Like, you know Symphony the Night doesn't think of you simply tonight everything.
Scott: if they took the RPG stuff out I think it would be maybe better than Super Metroid.
Scott: It's not so.
Rym: I really like all those Castlevania level up your show.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: I mean like.
Scott: both the games are so excellent games.
Scott: But I'm just like, you know, I'm arguing over the tiniest difference between the a plus plus and the a plus game.
Rym: Yep, right But if you haven't played Super Metroid, you don't know games then I'm gonna do an easy one.
Scott: You're not qualified to talk about games.
Rym: I'm gonna say Super Mario Brothers 3 because it is.
Rym: I still think it is like it Redefine what it meant to have a tight Platformer like Super Mario Brothers 3. controls are so like.
Rym: I don't.
Rym: it's hard to 3m.
Scott: it's like, you know people tell about Mario World.
Scott: Mario was again.
Scott: It's a Fantastic.
Scott: It's another case of a plus plus versus a plus.
Scott: but it's like Mario 3 is like.
Scott: is the perfect Mario?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: I don't think any Mario since or before has been as good as Mario 3.
Rym: like Mario 2 the like Mario 2 that became the real Mario doki-doki.
Rym: panic was a Significant leap from Mario 1.
Rym: Mario 3 was a significant leap.
Rym: again.
Rym: Mario world was significantly begin.
Rym: like all those games made radical revolutions to that kind of gaming I think Mario 3 was the biggest jump.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: All right your turn This gets hard Mario galaxy.
Rym: Oh, I never actually played it much.
Scott: Well, so I mean basically it's like you could say Mario 64, right?
Scott: But the problem is Mario 64 has a lot of jankiness, right?
Scott: Yeah, though I played the re-release on even though Mario's yes or was basically the first 3d platformer that was like Playable, you know, you know everyone else had to copy it because all the other ones were just completely unplayable like complete garbage.
Scott: You know Mario Galaxy, it's like all that, you know, there was a in between before galaxy.
Scott: what there was like sunshine.
Scott: It was I don't remember.
Rym: I like sunshine a lot.
Scott: All those games are good, but galaxy is still I think maybe the best one.
Scott: I probably gonna play it.
Scott: It doesn't have you know, the the kind of nonsense, you know.
Scott: It doesn't have any flaws or other weirdness, you know, I guess, you know, you could even say Odyssey now.
Scott: But I think the only reason I don't say Odyssey now because maybe it's too soon.
Rym: So I would say speaking of too soon.
Rym: I am legit gonna say Breath of the Wild Why not?
Rym: and my argument is that?
Rym: Zelda.
Rym: if you're a game designer or like like.
Rym: if you're eating like there's reasons why you might want to go play Zelda 1 Zelda 2 Zelda 3 but Not everyone needs that experience.
Rym: I think Breath of the Wild encapsulates the intent of like the original Zelda games with modern execution.
Scott: The only thing you know, it's like Zelda 1.
Scott: I look at Zelda 1 But the problem is my Zelda 1 experience is tainted because I played it when I was a kid with nothing else to do except Bomb.
Scott: every bush Bomb every wall.
Scott: burn every bush, right?
Scott: It's like you know.
Rym: I'm climbing every tree looking for car rocks and shit.
Rym: in Breath of the Wild.
Scott: It's not this brute force of using a blue candle walking off the screen using the blue candle.
Rym: I just think back so much.
Scott: It's like Zelda 1 is a design that like if you don't cheat and you don't already have everything memorized To play it now fresh without any guides or anything.
Rym: That's a. that's a tall order.
Rym: It's a tall order for the year 2018 But also you see like what it was trying to do.
Rym: But Breath of the Wild like all the things you read about What cuz Zelda 1 was supposed to evoke the feeling of a kid exploring the woods?
Scott: And it does.
Rym: Breath of the Wild does that like?
Scott: Breath of the Wild is the no.
Scott: No one will play it that way in 2018.
Rym: Breath of the Wild is what Zelda 1 would have been if modern technology existed back.
Scott: Then yep, like I honestly firmly believe that feels like it gives you that same feeling of Zelda 1 like yeah Walk up to some ruin spooky ruins That's.
Scott: you know that that feeling you get when you're walking around in Breath of the Wild.
Scott: when I went Wild when I went into that haunted forest you see some landmark out there you go out there and inspect it And there's all kinds of you know it's like whoo.
Scott: that feeling It's the same feeling I had when like I discovered the graveyard in Zelda 1 like whoo.
Rym: yeah When I went into the haunted forest in Breath of the Wild and that music gets a little weird And it's dark and it got creepy.
Rym: I got that chill that I haven't felt since I was like seven.
Rym: right.
Scott: only it's playable.
Scott: I'm like you know.
Scott: yep, Zelda 1 is only playable for me because I can beat it super fast.
Scott: It got speedrun fast, but still super fast.
Rym: I'm gonna say it.
Scott: I memorized every fucking thing.
Rym: I think Breath of the Wild is the best Zelda game if you take all categories like all attributes into consideration.
Rym: Maybe others are better at different things, but Breath of the Wild is the most holistically good Zelda.
Scott: hmm Are we only doing video games?
Scott: No any game any game you got to play?
Rym: I Was trying to think about what tabletop game what RPG I got.
Rym: this is actually.
Rym: This is way harder than the top 40 tabletop.
Rym: like way harder.
Scott: I'm trying to think of sports.
Rym: That's why I was thinking about that too.
Scott: What is this?
Scott: if you're gonna play a sport?
Scott: What is this sport?
Scott: you must play tennis maybe?
Rym: Like tennis could fit Air hockey.
Scott: I was thinking about air hockey also.
Scott: air hockey actually jungle speed Slalom skiing I mean they're definitely bowling.
Scott: There has to be some.
Scott: it's like.
Scott: it's like yeah, okay, what is it you think of a sport you must play?
Scott: It's like well.
Scott: Yeah, you should play one, but which if you must?
Rym: I know what I'd say because it but it's one of those, but it's not my turn.
Rym: I got one.
Rym: that's really good, but it's it's just.
Rym: you know how.
Scott: in the tabletop It's like I could say like oh you got a swim, but you learn to swim But you know I don't think you have to competitive The thing that takes it into game in sports, so I'm gonna say something.
Rym: the one I have that it's your turn So I'm not gonna say it.
Rym: the one I thought of is the same bullshit that happens in our 40 tabletop games Where here's a great game that you can't play?
Rym: Okay, I got a really good one all right.
Rym: I'm gonna say next Yes, I was gonna say vampire.
Scott: That's not that's not even close to must play.
Rym: I think it is must play.
Rym: No, I think it combines.
Scott: you just say tag tag is must play.
Rym: I just said you know what I'll say.
Rym: some form attack Can't grow up into an adult if you haven't played tag, dude We were at a party a couple years ago where we all started playing.
Rym: these kids start to play in tag.
Scott: Have you seen the professional tag?
Scott: Yeah, make like obstacle course in a square.
Rym: Oh my god.
Scott: They put two people in and one person.
Rym: those maneuvers with the dude were like Spinning out of the way someone's basically park or the competition.
Scott: It's how long can you go without getting tagged?
Scott: yep?
Scott: It's the combination of endurance and maneuverability.
Scott: Yeah, ooh, so if you don't think you need to play that, but you do need to play tag all right So can you?
Scott: how can you grow up as a human being if you went sport?
Rym: Then I'm gonna go role-playing game.
Rym: if I had to pick one role-playing game.
Rym: You know I don't think for this.
Scott: I don't think I'd say that you know you must play D&D.
Rym: I think in the 40 tabletop games D&D is definitely on that list, but for games as a whole I would pick a different RPG mm-hmm, and I think I might actually on it.
Rym: I'm really torn on this, but I think I'd say burning wheel mmm, and my argument is burning you must play burning man.
Rym: Yeah, because I could take some other indie RPG.
Rym: But burning wheel has like it has a the best balance of meat in a lot of different areas and introduces a wide array of Role-playing concepts in an interesting form in a way that many indie RPGs are too focused for this kind of list.
Scott: I think the problem is is that it's like you know It's there you definitely like.
Scott: there's a category of game And it's like aha you definitely must play a game in this category right like.
Scott: I might say You must play a LARP, but it's like.
Scott: well which LARP?
Scott: you know how?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I'm not super knowledgeable.
Rym: the listeners given us ideas now anyway.
Scott: I'm super not super knowledgeable about LARP.
Scott: So I'm only moderately knowledgeable about LARP.
Scott: So I don't know which LARP is the LARP.
Scott: like if you ask me which Metroidvania is the Metroidvania.
Scott: It's Super Metroid no question right, but you say which LARP is the LARP.
Scott: I don't know, but you definitely should play a LARP at some point in your life.
Rym: You know we have that preface when we do the tabletop one.
Rym: I think I need to change it a little bit.
Rym: I think here like the first of the most important can matter sometimes.
Rym: But I think we want to make a point about for a category.
Rym: It's almost arbitrary, but it's not arbitrary.
Scott: There is one that is like the definitive one.
Scott: We're just too dumb to know what it is.
Rym: Yeah, so we say that someone who knows about everything.
Rym: so we say that we're not.
Rym: you gotta play an indie RPG.
Rym: We cannot pick the one like.
Scott: what if someone knew that FPS has existed, but like there You know it's like they're like.
Scott: well you got to play an FPS, but I don't know.
Scott: I'm not knowledgeable at FPS.
Scott: How do I know which one's the best one?
Rym: Maybe the answer is we're gonna unlike the tabletop one will change this panel a lot every time we do it.
Rym: You know what fuck it the way we do it.
Rym: I'm it was my turn.
Rym: I'm burning wheel.
Rym: fuck it.
Rym: That's the one I put on the list.
Rym: What do you got Tetris?
Rym: the listener suggested Tetris literally like a minute ago?
Scott: Oh good job listener.
Rym: Yeah, no, I can't.
Scott: your award is you don't have to listen anymore.
Scott: Go away.
Rym: Tetris is foundational.
Rym: The end which Tetra?
Rym: no we're not getting into rich Tetris.
Scott: It doesn't matter which Tetris a Tetris.
Scott: They're all Gameboy Tetris.
Scott: Yep, that's the that's the normal.
Scott: That's the main Tetris Gameboy Tetris.
Rym: So I'm gonna go to a hard guard game like trick-taking.
Rym: you just talk about that.
Rym: I think I'm gonna say hearts hearts good as much as I like wizard and all that stuff like hearts is Really like a distilled trick-taking experience.
Rym: There's a lot of cultural touchstones.
Scott: If you're gonna go there I gotta say and this also covers basically all roll and move games He did is like this, you know, there's move your mice games, right?
Scott: Yeah, and it's like well you go to monopoly you could go to candy land, which you don't even make any decisions.
Scott: You go to Uncle Wiggly, you know, but you know what?
Scott: I can cover all of those and get like two for one by saying you must play bad game.
Scott: Oh Bad gammon is roll and move.
Scott: But also if you gambling die.
Scott: It's also a game of gambling but also a game of World unity.
Scott: if you travel somewhere where people play back in and figure out what version they play before you get there.
Rym: Dude, I have all these photos in my flicker of just like old Turkish dudes playing it in cafes all over Istanbul.
Scott: Yep, that's what I'm saying.
Rym: Yeah, that's it.
Rym: That's it.
Rym: These games aren't necessarily play.
Scott: I played bad game with old guys in Israel.
Rym: I spent a lot of time as a kid playing backgammon and while that game does not scratch any itches I have is a mod like as a Experienced season game design.
Rym: like dude that gammon is still like.
Rym: I'm glad I spent a lot of time playing backgammon as a kid.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So we were gonna table talk for a while.
Rym: I should go back into a video game or something.
Rym: This gets hard to do in a hurry.
Scott: Like you think it'd be easier to have a much broader pool to get a category and then pick the the premier Ultimate, you know game of that category.
Rym: You know what bionic fucking commando.
Rym: You just picking games you like.
Scott: that's not the odds not the Top game in any category.
Scott: No, I'm gonna say rearmed because the top game in any category.
Scott: now because it's just a platform We might have Mega Man 2 is the same category in his way.
Scott: better name.
Rym: Another game in the genre of.
Rym: you can't jump.
Rym: Here's a grappling arm.
Scott: You're just picking games you like.
Rym: now the on a commando.
Rym: I don't think the original NES game you could skip but rearmed is both this perfect reimplementation.
Scott: I'm not saying it's a bad game.
Scott: I'm saying it is not the Best game in any category.
Rym: I'm saying this list has to be arbitrary.
Rym: There's no way to do it.
Scott: I think everyone should I say the gate the category.
Scott: the winner of that category would be a Different game with platform.
Scott: You could even just say the Super Metroid just covers that you don't even need.
Scott: no I'd say they're fundamentally different games because honestly I Respect super mature not far enough from each other.
Rym: I respect Super Metroid.
Rym: I don't like Super But by a commando, holy fuck That was mine.
Scott: I picked it Rym's of favorite game list.
Rym: No, it's not.
Rym: I've got thank you hearts ain't necessarily my favorite game.
Rym: Anyway, that's your turn.
Scott: Those are Rym just picks rooms.
Rym: favorite games got to pick something arbitrary.
Scott: Yeah, that's not arbitrary.
Rym: if I say Street Fighter 2 Oh Strange she has original or championship edition.
Scott: It does either.
Scott: one is fine.
Scott: Any anything that says Street Fighter 2 on it between Street Fighter 2 that only had eight characters all the way up to?
Scott: Super Street Fighter 2 turbo any one of those.
Scott: they're all Street Fighter 2.
Rym: so why Street Fighter 2 Cuz?
Scott: Street Fighter 2 is the main fighting game of all time.
Scott: every fighting game since Street Fighter 2 is based on Street Fighter 2. now Bushido blade She's not.
Rym: I'm not putting Bushido blade on the list, even though I like it.
Rym: Don't worry Right.
Scott: It's like really.
Scott: you could consider every fighting game after Street Fighter 2 to just be a sequel to Street Fighter 2.
Scott: No every 2d one, right?
Rym: Whoo, this gets hard.
Rym: I'm gonna suck.
Rym: They're gonna go with arcade game.
Rym: That isn't DDR But there's a lot of arcade games that are fundamental or important But they're not actually fun or they live.
Rym: they could not hold up to any modern sensibility at all.
Rym: So it gets hard.
Scott: It's not.
Scott: it's a game that it's.
Rym: pick a category and say okay I think we gotta get away from category and treat this a little differently.
Scott: No, I think you're just.
Scott: you're just failing.
Scott: I got plenty.
Scott: I just pick a category and then I know the best game in that category.
Rym: Yeah, best the category of can't jump bionic arm.
Scott: That's not Game.
Rym: I don't know why you're having a hard time with this.
Rym: Some sort of other sporty thing.
Rym: cuz tag is pretty fundamental, but there are other sport type games like cycling stuff.
Scott: You don't need to ride in a race though.
Scott: Yeah and saying I need to have ridden a bike if able That's not a game.
Rym: that's the.
Rym: yeah, we're definitely has to be game.
Rym: we're talking about games that have some form of competition.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: Maybe I'll go with a non-competitive game.
Rym: That's still a game.
Scott: Actually say why are you stretching so deep when you haven't even skimmed the surface yet?
Rym: But cuz I could go something like dixit like that kind of game.
Scott: No dixit is not a must-play game.
Scott: No, that's not a must-play game.
Rym: I we did.
Rym: Yeah, I think that's a must-play game.
Rym: They're very illustrative of fundamental points on gaming.
Rym: Mmm old console games are tough cuz I don't know.
Rym: I haven't such a hard time now trying to think of something that breaks from.
Rym: I see a lot of paths to go.
Rym: I'm trying to find up.
Rym: I'm trying to find a new path.
Scott: I could do like 10 in a row Alright, then I'll guess I'll go.
Rym: I'll go arbitrary again.
Rym: Let's go back into tabletop.
Rym: Let's pick a euro.
Rym: I think if I had to pick a euro like one of those euros.
Rym: I'm gonna come back to Tigger's and Euphrates.
Scott: Why wouldn't you?
Scott: That's obvious, yeah, cuz it's.
Rym: it's the one why and why we haven't played enough to understand.
Rym: T&E has stood the goddamn test of time.
Rym: That's right.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Let's see walk sideways and hit things games Streets of Rage.
Rym: Streets of Rage is kind of bad.
Scott: What walk sideways and hit things game is not bad?
Rym: Oh, yeah, that's my point.
Rym: Why do you need to play one to know?
Scott: I think you need to play a walk sideways and hit things game.
Scott: You should play Streets of Rage which is the best one and has the most bump in music.
Rym: Why not River City Ransom which has much more game?
Scott: River City Ransom is RPG and is not like all the other.
Scott: walk sideways and hit things games.
Rym: Hmm All right, so along those lines then Sport games like console or PC games that are like the football game.
Rym: No, it's my turn and I'm gonna say Because ice hockey?
Scott: I don't think you might even though ice hockey is good.
Scott: I don't think you must play ice.
Rym: I'm gonna say something though.
Rym: name an Actually better ice hockey video game NHL 94. that game's not good.
Rym: When was the last time you played NHL 97 or whatever 94 recently?
Rym: Yeah, do you remember?
Rym: What's different?
Rym: I don't remember 94.
Rym: I remember 97.
Scott: NHL 94 is the best one.
Rym: Is it?
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Is it really?
Rym: Yep Is it better than ice hockey?
Rym: Yep, if we were gonna play an ice hockey game right now, you'd rather play that.
Scott: Yeah, why not?
Scott: Because I don't remember NHL 9 hockey is not only looks like ice hockey.
Scott: It's a great game It's fun, but it's not.
Scott: it's not actually like super.
Rym: Oh, yeah NHL 94 is before they change the views.
Rym: All right All right I can see that but I'm going with ice hockey because it's such a pure During.
Rym: it's in that same category is like super dodgeball or windjammers like those very direct competitive games.
Rym: All right your turn we don't have to go till 40 We're gonna stop when we hit the end of the time here right?
Scott: Mario Kart.
Rym: Oh Which one?
Rym: because honestly the original Mario Kart is not worth Ever playing.
Scott: Well, I mean if you ask Scott, it's it's Mario Kart Super Circuit for the Game Boy Advance.
Scott: Yeah, I kind of agree with you, but that's the best Mario Kart because of the skill.
Scott: That's the skill Mario Kart.
Scott: I'm putting that whole one down in detail But the I think you know, you just really does it matter which one as the n64 when I say is the worst.
Scott: So it's like in the SNES one, even though it was the first one is not good.
Scott: so pretty much anything after the N64 the Wii or the GameCube or the the switch or the DS or no any one of those is fine.
Rym: All right I'm gonna say an arcade game like classic arcade and I'm going with Dig Dug.
Rym: Dig Dug because Dig Dug We haven't dealt like the bottom is not really me.
Scott: Dig Dug is our game.
Scott: But I mean, I think space invaders over Dig Dug.
Scott: I think Dig Dug is Malaga over either one.
Rym: Yeah I feel like they're different.
Scott: Yeah, they are.
Scott: but the thing is every back in those days every game was different right.
Scott: so you can't you can't just be like Oh, you have to play every single old classic arcade game because each one was unique.
Rym: Yeah, so that's why I got it at some point.
Rym: arbitrarily pick one.
Scott: I would arbitrarily pick Galaga over Dig Dug even though.
Rym: But I feel like for a modern person with modern gaming sensibilities you sound from a Dig Dug.
Rym: They'll get more out of the experience than they will out of Galaga.
Scott: That's cuz you know until they realize you can capture a ship then the eyes of the whole.
Rym: There's been a lot of modern schmup remakes or just fucking pac-man miss pac-man Miss pac-man's better than pac-man miss pac-man.
Rym: Is that yours want to put that on here?
Rym: - no It's saying.
Scott: sure please dig dug in this bag.
Rym: I will say miss pac-man is objectively better than pac-man like in every possible way obviously in fact.
Rym: actually the Atari 7800 miss pac-man is way good Like way good, it's not as good as arcade miss pac-man.
Rym: anyway I said Dig Dug where we can do like a couple more then we're gonna stop.
Scott: What are the categories we got here?
Scott: I just did racing That's right.
Scott: Mario Kart's better than all your forces and your Gran Turismo.
Scott: Yeah I'm gonna say I think F-Zero wasn't like revolutionary, but you got to play a Final Fantasy 6 bitches.
Scott: Or Chrono Trigger is tough call.
Scott: Yeah, you know let's say Chrono Trigger.
Scott: I think Chrono Trigger because Final Fantasy 6 edges out by the tiniest bit.
Rym: Here's why I'd say Final Fantasy 6 Does focus a lot more if you play the legit version at least like 4n6 a lot more on.
Rym: There's a lot of like tactical level up stuff and like strategy and fighting and it is way longer.
Rym: Chrono Trigger has a lot more emotional resonance per unit time spent playing.
Scott: you got to play Chrono Trigger.
Rym: Yeah, like Chrono Trigger is such.
Rym: Actually I saw a great essay.
Scott: if you're gonna play one JRPG It's Chrono Trigger.
Scott: if you're gonna play two JRPGs it's Final Fantasy 6 and if you're gonna play three It's Super Mario's Paper Mario Thousand-Year Door, and that's you don't need to play any other JRPG garbage.
Rym: We've gone on for Basically an entire GeekNights show, so I think we'll just stop here with the list we arbitrarily came up with.
Scott: Why don't you play some games?
Rym: you got some shade for a particular choice?
Rym: You made in terms of Streets of Rage here.
Scott: What's wrong?
Scott: What sideways walk?
Scott: What sideways and beat things up?
Scott: game is better.
Rym: I'm gonna really see.
Rym: let me go back to this here Too wrong in a row for Scott.
Rym: Let's see Doo doo doo.
Rym: Streets of Rage, but not Streets of Rage 2. what the hell Scott.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Streets of Rage 1 has more bumping music than Streets of Rage 2.
Rym: Actually Streets of Rage on the GBA was not.
Scott: the music in Streets of Rage 2 is non bumping the game of gear.
Rym: You know what.
Rym: we're gonna do one more, and then we'll stop.
Rym: I am gonna say Advance Wars Because there wasn't because that genre culminated and ended with Advance Wars and no one's ever been able to make something better than Advance Wars Civilization any one of them even more even one doesn't matter.
Rym: Yep, all right.
Rym: We're getting there at that point.
Rym: You started into got a second for you master of Orion or you.
Scott: You don't got to play master right if you played sieve.
Rym: Yeah, I think that's true.
Scott: You must play.
Rym: I will stop because I'm running out of steam here, and I'm tired.
Scott: I got all the steam I can get going.
Scott: I'm more knowledgeable with me.
Rym: this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: be sure to visit our Website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: remember GeekNights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Rym: It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this particular episode of GeekNights are Craig Oliver Ellen Joyce Heidi McNicholas shimming rubiobolus kangen in the sky kjartavijan.
Rym: mystady.com.
Rym: linki GJ Scootalone Lee Roberto Kingsley cash on Jaeger Matthew Smith Nicholas Brando mr.
Rym: Strong stretch in four to one creations Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn Shervin Von Harl Rory Rochelle, Monta, Nona Superboy tripwire sailor Vista Don sh like Joshua Joe star Clinton Walton written from New Zealand Ryan Perrin drew open Lander Finn Chris midkiff Daniel Redman Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: There won't be a show on Thursday because Emily and I'll be in London and then there will be maybe only one show next week Because Scott will also be out of town.
Rym: So, uh, we're probably gonna do the next Wednesday show on tatami galaxy of all things.
Rym: So yeah now I leave you with Runaway with me and the poltergeist and ghoul.
Rym: We can wander through the darkness And play by our own.
Rym: Run away with me to a cavern shades like home Where we'll build our own forever And never dance alone.
Scott: Whoa, sometimes I forget how totally deep I can be.