Rym: It's Tuesday, November 6th 2018.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Scott: rollin rights Let's do this.
Rym: So yeah, I would say if you live in the u.s.
Rym: And you're listening to GeekNights go vote.
Rym: But you're probably listening to the show The day after where everyone knows the results is probably too late.
Rym: So I hope you voted.
Rym: I personally Respect you less if you didn't unless you were refused the right to vote in which case you should go fight someone.
Scott: I just find it.
Scott: I continually find it shocking like I all on Twitter people like oh my god vote.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: does anyone on Twitter?
Scott: Following?
Scott: you really need to be reminded to vote.
Scott: So what I've discovered like the reason it could just it could just be because I am.
Rym: I guess you curate your Twitter feed like I do.
Scott: I'm just well just saying like in my circle of people not just on the internet just in general like I've voted every time since I was 18.
Scott: I'm pretty sure you voted almost every time.
Scott: Did you send some absentee ballots back to Michigan?
Rym: Yeah, but I sent some back to Connecticut when there was a couple of midterms or all actually some off years where I didn't vote because I Was traveling overseas and I didn't set up the absentee in time.
Scott: I mean, you know, they weren't in beacon.
Scott: We went to the VA Hospital the the veteran center, whatever it's called.
Scott: They still had the good machines.
Rym: they moved our lever polling place to a different place.
Scott: Yours got moved.
Rym: it got moved last year and mine It's way further away and there's no subway.
Scott: that takes you though Mine is so has been the same for nine years since I lived here.
Scott: Yeah, right and not only is it the same place the same two people at the desk the same two ladies at the desk Same deal.
Scott: I don't remember the number because I know where they are even though I do know the numbers right?
Scott: The thing is for for the first time ever even more than any past election Even presidential elections There was a line today.
Scott: at this morning before I went to work the line today I went.
Scott: there was a line because there were five scanning machines and two of them were not working.
Rym: Oh So I saw more people in law.
Scott: So it was two pages.
Scott: So you got to put you got to tear it apart and you got to put in one page and then put in the other page.
Scott: Order, it doesn't matter what orientation but you got to put anyone and then put in.
Rym: I watched a lot of people having a lot of trouble understanding the fact that there were two pages to deal.
Scott: well Because those people haven't, you know, I voted in the same place the same way nine times.
Scott: Yeah, and I'm a person who can whoosh.
Scott: I wish at the MTA to buy a metro card I wish at the grocery store.
Scott: I wish to get past the TSA Right.
Scott: I'm a person who can whoosh through things.
Scott: people who can't whoosh through things.
Scott: They got problems for something that for I don't know why they don't do it every year.
Scott: They should be used to it by now.
Rym: So even though I like read those propositions We were voting on like a million times thought about him a lot.
Scott: I read him again I went with I went yes.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: Yes, and I almost went yes.
Scott: No, yes Yeah, I was thinking that too because I didn't see any compelling.
Scott: there were a lot of people arguing for yes.
Scott: No No, there were some right-wing people arguing for no, no.
Scott: No, yeah, mostly people who had a hard-on for hating the mayor.
Scott: That's it.
Rym: the only complaint I could find about two was that it gives the mayor's office too much power.
Rym: it does but The risk of there being a Republican mayor in New York City in the modern era pretty low.
Rym: And if anything, I think the next mayor is gonna be left of de Blasio Because it's the city voting.
Rym: I don't have to worry about upstate.
Scott: Yeah, but yeah, so I just want the SES.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Yeah, it's fine.
Rym: So I hope you voted and I hope you're listening to this.
Rym: cuz I'm.
Rym: It's not in the bag, but I'm hopeful.
Rym: That's all I'm gonna say.
Rym: Okay, you're probably here to escape from all that.
Scott: Yeah, that's what I'm.
Scott: that's what I got to say.
Scott: Right is that there's too many people who like sit around all night constantly watching.
Rym: I'm gonna do that as it.
Scott: yeah That's you know, that's fucking stupid.
Scott: right when I'm playing a board But I'm playing a board game.
Scott: if I take my turn and I can't do anything till it's my turn again I just get up from the table.
Scott: I don't got to pay attention to what the fuck's going on until it's my.
Scott: until I can do something again You can't do nothing right?
Scott: Well, do I need to sit there while the score is counted?
Scott: No, I'll just come back and find out after everyone else finished counting the score.
Scott: It's tough though.
Scott: And this is a board game where I don't get another turn until next fucking year.
Scott: So I don't got to do nothing.
Scott: Why should I pay attention all night for no reason?
Scott: I'm gonna watch ice hockey.
Scott: Yeah, there's a good ice hockey.
Scott: I'm gonna play some video games.
Scott: I'm gonna read a book.
Scott: So I'm gonna watch a little ice hockey.
Rym: But I got a better plan to avoid cuz I am compelled because I have this weird duality where there's the rational like.
Rym: I have put the input into the system that I can and there's nothing I can do.
Rym: and then there's the.
Rym: I Appreciate this as a spectacle and enjoy watching it burn.
Scott: You know what a better spectacle is hockey 39 saves baby.
Rym: Oh My god that game I was there.
Rym: lung quiz.
Rym: good He is one of the greatest goalies in the history of the game like hot game.
Rym: Yeah, that was.
Rym: that was a real good game.
Rym: Also the Leafs game the day before.
Scott: it was crazy good Out of watching on New York.
Scott: it.
Rym: yeah, so you know what you know, what's good watching the leaf.
Rym: So I don't care that much about beat the everliving shit out of Pittsburgh 5-0.
Scott: Yeah, fuck you.
Rym: Yeah It was a good game to watch because of that.
Rym: but So what I'm gonna do and if any of you are watching the live stream and you want to get in on this I'm just gonna get as many people that can together and I'm gonna have one monitor where I got the flow the f5 and going On automatically of like the 538 breakdown.
Scott: You don't need that.
Rym: Well, I'm gonna be in the discord distracting myself playing overwatch with all of you.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: You just do that one only just just the second part.
Scott: Fuck the first gonna do both.
Rym: It's my new plan.
Rym: I play overwatch during election nights.
Scott: Just put my face in instead of the election.
Scott: Whatever also Related more to gaming also another thing we should do instead right?
Scott: We shouldn't play some stupid overwatch on election night.
Scott: We should just play time.
Rym: I am pro-scare.
Scott: bring die marker to unplugged.
Rym: I am.
Rym: I don't own die marker.
Scott: You had it.
Scott: you owned it.
Scott: No, I didn't you did?
Scott: you had it in Beacon?
Rym: Did I?
Rym: yes the fuck is it?
Scott: you own die marker?
Rym: I do not fuck if I remember owning die marker.
Rym: you own die marker if it's anywhere.
Rym: It's next to Tikal Demarca, I'm gonna go find it if I own demarca.
Rym: I'm gonna go find it.
Scott: you own it.
Scott: You own it.
Rym: Are you sure?
Scott: If you don't own it then you lost it.
Scott: or someone stole it or you sold it someone who.
Rym: I just stolen it.
Scott: It was a copy in the house in Beacon.
Scott: We played it once.
Scott: it belonged to not me.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: I didn't buy it.
Rym: I only remember playing it with Luke.
Rym: Are you sure Alex didn't own it and he just left it in our house?
Scott: That's possible.
Rym: I think Alex owned it because the other game Alex owns that we cannot get is Vinci.
Scott: I mean, that's possible.
Scott: But what?
Rym: how much money I'd have to give Alex to get his Vinci from him?
Scott: I'm sure he's not using it.
Rym: Yeah, but I don't know if you'd want to part with it.
Scott: I wouldn't either.
Rym: So the other thing that I did when we're getting into the news is as you know Overwatch Competitive.
Scott: well, well, it was it was it was Blizzcon.
Scott: Oh, there's a lot of Blizzard.
Rym: No Yeah, the the the overwatch competitive scene like the professional scene.
Rym: There are some a-plus games going down.
Scott: Also, there is a new Starcraft 2 champion who is not from Korea.
Scott: The first time ever a non-korean made it to the finals and the first time ever a non-korean won.
Scott: Congratulations, I forget your name and I don't have it on my screen.
Rym: So I Tried something I decided at the end of the previous competitive season to do something I've never done and because when I play overwatch, it's always like super chill people because I'm usually playing with like Gold's Maybe some Platinum's maybe upper Silver's at most.
Rym: So, uh, I joined the random solo queue by myself to do ten placement matches.
Rym: Uh, yeah, holy fuck are the worst people on earth Doing that?
Rym: I got put with teams with the things that I noticed the most are number one.
Rym: There is always always always 100% of the time a group of two That is together in the game with a bunch of randos who never joined the voice chat.
Rym: never communicate and lose the game for you okay, and to Every single person who was salty in the voice chat was French Canadian Mm-hmm.
Rym: I don't know if it was just an artifact of when I was playing a beer geography.
Rym: Yeah, right every time someone was getting real butter.
Rym: It sounded French Canadian.
Rym: But that was at the end of the season like three days to go.
Rym: So I made it six matches in and it was so bad that I just stopped and I even stopped livestreaming.
Rym: I just gave up.
Rym: so I did it again at the beginning of the season and it was like night and day.
Rym: I actually found some good people and I played some real games and My new plan is to just play rando competitive overwatch Rank be damned.
Rym: Let's just ride this train straight into hell, right?
Scott: Well, I mean that's the Hearthstone is the same thing because the way they do the seasons and most Blizzard games Right with their ranks and ladders is they give you everyone a big reset or whatever and every month.
Scott: So what happens at the beginning of the month?
Scott: Everyone is doing the same thing and getting back into it has been d ranked or has to place match again.
Scott: So because you're in with everyone you get matched really well with people who are close to your level, right?
Scott: You know things are doing good, right?
Scott: But then at the end of the month if you're still doing like placement matches or you're like You know low ranks at the end of the month Like if you play Hearthstone at the end of the month ranked and you didn't play all month because you're just not that into it I can just like get win streak like up like ding ding ding ding.
Scott: But if I play in the early part of the month It's like depending on how much I've been downranked.
Scott: It's like yeah, there's people there who are about my level who also got down, right?
Rym: Everything's still about where it belongs, you know, so in some news The TLDR is Salty.
Rym: babies are mad that a company released a game that is not targeted at them Mm-hmm, and they're mad enough to have tanked Blizzard stock.
Rym: I don't know how the stock market so stupid And What all I want to say is nothing I am about to say is investment advice.
Rym: I am NOT giving you investment advice.
Rym: I am simply talking about decisions I have made and personal opinions I have based on publicly available information.
Rym: I Have to say that a lot on getting nice.
Rym: So here's the deal.
Rym: Blizzard has Blizzcon.
Rym: Uh, I wouldn't go to Blizzcon, but this comes like.
Rym: it's not bad.
Rym: It's not like.
Rym: I guess I mean Where they fuck it up.
Scott: It's better than e3 or twitchcon.
Rym: I think it's more like going.
Scott: I just don't see a real reason to go there.
Scott: We were discussing this on the forum.
Scott: right is the most of?
Scott: Blizzcon is an advertisement.
Scott: So why would you pay and travel to attend an advertisement?
Rym: No, I would say based on the content edit It's more like going to AGD queue.
Scott: AGD queue isn't really the greatest thing to attend either.
Scott: but at least it's not an advertisement.
Scott: and if it is an advertisement It's an advertisement for charity.
Scott: A big part of cons like that like both of those is The drinking and hanging out outside of the con which is you can do that without buying a badge.
Scott: I'm not I'm not.
Scott: I'm not judging anyone for attending a gathering.
Scott: attending a gathering is great No matter where it is.
Scott: I'm saying why buy the badge?
Scott: right if Pax did not have anything valuable on the inside of it And I still wanted to attend to gather I would honestly just go to Paxes that are nearby and not go into the Pax and not buy a badge.
Scott: In fact, I hate to say this I'm only judging the buying a badge and going inside value not be going to hang out with people value.
Rym: But anyway, like Blizzcon is fine because it's at least it's run well Unlike twitchcon like it doesn't fail in basic ways,
Scott: but
Rym: at Blizzcon they announced that there's going to be a Diablo Mobile game an MMO for phones
Scott: and I was like, oh I can clear that's actually you know It's like Diablo is a game where you mindlessly click on monsters and get loot and then you do it again and again and again And get better loot and more stats.
Rym: and Was that is just Diablo, right?
Scott: That's what Diablo is.
Scott: So I'm like, you know what that kind of game.
Scott: if you're sitting at your PC You really want to play a mindless game like that and very rarely maybe once every couple years I'll spend like a day playing a stupid game like that.
Scott: Yeah In fact, I just played like a $1 do-nothing steam game for like it for like a few hours.
Rym: But it's like you put that.
Scott: if you put that garbage on my phone it's like.
Scott: well if I'm on the subway Yeah, a garbage game is perfect.
Scott: Yeah, especially if I can play it on the toilet.
Scott: That's like.
Scott: and I was like when I saw this news.
Scott: I was like, oh, you know what?
Scott: I don't really want to play Diablo on my computer that often.
Scott: I played Diablo 3.
Scott: It took me like a couple days to beat and then I didn't play it again.
Rym: So I saw this news and I ignored my phone.
Scott: I'm like him maybe I thought like.
Rym: I thought okay That's probably good for Blizzard.
Rym: I had a bunch of Blizzard stock.
Rym: I can see why they're doing this.
Rym: I'll probably poke at it.
Rym: I doubt it'll be good.
Rym: I looked at who they're sort of outsourcing it to probably not gonna be a good game.
Scott: Yeah, no That's the thing is that when I first saw the news making it is basically a shovel.
Scott: when I first saw the news I thought it was Blizzard making the game themselves.
Scott: But no they gave that.
Scott: they licensed the IP of Diablo to a company that made Garbage-o games and it's a garbage-o game.
Scott: And in fact people are pointing at an existing game.
Scott: Because if it's like they're not the first person to ever think to put a Diablo action RPG on a phone.
Scott: They pointed at an existing game that doesn't have Diablo IP obviously But it's basically looks 90% like what they showed from the Diablo and that game isn't a game I'm gonna play.
Rym: so whatever that canceled my Diablo phone plan, so it's not for me I don't care, and it'll probably make money.
Rym: and that's basically all I thought about it.
Rym: And then a little while later I get a stock alert because Blizzard stock dropped like 7% on this news, okay I don't know who.
Scott: the people who so that means people know I have access to People who owned Blizzard stock chose to sell it so much that it went down 7% which is a huge percentage.
Scott: so in a day so full disclosure.
Rym: I own a lot of Blizzard stock.
Rym: Yeah, okay, like I like I've it's one of my.
Rym: it's a big part of my portfolio.
Scott: So I immediately wonder what percentage of my index fund portfolio, so I immediately have a minor amount of pressure.
Scott: I own some indirectly.
Rym: oh Did something go wrong, and I didn't in any way think that this was gonna be related to anything that happened at Blizzcon.
Rym: I assume there was some like event that it like something happened.
Rym: And then I like I have access to a bloomer terminal.
Rym: so I start poking around the news.
Rym: nothing.
Rym: There's nothing other than that trending hashtag not my Diablo and salty babies flipping out in social media.
Rym: So basically the best I can tell is like what happened is that this announcement occurred.
Rym: Hedge funds and real investors who like know what they're doing looked at and said wow a game company That's good at what they're doing is taking a popular IP and going international with it because that's exactly what they're doing.
Rym: When you want to go international with a game especially if you want to go into say China Eastern Europe you basically make a shovelware MMO, and it makes shit tons of money.
Rym: That's like what you do.
Rym: That's like.
Rym: That's fine.
Rym: Yep and I Guess and this is all pure speculation.
Rym: I have to like really disclaim this is that what happened is that most entities that invest in gaming Don't actually have a lot of people who really know a lot about gaming that are making these decisions?
Rym: They're investing.
Scott: I'm one of my co-workers.
Scott: Who's very young and I think somewhat naive, but not the naivest right.
Scott: you know.
Scott: There's those naive investors who are like doing real stupid shit, and yeah shit.
Scott: He's a couple levels above that right yeah But he's big on investing in game companies cuz he knows a lot.
Scott: He knows as much about video games as any of us normal game And I invest in like Hasbro and Blizzard and likes the kind of companies.
Rym: I know a lot about right.
Scott: You know he's.
Scott: he's buying and selling game stocks, and I guess he's making money.
Scott: He's not poor and he's has a normal job, too.
Scott: He's not doing it like he's not obviously not day trading because I see him sitting there coding all day.
Scott: So it's made like it's obviously not a negative gambling behavior I've made like irresponsible level.
Rym: I've made over a hundred percent gains year over a year for two years in a row.
Scott: Yeah, it's like if you're an expert on something And there's nobody playing the market who's also an expert on the thing.
Scott: you can make money even without insider Trading with the specific knowledges about specific companies.
Scott: yeah, because I don't know any because you have general knowledge right.
Scott: for example Let's say you're investing in pharmaceuticals.
Scott: a lot of experts are investing in pharmaceuticals.
Scott: It's tough to compete there.
Scott: the markets probably gonna move in the correct direction.
Scott: But if you're investing in like you know lasers How many laser experts are there?
Scott: and if you see like a paper like who someone invented some cool new tech or something and you?
Scott: Know that certain company is the most positioned to move on that or whatever.
Rym: so here's an aside.
Rym: I'm gonna tell her that's gonna ruin another company's business.
Scott: They're not prepared for this new.
Rym: and you know the first time I ever made like real money in the stock market was a long long Time ago when I first bought stock.
Rym: I was like I'm a buy stock.
Rym: cuz I'm smart I know what I'm doing which was probably a mistake cuz I didn't know.
Scott: I won the stock market game in When I was in seventh grade, and then we went to the stock exchange.
Scott: Yeah, and then they took us to McDonald's.
Rym: so basically I saw all those news stories.
Rym: remember when Toyota Like a long time ago had the issue were like the accelerator was getting stuck and killing people yep And I saw that story and I saw Toyota's stock just collapse And I thought to myself That is definitely just old people messing up the pedals.
Rym: Yeah There is no way.
Rym: this problem is like is a real mechanical problem.
Rym: And I base this on the fact that just because of being someone who reads FARC There are so many stories of old people making that mistake and like it.
Rym: like that is a common problem.
Rym: It is a shockingly common cause of accidents.
Rym: is old people hit the accelerator instead of the brake yep And then they hit it harder when the car doesn't stop mm-hmm Other.
Rym: the other thing that commonly causes that is old people will like Shove the floor mat on top of the pedal.
Rym: Yeah, that's the other thing that happens a lot yep, so I thought there's no way There's a real problem here.
Rym: That's ridiculous.
Rym: Toyota's a smart company.
Scott: It wouldn't fuck up that bad.
Rym: So I took literally all my savings and bought Toyota stock and I made a shit ton of money Relative to how much money I had back.
Rym: when it bounces back Yeah, cuz like a few weeks later are people not buying Toyota's now.
Scott: Then I learned that buying Toyota's just as much as any other car.
Scott: so then I learned that space and it's also that's a very popular Call me the most popular car up there with Honda.
Rym: It's basically contra investing where you believe that a stock has tanked or is otherwise undervalued Because you have domain specific knowledge not insider domain specific knowledge FARC articles.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So in the gaming sector what I guess happened Is that most people who invest in games don't really know a lot about it.
Rym: so the algos that actually deal with these investments are primarily driven by Clever people who think that they want to base stuff on sentiment.
Scott: Yeah, they got.
Scott: there's a lot of sentiment analysis stuff That's very popular these days not just for Investing but also just for like, you know looking at social media like the bunch of tweets It'll search for something and collect a bunch of tweets and they be like, ah, we did sentiment analysis on all these tweets This search and it turned up negative.
Scott: So that means the populace as a general has a negative feeling about this thing.
Rym: We search for our positive feelings about this thing with the fact that like that hashtag was trending Probably in my personal opinion triggered a lot of sell-off Algos on the worry that people wanted to be ahead of the fact that this game company messed something up in gamers.
Rym: No better.
Rym: Let's trust the gamers.
Rym: Mm-hmm And that's ridiculous.
Rym: And as far as I can tell like hedge funds and people like the people who invest in games who hire Subject matter experts to advise them are probably doubling down on Activision Blizzard right now.
Rym: That's my guess and I to him doubling down.
Rym: I bought a lot of Activision Blizzard stock today because of this better Hope you write because you lose a lot of money.
Rym: Well also one I've never lost money and two I only invest for like the five-year ten-year horizon.
Rym: Like I don't ever sell stock.
Scott: really My index funds are still killing it.
Rym: so killing it by what?
Rym: if you made a hundred percent year-over-year two years in a row I don't need a hundred percent.
Scott: I'm gonna I'm gonna have listen No, but none of us even make it a hundred percent.
Scott: gonna have enough money to mathematically retire.
Rym: No, my retirement plan is a combination of Mad Max and communism.
Scott: But here's the thing is that all the other people our age all the other Millennials, right?
Scott: They have nothing for retirement.
Rym: That is also terrifying.
Scott: All right, it's very terrifying.
Scott: So the fact that I have any amount I figure even though it's not enough.
Scott: Like if I had to retire today, obviously enough enough money, even if you add the you know, 20 whatever years of more investing It's still not enough money to retire But I'll have so much more than everyone else.
Scott: So won't I be able to get?
Scott: I'll be doing alright.
Rym: So Scott my retirement stuff is like your retirement stuff.
Rym: This is separate.
Rym: This isn't money for when I'm seven.
Scott: not most people are not wealthy enough to have extra money.
Rym: Yeah, these investments are from when I'm like uncle money bangs or D. Yeah, I am also taking a huge amount of risk by putting almost all my savings Yeah liquid cash in a relatively small number of chosen equities.
Rym: That's what I keep saying, but it's never gotten me wrong so far.
Scott: But anyway, I'm doing great putting it on red.
Scott: It's been red.
Rym: I Mean, I can't go wrong.
Rym: all gills gonna eat food tonight.
Scott: I'll put it on black this time.
Scott: Oh shit zero That's an option.
Rym: What what's that is green the wolves in on old gills doorstep.
Rym: But anyway, I think this is ridiculous.
Rym: I think the people who are mad about this are being ridiculous The anyone.
Rym: and what's weird is this news made it into like basic culture.
Rym: people I know in the real world who know nothing about games Heard about this and they were all mad about it for the same reason.
Rym: the reason they were mad They all said the same thing they said.
Rym: But what about all the people who spent thousands of dollars to fly to Blizzcon only to get this instead of Diablo 4 like?
Scott: That's what I was saying before.
Scott: why are you flying and paying to go to witness an advertisement in person?
Scott: Get what you deserve pay and fly.
Rym: that is one to watch games and get drunk with your friends and hang out.
Rym: don't fly there To get a press release.
Scott: you can get the.
Scott: I got the same press release.
Scott: it cost me nothing And also I didn't get advertised.
Scott: in the face.
Rym: I think they're Diablo.
Rym: MMO for phones is going to make a shit ton of money.
Rym: probably It's just not for you.
Rym: Diablo 4 will come out when it comes.
Scott: I wonder how much money goes to the company that made it and how much goes to blizzard The other.
Rym: but basically if you're a fan of a thing that doesn't mean you get to say how said thing is made and you're Probably not the most important factor in the decisions that are being made.
Scott: also If the thing you know if there's an if there's an intellectual property you like and it gets attached to something You know it's like.
Scott: I like Megaman, right This good Megaman stuff Megaman 11 just came out whatever 12.
Scott: I don't fucking know yeah But I still like Megaman yeah.
Scott: And then they come up like a crappy Megaman board game and a crappy Megaman cartoon and a Megaman battle network.
Rym: It's I don't give a shit about a network.
Scott: I don't give a crap about any of that garbage, right?
Scott: But it's like.
Scott: I don't have to stop liking Megaman.
Scott: I don't have to be mad that they applied the Megaman IP to something else.
Scott: It's like okay They applied the Diablo IP to something else that you don't give a shit about.
Scott: who cares?
Rym: The creation of art is not a zero-sum game.
Rym: kids like it's not like.
Scott: there's a limited amount of things the Diablo IP can be applied to.
Scott: you could literally we could remake everything on earth so that everything has the Diablo IP.
Scott: every movie is Diablo.
Scott: Every.
Scott: every TV show is Diablo.
Scott: the TV show The main character is always Satan.
Rym: every time so occasionally a game will be made.
Rym: that is not for you specifically crying nerd on Twitter.
Rym: Yeah in other news riot The other big game company, and this is pretty breaking news like a little while like earlier today, right?
Scott: So this today's today's news is like a double news from riot, right?
Scott: So the news from today is that a current and former employees are suing riot for gender discrimination.
Scott: And I all I got to say is I'm not surprised.
Scott: every video game company hasn't been super gender discrimination.
Rym: Yeah, I'm not surprised.
Rym: and age-discriminated Every company is not sued for gender discrimination and age discrimination.
Rym: Yeah I mean, I've already got.
Rym: we're getting to the point like in four more years Scott and I are gonna be age-discriminated Again, it's gonna happen probably.
Rym: yeah I'm already I'm already.
Rym: it's weird how much older I am than a lot of people I work with.
Rym: But yeah, so right is straight up being sued.
Rym: You can read the article.
Rym: I mean I'm Definitely not going to give you legal advice or talk about a legal issue like this because I know a lot less about this than I do about the stock market.
Rym: Mm-hmm, and I don't know a lot about.
Scott: I know what the HR people tell me.
Rym: Yep But
Scott: and they can't be trusted all completely because they're on they're there to defend the company not to defend
Rym: lizard like the people I know in the industry who know a lot about the inside of Blizzard like Activision Blizzard Tend to have positive things to say like crunch isn't bad Like it seems like it's a reasonably okay place to work for a big.
Scott: It's not as bad as the other game companies at least in at least one or two ways.
Rym: It seems neutral to slightly positive.
Rym: is the what the impression I get from the average person?
Rym: the impression I get about riot Is pretty bad and pretty bro II.
Rym: like I get the impression.
Scott: only thing I've ever gotten a good impression About riot is that they seem to actually put in an effort and try to get shitheads out of their player base.
Rym: Yeah, and community, but they don't go as far as Kaplan with overwatch.
Rym: who's like I will fucking ban you for quitting a game.
Rym: Let's go bring it.
Rym: What are you gonna ban?
Rym: ban for life?
Rym: Oh, you made a new account band.
Rym: It's like that your money didn't?
Scott: we do a story on geek?
Scott: that's a while ago.
Scott: We didn't do the story.
Scott: We discussed the story where like that the worst possible guy was finally unbanned after a super long time.
Scott: I would never unban the worst possible guy.
Rym: be like nope That's so I'm gonna run just gonna quote the article because this is everything that needs to be said.
Rym: the class-action lawsuit alleges that quote.
Rym: Like many of riots games female employees plaintiffs have been denied equal pay and found their careers stifled because there are women more.
Rym: So plaintiffs have also seen their working conditions negatively impacted because of the ongoing sexual harassment misconduct and bias which predominate these sexually hostile working environment of riot games.
Scott: I believe it.
Rym: I have no reason to do in any way.
Scott: I mean if someone said that and replaced that company name with literally any company name, I would say I believe it.
Scott: Yeah It's like this.
Scott: What a company would I not believe it?
Rym: You know what the exceptions would be?
Rym: Scott companies that are so small that I personally know literally every employee of that company.
Rym: Yeah, maybe then I would be able to argue against it.
Rym: maybe but I do get the impression that riots kind of egregious compared to Even other game companies and like that.
Rym: this rumblings been around for a long time Like this is.
Rym: this is just that's a common rumbling.
Rym: and now there's this lawsuit.
Rym: Mm-hmm Of course, my thing of the day is also hanging out here.
Rym: So I think it's time for Things of the day about that.
Rym: So riot if you didn't know there have been music videos.
Rym: They're basically like League of Legends, but like real music video.
Scott: I mean, you know all these companies nowadays actually seem to be doing something I think is smart which is you got a video game coming out.
Scott: Maybe it's triple-a, right?
Scott: Maybe it's not.
Scott: you want to promote it.
Scott: You can a put out a demo.
Scott: Well, if you put in a demo people play it and then they don't buy a game because they got everything they needed from the demo.
Scott: You can make a trailer.
Scott: trailers are pretty good.
Scott: Yeah, a lot of trailers.
Scott: They have some bull shots in them.
Scott: So right, some of them have real game footage, right?
Scott: But trailer trailers are okay for promoting your game.
Scott: what I see lately as I think might be the best way to promote a game or at least I like it the most is Create content with the IP That's free just on YouTube to promote the game.
Scott: For example, there were those TF 2 videos with the characters meet the so-and-so.
Scott: Yeah, there was the watch.
Rym: does the like little movies for every character, right?
Scott: It seems like every Blizzard game is making like like the last hearthstone expansion.
Scott: They made like a little animated series.
Rym: Oh, who was it?
Rym: Someone on Twitter said something.
Rym: the effect of Blizzard realized that they can weaponize how thirsty the average gamer is in the marketing of Right, it's like, you know you people are.
Scott: now I think it's anyone.
Scott: if you're making a game I think of any kind even a board game just making anything maybe anything period you want to market it create some sort of like.
Scott: Not you know a commercial like you see on television but more like a Super Bowl commercial where it's like it's actual entertaining content that happens to include your IP.
Scott: that is You know something that someone would want to watch on its own and that is now a promotional item for the actual Thing.
Scott: so Katie is worlds like make transformers the cartoon to sell transformers the toy.
Rym: So Katie D they have a DB a debut single and it is this League of Legends music video and it is fucking amazing, right?
Scott: So here's the deal, right?
Scott: So the KDA is a is a it's.
Scott: I don't know if it counts as a k-pop group or not But yeah, basically there's four members.
Scott: I don't know all their names, but two of them are from re Evelyn Kaisa and Akali, right.
Scott: so anyway two of them are from this actual kpop group called g idol and g idol is a group that came out of like was new this year and Was I became.
Scott: I thought I was like, oh another new group.
Scott: and then they were strangely incredibly popular I think because they have this one member.
Scott: So, yeah, I don't know what her name is, but she's way popular.
Scott: and then I saw her in something else and she was way good.
Scott: But anyway, so two of the people in kata are from g idol and the two other people I think from America or something I never heard of them.
Scott: and they sing the parts of these four characters who are computer generated Animated characters in this music video.
Rym: They're like little characters.
Rym: You could pick and play right?
Scott: There's like four Lowell characters wearing specific skins that were just released.
Scott: I guess that you could buy.
Scott: And then they're dancing and singing and then the actual singers are the four people I just mentioned.
Scott: and then there are four other people Who created a dance the choreography for the music video?
Rym: You sent me the link to the practice.
Scott: So now those four people who I don't know their names their dance practice video went up today.
Scott: So they basically created for Hatsune Miku is basically for virtual.
Scott: Yeah, they took four of their existing lol heroes Hatsune Miku them, but the singers are not digital singers They're actual for real people and the dancers are for other different real people.
Rym: and this.
Rym: so I saw this blow up because they've done Although there's other lol videos like this.
Rym: There's this metal like.
Rym: there's a bunch of them.
Rym: They're good, but I saw this blow up in my Twitter feed among like all the people I know who play lol.
Rym: So I thought okay I should watch it and it was awesome.
Rym: and Then a little while later like a few days go by and it blows up among all my friends who hate lol.
Scott: And then it blew it out.
Scott: I hate lol.
Scott: I'm just indifferent.
Scott: It's a MOBA just like all the other MOBA and then it.
Rym: well, I hate.
Rym: I hate MOBAs.
Scott: personally I'm not really big on MOBAs.
Scott: Yeah, I don't hate them, but I'm not into them.
Scott: I would put it this way.
Scott: The thing is I would be into them if they fixed a long list of issues.
Scott: But those issues are so egregious I can't play.
Rym: The tropes of the game genre MOBA do not suit the personal preferences of Rym in Playing games.
Scott: The core of the MOBA does suit the personal preferences of Scott.
Scott: The details of every single MOBA implementation I've ever seen completely ruin it.
Rym: What's worse is even like they all get something right, but then something wrong.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: And I there's none.
Rym: that just got all the things Right.
Scott: I mean I can make one.
Scott: that's too much work.
Rym: But also I worry that if you got everything quote unquote, right?
Rym: You're gonna make a game that's quote unquote.
Rym: good that no one wants to play because it isn't fun.
Scott: I would agree.
Rym: But anyway, this video like it kept getting waves of blowing up in my social media and just watch it.
Rym: It's great.
Rym: Like it is it is a great music video and you need to watch it.
Scott: songs on Spotify also.
Rym: Yeah, the songs stuck in my head already like permanently.
Scott: Welcome to kpop every week.
Scott: Yeah So what do you got twice as a new guy?
Scott: so I got a cute video this cute little burp guy and he goes and he Supposedly the caption says he moves the camera and it's he pecks the camera.
Scott: Yeah, but yeah the bird he's near He's got a little camera and I think he's in a bag or something.
Scott: And this cute little burb does a cute little dance way to go a little burb.
Scott: I like your dance.
Rym: That's a really cute little burb.
Scott: Yeah, cute burb cute dance.
Rym: Also, you got to scroll down when you go click on Scott's thing today.
Scott: Yeah, so it this burb videos in a reddit thread.
Scott: So if you scroll down people, there's no there's no audio on the burb dance.
Scott: If you scroll down people made some like, you know gifts with sound and chose different songs and they chose Songs.
Rym: they range from a to a plus.
Rym: Yeah, it's good stuff.
Scott: So after you watch the burb video scroll down and watch it a couple more times with different songs Sync to it in the meta moment.
Rym: Uh, we're going to be live at PAX Unplugged Oh shit.
Rym: on Saturday with learn and win Puerto Rico Yeah, and on Sunday with a more advanced version of the 40 tabletop games You must play and every other minute in this convention We're either going to be videoing in the expo hall or playing tabletop games rolling dice.
Rym: It's gonna be amazing.
Rym: moving mice Yep, maybe playing a secret inheritance somewhere.
Rym: We'll see good time playing a role I'm gonna be.
Rym: I'm feeling this all in a play but don't hold out because uh Pax East is not that far away, even though it happens after packs out.
Scott: Yeah, you did packs.
Scott: East was not even on my mind.
Rym: Yeah, like I just finished so I did.
Scott: the dates have been leaked.
Rym: I just finished making our panel for PAX Unplugged and I just finished submitting our panels for PAX South And our panels for magfest.
Rym: I'm hyped for PAX East.
Rym: the hotels are going to be on sale Imminently, right?
Scott: So the the prices and dates for PAX East are up.
Rym: I think I leaked and then on leaked.
Rym: So this is an insider information.
Scott: It's not insider.
Scott: It was.
Scott: it was on the website publicly because people were posting images of it being up even though now It's no longer updated on the website, but people posted and it looks like the price went up.
Scott: five bucks a day.
Scott: Oh, no, and well, I mean adds up over the years five bucks a day this year five bucks a day next year.
Scott: But and suddenly it's 20 bucks a day.
Scott: It's like oh fuck.
Scott: That's a lot, right?
Rym: Yeah, it's still cheaper than a lot of anime cons.
Scott: It is but still it's not cheap, but the dates look are gonna be the very end of March 2019.
Scott: Yep, so the Thursday Friday Saturday Sunday at the end of March 2019.
Scott: So be on PAX East.
Scott: so put in your vacation requests.
Rym: So it is.
Rym: it is high alert for badges and hotels.
Scott: Oh highest I'd give it a couple weeks But yeah, so, you know, it's it's high alert.
Rym: It's not.
Rym: it's not critical alert.
Scott: critical alert soon.
Scott: No you can't.
Scott: I remember in past years like Going to Thanksgiving and being put at ease by a tweet and then after Thanksgiving being on critical alert.
Rym: I feel like it might happen before Thanksgiving.
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: and if you don't know there is a Google Doc spread a Google Sheet Out there that you can.
Scott: that's publicly visible.
Scott: that has all the information on every day that every packs went on sale Sold out if it sold out How much the badges cost literally everything.
Scott: so you can plan your packs ticket purchasing whatever.
Rym: and if you really want to go deep I'm not going to link to any instance of it.
Rym: But a long time ago when the contract got signed for PAX East and general Boston used to just publish like everything that's gonna happen in Boston on this like it's kind of not secret Just not well-known like bureaucracy.
Scott: Sometimes you can go to like the Convention Center website and you can see that either a Pax is listed even though it's not on the packs website.
Rym: You'll see like read expose something something or be.
Scott: the thing that happens actually even more often is the Convention Center has only booked Literally every single weekend except that one conspicuous weekend in March April ish Right around.
Scott: what PAX East usually is so same for any other convention.
Rym: if you really care You can find out the dates to every PAX East through.
Rym: I think 2024 is as far as I've seen like.
Scott: so the schedule is.
Rym: we got PAX Unplugged coming up first And then we got lag fest mag fest pecs out Paxis that's right.
Scott: So that's what's coming up.
Rym: So stay tuned.
Rym: We're gonna be at all of them Of course.
Scott: and the book club book is 2001 a space odyssey.
Scott: as soon as I finished the fantasy novel I'm reading right now I'm gonna read it and then we'll do an episode.
Rym: and If you need because again You're probably listening to this after the election happened if you need a social place to hang out on the internet that is guaranteed 100% Nazi free because Twitter still won't ban the Nazis Just say in the geek guides forum.
Rym: That's like.
Rym: our one rule is you can't be a nice.
Scott: Yeah You go to our website front row crew calm where you can find it literally all of our content and then from there you could Got links to all of our social medias.
Scott: You go to community dot.
Scott: front row crew calm for the currently active forum and you want to look at the old forum You can still go to forum dot front row crew calm.
Scott: It's a little broken, but all the contents there?
Rym: Yeah, there is a shit ton of content in there.
Rym: Yeah This forums and going for a long time and a lot.
Rym: and the scary thing is there's a number of people who post regularly.
Rym: There's a number of people who post occasionally.
Rym: There is a shocking number of people who have accounts and read this forum religiously, but never say anything.
Rym: They don't say a goddamn thing, but there's a lot of content like the forums good stuff Like.
Rym: I would.
Rym: I would not tell you to go here if I didn't personally like use this on a daily basis.
Scott: That's also ours.
Rym: Yeah, but I use it.
Scott: There are people there who are wisely not GeekNights listeners.
Rym: Yeah, I think there's more non GeekNights listeners in the GeekNights forum than there are.
Scott: They listen to a GeekNights.
Scott: They join the forum and they stop listening to a GeekNights.
Scott: Yep That is the wisest move.
Scott: That is the the the the the the most expanded brain.
Rym: Alright, so I thought I should make that.
Scott: that's.
Rym: that's a good.
Rym: that's a good expanded brain.
Rym: So Rollin rights are a genre of games that have existed for a long time.
Rym: I'm not gonna try to even like talk about the history of them because you don't know it.
Rym: No, well one I don't know it.
Rym: and two No one gave a shit about rollin rights in like the broader like tabletop community.
Scott: Yeah, this is like a recent thing like past couple to two three years I want to say like
Rym: maybe
Scott: even more recent than the
Rym: rollin rights were like creeping in here and there and like you'd occasionally see One there were more in Japan than there were like in the US.
Scott: It's a genre of tabletop games rollin right that for most of my life The only one I ever saw was Yahtzee and I didn't even realize it was a genre.
Scott: and now over the past I you know, what was that?
Scott: We played when did we play rolling America?
Scott: It was a pack last PAX East.
Rym: I think it was two packs ago.
Scott: I think it was two PAX East ago.
Scott: So that's when I sort of realized Oh, not another game.
Scott: Oh this I see how it works.
Rym: So I can think of one other rollin right?
Rym: I played as a kid that you didn't name triple Yahtzee a different Yahtzee.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, okay So the Yahtzee was way bad.
Scott: Anyway, so is with the deal.
Scott: a rollin right game is Exactly what it says everyone has every player has some sort of sheet alright, or it could be a dry erase board or paper with a pencil and Some sort of dice get rolled.
Scott: It could be you roll your own dice.
Rym: It could be cards or something else.
Rym: it's right.
Scott: some sort of random input occurs and you have to put take that random input and put it onto your board right and Then another input is generated and you put it onto your board and you continue doing this and at the end We see who's got the best board who is optimally placed.
Scott: all these inputs Yep, right onto the board that they have.
Rym: now this seems on this if you don't think about it a lot and we both fell for this.
Rym: the first time I played a modern rollin right was when we played roll in America and the rules Were explained to us and we looked at each other and thought wow We're all just gonna do the exact same thing cuz we're all intelligent adults.
Rym: No Right.
Scott: So here's the thing.
Scott: So at the first at the first baby level of rollin right is Yahtzee right and the thing with Yahtzee is there's a luck involved Because everyone's rolling their own dice.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So if I get different it's easy to optimally place and mostly easy for top to me place in Yahtzee.
Scott: We.
Rym: sometimes it's a little trick Scott and I verified years ago with a website where you play Yahtzee nearly optimally.
Scott: Yeah, like we play Yahtzee This is a very very early GeekNights thing of the day was was a website that will.
Rym: basically there's an optimal Yahtzee playing Computer and you play a ton of Yahtzee and then it tells you how close your play is to perfect optimal mathematical play, right?
Scott: So if you could say roll all the dice in advance on Yahtzee You could obviously place them optimally but because you have to place immediately after you roll.
Scott: It's like alright I just got four of a kind but that's also a 20.
Scott: It's also four sixes.
Scott: do I go 24 in the sixth column or do I go like wait?
Scott: I just thought of a game 28 in the.
Rym: so here's the.
Rym: here's the game of Yahtzee.
Rym: to make this more like a modern roll And right so someone's turn they roll the dice and they're out there.
Rym: the end result of these rolls Everyone has to put on their sheet, right?
Scott: So that that is what modern roll and rights are.
Rym: but the problem is with Yahtzee.
Rym: The person's going to whoever rolled the dice is then gonna like optimize the dice like they're gonna.
Scott: Oh, they're doing the rerolls in their favor.
Scott: So imagine that might be not in someone else's favor.
Rym: Yeah Oh.
Rym: So imagine a Yahtzee game where some of the real dice get rolled in the middle and there is some sort of mechanic For everyone to affect those dice Independently are your?
Scott: are your score sheets public or not?
Scott: That's a big difference.
Rym: Yeah, I think the score sheets aren't public.
Rym: and then it gets real.
Scott: is then I see I see Rym or discord a board of a kind.
Scott: I guess I reroll in this.
Rym: So rolling I think I think there's a game there.
Rym: I gotta think about this.
Scott: Yeah, that's not about.
Scott: but anyway, so that's Yahtzee.
Scott: You have this luck involved where you're trying you're solving a puzzle of optimally placing these numbers into slots to get the most points.
Scott: But since your dice are not the same as everyone else's dice there's luck involved, right?
Scott: I got a Yahtzee You didn't.
Scott: yeah, the next level rolling right is what's happened.
Scott: Most of these games are these days, which is okay.
Scott: We roll dice Everyone has a sheet everyone starts with the same sheet Everyone gets the same inputs the in.
Scott: if we gave you all the inputs if we rolled all the dice in advance You could easily Everyone could just sit there and think for a long time and optimally put all the inputs in the right slots on the sheet To get the highest score.
Scott: But because you have to put them in one at a time and you don't know what the next inputs are going to be in The future it's like alright.
Scott: you had to gamble for it.
Scott: Let me think.
Scott: real simple example, right?
Scott: Here's a game.
Scott: There's three squares, right?
Scott: if you put numbers in the squares in Increasing sequential order you get a perfect score.
Scott: If any numbers are out of order, then you you know, you you lose points every time.
Scott: a number.
Rym: This game I roll a d-hundred a 40 is rolled.
Rym: Where do you put it?
Scott: Do you put it in number one?
Scott: Or number three, right?
Scott: It's like I. you're sort of gambling a little bit.
Scott: So it is kind of luck, but you're also playing the odds, right?
Scott: I would put my 40 in the middle slot and then the next roll is a 10.
Scott: So I put that in the left slot and then the third roll is 20. ah fuck.
Scott: I got.
Scott: I got one row.
Scott: It's 100.
Rym: Yes, right Yeah, so typically what a lot of these games will have is another element where one the board will be bigger There's more places or something.
Rym: Yeah, and it doesn't have to be places.
Rym: It can be lines it can be shapes like part of the reason why this genre I think is starting to like explode is that?
Rym: With very minimal materials you can design like very different games Like in a very minimalist fashion.
Scott: Yep So some examples of roll and rights I've played.
Scott: and the thing is roll and rights.
Scott: the best thing about them Is that there's no digging people over which turns people away from games a lot.
Scott: Yep, right?
Rym: There's no There could be but there is.
Scott: you can play them solitaire You can just sit there roll dice and try to get the best score.
Rym: These are games you could theoretically have an unlimited number of players Like.
Scott: you could have a panel where you're rolling dice at the front and everyone's yeah Just on the big screen in the front you could actually somebody should make one with jackbox technology.
Scott: Everyone Jack everyone fills out their sheet on their phone and then in the whole room We see who got the best sheet from the same dice.
Rym: I feel like if a pet if we're ever at a gaming con where they need extra panel content Let's run rolling rights for an entire room.
Rym: Yeah, let's make it.
Scott: Let's make a jackbox rolling right anyway.
Scott: So examples of roll and rights I played recently that are hot are Ganshan clever.
Rym: That's the one I didn't play I've only played it solo.
Scott: I think I read the rules once and I vaguely remember reading something that when you play it With other people that like the dice you don't use go to the next person and there's some sort of interactivity.
Scott: That's really fascinating which makes me it makes me want to play it with other people.
Scott: But when you play it solo, which you can do for free on the web There's sort of a janky web app, but it totally works.
Scott: It's basically sort of like Yahtzee you roll the dice There's different dice of different colors and it's like, okay well I can use this dice for the number or for its color and then I take it and then I remove it and I roll The remaining dice and this.
Scott: you can read the rules.
Scott: but you have a big of this really crazy score sheet and you can score in different spots on the sheet and It's like you sort of want to get.
Scott: you can try to pick one area and get in it a whole bunch or spread your Out over different areas and then when you reach certain Milestones and certain spots on the sheet you get bonus stuff like extra dice and extra fill-ins and I guess I don't know If it's mathematically possible to fill in the whole sheet.
Scott: I've never done that.
Scott: but you add up a score at the end and You get you know, you try to get hundreds of points or whatever.
Rym: so in a way this sort of functions like those rotating tournaments like in a bridge tournament where There's a table with a deck with an order of cards.
Rym: So every group plays like the same deck to see who optimizes it's all.
Rym: it does that with a modern minimalist sensibility yep, and it does it well and the games are fun and I think rolling America is the one I played the most.
Scott: rolling America is real simple the way it works.
Scott: You roll some roll dice, right?
Scott: And then you have to put the numbers onto your map of America in these states.
Rym: But then the numbers like one through six can't be more than one away from all it.
Scott: So if I put five in Florida and if I put a four in Georgia I'm good because they're two adjacent states and their numbers are one apart from each other.
Scott: But guess what Florida is also adjacent to what Alabama next to it, right?
Scott: And it's like well, what if I get a I have to put a two and out?
Scott: if I put a three in Alabama That's good.
Scott: It's one away from Georgia, but it's two away from Florida.
Scott: That's not good.
Rym: So another common element of these games then and this is what really makes these John those genres start to shine is Usually they'll give all the players a limited number of special powers.
Rym: They can use that their discretion.
Rym: so things like skip this role or Do this one twice or change a number or change a cut like something they can use a limited number of times a wildcard of Some kind right.
Rym: so which together with the rolling gives a very nice and distinct element of push your luck.
Scott: a good example This we played railroad Inc.
Scott: I nk.
Rym: I like that one a lot.
Rym: We played it at PAX West West.
Scott: there's red and blue versions that was in first.
Scott: look Yeah, they're mostly the same game but there's red and blue versions that are slightly different and the way it works is this dice.
Scott: the dice have pictures on them of roads railroad tracks and Tunnels.
Scott: Yeah, all these sort of like, you know the transportation lines that you would draw like
Rym: SimCity looking transportation
Scott: Right and you the dice get rolled and everyone has a little dry erase grid and you have to put those Pictures onto your thing and make a network of Interconnecting roads and rails.
Scott: and you don't want to leave dead ends.
Scott: You want things to connect to the edge of the board?
Scott: You want to make you know a long road you want to.
Scott: you know You want to arrange them in a way that scores the most points.
Scott: and then there's like like Rym was saying this certain of like Get out of jail free make it.
Scott: you're allowed to make a few mistakes.
Scott: There's like a few dice you can better to sort of freebies you can use like once per game.
Scott: You can ignore.
Scott: you don't have to place every dice every time like you know.
Scott: ignore some Right the stuff like that.
Scott: So you don't.
Scott: if you're not like locked in everyone can approach the game really differently and with the same dice You're like four or five players.
Scott: Everyone's boards are completely different.
Rym: Yep So the push your luck element the like risk/reward element, like I'm not doing well I'm going to take bigger risk Like there's a lot of things that make these games good.
Rym: But if you're like are a game designer and you want to like make some basic games and like try to design games This is a really good genre to try.
Scott: actually I just remembered there was a roll and write that I played after Yahtzee, which is roll through the ages.
Scott: Oh, yeah, roll through the ages.
Scott: hate that game.
Scott: It's basically Yahtzee.
Scott: It's really just Yahtzee with a different theme.
Scott: Yeah, it was like nothing about it.
Scott: that like was anything like the modern roll and writes.
Scott: But if you come I didn't think of it.
Rym: if you come up with a good idea for something like this You can basically just make it with dice and dry erase stuff.
Scott: Yeah, roll and writes are just so simple to make.
Scott: there's actually there's a bunch of it's like text adventures, right?
Scott: There's like communities of people just cranking out roll and writes and the fun part is usually the theme of the sheet of paper that They make.
Scott: yeah, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, Ganshan clever is just like numbers on a board But a lot of the ones I see is like Halloween.
Scott: roll and write You know, it's like, you know, what I you know anime roll and rise, you know, you know would you go up?
Scott: I'll put my six in my Super Saiyan area.
Rym: But the other thing about these is that just by their nature both physical and design wise they're really good to Bust out if you got like a weird number of people while you're waiting to start a bigger game a different game.
Rym: They're great to bust out at restaurants.
Rym: They're great to bust out in lines at conventions.
Scott: They're accessible to almost anybody.
Scott: Right because it's sort of like, you know, it's the kind of thing you could just get one on your phone, you know I don't have it actually searched.
Scott: I probably should for some phone apps of rolling rights because I can sit there and it's just.
Scott: you're just solving this puzzle.
Scott: All right, it's like as opposed to a puzzle that you would normally solve where it's like, okay, you know There's one correct solution find it you have all the time in the world.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: no the inputs come in a certain order and you can only see what one input at a time without knowing the future.
Scott: Inputs, but they're also eyes it that way.
Rym: they're not random in the sense of oh you just rolled double sixes.
Rym: That's why you won.
Rym: It's you made the optimal decisions based on the inputs that we all shared.
Rym: Yep, so check these games out.
Rym: This is going to be a Fast growing and I think very popular sector of tabletop and I think it's already a fast growing and popular section of tabletop.
Scott: It's like and I don't think it's Reese's Peak yet, but I think it will level off, but I don't think it'll go away.
Scott: I think this will be like a constant.
Scott: There'll always be a few rolling rights hanging out.
Scott: There's always some text adventures.
Rym: I think it's gonna level off and then there's good as like someone's gonna come up with a clever twist on the genre.
Scott: There are already tons of clever twists exactly.
Rym: I think people will keep coming up with clever twists.
Scott: Yeah the one that's one that's hot right now that I played is called welcome to where you have to.
Scott: you have like this town and you're like Putting things into houses and the sheet of paper that you fill out looks really nice and it's like there's certain score bonuses for like.
Scott: You know the houses with the pools and you draw fences between the houses and you want to make groups Of houses that are like together.
Scott: nicely, right?
Scott: Yeah, it wasn't bad But I don't think it was as fun as some of the other ones but it's really popular right now.
Scott: People are way into it.
Rym: But think about the kind of things you could do.
Rym: you could play a game.
Rym: you can have a game like this where there's a Shared space multiple people are writing on.
Rym: Yep You could do something like between two cities where like you and me Share a board and then me and the person in my right share a board.
Rym: there are the possibilities of this tiny Between two rules.
Rym: Yeah Though I think this is a space that you should watch closely and play these games.
Scott: I make some.
Rym: yeah, I'll make one.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of gig nuts.
Rym: Ah Craig a la Rala Joyce Heidi Nicholas showing Ruby a blast hanging in the sky In my state.
Rym: e.com linkage ej-ban scooter lonely Roberto Kingsley Shawn Yeager Matthew Smith Nicholas brand up Mr.
Rym: Strong stretch in four to one creations Chris Reimer and Tom is Han Shervin Von Harl Rory Rochelle, Montanona Superboy tripwire sailor Vista dodge like Joe Joe Joe star Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perry drew open Lander Finn Chris midnuth midkiff Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas on and now I leave you with Me too.
Rym: Yeah, I could take you to the top So keep your eyes on me now.
Scott: Most important you I go.
Scott: Yeah, that's the one Now I take a woman there.
Scott: actually We got it.
Scott: So can you?
Scott: Can you feel the rush now?
Scott: ain't nobody bringing us down down down down down down like a tribe always wanna wear the crown.