Rym: It's Tuesday, December 4th 2018.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, Treasure Island.
Scott: Yarr.
Rym: Let's do this.
Scott: Woman.
Rym: Yeah, right?
Scott: Yesterday.
Scott: It is cold.
Rym: Yesterday was like 50 something degrees.
Rym: Like on the way home from PAX, like literally.
Rym: I brought a winter coat because on Thursday it was cold.
Rym: And then I come home and it's like 60 degrees outside.
Rym: And now it's winter again.
Rym: I feel like winter started like three times already.
Scott: It's too cold.
Scott: Also, you know, if you have an iPhone 7 and some other numbers, I guess you have until the end of the year to get a new battery for $30 instead of $80.
Rym: It's worth it.
Scott: My battery didn't have any problems, but I just went to get a new battery anyway, because all the iPhones are too big.
Scott: So my plan is to make this iPhone 7, which is still perfectly fine and smaller than all new iPhones, last as long as humanly possible.
Scott: So I got myself a $30 brand new battery.
Rym: A year ago I got the last good Android phone, the Xperia XC1 Compact.
Rym: And the new version of this phone is a piece of shit.
Rym: So I bought, because I found one cheap unopened, another one of this phone.
Rym: And when this one starts to get battery shitty, I'm just going to sell it on eBay.
Scott: The only problem is eventually they're going to have 5G networking on the new radios.
Rym: The thing is, 4G is already 5 for now.
Scott: Well, for now.
Rym: Yeah, I mean, yes, eventually.
Rym: Within like five years, I'm going to have to give up on this Sony phone.
Scott: Right, but the point is I'm going to make this phone last as long as possible.
Scott: Are there other notes?
Scott: Just side notes?
Rym: I might have to finally find my new laptop though.
Rym: I have a laptop that will have made it 10 years, and there's nothing wrong with it, except mini display port is a failed connector type.
Scott: Yeah, so side notes number one, if you go and get a new battery, the battery they give you is basically empty, so bring with you your Anker battery so you can charge it.
Rym: Oh yeah, otherwise however you get home is going to suck.
Scott: Right, and B, you know, you got your iCloud backup or your backup to your hard drive, because basically what happens is if they break your phone, which happened actually to the person next to me, if they break your phone while changing the battery and it wasn't your phone's fault, they just give you a new phone.
Scott: That's the backup, which totally works, because iCloud backup actually works.
Scott: I've used it several times, but the one thing that will not be backed up with an iCloud backup is, you know, the way it works.
Scott: is it basically instead of actually saving your apps in the backup, it just remembers which apps you had and where they were on the screen.
Rym: You got to type your password into everything.
Scott: And then it re-downloads them all from the store all at once, and it also saves certain documents and data, like photos, text messages, that sort of thing.
Rym: Androids the same way, when I like, I took the backup from my old phone into this phone.
Rym: It's actually pretty clever.
Scott: It's a good way to back up when you have such a locked in OS.
Rym: Except I had to type my fucking password into like 20 apps once.
Scott: Yes, you have to do that.
Scott: I had to do that on my new iPad, which I restored from a backup of the old iPad.
Rym: Which was annoying because the password, my generic password is really, really, really long to type.
Scott: One thing, though, is if for some reason you have to get like a new phone and lose the actual data, you and your two-factor authentication app, right, you will be in trouble because you open it and it will not allow you to lock into anything.
Scott: Now, make sure you have, if you use 2FA, which you should be using for anything that uses it, proper 2FA, not stupid text message 2FA, make sure you go spend.
Rym: SMS 2FA is actually minus one modifier to how many factors you have.
Scott: I know, but the point is, is that if you're using it extensively, as you should be, make sure to go through, take an hour or two, wherever, and go down your list of all the things you have 2FA for.
Rym: And print your backup codes.
Scott: And print out backup codes.
Rym: Now, this is important because Scott lost a Discord account, because some things, like Amazon.
Scott: The only one I've ever lost.
Rym: Amazon, if you mess it up, like you can do a reset, I think, and like fix it.
Rym: Like most services have a way to like reset it with email.
Scott: This was years ago.
Rym: Yeah, and Google is pretty good because if you get a YubiKey, you can have that and TOTP.
Rym: So I have a YubiKey and my two-factor here and the backup code, so I'm good.
Rym: But Discord does proper security.
Rym: If you lose your two-factor and you don't have the backup codes, you are fucked.
Rym: That account is gone.
Scott: Yeah, so I lost my Discord account that's associated with my actual email address.
Rym: Is that the one you used to make that old Discord?
Scott: I had to use an alias email, I don't know.
Scott: I have to use an alias email address in order to, you know, log into Discord now.
Scott: It's like when I log into Discord, I got to remember, oh, right, it's not my normal email to log into this.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Also, if you use the GeekNights Forum, I know that we support TOTP, like Google Authenticator.
Rym: It just works.
Rym: You should use it.
Rym: Exciting.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So my opening bit, and I'll tell the short story because it just is a fascinating thing happened to me, but basically, I need a new monitor because my monitor is also like 10 years old.
Rym: It's like this ancient ultra sharp and I didn't get monitors.
Scott: Your ultra sharp is the same ultra sharp I have two of on my desk.
Scott: It's not ancient, it's perfectly fine.
Rym: Yeah, so it's not enough pixels.
Scott: It's not 4K.
Rym: It's way, it's not, it's 1920 by 1200.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: That's not enough pixels for the Adobe stuff I do.
Scott: It's perfectly fine.
Rym: It's not for Adobe.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Basically, I need...
Scott: I've never had a problem.
Rym: The thing is, you don't edit that much.
Rym: The only things I need a lot of pixels for are arguably gaming, but not really because like.
Rym: it's fine.
Rym: 1920 by 1200 is fine for Overwatch and Civ or whatever, but I want those pixels for Adobe.
Rym: And also at work, I have like a really nice, like super quality, like 4K, like new monitor.
Rym: So I didn't really notice that over time, this old ultra sharp has gotten less and less color correct.
Rym: And also I want to take this one and make it my secondary monitor.
Scott: Also, I have two of those.
Scott: You have...
Rym: Yes, I have one of those.
Rym: My secondary monitor is Scott's 4x3 LCD monitor.
Rym: That was one of the first LCD monitors with a fast enough refresh rate on earth to play games.
Rym: that was affordable by normal humans.
Scott: That monitor is from 2000 single digit.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: Like 2002.
Rym: Two-ish.
Scott: Let me go.
Scott: Very early and it's still rocking.
Scott: I paid $500 for those monitors and they're totally worth it.
Scott: They kick ass.
Rym: So I'm going to replace that with my current ultra sharp.
Scott: Kicking ass for almost 20 years, those monitors.
Rym: And I'm going to replace my ultra sharp with a new 4K ultra sharp.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: But so I ordered one and like you do, I went to Dell.
Rym: I figured out which ultra sharp has like the right color correctness and things that I care about because I don't need the one that costs three times as much.
Rym: That's slightly better colors.
Rym: And I ordered it from Amazon.
Rym: So I get the 5% off because of my Amazon card.
Rym: I didn't notice until after I ordered it later that while I got it from Amazon, because I was just clicking through, it was like 150 bucks cheaper than what Dell is selling it for before that discount.
Rym: And it was shipped by someone else, not Dell, which is fine because like Amazon's got your back.
Rym: So I ordered this thing and it says, yeah, this will arrive like December 24th and I'm not in a hurry.
Rym: So yeah, I'll save like multiple hundreds of dollars and just not wait, like not be in a rush.
Rym: So then like a few days later, like four days later, a suspicious package shows up at my house.
Rym: The box is an HP pavilion monitor of the same size as this one.
Rym: And sure.
Rym: And even worse, the box has two labels on it.
Rym: The monitor box says it weighs like 14 pounds.
Rym: The shipping label says it should weigh like 18 pounds, but then put it on a scale.
Rym: No, but then the shipping label from the actual shipment said it weighed 24 pounds.
Rym: It was from a Turkish name I didn't recognize.
Rym: And even worse, I was like, I was like vaguely suspicious of like, what did my mom like buy me a gift?
Rym: Did someone buy me a gift?
Rym: I'm trying to figure out like what this is.
Rym: Did someone just put something in this monitor box?
Rym: So I pick it up and shake it and I hear metal banging against metal and it's pretty heavy.
Scott: So we're confident this box contains cellular phones.
Rym: So it's not often that like my suspicious signs go off.
Rym: So I do the thing.
Rym: I take this UPS shipping number and I put it into the UPS site.
Rym: To see if it was actually shipped to me and where it was shipped from.
Rym: And it was shipped and it weighs as like the weight was weird, but whatever.
Rym: So then I look it up and I figure out that it came from this like Costco wholesale distribution center.
Rym: So I look it up there and I end up actually like getting on a customer service call with them.
Rym: And I'm like, did you ship this package to me?
Rym: And can you tell me what is in it?
Rym: And what comes back is after many minutes of talking to these people.
Rym: Yes, we shipped that to you.
Rym: We can't tell you anything else about it or what's in it.
Rym: Weird.
Rym: So finally, I'm like, all right, fuck it.
Rym: I'm just going to open it.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But I did a little bit of due diligence.
Rym: I open it and sure enough, there's this HP Pavilion 4K monitor in there.
Scott: Of course.
Scott: Weird.
Scott: Obvious.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But it was shipped naked like it was shipped in the box.
Rym: It was like usually when you buy something like that, the monitor box is in a regular cardboard box.
Rym: And like my mom or like people I know will just use old monitor boxes to ship stuff like, why not?
Rym: So that plot thickens.
Rym: So I go and check like, did someone just ship me the wrong fucking monitor?
Rym: But no, because the ultra sharp I ordered was supposed to arrive like many weeks from now and sure enough, did not show as delivered.
Rym: So I'm like, all right, weird.
Rym: I'll deal with this later.
Rym: And I go to Pax.
Rym: During Pax, I discover that basically the company, some company did in fact ship this HP Pavilion monitor to me ostensibly by accident and wants me to ship it back.
Rym: So that seems shady.
Rym: So like, I'm just, it seems weird.
Rym: So then I go into Amazon to look at the order of my Dell ultra sharp and it says delivered backdated to the day I got the suspicious package.
Rym: So things are starting to line up and I'm assuming scam.
Rym: So I just say, fuck it.
Rym: I want to return this Amazon.
Rym: They shipped me some bullshit, whatever.
Rym: And Amazon, of course, is like, all right, cool.
Rym: Just ship it full refund.
Rym: Then the seller that sent me this monitor contacts me independently and says, hey, we made a mistake.
Rym: Ship it back to us and we'll ship you the right monitor.
Rym: The shipping label they sent me is very different from the shipping label Amazon gave me.
Rym: So even more warning signs.
Rym: So I'm just shipping, shipping it back with the Amazon label.
Scott: Sounds like some scam is going on.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So I assume I'm going to get a refund.
Scott: Someone trying to launder money by moving monitors around.
Rym: So I get the shipping label, I get a refund from Amazon and I'm just shipping this thing back.
Rym: I'm actually going to drop it off at the UPS thing tomorrow.
Rym: Like everything's fine, whatever.
Rym: I figured there's some scam where they like shipped the wrong monitor and hope you won't notice.
Rym: You're like, I don't know.
Rym: So, uh, the plot thickened because I got home today and Adele ultra sharp is sitting at our house.
Rym: All right.
Rym: From that same Turkish name.
Rym: I don't know how they got it here that fast.
Rym: So I'm going to figure out what to do.
Rym: I'm going to see if this box in fact contains the delta sharp I ordered or what I'm suspecting a bunch of spiders.
Scott: So something similar, not too similar, but happened to me where, uh, I ordered stuff on Amazon and I ordered this glass mixing bowl and I really needed a glass mixing bowl because all the mixing bowls I have for baking are metal.
Scott: and I got a cookie recipe that requires brown in the butter first, which means the butter's going to be hot.
Scott: I want to put the hot butter in a metal mixing bowl and hurt myself.
Rym: I have one big glass mixing bowl for similar purposes.
Scott: So I went and bought a cheapo pyrex glass mixing bowl, whatever, you know, nice big one.
Rym: Oh, and then someone shipped you a weird box of glass broken in charge.
Scott: I see a message.
Scott: It hasn't shipped yet according to Amazon, but I get an email from FedEx.
Scott: It's like, Hey, Sutton's on the way from Ben bath and beyond.
Scott: I have not shot that a bed bath and beyond in a very long time.
Scott: I will not do so because the last time I did, they started spamming me with a bunch of garbage and I don't like them and their store is a mess and I don't know how they still in business.
Scott: Fuck them.
Scott: Uh, but so I'm like opinions, big mood.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So I'm getting this package.
Scott: I'm like, did someone buy me a gift from bed bath and beyond?
Scott: Just coincidentally, it's close to holiday season.
Scott: What's up with that?
Rym: That's the thing.
Rym: It's the modifier of it's near the holiday season.
Rym: Random package might just be gifts, right?
Scott: So I check.
Scott: I look on Amazon and on the FedEx or the tracking numbers of the glass mixing bowl and the bed bath and beyond.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And the tracking info for them was actually the same, but the numbers, the first four digits of the numbers were shuffled up.
Scott: So I'm like, huh, maybe I learned something today.
Scott: Maybe I learned the first four digits of a tracking number don't matter.
Rym: Actually there was something similar with my monitor situation.
Rym: So right.
Scott: But I checked and I tried to shuffle up the first four digits to another configuration.
Scott: that didn't work.
Scott: Only these two configurations worked.
Rym: Now I'm curious.
Scott: But anyway, the point is, is that I basically got, uh, you know, I got shafted because all the place that I bought the glass mixing, the reseller on Amazon basically just found out that the glass mixing bowl was cheaper on bed, bath and beyond.
Scott: So they bought it there and arbitrage me for a few dollars.
Scott: Uh, but it didn't really matter to me because I'd saved the 5% with Amazon.
Scott: It's not like it would have been cheaper for me to go to bed, bath and beyond it, nor would I want to go there because I hate them.
Scott: I just don't like going to stores, but it was, yeah, well, I mean I could have bought it from the bed, bathroom.
Scott: on website is the point for cheaper.
Rym: The list price was cheaper, but I mean I total cost.
Rym: At this point I buy like hand soap and conditioner on Amazon.
Rym: Like I don't even want to go to a drug store.
Scott: No, even though Amazon is also evil, at least they don't spam me.
Scott: They're, they're evil to everyone but the customer.
Scott: So I will continue to criticize them for being evil to their employees and everyone else they work with.
Scott: Uh, but I can't not be their customer cause they're too good to the customer.
Rym: So anyway, if you were confused why we're talking about monitors and bed, bath and beyond, uh, because you saw us at PAX Unplugged and wanted to see what this podcast was about.
Rym: Welcome to GeekNights.
Rym: So now we're going to talk about PAX Unplugged.
Scott: I told you not to listen.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So uh, PAX Unplugged just happened and second PAX Unplugged.
Rym: It was from the perspective of reasonable attendees and ourselves.
Rym: It was a triumph.
Rym: It was a fantastic packs.
Rym: I had a really good time.
Rym: I played a shit ton of games.
Rym: The con achieved everything I wanted and uh, I don't know what else I can say other than PAX Unplugged.
Rym: really, really great packs to go to.
Scott: The only problem I can add with PAX Unplugged is that I didn't have enough time there because you know, it ain't four days.
Scott: Yeah, I had, I was missing a lot of time cause like I would go do a panel.
Scott: One of the two panels we did was two hours and then I got prep time before and clean up time after.
Scott: And even though going back to the room is just a walk through a skywalk, we don't have to go outside even.
Scott: I did not play as many games as I wanted to play.
Rym: You guys, they were only three days, but they went till two am.
Scott: That's also true.
Rym: So even if we did like three panels, like we felt like we got all the time we needed to game and then just as packs started coming into midnight, they all went four days or they're packed south where like we're just like we have infinite free time.
Rym: Like PAX South is just got a lot of downtime.
Rym: It's really easy to play games.
Rym: PAX Unplugged.
Rym: We did a bunch of panels and it's only three days and it ends at midnight.
Rym: and the lobby gaming situation, I think part of it too, is that back in the day we would all go into lobbies of hotels and continue to game for several hours.
Rym: You all went to bed.
Scott: We did not get a lot of pre-packs gaming and also cause it's so close to home on Sunday, we just go home immediately.
Rym: I'm staying the night on Sunday next year.
Scott: We don't get Sunday night gaming.
Rym: Yeah, well I got evening gaming.
Rym: You went to bed like a little baby.
Rym: So in fact I played a really good game on a Friday night and we had some beers.
Rym: The Marriott lobby was interesting though because that hotel's lobby is not great for gaming, but it has a bar, but the bar is filled with 50% basic people who aren't even staying at the hotel.
Rym: They're just like in Philly and want to drink in this Marriott bar for some reason.
Scott: I actually did not like the hotel, but I will probably book it again next year.
Rym: Because it's connected to the skybridge.
Scott: Cause you don't have to go outside.
Rym: Yup, that is the only reason to stay in that hotel because it had surly staff, surly security.
Scott: It was really big.
Scott: The room was meh.
Rym: And the bar...
Scott: It wasn't a Chai Lai Inn room, but it was meh.
Rym: Like the bar wasn't rowdy.
Rym: Like I have no comp... Like there were Pax Hairs gaming at like after midnight next to basic people drinking.
Rym: But what was annoying about it is that the guards are like super surly and there's this weird cavalcade of like drunk people.
Rym: Like I don't understand why you go to a hotel bar in Philly to drink at night as opposed to an actual bar because none of these people can use the bathroom in this bar because the bathroom requires a room key that they won't give you if you're not staying in the hotel.
Rym: So like all these basic people are like walking past our board game trying to go into this bathroom like all night long.
Rym: It was just a weird situation.
Rym: But the secret is even if you're not staying in Home 2, the other hotel, just go game in Home 2.
Rym: It has like no security and has a million big tables in the lobby and basically no one will hassle you.
Rym: It's just like this place to go game.
Rym: And they have free tea and if you're slightly evil you can also get free cereal.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: We were there playing Gamely Games.
Rym: What's funny about Pax Unplugged though is that if you look at all the gamers who went to it and like the feedback people have out in the wild like on Reddit and the Penny Arcade forums, it seems like there's three kinds of people talking about Pax Unplugged.
Rym: And what's interesting is that...
Scott: I think it's more than three kinds.
Rym: There's three main kinds.
Rym: I would say the three main kinds are people who are used to Paxes who go to Pax Unplugged because it's another Pax.
Rym: The people who are used to shitty board game cons like Gen Con who expected Pax Unplugged to be like Gen Con and thus it wasn't because it's better and now they're mad about it.
Rym: And the people who really don't go to cons at all and this is their first gaming con because it's the first one that's near them.
Rym: that's big.
Rym: And those three groups have a lot of disagreement over what attributes would make a board gaming con successful.
Scott: There's definitely a clash of cultures at Pax Unplugged that unlike what is at the other Paxes.
Scott: The other Paxes, it's like the cultures don't clash as much because A, they're sort of separated.
Rym: Yep, like these streamer kids literally don't interact with the table toppers.
Scott: Like they're separated by space, right?
Scott: It's like those swag hunting people.
Scott: They're in this giant expo hall, right?
Scott: They don't come into the tabletop zone too much, right?
Scott: You're not seeing them, right?
Scott: And then the tabletop people are in the tabletop zone.
Scott: It's like you're not interacting with these other people even though they're also there.
Rym: Also both of those groups get what they wanted and are happy and go away, right?
Scott: But at Pax Unplugged, you have in this one giant free, everyone's there for tabletop.
Scott: It's all tabletop.
Scott: This is one giant free play space.
Scott: And in that replay space you have the same, you know, grog nard from Gen Con, you know, new board gamer type person who's, you know, fresh, you know, you know, Pax people all in the same place, all buying the same cookie brigade cookie.
Rym: So like literally, there are people, like we show up, we're like, okay, panels, like you see the Pax people, they know the drill.
Rym: Like they go to the keynote and the Q&A and they go to a panel and play the games.
Rym: And then you see the fresh people who are like, panels?
Rym: Like what's a panel?
Rym: What's going on?
Rym: What are these things?
Rym: I just want to buy board games.
Rym: What?
Rym: And then the Gen Con people are like, how come I have to wait in a line?
Rym: Why couldn't I buy a ticket to this panel in advance?
Scott: Because money doesn't get you anything at Pax.
Scott: It's egalitarian Pax.
Scott: Deal with it.
Rym: I think the Pax culture is going to win out in the end because that is because it's Pax.
Rym: But also because I think it is the superior experience and the people who disagree are welcome to go to Gen Con instead.
Scott: Well, they go to Gen Con, they already go to Gen Con.
Scott: They want more Gen Con because there's only one Gen Con a year.
Rym: Well, you know what?
Rym: Maybe if Gen Con was better, there could be more than one Gen Con.
Scott: I mean, they, you know, there is.
Scott: there is some other Gen Con type stuff.
Scott: There's like, isn't there European Gen Con?
Scott: or there was at one point?
Rym: Or like, there's also those like, regular tabletop gaming cons.
Scott: There are many Gen Con-like cons.
Rym: I mean, UberCon was like that, just small.
Scott: And it's, you know, it's also, it's mostly like the RPG people are used to having like schedules and things arranged.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: You know, but it's like, they're not used to coming to a con and be like, what?
Rym: Just show up and like try to get into a game?
Rym: What?
Rym: My whole weekend is dependent upon playing this one particular D&D scenario.
Rym: And if I don't know in advance, I can do that.
Rym: I don't want to go.
Rym: Like, I would rather that culture never interact with PAX.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: But yeah, it was a good time.
Rym: So in some other gaming news, Fortnite and Epic are doing something interesting.
Rym: They're basically pulling the Valve 2.0.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, you know, way back in the day, Steam was created and I have a Steam account that is as old as Steam.
Rym: My Steam account is like three days younger than Scott's.
Scott: Go look at my Steam account.
Scott: Anyone can see my Steam profile.
Scott: You'll see that it says that it was created on a day in 2000 something.
Rym: So Scott, why?
Scott: If you go to Wikipedia, you'll see that Steam was launched on that very same day.
Rym: So Scott, why did you install Steam in an era when there were literally no games to download on Steam?
Scott: Because there were games to download.
Scott: In that year, the early 2000s, everyone was playing the very important game that is still around called Counter-Strike.
Scott: And if Counter-Strike released an update, what you had to do every time Counter-Strike updated, which was several frequently.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Like at least once a quarter at RIT, sometimes twice.
Scott: You had to go to counter-strike.net, click on downloads, hope the site was live.
Scott: There would be a list of mirrors and you had to click on all of those mirrors in your browser that did not yet have tabs.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: The tab browsing was not a thing.
Scott: And all those windows like file zone and two cows and all these different file hosting sites.
Scott: You had to find one that was still live because they were all being pummeled by people trying to get the latest version of Counter-Strike.
Rym: And even though we were in RIT and had like two OC3 connections to the internet, which back then was more bandwidth than God.
Scott: We weren't limited on our end, we were limited by these file hosts that were down.
Rym: We were also limited by the fact that at RIT, there were what, like 12,000 students?
Rym: 11,500 of them were trying to download this file simultaneously.
Scott: If you got the file though, you could share it directly with your friends because it was the era of P2P.
Rym: Yeah, but fuck you, I'm playing immediately.
Rym: I'm not uploading a file to the drive connect.
Scott: I could put it in my hotline folder and then run it.
Rym: Oh right, your hotline.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: That also had the Trygun fan subs.
Scott: Yes, anyway, the point is you could go and that was how you got Counter-Strike updates.
Scott: It sucked.
Scott: It was a giant pain in the ass.
Scott: Steam was like.
Scott: alright, we're putting up Steam, why are they putting up Steam?
Scott: Why did they make this thing Steam?
Scott: It didn't have friends, it didn't have any of the other stuff.
Scott: It was just a way for you to automatically install and update your Valve games without having to buy a-.
Rym: Well, you said buy your Valve games.
Rym: It was a way to update Counter-Strike for pretty much everyone who used it.
Scott: Also Half-Life 1.
Scott: Yeah, but even by then Half-Life- Half-Life 1 things, like Half-Life 1 whatever.
Rym: No one was playing like- Day of Defeat.
Rym: Yeah, whatever.
Scott: Whatever, anyway.
Rym: In those early days of Steam, 99.9% of people were playing Counter-Strike.
Scott: It was also replacing WAN, the World Opponent Network, which was if you wanted to play Counter-Strike, you had to like find servers.
Scott: You'd bring up this window to browse for servers to join.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: And that was run by Sierra/WAN, the World Opponent Network.
Scott: Right?
Scott: If you look at the original box for Half-Life 1, it has a Sierra logo on it.
Rym: That's the same logo that's on like Quest for Glory.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: But Steam was also replacing that.
Scott: Valve was running their own servers and their own, at some point, to browse, you know, their own lobby servers to find Counter-Strike servers.
Rym: The point is we're old, but the other point is that because Valve made Steam and Steam was the way to update pretty much the most played PC game on Earth at the time, it meant that when Valve wanted to just make the store to sell games and turn Steam into that store, they had the guaranteed built-in audience and it was guaranteed to succeed.
Scott: Yes, Steam added all those features like friend chat and a store as they went on and it became To Conquer the World, it is now basically the PC game store.
Scott: Many other companies have been like, "Damn it, I want to sell PC games, so I don't want to give Valve some of my
Scott: monies."
Scott: Right?
Scott: "So I'm going to make my own
Scott: store.".
Scott: There's a Ubisoft store, there's an EA origin store.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: You all know how well those stores worked.
Scott: There's all these competing stores because they don't want to give Valve a cut and all those stores have not done well.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: They had not dominated the scene.
Scott: Sometimes you install one of them just because it's a game you want to play, but you don't actually buy anything else in that store.
Rym: More than once in my life, I have re-bought a game I already owned on Steam just because it was easier than dealing with the old store.
Scott: You use the Steam store, all those other things, except for the battle net one maybe because you have to, right?
Scott: It's like they're just launchers for a specific subset of games that are not on Steam and all the other games you buy on Steam.
Scott: But today, the Fortnite people, Epic, the people who also make the Unreal engine, are like, "Hey, we got Fortnite.
Scott: We'll make a fucking
Scott: store.".
Scott: Right?
Scott: We don't want to give Valve or whoever a cut of our Fortnite monies.
Rym: We're number one.
Rym: And also, Valve takes a huge cut.
Rym: We'll just take away less of a cut because fuck it.
Scott: Right, they're like, "Alright, not only are we going to make our own store for Fortnite, but you know what, you want to sell your games on the Fortnite store?
Scott: The thing that people probably have installed just as much as they have Steam
Scott: installed?".
Rym: More people are probably playing Fortnite.
Scott: "We will take less of your money than Valve will
Scott: take.".
Rym: More humans are probably playing Fortnite right now than have ever played Counter-Strike.
Rym: Maybe.
Rym: Like, Fortnite is the Counter-Strike of this era, which means that Epic gets to be the Valve of this era starting from a clean slate if they want to be.
Scott: If they can get enough people to sell their non-Fortnite games on the Epic Fortnite store...
Rym: I would put them on the Epic store if I had a game.
Scott: Yeah, if I had a game, why wouldn't I put it on that store?
Rym: Plus, I'd get access to a fresh audience, not these old Counter-Strike nerds who bitch about everything, like Hank, Jim, and Scott.
Scott: The point is, is that Valve has also done something.
Scott: They said, "Alright, we realize our cut, which is a flat percentage, is too big if your game is too
Scott: big.".
Scott: If you have a small game on Steam and they take this percentage, it's like, "Alright, you've got to give Valve enough money to pay for the services they're providing you, like delivering your files to everyone who buys your game and handling all the
Scott: monies.".
Scott: It's only fair that you give them some money.
Scott: They're doing all the shit for you.
Scott: But, if you have a big, big, big popular game on Steam, that percentage cut, even though it's a small percentage, comes out to an enormous amount of money, which is way worth, way more than the services Valve is providing you.
Scott: So they said, "Alright, we've got a new deal on Steam.
Scott: If your game gets real big, we will shrink the
Scott: cut."
Scott: Sort of like how if you're a retail store and you order more product from a wholesaler, you know, they give you a better deal.
Rym: So what this means, I think, is a couple of things.
Rym: One, it means that Valve's Monopoly days are numbered.
Scott: Yeah, you feel like nothing can be affronted.
Scott: Myspace died, tons of Google things have died.
Rym: Someday Amazon will die.
Scott: All things die.
Scott: Facebook is vulnerable.
Scott: Even Steam is vulnerable.
Scott: I still will go buy things on Steam before I buy them anywhere else because Steam has been around as long as I've made that account.
Rym: I own so many fucking games on Steam.
Scott: Steam has been around since before browsers had tabs, basically, but meanwhile you go to, like, say, the Nintendo Wii shop is gonna die, like, early next year, right?
Scott: So that is why, if there's a game that is on Switch and Steam, I almost always buy the Steam one and not the Switch one.
Rym: My Oculus.
Rym: Oculus has its own store, built in, real easy to use.
Scott: Can't you also buy Oculus games on Steam, though?
Rym: Yes, I buy all my games on Steam and I go into the Steam launcher instead of the Oculus launcher.
Scott: I trust that Steam, even if it is affronted by the Epic store, will continue to exist for a very long time.
Rym: So here's what I predict is gonna happen.
Rym: There is now going to be a real competition on how much of a cut the stores take and how many features the stores provide.
Scott: Great for game developers.
Scott: Great for game players and customers.
Scott: It's only bad for Valve and Epic.
Rym: When I say the features...
Scott: They're going from zero to money.
Rym: But when I say the features that the stores provide, I don't mean to you and me, they don't give a shit about us, I mean to the developers, because it sucks ass to put a game up on Steam because they knew they didn't have to help you.
Rym: Now, the stores are going to compete for the attention of the developers.
Scott: They're going to try to get exclusives, like please put your game on the Steam and not on the Epic.
Rym: Or they're going to reduce friction to make it real easy to manage your game on their platform and deploy it to the platform to make it more likely for more developers to use the platform out of convenience.
Scott: Much like consoles, they're going to be not only trying to get exclusives, but both of the companies that own stores are also developers, right?
Rym: Oh, that's the other thing, they're going to start making games again.
Scott: Right, Fortnite will fade, right?
Scott: Artifact hasn't really done great, as predicted.
Rym: You know what this means, Valve might actually have to make fucking Half-Life 3.
Scott: These companies, you can expect as Fortnite fades, and Valve, as all of their games fade, they are going to have to develop games to make their stores things that people must install, right?
Scott: Also expect Blizzard Activision, you know, they already got, what's the friggin' Destiny, whatever in their store there, in the Battle.net client.
Scott: You can expect them to maybe be trying to load up that client with other stuff, right?
Scott: Yup.
Rym: So, stay tuned, this is all good news for us, and I mean, most people in the old days, like when we were young, they'd be like, "Oh, Counter-Strike will be the top game
Rym: forever.".
Rym: And it was, until pretty recently, actually.
Scott: You'll know that it's a real thing.
Scott: when I have to install the Epic Store to install something, I won't install Fortnite, but there might be something else I need it for.
Rym: We did a panel in like 2010 or 2011, I still have a screenshot of it, I took a screenshot of the current simultaneous players of the top ten games on Steam, and it was literally, number one was Counter-Strike Source, number two was Counter-Strike 1.6.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: So, everyone who complains about Fortnite because you're old like us, listen, Fortnite is Counter-Strike, everything cycles, everything that's old is new, this is the same thing happening all over again.
Scott: The question is, even though Fortnite is obviously huge, right, will it last as long as Counter-Strike has lasted, or will it, at some point, go
Scott: "DING!"?
Rym: Or will it be that the cycle of this will just be faster, because in the old days, it took a long time for anyone to even try to compete with Counter-Strike.
Rym: Meanwhile, we had like, PUBG and Fortnite are out like within hours of each other, effectively.
Scott: Well, PUBG went
Scott: "EEEW!".
Scott: It's not, obviously there's still plenty of people playing PUBG, but it sort of did not win its win them battle.
Rym: No, PUBG won a battle to lose the war.
Rym: It'll be its initial experience, and even though I prefer it, I'm not going to complain about Fortnite, because Fortnite is very accessible and is going to really deliver, Fortnite is doing to PC gaming and cross-platform play, and when I say cross-platform, I mean like, on a PC, or on a Switch, or on a tablet, or on a phone, who gives a shit, just games everywhere.
Rym: It's going to do to the modern space what Counter-Strike did to earlier PC gaming, what Quake 2 did to even earlier PC gaming.
Rym: It's all good news.
Rym: Of course, also, if you're not aware, Smash is coming out on the Switch.
Scott: The new Smash is going to be out this Friday, so if you're wondering, you know, you want to let me Smash?
Rym: I'll let you Smash.
Scott: You want to let me Smash?
Scott: You can Smash on Friday.
Rym: I'm going to Smash.
Scott: So get ready, because your holidays and your MAGFest are going to be full of smashing.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: The only worry I have is that the local wireless multiplayer, I assume, will just not work at all, because Nintendo has never gotten that to work ever on any platform they've ever delivered.
Scott: And I'm not paying for the online service?
Scott: Nope.
Scott: So it's going to be local, one Switch multiplayer with a bunch of controllers, as per usual.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: At least they're wireless.
Rym: And of course, Rastakhan's Rumbles just came out in Hearthstone.
Scott: Yup, a new Hearthstone expansion came out today.
Scott: Like, it's out right now as I speak.
Scott: When I get home, that's probably what I'm going to do.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So Emily shared this video with me, and it's a stream of some people playing VRChat.
Rym: If you're not familiar, VRChat is kind of fascinating.
Rym: It's basically...
Scott: Is it just people who put on VR things just to chat in VR?
Rym: But it also has a desktop client, and it is basically the cyberspace that we all wanted in the 90s, but it kind of just exists today.
Rym: People just interact in this space, and it's a whole thing on its own.
Rym: But in this space, people have also made these games.
Rym: You can just play these kind of low-rent games with a lot of people.
Rym: And because most of the people who are using it do have VR rigs, because you're capturing all their motion, it's pretty immersive and pretty interesting.
Rym: This is something that if you have kids, they are in this thing, even if you don't own VR, and you probably don't even realize it.
Rym: It's real big.
Rym: But this video is a stream with this kid and this guy.
Rym: I don't know if it's an older brother or a dad, but the kid's name is Jordan.
Rym: And the kid has been living in VRChat, and this older person is like, "Let me play with you.
Rym: I'll come in there, and I'm going to record us playing, and we'll see how it
Rym: goes.".
Rym: And this kid is basically Catbug in real life, and this kid is just too cute and too innocent for the terrifying world of VRChat, let alone the evil realities of a cruel Earth.
Rym: And this is so cute to watch.
Rym: He's like, "Okay, here's what we're going to
Rym: do.".
Rym: And the older guy's like, "All right, Jordan, tell me what to
Rym: And he's like, "So first you take this
Rym: bomb.".
Rym: He's like, "Whoa, bomb.
Rym: Okay, whatever, let's
Rym: go.".
Rym: He's like, "And you run up here.
Rym: Okay, Jordan, what do you
Rym: do?".
Rym: Then you huck it over the edge, and then it explodes.
Rym: And he's like, "Maybe I killed
Rym: someone.".
Rym: And the dad's just like, "Whoa,
Rym: okay.".
Rym: It's so cute.
Rym: You gotta watch this.
Rym: Yeah, seriously, this kid is just Catbug in real life.
Rym: The kid's going to be a famous streamer someday, I think, because of this video.
Scott: So, check this out.
Scott: There's apparently some movie called The Art of Rhyme, or maybe a documentary or something.
Scott: I've never seen it.
Scott: I've only seen this clip, this one minute and forty second clip that was posted on YouTube, because a coworker shared it on Slack.
Scott: And this is video footage from Bed-Stuy neighborhood in Brooklyn.
Scott: And in this video is the long-deceased Notorious B.I.G.
Scott: freestyling like, "Oh,
Scott: snap.".
Scott: And he's only seventeen years old.
Rym: Oh, damn.
Scott: So you can see, in case you are too young to know about Biggie, now you can know, like going back and watching, you know, Michael Jordan dunk or whatever.
Scott: You can see why he was so talented and why he is so missed.
Rym: Wow, look at this.
Rym: That video, this video gives me life.
Scott: That's what I'm saying.
Rym: In the meta moment, we're back from PAX Unplugged.
Rym: We'll try to get video of our two panels up when we get a chance.
Scott: Oh, I forgot to bring it.
Rym: That's fine.
Scott: I have it backed up in three places, just not with me.
Rym: Yeah, that's fine.
Rym: I'm not going to have time to edit shit until this weekend, even if then.
Rym: And also, I'm going to get PAX to give me the actual video they took, because at the 40 tabletop games you must play, we didn't just do the panel in a panel room.
Rym: It was in the big panel room, so it was live streamed on the PAX Twitch.
Scott: So can you go to the PAX Twitch, and is there a VOD available to see it right now?
Rym: I'm not sure, because I haven't had a chance to go check.
Scott: Well, go check the twitch.tv/pax2.
Rym: Yeah, I assume it was PAX 2.
Scott: I assume it's PAX 2, but check all the official PAX Twitch TV channels.
Rym: GeekNights is moderately popular, we are not popular enough to be PAX 1.
Scott: Right, look at their VOD, this main theater.
Rym: Yeah, the day we're in the main theater is either the day that something crazy has happened, or the day that PAX has made a terrible mistake.
Scott: Right, check the saved videos attached to those Twitch channels, and see if you can find our panel, if you really have nothing better to do.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Yep, and we will be now, upcoming at MagFest, doing like, a bunch of panels, you don't have to be on all of them if you don't want
Scott: to, and
Rym: we will be at PAX South in San
Scott: Antonio, like right after that,
Rym: doing at least one panel, and that panel is a brand new one that I still have to write, nostalgia versus game design.
Rym: I think we're going to talk about Windjammers at least once in this panel.
Scott: No one wanted to accept my panel about harmful games.
Rym: I think we're going to do that one at PAX East.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: That's a good place, I think PAX East is a good place for that one.
Rym: Maybe at MagFest I might sneak it in into mages, we'll see.
Rym: So stay tuned.
Rym: Otherwise the Book of the Book is 2001, Space Odyssey, I have a lot of downtime over the holidays, I'll probably read it.
Scott: I do not have to go to work from Christmas through New Year, and I'm only not partying until New Year.
Rym: Oh, the cold guy says it was on PAX 2.
Scott: It was on PAX 2.
Rym: Because PAX 3 was a different room.
Scott: Alright, well verify if the video is there or not.
Scott: When I get a chance.
Rym: I've been busy.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: I haven't even unpacked from PAX yet, give me a break.
Rym: God, it's always hard to, like, our lives are different now from what they were a decade ago, but every year we'd be like, oh it's time for PAX, this once a year event.
Rym: So I get like five PAXs a year now, two of them, I've got three, four gaming conventions in the world, we're going to be doing Eeknights, you know, we might miss some because holidays and shit, right?
Scott: So, you know how it is, next week there'll be a Monday Wednesday, hopefully.
Rym: Yep, hopefully.
Rym: But I do intend to do some other shows when Scott's not around, and both of us, when shows don't happen, we'll probably be livestreaming a bunch of stuff, and sometime soon we're going to be judging the upcoming season of anime.
Scott: Yeah, we have to do that in December.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And if you look at our website now, you can see when we judged the previous season of anime, the fall season before it came out, so you can find out if we were right about Tokyo Ghoul Re 2 or whatever.
Scott: Alright, so, we're going to talk about a game called Treasure Island, the most...
Rym: Oh, someone in the stream just linked to the VOD of the stream.
Scott: Good job.
Rym: So yeah, go to the livestream right now, and you can click on this link.
Rym: I hope that link actually goes to it and out to a Rick Roll, I didn't check it.
Scott: I hope so.
Scott: Anyway, so, Treasure Island, the most straightforward game name you could possibly think of.
Scott: Yes, it's just directly based on the book, there's a Long John Silver.
Rym: The Black Spot, the Monkey, everything.
Scott: It's pirate themed, it's literally just fucking Treasure Island, the game.
Rym: So here's the deal.
Scott: The way it works is it's a lot like Fury of Dracula.
Scott: One player is Long John Silver.
Rym: Yarr.
Rym: I played, the first and only time I played this game, I was Long John Silver.
Rym: Holy shit, is that stressful and difficult.
Scott: The other four players are parrots.
Scott: I don't remember if they're characters in the book or not, I assume they were.
Scott: They're characters, whatever.
Scott: They have slightly different powers.
Rym: I haven't read, I've never read the book all the way through.
Rym: Oh, I have.
Rym: I read excerpts from it in elementary school.
Scott: But it was a very long time ago.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I saw the one old movie.
Scott: I have better memories of Muppet Treasure Island, which I saw several times.
Rym: I remember Muppet Treasure Island better than I remember any other form of Treasure Island.
Scott: That is true.
Scott: Anyway, Animal Treasure Island is also good.
Scott: Is it Miyazaki or Tezuka?
Rym: I've never actually seen it.
Scott: I haven't seen it either, but I just know it exists.
Scott: Anyway, the point is, this game, much like Fury of Dracula, has Long John Silver hiding a treasure instead of running around Europe like Dracula, and four players, up to four players working together to find the treasure.
Scott: But, not really together unlike Fury of Dracula, they're competing to who gets the treasure first.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: And the other conceit that's interesting is that Long John Silver, the game is basically.
Rym: Long John Silver is being interrogated by the pirates.
Scott: He's in jail.
Scott: On the island somewhere.
Rym: So first he's just being interrogated, and you have to use cards to basically give clues about where the treasure is.
Scott: Right, well Long John, while he's being interrogated, gives clues to the interrogators.
Rym: But then at some point, during one of the turns, one of the players puts Long John in a prison on the island somewhere.
Scott: Right, there are several prisons on the map, Long John is in one of them.
Scott: At some point you find out which one he's in.
Rym: Eventually, the end of the game, if none of the pirates found the treasure, Long John breaks out, and now moves around the map with the same rules as the players, and if Long John gets to his own treasure, he wins, fuck you all.
Scott: Right.
Scott: One other thing is that Long John is giving these clues to the players, whether they use their powers, or just every turn he has to sort of do something, or every so often he has to give information to the interrogators, but he can lie up to two times during the game.
Scott: He doesn't actually have to lie, but two of his clues, all the clues must be true, except up to two of them may or may not be true.
Rym: Yep, and the may or may not is key, because one of my lie attempt, like possibilities of lies, I actually told the truth to try to double cross the players, and it worked on everyone but one player.
Scott: Because you basically tell the truth, you put the lying token next to it, a player uses their power to look at the token, and the other players don't see it.
Scott: They see it, that player now sees like a question mark, right, but they assume, oh that means it's not true, and they invert that thing, it's like no actually.
Rym: So get this, this happened in the game, so our friend Tracy, he assumed that the first clue I put down was a lie, and he was right.
Scott: I thought you're not allowed to lie in the first one, you can't get a lie token until like the third.
Rym: No, you get one lie token at the beginning of the game, and you get one about half way through.
Scott: I thought you get one like after turn X or something.
Rym: Yeah, you get the second one after turn X. Oh okay.
Rym: You have to put one clue out that you can't lie about before the game starts.
Rym: That's right.
Rym: Then you put ones out.
Rym: The first one I put out that I had discretion, I put the lie token, and I did lie.
Rym: Tracy said before the game started, I bet Ram will put the lie tokens out but not actually lie, but then he used his power immediately to check to see if I lied in the first turn, and of course I did, and I did lie.
Rym: He then played the beginning of the game, searching and acting as though he thought I was telling the truth, trying to trick the other three pirates into thinking that I had told the truth there, when in fact he thought I had lied, and in fact I had lied.
Rym: That was really well played.
Scott: The point is, this game when you see it, is a huge ton of fun, because you're not just moving around a map, right, you know with little tokens like a normal game, you're drawing on the map, everyone has a personal map that they can draw on.
Rym: Yup, including Long John Silver.
Scott: Right, the game comes with all these dry erase markers and a compass, you can draw radiuses, radii.
Rym: Yup, there's a ruler, if you move, you like draw on the ruler how many miles you're going to move, there's a smaller rule for the minimaps.
Rym: Much, it's
Scott: very theme appropriate, it's like you're using all these sort of nautical-ish, much simpler than actual nautical sextants or whatever, but you know, tools to draw on this map, the shared map as well as your personal maps, they give you a mini ruler, so you can use that on your tiny map, and it's at scale to the big ruler you use on the big map, right, so you can measure things out privately, you know, and it's like, oh, you can see, so you'll be like, ah, yes, the treasure is within three of one of these players, stuff like that.
Scott: But then of all the players, everyone starts drawing circles and being like, okay, it's got to be in one of these circles.
Rym: But some of the clues are things that I hand to the other players, so each player knows like five sets of information independently of one another, and then collectively they know another set of information, but that set of information may or may not be true, and different players might have looked at different tokens.
Scott: And the players aren't sharing info with each other.
Rym: Hell no.
Scott: So even though it might be like, if all the players shared info, they might know exactly where the treasure is right away, because they each have separate info, right, it's like, well, it's going to take any one player a longer amount of time to figure out where the treasure is.
Rym: This also means that since I was long John Silver, I was keeping track of, as best I could, the kinds of information I'd given to different players to try to give individual players worthless information to them if I had the opportunity to give just them information.
Rym: And I successfully gave two players fucking bullshit because I knew things they knew and I gave them the same information over and over again via different mechanisms.
Scott: So that's basically how this game goes.
Scott: Long John tries to give as little information as possible, the players do a Scotland Yard, Fury of Dracula kind of narrowing down possibilities thing.
Scott: They walk in, they walk along the map to the possible areas, use their searching ability and attempting to find the treasure.
Rym: So the fun part is that the placement rules for the treasure are literally, I just fucking mark an X anywhere.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: Anywhere on this whole, the map doesn't really have like a grid or anything.
Scott: It's just a picture of an island with a bunch of features on it.
Scott: And you put a dot on your private map and that's what the treasure is.
Rym: And of course what Scott was musing that I would do and what I did in fact do is I drew one goddamn pixel.
Rym: That's right.
Rym: And I was like, it is here at the intersection of the edge of this building and this forest.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: You're very precise and where the treasure was.
Scott: So if someone came close and someone did.
Rym: Someone came literally within like two millimeters.
Scott: They were more like a centimeter away.
Rym: They were less than a centimeter.
Scott: But the point is, is they came real close and but their circle clearly was not on the spot you had selected.
Scott: So no treasure for you.
Rym: And the way you search and there's a fun little bit here is you use this little ring and you literally draw on the big map, a circle around where you're searching and the ring has to fit around your character.
Rym: So where you move to, like you're really limited.
Rym: And then I have to decide if it's inside or not.
Rym: The rule is if there's any question as to whether or not it's inside, it is.
Rym: Hence, I literally put a dot on my map and then I use my fingernail to shave off pieces of that dot because the felt to the marker is only so precise to make it down to like this one pixel.
Rym: And then I took a picture of it in case I accidentally smudge that one pixel off.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: But anyway, the one very interesting mechanic in this game is that when players search, if they find the treasure, Long John takes this little cardboard treasure chest, puts the big treasure token.
Scott: So hands it to the player.
Scott: They open it.
Scott: The big treasures in there.
Scott: They win.
Rym: When anyone searches, what I did is I took the the treasure chest, this big cardboard box.
Rym: I either put nothing in it.
Rym: I put one of the mini treasures that I can give out of my own discretion.
Rym: There's reasons why you would.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Or if they got it right, I just would have put the big treasure in and not said anything.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That's what you're supposed to do.
Scott: But what I'm saying is the clever mechanic is those small treasures.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Long John has to give out these clues as the game goes on to the players.
Scott: But it's like a deck of clues.
Rym: The clues suck.
Rym: You read these clues.
Rym: It's like, wow, any one of these will just fuck me.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The clues, if you have to give those clues, if you give them honestly, which you have to do all but two times, you're just going to tell them where the treasure is.
Scott: But if you give players these mini treasures when they search right, then what you can do is if you've given enough tiny treasures to the players, not the big treasure that makes you win the game, but the tiny ones that gives you access to these other clues that are weaker clues.
Scott: and using the weaker clues is much easier because now you won't have to basically give the whole game away with your giant lousy clues.
Rym: But now you've given players very powerful tools to use.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: Those tiny treasures give the players abilities that they can now use during the game.
Scott: So it's like I can either give them TMI or I can give them less info, but more abilities to make their search easier.
Scott: And you have to sort of figure out what you want to do.
Scott: Meanwhile, players know this.
Scott: They know that's how the game works.
Scott: So what players can do, which I learned after the first game, is don't use your searching ability early in the game.
Scott: And thus Long John is forced to give the big clues.
Scott: You can't give the little clues if you haven't searched because then he can't give you the little treasures.
Scott: Then again, you're also not searching.
Scott: You're just walking around using other forms of clues and other actions besides the search action.
Scott: So you got this balancing act going on.
Scott: That's the cool part of the game.
Scott: What I think is the problem with this game is that with intelligent players, I do not think Long John can win.
Rym: So I played.
Rym: I was Long John the first time ever played the game.
Rym: Two of the people at the table had already played this game multiple times and all three of the pirates were very smart people.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: I was literally one turn from winning.
Rym: I busted out of prison and I got right next to my fucking treasure.
Scott: You would have gotten it next turn.
Rym: You were definitely in range.
Rym: I did.
Rym: They had narrowed down, but by the end of the game, they couldn't find the treasure.
Scott: Like I said, one person on that previous turn had searched less than a centimeter away from the treasure location.
Rym: They collectively narrowed it down to maybe six square centimeters on the entire map.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Like they were so close and then I couldn't get, because I hosted myself by my own petard, because I drew my treasure dot as such a precise pixel, I was literally less than half a centimeter away from being able to just win.
Rym: And then I lost in the last, last possible round.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: I think, I mean, that's what I think is.
Scott: I think it's calibrated in such a way.
Scott: I think if the players are not that good at searching or are less skilled, I think a skilled Long John would just dominate.
Rym: But I think a poor quality Long John will lose immediately.
Scott: A poor quality Long John will lose immediately and give everything away.
Scott: But amongst all skilled players where everyone is up on up, I think that the Long John, they can take the game into the late stages, but I don't think they can get away with it.
Scott: It's, you know, I think what would be good is if you just kept exactly the same everything.
Scott: Don't change a thing, except make the map just maybe like six inches larger in both directions.
Scott: That way with the same exact clues, right, you're making it a little harder to narrow it down.
Scott: And maybe at the end, you know, it might also be a problem, but at least the players might have two choices and have to pick one.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's like, OK, well, the game comes down to luck then.
Scott: Well, maybe it does, but at least it's not just sort of like this locked in thing.
Rym: That's I also feel like if you get really fine tipped dry erase markers, you can make the game more interesting.
Scott: because I would love to see a digital version of this game.
Scott: Oh, hell yeah.
Scott: That was pixel perfect with zooming in and zooming out.
Rym: I would play I would play it a lot where you had to literally click the exact pixel.
Scott: I'm like, you know, like you get like a like you do your search, like a two thousand by two thousand JPEG and you must click.
Scott: That would be what?
Scott: Forty thousand pixels.
Rym: Well, you got to search the area around your character that includes some number of right.
Scott: Your search must include that pixel specifically if it is what that pixel is just outside the edge of your radius.
Scott: You didn't get it.
Rym: But the moral is like.
Rym: in the end, this game is way fun and worth owning.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: If you want to have a searching finding game, I would rather play this than Scotland Yard.
Rym: Well, because Scotland Yard slash Mr.
Scott: X or whatever.
Rym: If you're a computer scientist or even computer science adjacent, you can easily determine an algorithm that guarantees Mr.
Rym: X will lose.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: I would rather play this inferior of Dracula, because even though I like the hidden card movement and searching inferior Dracula a little bit better than the Treasure Island, I do not like any of the other parts of your Dracula.
Rym: Dude, busting out the compass and drawing a giant fucking circle on this map is really, really satisfying.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: Especially when the treasure is like a millimeter outside of that circle and you're just like, nope, stone face.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: There is a game I played that you did not play called Cryptid, which as a hex map.
Scott: Oh, and you're trying to find a chupacabra or equivalent.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's in this room and there's clues like like, you know, different information that the players like, OK, I know it's not in a mountain hex.
Scott: I know it's too away from a forest hex, that kind of thing.
Scott: And you sort of narrow it down and see who can find it first.
Scott: I played that game once and I won because I narrowed it down to three hexes and guessed and I guessed right.
Scott: But, you know, it's similar.
Scott: But Cryptid is, while perfectly fine, it does not have the fun of drawing with the sextant to the compass and all that biz.
Rym: The drawing makes it real fun.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So in terms of while it is not perfect and has some flaws in terms of one versus many hide and seek games, I think Treasure Island may be the current number one of ones that I have played.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows, SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Craig Oliver, Alan Joyce, Jaime Nicholas, Sherwin Rubiobolos, Kanging in the Sky, Jartavishan, Linky G, MyStady.com, Jay Bantz, Scootalonely, Roberto Kingsley, Sean Yeager, Matthew Smith, Nicholas Brando, Mr.
Rym: Strong Strachan, 421 Creations, Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn, Sherwin Van Harl, Rory, Rochelle Montanona, Superboy with eight exclamation points, Sailor Vista, Don Schleig, Joe Shiro, Joe Star, Clinton Walton, Run from New Zealand with three exclamation points, Ryan Perrin, Drew Openlander, Finn, Chris Midkiff, Daniel Redmond, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: So yeah, we're back from PAX, just in time to start preparing for another PAX, and a magfest, and yet another PAX.
Rym: So expect I think four new panels and like six reruns in the next couple months.
Rym: And now I leave you with...