Rym: It's Thursday, June 21st 2018.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: How we've changed in 20 years.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So this is Thursday obviously not Tuesday, but it's worth mentioning that both Scott and I because it's on sale.
Rym: But pub G.
Scott: Well, I mean it was originally I was like, oh man that game looks like the kind of thing I want to play but I don't got time.
Scott: and then I was like, you know Especially when he gave the guy who made it gave a talk at PAX East.
Rym: He's actually really made me want to play.
Scott: Well, I mean, I already knew that I wanted.
Scott: it was my kind of game.
Scott: But I was like, you know that basically was like.
Scott: well, it is my kind of game confirmed.
Rym: Like I thought Your kind of game and you won't play that but I missed the boat.
Scott: I was like, I'm too late for the pub G vote.
Scott: I can't get into it now But suddenly the game is on sale and it's like.
Scott: well You know what?
Scott: for 20 bucks even if I play it and then only for a short time like maybe a month or so You know and then stop playing it.
Scott: It'll be it's worth 20 bucks.
Scott: steam sales started today, whatever.
Scott: So I played it last night for the first time.
Scott: I played like between 10 and 20 matches and I killed one person.
Rym: I have so far killed zero people, but I almost killed one dude.
Scott: This game is hard.
Rym: Yeah, dude I almost killed me.
Scott: still fun despite being hard and having some annoyances.
Rym: Well, but also I like those early days when I picked up counter-strike and I was like wait, what's up with this game?
Scott: Also, I feel like people have told me that since I waited so long to play it it used to be worse.
Scott: So I actually feel like maybe if I started earlier I would have been pissed off at it for sucking a hole for having a lot of issues and it has been polished much in The time I was not playing it and now I am less angry at it.
Scott: No as a result, which I guess could be a good thing.
Scott: So I guess for me the game is far from dead despite, you know, not no longer being number one.
Rym: well, it's above this line that happens in games where it is Popular enough to where it might end up like counter-strike.
Rym: Well, it'll just always be kind of going in the background forever.
Scott: It's gonna last longer than the tribes of two.
Rym: Yeah, I think it's tribes two is still probably the most fun.
Rym: I've had per unit time I played.
Rym: you know, it's really online multiplayer.
Scott: It's really weird is obviously I suck ass at this game.
Scott: Yeah, but I played.
Scott: there was a quake.
Scott: champions is is is free on Steam.
Scott: you can get it for free.
Scott: It's a. it's like a free to play quake and I played that because it was free And it's the most loot box.
Scott: It's basically quake plus loot boxes.
Rym: I'm sick of this loot box and also classes.
Scott: But the loot boxes are purely cosmetic.
Scott: They don't.
Scott: there's not a single loot box thing I could find in the game.
Scott: that was any in any way Material to gameplay.
Scott: so it's not pay to win.
Scott: It's it's a legit quake.
Scott: It was way faster than quake 3 or quake arena or any or any quake that I've played recently Like a quick one.
Scott: it was a full speed quake.
Scott: It was.
Scott: I was like wow this I do not want this to be any faster because that will be beyond my abilities to control.
Scott: And you know what.
Scott: obviously I was a deathmatch.
Scott: it was like a team deathmatch where it's like just get as many kills as you can of people on that are not the same color as you and Despite the fact that I was not like the best or anything My team won every time I played and I got a respectable number of frags every time.
Scott: so I still have some amount of FPS skill.
Scott: Yet PUBG is way way way way way slower.
Scott: It's like molasses compared to that quake champions and I killed one person because we happen to spawn in the same place.
Scott: We were having a fistfight.
Scott: Then they went to pick up a gun and they punched them to death while they were picking up the gun.
Rym: the big difference is that PUBG is Not about FPS skills so much as about situational awareness skills.
Scott: I have no situational awareness pretty much almost every time I got shot.
Scott: It was like oh my god These bullets coming from oh my god.
Rym: Oh my god.
Rym: I'm dead.
Rym: It's always sniper across the map like picks me off.
Scott: Maybe it was a sniper.
Scott: I spin around.
Scott: I don't see anyone.
Scott: I hide I get my scope out.
Scott: I'm looking all over the place.
Scott: my favorite moments are where you hear still shooting at me.
Scott: the bullets are landing real close.
Rym: I'll be like in the woods, and then I hear like And I'm not sure how if the gunfire was directed me or not so I freeze.
Scott: I'm gonna switch to using headphones to figure out.
Rym: Oh, yeah, 100% headphones when I play.
Rym: But yeah, I mentioned it because the good news is we're gonna play PUBG and hang and like.
Rym: if you want to play with Us I think we'll be able to get some groups together because a lot of there's a bunch of forum I it's already playing PUBG who are way better than us, but also still really bad.
Scott: They're bad, but they're better than us, which is how bad we are, but they're awful.
Scott: They're bad We're the worst.
Rym: this is definitely the kind of game where if this had come out well They're poop we're diarrhea much like counter-strike and tribes - if this had come out while we were at RIT This would have been our lives.
Rym: Oh probably I would have played this every goddamn day.
Rym: No, probably because it's got that arm a or like weapons factory thing.
Scott: our may is our ma.
Rym: our may thing to say is You have like 50 things to bind to your keyboard, and I just left all.
Scott: I just left all defaults and learned them.
Scott: I changed I don't like that all the defaults.
Scott: I like some of them But I just decided it's what I do in life as I just learn defaults now Policy they all assume you inverted your y-axis course.
Scott: I did.
Rym: I did not but I Didn't change all the bindings willy-nilly.
Rym: what I did is I played the game and as soon as there was a thing I wanted to do and The default wasn't good only at the moment where I had a reason to do the thing in the course of the game Did I bind rebind it?
Rym: But I followed my ancient philosophy and a lot of the things you can do in this game are Analogous to things I used to bind to standard positions in old games that I used to play.
Scott: so like grenade I don't know I haven't actually played a lot of FPS is where you can go prone And this is I think the only one I ever played.
Scott: that where you can go prone was soldier of fortune.
Scott: I don't even remember if that's 100% correct.
Scott: Yeah, so that was new to me.
Rym: Yeah going prone I ended up binding to crouching and I use it instead of crouching and crouching I found somewhere else.
Scott: Yeah, well crouching I like how you can run while crouching and also walk.
Scott: walk crouching Yep, or you can like whatever.
Scott: I spent like five minutes just prone crawling through the only thing I was gonna complain about like I couldn't figure out how to use the scope.
Scott: like Right mouse button brings the gun up to aim But it doesn't to give you.
Scott: I had a big scope on the thing.
Scott: a scope I found was an item on the ground.
Scott: I attach it to the gun and I couldn't figure out how to get the scope.
Scott: and then I Googled and it said double click the right mouse button and that wasn't because it wasn't a binding like activate scope in the settings.
Scott: And then I was like I was annoyed that the game didn't teach me that and it was.
Scott: But actually that's a good default.
Scott: I liked it.
Rym: So also you notice you can bind.
Rym: anyway, we'll talk about this in a Tuesday show, but we're playing pub G and It's tates eating into my overwatch time, which is a problem.
Scott: I'm playing pub G and hearthstone and netrunner died and I finished.
Scott: I went back and beat Skyrim And Mario tennis comes out like did air tomorrow.
Rym: I actually started playing fallout 4.
Rym: Okay, cuz I never actually played it.
Scott: not playing that, you know, it's on Steam sale for 30 Which is too much cuz I got it in VR and it's just if you have VR and you have that game.
Rym: It's real fun to play in VR But it wouldn't be worth getting VR just to have that experience is the way I'd put it.
Scott: Hmm So I'm interested in the 76 weather.
Rym: Yeah, I'm actually really into the online aspect of it because I As a 36 year old I don't have time for single-player games that are long.
Scott: Nope The way I played Skyrim just now an easy mode and I blitz through it and ignored all the garbage.
Rym: I feel I have this feel like I want to play Final Fantasy 4 again.
Scott: No, you can't cheat and blitz.
Scott: Yeah, I think I'm just gonna cheat.
Scott: I'm actually considering playing Final Fantasy 6 and chrono trigger and cheating to just make like turn off all random encounters and make my Characters like level nine nine nine nine nine nine nine and just win every combat without doing anything.
Scott: All I do is walk around and talk to everyone in town and then Explore the dungeons for Final Fantasy.
Rym: one cuz I was feeling a weird craving to play that again like a really weird craving like oh I could cheat at that too.
Scott: No, don't even need to cheat.
Rym: I just watch an AGD Q speedrun.
Scott: That's glitchless Yeah, but I can't.
Scott: they don't talk to everyone in town.
Scott: That's what I want to do is the talking.
Rym: We need a.
Scott: you got a white guy As GD Q starts in like a week.
Rym: I know my god.
Scott: Or does it start this Sunday?
Scott: it starts soon.
Rym: speaking of things that are long that I don't have time for the World Cups happening yeah, and Because I work in a very very international company.
Rym: It's very interesting to see the stark line.
Rym: Most of the people who care about the World Cup Were not born in the United States and most of the people who do not care about the World Cup were born in the United States.
Rym: that is what I have noticed.
Scott: Well, I mean the thing is the World Cup like as much as we rag on the sport of soccer, right?
Scott: It's like the World Cup.
Rym: It's a cultural touch.
Scott: It happens fucking every four years.
Scott: Right, all the teams are based on countries.
Scott: So it's not like you got these teams of like, you know, whoever players you manage You know the rich team gets all the good players.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: no it's country based.
Scott: where the country you're from is the team you play.
Rym: I think the rich country does all the best players, but that doesn't end up being the case, right?
Scott: it doesn't happen that often and It's like the most and it's like, you know, it's the most cared about but it's like it is for serious.
Scott: It's like I you know and all the aspects if they just weren't playing soccer I would be say would be more into it than like any other sporting events.
Scott: people who don't disrespect soccer Obviously, it's the biggest fucking deal in the universe.
Scott: Which one day there'll be an eSports that is that big.
Rym: I'll be at work cuz it's a giant like.
Rym: I'm on this giant open floor.
Scott: It's on even in my newer small work.
Scott: It's on this in the kitchen.
Scott: They got a projector aimed at the wall.
Scott: Everyone who cares and it's like all the games are on on their second monitor anytime you go to any restaurant in the city.
Scott: right now The game if there's a game on it's on.
Rym: yep Every now and then I hear a little commotion because something big happened in a game.
Scott: everyone I walk around the office I'd say 25% of the screens have a little stream in the corner.
Rym: Yeah but In terms of the World Cup, I don't know.
Rym: There's a big bracket and people are like really excited.
Rym: It's still the great stage and I just don't know they're betting.
Rym: Yeah, no people are really invested in this like company-wide bracket.
Scott: Maybe this big pad.
Scott: if you get it, right You give big money.
Rym: Well, apparently anyone who has a Bloomberg terminal not just employees This is like anyone has the terminal can be involved in this really really elaborate bracket.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: That's like right there like type magic word.
Rym: That's the official bracket like go for it.
Scott: Why don't you go and just figure out like, you know, the this go to the odds makers who you know And they'll say these are the best odds.
Scott: just bet on the most likely outcome.
Rym: I don't know though.
Rym: Meanwhile, at least for the Stanley Cup Emily's bracket was was scarily open the envelope Lisa accurate.
Scott: Hmm so yeah World Cup's happening and Yeah, I'm not really gonna watch it cuz it but I mean I watch it when I'm sitting in the room or restaurant But I never intentionally I haven't.
Scott: I've yet to Purposely to go to Google and like look for the stream and open it.
Scott: Yeah, right It's just if it's on.
Scott: I'm watching it, but I don't turn it on.
Rym: So in some sad news if you didn't see this Coco the very famous awesome gorilla who could speak sign language Pretty well and was smarter than a lot of humans like legit smarter than a lot of humans, especially very young humans.
Rym: Yeah, I mean they reading this article also made stronger than every human ever.
Rym: they estimate her probably IQ was between was around 75 to 95. that's that's for his gump level.
Rym: Mmm That's but Coco was an amazing gorilla and it's kind of sad that Coco is dead.
Rym: And if you do not know about Coco, you should watch some of these videos and learn about Coco because I mean I think people have like heard of Coco.
Scott: It's like why it's like they know.
Scott: Oh, yeah There's a girl that knows sign language But like a gorilla
Rym: who got bored one day and ripped the sink out of her enclosure And when the handlers asked her what happened to the sink She literally lied to them in sign language in English and said her pet cat did it.
Rym: That is a level of deception that many humans are incapable of Straight facedly lying.
Scott: and what would be even better is if somehow we could tell that Coco is actually, you know Not not lying thinking it would work But you know making it funny joke.
Rym: Coco made jokes.
Rym: from what I've read like Coco understood our concept of humor.
Rym: So you should learn about Coco if you don't know because if you don't if you haven't really watched videos of Coco interacting with humans.
Rym: it There's a difference between knowing Coco existed and crocking the ramifications of a gorilla.
Rym: who is that?
Rym: Intelligent in a way that humans can comprehend and you know.
Scott: This is one of the reasons why despite eating meats I don't eat monkey brain and I won't eat octopus and I won't eat dolphin.
Rym: I really try to avoid eating octopus, but occasionally I bump into it.
Scott: I mean it helps that octopus is way chewy and I don't like it.
Rym: Anyway, yeah, it's only chewy if it's not the best octopus.
Scott: I also usually avoid eating squid because even though squids are way dumber than octopuses.
Scott: They're also chewy Chewing kind of a. yeah, I just I just really like the image the anime manga image of like a yaga's a chewing on a dried.
Rym: So in some other news that's actually pretty interesting because stuff's moving rapidly.
Rym: So if you didn't notice Canada legit fully legalized cannabis like fully.
Scott: so you can just go to Canada get high There's.
Scott: no you're not breaking any law at all whatsoever Yep, and you can just open up a weed store in Canada and just so lead to any Canadian.
Rym: No, it's funny is in a bunch of parts like in Toronto.
Scott: Is that what I say?
Scott: I'm just confirming that's true.
Rym: Uh, yes, but it doesn't fully take effect until I think October.
Scott: So in October I can.
Scott: if I was Canadian citizen, I could go to Canada Yep in my backyard grow a bunch of weed.
Rym: Well debating whether or not they're gonna let people grow it themselves or how much they can grow.
Scott: but probably okay I start.
Scott: I can start a business in Canada.
Scott: That's a weed farm.
Scott: Yep legitimately openly you can go to it.
Rym: you can go to a wine store and be like smelly a. I would like a Bordeaux from 1988. or you can go to the weed store and the cannabista and be like I would like your finest lemon drop.
Scott: I can sell it to anyone.
Scott: Anyone just sell it over the age of as much in any quantity or some.
Rym: it looks like some provinces have the right to set The age 21 instead which I'm fine with and people who buy it just can walk up with.
Scott: no We're just age-proof and you'll buy as much as they want.
Rym: There's a limit on how much you can buy but it's a really high limit.
Scott: They can buy like a bushel.
Rym: Yeah A bushel of cannabis is a lot.
Scott: I know.
Scott: And then they can just smoke it wherever the fuck in the park in their house.
Rym: You know if smoking it'll be restricted pretty much the same way.
Rym: cigarettes are Fine with you can't like use it in dry.
Scott: What if they?
Scott: what if they consume it in a non smoke emitting way?
Scott: Can they do it?
Scott: Just fucking anywhere seems like you can just like go to a hockey game.
Scott: It's Canada, right?
Scott: Just start eating.
Rym: Yeah, I mean people do that.
Scott: Anyway, I know I mean I was in drug.
Scott: you person who's vaping at the garden Fuck you just.
Rym: yeah vaping no good But lucky.
Scott: I forgot that there was a text message number where you can report things happening in the stands.
Scott: And you're lucky.
Scott: I forgot that number at that moment because I only only announced at the beginning of the game.
Rym: Yeah, I mean when I'm staffing conventions, I shut down the kids vaping.
Rym: I don't care what they're vaping because it personally annoys me.
Rym: But yeah, this is actually a big deal because it unlike the u.s.
Rym: Where some states have done it and it's complicated Canada is only the second nation on earth to fully legalize it in an industrial capacity.
Rym: the way.
Scott: Well, I mean there's countries where like this basically lawlessness.
Scott: Yeah Practices is the other one just Denmark.
Rym: No.
Rym: No, it's Uruguay.
Scott: Oh, okay But what what's I mean, I thought Denmark isn't famous for like having like, you know, please you can go to smoke Yeah, but apparently the law is actually pretty complicated there.
Scott: No, it's not just full open this Yeah, it's much.
Rym: it's much more complex than even I realized and I don't know a lot about it.
Scott: That's always like.
Scott: that's the famous place that used to be the famous place for weed smoking, but I guess not now.
Scott: Yeah, now everyone's gonna go to Canada and Portugal.
Scott: Mark's Denmark's tourism is gonna get hurt by Canadian tourists.
Rym: It's Portugal desert thing where they basically decriminalized all drugs, but they didn't legalize it like go to a store Just buy as much different decriminalization and legalization.
Rym: Yep so this is probably really good news for Canada's economy and It's probably good news for me because I own a bunch of Canadian weed stock.
Scott: Well, the problem is is that people who smoke weed tend to lean to left and now they're all gonna move to Canada.
Scott: for reals Not like before where they just talked about moving to Canada another.
Rym: I'm gonna move to get well Some other news that that will maybe buttress that.
Rym: so New York State actually suddenly started moving Very quickly to legalize it and part of that was the no, that's just fake Cuomo.
Scott: Please reelect me and then yeah November We're not actually gonna do anything.
Rym: No, they're gonna do it this time.
Scott: No, they're not.
Rym: I think they are.
Rym: believe it there's a couple of things going on.
Rym: So this is all.
Rym: this is my opinion my read into this.
Rym: but what happened was the New York State Health Department Issued after their multi-year study their actual guidance on Whether or not it should be legalized and what the consequences would be.
Rym: and the health department was like, yeah There's no reason.
Rym: there's literally no reason not to legalize it.
Rym: not legalizing.
Rym: It harms people.
Rym: It's not a gateway drug.
Rym: It's way less bad for you than alcohol.
Rym: Like there's like go for it.
Scott: It's definitely way less bad for you than alcohol.
Scott: Yep, except as long the thing is alcohol only hurts other people if you drive whereas smoking weed makes everything stink.
Rym: Yeah, I don't think people should smoke weed for what?
Rym: but anyway, so the other part of this is that Cuomo who's always been very KG on cannabis legalization mostly because he acts like a progressive when selection year which it is Every other year he eggs like a Republican.
Rym: half the population of New York State lives upstate and apparently hates all that is good And right with the world and the other half of the population lives.
Rym: There are cities upstate are but generally the governor of New York State has to get has to get deal with both the shitty people upstate in the rural parts of the country and the people in New York City who arguably outnumber them.
Rym: and He basically ignores New York City and talks a lot about Upstate even if he doesn't do anything for the upstate because the upstate people get real mad and vote for Republicans.
Rym: if you don't constantly To their baby as needs meanwhile the city He'll remember we exist during primary season.
Scott: because if he doesn't try Here's the thing he needs the city votes for him to be elected because we have most of the people and governor is a popular vote.
Scott: Yeah But he needs the primary which only New York City people really needs all the state so that he can control who is in the legislature.
Scott: So you can actually control what laws there are.
Scott: cuz you're just the governor.
Scott: you don't write laws.
Rym: I really don't like Cuomo.
Rym: I'm voting against him in the primary like I do every primary.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much.
Rym: and Cynthia Nixon She checks off all the boxes of policy I want.
Rym: But the reality is I'm gonna vote for whatever Democrat wins the primary because that's how things are right now.
Rym: But here's the other reason why I think he's going for it.
Rym: It's not just primary season and it's not just that and it's not just Canada.
Rym: It's because New Jersey is Already moving faster to legalize it.
Rym: and if New Jersey legalizes it first New Jersey's gonna get a shit ton of tax dollars that New York won't get.
Scott: New Jersey's already got their sports gambling operation.
Rym: Yeah, New Jersey's moving real fast on this stuff and New York realizes.
Rym: That's a lot of money They're leaving on the table.
Rym: and that I think is the reason why this is suddenly moving.
Scott: hmm The people go to Canada - we touch and we're touching both Canada and New Jersey.
Scott: Stuck between.
Scott: people will be driving their weed from Canada to New Jersey Or vice versa.
Rym: I feel like if New Jersey legalizes it first path trains are gonna get shockingly full.
Scott: I Don't think.
Scott: I think one person will just bring it over from the patreon.
Scott: We don't need everyone get on the path.
Rym: Yeah, I feel like that is also gonna happen.
Scott: They'll just oh, why don't you buy some real estate on the other end of the path train next to the parking lot and make A weed shop there.
Rym: I mean we've seen that happen.
Rym: the United States.
Rym: There's precedent for this because if you don't live here some states in America allow you to have fireworks and some states do not exactly.
Rym: and if you Drive around the United States and you get near the border between a state that has fireworks in the state that doesn't you will notice a huge number of people selling fireworks Ten feet away from that border.
Scott: You're literally.
Scott: you'll see a sign that says now entering Tennessee last By and then there's an explosion.
Scott: There is a rest stop right there.
Scott: as soon as you enter, Tennessee You don't need to exit the highway.
Scott: They'll just be a little turn-off and there's a Fire with a giant fireworks store right there ten feet across the line.
Scott: And then when you turn around and you go back into the other state wherever the fuck you came from because Tennessee touches like six Tennessee is in fact the nearest state to us that has real fire touches a lot of states.
Scott: you drive back across the border to A state where the fireworks are not legal and police are waiting on the other side of the side now entering wherever.
Rym: Every single time my family went on a vacation like anywhere where we even went near, Tennessee We were diverted to Tennessee and fill the trunk with fireworks and bring it back into Michigan.
Rym: but anyway things of the day.
Rym: So I had a thing that I was gonna use but I found this story this morning.
Rym: I laughed out loud So hard at work as I read this story that it fit it fits the pure definition of thing of the day.
Rym: It's the best thing I've seen today.
Rym: I'm not gonna spoil.
Rym: what the deal is.
Rym: It's a Twitter story as one of those ones where it's basically screenshots of the text of the story.
Scott: Just people copy and paste the text.
Rym: come on the text is too big for a tweet.
Scott: You put the text in a paste bin and post a link anyway.
Rym: It's in this case and this is part of why I brought that up.
Rym: the fact that is three Separate sections is very important to the humor and wonder of this story because screenshot one begins the tale of a plumber at a hotel Who is using a industrial drain snake to try to deal with a clog that they cannot deal with.
Rym: like There's this preternaturally difficult clog.
Scott: It was it was the clog made of a living creature of some.
Rym: so phase two is They pull something out of the drain and don't know what the fuck to do about it.
Scott: Yeah It's some kind of horrible phase three.
Rym: the third image is one of the funniest goddamn things I've ever read.
Scott: Was it like a live raccoon or in the drain or something?
Scott: Didn't drown all?
Rym: I'm glad you've just got to read this story.
Rym: I am NOT gonna in any way spoil this for you.
Rym: It is real good, and I thoroughly enjoyed it.
Scott: some sort of sea creature It is.
Scott: that's why I didn't drown.
Rym: So let's just say that the second panel It it opened like what they pull something out of the drain.
Rym: I'll spell you for that.
Scott: they use the snake and a snake came out.
Scott: now Snakes the so I mean one in a real one what they found in the drain.
Rym: I will spoil that here.
Rym: the sleep in the mystery is not a living thing.
Rym: a human limb a shower curtain.
Scott: Okay, an entire shower curtain was something wrapped in the shower curtain like a human limb.
Rym: Just a shower curtain.
Rym: Okay, and the mystery that is opened is that this is a hotel right a motel.
Rym: The shower curtain is the shower curtain from the motel like the exact ones they use.
Scott: But the shower still had a curtain.
Rym: in the shower in the room that had the clog still had a shower curtain.
Rym: Yes That the there was the resolution of the mystery is some good shit.
Scott: if you're I imagine that how the the you know The housekeeping.
Scott: if they come into a room and there's no curtain they put up a new curtain.
Scott: They just have curtains.
Rym: So yeah Well, yeah, I read this story where I read the second one.
Rym: I'm debating like alright I'm trying to think of plausible scenarios, but I guarantee you will never in a million years guess how The shower curtain came to be in the drain because it is amazing.
Rym: Okay?
Rym: It's so specific and detailed that if this is an elaborate like if someone just made this story up, they're an excellent writer Mmm, but I actually believe this is true.
Rym: Hmm.
Rym: So anyway, that's my thing of the day.
Rym: What do you got?
Scott: so this is these people are at the zoo and They're next to the tiger zone where the Tigers hang.
Scott: That's a good place to hang out and you know the glass wall and then a moat and then some land and then some Tigers and You know, they're standing with their back to the to the Tigers chatting.
Scott: Some of them are facing towards the Tigers, right?
Scott: you know just chatting with each other little group and one of the Tigers starts to quietly sneak up on Their party member while their cameras are.
Scott: that is a quality.
Rym: I think the word here is stock.
Scott: Yes, and they're like.
Scott: they're basically like don't turn around don't turn around don't move don't move.
Scott: We want to see the tiger keep creeping up on you.
Scott: if you notice the tiger it'll stop creeping.
Scott: We want to see it to keep creeping.
Scott: don't move.
Scott: Don't turn around.
Scott: Just stay still and the friends stay still and the tiger creeps and obviously I guess thankfully is blocked by the glass wall.
Rym: But tiger does what Tigers do?
Scott: Yeah, you see the tiger do what he do.
Scott: this is the best part of the video is There's a part where the tiger gets close to the glass wall and you can cuz nor the Tigers in the moat, right?
Scott: So you just see the top of its body moving slowly But when it gets close to the glass wall, you can see its feet moving slowly, right?
Scott: Yeah that part Yeah, and you can see how the tiger how he creep and that's a good part.
Rym: Tigers got a plan.
Rym: Yeah, he's foiled by one thing.
Rym: So in the meta moment the GeekNights book club book which we're going to do very soon is Emily Wilson's translation of the Odyssey by Homer.
Scott: if I had realized we needed to show today.
Scott: I could have read it faster instead of watching anime.
Rym: pretty sure.
Rym: the next pub G the night.
Rym: Yeah, I was too The.
Rym: I owe you the graphic designer stuff too, but I was playing pub G. But anyway the We're probably gonna do it on the next Thursday show.
Rym: So not next Thursday But the following Thursday.
Rym: our next Thursday GeekNights show will probably be the GeekNights book club on this Translation of the Odyssey and it is give me a deadline.
Scott: Great.
Rym: I mean probably I said probably remember I am.
Rym: my day job now is I am.
Rym: I'm one of the people who has to make the official decisions for very important things.
Scott: Just make the first decision go the gut every time.
Scott: it won't take long.
Rym: Ah, but I have learned very very carefully the arts of Promising something.
Rym: but the actual words I say if parse logically do not actually promise shit That's your move.
Scott: Yeah, but now it's I mean your move.
Rym: I've gone from being merely a dilettante in that skill to being a professional.
Rym: I am by the definition of the word a professional now at that move.
Rym: I'm no longer an amateur I'm now.
Rym: I'm not a master of life I'm a professional of the act of promising something without actually promising anything.
Rym: So notice I use words like we will be likely projected.
Rym: we are project.
Rym: We're targeting the next Thursday show.
Rym: So, uh, yeah, uh Scott didn't want to talk about anything on this Thursday.
Scott: Well, I do.
Scott: I just don't have any show ideas whatsoever nor time to think of one nothing at all.
Scott: So let's indulge him and let him do whatever he wants and then I can go home.
Rym: I was thinking about this recently about how we've changed over the years because I was looking for yes people change.
Scott: is that happens?
Scott: Life is long.
Rym: Your whole life isn't the same but some things change and some things don't.
Rym: what doesn't change How I look?
Rym: apparently because I was looking for these old pictures.
Rym: Well, you haven't changed how you look Yeah, but old pictures of Scott look very different because your face looks younger your hair is different.
Rym: obviously I changed how I look but I look the fucking same when I was 19 as I do now Except my hair is.
Rym: I've got this tiny little bit of gray.
Rym: But I was thinking about like.
Rym: have we changed?
Rym: like?
Rym: are there opinions that have changed?
Rym: are there like big parts of our lives?
Rym: that have changed?
Rym: so draw to try a Strategy of pick various random areas of our lives GeekNights or non GeekNights and try to look back 10 years and 20 years and see if anything's actually changed like What we're rooming Scott doing in PC gaming compared to today in 2008 or 1998 in PC game PC gaming video
Scott: gaming the iPhone.
Scott: it was a year old 2008.
Scott: I was playing mostly we.
Rym: I thought PC gaming was dead.
Scott: Yeah, we weren't playing too many PC 2008.
Rym: That's around.
Rym: when I was you trying to use that shitty Mac to make a podcast.
Rym: Because and I was using I was using Linux on the desktop because there were no PC games I cared about.
Scott: look at GeekNights' episodes in 2008.
Rym: yeah, I was looking at GeekNights' episodes in 2005 to try to figure some of that out, but tooth a like 2008 Rym only played console games.
Rym: pretty sure is playing we in DS games and mobile games And I didn't play like.
Rym: PC gaming was dead to me.
Rym: if you look at 2018 Rym 100% PC 99% of PC 1% switch and if you go to 1998, it's all PC no console.
Rym: So I every 10 years I flip to the exact opposite spectrum of video games.
Rym: so by projection in 2028 I'm gonna be playing only console games.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Yeah, they're good.
Rym: Did you play different games and do the night in 2008 like what games?
Rym: Did you play when you're just like sitting around?
Scott: I'm trying to remember.
Rym: you really don't remember.
Scott: I just I'm remember that you mean you know blurs.
Scott: together with all the adjacent years I don't know.
Rym: 2008 seems pretty because 2008 was the era when We'd been doing GeekNights for a while already But we were still pretty close to our college years like we were living up in Beacon.
Rym: We hadn't really made plans to leave or like move to the city or anything.
Scott: episodes.
Rym: 2008 like 2008 was an era when we would do GeekNights watch movies and play games and not do much else.
Scott: See by the commander rearm doesn't 2008?
Scott: Most of the episodes we did on the show were about old games But there was you know Wii games in here a lot of board games in here Professor Layton yet DS games.
Rym: Yeah, I feel like that was the era of like the portable console.
Scott: Oh, we did that.
Scott: our dwarf fortress episode was in 2008.
Rym: Oh, yeah We tried to play dwarf fortress for a little while back then.
Scott: Yes, that was.
Scott: it's a PC game.
Scott: It's interesting though cuz back then I'm in a rear and I played that on PC.
Rym: Yeah, I guess that maybe that was the beginning of the resurgence of PC gaming.
Rym: Cuz I remember 2009 is when I said fuck it drop Linux on the desktop drop Mac and went back to a Windows PC.
Scott: I think I was mostly playing DS games in 2008.
Scott: Yeah, even bad ones Like cuz we did an episode of Final Fantasy Crystal Chronicles Ring of Fates, which is that game was awful the garbage DS one Right.
Rym: Yeah, that was that we didn't even fit.
Rym: We played like.
Scott: I played it for like 10 minutes, but Like 30 or 40 dollars for a brand new game.
Rym: I gave it away.
Rym: I remember giving it away cuz it was so bad.
Rym: Yeah, that was only DS years around then for sure which makes sense because PC gaming was still pretty bad.
Scott: Yeah, the DS was super new and geeked.
Scott: I started remember Yeah Like it was during beacon GeekNights when like you broke your DS fat as an excuse to get a DS light.
Rym: in fact, I remember now I was working at IBM on co-op and I bought the the original DS Fat the day it came out.
Rym: Yeah, because we thought it might be a virtual boy.
Scott: Well, I mean, it's not.
Scott: we thought it might be virtual boy.
Scott: It's worst case a virtual boy.
Scott: Otherwise, it's great.
Rym: Oh, here's something different.
Rym: So 2008 was probably the peak era of us going to a lot of conventions.
Rym: Nowadays, we've actually cut almost all the non pecs is out of our lives.
Scott: I mean, it's just you know, the anime con 2008 did we go to?
Rym: I think that was when we still went to Otakon.
Scott: Yeah, well we would.
Scott: last time I went to was oh nine.
Rym: yeah, so 2008 was when we still went to katsucon and Otakon.
Scott: and like anime next and Kinetic, I think we went to those cons back then.
Scott: first of all, a lot of our people came with us.
Scott: Yeah, even if the con did not provide a lot to do We still had people there and ended up doing a lot of stuff and having a good time.
Scott: Yeah But then what happened is our other people stopped going to the cons.
Scott: actually remember to say you would go to like we were still Going to like animate.
Scott: We stopped going to Otakon for other reasons.
Scott: Otherwise, we would have kept going.
Rym: Yep, but we know we wouldn't stop though.
Scott: We sure but we kept going to anime Boston and it's like.
Scott: but what happened?
Scott: it's because no one else was going really or very few people were going and What you know, we ended up like you walk around you go.
Scott: There's artists all you go.
Scott: Do you assume you do your panels and you go to maybe a couple panels and the rest of the time?
Scott: It's like we're just hanging around in the area eating and not much.
Scott: I think the big difference Wasn't really worth it for us to make travel and put all this effort to something where we're just most of the time We're spent.
Scott: we'd spend time literally like sitting around waiting for our panel to start.
Scott: We got nothing to do.
Rym: So I think 2008 was actually a pretty like by coincidence.
Rym: That doesn't
Scott: happen at PAX
Rym: Nope But 2008 by coincidence was
Scott: all our people still go to bags pretty
Rym: Pivotal year for our lives and for gig nights because that was the first year we went to apex and I'm looking at all
Scott: this Correct
Rym: and you noticed something very specific because 2008 it was in September.
Rym: We went to that packs.
Scott: We did three GeekNights episodes about packs in 2008.
Rym: Yep, but 2008 we did two episodes just about fucking Katsucon Because that was before we went to packs.
Rym: We did Katsucon.
Rym: I think that might have been the last Katsucon we went to.
Scott: I only went to not too many of them.
Rym: We're like three or four.
Rym: I went to three before you started going to the one where I got sick.
Rym: Yep, we went to it one before that and I would think we did one more and that was it.
Scott: I don't remember any other one.
Rym: Those are the three.
Rym: maybe one maybe one more but before we staffed and did like all our big panel Wasn't more than two is two or three because I went to three Katsucon's before you started going where I didn't even do panels.
Rym: I just showed up like oh shit anime con.
Rym: Let's go.
Rym: but 2008 we went to packs and that was the year the fire nation attacked like everything changed like we came back from cat packs Giddy and literally told everyone we knew yeah, fuck every other kind.
Rym: we go to you only packs is now and make this.
Rym: and That was the year where like the next year We brought more of our people to pax's and then it wasn't till 2010 that there was a people didn't really go with us To packs.
Scott: Oh nine.
Scott: It was still mostly just that.
Rym: well because while we have a lot of friends.
Rym: They're all East Coast We have the luxury of having the infinite money to go Not appear until 2010.
Rym: I believe in 2010 our Entire con crew that used to go to like Katsucon and Otakon with us.
Rym: they all went to that packs that PAX East and Then after they went to that PAX East they basically all dropped all the other conventions like that year Like pretty much everyone we know stopped going to anime cons after they went to one packs.
Rym: But then fast forward two years later They all stopped going to packs because PAX East is really hard to go.
Scott: they went to pack season 2011 2012.
Rym: people stopped going to pack because 2012 was the year you couldn't get hotels anymore.
Scott: and then people go to mag fest though for Now I think some of them do at least you know.
Scott: people on and off go to mag fest But I think everyone still wants to go to mag cuz.
Rym: our like GeekNights Set like we have a set of people that go to the packs is with us, but the broader front row crew Really only goes to mag fest now and no other cons.
Rym: I guess the only con.
Rym: we get our whole crew together.
Rym: That's a big change in our lives because Everyone we knew in our crew went to a lot of constant like.
Rym: going to cons was a big part of our lives.
Scott: now Most of our friends have dropped all conventions from their lives except mag fest and when we go They're not doing panels or staffing like we are this so as an attendee and you know the time that you know They don't have a ton of money.
Scott: They don't have infinite time.
Scott: They're all adults.
Scott: Yeah, so the number of you know, do they really want to spend a weekend at a convention?
Scott: unless that's you know.
Scott: Unless their staff some of them are staffers or people who run conventions and those people are going.
Scott: still true But if you know the ones who would just be attendees And aren't enforcers or anything.
Scott: It's like why would they?
Scott: I don't blame them.
Scott: They're doing what I would do if I was them But I didn't notice.
Rym: it was interesting is that The main reason they all stopped going to PAX East was just that it was too hard to get a hotel.
Rym: It was too much of a pain to go to it.
Rym: The money wasn't even a factor.
Rym: was the pain in the ass that it was?
Scott: I mean it's if you if any of if anyone is not going if anyone I know is not going to PAX East simply because you're having trouble getting the hotel and the The badge and you just don't want to deal with the hassle But you're perfectly willing to spend the money and do the travel and stuff like that.
Scott: Just let me know and I'll make it happen for you and I'll take the hassle away So you can come.
Rym: actually I want you to be there because actually we are working on a strategy to make our PAX East experience be more like our mags.
Scott: We have a bunch of people who go to PAX West every year and we manage to buy a bunch of badges and get through The queue and get room somehow and yeah it works.
Scott: so we can do the same thing for East to make sure you go if that's the thing you want to do.
Scott: if you if the Time and if the because I cannot do that only thing stopping you is the hassle and stuff and you don't care about the money Or the time then and you want to go then just let us know.
Rym: Yeah, cuz uh, but I worry that magfest will suffer the same fate if it starts to sell out in earnest.
Rym: I feel like magfest is gonna start to be a real pain in the ass to go to in the coming years.
Rym: Yeah, for normal people like if you have a hookup all counts are easy to go to is the problem?
Scott: Yeah, you need that hookup these days, but one time we were on a vacation we were in some, you know, rando tiny hotel like a holiday and whatever kind of place that you stop on the highway and Maybe it was New Hampshire.
Scott: I think we're in a hotel and you know, there's like that little.
Scott: there's those magazines They have only in hotel rooms that tell you about the local shit.
Rym: Yeah, there's that little.
Rym: there's like all those little.
Rym: There's also there's the little pamphlets by the entrance to the motel, right?
Scott: so there was a. there was one of those magazines.
Scott: in the hotel room is all kinds of advertisements for local stuff and one of them was for an RV lot where you could park your RV and it was like We got hookups.
Rym: and I was like.
Scott: And I was like, you know, I guess I sort of knew that what they meant by we got hookups for you Know your electricity in your toilet in your water and stuff, right?
Scott: But I was like, oh man, we got to go there You can get hooked up.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Oh, man.
Rym: I'm looking at these little geek guys episodes.
Rym: We're like really fucking pumped for katsu.
Rym: Can we like keep talking about it was hype then.
Rym: Yeah Well Katsucon actually back then.
Scott: now it's still exists.
Scott: It's still a cosplay city there.
Rym: It's basically a different con though.
Rym: Yeah, like it's called Katsucon, but it had a complete refresh of the staff.
Scott: It's in a different place with different staff with different stuff.
Rym: Like it's a different con because the old Katsucon Was more like magfest than like an anime con.
Scott: Well, it was much less gaming than mag.
Rym: I had a free-to-play arcade though It was pretty fucking legit.
Scott: Yeah, just small.
Scott: It was like 10% of magfest arcade.
Rym: Yeah, but it was a drunken 24/7 debaucherous con with a free-to-play arcade.
Rym: Yeah, that sounds like magfest to me.
Scott: It had those things.
Rym: Yeah, so how about 1998?
Rym: did you go to cons in 98?
Scott: I didn't even understand that a con existed in 1998.
Rym: So I didn't know that.
Scott: when I went in 2000 when the anime club started talking about cons I didn't really understand what they were talking about.
Rym: I didn't know what an anime con was till 2002 when we went to one.
Scott: I like oh, I know I understood before then but I didn't like.
Scott: I didn't fully grasp Like what are they talking about going to this thing?
Scott: And I felt like whatever they were talking about.
Scott: I'd understand it, but it was definitely not something that involved me.
Scott: It was something for someone else.
Scott: Yep, and I ignored it mostly and whatever It's like I didn't know a con was a thing.
Scott: The only thing I had been to ever at that point was a mad to the gathering tournament in a hotel, New Jersey.
Rym: I used to actually go to a lot of gaming like I was going to gaming cons in middle school.
Rym: So I was going to gaming cons and LAN parties in 98 Mm-hmm.
Rym: I went to LAN parties all over the place like I'd bring my computer and play quake 2 or something or quake 1 something in the earliest ones.
Rym: or like we'd wire up our null modems do like the doom thing in a hotel.
Rym: and I went to a lot of like Grognard asshole gaming cons where I'd sign up for a four-hour D&D session.
Rym: Like that was what I did in 98 and in the 90s.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: Yeah, so I was playing Pokemon in 1998.
Scott: I was not playing Red.
Scott: I had red one.
Rym: actually 98.
Rym: I was still playing magic.
Scott: a little bit is not playing magic.
Rym: in 98 I was playing magic.
Scott: I actually looked it up recently.
Scott: I was only playing magic for like two to three years in middle school.
Rym: So in 1998, I was playing magic with all the people I knew who played magic when I originally played magic Tuesday episode.
Rym: you somehow Politics, what were your 1998 politics?
Scott: I didn't give a shit really.
Scott: No, not at all.
Scott: I didn't even know that.
Scott: I mean, you know There are things that I believed generally which are a lot of the same things I believe now.
Scott: But I didn't even know which was left and which was right.
Scott: or the didn't see a Democrat or Republican.
Scott: 1998 I would just.
Scott: I basically was like y'all politicians are fucking bullshit.
Scott: They're all corrupt.
Rym: assholes was wrong with your school.
Rym: Like in 1998, I was taking like poli sci classes in high school.
Rym: Hmm, like serious ones I was I was actually getting.
Scott: I was reading a lot of like Marx and Marx's literature and being mad about it because I mean I knew what communism was but it's like and what capitalism was but like, you know Didn't care too much in 1998.
Rym: But that was what 10th grade.
Rym: I wouldn't say 10th or 11th grade.
Rym: I had a teacher.
Rym: I won't say his name.
Scott: Looking back now I see the difference between The literature teacher who had us read Vonnegut and the social studies teacher who had a picture of Strom Thurmond on the wall Right now and nowadays looking back.
Scott: I see the difference.
Scott: But in the day, I was just.
Scott: it was just like oh this teacher really likes that.
Scott: You know congressperson who's the longest person who's been in Congress a long time.
Scott: So when
Rym: I was a when I was it was either 1997 or 1998 when I was in 10th grade I had a teacher for social studies who took me and two other kids aside from the class one day like early in the air and He was like listen you three are the smart ones.
Rym: so I think you're ready for this.
Rym: and he gave us all a copy of the Communist Manifesto and a copy of the play Marx and Soho and said I want you to read these and Let's talk about him in a few weeks.
Rym: That was a real interesting experience In 1998. say I guess you just didn't you weren't?
Rym: you didn't think about politics in the 90s.
Scott: No, I was playing games.
Rym: I was kind of really invested in politics, but I didn't know a lot about like party Strategy at that time.
Scott: I believed you should eliminate political parties, which I still sort of believe that
Rym: I was very caught up in Libertarian ideas, but I got to put a big asterisk there because I
Scott: learned about that until college
Rym: because the way libertarianism was sold to me in the in the early to mid 90s was You shouldn't regulate things unless you have a good reason to and people should be free to do what they want Unless they hurt people.
Rym: and I was like, yeah, I'm all for that But that is not what the libertarian party is all about.
Rym: They're basically just Republicans.
Scott: Yes At least now they are.
Rym: so how about 2008 politics got By then?
Rym: you already had the opportunity to vote in multiple elections.
Rym: I mean, did you vote?
Scott: Yes, did you?
Scott: I voted.
Scott: I voted every time I've been allowed to vote.
Rym: Did you hold for Al Gore?
Scott: Yes.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I was in the year 2000.
Scott: That was not in the year 2008.
Rym: All right, so 2008 I guess you were active.
Rym: you cared about politics.
Rym: Was there any issue you particularly cared about in 2008?
Rym: copyright?
Rym: Yeah, that is something that has definitely changed for us in 98.
Rym: I was More mad about copyright than I was about fucking anything Yes and also I was really mad about Richard Solomon style stuff like 1998. Rym was so fucking mad about open source software and about freedom of the internet and free speech on the internet and Copyright on the internet and remixing and DRM and CBD PPA type stuff.
Rym: 2008 Rym Was still almost equally mad about all that stuff.
Rym: and now 2018 Rym just doesn't give a fuck because that is like.
Scott: I think we were also at that point.
Scott: I was also mad about.
Scott: I Started to care about some New York State level stuff because we were voting to give more money to the MTA on the referendum and we lost.
Scott: yeah Even though I voted yes, and if we had voted yes, then maybe we wouldn't be yelling about the subway being shitty.
Scott: now.
Rym: Yep, the problem is the people at the vote in that.
Scott: well we were upstate and voting on you know what that's that was.
Rym: That was an awakening I had because 2008 was when I was aging toward moving into the city.
Scott: Like I don't know if it was exactly 2008 that vote with that era.
Rym: It was around then plus or minus two years in the direction.
Rym: That was right before we moved to the city.
Scott: It was well, it must have been too early.
Scott: It was either earlier or it was 2008 at the latest
Rym: but I guess that was an error when I was using Metro North and That was when I had an awakening in state-level politics in the sense that I Recognized the problems that upstate New York was causing for New York City And I started to be real mad about it as I started to learn how New York State was structured Because up to that point I still knew more about Michigan politics than I did about New York politics.
Rym: Cuz I moped by the 2008 era I mostly cared about federal politics.
Rym: That was the era when I started to actually care about the details of state and county Legislation in the place I lived.
Scott: well, it's like they'd never really taught me in school or anything before.
Scott: I was like Oh, I have to vote for state legislators.
Scott: That's who this person is.
Scott: Oh, I get it.
Scott: There's another.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't fully grasp Until I had to vote for it 2018 and I didn't vote for it when I was you know When I technically was getting like absentee Connecticut ballots, I wasn't voting for that shit.
Scott: It wasn't until you know went to New York that I was voting for that.
Rym: but I guess the difference is I cared a lot about all these technology issues in like 2008 and Frankly in 2018 like while I still care about all those things There are way more important things to deal with right now Like I did not.
Rym: I cared a lot about open-source stuff because Nazis were not an imminent threat.
Rym: Another Nazis are an imminent threat.
Rym: That is the thing.
Rym: I mostly care about politically.
Scott: I mean, you know Maslow's hierarchy.
Rym: Yeah, Nazis are there.
Rym: so I have to go climb back down the pyramid and start fighting with them again.
Rym: How about like TV and movies and stuff cuz 98 like the night or late 90s?
Rym: I watch TV.
Rym: I Didn't watch TV after that.
Rym: 1998 is actually the end of the air 1998.
Scott: I was mostly watching DVDs from Netflix.
Scott: Yep, and I was downloading illegal.
Scott: I was party maze fan subs still because there wasn't really streaming.
Rym: You were not downloading fan subs in 1998.
Scott: Oh No, not 19 Oh 98.
Scott: Oh, I first oh I did watch TV 98.
Rym: I watched The Simpsons on TV in 1998.
Scott: that my TV watching consisted of Simpsons inside and felt which are on before slash after dinner.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: I watched those tsunamis still on.
Scott: I think.
Scott: yeah B test reruns.
Rym: You know, I was watching a lot of in 1998 fan subs.
Rym: I was but I was watching it New York Rangers hockey on MSD network.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I was watching a lot of Red Wings.
Rym: I watched on broadcast TV footballs.
Rym: Yeah, I was watching footballs.
Scott: I guess an anime and VHS.
Scott: That was not a fan.
Scott: I didn't know what a fan sub was 98 legitimate animes 98
Rym: In the fan sub here
Scott: on sci-fi channel like
Rym: just recently
Scott: Was on Cartoon Network at the time like, you know, Powerpuff Girls count chickens
Rym: But like I would turn on
Scott: the TV
Rym: and watch The Simpsons I could watch TV shows.
Rym: Yes, I did that but that was the end of that era because soon as I got to college never fucking watch TV again Except we watch the car very rarely.
Rym: We watch Lupin at midnight for a little while.
Scott: I think we watch like Simpsons two times.
Rym: Yeah, but then that was when The Simpsons got bad.
Scott: Yeah, and Nowadays, actually I thought he's having a 2008.
Scott: That's why I started talking.
Rym: So 2008.
Rym: Yeah, 2008.
Rym: I was talking about Netflix DVDs.
Scott: 2008.
Rym: I was only watching two things Netflix DVDs and anime fan subs.
Scott: I was also Occasionally streaming some sports, but it was very hard to watch sports in 2008.
Scott: Yeah, I pretty 98 guys like Formula One races in 98.
Rym: I really watched and cared about hockey a lot.
Rym: 2008.
Rym: I wasn't paying that much attention because it was hard to watch.
Rym: 2018.
Scott: I'm really watching Sports I was watching.
Scott: most actually were football because it was easy to get watch Formula one because people had a good way of bit torrenting it.
Scott: Yeah, and actually baseball because the Mets were less bad.
Scott: That's that's around the time where the Mets made the playoffs and I bought playoff tickets and then in the final game of the Season they missed the playoffs and then I had to get refund on the tickets.
Scott: I guess I went this interesting transformation where I forget if that was those seven or eight that happened.
Rym: I didn't really watch a lot of serial quote-unquote television in the in that middle era around 2008.
Rym: But now with Netflix, I'm actually watching a lot of shows again Like a lot of shows between Netflix and Hulu and crunchyroll and all these things I rotate through and
Scott: I think the main
Rym: reason I'm watching a lot of stuff Is that I don't have to go through the hassle of pirating it and I can watch it legally without ads.
Rym: Alright, I think we killed enough time.
Rym: Okay, good This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and brand Okay for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night
Rym: and the patreon favorite for this episode of GeekNights are Craig Oliver Allen Joyce Rebecca Don, honey I mean Nicholas and Ruby obelisk hanging in the sky cajar tavish in my state of the dot-com germany minor link Eiji Roberto Kingsley Kelly Snyder cold guy Amanda Duchette Shawn Yeager Matthew Smith Nicholas Brando mr.
Rym: Strong stretch in 4 to 1 creations.
Rym: No, I never ever wonder why we're here.
Rym: Semper Fi bitch.
Rym: You're from on horrible Rory James David white Rochelle, Monta superboy Tripwire sailor Vista dodge like Jojo Joestar Clinton Walton right from New Zealand.
Rym: Ryan Perrin drew open-lander Finn Chris midgift annual Redmond Shawn Klein Chris Reimer.
Rym: and time is on.
Rym: I read it in a slightly different style because I do say the names every single fucking time because I guess that's what you're paying for.
Rym: and Now I leave you with something.
Rym: I got some pizza and I bring it home.
Rym: I've got two tickets to paradise.
Rym: I've got two tickets to paradise You know doo-doo-doo-doo.
Rym: Oh My name is Luca I live on the second floor So call me the.
Scott: I Feel like making love making love to you Can't you?
Scott: song?
Scott: All right, you really wrote it.
Scott: Yeah as a tribute to Princess Di and Dodie because these days princess I Better accept the power everything in our house.