Rym: It's Wednesday June 27th 2018.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: Holy crap.
Rym: We're reviewing an anime made in abyss.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So I've been doing something.
Rym: I haven't done in a long time.
Rym: I've got out pooping.
Rym: I got out my trumpet My trumpet that I get annoying noises.
Scott: It's not something you don't haven't done in a long time.
Scott: There's something you do.
Rym: Trumpet playing is more Athleticism Than it is like actual.
Scott: you know, it's making annoying noises.
Rym: So I haven't played my trumpet seriously in like 15 years.
Rym: so I started playing it again.
Rym: cuz I do would take me about a month of playing every single day to get my Strength just like my physical ability back up to me like an approximation of what I used to be back.
Rym: And I was thinking about doing it professionally and I don't know what I'll do after that.
Rym: It seems like good exercise and I actually here's how old this was I had to buy new valve oil because that valve oil I had was so old and it denatured and basically turned into kerosene.
Rym: Okay, it smelled like kerosene.
Rym: I had to throw it away too bad.
Scott: It didn't melt your trumpet So you couldn't make annoying noise.
Rym: That's like a $3,000 trumpet.
Rym: It ain't melting anything.
Scott: Well sell it.
Rym: I Thought about selling it at RIT to pay for like food.
Rym: I'm glad I didn't.
Rym: I'm glad I held on to it.
Rym: Really love that trumpet.
Scott: I'm not glad You would have sold it.
Scott: So you got a. you could no longer make annoying noises.
Rym: I'm still playing it out with my 3c mouthpiece, but I do.
Rym: I did fine.
Rym: I had an old 5a mouthpiece.
Rym: I've been playing with that one that It's hard to play in the upper register with that 5a, but it makes a really good sound in the low stuff.
Rym: So we'll see.
Rym: maybe around Christmas time I'll just go to the subway on a weekend and play Christmas music and bus can see how that goes.
Rym: I Could be a dozen air if I work hard on that.
Scott: Good do it far away from me.
Rym: So anyway got any anime news.
Scott: There's not a lot of anime or comic news right now because San Diego comic-con is very soon.
Scott: Yep Everyone is charging their laser and holding back on any kind of news.
Scott: But the one kind of news they're not holding back on is hey everyone come check out shit That's we're gonna tease you about.
Scott: that's gonna be at San Diego comic-con that you can spend money on.
Scott: That morons will wait in line for yeah But one of these things is the first time I've ever is actually the first time I've seen something that was like an extending your comic-con exclusive that I Wanted an amount more than zero.
Scott: It's not much more than zero like.
Rym: I'm not gonna try again.
Scott: I'll be willing to spend like 50 cents to get one of these which I'm sure is much less than the actual price I want it but for the fact that I do not want physical things anymore.
Scott: I know right it's like but anyway So what basically the what's going on is, you know, it's a he-man action figure.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: well, I already owned he-man action figures in my life and I got rid of them.
Scott: Why would I want another one?
Rym: pretty sure my mom actually still has mine and it's like.
Scott: now that I'm an adult I realized I don't even like he-man.
Scott: I only liked it because I was a kid and it was stupid.
Scott: That's why kids because he's stupid man's crappy except it has a castle and a sword and a skeleton Which is why I liked it, which is the only part they still like and also orko, but other no one else likes orko.
Rym: Anyway, I don't like orko.
Scott: Oh and modulock was a good toy.
Scott: Anyway They're making a he-man action figure.
Scott: but it is not just any he-man action figure.
Scott: it is the hey Laughing he-man action figure complete with pink sword.
Scott: So that's whoever made that pretty smart.
Scott: I'm sure people are gonna line up at the front of the con and then like how it's just gonna run to the booth that They sell these and buy them all right away and then put them right on eBay for a lot of money.
Rym: I like how it's just called laughing Prince Adam.
Scott: Well, I mean what else you gonna call it?
Rym: Yeah, yeah.
Rym: Yeah, I mean if you start typing hey Into YouTube, it's like I know what you're looking for.
Rym: I know what you're trying to find.
Scott: Well, you type hey, but as soon as you add one more letter that it's like, okay We're good here.
Rym: So in some much less fun news and it's relevant if you're going to Otakon the big anime con well, we don't go anymore because Otakon is you know moved to DC a while ago and Otakon's on the decline.
Rym: the Nazis are trying to have a big rally at the same time, right?
Scott: They don't know about Otakon.
Scott: No, they're not rally.
Scott: They're just having a rally in DC and it happens to be near Otakon at the same weekend as Otakon by coincidence Yep, which is kind of bad.
Rym: I mean, it's I don't.
Rym: it's always bad news when the Nazis show up.
Scott: I mean there have been not Nazi incidents at Otakon when I was there.
Rym: Yeah, in fact I have video of a Nazi incident from Otakon I want to say 2005.
Scott: so I there must.
Scott: there are people who are attending Otakon who are clearly prone.
Rym: I don't have that video.
Rym: James and Pete have that video.
Scott: Mmm The point is there are pro Nazi kids at Otakon to begin with.
Scott: Yeah, they don't need any help from not see.
Rym: I'm in the Otakon forum and I already see some people defending the free speech rights of the Nazis.
Scott: Uh-huh People posted such things in my forum.
Scott: I would Withdraw their badges, especially since I'm handing them out at the door.
Scott: I can keep them out.
Rym: I guess we're still technically Otakon staff because they never formally informed us of being kicked out or anything.
Scott: Can you log into the Otakon staff?
Rym: It says my account is suspended.
Rym: Okay, so then I think you're suspended But they didn't follow all that procedure that I saw it.
Rym: There's two anyway, if you are going to Otakon or if you even were thinking about going to Otakon You should go to the National Mall and Memorial Parks website and register a formal complaint about the dangers of this rally and how you think it is unsafe for the rally to occur because maybe we can prevent this Nazi rally from Occurring.
Rym: so if you're an anime fan also I'm sure there'll be a lot more people at Otakon than there will be at the Nazi rally and we were at Pac South during Trump's original travel ban and Bunch of people left the con to go protest at the airport, right?
Scott: You can get probably more people just from Otakon alone To go and harass the Nazis and make their life miserable while wearing awesome cosplays.
Scott: Yeah, and that would be real good if you did that don't wear your a Hetalia cosplay though.
Rym: No At least not certain Hetalia cosplay.
Scott: If you are a Gundam cosplay make sure it's Earth cosplay Not a Zeon cosplay.
Rym: Yeah, Zeon's a little too soon to talk about Zeon right now.
Rym: So in some other worst news and I got to bring it up because it just happened and it's pretty big deal if you didn't notice a Supreme Court justice just resigned and if you're in the US That's a really really bad thing to have happened right now.
Rym: like to the point that Everyone listening to these words if you're above 18, you got a fucking vote If that even helps.
Rym: Yeah, you got to do it.
Rym: Anyway, and you got a vote straight ticket Democrat No exceptions, if you're uncomfortable about the fact that we're talking about politics right now I don't think you should even be listening to GeekNights and I don't respect you.
Rym: Okay, so Read this story and for the love of God votes, but anyway, it's time for Things of the day Moving right along here.
Scott: We already had things of the day.
Rym: This is the first time we both watched the same anime all the way through.
Scott: So now you're confident you have enough mean bit.
Scott: You don't have to drag out the news I'm so.
Rym: I think we could talk about the show for way longer than we're gonna okay.
Scott: So anyway, so I wasn't sure if I should use this thing of the day, but it's kind of funny video.
Scott: It's very New York video.
Scott: Well early gentlemen Went down on the subway tracks for who knows what reason he appears in this video to be Under the influence of some sort of something.
Rym: He's enjoying himself, right?
Scott: He's like.
Scott: he's like chillin and checking his phone.
Scott: They say he was laying on the tracks previously, which is disturbing But the video is not about the the disturbed man or the police who go and pick him up and take it.
Rym: He's fine.
Rym: The cops are sure they're like, come on.
Rym: Come on guy.
Scott: It's about the people the very New York people on the platform saying things like get your ass up here.
Scott: I need to get on the train.
Scott: Go kill go commit suicide somewhere else.
Scott: You're holding the train up.
Rym: It's uh You know, we taught in the early GeekNights days because we were fresh.
Scott: I just want to give you a feel of what New York is like.
Scott: Yeah Cuz honestly this is a very accurate New York video.
Rym: something on this level happens to me once a week like by default Like I got no exaggeration Something on this level I experience on a weekly basis at minimum sometimes multiple times per week.
Rym: In fact, if a week goes by and nothing weird happens, it's sort of weird.
Rym: It's a boring week Yeah But I remember way back in early GeekNights because we were fresh out of college and we were really missing University life and we talked a lot about how we missed the burning couches.
Scott: not literally because honestly you saw burning couch recently.
Rym: now No, I saw a burning couch last summer But not specifically burning couches because to be honest the burning couch was funny.
Rym: But it also stunk up the area outside of our apartment for like three days.
Rym: But we missed the fact that when we were in university Crazy shit kind of just happened all the time and it was just like this.
Rym: background to our lives Living in New York really brought that back.
Rym: So my thing of the day, uh, I don't think Scott knows what a hurdy-gurdy is.
Scott: I mean, I know it's like it's either Beatles thing or is that flint?
Scott: There's like a song but the hurdy-gurdy man or something.
Scott: So, I don't know what the day.
Scott: I never bothered to look it up.
Rym: What do you think a hurdy-gurdy man does?
Rym: Like the reefer man.
Scott: I imagine you know just based on the language that it's somehow somewhat akin to a hobo.
Rym: So now a hurdy-gurdy is actually a medieval instrument.
Scott: All righty I guess that is why it is musically related.
Rym: a way to describe it to a layman would be cross a violin with bagpipes.
Rym: But a better way to put it is how does that work?
Rym: So it drone, you know bagpipes have a drone like a constant tone Yes, and also music like also a melody possibly a melody and a harmony.
Rym: So this is basically a violin where you have a something instead of a bow that is Constantly making the strings vibrate.
Scott: Oh, it's not.
Scott: it's not a sack full of air It's just the strings are always vibrating and then so they're always making this noise.
Rym: Then you and you play it with basically a modified keyboard that is working kind of like how fingers would.
Scott: so it's sort of like an accordion.
Rym: almost so in that.
Scott: so an accordion with strings String pipe an accordions a string into accordion.
Rym: Anyway, if you don't know what a hurdy-gurdy is if you watch this video You will know what a hurdy-gurdy is and you may find out that actually you like hurdy-gurdy music, which I do And I like bagpipe music as long as the thing is it's weird.
Scott: I like bagpipe music as long as it's like recorded bagpipe music or on TV or something a live bagpipe That is very close to you makes me want to puncture the bagpipe.
Rym: Well, the point of a bagpipe is that you hear it from and remove the kilts from the person who is playing the bagpipe.
Rym: Generally bagpipe performances the bagpipers are quite far away from the audience not when they're in a parade in the street in the city.
Rym: Yeah, I like.
Rym: I like the parade bagpipes though only if it's.
Rym: you know The problem is is like my favorite thing is when there's a shitty marching band.
Rym: But the bagpipes that came by before them are so loud that they're still overpowering the shitty marching band.
Scott: They're too loud.
Scott: It just hurts my ears and I cannot hear the music.
Scott: the drone overpowers the the music.
Scott: When people record bagpipe music in the studio or whatever they you know The drab the drone part gets mixed way down or perhaps removed and you only hear the nice.
Rym: So in the meta moment the book club book home is Odyssey by Emily Wilson.
Scott: We keep talking about it sometime soon this summer Definitely a bit today because I took the train today instead of biking and it's gonna rain tomorrow.
Scott: So I'm gonna read more tomorrow.
Rym: I'm gonna try to blitz through it and finish it sometime in the next month or so.
Rym: This will probably be the episode.
Scott: just read it.
Rym: It ain't long and it's good.
Rym: Otherwise, look forward to us at PAX West.
Rym: I Think that's our next con.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah PAX West and all the other packs is and There's a good chance we'll be cuz it's you know, Wednesday.
Rym: I got anime.
Rym: This is a good chance.
Rym: We'll be at anime NYC.
Rym: I'm gonna put in some panels Even if we don't get any battles.
Scott: am I go over there for a day cuz gonna pay money to go there for a day?
Rym: I'm confident I can get myself a badge that is not costing me money somehow.
Rym: But I can take the subway to it and generally I'll go to a con that I can take a subway to.
Scott: yeah And it's not a time of this good weather.
Rym: Yeah, exactly.
Rym: Now if it happens to somehow be a glorious 80 degrees sunny day Hooray, then probably not going to that count.
Rym: It looks like a panel schedule.
Scott: It's got two days We can go to the world or three or two or three days.
Scott: three I'm sure at least one of the days will be not 80 degrees in what November?
Rym: Yeah, but it'll probably be.
Rym: if we go to any anime cons ever again It's probably the only one we're ever gonna go to and perform at.
Rym: so The good news is their panel slots are only 45 minutes long.
Rym: Way easier to write a 45 minute panel than a 60 minute panel, especially for anime.
Rym: we can do a lot of topics We normally wouldn't be able to fit into an hour and the new anime season is starting real soon.
Scott: So we're gonna be judging that season like this weekend.
Scott: Maybe I don't get the video out.
Scott: Hopefully next week.
Scott: We'll see.
Scott: It's work.
Rym: Yeah It is indeed work so made in abyss.
Rym: We actually watched it.
Rym: It's an anime and I think it's based on a new one.
Scott: Yeah, did we judge it?
Scott: I don't remember if we judged it or not.
Rym: I don't know if we judged it or not Because I tend to only watch like three or four of the anime we judge at any time.
Rym: we judge, right?
Scott: So here's the deal.
Scott: It's an anime and in this anime there is it's a fantasy world and in the fantasy world I think is earth.
Rym: No spoilers will save spoilers for the end.
Rym: So don't worry.
Scott: There's some island and on the island There's a big-ass fucking hole.
Scott: It's just.
Scott: it's just like a Completely isolated island.
Scott: It's just like, you know, and the whole island is a big hole and there's like a ridge around the hole with this town.
Scott: There's a ridge around the hole where everyone lives like.
Scott: it's some RPG or some shit and the hole is the abyss and it goes Down.
Scott: no one know.
Scott: it goes all the way down like way down.
Scott: I don't think it even has a bottom and there's like, you know, they have maps of it and at the bottom of the map.
Scott: It's just like wow.
Rym: Now the gist of the show is what's the deal with the abyss?
Scott: It's as terrible.
Scott: so you get a space.
Scott: Whoo, wait, where did the abyss come from?
Scott: Why is it the way it is?
Scott: Why is there a fantasy world down there and but not outside of it, but unlike say a darker than black Where there's a secret in space?
Rym: and then they do all this other nonsense and the secret in space.
Rym: just in the background.
Rym: This show is a beeline.
Rym: It's basically here's the characters.
Rym: There's the abyss.
Rym: They're going fucking as far down as possible as fast as possible and that is the plot.
Scott: Yeah, there's a character and her mom was like an abyss master.
Scott: They have like this.
Scott: It's a very RPG, right?
Scott: They have like.
Rym: it feels very secret of mana.
Scott: Yeah, it's like they have these colors of whistles for like how strong you are going in the abyss.
Scott: JRPG.
Rym: Oh, they're.
Rym: she's a white whistle The strongest right?
Scott: So her mom was a white whistle who went to the bottom of the abyss and she gets a note from mom saying come find Me at the bottom.
Scott: so she's like well Even though I'm just a little kid with a little red whistle who doesn't know what they're doing.
Scott: I'm going to that bottom and we're gonna as the viewer you're gonna learn all about the abyss because all you want to do Is know what's the deal?
Scott: What's the deal?
Scott: Because there's so many things to know what's the deal with?
Scott: You know, where did this person come from?
Scott: Where did these mother with the abyss come from so far?
Rym: How come this unlike say attack on Titan that just doesn't even get close to the secret in space and when it does It's stupid so far at least having watched one whole season of this and there'll be more season one.
Scott: There's a man.
Rym: Yeah, this manga does not actually end the story But it is a pretty good place.
Rym: like I feel pretty good about where it ended.
Rym: like I don't feel.
Rym: I don't feel like I did at the end of The first attack on Titan season.
Rym: No It feels like it's going somewhere and it feels like there's a real secret.
Rym: That'll probably be interesting.
Scott: It's like they don't answer necessary the questions that you're asking but they keep revealing more things and which then Give you more questions, right?
Scott: Yeah, it's like I think this, you know How much is spoilers or whatever?
Rym: We'll get to a spoiler line.
Scott: and well The main thing is there's this like a curse of the abyss where going down is easy.
Scott: Anyone can go down as long as you don't get killed by some horrible monster or something like that.
Scott: Yes, it's a really hazardous place that gets more hazardous the deeper you go.
Scott: But there's nothing inherent about the abyss.
Scott: Like if you just had a rope and came from the sky you would go all the way to the bottom.
Scott: just no problem.
Scott: But if you try to go up in the abyss horrible things happen to you immediately like if you go in a little bit and then like you let's see you take a few steps Down and come back up.
Rym: I'll get like a headache.
Scott: You'll be like dizzy just because right.
Scott: and if you go down maybe like they have levels of the abyss if you go down Like one level and come back up you'll be like vomiting and nauseous like crazy.
Rym: Yeah, go a little further like blood just starts spurting out of your eyes But only if you go up.
Scott: as long as you're going down or horror or staying at the same elevation You're not affected.
Scott: but if you try to go up out of if you're already in the abyss and you try to go upwards towards the out of the Abyss that's when you know this sort of curse just nails you.
Scott: there's even situations.
Scott: We're like they're in the abyss standing on like a tree or something and they want to get into this tree house That's above them and they're looking at it like The tree.
Scott: the people in the treehouse lower like an elevator basket thing and they get in the elevator And it's like the elevator is only going up a little bit.
Scott: But it's like oh my god, if I get in this elevator that goes up to the tree house I'm gonna be all sick aren't I?
Scott: it's like yes, they get out of the elevator like vomiting all over the place.
Rym: Let's talk a little bit about the world because the main characters like the people we follow in the show are little kids.
Scott: They're like 12.
Scott: Yeah, they're little kids right and they're drawn in a very cute way.
Scott: Well, one of them is not maybe a kid.
Scott: Well, one of them is a robot who we don't know how old it is Yeah, but it is.
Scott: it is a robot 12 year old child.
Scott: It could be like a hundred year old robot that looks like a 12 year old child but it has the mentality of a 12 year old child and the and the visual appearance kids and they're all red whistles.
Rym: and the storytelling we get.
Rym: there's some environmental storytelling and some characters explain things and there's little details that kind of fill in the picture, but Basically, there's an orphanage in this town and all the kids in the orphanage Basically are made to go down into the abyss Get artifacts and bring them back
Scott: up Very
Rym: RPG style and as they get better
Scott: see it doesn't seem to be an abusive orphanage.
Scott: It seems to be like an okay orphan like it's pretty legit like the kids die It's like it's like it's strict, you know, we're like the but it's not.
Scott: you know, it's not like an evil orphanage like Oliver.
Rym: You know one of those guys later in the show you see what the evil orphanage looks like.
Rym: Yes But like the kids go down and get these artifacts and here's why the shit like.
Scott: one of the reasons I like the show and It's like it's like there's a mystery of like whoa.
Scott: Why the fuck is this abyss full of artifacts?
Rym: Yeah, it's.
Rym: it's all precursor technology.
Rym: And as you know, that is one of my main things.
Scott: They also find like they constantly find skeletons in the abyss.
Scott: Skeletons are always praying.
Rym: there's three things in the abyss.
Rym: There's priceless artifacts from an ancient and unknown civilization that some of which are like powerful magic items.
Scott: And also for some reason the deeper you go the artifacts become more complex and more powerful and amazing.
Rym: So it's like you go down one level you find like a plus one sword go down three and you find a weird magic box That like blows up if you look at it and like weird stuff.
Scott: It's like how did this come to be?
Rym: There's monsters down there.
Rym: Yep, and there's prey and the monsters are more dangerous as you go deeper because it's JRPG Yep, and there's all your monsters guard the better treasure but buried everywhere in a circle around the abyss are skeletons in a praying position.
Rym: No one knows where they came from.
Scott: they don't tell you the viewer.
Rym: well so you get the impression right away because there are people who know stuff that you don't see as the viewer.
Scott: and the Characters you see in the show don't tell you the viewer.
Scott: Yeah You can see people in the show who clearly know more than they let on like the white whistle people.
Scott: But people still tell other characters like a lot of info like they're not they don't hold back Yeah, but it's like this one point where they go to this place.
Scott: That's like a museum of relics or whatever and they're there to see some specific things.
Scott: But it's like what all this stuff is in there that we're not seeing.
Scott: Yeah, it's like a huge building.
Scott: It's like what are the scientists who work there?
Scott: No, what are the archaeologists?
Scott: No, they must know something.
Rym: so the abyss is basically this pit and It's either maybe a spaceship crash.
Rym: Maybe it's some precursor technology Like.
Rym: we don't know the show no idea what it is.
Scott: It could be anything could be a portal another world.
Rym: It's implied that there were other abysses all over the earth and that this is the last one.
Scott: Oh, I didn't catch that at all.
Rym: Talk about how.
Rym: they mentioned this a couple times early on that.
Rym: This is like the only unexplored one Mmm that there were other holes that were like had similar things.
Rym: And there's also this sort of side sub story about like all these nations in the world warring This abyss.
Scott: they do allude to that.
Scott: I don't know what they don't explain it enough, but they're definitely Stories they tell about like the cave raiders or the people go down to get relics and how they play with other cave raiders On other countries, right?
Scott: It's like for some reason I guess this island where the abyss is must be some sort of neutral territory.
Scott: But the abyss itself is not or the nation that controls it now like won that war like yeah there was a war in the past where they destroy where they won and now that that country or Controls the abyss or maybe the whole world they control.
Scott: Yeah, but yeah, this is like these unnamed countries.
Scott: You don't know the deal is so.
Rym: the main character is this girl who lives in the orphanage and she's a red whistle and normally Kids.
Rym: just as they get better at learning these cave reading skills They progressed like blue whistle and right and like you see they show you people who have you know Higher whistles and they're clearly stronger, you know They've.
Scott: they've gone into the abyss enough that they've with their.
Scott: with their greater strength They can go deeper and come up without vomiting and they can.
Rym: they're also super strong like diving like they like.
Rym: they have Artifacts that help them.
Rym: They also just have gained skills.
Rym: It's like you dive too deep scuba diving and then you have to like do special things on your way back.
Scott: They're higher-level RPG characters and they can go into the abyss deeper and beat stronger monsters and do more awesome stuff.
Rym: so like the kids go way deep like in the early part of the show like deeper than they should and There's people who are down there who are totally okay.
Rym: We're just higher level than them and they interact with those people and interesting stuff happens.
Rym: But the general plot is that this there's one girl Here's our main character and her mom was a white whistle.
Rym: the white whistles are the only people who have no depth limit.
Rym: They're allowed to go as deep as they want and they're basically on their own discretion and no one can tell them for what.
Scott: they're also All like legendary people like they know like all the names of all the white whistles.
Scott: Yeah, there's not too many of them and they're all they're.
Scott: all Whistle is like a unique.
Scott: they have to wear physical whistles on their neck.
Scott: Yeah, they have like all these unique whistles where it's like all the red whistles are the same red whistle, right?
Scott: like the white whistles are all unique and like one guy's got these like two skull hands like two skeleton hands holding each other as his white whistle and you know, it's like whoa, what's up with that dude and This girl?
Rym: her mom was a white whistle and either disappeared or died down in the abyss.
Rym: Yes, and She Wants to go find her mom and find out what the deal is because a letter comes up from the abyss that says meet me Mm-hmm, and she's no other papers from mom as well.
Scott: And mom's white whistle and a robot kid and a robot kid.
Scott: Well, the robot kid doesn't come up with the mom stuff, but in the notes that mom sent back There's a picture of the robot kid, which is there must be some connection between mom and the robot kid.
Rym: And the robot kid doesn't remember anything.
Rym: Nope, but has terrifying powers.
Scott: and see the robot kid really actually only has two powers.
Rym: He has well bionic commando arms.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: No, he's bionic commando arms Great strength and immune to the curse of the abyss.
Scott: because he's a robo He's immune to the curse of the abyss.
Scott: Yeah, and also some crazy super powered cannon in his arm.
Rym: yep, and the cannon in his arm is very like Spear of longinus level technology, it's ridiculously powerful.
Scott: But if he uses it he shuts down and then has to recharge and then wakes up.
Rym: now one thing the show does and other shows Like mushishi or there's a lot of shows that have done this over the years where there's rules of how things work like magic systems or whatever has rules But doesn't have too many.
Scott: They're pretty much.
Rym: the rule is like if you go to too deep in the abyss coming back up sucks or like if he uses that In a certain amount of time he'll pass out for a certain number of hours, right?
Scott: Well, he recharges his bat and there's some rules, but they're like societal rules Like, you know, we don't we don't allow red whistles to go deeper than level one because they can't handle it But it's like nothing stopping you from doing that.
Rym: It's like if they go past level two.
Rym: Well, good luck.
Scott: Yeah, you can't come in after you know Because even if we come back after you if we try to pick you up and bring you back to the service You'll just die.
Scott: You'll die while we do that.
Scott: So Go.
Rym: so the girl Spoilers from the very beginning of the show and the robot just fucking go forward and jump down into the.
Scott: yes I mean this isn't spoiler cuz like that's the shows about.
Scott: it's like they just fucking.
Scott: once they know the mom is down there They just go and as the show progresses, I'm into it.
Rym: It's pretty cool.
Rym: Like the the rate of learning new things versus new mysteries arising is the exact opposite of attack on Titan.
Rym: Yeah
Scott: it's like you actually keep learning new stuff meeting new people people who tell you stuff
Rym: and just as it is
Scott: and They also show you as you're going deeper seeing more stuff You know as the characters go deeper and getting into trouble and out of trouble and whatnot.
Scott: They don't they don't.
Scott: it's like the top part of the world that you got used to in the first two episodes.
Scott: They still keep flashing up there showing you what those other guys.
Rym: the interesting thing the plot progresses on the surface Even though based on everything, you know, there is literally no way these characters could ever return Like this is a one-way trip.
Rym: and yet you keep seeing the.
Scott: maybe they could stay down there until they become so.
Scott: white whistle strong true because Many years in the future if they somehow survive in the abyss for the super long time like a decade or two Then they could come back up because one thing we don't know leveled up enough black.
Scott: Well, maybe if they found some powerful artifact that allowed them to come back up black whistles and blue whistles or maybe they could defeat the curse of the abyss and beat the final boss and then Everyone could come back up.
Rym: of course defeat destroy removing the curse might be a bad idea I don't know.
Scott: I don't know enough because yeah, even watching the whole for a season I don't know enough about the abyss to know if that's even a thing that you can do.
Rym: but Black whistles and blue whistles like they go pretty deep like way deep and come back up and once you watch the show a little Bit and you see like what level two is like and they're like, yeah These blue whistles are down to like level four just fucking around like, okay, that's interesting.
Rym: I guess that's what a like 17th level Bard can do.
Rym: but the white whistles are Very much not quite human anymore.
Scott: No, they're all really weird Like.
Rym: I don't want I won't spoil anything about this character.
Rym: But the first white whistle you meet is Oh Zen the immovable and holy shit that character Very very powerful individual.
Scott: that is a fascinating character with some like insane strength.
Rym: Like you meet a I think a blue whistle or a black whistle that the dwarf looking guy.
Scott: Oh my god, he's basically like the uncle.
Scott: I love that guy.
Scott: He looks like, you know typical RPG like fat dude with a with a blue doe beard the guy who's like way dangerous, but everyone underestimates him, right?
Rym: He needs the kids like pretty deep early on in their adventure.
Rym: He's like, whoa, what are you doing down here?
Rym: And they're like we're fucking going for it.
Scott: He's like, all right, cool Well, he's friendly and good guy, but it's like he's not white whistle.
Scott: He's like one under that But he's like right but he's but he's way super strong and super fast and he can you know, he's like, whoa He's and he's like do you need help?
Scott: He's the one who brings back the mom stuff to begin with.
Rym: Yeah, and they're like no No, we're going for it.
Rym: And he's like, okay just heads up Oh Zen the immovable watch out Watch out The.
Rym: Occasionally the show edges a little too much into a character explaining something But it usually then immediately Escalate.
Scott: well, I mean explaining something is better than not explaining Especially when it's a show that's a hundred percent focused on this one secret of space with no other stuff going on Like.
Scott: it doesn't get into like the explaining is so much like there's like a lot of character dramas or other things to spend their Time on.
Scott: it's like the whole show just spends all its time.
Rym: The light novel translated into an anime problem where it's just characters fucking explaining everything and nothing happened.
Scott: It's a manga.
Scott: So, I don't know if it's a light novel or not.
Scott: I'm pretty sure.
Scott: I'm pretty sure it was originally a manga.
Scott: I don't know how far the manga goes.
Rym: I want to find way beyond where the show was so far.
Scott: You know that for sure.
Scott: Yeah, so I should read the manga.
Rym: the manga is still going right?
Scott: But the manga is out in English at least a few volumes.
Rym: Yeah 2012 it started.
Scott: It's still going but but it goes beyond what the anime does.
Rym: Yes, so I should read it and to know more right now or wait, because I Feel like you'll spoil a lot of stuff for the anime.
Scott: I don't know if I would.
Scott: I can read the manga instead.
Scott: and just because the anime.
Rym: the one problem with this show is That based on having watched the show and based on having read a little bit of the manga pretty sure Akihito Tsukushi the guy who wrote the manga is a pervert.
Scott: Mmm.
Scott: That is true of many money.
Scott: The
Rym: anime tones it down and now that the show and let we've been saying there's a lot now in our own lives Some anime have something I like to call the anime tax meaning if a person who is not steeped in the world of like the Shit that happens in anime.
Rym: because of the way anime is Watches certain shows they can't deal with it and have to pay the tax like kill la kill.
Rym: if you show it to your mom She'll be.
Rym: you'll be trying to explain the complex metaphor of clothing and presentation And everyone's naked with boobies on and your mom's gonna be like why isn't that girl wearing pants?
Rym: Yeah, so Every now and then this show Will something will happen and they'll be naked twelve-year-olds and you'll be like, okay That was weird, but then we just moved on and it.
Rym: it could be innocent, but you don't know.
Rym: but having looked at the manga Yeah, we know The a. yeah, so it seems like in this world Carrot like adults will just to punish children String them up by ropes naked and upside down for like a day.
Rym: is it like?
Rym: that's the equivalent of spanking in this world And that is brought up more than once.
Scott: There's also multiple scenes where she's like going swimming just gets naked.
Scott: She doesn't care.
Scott: Yeah Basically the main character a twelve-year-old girl is naked Frequently more often than is prudent or comfortable.
Rym: the robot boy.
Scott: who is her?
Scott: companion and friend?
Scott: They take these on multiple occasions.
Scott: They specifically call out how he has a human penis that works well because she keeps checking it out.
Scott: there's even a scene in which he is aroused while they're in like swimming or something and A twelve-year-old robot boy and it's over hold.
Rym: good due to the nature of the abyss there are a lot of because this show gets really really dark and Violent and difficult to watch.
Rym: so these irrespective of that, right?
Scott: So you have these character designs like Monica style right that are super super cutesy.
Scott: They're not like SD, but they're like one step above SD and then but like breaking an arm is hyper realistic, right?
Scott: They're like they have broken.
Scott: Ah, they break an arm.
Scott: they're like vomiting and and all kinds of horrible horrible things are happening characters, but dangerous and urinating themselves due to pain happens Kind of often frequently.
Rym: Yes now to.
Rym: Despite having said all that the anime does a good job of minimizing the occasional weird things And it doesn't intrude into the show enough to say to where I would say you shouldn't watch it.
Rym: the show is still really good.
Rym: that stuff is definitely sidelined and Could be interpreted as innocent and just part of this world and part of the show.
Rym: But be warned that if you are uncomfortable watching very cute characters who are Presented as like 12 year old kids being hard being horribly mangled by a monster.
Rym: Yeah Experiencing the reality of traumatic injury.
Rym: This show is not for you.
Rym: No But I've thoroughly enjoyed the show and I'm going to watch the sequel.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, it's it's.
Scott: I'm not gonna say it's like the best show ever But it's a very good very good show and I want to mostly just you know.
Scott: It managed to provide a secret to space.
Scott: that was good.
Scott: It made me want to know it.
Scott: It made me want to know it's not like I don't care.
Scott: Yeah, I really want to know.
Scott: and it managed to not do a attack on Titan where the answer is bullshit at least not yet.
Scott: and It managed to also give information at like a pretty good clip without spilling all the beans.
Scott: It like continued to spill meaningful beans, not bullshit beans Like alright, they just keep giving you.
Rym: you learn more and more about the abyss and it you know, you're moving right along Yeah, and I guess if you liked shows like Madoka Magica or Shinsekai Yori from a new from the new world like there's interest overlap there with those kinds of shows.
Rym: I Don't know if we should but I think we should maybe do a separate like final thoughts episode, but Maybe wait until you see more season.
Rym: Yeah, but I will say there's only 13.
Scott: Maybe we should wait at least 26.
Rym: I didn't want to avoid spoilers.
Rym: But if you read the prince of nothing This abyss feels a lot like Golgotha wrong like a lot and Like those eggs like those weird egg looking things that nobody knows what they do.
Rym: Yeah, like like you find they find these egg looking things in the upper levels.
Rym: They're like weird technology like there and there's tons of them.
Scott: Yeah, and they go deeper and they find more but when the ones that are deeper are more complicated But they're not worth anything because no one knows what to do with them.
Rym: Yeah, like some of the artifacts like at least they do something useful.
Scott: But some yes, some of them they figured out what they do.
Rym: But like the girl has to learn to like not pick all this stuff up on her way.
Rym: The inventory management is a big part of this show.
Rym: It's very JRPG.
Scott: Look, they might not only going up is difficult enough.
Scott: They're gonna carry a bunch of heavy shit.
Scott: Yeah, like you went down there to collect artifacts and now you're going like in pub G and carrying things.
Rym: Do you really need another scope?
Rym: You only have one rifle just like leave it there.
Rym: It's fine.
Scott: Well, what if the next day comes and gets it now they got a scoop?
Rym: Yeah, well then pick it up and like throw it in the water or something.
Scott: I wish there was easier ways to do that.
Rym: Yeah, I leave stuff out and try to leave traps.
Scott: It doesn't work No, but anyway, if you could make traps in pub G that would be great.
Rym: that's for tonight almost has stuff like that.
Rym: like you can build structures and like fortifications.
Rym: anyway.
Rym: Yeah, I don't really want to spoil anything about this show.
Scott: But yeah, if you need it, if you like a fantasy anime that's you know, got some JRPG elements.
Scott: This is the best new anime I've watched in a while like a terrible secret of space.
Scott: Then this is 13 episodes for you in a u.s If you want to watch it legally I could only find it on Amazon Prime's.
Scott: if you Amazon Prime Yeah, you can watch it for zero dollars because you've already paid for it.
Scott: And if you don't have Amazon Prime Find some other way to watch it.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Oh, and I guess cuz I kept asking this question You see a lot of art and a lot of memes a lot of Twitter chatter about this show But they pretty much only show the rabbit girl.
Rym: The rabbit girl doesn't actually show up until like the end of the season.
Rym: Yeah, but the rabbit girl is that.
Rym: this is that show.
Rym: if you've seen people like sharing images of this rabbit girl all over Anna Twitter this is the show that is from.
Rym: this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the patreon patrons for this particular episode of GeekNights because you're paying for me to say this every goddamn time Craig Oliver Allen Joyce Rebecca Dunne, how do you nickel the shimmering Ruby obelisk hanging in the sky?
Rym: my stage I come Jeremy mine only kid you Kelly Snyder.
Rym: your chart obviously Matthew Smith Chris Reimer Joe Joe Joe star read from New Zealand mr Strong stretch and Finn cold guy Daniel Redmond Nicholas Brando's shirvin on Harold dodge like Rochelle, Monta, Nona Drew openlander Christmas gift Rory tripwire Clinton Walton sailor Vista Ryan parent Amanda to shed Thomas Han Sean Klein James David White and Sean Yeager.
Rym: That was the most.
Rym: those names have changed ever and I can't believe I didn't mess that up.
Rym: Anyway, uh, here's some hurdy-gurdy music.