Rym: It's Monday September 17th 2018.
Rym: I'm Rym, I'm Scott and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We're talking about that weird EU copyright law and upload filters and all that kind of nonsense.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: Yeah, it's been a while.
Rym: So weird to not do shows for that long except over the holidays Mm-hmm.
Rym: I guess we were.
Rym: we had packs and then we tend to get lazy after packs and just not do like shows.
Scott: I got other stuff to do.
Scott: I got a clean laundry.
Scott: put away my all of my things on pack.
Scott: Yeah, today the show was under threat of not even how to happening again because I was stuck in a ball pit.
Rym: Yeah, but luckily while you were stuck in a ball pit, I was stuck dealing with something at work.
Rym: So we both got home late.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So I worked out and last week actually it just turned out so many.
Rym: You know that I have a new job.
Rym: It's actually been.
Scott: it's not that new.
Rym: It's been exactly one year since I started that new job and I know this because when I started the job I left my previous job earlier than I had planned Because they wanted me to come to this giant global summit of like the whole group that I'd work with.
Rym: So I went to this giant summit not knowing anything of how it was going on a year ago.
Rym: So this year the same summit happened again, but now I know what I'm doing and I'm in charge a lot of this business.
Rym: So I had to actually go to the summit and it as a result It meant that I didn't really have time to do shows last week.
Rym: So we had an extra week of not doing shows which sucks because there's a ton of gaming news.
Rym: There's a ton of like anime we've watched to review.
Rym: We actually have a pretty deep hopper for everything except Monday.
Rym: So we had to come over the show to do tonight because I didn't want to just bail on yet another show and stay tuned cuz we'll be reviewing like walk on girl.
Rym: the night is short and Middle manager Tony gawa.
Rym: There's a ton of games.
Rym: We've been playing but it's Monday.
Rym: So you got any other opening bits anything new.
Scott: I was in a ball pit.
Rym: how big was this ball pit about?
Scott: you know like bigger than a rich person's swimming pool, but smaller than the public pool.
Scott: I Can see that so big pretty is pretty deep.
Scott: you could go below.
Scott: you can go deep so deep in the balls No one would see you and then step on you.
Rym: That sounds like a recipe to get stepped on.
Scott: Yeah, there was stepping on.
Rym: so how do they?
Rym: cuz?
Rym: I assumed this was a ball pit for adults as a ball pit for all.
Scott: Okay, mostly filled with adults.
Rym: How do they sanitize those balls?
Rym: I'm just curious cuz I would have I would.
Scott: actually I thought of that myself And I said as soon as I get where I'm going I'm gonna wash my hands.
Scott: Yeah, and then I forgot to wash my hands.
Scott: Oh Plagues are coming, but I brought that up when we were in the ball pit.
Rym: I'm like Yeah, I feel like once you're in the ball pit that quite like it's already too late.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, cuz you're gonna touch your face.
Rym: They're gonna touch your face.
Rym: There's no way out of that.
Rym: I was completely submerged in balls But I tell the shares out about that.
Rym: they might have an opinion.
Rym: So there's a lot of tech news.
Rym: We actually have a lot more to say about the news than we might have on the main bed But there's plenty of news.
Rym: the main bit is one news By gonna miss a lot of the news you might think we were gonna talk about because if we don't talk about something that we Could.
Rym: happens we forget it happened.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: It's how we were all here on GeekNights.
Rym: But I guess we can start with the Apple news because there was actually kind of a lot of it.
Scott: Well, I mean Apple Day, you know people don't realize right people like who is Apple gonna announce?
Scott: listen Apple is at the same announcement schedule for since maybe even before it was an RIT, right?
Scott: Yeah every September they announce back-to-school shit and that used to be iPods and then it became iPhones.
Rym: How they used to be iPods.
Scott: every single September they announce iPods slash iPhones Every single one.
Scott: they have done that since the time in the first iPod and maybe even since before.
Scott: then I don't even know how to go.
Scott: look it up, right?
Scott: You know in September they can announce iPhones.
Scott: so they did and they also.
Scott: I watches in September right then it's CES.
Scott: That's where you get like your Mac, you know stuff.
Scott: that's for consumers.
Scott: Like usually they spend way too long talking about I work The spreadsheet keynote thing right and then at the WWDC they always talk about the updates to the OS is in the software and how the App Store sells a million apps and you'll make a bunch of money if you make an app and Here's new MacBook pros because your developers right?
Scott: It's the same fucking schedule every year.
Scott: So it's September.
Scott: Yeah, we got new iPhones.
Scott: So I don't know people listening probably know this.
Scott: I bought iPhone 3g the day it came out two years after that.
Rym: I got an iPhone for you On the good upgrade cycle.
Scott: I got an iPhone.
Scott: Well, cuz iPhone one was garbage.
Scott: Yeah Right two years after that.
Scott: I got iPhone 5 to use that to that.
Scott: I got iPhone 6 to use.
Scott: after that I got an iPhone 7 and that iPhone 7.
Scott: I said, you know what they got this upgrade plan thing.
Scott: now Let me get on that Right.
Scott: and the way it works is basically you buy the phone with a loan you pay off the loan monthly and then after a year When a new phone comes out in September, you can return the old phone because it is infinite Apple care.
Scott: So even if you damaged it, they'll repair it for free because the infinite Apple care.
Scott: Yeah And then you turn it in for what it's worth and that pays off your old loan Allow freeing you up to now get another loan to get a new phone.
Scott: So last year it was iPhone 8 and iPhone X and I you know and I was like, oh well I could turn in my iPhone 7 Get my loan paid off get a new loan get one of these new phones.
Scott: and then I looked and I said wait a minute.
Scott: These new phones are more expensive than that old one.
Scott: Yeah when X is a thousand fucking dollars So are they more expensively better?
Scott: Well, the iPhone 8 is basically Almost identical to the iPhone 7. there's almost no difference between the iPhone 8 and iPhone 7. the difference is like so trivial.
Scott: They might as well be the same fucking phone.
Scott: Right the iPhone X is way better except if you depending on how much the notch bothers you.
Scott: But other than the notch is just way better.
Rym: So the knowledge actually kind of bothers me a lot.
Scott: but I mean, you know if you think about it, okay So what if they just blacked out the areas to the side of the notch?
Rym: That'd be fine.
Scott: But you're basically you're getting more screen More screen.
Scott: the only thing that goes next to the notch is like the time and date and your signal.
Scott: that is true Who doesn't you know, so it's like you're getting more screen just by adding the notch.
Scott: It's like why not is my phone?
Rym: the screen just goes near the top of the phone.
Rym: So there's not like.
Scott: well, the notch is used for all the face sign in which I would not enable But anyway, but you could use.
Scott: I would still might use it for some me emojis.
Rym: Anyway, I saw some terrifying emojis.
Scott: Better because it has mostly the main feature is the OLED screen which is a vastly superior screen to all screens and all other phones.
Scott: But it's a thousand fucking dollars.
Scott: So I was like, well if I do the cash in though, then It's gonna be a bigger monthly loan payment And it's not that much and I'm not getting $1,000 phone.
Scott: so fuck that Yep, so I didn't.
Scott: and then last month I paid off the loan in the iPhone 7s and now it's just mine.
Scott: I just paid it and it wasn't any more.
Rym: You know I gotta say back when I bought that Sunfire that like Cripo car that I drove around forever until it died and then it Got towed.
Rym: and now it's gone.
Rym: But I While I had it and I was paying my car payment I always thought I really want a better car.
Rym: But the moment my car was paid for and it was just mine Suddenly, I didn't want another car because this was just that's right car.
Scott: That's why car dealers of the lease?
Rym: Yeah because every Leasing car every day that I continued to drive that shitty old car that I didn't own a car payment on was just Free money like free time before the next car payment.
Scott: Yep So now it's like.
Scott: well now my I'm basically increased my salary by like 50 bucks a month.
Scott: Yeah, and I got the same phone and they got new phones.
Scott: So I was like, oh well I was expecting I was gonna get one of these new phones.
Scott: so they came out with the iPhone XS the iPhone The XS XS Plus and the XR and the XR.
Rym: so I don't know what the deal is with the XR.
Rym: I actually didn't read about it.
Scott: Oh, so the XS and XS Plus are basically the thousand dollar plus iPhone X Upgraded to be even better.
Scott: Yeah, it's super expensive super big.
Scott: It's like buying the iPhone X only upgraded right?
Scott: All right iPhone XR.
Scott: It looks like an iPhone X. It has a lot of features of the iPhone X but some of those features are fake.
Scott: For example, the camera and the iPhone XS is like a super awesome double lens Riddick, you know thing right that's like a has a really wide aperture at least for a phone camera.
Scott: the iPhone XR Pretends to have a wide aperture using some software to imitate Right, so it seemed you get some of those same features, right?
Scott: But the iPhone XR also.
Scott: it looks like it has the giant screen that the iPhone XS has but actually That's an LCD screen.
Scott: Not an OLED screen.
Scott: Oh But it's still in terms of ratio that theoretically also potentially mean lower battery life.
Rym: I don't know cuz the backlight would have to be.
Scott: they have enormous batteries these.
Scott: Oh, yeah way better than your stupid Android phones.
Rym: Anyway, my Android phone lasts like two days.
Rym: if I don't use it heavily iPhone last a long time.
Rym: Your iPhone doesn't last two days.
Rym: All right, don't charge your iPhone at work and don't charge it tonight and see how long it gets into tomorrow.
Rym: Anyway, my Android phone is a lot of the.
Scott: the point is is that none of these all these phones are way more.
Scott: You know the iPhone XR.
Scott: it was like the one I would get But I don't want to else.
Scott: the LCD screen is not much.
Scott: I have an LCD screen I'll.
Scott: the only major upgrade is an OLED screen which cost too much.
Scott: So why would I get the iPhone XR?
Scott: and they're even still selling the iPhone 7 and 8 Right, which are way cheaper.
Scott: Like if you can get a new iPhone 7 now for like 500 something, right?
Scott: Which is totally reasonable.
Rym: Oh, you get a brand new Xperia and like the good phone for 200 220 iPhone 7 I think is much better.
Scott: The point is even the iPhone XR which does give you a is bigger than the iPhone 7 But it gives you a lot more screen per phone size.
Scott: So it's like your phone.
Scott: your phone grows a little bit, but your screen grows a lot.
Rym: I guess that.
Rym: what worries me though is still that the pressed in it sets because even the super tiny Android phones I'm getting they're creeping up a little bit like to get one millimeter water.
Scott: The thing is it none of.
Scott: for once I waited two years and every two years that I waited there was a significant improvement.
Scott: iPhone 3g was just a significant proven over every phone that came before it.
Scott: Yeah, the iPhone 4 I think added like was it was either the retina screen or LTE or some or the iPhone 5.
Scott: It was one iPhone.
Scott: I think I added LTE.
Scott: Maybe the iPhone 5 added the retina screen I forget but like those iPhone 4 5 6 7 all of them added Somewhat significant features.
Scott: All right, the 7 was added the button that you don't have to actually push and the fingerprint reader.
Scott: It's like, you know, the features decreased in significance.
Scott: It used to be Oh LTE now.
Scott: Well, that's huge But now it's like they've decreased in significance so much.
Scott: I didn't fucking need New iPhone I just keep my iPhone 7.
Rym: Yeah I mean I only upgrade phones when my phone is worn out or can't do something.
Scott: the old phone couldn't do that LTE+ like multiband whatever I used to upgrade because there was a significant better phone But now there isn't and they're all bigger.
Scott: It's anyway.
Scott: and also this one cost me nothing now and it's way good.
Scott: Yeah, and they updated my iOS today.
Scott: It totally worked.
Scott: So they also announced a new Apple watch and that's actually so big deal.
Rym: Watch is way better, but they got FDA approval on something because it might be a medical device.
Scott: Yeah, it is a medical device.
Scott: It can supposedly perform an ECG Which is kind of crazy.
Rym: Yeah, and what's interesting is cut.
Rym: I I suspect.
Rym: I mean, I am NOT a doctor nor am I an expert on this technology, but Similar to the heart rate monitors where they're not super accurate Like like both watches and like Fitbits and everything like the heart rate monitors are not actually that accurate.
Scott: But once you can strap to your chest that are better.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But even then the point is that they're still getting data Consistently over time and that data could be used to infer things about one's health and I think this is actually a pretty good Well thing.
Scott: the previous Apple watch also does this.
Scott: the one I have also does this.
Scott: it just doesn't do it as well And it doesn't do the ECG.
Rym: Yeah, it just does regular heart rate monitor Or EKG as more commonly referred to in the u.s.
Scott: It's a lecture.
Scott: It's not electrocardiogram with a K.
Rym: Yeah Well, it's like the difference.
Rym: you can tell where someone came from in their life if they say MRI or if they say NMR.
Scott: Someone who says NMR.
Rym: I know people who say NMR because it's an MRI.
Scott: It's MRI magnetic resonance.
Rym: No, it's nuclear magnetic resonance imaging.
Scott: Where's the nuclear part?
Rym: Uh, Do you know how MRIs work?
Rym: magnets not just magnets?
Scott: Anyway The point is the new Apple watch is way better.
Scott: The only thing is It's the one negative is that is bigger which exactly?
Scott: for most people that biggerness is going to be an improvement.
Scott: No, I've already got the smallest goddamn Android watch there me though a bigger watch is not an improvement because my wrist is like a toothpick.
Scott: Yep So I'm gonna stick with this Apple watch 3 with LTE until it no longer functions.
Rym: Yep, I got the LG style which is pretty much the best like size price feature ratio.
Scott: You can get also having this Apple watch, right?
Scott: The only improvements I can say that it has over the pebble watch that I previously had is that it's a lot more reliable In terms of its functionality.
Rym: Yep but the The reliability was only a function of the bit rot of the software.
Scott: The hardware was rock solid yeah, and also the Apple watch is better because in the pebble because The heart rate stuff.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Well the pebble that never came out was gonna have a heart rate monitor.
Scott: Yeah, but other than that, it's like that's.
Scott: you know, I don't what other feature gonna pass me None of this Apple.
Scott: Yeah, you know, it makes it.
Rym: so I don't have to look at the phone Yep, but you know what I want, you know what feature I want.
Rym: I want to go back to a pebble style screen so I can have a battery in the last a week.
Rym: There's battery last pretty long time not a week No, not not so long that I didn't ever bring a charger with me when I traveled.
Scott: No, but also if it's heart rate monitoring it might need more battery, too.
Rym: Yeah true because actually I do the.
Rym: my one regret about my current watch is that it does not have heart rate monitoring.
Rym: That's part of why it's so small and cheap.
Rym: So in some other news You know We talked about daylight saving without an s-time and now we have very strong opinions about it and most we believe Rightly in case you're not aware.
Rym: Oh, yeah, we're correct.
Rym: Anyone else if anyone thinks otherwise is dead wrong on this.
Scott: the way the clocks are in the summer after they spring ahead is It is all correct.
Scott: that is the time and it should universally be that time now my Everywhere on earth.
Rym: My rationale is very simple any daylight hours while I am at work are wasted.
Rym: Yes, so I want there to be as much light as possible between when I leave work and when I go to sleep.
Scott: I have a new better idea We should rearrange the entire schedule of our entire society So that we get to work.
Scott: if we're gonna assume we're gonna still work eight hours, which I would argue with Yeah, but assuming we still have to work that's gonna be a separate Thursday show in the future Assuming we still work eight hours and we're not gonna argue about that now.
Scott: everyone should go to work at 10 p.m.
Scott: And leave at 6 a.m.
Scott: And have as much fucking daylight as you want and then sleep When the Sun Goes Down and then wake up shortly before 10 p.m.
Scott: To go to work.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, I mean cuz my only work in this useless dark time.
Rym: I mean the trouble is human bodies Really need the lighting and the timing of life to work out or shit goes wrong like shit goes south.
Rym: You got to sleep when it's dark.
Scott: Yeah, you sleep when it's dark until 10 p.m Then you wake up.
Rym: Yep, but Depending on where you live latitudes like what if you live in a place where it doesn't get dark during the summer?
Scott: What do you feel in a place where it's always dark?
Rym: Yeah, I think the real answer is it sucks to live in those places But I mean don't live in places with his natural disasters or weird shit.
Scott: I don't know why people consist on living in these places, you know I guess some of them their parents lived there because they were stupid.
Rym: So name a place that does not have significant disaster risk.
Scott: I mean New York is mostly safe.
Rym: New York got hit by Sandy and I could have really fucked up our Jimmy's way worse than It did.
Scott: Yeah, but it's not like living in Dominican right where you're gonna get destroyed.
Rym: Yeah Well, like the minute you want the safest place to live is probably the Midwestern United States and like Ontario right there Cuz the only thing he's got to worry about in those places are tornadoes.
Rym: Tornadoes are very easily avoided in places like.
Scott: there are many plays on earth that are relatively safe from earthquake or weather incidents.
Scott: but
Rym: anyway, the news here is that the Usually in the end in the US internet the complaint is daylight saving time sucks And then people don't understand how it actually works, but they all kind of agree that they don't want it to happen Even though most of the arguments they make for abolishing it I think are stupid arguments.
Scott: Yes, the only argument is that's the way the clock should be.
Scott: get deal with it.
Scott: Yeah I want to be out in the sunlight.
Rym: So the EU is going to stop changing the clocks next year.
Rym: good The EU is quote doing away with twice yearly clock changes and what their way they're gonna handle?
Rym: it is very simple.
Rym: Every member state will get to itself decide however, it wants which of those times They're gonna move to and stay at forever.
Scott: Rym is gonna be in high demand as every computer needs to make sure it's NTP.
Rym: No, NTP has nothing to do with this because NTP sets your GMT clock.
Rym: unless you really fucked up or using windows Everyone's still gonna fuck up something.
Rym: Oh, yeah, they are because It's.
Rym: the only difference is when I worked at a broker a long time ago We would fuck up daylight saving time in some way four times a year because the u.s.
Rym: Would move.
Rym: Then Europe would move.
Rym: then the u.s.
Rym: Would move back.
Rym: then Europe would move back.
Scott: Wouldn't it take like one year to fix it?
Scott: And then the second year you'd fix the thing the weird bit you didn't know To be fucked up in surprising and novel ways.
Scott: perhaps forever Time zones get ready to fuck up again.
Rym: You know what I feel like.
Rym: I feel like there's this nice curve of people who have not done a lot of coding think time zones are Difficult and then people who have done a little bit of coding think time zones are easy and then people who have been around the block Long enough realize that time zones are difficult again.
Scott: But what's that website that always has like the time news?
Rym: Oh, yeah There's a couple of sites like that.
Scott: there's also.
Scott: there's one that's like obviously like the super boring like Open source.
Rym: Well, there's also NTP dot org.
Scott: No, no, what's the time news?
Rym: anyway, I know I Care about this in such an abstract way that if in my work someone messed up time zones that is so far beyond what I care about that I'll let people who used to do the kind of jobs that I used to Do that do the jobs that I used to do deal with it.
Rym: We'll see how this goes down.
Rym: But I suspect that people like me in a distant future meaning 2019 time and date calm.
Rym: I've been to that side.
Scott: That's the one.
Scott: Oh you push to scrap DST clock.
Rym: Yep So here's what I think.
Scott: he changes dates for daylight savings time.
Scott: Japan considers daylight saving time for Olympics.
Scott: Yeah, North Korea adapt South Korean time zone.
Rym: So the funniest one I ever ran into was when a certain South American country Florida says yes to year-round daylight saving time.
Scott: Yeah, there's there's movement.
Scott: We might find that was this battle.
Scott: That was in March of this year.
Rym: Yeah, we might finally win this battle.
Scott: So time and date calm is a real good website.
Rym: What'll be very interesting is to see which you EU member states Vote to go to the correct time versus the stupid baby time.
Scott: Well, I think you're gonna see a difference in voting based on latitude.
Rym: I think latitude I will give an allowance for latitude.
Rym: if you live in a place that votes for stupid baby I'm gonna be like shit.
Rym: So in some other news you might have seen this going on.
Rym: Scott pointed out and we've been talking about this in the forum This is not new.
Rym: It's more that a lot more people have realized it's happening.
Scott: I think it's Americans have realized it's happening.
Rym: Yeah, but the broader problem the story here specifically is that people are spoofing music plays in Spotify to drive the charts which is extra problematic because The rate and which people play music is also used to determine how much money to give to artists, right?
Scott: So there's basically two layers of things going on here, right?
Scott: So it's mostly coming from Korea, but also other countries.
Scott: But Korea is like the heart of this right the kpop scene because you have these massive organized fandoms, right?
Scott: So what happens is First you have the Korean people as a society At least from what I've seen on their television that I've paid more attention to than probably anyone listening to the show.
Scott: They are obsessed with charts and rankings like obsessed like they have that you go to like their home.
Scott: There's a website neighbor, which is like the Google of Korea and if you go there It's not just a home page with a search box.
Scott: It's like all these stuff and they there's real-time search rankings and people care about those a lot.
Scott: They talk about them on TV.
Scott: Like oh my god.
Scott: Did you see I was trending on the real-time search rankings?
Scott: Right and they had like a party because of that and shit, right?
Scott: So people are obsessed with the rankings there They have and this constantly news articles like oh such and such reputation ranking every month.
Scott: They're like ranking reputations of celebrities and how much brand value they have and all those ridiculous nonsense.
Scott: And there's like websites.
Scott: they're like real-time music charts.
Scott: even music fans in the u.s Don't pay that much attention to Billboard music charts.
Scott: I feel like a little bit if you read way into it.
Scott: But it's like you think metal fans paying attention like the metal music chart Band is on the chart, right?
Scott: But Koreans kpop fans they obsess about the chart.
Scott: it updates Hourly, right sometimes even more than that and it's like it matters a lot where you are in the chart.
Scott: They give up prizes on music shows four or five six times a week to people who are ranking high on charts.
Scott: So they care a lot about charts.
Rym: So if you can manipulate the data that's driving the charts you manipulate the charts.
Scott: So fit on the level one you have the big fandoms these organized groups of teenagers who care about this more than anything Doing whatever they can to bump up their favorite people on the charts spending money spending time Organizing right.
Scott: and on the other layer you have actual record companies trying to Fake and get people their own artists up on the charts going to stores buying tons and tons of albums Right pulling dirty tricks like saying aha if you want to come to the handshake meeting you have to you know Buy X number of albums.
Scott: so fans go and buy a hundred albums and then they can go to that, right?
Scott: And to get just to get themselves up on these?
Rym: there's a wide variety of adverse incentives in this.
Scott: Record companies want to fake get up on the charts.
Scott: the other record companies get whoever Legitimately popular get mad when someone else fakes themselves onto the charts.
Scott: well, the fans want to get their artists fakely up onto the charts and all alright and What this ends up happening?
Scott: it means is that someone who doesn't deserve it is getting more royalties and they're supposed to and it also Translates into other things like oh that group looks like a big deal now.
Scott: They are a big deal, but are they really as big a deal as you think?
Scott: BTS like the biggest thing in kpop right now Trends on Twitter and gets more likes and more retweets than literally anything else more than the president.
Scott: No matter what crazy thing happens in the world news BTS gets more tweets more retweets.
Scott: Their hashtag is bigger.
Scott: Are they really that fucking big?
Scott: They're real big but that big the biggest thing on earth the biggest thing on all of Twitter?
Scott: I don't think so.
Scott: Yeah right the fans are just so Organized and so passionate that they go crazy and make a ton of accounts and push real real hard in a way that no one Else is doing for anything else and this results in like.
Scott: oh they get to appear on TV TV stars and start calling them.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: well if they knew how big they really were and it wasn't fake Hype would the TV stations really be calling them to appear on TV in the US?
Scott: Now take the same But also also how many people became fans because the fake hype to reach them Right, which is what the original fans are trying to do, but here's the real problem.
Rym: So this this problem in and of itself is a problem, but take that incentive model and apply it to Modern streaming platforms that distribute revenue to artists based on these metrics.
Rym: Yep, and now you've got a system that is ripe for direct abuse.
Scott: It's basically, you know, you might have popular music and someone else might have popular music But if they're popular music has an active organized and engaged fan base that will pump you up artificially or we'll get more money per listener and Else will malware.
Rym: that logs into people's Spotify accounts and just plays things on loop.
Scott: There's lots of ways to find a way to make API calls to Spotify that say you played a song even though you didn't fucking Play anything.
Scott: Yeah, you just tell Spotify you want to play this song.
Scott: They start sending you bits.
Scott: you ignore them.
Scott: You know you don't have to play them out of speaker and even if they piece of software that does this.
Rym: even if this was 100% locked down and like you couldn't game the system directly You could still just install legit Spotify accounts like legit clients and just have farms playing music to dev null.
Scott: there are supposedly places where they have like basically rooms and rooms and rooms of phones all lined up and they can Orchestrate all the phones to do the same thing and they have them all just like play the same song or visit the same site.
Scott: Or do you know anything that you need done in mass?
Scott: They just got a room with thousands of phones in it and they'll do it for you.
Rym: I guess it's interesting because you think that we know in the old era you'd have like Nielsen or like some organization doing surveys to figure out this is popular or that's popular.
Rym: but monetization was separate because people would just sell albums, but now Monetization isn't so simple.
Rym: It's not just sell albums.
Rym: That doesn't really work anywhere anymore Not in the long run definitely not in the US.
Rym: and then simultaneously - how do you track what is actually popular?
Rym: How do you track what people are listening to?
Rym: even the direct clicks and the direct listens aren't actually a reliable metric.
Rym: I Think this is good.
Rym: This is gonna be kind of like the advertising industry on the internet and that there aren't good solutions.
Rym: And I think this entire industry is still ripe for a giant collapse.
Scott: I think we should just make whenever there's an industry that's baking basing You know financial distributions on fake numbers.
Rym: Should we game those numbers, right?
Scott: We should just make something and game the numbers to give ourselves a lot of money.
Rym: Why is the GeekNights podcast the number one pop album on Spotify, right?
Scott: Why isn't it?
Scott: and the thing is it becomes a self-fulfilling thing because they have Automatic algorithms that see that we're getting a lot of listens and then they boost us up and like positions on Playlists and then we get listens and it sort of falls in on itself.
Rym: I mean, that's how the early rounds of like big YouTube celebrities can twitch celebrities came to be.
Rym: You'd have a slight uptick in following and I'm in a slight uptick in engagements Which meant a slight uptick in more people seeing you which was a self-fulfilling prophecy.
Scott: there was one kpop artist who got onto the top of the chart and everyone was mad and they were like What the hell is this?
Scott: and the song was garbage.
Scott: and then the person was like they wouldn't have a fan meeting Because like no one showed up.
Scott: Yeah, but then there's someone else new who's like suddenly it's like a no-name person no one ever heard of was like on the top of the chart now and Everyone's like what the hell is this?
Scott: and I don't know if they faked themselves to get there in the first place.
Scott: But they're still there and people were like, oh this song is actually good It's just because it was not a famous person.
Scott: Everyone was way hella suspicious.
Rym: Well, it comes down to a quote here.
Rym: That's pretty pretty sums it up.
Rym: But if a superfan decides to listen non-stop to a track Is that fake?
Scott: is it?
Rym: if so how many times do they have to listen to a track continuously before it is deemed fake?
Scott: Spotify brings in X dollars in revenue and then divides it among all the musicians and songwriters based on how many you know listens Right.
Scott: Should you really be getting more of that pie?
Scott: if you have a superfan then, you know, if I have a superfan and That metal band over there just as a regular fan who listens to their song once a day And I have a superfan who listens to my song on repeat day and night Do I really deserve more of the Spotify pie than that metal band does?
Rym: it's the same problem in?
Rym: Counter-strike cheating.
Rym: as if you're not cheating by using like an actual bot like cheating with the software.
Scott: Both legitimately listening.
Scott: forget the cheating part.
Rym: But I'm saying what's the difference between a human using a mouse and a keyboard is really good versus a computer Controlling a mouse and a keyboard with a webcam pointed at the screen.
Rym: There's no way to differentiate those.
Scott: So the fonder lying metric is itself suspects, but I'm saying, you know, I'm not even talking about that.
Scott: I'm talking about Why do you deserve more of the Spotify pie for having a superfan versus having a regular fan?
Scott: Or do why is it?
Scott: Why should it be based on listens?
Scott: Why shouldn't it be based on number of fans or number of fans?
Rym: I've got 10,000 accounts that all like me.
Scott: I'm not talking about how you've determined it.
Scott: I'm saying let's say let's pretend everything's legitimate, right?
Scott: There's no cheating technologically, right?
Scott: How much?
Scott: why do you deserve more?
Scott: because you had a person listen to your song twice?
Scott: Two people is near its -.
Scott: should you get more money if two people listen to your song once?
Scott: then if one person listens twice That's the crux of it.
Rym: If this were just what is popular.
Rym: It's a very different much lower stakes gambit But the fact that it is the primary driver for the metrics used for revenue distribution.
Rym: The real problem is that we still don't have a sustainable monetization model for music.
Scott: We should I mean, can we even come up with a fair way to distribute the revenue?
Scott: if no one's cheating, right?
Rym: I think the fairway is some sort of system where perhaps a communist government allows people to have the luxury of creating music with their needs taken care of And we don't worry about monetizing it and how music is free.
Rym: Yeah, I think that would work better than what we're doing now.
Scott: anyone who is you register as a musician you get X dollars.
Scott: Yeah, the end and I said and well and then if you be if you're popular You should be able to make money off endorsements and concerts monetize beyond the government minimum Mm-hmm, and if Everyone in America signs up for the government minimum It's probably not that much.
Rym: and if you're willing to live off that sure
Scott: And everyone in the whole country signs up to be a musician just to get their piece of their even piece of that
Rym: Ah, maybe you're maybe you're not allowed to have a non music source of income if you sign up for this Like you can't.
Rym: you can't just work for a company and also say I'm a musician give me my 20 grand.
Rym: Anyway anyway in some other minor tech news that's actually worth mentioning.
Rym: briefly Linus Torvalds anyone who's unaware has a reputation.
Scott: No, he doesn't a reputation being a giant dick.
Scott: No, here's our reputation being a giant dick.
Scott: He is a giant.
Rym: Yeah, but he has a reputation for being a giant dick And that reputation is entirely grounded in reality.
Rym: In fact, right that is demonstrable.
Scott: He is the person who created the Linux kernel.
Scott: is objectively is that BS OD?
Scott: Yep, right.
Scott: He's like he is that asshole.
Scott: Basically if you read his emails Basically, the thing he's known for is he's usually most of the time I'd say at least 80% Maybe even 90% of the time on the correct side of arguments.
Scott: Yeah in terms of technology, right?
Scott: I remember watching the.
Scott: I'll never forget the one where he's talking about git.
Scott: He's like if you don't use git you are stupid Right.
Scott: He's like argue Technologically correct git is way better and all the things he was saying was right and He's bashing all the other version control systems, but he was basically calling the whole audience morons stupid idiots Whatever.
Scott: It's like it's like Don't do that.
Scott: So the new one who's stupid asshole just because you're technologically, right?
Rym: This came to a head recently.
Rym: I'm not gonna get into all the details after 20 plus years The night late 90s.
Rym: But basically he did something that as far as I can tell he's never done is one.
Rym: he issued a public apology for something specific.
Rym: that was shitty that he did.
Rym: and then he issued a Planket apology for 20 to 30 years of assholiness.
Rym: Yep But he's got a long way to go to make up for that true but what I will say that was very interesting is that this was One of the rare instances of an apology that was actually an apology his news.
Scott: because in 20 to 30 years It's like.
Scott: it's weird because on the one hand one apology doesn't make up for that much assholishness But on the other hand, it's been 30 years.
Scott: He's never apologized for fucking anything.
Scott: Yeah, it's weird It's like what it was really.
Rym: it wasn't one of those like.
Scott: I'm sorry I didn't even know if he knew the word.
Rym: what sorry was a word.
Rym: This was not one of those.
Rym: I sorry you.
Rym: I'm sorry you feel that way apologies.
Rym: This is basically I fucked up.
Rym: I've been shitty for a long time.
Scott: You've been shitty for a real long time.
Rym: He even went further I know.
Rym: he basically said that he knows apologizing doesn't fix any of it Of course not and it's basically the first step in him getting his shit together And he's gonna take some time off and get some help, right?
Scott: We'll see if he gets some help, but it's he needs a lot of help He does.
Scott: how you gonna teach the oldest dog new tricks.
Rym: I Mean maybe getting helpful also involve finally passing the torch.
Scott: I don't know fashion.
Rym: We'll see how this goes But it's it's notable because how this plays out will actually have long-standing ramifications for a lot of technology We all use.
Rym: yeah Linus is very important.
Scott: like this level of one person is going to affect all your Android Yep, in a way.
Rym: There are very few people for whom an apology like this would be notable enough for us to talk about it.
Scott: Can you think of any other incident where someone who's been like a lifelong asshole?
Rym: There's that learned a new leaders that one KK a guy the guy who was like, yeah, this is all bullshit.
Scott: I'll always be a KKK a long time Mmm, we used his.
Rym: we used him as a thing of the day like a decade ago.
Rym: Maybe remember that guy.
Scott: I mean this has been a few guys like that.
Rym: Yeah, but they're.
Rym: they're gonna have too many.
Rym: not many but more than one But anyway things of the day.
Scott: so shit was my thing.
Rym: I I got your thing today up here.
Rym: You don't remember what it was.
Scott: Oh, I do remember.
Rym: it was that it was the incident with the Mustang.
Scott: I do remember.
Rym: So I thought this video is pretty recent and this is something where I'm curious Scott Do you know the origin of the word?
Scott: Okay, I feel like I've watched something about it at one point and then don't remember.
Rym: Yeah, so I thought I knew like.
Scott: I thought they feel like I've been told by a linguist and then do not remember what they Said.
Rym: yeah So I thought I knew the answer and it was some military thing and I thought it stood for like some German phrase.
Scott: and now I mean, I think I actually I think was an article that was talking about how why is it was like?
Scott: why is okay?
Scott: So universal around the earth.
Rym: No, it was something like that because Vox has a video that goes into pretty like really deep depth on it.
Rym: Not only was the thing I thought I knew way wrong But the actual answer is so much better than I expected.
Scott: You know that they're right and they're not making stuff up.
Rym: I'm confident.
Rym: They're right.
Rym: This is well research.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Rym: So you're welcome.
Rym: You're welcome to debate with these people.
Rym: Maybe they're wrong.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: So here's the deal.
Scott: How do I know?
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Now it also the second half of this video gets into why it's such a universally used phrase.
Rym: Yes Well, that's that's what I think I write about because that parts really important and that part basically it sounds the fact that is a neutral affirmative meaning it implies that you receive the information without Judging the information in any way or expressing any opinion on the information.
Rym: So you say something and I say, okay It means I heard you but it does not imply that I give a shit or that I have an opinion and that's why it's So valuable.
Rym: we didn't have a good way to do that.
Rym: I guess affirmative Could be used in that way.
Rym: But anyway, you can watch this video.
Rym: But the gist of it is that meme Lords in the 1830s had a fad in Boston and the fad was that they would make up Acronyms for common phrases and then fuck the acronyms up so that they're wrong and then use the wrong Acronyms to be funny.
Rym: So they'd be like there are.
Rym: there's a ton of examples Like people clever hipster dudes in like 1810 in Boston would be like KC and KC stands for enough said spelled really really badly Mm-hmm.
Rym: So okay is all Correct all spelled OLL and correct spelled with a K because that's super wrong.
Rym: and Hipsters in the 1820s thought this was really funny.
Rym: and then there's this whole story of how that ended up becoming This widespread used word that's around the world in many and even non English languages today.
Rym: All right, so it came out of meme Lord hipsters in Boston in the early 1800s.
Scott: Okay So Here's a guy riding a bicycle getting run over by a Mustang and you're probably already over.
Scott: you're smart You're a GeekNights listener.
Scott: You probably know it's gonna be a horse and not a car But that doesn't matter.
Scott: I already could.
Scott: I already caught that joke before watching the video as well as soon as it's not the headline.
Scott: I knew it was gonna be a horse.
Scott: doesn't matter.
Scott: It's funny.
Scott: Anyway, it is.
Rym: it's pretty funny in the tape.
Rym: Watch the whole thing the exact amount of time it takes between you.
Rym: start the video and your brain thinks I'll bet this is and then the horse appears.
Rym: Well, the horse is it doesn't matter.
Scott: and this is I want to show again.
Scott: This is proof to all those people argue with me spoilers don't ruin things.
Rym: They do change the experience They do.
Rym: are you disagreeing?
Scott: I disagree.
Scott: you disagree.
Scott: This is funny.
Scott: whether or not you know It's a. if you don't and also if you don't know it's a horse Line you are.
Scott: you need some some skills, okay In the moment we didn't do shows for like two weeks.
Rym: But if you saw us at PAX and now you're ordered why the hell we're talking about like Linux and stuff?
Rym: guess what GeekNights is four nights a week.
Scott: and That doesn't mean we do four shows a week.
Rym: We used to when we were young and incredibly stupid and nothing better to do.
Rym: now We have better things to do so we do two nights a week.
Rym: So This week is a Monday Wednesday week.
Rym: So we're doing a Monday show on technology and on Wednesday We're gonna do a Wednesday show on anime and we're gonna review walk on girl.
Rym: The night is short because that movie is.
Scott: we can now think we should see some time a galaxy first.
Rym: Oh, I only watch two episodes But I think I can review the movie at least in a vacuum and I got a lot to say about it having seen two Episodes time a galaxy.
Scott: I don't know if you can.
Rym: well, it'll be good to have these your opinion?
Scott: They're just watching the timing.
Rym: And then we actually have a backlog of multiple anime to review because we've also watched Mr.
Rym: Tonegawa's middle management, whatever.
Rym: And I've watched all of the new DuckTales Which you should watch because it's uh, I don't want to say my life to watch things here DuckTales, uh Remember how when we first got into ponies and we kind of really got into it DuckTales is like that.
Rym: It's it's filled that void for me.
Scott: No, it's good.
Scott: It's Time do I have in my life?
Rym: It's better than you expect.
Scott: and also I don't have time.
Scott: like Scott I have seen him spends all the time sitting around watching TV.
Rym: I have seen Every episode of Adventure Time.
Rym: I know Literally everything that anyone who has watched this show could know.
Rym: I know as many answers as you could possibly read all the Adventure Time comics.
Rym: I have not but they are ostensibly not canonical to this.
Scott: I don't know doesn't matter I own a bunch of them.
Scott: Yeah, they're really good.
Rym: But the show ended and all I'm gonna say cuz we'll eventually talk about this.
Scott: It is a very good show.
Rym: I feel like I'm gonna watch the entire show again.
Scott: I'm gonna.
Scott: I think I might have to watch the show again.
Rym: Do not watch the end unless you have seen Literally every other episode of Adventure Time because it does tie everything up.
Rym: Well, I think it is literally a perfect ending.
Rym: I could not have asked for more and I love.
Scott: how long is this ending?
Scott: Adventure time episodes are short.
Rym: It's long enough.
Scott: Okay it I Don't even want to say anything about it other than that movie also.
Rym: Yeah, but the movie will not impact the end of the show.
Scott: my boy Prisma at the end, uh How about cosmic album?
Rym: Oh, yeah, they're they're they're involved.
Scott: That's good.
Scott: How about glob my boy?
Rym: Oh, yeah glob is involved.
Scott: Oh, baby.
Scott: Also, give me that glob.
Scott: All I'm gonna say is we're not.
Rym: Yes Magic man's magic is involved.
Scott: It sounds like magic.
Scott: man's magic is heavily involved.
Rym: Uh, the lich like everything is involved.
Rym: Everything comes to an appropriate ending.
Rym: It's real real good.
Scott: lobbers lit showdown.
Scott: Let's go.
Rym: Well, you might remember cuz glob was one of many entities out there in space.
Scott: remember gold No Watch adventure time again.
Rym: There's a moment that I remembered very much where the lich says something.
Rym: the lich Has a few.
Rym: every time the lich appeared he got like a couple of sentences that were said really well with a good voice actor.
Rym: That are really really good.
Rym: So one of those times the lich says something like, you know I am death the last scholar of gall, etc, etc.
Rym: It all comes together in the end.
Rym: I don't remember that but I remember that matters when it when when I saw what was going On at the end.
Rym: I was that person sitting here pointing the screen going.
Rym: Oh, oh, I see it.
Rym: It was super good Mm-hmm, so we'll be reviewing a lot of shows queued up and a lot of stuff to do.
Rym: So if you saw us at PAX and you only want to hear about games next Tuesday, we're talking about games and also our panel you might have seen us at PAX is not on YouTube yet because The exact same panel with almost the exact same content that we did at PAX East is already on YouTube.
Rym: It didn't actually have to go to the panel Mm-hmm.
Rym: If you saw streamed if you found GeekNights Because you saw the live stream of our panel from PAX West on PAX to let me know I'm curious.
Rym: I saw.
Rym: apparently we had like between two and three hundred people watching it live on Twitch and I don't know how many people watch it after the fact because it's a GeekNights lecture.
Rym: That's not on my personal YouTube channel So I don't have the stats for it.
Rym: But I'm curious if you found us because of that twitch stream because if you did I am inclined to try to get more of our panels on the PAX twitch stream as opposed to just in a panel room.
Rym: So yeah, otherwise the book club book is Still Homer's Odyssey because God didn't update the website.
Scott: Oh it is Space Odyssey, it's another Odyssey.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: These fake.
Scott: we went from the Greek Odyssey to the Space Odyssey.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: I'm reading books and I'm not reading that one.
Scott: I'm reading other super fantasy novels.
Rym: The problem is I just all I want to do is read a bunch of our NK jemisin stuff.
Scott: go ahead I'm ready.
Scott: I'm reading some garbage old fantasy.
Rym: No, ooh, I Will see.
Rym: because if depending on once we do 2001 a Space Odyssey in the GeekNights book club I feel like I might do another Odyssey adjacent book.
Rym: that is really really potentially.
Scott: what are the Odysseys are there?
Rym: It's adjacent and that it's based on some Greek stuff.
Rym: that's adjacent to the Odyssey, but it is technically a planescape book by Troy Denning.
Rym: So we'll say a Plains Odyssey, yeah possibly it is Theseus.
Rym: my boy is involved ship of Theseus the ship of Theseus.
Rym: Theseus is involved in in the most Tangential way and only if you really read into it.
Rym: But it is involved because it actually gets into a lot about like what is memory and what is a person and is a person?
Rym: Nothing more than the sum of their memories, etc, etc.
Rym: I remember it being pretty but anyway, that's not the booklet book.
Rym: The booklet book is the 2001 Space Odyssey the real one.
Rym: Yes so for the entire run of GeekNights since 2005 a perennial theme has been That we're really mad about copyright law Mm-hmm, and we want to reform it radically while still because we were baked in the in the maybe early 2000 slash that we grew up.
Rym: But we all not only that but we also came of age during what might have been Literally the golden age of modern piracy.
Rym: Yes, like I don't think you young listeners today Who are younger than some of my Final Fantasy 1 save games realize the extent to which?
Rym: pirating media and software Shaped my young life.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Like that was a fucking era.
Scott: I think young people these days.
Scott: I think they don't pirate.
Scott: They all got like mobile phones.
Rym: They don't really, you know about they do but what I've found is that they usually pirate in a really bad way.
Rym: they pirate software by downloading malware and They pirate media by watching fucked up like color.
Scott: They'll go don't like they but they won't even realize they're pirating.
Rym: They'll go like a website with manga and not realize that it's an illegal manga site or they'll watch these YouTube videos Better like zoomed in cropped squash and there's reverb added to the audio.
Rym: That's pitch shifted to avoid all the content filters, right?
Rym: It's like watch like all of adventure time like people.
Scott: you have these people buying the Nintendo online Service or people buying the stupid portable like that mini Nintendo or the mini Super Nintendo.
Scott: It's like bro I got ROM of.
Scott: I have every NES SNES Genesis Gameboy fucking every fucking game 100% of them there isn't even the Japanese ones.
Scott: I have all the games ever.
Scott: it cost me nothing.
Scott: I can play them on my computer or even allow my DS lite, right?
Scott: I paid nothing.
Scott: Why the hell you paying and waiting in line to pay who knows what the fucking tiny NES cost?
Scott: that is 20 goddamn games on.
Scott: It's fucking useless piece of garbage.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: What the hell's wrong with you adding another box under your TV Even if it's a tiny one, I don't understand what these people wrong with them.
Rym: Now the important thing is that I don't.
Scott: we don't want is piracy.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, but also times change.
Rym: like during that era it was also.
Rym: piracy felt very different partly because it was easy to spin a narrative of like the people trying to free music from the RIAA and simultaneously the RIAA was being Overly draconian and what didn't really have the artists interest at heart so much as its own and there's a whole giant history of this
Scott: Doesn't matter.
Rym: Yeah the point is that one of the common themes of this was that For every shitty thing that the US would do in terms of Throwing the baby out with a bathwater and trying to quash piracy Europe would always go above and beyond and do something way worse.
Rym: and It's that this is continued to this day.
Rym: But now we're in an interesting situation because on one hand I don't trust the US to regulate free speech on the internet Right because our government is in disarray But still the US does it better than even the countries that do everything else better.
Scott: Here's the problem, right?
Scott: It's like a we believe in free speech and that the government should not regulate speech But also we believe that private companies shouldn't kick all the Nazis off because you're allowed to yep You're.
Scott: it's not the government doing it.
Scott: So it's not censorship, right?
Rym: So I'd also be okay with the government saying all speech is free except this narrow band of Nazis.
Scott: Yeah that you know it's not perfect.
Rym: I would not have been for that if I were not for the fact that Nazism is on their eyes again.
Scott: But anyway, the point is is that you know, we believe in things like, you know, like privacy and you know Whatnot, but then what happens is that when you take when you try to actually make laws that enforce those things and you know Encode those things you end up reaching too far and destroying the internet.
Scott: and it's like no Right, we have to do what we can for those things without destroying the internet.
Scott: Yep, right.
Scott: The internet is amazing because it allows the free flow of information around the entire world right, and it's like people keep trying to do things like get rid of net neutrality and You know regulate speech on the internet.
Scott: It's like Internet's no good in China, right?
Scott: What the fuck?
Scott: It's useless.
Scott: Well, it's barely good.
Rym: here There's this tweet that always sticks out in my head where someone said someone expressed all my myriad concerns about the web very succinctly and all They said was I feel like there used to be more websites.
Scott: There did used to be more.
Rym: Yeah, like my Tenchi Muyo fan site or the Anna what Anna Pike web ring stuff?
Scott: Yep Now it's just that's just someone's tumblr.
Scott: now But I'm not gonna get there's only one website.
Rym: tell them the full details of what the EU is doing.
Rym: But basically there's two parts to this directive and I'm not a lawyer and this is a naive reading.
Scott: Tell you that the people who are in the media industries, right?
Scott: You know foolishly believe that this is gonna make them more monies.
Scott: So they're very happy about it because they don't really give it, you know, it's not their priority to not break the internet They just want.
Scott: they're just thinking.
Scott: Oh, yeah, I make I make movies I get more monies.
Rym: So one part of this is the link tax and it has to do with like news aggregators Don't even want to talk about that one.
Rym: That's a whole different ballgame, right?
Scott: It's like basically the link tags would be on paper real bad.
Scott: Like oh you want to link to this news article.
Scott: you better pay us a bunch of money.
Scott: But they put in a bunch of exceptions for all sorts of common sense things.
Rym: So there's a lot like a link in and of itself doesn't seem to cover it but a link plus too big of a snippet Counts, right?
Scott: so basically that they put all sorts of common sense exceptions to read on to pay the tax and it's unforeseen whether this is actually gonna be a problem or not and We're gonna have to sort of wait and see.
Scott: but it's kind of vague and it's not great and they shouldn't have done it.
Rym: But whatever and I can also see a lot of companies just serving a different website to the EU.
Rym: That's happened before.
Rym: there's already a bunch of game companies that just don't provide their forums or support anymore to anyone in Europe.
Rym: Mmm, like there's there are numerous game companies or if you go to their website from Europe It just says sorry GDPR can't help.
Scott: I don't have any cookie warnings on our site.
Scott: Should I block everyone in Europe?
Rym: Yeah, I just don't care.
Scott: Someone come after us.
Rym: article 13 is the problem the so-called upload filter.
Rym: now the problem is that basically what they want to do is require big aggregators like YouTube and whatever to Pre vet uploaded content and prevent the upload of copyright infringing content.
Scott: All right.
Scott: So how is this humanly possible for everybody?
Scott: Yeah case in point You know how much video is uploaded to just YouTube?
Scott: More in one second more video is uploaded to YouTube than you could watch in your whole life.
Rym: So my problem is specifically the only thing I want to get into is the idea of upload filters as opposed to post-hoc filters because an upload filter cannot differentiate between Someone who has overused clips and pirated in some way versus someone who is using clips fair use for another purpose a derivative work of some kind commentary etc, or Specifically fair use for parody or news reporting.
Rym: there's no way to differentiate between those in a meaningful way because if there was we'd already see that technology being used things like YouTube
Scott: Upload filter and simply you upload it, but then you just it doesn't get published on YouTube until Someone takes a look at it first because right now you upload a video on YouTube It just goes live right away And then you get a copyright takedown.
Scott: the system comes in a timing right instead which I think is better.
Scott: Instead you upload your video to YouTube.
Scott: You can't push the publish button until you've gone through the Yelp system.
Rym: the problem There is maybe a different system than it is now But I think the big difference is that I can upload anything and it's live Until someone takes a positive action or as a rule that triggers and then I have to go through a process.
Rym: The real problem in my opinion is that unlike the US?
Scott: Where we have didn't even have fair use over there, that's the problem.
Rym: Every European member state has different rules about this shit Mm-hmm And I don't think there's any reasonable way for a large company or a small company or really anyone To deal with all those different parts.
Rym: like UK's libel laws are ridiculous.
Rym: Every member state in the EU is all these different fair use ideas if they even have the concept of fair use.
Rym: The US has a pretty good system But even that is not very well defined and ends up coming down to court cases more often than it should.
Rym: and I feel like There's like people are saying that these the kinds of upload filters and laws.
Rym: the result would be ending memes Like but not memes like actual memes, but memes like those funny Images and macros that we post everywhere.
Rym: I feel like it kind of could I feel like Preventing people from uploading or publishing on all these platforms in Europe with this prior restraint because remember US Copyright law makes a big deal about the difference between prior restraint versus post publication action?
Scott: Well, the fundamental the way the reason all this problem started to begin with right is because they took away everyone's IP addresses.
Scott: It used to be back in the days, right?
Scott: You had a computer.
Scott: you could just host things from your own goddamn computer.
Scott: You had as much upload as you had download, right?
Scott: You didn't need right now a day.
Rym: Yes, I did most uploads that did download on my 3036 modem.
Scott: I'm just saying right.
Scott: people had an eye an actual IP address.
Scott: They weren't netted.
Scott: They didn't have some dynamic address.
Scott: that was changing.
Scott: right you guys.
Scott: you didn't need to have a web host.
Scott: You just run services on a computer in your house, right?
Scott: You didn't need to use YouTube.
Scott: You just put videos on a computer in your house and deliver them to the world, right?
Scott: We're using peer-to-peer Sharing software like Napster and hotline and all these other things which surely though like this bottom sending your sending data Directly from our computers to our friends computers, right?
Scott: The reason that this sort of control can even be enforced is because Technologically speaking on the IP level right?
Scott: We've created an internet right where you can't just host things in your house anymore.
Scott: You don't have enough upload bandwidth.
Scott: You're not given an IP.
Scott: that doesn't change.
Scott: We're not using ipv6 yet everywhere, right?
Scott: So if you want to have a video that's sent to the whole world You can't just upload it from your house directly to the people watching.
Scott: You need to stream it to twitch who then streams of the people watching or upload it to YouTube who then send to be watching.
Scott: And that creates this bottleneck this single point where these kinds of things can be enforced.
Scott: right if we go and fix the internet and let everyone have IP addresses again and go to ipv6 and Upload bandwidth right it just turns into another weird shitty old Wild Wild West.
Scott: in some ways We can bring back the Napster glory days that what you just referred to as a Golden Age and there.
Scott: well We don't need a fucking YouTube.
Scott: You can just go to Scott dot whatever and let's see them enforce their copyright regime against 10,000 million youtubes because everyone's got their own.
Rym: I think a much more modern approach.
Scott: everyone runs their own YouTube Scott tube Rym tube.
Scott: Let's see them fucking I do.
Rym: I do want there to be a more distributed model like the old internet.
Scott: deal with it.
Rym: I simultaneously want massive copyright reform to Specifically protect fair use and parody because Piracy it piracy.
Rym: if piracy disappeared Entirely without any other side effects.
Rym: I wouldn't be that angry.
Rym: the problem is Piracy cannot be cannot in my opinion be quashed without severely limiting many other things that are not piracy.
Rym: There's very little way to disentangle them.
Scott: well all this stuff is like you know Saying the same thing since the beginning even before GeekNights, right?
Scott: Yeah, because we don't like the laws of thermodynamics let's make a law that says we can we can get more energy out of the system than we put in.
Scott: that's not gonna make a Perpetual motion machine that suddenly works, right?
Scott: That we could have we.
Scott: we could enforce copyright and have privacy.
Scott: But you know what the reality of the world is that once something becomes digital data it can be copied and distributed Infinitely for almost free.
Scott: there is no way you can stop that from happening no matter what law you write.
Scott: You might be able to catch some people who do it and punish them but you can't stop from happening no matter how much you want to.
Scott: so instead of trying to stop it or Punish people for doing it.
Scott: You should instead just create a society where you accept that as reality.
Scott: You just same way we accept that we can't have a perpetual motion machine, and we instead have an energy policy.
Scott: Here's the fun copyright policy that accepts the fact that you can't that that's the law of the universe.
Rym: Yes, but that copyright policy cannot exist in a vacuum.
Rym: It also needs an economic restructuring so that the creation of art is still funded somehow.
Scott: I'm sure But that doesn't think.
Rym: well, that's the easy part.
Scott: No, we're done You know you.
Scott: just the point is no matter what it is You just have to accept reality instead of fighting against reality.
Scott: and this is a fight against reality and it's also You know it They didn't destroy the Internet.
Rym: I would not be nearly as potentially worried about this were it not for the fact that at least based on what I've read so far and just The EU's and Europe's history with this kind of thing I do worry that this will significantly curtail Parity and fair use rights globally and will edge us toward Using European standards for this as opposed to US standards because as shitty as US standards Are I think US standards of fair use are still the best we've got?
Rym: And we're just gonna stop now cuz we're back GeekNights back, and I'm real hungry, and I'm gonna do another show in a couple days This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: be sure to visit our website At front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: remember GeekNights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patreon supporting this episode of GeekNights.
Rym: It's been a while.
Rym: I apologize for that.
Rym: are Craig Oliver Alan Joyce Rebecca Dunne Heidi me Nicola shimmering Ruby obelisk hanging in the sky kajar tovish in my state e.com.
Rym: That's my s t ad y dot com.
Rym: Jeremy minor linky GJ bent scooter lonely Roberto Kingsley Kelly Snyder Amanda duchette Shawn Yeager Matthew Smith Nicholas Brando Mr.
Rym: Strong stretch in 421 creations Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn Shervin von Horrell Rory James David white Rochelle, Montanota Superboy tripwire sailor vista dodge.
Rym: like Jojo Joestar Clinton Walton Renford, New Zealand Ryan turned her open letter.
Rym: Finn Christmas gift handle Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: Yeah, we missed two weeks of shows because of you know real life stuff, but we are picking up the content again.
Rym: We're planning all new panels.
Rym: Hopefully for PAX Unplugged and PAX South the patreon special rewards.
Rym: We're gonna do the QA's again soon.
Rym: We're ramping that back up.
Rym: I have a better system from what we did before so stay tuned for that.
Rym: If any of you are patrons of the page around and haven't clicked on it in a while I did post a special video.
Rym: That was only.
Rym: the only people who can see this video are people who either saw our panel at PAX West or Can click on that link in the patreon, but it's the pre-show pop-up video loop that we played in the room while the crowd was Loading.
Rym: but stay tuned for.
Rym: nor more Rym's rants.
Rym: stay tuned for more rimbly reviews.
Rym: Emily and I are gonna start reviewing every Disney animated feature in chronological order.
Rym: There's a bunch of stuff coming mostly because it's gonna start getting cold enough a lot more time.
Rym: I'm not out biking and running and going to cons and doing nonsense.
Rym: So now I leave you all With all right professor Stevens consider me handling the situation in the meantime.
Rym: Just stay here and rest.
Scott: Please hurry, mr Tracker the radioactive power in that meteor is the key to my new life-saving technique.
Scott: the wrong people could use it for destruction.
Rym: Not.
Rym: if I can help it.
Rym: Give me the best agents for this mission.
Rym: We did it partner.
Rym: Why don't you all bring in the last piece of that old meteor and we'll fix up Hondo Good as new.
Rym: I don't have it dusty.
Rym: I failed.
Scott: Hey anyone want a meteor?
Scott: It was stashed in a truck.
Scott: me and T-bob took.
Rym: I don't know whether to hug you or spank you.