Rym: It's Tuesday July 31st.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott, and this is GeekNights side.
Rym: We're talking about rogue.
Rym: you like Rogue likes as in games that are like the game called rogue.
Scott: Let's do this All right, so earlier this year when it was fucking cold, and I perhaps foolishly agreed to bike ten Saturdays in a row Which is great except for the cold part everything else about it was great.
Scott: There was one ride.
Scott: we went on and on the way home on that ride We hopped onto this bike path, and it went from someplace upstate.
Scott: I don't know where the hell we were all the way to Tarrytown, and I was like where the hell is this path been?
Scott: I've never seen it before.
Scott: no one ever told me about it.
Rym: I've biked up there And I found like these really really great bike paths But I never was able to cobble together like a route around.
Scott: so I you know went online.
Scott: I found it and on Sunday Rym didn't want to come because I don't know why but I went out stuff to do.
Scott: I went Out to take the path and supposedly according to maps the path would take me from the Bronx to Brewster it where I would then Take the train home, so trying to find the start of the path I got to the Bronx.
Scott: okay because I'd been that down that way before But trying to find the beginning of the path near Van Cortlandt Park was not so easy.
Rym: There's a lot of like really nice two-lane bike paths up there that start at random points.
Scott: as I go Went into the woods in the mud and the various I saw bike like tracks in the mud.
Scott: so I was like huh?
Scott: I think I'm going the right way, and then I was slightly lost.
Scott: But I basically just gave up on finding the a real start of the path And I just went on the normal roads on like the 87 service road until I got to Tibbetts Park.
Scott: Whatever that is yeah, then from there I was able to find the South County Trail way Which goes north and then becomes the North County Trail way which takes you all the way to Brewster.
Rym: So unrelatedly I was looking for a map of that bike path And I found something I didn't know about apparently the sprain Ridge Park bike trail Which I've heard of.
Scott: yeah this there is another path someone posted about that's farther to the east.
Scott: It's not a bike, but it doesn't go as far, and it's not as you know.
Scott: It's it.
Rym: Oh, it's not a bike trail.
Rym: You know what it is.
Rym: It's a mountain biking park that I didn't know was there.
Rym: Oh, I can go mountain biking.
Rym: I'm sure Emily.
Scott: I'm sure it's not very mountainous.
Rym: I mean it looks like it's about on the level of Palau bin.
Scott: I mean the climb from the whole entire path was not much.
Rym: Mountain biking doesn't necessarily mean you're going up and down mountains sometimes.
Rym: It just means you're going straight over crazy obstacles.
Rym: Looks like it's more like that.
Rym: This is like what I did in Singapore.
Scott: Yeah, it was so nice to ride in this path because basically there's no cars.
Scott: There's nothing in the way is you know?
Scott: there's people all along it also using the path.
Scott: the only thing I would do differently As I managed to have good timing and caught the 211 train back.
Rym: Yeah Cuz those upstate trains do not run that often on Sundays.
Scott: if I had missed it which would have been a close miss based When I left my house.
Scott: I want to our weight I would had to wait an hour for the 311, but you know what I would do next time.
Scott: the only thing I do differently is Take the train there and bike back.
Scott: You're not gonna get lost trying to find the start of the path right you're not gonna have to worry about the train timing of Getting there.
Scott: yeah, yeah, you just wake up go to Grand Central take the train there and Once you're at the Brewster train station.
Scott: It's easy to get to the path, so then just bike home and bike home Whatever.
Scott: you're not gonna get lost in the Bronx.
Rym: Yeah, well the time.
Rym: because I do a thing like when I run my half marathons the route I take is to the top of Manhattan basically from here.
Scott: I also you know the trouble is I would just bike to Brewster and bike back, but that way to take a long.
Rym: Yeah, but same thing.
Rym: so I end my run.
Scott: I would have been home at like 8 or 9 and I'm at the top of Manhattan.
Rym: so my options are either just run home or Take the subway home.
Rym: And it takes like an hour to take the subway from the top of Manhattan back to here.
Rym: So I decided the last time I did it then I'm gonna take the subway there in the morning and just run back.
Rym: That way I'll end when I'm exhausted and feeling like crap in front of my own apartment.
Rym: Yep, as opposed to next to the only grocery store in the top of Manhattan.
Scott: So if you want to you want to come you should come because it's way good I'm up for it next time and I since now I now I totally know the way so you can just follow me.
Rym: See that's it.
Rym: you figured it out, and now I can come and read.
Scott: I know the way in the reverse.
Scott: I'd still probably get a little lost trying to find it from the bottom.
Rym: I mean I remember a couple times.
Rym: I only went over the RFK one way because I wasn't really sure where the entrance was.
Scott: I figured out Randall's Island - I can Show you I know I know Randall's Island in excruciating detail.
Rym: now That's.
Rym: I figured I had a bike over the bridge to 125th Street because I have another route where I go when I do a loop Around Randall's Island, and then I come back over and run down in Queens anyway.
Rym: anyway in some gaming news.
Rym: so valve Added a temporary fix for this fake item scam.
Scott: right.
Scott: so I don't I'm not.
Scott: it's still not a hundred percent sure on all the details.
Scott: So if I'm wrong about anything, I'm wrong.
Scott: That's just how it's gonna be.
Rym: wait.
Rym: It's GeekNights.
Rym: I should be the disclaimer in literally every episode.
Scott: I might be wrong.
Rym: I'm likely wrong, but here's we reviewed games based on half a play.
Scott: This is what it seems to have happened.
Scott: It seems like there was some indie game called something.
Scott: So many game called something and it seems like it changed its name or something to try to trick Abstractism.
Scott: right.
Scott: so apparently the game was up to multiple scams at once.
Scott: scam number one It was just mining coins and all the reviews were like oh my god.
Scott: This isn't a game It's just mining my coins.
Scott: what the hell you know.
Rym: I wouldn't be surprised if battle tech were doing that because battle tech somehow maxes out my 1080 every time I play it.
Rym: yet both live streaming to two different streams Does not even touch.
Rym: overwatch like overwatch can do that fine.
Scott: Well, that's the difference between a indie studio and a blizzard.
Scott: yeah.
Scott: so the other thing is That apparently it.
Scott: This is the part I'm probably wrong about right is that there was some sort of fake item scam where basically this game had steam items that you could Trade and sell on the steam marketplace that were associated with this game.
Scott: They made their items look like valuable items from tf2 to trick the trick people into trading for this games items and thus they scanned people out of their valuable items and Got and to get monies.
Rym: this reeks very much.
Scott: valve is basically giving people their legit items back.
Rym: I mean one on one hand like I don't want to blame the victim But you could have you could have figured this basically the steam.
Scott: look It's the steam equivalent of going on ebay and buying a picture of a macbook pro.
Rym: I'm gonna say that the statute of limitations ran out on this considering that the MMO is long gone.
Rym: But you might know I talked about it a lot.
Scott: I was having a minor minor minor resurgence right now.
Scott: for some reason.
Scott: there was actually a news about Wow.
Scott: First of all I see people in my you know battle net friend list playing Wow Which is strange.
Scott: I've seen news about Wow recently.
Scott: how like they're basically making everything free except for the new expansion.
Scott: So like you don't have to go and buy all the old expansions.
Scott: You can just play Wow and you'll get every old expansion.
Scott: I think that's what it said.
Scott: and also There's some bug in the Wow leveling.
Scott: that's happening, and they're fixing it or something.
Scott: There's some news about that huh.
Scott: so wow is having a minor resurgence I think because there haven't been MMOs And I think people.
Scott: true it's been so long since MMO.
Scott: people are back on the MMO.
Rym: so in Sierras the realm yeah, okay, the only MMO Rym can talk about because the only one I played cuz I knew better But everybody gets one, but well no I played oh, but I really knew better.
Rym: I played what's it with you at RIT for a while the Korean grindy one Ragnarok.
Scott: we played that for like a week.
Rym: I kept playing it for a couple months, which maybe was a mistake, okay?
Scott: But I bash.
Scott: I never got beyond bashing slimes, and then I see errors.
Rym: the realm.
Rym: I had my main character and my brother as character and I had another character that I leveled up enough to be plausible who had a fake identity and generated a pretty reliable in-game gold income by crafting items that appeared to be very valuable items and Trading them or selling them with people who were too dumb to actually right-click on the item and look at the stats to see What it really was.
Rym: and I generated a handsome income with this.
Scott: That would be like if I had a magic card and at the top it said mox emerald But at the bottom it didn't say tab get a green mana.
Scott: It said tab do five damage to you, so Stop hitting yourself.
Scott: And I sold it to you for the value of mox emerald.
Rym: It's just it's interesting.
Rym: I think that the salient point Lose the game is that if you're gonna scan people in the modern era you can't just run one scam.
Scott: this game looks like It was multiple interleaved scams props to the scammers, but also because valve is fixing it, but yeah This just it's just more examples of valve.
Scott: you cannot get around this.
Scott: you need to pay fucking money all the zillions of dollars You make from steam and whatever to hire people and treat them well and have them human moderate Steam and choose which games go in and which games go out just like Apple does with the stupid Apple App Store.
Scott: Right because otherwise steam will be.
Scott: steam is right now sort of in between the Apple App Store and the garbage Google Play Store.
Rym: I mean, I would never search steam for a genre of game to see what's out there.
Scott: No, it's like the Apple Store is like almost all human controlled.
Scott: It's very hard to get crap in there, but not impossible.
Scott: and the Google Play Store is just a fucking mess.
Scott: And steam is in the middle.
Scott: right and steam.
Scott: you know the Apple Store.
Scott: They're legit criticisms of that method as well, but you know you steam basically has to do what the Apple Store does But not the evil part.
Scott: It's just the good parts.
Rym: yep I mean if they really wanted to valve could have like its default stuff Google to do that, too.
Rym: But they could have the like.
Rym: yeah, here's where all the garbage is.
Rym: you can buy it if you want, but there be dragons there.
Rym: Yeah, bad dragons not good dragons But not bad dragon.
Rym: so in some other news that's actually pretty interesting.
Rym: I Did not think this would ever happen okay?
Rym: But you might recall that a long time ago like I was still working at IBM I would think it was still God.
Scott: I think we're still.
Rym: yeah, well remember.
Scott: I was working at IBM Or just out of art.
Rym: it was in that era the mid 2000s.
Rym: the escapists was a magazine.
Scott: I remember I got the first escapist ever.
Scott: it was like a PDF cuz.
Scott: I tried to make it like a magazine.
Scott: It was a real magazine Form fancy looking articles, and you would flip the pages, and I don't remember was actually PDF, but it felt like a PDF.
Rym: Yeah, I think it was actually a PDF cuz.
Scott: I've been.
Scott: it might have been a fancy website.
Rym: I remember getting emailed to me And I like read it at work right the PC.
Scott: the point is is that they're like hey We're doing highbrow games journalism digitally with fancy magazine looking stuff.
Rym: It was just original escapist.
Rym: people described it as the you know the New Yorker of video game journalism.
Rym: That's what it was for like a month yep And then it just got kind of hacky and bad and eventually it kind of got taken over by gamer.
Scott: Eventually it became the escapist that you know right the one that employed You know Yahtzee and all those other people.
Rym: yeah But it had a lot of problems that we don't want to get into.
Rym: it was bad news, and I wasn't eventually died right?
Rym: I don't even know.
Scott: all I know is either Not telling.
Rym: I don't know either cuz the news is that Defy Media who owns the escapists And had been just ignoring it they sold it To let's see to Canada's Enthusiast gaming.
Rym: so the escapist is now Canadian, and it's owned by this group called enthusiasts gaming which I didn't know anything about.
Rym: okay I don't know either of these groups so but their goal is to bring it back and make it as good as what it Originally was.
Scott: so for that one week what?
Rym: and not let like gummergate bullshit infiltrate it and ruin it all right.
Scott: good luck with that.
Rym: I Would not even talk about this on gig nights But for the fact that there is a piece of information that makes me go from very distrustful of this to cautiously optimistic.
Rym: So the escapist former editor-in-chief like way back in the day Russ Pitts who you may know is running take this Didn't he?
Scott: wasn't he also like editor at?
Scott: Was a gamers with jobs?
Scott: was that what Russ Pitts?
Rym: is that what it was stuff?
Scott: I think that and I think I think that's Laura that worked with that.
Scott: right.
Scott: well Well, I think she wrote at gamers a job.
Scott: That's the first place.
Scott: I heard him was actually in the earliest days of podcast 2006.
Scott: I never read gamers of jobs, but I did listen to the gamers of jobs podcast Which I believe was Russ Pitts and another guy I forget.
Rym: yeah, so Russ Pitts I trust and for a lot of reasons.
Rym: I know him he's a good dude.
Rym: But take this is a fantastic organization that provides the AFK rooms at conventions and does training for convention staff Among many other things.
Rym: yeah, just super stand-up, dude.
Rym: The fact that he is involved in this and is basically in charge of the new escapist Means that if there's if there's a chance for this to work.
Rym: This is the chance.
Scott: Like I wouldn't trust my by escapist Why not just make something completely new?
Rym: well because escapist had a pretty good brand And it actually has a back catalog of a bunch of good long-form journalism that could be brought back or revisited.
Rym: There's a lot of reasons to bring it back I guess.
Scott: I guess when I guess they bought it right so they must.
Scott: there must be some value in what they bought.
Scott: you know The intellectual properties and yeah contracts or who knows what they've got hopefully not debts Yeah.
Rym: But Ross also made a good point on Twitter and because a lot of Gomer gate types were really invested in the escapist adjacent media And he pretty much said straight up.
Rym: Yeah political extremists referring to gamer Gators are not welcome in this new outlet.
Scott: So We'll see how this goes.
Rym: I'm cautiously optimistic.
Scott: I wonder if that's a good strategy.
Scott: right of buying like buying media outlets, dude
Rym: I would have bought the Gothamist if I could have
Scott: where the audience is the enemy and then start publishing things that you know are Anti the the audience to then right like
Rym: two ways
Scott: to imagine if I could buy Breitbart And then suddenly only publish you know actually good stuff.
Scott: Yeah, actually publish real journals suddenly publish real news But I but I right like that cut.
Scott: is that a good idea.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: or is that a bad idea?
Scott: I don't know like if I Go by Fox News and put legit journalism.
Scott: Here's the difference though.
Scott: Would that be a good idea or a bad?
Rym: Fox News and Breitbart were always vile garbage?
Scott: I mean, I guess this was.
Scott: I guess it could only help right it can't hurt.
Scott: Yeah, it would hope because at least you'd get rid of the fox Even if you buy it and it fails, but here's the case.
Scott: Here's the case where the escape was already dead.
Scott: so if Fox News was already dead And off the air would it be worth buying it yeah?
Rym: I mean if I had the money I would have done anything possible to buy the Gothamist when it went down.
Scott: so trivia the Person who was my boss two jobs ago his friends childhood friends I believe with Jake Dobkin the Gothamist guy and he his startup that he started after He left the company where I was working for him in Dumbo, Brooklyn.
Scott: It's apparently very successful, and he gave mad monies to the new Gothamist.
Scott: Interesting that he's a very interesting, dude He was involved with like the FBI raiding him for Apple to wears when he was a kid and such.
Rym: So in some other news if you are going to be at Gen Con Which I would not personally recommend Don't go to Gen Con.
Scott: if you live near, Indiana I still maybe it's worth.
Scott: It's okay.
Rym: We live on the same train lines.
Rym: the New York Comic Con.
Rym: We don't go to that nonsense.
Scott: Yeah, I mean Gen Con is a little better than New York Comic Con.
Rym: yeah But it's also got like.
Rym: I wouldn't do panels at it.
Scott: the thing with Gen Con is like has good parts and bad parts.
Scott: Right it's actually so you know what I might get.
Scott: actually good in a socially progressive way.
Rym: It's just bad in a convention management like gig nights would never perform at Gen Con.
Scott: It's like Gen Con.
Scott: it's like you know the people they're good and the the content is good and all that stuff is just the Convention structure is bad, but if you are going to be there And you listen to gig nights, then you might be interested that Luke Crane.
Rym: Oh, you know Head of games at Kickstarter burning wheel dude among other things he has a game That he wants to play test at Gen Con?
Scott: pretty sure, but if you are hearing this now for the first time It's too late to get in on that game.
Rym: It's hard to say though because I feel like he's going to be selective about who he brings in and the things I know about This are that one.
Rym: he published a Twitter poll that was adjacent to this and the question was fuck elves Or I want to be an elf?
Scott: Rym wants to choose.
Rym: I want you both fuck elves and be an elf.
Scott: I Would choose fuck elves, but not in the way the Rym wants to and I'm more the way that like you know Fuck the Philadelphia Eagles and fuck elves.
Rym: You know there is a third way though the drow.
Rym: It's both fuck elves, and I secretly want to be an elf because I kind of am an elf anyway.
Rym: The other thing is Luke said to me specifically and I quote you will like this yeah I Hope they're Santa's elves and not oh great.
Rym: That would be super great, and it wouldn't change the answer to my question.
Rym: Maybe anyway You should check this out.
Rym: if you're gonna be at Gen Con.
Rym: There's rumors that we there might be able to.
Rym: something similar might happen at PAX West so we'll see.
Rym: If it happens, I'm gonna do everything I can to be involved in that.
Rym: but also If you are a fan of parsley games the Jared Sorensen variety like such games as danger town beat-down spooky man Action castle with torch hands They're going to be there and the parsley hardcover collection is out.
Rym: the Kickstarter is like done and everything.
Rym: yep.
Scott: So yeah, I kick-started it.
Scott: So I'm just waiting for my book to come in the mail.
Scott: But so originally the parts the games are published in individual pieces of cardboard which I have all of.
Scott: yeah But why not get all the games again in a hardcover book?
Scott: That's much more convenient.
Rym: And they are running events at Gen Con and I remembered why I don't like Gen Con.
Rym: two of the events are sold out And you can't go to them yep, but for two dollars on Saturday at 3 or 4 p.m.. That's okay.
Rym: I've put more money into arcade machines before.
Rym: you could play spooky manor or danger town beat-down And that's why we don't go to.
Scott: Jen Do you think Jared gets those two dollars?
Rym: No, I'm pretty sure Gen Con gets those two dollars.
Rym: Jared probably has to pay for the table that he's gonna have in the room.
Rym: Fucking Gen Con you're like so close and yet, so you just got rid of your stupid ticketing.
Scott: I'd be like well.
Scott: Let's go Jenga.
Rym: Yeah, good ticketing will never be a part of Pax.
Rym: unplugged That is the hill I will die on.
Rym: But anyway things of the day.
Scott: so this Rym Had for once an Respectable high quality thing of the day.
Rym: I'm rid.
Scott: This is a real good could not compete with my even better thing of the day.
Rym: So the problem is with Scott's thing is that my thing of the day is great because one my thing of the day It is great Mine is just greater.
Scott: as usual my thing of the day you tried to step up.
Scott: you came up to my usual level of thing Of the day goodness, and then I stepped it up even more.
Rym: my thing of the day is a mathematical model That you can use to determine when you should leave a Mets game.
Scott: So I got a lot of stories about this.
Rym: I've been in some situations.
Rym: We left a hockey game a little early once because there was a snowstorm.
Scott: That was a fucking mistake all right, so I got.
Scott: I got two stories right.
Scott: so first of all when we were young We went to a lot of games.
Scott: Yeah, especially Mets games You know you would go home early because you drove there And you didn't leave early.
Scott: if there was if there was if you're gonna lose the game There's no reason to stay to the end.
Scott: yeah Inning ninth inning why the hell would you stay to watch?
Scott: right you know anyway, and it's like not like hockey.
Rym: We're like something might have nothing's gonna happen.
Scott: You're all you're gonna.
Scott: Do is get home way later.
Scott: You're gonna sit in traffic in the parking lot.
Rym: It's like you know what I remember to get out of the Joe Louis arena.
Rym: We would sit in the parking garage for almost an hour.
Scott: yep exactly.
Scott: so you want to leave before right?
Scott: yeah.
Scott: And nowadays though I go to MSG and everyone else.
Scott: they start leaving the game.
Scott: Man if I drove here, I'd be leaving - yep, but I took the train No matter what happens, but anyway, so there was two notable incidents.
Scott: one notable incident, which is actually a Mets game.
Scott: We went to this mess game and I remember Kurt Schilling piece of shit douchebag was pitching and There was a rain delay like partway through the game and the rain delay went for a long time.
Scott: And you know it's a long rain delay when they start showing the videos of the two times the Mets won the World Series On the screen on the little TVs To keep you entertained while you wait.
Scott: Yeah, it went on for quite a while.
Scott: I think we waited at least maybe an hour or even longer and then the game didn't resume And it was still wet and the tarp was still on the field.
Scott: so we left in the car on the way home.
Scott: we're already in Stanford, Connecticut dropping people off I think and On the radio the game continued.
Scott: Oh, you're losing.
Scott: by the way when we left Continued and somehow the Mets miraculously came back in one and like the was extra innings.
Scott: I need to remember this was 19 late 90s Maybe 898 or 99 something like that.
Scott: if anyone can figure out exactly which game this was props to you.
Rym: great this is the thing of based on the the number of runs that a team is up by and What inning it is?
Rym: What is the confidence interval where you can leave and know the outcome of the game?
Scott: Like what are the odds that the team's gonna make an app where you tell it what game you're at and it tell it goes Ding time to go home.
Rym: This is so simple that you could do the rule yourself And if someone's up by six just leave after the first inning, maybe I will make that app.
Scott: Yeah, you put in what game you're at.
Scott: The problem is getting the stupid sports data.
Scott: That's yeah That's every.
Scott: I have all these great ideas for sports apps and I don't have access to just the basic sports data.
Scott: Hey I've looked into getting it and basically the only places that offer sports data are Offering it for fantasy sports and they charge a fortune because that is a Incredibly granular amount of data about all these players.
Scott: It's like no I just want to know the scores of all the games in real time.
Scott: That's it.
Scott: So not even real time.
Rym: So read this article.
Rym: I'm not gonna explain you the details, but it's really good and like this graph.
Rym: Yeah, that they show is excellent.
Scott: The other incident.
Scott: We were at New England Patriots game against the Saints and The Saints made a big interception.
Scott: There was like no time left in this game and the Saints were ahead.
Scott: So as soon as he caught that interception we got up and we walked to the parking lot Got in the car.
Scott: We're in the parking lot waiting in a line of cars to get out Patriots fans, right?
Scott: So all the Patriots fans had left this game also right before us even and suddenly we're just sitting in the car and People outside the car walking around start like getting crazy hootin and hollerin hootin and hollerin.
Scott: So like you do whenever you leave a sporting event in a car you turn on the sports radio And sure enough Tom Brady had miraculously come back to win that game.
Scott: So those are the two times you left early and it was a mistake.
Scott: We left early many other times and those times were not mistakes.
Rym: So now there's a data model at least for baseball.
Rym: I'd love to see this for other sports.
Rym: It's 538.
Rym: So maybe they'll do it.
Scott: I really want the date.
Scott: I really want access to data so I can make an app that tells you when to leave.
Rym: but I would Love to see a similar analysis for board games.
Scott: Oh, yeah, when do you quit the board games?
Rym: Yeah, at what point should you just flip the table?
Rym: Cuz the game is all my homo Shindeiru.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Oh I mean, oh my thing of the day that's better than you.
Rym: So what I'll say to prelude Scott's thing of the day is I clicked on it.
Rym: It's in French doesn't really tell me the deal.
Scott: I think it's might be Italian.
Scott: I don't even know.
Rym: This looks like French.
Scott: I have no idea.
Scott: It doesn't even matter.
Rym: It takes three seconds to know how great this Maybe is French because you click play and three seconds later, you know exactly how.
Rym: why this is so.
Scott: Yeah, so I actually don't know any information about this.
Scott: is le jutes Provencalis Something?
Scott: I'm pronouncing all this wrong.
Scott: It must be in Cannes right?
Scott: the place of the festival is the film festival But basically it's dudes on boats that look a lot like the boats They use in Venice only much bigger and it seems like the boats also have people on them Like.
Scott: I don't know what they're doing.
Scott: Are they rowing?
Scott: But these dudes are basically standing on the front of the boat Fucking jousting.
Scott: This is so great.
Scott: When you lose the joust you fucking fall in the dirty-ass water.
Scott: How amazing is that?
Scott: This is incredible.
Scott: It the only is this even better than that.
Scott: Basically that bloodsport.
Scott: They have in Italy the violence football Yeah, that even caught I don't know but this is even better than that.
Scott: This is like, holy shit.
Rym: This is real good.
Scott: I I would even actually try this because even though it seems like you get hurt and to be dangerous It's not that day, right?
Scott: It's like you fall in the water and they have these big fat wooden boards on their chest.
Rym: I mean, I guess you might get hit in the face.
Rym: So it's really.
Scott: it's really just a game of pushing, right?
Scott: It's like push but you're on a boat and like the boat is also pushing so there's like a lot of balance going on.
Scott: This is looks like way fun and way awesome.
Rym: Yeah, I would do.
Rym: it's very telling to this video zero dislikes.
Scott: If you dislike this you are not a good person.
Scott: In the moment.
Rym: you may recall that the book club book was Emily Wilson's translation of Homer's.
Rym: Odyssey was great.
Rym: We did the show.
Rym: it's done.
Rym: You can listen to the book club episode.
Scott: There's a GeekNights' book club.
Rym: Yeah, we've done a bunch of these books.
Scott: if you're an intelligent human being you should read books.
Scott: Yeah, the paper kind if you can read.
Rym: Yep, the Braille kind if you can't see Yep, or the audiobook if you need to like.
Rym: there's reasons.
Scott: Yeah, and I respect the audiobook that much anyway.
Scott: So I tried to happen.
Scott: it's my turn to pick a book club book and usually I just got a book in mind.
Scott: Right this time is a little harder because I didn't have one in mind.
Scott: So at first since we had just done this Odyssey and since it had been talked about on the internet.
Rym: reason thinking about the idiot?
Scott: No, I was thinking about.
Scott: So there's this book by.
Scott: I think it isn't xenophon the guy's name The old set you're talking about.
Rym: I might have already read this right?
Scott: It's the.
Scott: it's basically this journey of like from Persia to Turkey or so.
Rym: I've read a lot of that.
Scott: we had to read it in high school and apparently one of these is the story that the was based on.
Scott: So I was like, oh we should read that but there's no Emily Wilson translation of that.
Scott: No, no.
Scott: So then I said wait a minute.
Scott: Wait a minute.
Scott: Why don't we just read no Warriors Cuz that's a book.
Rym: I've never read that boy.
Scott: I've never read it either.
Scott: and I'm saying the movie like ten times.
Scott: Yeah, I might read it.
Scott: But then I got an even better idea than that because This evolving well, cuz I don't know if I don't really know.
Scott: if the Warriors is a good book I don't know.
Scott: I just know that there's a Cult classic movie based on.
Rym: I like aspects of the movie, but the movie is actually super long.
Rym: Not that much happens.
Rym: It's not that good what I like the movie.
Scott: It's not that long.
Scott: It's kind of pretty sure why it's very.
Scott: I think I like the movie more than it deserves because it's very New York Yeah, but it's got.
Rym: it's deeply flawed and not that enjoyable except for a very specific key moments.
Rym: It's also got some problematic shit.
Scott: Well, it's an old 70s movie.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway, I think it's right for a remake.
Scott: Hasn't it been a good remake?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: Anyway, the point it already is a remake.
Rym: It's a remake of something that's a robo cops getting a sequel from the original Robocop as in they're canceling Robocop 2 & 3 every for every Robocop since the first Robocop movie is Dropped and this is a direct sequel to the original Robocop.
Rym: The rest of its not canon.
Rym: Fuck it.
Scott: I'll take that Frank Miller.
Scott: So then I had an even better idea.
Scott: I was like well thinking about books based on movies, right?
Scott: Yeah this Sunday actually It's it's you know this Sunday.
Scott: I'm going but actually I think it started playing already.
Scott: There is a a on Remaster basically of a very very famous and excellent movie in 70 millimeter Screening at the Museum the moving image, right?
Scott: I think it started already, but I'm going to see it on Sunday.
Scott: Oh and that movie is also based on a book that I haven't read and is definitely a good book because it's ultra famous And I don't know I haven't read it.
Scott: So the book club book is 2001 a Space Odyssey.
Scott: Alright, that's a good pick.
Scott: Have you ever read it?
Rym: I've never read it, right?
Scott: So yeah, I don't know if it's good, but you have all stayed your execution.
Rym: This is a good enough book to where I am.
Rym: Once again Deferring my selection of some Dumas.
Scott: It's ultra famous.
Scott: It's a sci-fi book.
Scott: It's got like one of the best movies ever is based on it.
Scott: I might as well see what the deal is.
Scott: Is it as fucked up as the movie is how 9,000 even in it?
Scott: I don't even know.
Rym: I've never read it.
Scott: I've literally don't know anything about.
Scott: I feel like as a nerd.
Scott: I probably should right.
Scott: Yeah, and you know I wonder if the same thing will happen cuz it ain't even long there.
Scott: It's not.
Rym: it's like 200 and something pages.
Scott: This will be quick Yeah, but you know something interesting has happened.
Scott: my lat my previous book club bit books that were in series.
Rym: So we're real of time and I have gone on to read the entirety of all of them.
Scott: And what was the other one?
Scott: the other shattered or in cage MSA?
Scott: Yeah, right.
Rym: that is so freakin good.
Rym: So you need to read the rest of it.
Scott: I will.
Rym: it's basically Evangelion culture.
Scott: I know I will but you know I did.
Scott: Rym Immediately reads the whole series and I make the first volume.
Scott: So will Rym go on to read about Europa immediately after?
Scott: Go on to 2010 right as soon as.
Rym: even if I know one thing about Europa, I know that I should attempt no landing there.
Rym: So, yeah, otherwise If you are going to be at PAX West we're doing at least one panel.
Rym: our panel is on Monday.
Scott: so yeah, we got a Monday first thing.
Scott: as soon as packs opens panel, which is not a great time slot and Whatever, but it's in the live streaming thing.
Scott: for the first time ever They have put us in a theater which will stream live on a official PAX twitch channel Probably twitch like PAX 3 or something.
Scott: because.
Rym: so if you're at PAX I've never said this before and I'll never say it again because the reality is we video most of our panels.
Rym: But if you're at PAX, you should go to this.
Rym: So we have a loud crowd in the background for the live stream.
Rym: We don't.
Scott: but if you're nothing to be funnier if there was no crowd and I could play it up to the crowd.
Scott: And yet and the people who are why I think the few people watching on twitch should be like what the hell?
Scott: They'd see me.
Scott: be it all, you know, do my panel to nobody.
Rym: But we're gonna live stream.
Rym: So if you've never been able to see us live out of packs, you can pretend you're there.
Rym: Mm-hmm It's gonna be glorious.
Scott: You can also watch those packs channels to see everything else at PAX.
Rym: Yeah, at least everything that's in the albatross theater the Hydra theater or main events.
Scott: Yeah So we'll either be PAX 2 or PAX 3 as soon as you make it on family along with us.
Scott: Yeah in slight you'll be slightly delayed But you won't know that.
Scott: and you know what.
Rym: frankly the last few when I got that finales haven't been that great.
Scott: So no, but I'll see what else you gonna do on Monday.
Rym: Yeah, boy, you can play one more board game Monday at five o'clock.
Scott: You gonna go to Benaroya.
Scott: What you gonna do?
Rym: I mean the table tops open till seven.
Scott: No, well, we can go there right after and then go to dinner.
Rym: Yeah, maybe we should anyway.
Rym: So, let's see.
Rym: We were talking about Ruby likes.
Scott: Yeah, so we haven't played a new game recently.
Scott: So let's just pick a category of game.
Rym: I played some new games that we just Scott hasn't played.
Scott: Scott is not Played.
Scott: if you played Sanrio P cross that just came out for three.
Rym: Yeah, I know the deal with P cross.
Scott: It's a Sanrio P cross.
Scott: It's very cute.
Scott: Yeah, the first item was a was a was a ribbon.
Scott: It's how I.
Rym: uh, I know this is a slightly controversial opinion among our fans, but I am.
Rym: I do not respect P cross It's just better Sudoku.
Rym: Yeah, you're not selling me Good it doesn't.
Rym: So rogue the original game.
Scott: the reason I don't know if anyone doesn't know this But just in case there was a game way back in the day Probably older than most of the listeners called rogue same as the rogue is the D&D class.
Rym: So the genre roguelike literally means games that are like this one old be like it.
Scott: instead of calling games Platformers we call them Mario likes.
Scott: that's what this is, right?
Scott: So What qualifies something as a rogue like?
Scott: what was it about rogue that was different than other games really - it's really just two things.
Rym: well I'm sure it's interesting you bring that up.
Rym: as to the the Scotsman argument about roguelikes because there is a Concept that I've been annoyed with for a long time.
Rym: I'd look at Wikipedia to figure out the name of it the Berlin Interpretation whatever.
Scott: There's really only two concepts that make something a rogue like only two.
Rym: There's like eight listed here.
Scott: Whatever the only two that I believe in are number one.
Scott: The game is different.
Scott: every time you play this Sort of procedurally generated map some sort of you know something that mixes things up every time is fresh, right?
Scott: So imagine if you played Mario, but every time it wasn't just the same world 1-1. every time It's like completely new level.
Scott: every time that's item 1 and 2.
Scott: Is that the?
Scott: when you play the game you start at the beginning and you play until you die?
Scott: And then that's gg game over.
Scott: you have to start again from the beginning with a new game with the new map with a new World and that's what makes the game a real good.
Scott: Yeah, now what else?
Scott: what other six things do they think you need?
Scott: so first?
Rym: I would say that that's a good modern distilled definition Mm-hmm partly because there's a lot of like games that do these things that definitely feel like they're in the genre That don't do a lot of the other things most of the people who have more profound Definitions or more specific definitions are really.
Rym: I'm married to the idea that rogue is the one true roguelike and every other game is just an interpretation of this one Specific experience.
Scott: what what else?
Scott: what I think has to be.
Rym: but I think the two things you brought up What they really mean is that the game is an emergent narrative experience every time you play it Mm-hmm and that it's the journey is the goal as opposed to winning and all like the that's.
Scott: but you can't usually can't win.
Scott: I guess net hack you can get to the whatever level there are definitely like.
Rym: you can win.
Scott: like dragon crystal I guess yeah, you can win a lot of them.
Scott: But like even if you win one, it's like if you beat Mario one.
Scott: how much value isn't there playing it again?
Scott: Not much, right?
Scott: Yeah, but roguelikes like you I've beaten slay the spires a million times and I keep playing it.
Rym: Well, I dragon crystal which I never beat as a kid.
Rym: I didn't even know you could beat it until game facts existed, but because this game came out in like 1990 1991 on the Game Gear But it was a pro like.
Rym: this game is very rogue, but I never even heard of it before today, by the way It's procedurally generated, but eventually it runs out of steam.
Scott: Usually when Rym talks about Game Gear games.
Scott: He talks about a gem fire.
Rym: Gemfire is not a game of your game.
Scott: I thought what was the one you can talk crystal warriors.
Scott: I get confused cuz one's gem and one's crystal.
Scott: You come on.
Rym: There's dragon crystal and crystal warriors.
Rym: Come on, those are the two Game Gear games I talk about Dot star crystal dot star.
Scott: So Rym by all you had to do if you wanted to sell a little kid Rym a game was put the word dragon Crystal or gem on the cover.
Rym: So fun fact, this is actually a total aside.
Rym: when I was a little kid crystalis.
Rym: Uh-huh Yeah crystalis or crystalis as most kids.
Scott: Anyway, I didn't know better then.
Rym: so I had dragon crystal and crystal warriors the Game Gear and I went to the public library My family and one day in the science fiction section because there was no fantasy section I saw a novel that was called crystal warriors.
Rym: Were all these sword dudes and sword ladies decked out in crystals?
Rym: it looked very much like crystal warriors.
Rym: So I got this book.
Rym: This book was basically an erotic like thriller Bullshit garbage novel that to this day haunts me.
Scott: I mean just go to any used bookstore.
Rym: You'll find that I learned I learned things about the human body reading this book.
Scott: I hope you consulted an anatomy.
Rym: I learned a lot about crystals and heterochromia.
Rym: and this fucking book I'll make tell you what.
Rym: if you ever pick a bag book club book, that's what I'm bringing back.
Scott: I'm gonna read that book again Have to read it yourself again.
Rym: Yeah, I remember every goddamn detail of that book.
Rym: you want to talk about the hot brothers.
Rym: anyway When the game they they were enemies, but then they became friends sort of.
Rym: but then they kiss anyway, so brothers it's incest It's complicated.
Rym: Okay, it's it's.
Rym: it gets into some of that technically anime territory.
Rym: so Game gear doesn't have a lot of memory.
Rym: So dragon crystal runs out of steam and eventually it runs out of colors to use for palette swaps for all the enemies.
Rym: So in the very end of the game there's just this trophy in a room in the last level.
Rym: if you step on the trophy and Literally, it's just like yep you won.
Scott: Congratulation.
Rym: Yep, you get to go back home Because I guess you were a kid.
Rym: you got trapped in this fantasy world.
Rym: So the Berlin Protocol The interpretation of something that happened after World War two from the international roguelike development conference in 2008 That was held in Berlin.
Rym: Some people care way too much about this.
Scott: If anyone I'd be very very surprised.
Scott: if there's any attendee who is below the age of 40 and did not have a beard That was good.
Rym: Oh, this is a eunuch Santa Convention to be.
Rym: to be clear They based this set of high-value and low-value factors.
Rym: for what - what is a roguelike based on the five?
Rym: canonical roguelike games Net have rogue.
Scott: Yeah, net hack net heck Lindley's dungeon crawl.
Scott: never heard of it.
Rym: ang band.
Scott: I've heard of that.
Scott: and Adam ad om never heard of.
Rym: I've heard of Adam.
Scott: I've heard.
Scott: I think it's an acronym.
Scott: I'm pretty sure ang band was a mud though.
Scott: I guess I must be wrong.
Rym: Yep, so anyway, the idea is to determine how roguelike a roguelike is.
Scott: I mean, those are all like ASCII text games I'm pretty sure.
Rym: Yeah, so one the game uses random dungeon generation increased replayability.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, cool - permadeath.
Scott: Yeah, which true use of the two things?
Rym: I said, yeah Three turn-based as in not real time if you stop doing things the game stops doing.
Scott: I don't believe in that because rogue legacy is clearly a roguelike.
Scott: true is rogue in the name and it is a Platforming game.
Rym: so one could argue that that means that rogue legacy is a roguelike that evolved a core characteristic of the original cannons.
Rym: The game is non-modal in that every action is available to the player regardless of where they are in the game.
Scott: I think that's because like you think of a game like net hack and there's so many things you can do in that hack you Can do that at any time.
Scott: Like a net hack does like this huge list of actions right that you get just from the start and the whole game being good At.
Scott: net hack is basically knowing about all those actions But it already knows the hang.
Rym: then breaks this because of their shops or you can buy special things later in the game, right?
Scott: But yeah, I don't believe in that either because you know, even rogues are RPGs, right?
Scott: Yeah, even net hack which has this huge list of actions you can do you can't just like Fireball and net hack for the beginning you have to get a fireball spell or wanders scroll or whatever it is or learn fireball Right.
Scott: So now even that violates its own idea and because an RPG in an RPG At least not the kind of RPG you play tabletop storytelling RPG the JRPG kind, you know The the Ultima kind.
Scott: you let have a character that levels up and gains abilities and when you gain abilities you gain new actions.
Rym: So I'm gonna read the whole sentence for this next one because this one's actually a pretty interesting Though grog Nardin statement, you'll hear the grog Nardin coming out of this.
Rym: Okay The game has a degree of complexity due to the number of different game systems in place that allow the player to complete certain goals In multiple ways creating emergent gameplay.
Rym: I mean Apple to get through a locked door.
Rym: You may attempt to pick the lock kick the door down burn the door down dig under the door.
Scott: I mean, I sort of agree with that and that if you have a game where you're procedurally generating a map and you want to Replayability you need to
Rym: have a lot of systems that can interact and just let them play out the way they do
Scott: right and you Have a lot of this variance, right?
Rym: They actually give a really good example.
Scott: This is sort of you know, having Multiple, you know systems that interact in this way is sort of necessary in order to make the read.
Scott: Otherwise you would just be.
Scott: it might be a roguelike, but it'd be a really crappy boring.
Scott: Yeah, I wouldn't want to replay it again.
Rym: Well, it's made makes it.
Rym: this is more This is the door fortress thing.
Scott: even slay the spire works this way where it's like you're fighting the same bad guys But you already have three different classes, you know different cards different figure out different ways to beat the bad guys You know, so even slay the spire the deck builder has this right?
Scott: So of course, you know, but I mean you could really instead of having that huge sentence You could really just say needs to be complex enough to make real play worth it.
Rym: They do give a really good example, though I feel like I'll use this in a panel in the future.
Scott: Not the door example.
Rym: Uh, so, let's see the dev team thinks of everything blah blah blah blah Such as using gloves to protect your character while wielding the corpse of a cockatrice as a weapon that as a result petrifies any enemy that it touches.
Scott: Yeah, I mean like that kind of fortress kind gets that complicated.
Rym: Yeah, but yeah, the player must use resource as a cockatrice.
Scott: I've always said cockatrice always said cockatrice and I don't know what's right.
Scott: No Bunga At least we both agree on the cocka.
Rym: The.
Rym: uh, I think the height of this is.
Rym: I knew a kid who called the game the NES game.
Rym: Dr.
Rym: Chaos.
Scott: Dr Chaios, I want to.
Scott: I've been thinking about dr.
Scott: Chaos actually lately.
Rym: Dr Chaos has come up a couple times in my life recently like in the last year.
Scott: Let's do a stream of dr Chaos because I know a lot of stuff about it.
Scott: Oh, and then let's maybe do a GeekNights episode about dr Chaos.
Scott: cuz no one knows what we should do.
Rym: We'll sit on your couch We'll just do like you play the game and we'll just talk about it.
Scott: Well, no one knows about this game besides me and the kid I borrowed it from.
Rym: Yep I too borrowed it from a kid.
Scott: I couldn't.
Scott: I never saw it at a store.
Scott: The only reason I knew it existed is because our friends had it and I borrowed it from them.
Rym: I borrowed it from the same fucking kid Who traded me Megaman 3 from a copy of hide lied?
Rym: And then his mom came and made us trade back because apparently he was crying about it for a week.
Scott: Highlight is garbage.
Rym: One of the worst NES games ever made.
Scott: It looks like a roguelike.
Scott: I saw it in video game magazines or strategy guides when I was young.
Rym: I bought it from Funkoland for $4 And they wouldn't buy it back from me.
Scott: It looked awesome in the skin in the books But I never saw it in any store.
Scott: I never knew anyone who had it.
Scott: so I never played it and that was lucky because that means I never wasted money on it.
Scott: And then when I was older, I got emulators in like 96 7 something like that and I was like, oh my god I got every NES game ever.
Scott: Let's play hide lied and I played.
Scott: hide lied and it was fucking garbage.
Scott: Okay, so and not a roguelike but looks like a roguelike.
Rym: They argue that this I want to.
Rym: actually I've seen in a lot of these games.
Rym: There are there's multiple sets of Limited resources that you must manage to progress things like food or stamina not just hit points.
Scott: Um, I don't know if it's absolutely this is necessary But I think it does make a better roguelike.
Rym: well like even faster than light has fuel right exactly.
Scott: Oh, I think that what it is.
Scott: Is that these other these other things they've listed this beyond the core two of permadeath and procedural generation is things that make a procedural generation permadeath game good, right.
Scott: So it's like yeah, you can have a game with.
Scott: proceed, you know, just the two that I mentioned.
Scott: but if you don't have the multiple ways to solve or Resources that run out then it's not going to be very good Right,
Rym: actually, so rich Carlson one of the creators of strange adventures like you need
Scott: those limited resources of some kind Be it time or money or food art provide the pressure to push you forward into that.
Scott: permadeath Yeah is what makes you know, the procedural generator permadeath game good.
Rym: So rich Carlson called that the clock Some clock that forces the game to progress.
Rym: so Crystal had that.
Scott: Oh, thank you.
Scott: Yeah, I'll mention slay the spire again because it's the roguelike.
Scott: I'm playing the most lately.
Scott: It's real good.
Scott: You can't refill your HP very easily at all.
Scott: Yeah, like you run at you you go into a fight you lose some HP.
Scott: Good luck healing, right?
Scott: It's like I don't die.
Rym: so, you know, it's even better about that is that the decisions and slay the spire because you eat whenever you whenever you can heal hit Points it almost always gives you something you're way more interested in doing as an option.
Rym: instead It's always like yeah, you could get some hit points or I get this car.
Scott: It's like look cuz hip losing hit points doesn't met.
Scott: This is true for all games and people have a hard time understanding this.
Scott: I comes up in like every game I play comes up in netrunner It comes up in hearthstone comes up and slay the spire comes up in.
Scott: counter-strike is like hit points don't matter unless you're dead.
Scott: It doesn't matter if you have one hit point or a thousand hit points as long as you don't have zero.
Scott: So if you have an ability that's like lose ten hit points do something fucking awesome.
Scott: That is amazing as long as you don't die Right.
Scott: So like in hearthstone There's a warlock and the warlocks base ability is spend two mana lose two hit points draw a card and that is fucking incredible.
Scott: No, it's just don't die.
Scott: It doesn't matter.
Rym: You're you still win the game All right, so the so the other options here.
Rym: I know we'll just go over this quickly to get away from this Berlin thing.
Rym: Yeah, because the one thing that really stands out now that I'm looking at this Berlin thing in detail It reads I want to say like naive game design like people who like roguelikes Tried to define Basic ideas about game design, but they don't know about game design.
Rym: They only know about roguelikes.
Rym: So they describe these like over complicated things that a modern designer or Reviewer or someone who understands games with a narrow view exactly only know roguelike?
Scott: Yeah, kind of like how like training they're going to the roguelike convention.
Rym: That's true true But like you see a lot of old board games will have like rules that are written similar with similar logic and phrasing.
Rym: But games are hack and slash where the goal is to kill things and there's no peaceful options.
Rym: And actually I like this one because Dragon Crystal did this to the their unidentified items The purpose of which must be discovered over the course of the game Like a bubbly potion like things that'll have description.
Scott: I mean, that's a fun mechanic, but that's not required to be a rogue at all And it's not well like Dragon Crystal did that in the sense that you'd pick up a red rod red sword.
Rym: There's a whole set of colors and there'd be books rods swords rings that all had the colors.
Rym: You didn't know what red did and what red did was randomized every game.
Rym: Once you used a red thing, then the game would translate red into the thing, right?
Scott: It is a thing that does add to the replay value of a roguelike game, but it's that's definitely not necessary.
Rym: Yeah, so forget these stupid semi-formal definition.
Scott: I think it's I think basically what all.
Scott: the only real mistake that they made with that list is that they listed things as required to be a roguelike when most of the things except for the two I mentioned at least in my belief are Things that are simply things that make a roguelike good.
Scott: if you do them They listed them as.
Rym: how close to the original roguelikes or rogue are these games?
Scott: Sure.
Rym: Okay Yeah, so I guess it's doing what it's supposed to do, which is it's not a necessarily a measure of a good game.
Rym: It's almost like it misses the point of why roguelike is a important and interesting genre because if like for example in faster than light if I could save state I Probably would and the game would be very different because I the decisions I was making would not have the kinds of consequences And the kinds of emergent storytelling that they have when I'm playing
Scott: every time Yep,
Rym: when I play FTL and I make a narrative choice and someone dies because of it It's actually really interesting to continue and roguelikes one of the only game genres where Continuing past failure is interesting or possible.
Rym: Most games failure ends your run or Failure just sucks.
Rym: Like if someone dies in fire emblem.
Rym: that just sucks.
Rym: No one's gonna keep playing, right?
Scott: Well, I mean if you die in a game that is not Procedurally generated and you the penalty is to go back.
Scott: You have to do the same thing.
Scott: You just did again Mario you die.
Scott: It's like we'll do the same fucking thing again.
Scott: It's like that's not fun.
Scott: But if you die in a roguelike, it sucks that you're not gonna see what's beyond there.
Scott: But you don't have to do the same thing again.
Scott: You're basically constantly getting fresh gameplay.
Scott: whether you're at the beginning or the end It's just always fresh all the time, which is what makes it so addicting.
Scott: Just keep playing roguelike game Constantly without stopping right?
Scott: That's how come I can play the slay the spire every day And even though I like Super Metroid and Megaman 2 better I play them once a year every two years.
Scott: You know, there's.
Rym: I think there's actually a more interesting point there about these in terms of When you play a game that's procedurally generated you have to explore in this manner and you build this narrative up.
Rym: I still can't think of other games that Do.
Rym: they can achieve this without having people write at all?
Rym: But you can have crazy things happen or game breaking things or unbalanced things Like you might like in slay the spire.
Rym: Sometimes you get a combo.
Rym: That's just on fucking beatable.
Rym: In a normal game people would just use that combo every time now and the game is broken and dumb.
Rym: But in a roguelike because you're only gonna get that playthrough once if something's broken and a player encounters it That's just awesome.
Scott: Well, I think that's the thing that happens in game.
Scott: any game not just roguelikes that have both Complex enough systems and RNG.
Scott: right is that you get the.
Scott: if you're playing I'll just keep stick with Mario.
Scott: Right is like.
Scott: what can you do in Mario?
Scott: You can post a better speedrun You can.
Scott: you know, it's like, you know, there's only so much you can show right?
Scott: But with if you're playing roguelikes or any game with RNG and complex systems You're gonna have things happen in your games that no one else has ever encountered.
Scott: Yeah, and you can suddenly have like a nice community online where everyone posts screenshots of oh my god Check out the crazy thing that happened Right.
Scott: Look at this and people, you know, like look at my.
Scott: look at my run and from slay the spire Look at this deck.
Scott: I had holy shit Like 20 of that ultra powerful card in his deck and a managed to eliminate all the weak cards.
Scott: Yeah, but it doesn't end up being like posted like a gift the other day of like playing Thunderstruck.
Scott: But they had echo form so it cast Thunderstruck twice.
Scott: Yeah Thunderstruck did like a bajillion damage and it was great.
Scott: Awesome.
Scott: It's like I've had close to that happen But not that exact thing.
Scott: It'd be like beat the final boss.
Scott: We're playing one card.
Rym: Other genres of games can't pull that off because unbalanced broken experiences are just detrimental to the experience, right?
Rym: But with a roguelike they are literally the reason a lot of people play because people will tell those stories.
Scott: Yeah You can't having outliers of crazy weak or crazy strong outcomes in a game That doesn't you know.
Scott: have this sort of permadeath thing going on?
Scott: Yeah is real bad because those extreme outliers will become the norm Right, and so people are using degenerate strategies constantly like if it's Street Fighter There's a frame perfect input that makes you invincible.
Rym: Guess what literally everyone in the tournament scene has framed perfect input.
Scott: But if you have permadeath and procedural generation then suddenly it's okay.
Scott: If occasionally a run has some crazy weak or crazy strong Outcomes where it's the player gets to do is too weak to even get past level one just got bad luck.
Scott: They just start again big deal.
Scott: or they get so lucky and just get the perfect Stars alignment that they can beat the final boss with one card.
Scott: It's totally awesome because then it even after they beat the final boss.
Scott: Guess what you're back to square one.
Scott: It's not like you can keep that and use it forever.
Rym: Yep, and as a result also gives you That LS Metroid about cuz.
Rym: I'm really hungry.
Rym: I might as well just stop.
Rym: we've gone on for now.
Rym: Okay This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night
Rym: and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Craig Oliver Allen Joyce Rebecca done hiding me Nicola shimmering Ruby obelisk hanging in the sky kajar Tava shin my state II calm Jeremy minor link a G scooter lonely Roberto Kingsley Kelly Snyder Amanda to shed Shawn Yeager Matthew Smith Nicholas brand now, mr Strong distraction for to one creations Chris Reimer and Thomas on.
Rym: Shervin von Horrell Rory James David white Rochelle, Monta Superboy tripwire sailor Vista dodge like Jojo Joestar Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan parent drew open.
Rym: Lander Finn Chris midkiff Daniel Redmond Shawn Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas, huh?
Rym: I'm gonna leave you with something that might get stuck in your head.
Rym: It's been stuck in my head.
Rym: We'll see if it gets stuck in your head.
Rym: I'm curious if any of you recognize it.