Rym: It's Monday, June 25th 2018.
Rym: I'm Rip.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight SQL and relational databases.
Rym: because in 13 years, I guess we never talked about this.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So I think we got at least temporarily a new bit in the show.
Rym: in the beginning You know the format of GeekNights.
Rym: like we do our opening bit where we're like, oh, it's warm today rained on me I ate a taco last night and we do news Things that things of the day.
Rym: then we do our meta stuff.
Rym: Then we do the main show and then we do like the stinger nonsense I got a new bit the pub G moment because we just do we're gonna do Tuesday on pub G Might as well just hold it.
Rym: So I'm gonna just tell one pub G story because I've been playing a lot of pub G Uh-huh.
Rym: So my story is how I indirectly killed a guy in a way That was so funny that I was laughing and because I was laughing someone else killed me.
Rym: So I started like the upper right corner of this map and the circle of course is as far away as possible.
Scott: Time to run.
Rym: Yep, and I'm at this like little tiny town that's on a road.
Rym: There's no vehicles at all.
Rym: Like I figure there's no way to run there in time.
Rym: So I'm looking for a vehicle that I confirm there are no vehicles anywhere near me Except why.
Rym: so I decide to run toward this next little town and hope there's one there and if not I was just gonna die, but then I hear a noise and a dune buggy is driving from even further away Coming into town.
Rym: So I take a couple of potshots and this uh this individual instead of just driving by like a smart person.
Scott: Right because you'll die from the wall that you know, but they guess they want to get a kill.
Rym: Yep So, uh, they they stop and get out and start stalking me.
Scott: So the circle is coming.
Rym: so I take a couple more potshots and then I hide and I keep sneaking around away from this Guy and eventually I have a clear shot toward his dune buggy.
Rym: So I just ran for it and he didn't see me.
Rym: and I got in the dune buggy.
Rym: and just as I start driving away I hear a ton of gunfire and he's behind me running and just emptying his clip and missing and I left him behind.
Scott: because Kill even though it you should Game has no way of knowing that you killed that person with the wall, but I was all gets credit.
Rym: I was so happy about this that I was just sort of holding down on the road and laughing.
Scott: That didn't actually count as a kill on your stats.
Scott: No, no, no.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: I did kill two other people.
Scott: Big step up I think.
Scott: so you've killed three people.
Rym: so I've killed three people.
Scott: That's a total of two more people than I have killed.
Rym: We got to play some more.
Scott: Maybe I should just plate after I eat tonight.
Scott: I'll go home I'll eat and then I'll just play until I kill someone no matter how long that takes even if I don't go to work.
Rym: Maybe when we team up again, our new goal should just be our only goal is to kill someone.
Rym: We don't care if we make it past that point.
Scott: Yeah, they're their teammate can kill us.
Scott: We're okay with that.
Rym: Yeah, we just got to kill one.
Rym: All right, so it's a tech day.
Rym: It's not.
Rym: if we somehow kill two And then some sniper will be like what are those guys jumping around for?
Scott: but oop So I got any news on this glorious Monday, there's not a lot of Monday news, but I got this one.
Rym: So this is actually a pretty big deal.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: It's not that big a deal.
Scott: Adobe is always.
Scott: if you go look at it You know people always pay attention to Apple and Microsoft or whatever, right?
Scott: But when Adobe announces stuff, they usually announce these ridiculous features Usually that make it to Photoshop way after they announce them or other software like Premiere.
Scott: I remember when I was watching an Adobe thing a few years ago and they were announcing the ability.
Scott: in like Premiere you could like draw around a license plate in a video on one frame and to blur it out and that it would Automatically follow that license plate and all the other frames of the video and blur it out.
Scott: So you wouldn't have to like go to every single frame and blur.
Scott: Yeah, I was like.
Scott: that's really amazing that they did that and that was years ago.
Scott: So a new thing that they they announced is of course the people who made Photoshop can do this right the technology that can tell When something's been photoshopped and which parts of the image have been photoshopped.
Scott: This is actually now you no longer have to be able like I see the pixels.
Scott: as soon as this software becomes available for public Use there'll be some tools and you could just load it and be like, yep This tool says this was likely Photoshop.
Rym: The reason this is so important is that the Adobe tools and in general media creation tools.
Rym: There's sort of this.
Rym: there's an ethical dilemma where if you make certain kinds of editing too good and too accessible It makes it very easy to make convincing fakes.
Rym: that can as we saw in the 2016 election Really damaged society.
Scott: There's a lot of and the technology of making fakes.
Scott: You know, there's that fake porn thing recently where they put celebrities faces on to porn actors or even more.
Rym: What about the the audition stuff where you could theoretically have audio of someone and just change one of the words?
Rym: They said it sounds totally natural.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Now normal person thinks oh, I will use that to correct when I mispronounce that word in my podcast, but Expanding brain person says I will just use that to get people to say things they didn't say and then sue them over it.
Rym: So the technology the ethical thing to do is Expanding expanding super mega.
Scott: brain person says I'll pretend I used that technology when I didn't.
Scott: Yeah But the ethics of that kind of technology say bad things and then claim that someone used that technology to make me say bad I mean when I didn't.
Rym: how many conservatives are doing that now, but I didn't tweet that someone hacked my accounts exactly.
Rym: But The because there's been a lot of problems lately with technology being used to harm society in very direct ways.
Rym: the the ethical thing to do is as you design technology that obviously has possible nefarious uses is to Also design at the same time the technology to mitigate that.
Scott: damn if you're gonna be a mad scientist to invents a poison.
Scott: But that poison also cures a disease and doesn't kill.
Scott: people have the disease.
Scott: So we need to make this poison.
Scott: You should also make the antidote for that poison in case someone gives it to someone who doesn't have the disease.
Scott: Right.
Scott: to just make the poison only would be bad mad scientist shit.
Scott: Yep Also, don't be like a cartoon mad scientist.
Scott: We're knowing and get the antidote.
Scott: You should make the antidote more plentiful than the poison.
Rym: Well, don't be a supervillain is really the answer.
Rym: you can be a mad scientist But the situation Scott described starts edging into mad scientist supervillain.
Scott: what mad scientists are not super.
Rym: I imagine there's some okay mad scientist.
Rym: They're just mad.
Rym: They make like an apple replicator that just makes more apples and that's it.
Scott: That's not mad.
Scott: That's just that's kind of mad.
Rym: What do you what do you need that for?
Scott: Apples feeding feeding the world.
Rym: apples literally grow on trees.
Rym: We have more food and more apples than we know what to do with.
Scott: No, there's a lot of people are hungry.
Rym: Yeah, that's a distribution problem.
Scott: Not a production problem Yeah, but what if we can't put an apple tree where they live because it's not fertile But we can put an apple machine where they also?
Rym: apples are not enough to live on by themselves better than starving.
Rym: Contrary to the Disney cartoon about Johnny Appleseed apples are not alone able to sustain.
Scott: You know, keep you going long enough that you can grow something else, maybe You eat some apples.
Scott: You won't be dying of hunger immediately.
Scott: So now you can go to Maslow's hierarchies next level and start making a farm.
Rym: So in some actually pretty related news There's some facial recognition company and the CEO made an interesting argument.
Scott: I saw this.
Scott: he basically said and I'm gonna cluster a CEO of facial recognition company.
Scott: I know all about this technology, but trust what I have to say There's a
Rym: bunch of stories are in facial recognition recently again but this was pretty interesting because they got that the head of this company basically said
Scott: law
Rym: enforcement should not be allowed to use facial recognition because of the technologies built-in biases and vulnerability to abuse
Scott: Mm-hmm,
Rym: so he started making this argument that Commercial or even surveillance capitalist uses are probably okay Or at least they're neutral because they have both benefits in arms of society.
Rym: But using them for government or law enforcement purposes is way more dangerous than it is valuable.
Scott: All right, I'm gonna make an argument, but you have to promise that you will not start discussing this argument.
Scott: You will just hear the argument and the question I'm going to make and not answer it because it will take you hours.
Rym: okay in return we should do either a Monday or Thursday show in the future on the Tech transfer questions around facial recognition.
Scott: No, this is a different question, but it's not a tangent.
Rym: I'm just saying to get my promise to not turn this into an argument.
Rym: You got to give me the show at some point.
Scott: Here you have a person and you heard Scott said alright and this person owns a company and they are declining To serve customers based on the industry that they are coming from.
Scott: So we obviously think this is okay.
Scott: Yeah, and we think it is not okay to decline to serve customers because they are a certain color gender sexuality.
Rym: I'm going with this.
Rym: I won't start the argument.
Rym: I'm just gonna point out that There's a very obvious and clear line.
Rym: if where you're going is where I think you're going So what if someone were to do both?
Scott: What if a gun store refused to sell guns to white people because but used this argument instead of a discrimination reason Ah, or just freedom reason law and precedent aside answering the question you promise not to answer.
Rym: I'm not gonna argue it.
Scott: That's the end.
Scott: Go move to the next topic.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: I'll just let it be.
Rym: I got things to say.
Rym: I I will hold up to my bargain.
Rym: I'll just keep it in.
Scott: I'll keep it in.
Scott: it's hard, isn't it?
Rym: tantalizing question in Some other news.
Rym: that won't start an argument.
Rym: So I saw this trending all over the place and It won't affect me because I'm gonna buy a 4k monitor.
Rym: I gotta buy a new monitor.
Scott: But what's wrong with your monitor?
Scott: Oh the other one the one that's that one.
Scott: It's 16 17 years old.
Scott: that one Also this one.
Scott: I think I bought that in 2002. also this monitor.
Rym: The only reason it looks okay is I've turned the brightness way up.
Rym: This monitor is real old and real dim.
Scott: I was actually watching on YouTube.
Scott: It was some people who it was like people recording a radio show But they're also just live-streaming them sitting in the radio studio and around the table with microphones.
Scott: They had that monitor the Samsung 17 2x with Wow But it's got.
Rym: this monitor is from I think I bought this in 2007 this old Dell ultra sharp.
Scott: What that's the same ultra sharp I got right?
Scott: Yeah, the u2410?
Scott: Yeah, it's like the best 1600 by 1200 monitor you can get.
Rym: yep, but I want a higher resolution monitor.
Scott: now 16 by 9.
Scott: I know I'm gonna I'm.
Rym: I have to give up on 16 by 10 even though it is the superior aspect ratio.
Scott: Why I just stick with lower resolution?
Scott: Because I also why do you need so many case?
Scott: for I do need.
Rym: I need more peas.
Scott: You don't need more peas.
Rym: I need a few more peas I don't need.
Scott: you know what I've got.
Scott: I got two of those monitors right on my desk And you know what?
Scott: I'm planning to keep them for another until like everything is 4k like all the video.
Rym: Real it's because I edit a lot of video.
Rym: more peas would make it easier.
Scott: But I'm gonna buy a 4k TV before I buy a 4k model.
Rym: But also it's got.
Rym: I'm gonna take this monitor Turn it sideways stick it here and take this old Samsung monitor and give it its proper Viking burial because this thing is too old to Suffer.
Scott: don't work.
Scott: Someone can use it.
Rym: Yeah, it's got.
Rym: the brightness is turned all the way up and colors Just don't up here.
Scott: I see colors blue green red.
Rym: There are still some colors on this morning John there.
Rym: That is true.
Rym: But anyway, here's the problem.
Rym: so the without with LCD monitors you never Want to run the monitor in a resolution that is different from its native resolution.
Scott: I don't want to get into why because right there's always some other way like for example if I am Playing a game and I need to be 1080p right for streaming purposes.
Scott: I won't change the monitor to be 1080p I'll just get the game to run and 1080p full-screen.
Scott: So there's black pixels at the top and bottom.
Rym: Yeah, there's ways to get around it.
Rym: But it's old monitors actually did have variable resolution like pixels could be smaller and it would be fine.
Rym: but CRT is our ancient technology.
Rym: ready to talk about them in the modern world with an LCD.
Rym: if the resolution that your video card is sending to the monitor is not its native resolution meaning one LCD pixel equals one computer pixel Your monitor is gonna look like shit.
Scott: Well, you could use a resolution of the same aspect ratio and then it would still be one-to-one pixels.
Scott: You would just have a lot of pixels that weren't doing anything.
Rym: Yeah, well the so the well.
Rym: Yes If you also if it's if it downscales and you have a lot of blank space around it exactly There'll be a setting in your monitor for like stretch or no stretch.
Scott: You never want to stretch.
Rym: but the other problem is that even if you do that, yeah, it would be fine But then you're just wasting a whole chunk of your.
Scott: obviously.
Rym: But even if you do some perfect aspect ratio like every four pixels in the square be the equivalent It has to be one-to-one.
Scott: the resolution you're right.
Scott: Yeah, one pixel of the actually one physical pixel needs to represent one pixel in the frame buff.
Rym: Yeah, what I was getting to is that that still is not good.
Rym: So what's happening now?
Rym: Hi, this happened a while ago where suddenly everyone was making these 1920 by 20 1080 panels and that's why monitors got to the weird place They are today because it's cheaper for manufacturers of the core components to make the same thing over and over so it costs pretty much the same in the modern era to make a 2560 by 1440 panel as it does to make a 4k panel.
Rym: So what some companies appear to be doing now when they sell a 1440p Monitor is they just put a 4k panel in it and lock the firmware into downscaling Mm-hmm.
Scott: So the moral is either don't buy 1440p monitors Only buy a monitor from a high quality that you know is a high quality model.
Scott: That is the advertised.
Rym: or if you want if you actually want to buy a 1440p resolution monitor you need to do your research to confirm that the monitor you're buying has a physical native resolution of 1440p.
Rym: because if it's a 4k panel in there your monitor is gonna look like shit And you probably can't easily hack that firmware to use the rest of them.
Scott: I'm sure someone will but the point is At the you know Especially at the prospect of being able to get a 4k monitor for much less than a 4k price.
Scott: Someone will find a way to hack that firmware.
Scott: But yeah, this is why on monitors.
Scott: I never skimp.
Scott: I always tell people, you know get that fancy IPS screen get the you know, go all out.
Scott: get the ultra sharp.
Scott: Don't get that shit.
Scott: Oh crap model.
Scott: get the fancy model cuz monitors matter a lot.
Scott: That's the part of the computer actually that's going into your eyes.
Scott: You're using it the most.
Scott: it matter.
Scott: you better off getting a better monitor than a better CPU or a better video.
Rym: Like at my old job I had a generic 1080p the mouse keyboard and monitor the three most important things kind of like the computer chair.
Rym: Yeah But when I had that gennaro 1080p like monitor at work The problem was soon as I go into Photoshop or InDesign to make something Something to look fine because I just can't see the full color gamut and then I look at it on a real monitor later Or I print it and it looks like garbo.
Rym: But anyway things of the day.
Rym: What do you got for me?
Rym: I see two videos.
Scott: These two videos go with each other.
Scott: one video is actually they're from the same channel And one of them is linked as the top comment on the other one.
Scott: But we're gonna provide both links to make life easy for you.
Scott: So here's the deal, right?
Scott: There's a lot of you react videos all over YouTube.
Scott: That's a big trend and it started off as like those kids react things and it was sort of just like lol.
Scott: watch people's You know emotional face reactions when they see things like have kids use old computers lol, right?
Rym: They're usually utterly painful to watch.
Scott: Yes, but now there's actually this new genre of react video.
Scott: I don't it's not that new but I'm actually way into it because what it is?
Scott: It's have person who is expert react to thing and inform you about it, right?
Scott: So for example this one it is like this really good kpop channel.
Scott: It's react to the K where there's a bunch of students Who are students at the Eastman School of Music at U of R and they watch their classical trained musicians, right?
Scott: Attending like basically a conservatory.
Scott: that's relatively highbrow, right?
Scott: It's not as fancy as the one in New York, but it's still still highbrow and they're watching kpop videos, right and being like Oh, do you see the pentatonic thing they did there?
Rym: Oh, all right, so What is pentatonic means guy?
Scott: I have no fucking clue.
Rym: Okay, just saying move and carry on.
Scott: The here right is a same genre of video.
Scott: we have three Mario's not Mario's with their chefs from Italy from high fancy Italian restaurants in Rome, right and They're watching the top five most viewed YouTube videos about how to make Carbonara and they are judging the people who are you know, including one famous chef, right?
Scott: They're judging these people and they're like, oh, what do you put in the garlic?
Scott: Right, and then the other video is they show you how they make it The right way.
Scott: so it's really fascinating to see them.
Scott: You know like actual Italian chefs go to celebrity chef and be like, oh, what are you doing?
Scott: You don't know how to make that What's wrong?
Scott: You Know.
Scott: that also shows like, you know, you can't always trust the most viewed thing on professor you right?
Rym: Oh my god You know what?
Scott: I could have gone to YouTube and search for like how to make carbonara and in the top five videos are all Wrong.
Scott: I gotta find don't make this happen.
Rym: I want to get some filthy casual to like who's good and like you like I'd like to see a Speedrunner of Megaman to watch you play Megaman and a speedrunner of bionic commando.
Rym: watch me play bionic commando Commentate like.
Scott: the thing is I don't play Megaman 2 in a speedrun way I play in a in a. when I play Megaman 2 I play in a way that's safe.
Scott: I know that I can get really far and have a high chance of beating the game without dying Exactly in a hurry, right?
Scott: It's like I get to a hard jump.
Scott: I'll stay there.
Scott: I'll get ready.
Rym: think about it.
Scott: You know like in Mario if they go there's a big jump coming.
Scott: All right, let's get ready.
Scott: Let's get in the right position.
Scott: Okay, go right I won't just be like go go go go go except this level one.
Scott: then I go go go right because it's so easy.
Rym: so my thing of the day and Before you ask us got asked when I said this is my thing of the day if the if this lock is easily defeated.
Rym: The answer is clearly yes, because otherwise it wouldn't be my thing of the day.
Scott: Okay, so it's so easily defeatable lock.
Rym: there's this fancy hundred dollar smart lock and it's a padlock, but it's not like a Online internet of things.
Rym: smart lock.
Scott: It's okay.
Scott: You can't hack it with some Wi-Fi.
Rym: You can't hack it with some Wi-Fi or anything.
Scott: Just it's just a computer inside of it.
Rym: Yep, instead of having a combination or key.
Rym: It just has a fingerprint reader.
Rym: You can program different fingerprints into it and the fingerprint reader Not only is super reliable and they couldn't easily defeat it But even if they scratch the shit out of it, it still works fine.
Rym: Hmm, like they scratch the shit out of the reader It still unlocks only when the right person tries to also.
Scott: the actual fingerprint memory and record Detection technology was actually very high quality.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: That's not the vulnerability.
Scott: It's not a hundred percent foolproof, but it very good.
Rym: So The problem with this law?
Scott: it actually sounds really useful as like a good lock.
Scott: You can't get your combination You can't forget your key.
Rym: I'd be very inclined to get this right.
Scott: is the lock like actually Physically secure as well as as good as any other padlock in terms of you know, like being damaged by a hammer?
Rym: So it is in the sense that not physically.
Rym: to break it.
Scott: It would require a big old bolt cutters So the same as any other equivalent lock except for basically paying extra for this convenience except for one fatal flaw.
Rym: Okay, so I can hack this thing in 30 seconds.
Rym: Oh, no, so it turns off.
Scott: it turns out that the back of it Does it have a battery or something that runs out?
Rym: Well, it has a battery but if the battery runs out you just can't unlock it.
Scott: That sucks.
Rym: The battery seems to last for fucking efforts like this giant lithium-ion battery.
Rym: They're just in it.
Rym: All right, but the back Looks like it's steel.
Rym: You can't just break into it If you just put a suction thing on the back of this lock and twist it the whole back just comes off.
Rym: What's under there for Phillips head screws?
Rym: and if you remove those because the back that you twist off is how you replace the battery and then if you just open that Back take the battery out and open the for Phillips head screws You can just physically open the lock by tugging on a thing inside of it and you're done So.
Rym: you can just take the back off the lock.
Rym: Once again tech bros like to design Technological solutions that solve things but lack the basic domain knowledge of the core area From which the problem arises.
Scott: If I'm making a lock that has a battery Right, what you should do is make it so that you can only access the battery compartment if the lock is unlocked.
Rym: It's almost like a lock.
Rym: you should talk to someone who is an expert in.
Scott: you could easily made that twisty panel untwistable when the lock was locked with some sort of you know piece of metal in the way and then make it so that when You unlock the lock the twisty piece of metal on the back to access the battery compartment is now twisted.
Rym: Oh my god, so one of the first comments on this YouTube video.
Rym: now imagine if someone did this.
Rym: But instead of stealing stuff, they just remove the battery and close the lock.
Rym: Troll of the century.
Scott: Well remove the battery open the lock steal the stuff then close the lock.
Scott: The person's trying to open this lock desperately, right.
Scott: They finally go and get some bolt cutters or whatever and find a way to open it And then they open the lock and then everything's gone.
Scott: when they open it and it's already gone gone with the shit Instead of looking for a thief they tried to fix their lock.
Scott: They didn't think there was any thief involved.
Scott: They didn't check any security camera footage because they didn't think anything was stolen.
Scott: By the time they check it you're even farther away.
Rym: That's something I've learned in my entire life and it's my advice to you.
Rym: If you think you're gonna commit a crime The most important thing to know is how long all the places that have security camera footage from that area Actually keep their archives because usually they don't keep them that long.
Rym: Nope.
Rym: You got a time delay.
Rym: the discovery of your crimes children.
Rym: So in the meta moment the book club book, which might be if it is not the next Thursday GeekNights episode It will definitely be the following Thursday GeekNights episode Because we will be done within a month reading the Odyssey.
Scott: I'll have to set a reminder to read it again because basically I've only been reading it on my iPhone on the train and I Haven't been taking any trades, but if we go to the beach on Sunday I'll probably finish the whole thing laying on the beach.
Scott: I'd have to bring a phone.
Scott: I guess I'll bring my phone.
Scott: Yeah, I'm gonna bring my phone.
Rym: Phone's waterproof.
Rym: I can just bring you to the beach.
Scott: Don't?
Scott: I'd rather just not her.
Scott: Maybe I could just get away with my watch only.
Rym: I'm confident.
Rym: We'll do this soon, but We'll start the thread.
Rym: I'm gonna start poking in the forum thread and tweet and typing up some initial thoughts.
Rym: because uh, I really really recommend That everyone read this translation of the Odyssey regardless of whether or not you have read any other translation of the Odyssey.
Rym: It's great Mm-hmm in the rest of the meta moment.
Rym: the next big convention that we will be performing at is packs Wes and then PAX Unplugged And then after that, I think it's magfest and hopefully also the anime NYC Because I can take the subway to it and I seize after unplugged before breakfast.
Rym: I don't even know when they all all I know is all the panels of vision deadlines are like this week.
Rym: I'm sorting all that stuff out.
Rym: I've submitted a bunch.
Rym: I haven't run any of them by you for West but I'm sure we'll be fine.
Rym: Whatever.
Rym: I'm putting in a bunch because I figure variety.
Rym: let them pick anyway.
Rym: Otherwise, I want to call this out again because I've noticed lately a lot of people have been fleeing in particular anime forums and tabletop gaming forums.
Rym: I've seen a lot of Twitter Chatter about that and the reason that people are leaving all those forums is because most forums on the internet are full of fucking Nazis these days Because they have poor moderation or they worship at the almighty teat of free speech without understanding what that actually entails.
Rym: So I just want to remind all of you that if you're a near nerd or geek of some kind and you're listening to these Words, why would you be?
Rym: I don't know but apparently you are anyone who's still listening to this episode of GeekNights this far into.
Rym: it would probably do well to join the GeekNights community forum because We the only rule we have is you can't be a goddamn Nazi and you can't be annoying and we don't make a big ceremony.
Rym: Just if someone shitty we don't even say anything.
Rym: we just ban them and they disappear forever and you don't have to worry about it.
Rym: so if you want a community of people who are chill to talk about anime or to form gaming groups, I Can't think of a better one than our own forum.
Rym: Like I'm not even joking.
Rym: Mmm Boardgame geek doesn't really have the Nazis like a and n does but even then board game geek I would not for me.
Rym: I mean it just has you know, grog nard misogynist I would not form a gaming group from the board game geek forum is all I'm saying.
Rym: That's right.
Rym: I would not advertise where at a PAX I am hanging out LFG in that forum.
Rym: No, but I would do that in the front row crew forum, which is our forum Mm-hmm.
Rym: And also if you don't feel like you have a lot to contribute I say join anyway, because you know people don't realize how many lurkers that forum has.
Scott: It has a lot of lurkers like.
Rym: it's terrifying.
Rym: But if you post in the GeekNights forum You probably get more readers than your actual blog.
Scott: a lot of people like use it as their blog and like start a thing Like, you know a lot of people have threads that are like only so and so cares like only Scott cares and they post about a thing all The time and even though they're the only one posting in this thread using it like a blog People are reading it.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: I have proof.
Rym: I Mean, I'm just looking at like the the things of your day.
Rym: thread has like 35,000 views and like 2,000 pose.
Rym: There's people in here and they're all cool.
Rym: Cuz if they're not cool Scott or I just banned them and you'll never worry about them again, oh And uh, we're not there obviously, but as GDQ is happening right now Yep, and I'm just gonna watch it all on YouTube as they get uploaded.
Scott: cuz I watch some live-action.
Rym: I've been too busy I've I?
Rym: the nature of having changed jobs is that I do.
Rym: it's interesting.
Rym: I do less like Work, like I'm not Designing you eyes anymore Like I'm not.
Rym: I'm not looking at an API and trying to do a proof-of-concept like I'm not doing that type of work anymore But instead I have to.
Rym: all my work entails talking to people Talking to people making powerpoints and then presenting them to people and making decisions
Scott: So
Rym: I don't have as much time to sit at my desk and like idly consume something while I work on something I spend all my time literally like going to a meeting being the adult and after people plead their cases to me for an hour I say this is what we're doing.
Rym: That is the decision and that's all I had to do.
Rym: So yeah, I'm gonna watch YouTube streams instead of the live stream.
Rym: So, uh, yeah, we somehow did an episode on fucking no SQL.
Scott: Well, cuz that was the hot thing.
Scott: It was.
Scott: it was actually a funny article today.
Scott: Someone wrote and they were like blockchain 2018 no SQL.
Scott: Yeah, that's right that's accurate.
Rym: yeah, yeah, so we're gonna talk about relational databases.
Rym: I don't think we're gonna get to do like.
Rym: you're not gonna learn from this episode Whether or not you should use MySQL or Postgres.
Scott: as far as you write all that matters to you is as for most people They're the exact same goddamn thing with slightly different user interface.
Rym: So I guess what is a relational database compared to all the other ways you might store data Start babies first.
Scott: So you are gonna make some software right and you got it.
Scott: You have some data and you want to store that data Somewhere where it doesn't go away.
Scott: when someone closes the program it opens it again.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Now if you just put it in a fucking file Yep, if you're using Python you could just like what pickle dot IO.
Rym: There's other ways to put stuff in a file But you could like serialize it into an object and like write it to a file system somewhere, right?
Scott: There are a lot of ways to put things in a file But the problem is when something's in a file, it's not that easy to work with that data, right?
Scott: It's like you can't easily if you want to search your file for things.
Scott: or let's say you got like a list of names And you want you know, it's like that.
Scott: that's hard to do.
Rym: I'll put it this way the thing that put the data in the file is usually the only thing that can really take the data out of the file and If there's any question about how you're gonna use that data the people who wrote the thing to put the data in Have to deal with that.
Rym: so like what if two people are gonna try to write to the file at the same time?
Scott: you have to what if you want a bunch of different programs to all share the same data and You know like you've only got one file in the file system.
Scott: You can like synchronize this file.
Rym: like what if the data you want to store is four thousand terabytes of data, right?
Scott: So this is what a database solves.
Scott: now the thing with a relational database, right?
Scott: It's like well, what's what's relational about it versus other databases?
Scott: Well, imagine you got yourself a spreadsheet, right?
Scott: And this spreadsheet has a bunch of columns name spreadsheets already Revolutionized like data in the modern world like spreadsheets are a big deal name phone number address Whatever, you know all the data, right?
Scott: And you can certainly got a spreadsheet.
Scott: well spreadsheets you can search spreadsheets You can sort spreadsheets you can filter spreadsheets you can write functions against them You can make reports you can put math in the cells You can do all kinds of stuff in a spreadsheet.
Scott: The problem is if you get lots and lots of data suddenly spreadsheet gets really really big.
Rym: I was all show on my desktop at work.
Rym: So I was doing a little like some really simple data analysis.
Rym: It has like 900,000 elements right now.
Scott: imagine sometimes, you know spreadsheet gets lots of redundant data.
Scott: For example, let's say we were gonna make a spreadsheet of Game collections right now.
Scott: It's one thing.
Scott: Normally if you're just keeping track of your normally as it normalized People who would put a game collection in a spreadsheet are just keeping track of their own game collection.
Scott: Yep, so they just they only one sheet they could just have.
Scott: you know name of the game, you know, what year it came out Who designed the game?
Rym: No, this is fine because say if I'm the only one using it It's just like the file thing we talked about.
Rym: spreadsheet is just fine But if I change my schema, like I want to add another column, I'm the only one using the spreadsheet.
Rym: anyway It's not gonna break anything because it's my spreadsheet.
Rym: I know what I did to the data, right?
Scott: And it's only.
Scott: but now let's say you want to have a website that lets everyone keep track of their game collection.
Scott: Well, so suddenly you got a spreadsheet and column one is you know name of the game and column two is name of the person Who owns it?
Scott: Alright, so I own a copy of Puerto Rico.
Scott: now Rym also owns a copy of Puerto Rico.
Scott: So now in the next row, it's like well, it's Scott, Puerto Rico.
Rym: Then it's Rym Puerto Rico, but both Rym and Scott Puerto Rico have to have all the information about Puerto Rico, right?
Scott: It's like well, we're you know, suddenly it's like Scott, Puerto Rico Made by Andrea Seyfarth came out in whatever year it was, right?
Scott: And then suddenly we're repeating all this information about Puerto Rico and we're repeating all this information about Scott every single freaking time.
Scott: Well a relational database is basically a bunch of spreadsheets except you can link from one spreadsheet to another.
Scott: so we can say Scott Puerto Rico and that Puerto Rico is actually a link to another spreadsheet that has all the info about games.
Scott: You have one spreadsheet with all the people one spreadsheet with all the games and then we have a table that links the people to The games.
Scott: so now we don't have to repeat ourselves Right, and if we update say that if Puerto Rico changes its name to a different game We can change that and it changes for everyone.
Scott: We don't have to change out for everybody We just change it one place change for everyone because it's just a link.
Rym: now the problem this solves is primarily around data integrity In that now you understand like you basically put rules around how data is related to other data and You can enforce those interactions.
Rym: You can react to those interactions you understand them and You'll never get in a situation where the data gets out of sync.
Rym: The detriment of doing this is that it does reduce the performance because if I want to do a query against this data now I have to hit look at all these different tables.
Scott: If you want to say right if you want them together, right?
Scott: It's like oh, I want to get a list.
Scott: So we've got one table.
Scott: This is a list of people.
Scott: when I want spreadsheet That's all people and one spreadsheet.
Scott: That's all games.
Scott: And now we want to say All right Give me a list of every game Scott owns.
Scott: Well, we got to get the Scott row from the people table and then we got to look at this other in-between table and figure Out okay Well, which games is Scott own?
Scott: get all those from the game table and then mash them together into one new spreadsheet And then we'll actually deliver that.
Scott: and that takes CPU.
Scott: the CPU has to do a bunch of work, right?
Scott: Normally if you just had spreadsheets you had to do any work.
Scott: you just look at it right now.
Rym: one reaction to this problem was no sequel which we've talked about.
Rym: Another reaction to this problem is you might hear people who are more database II talking about Normalizing a database.
Rym: or do you normalizing a database?
Scott: That's just about you because you have to make decisions about where are we gonna break apart?
Scott: Sometimes it's obvious people games.
Scott: So when you're actually doing real-world work It's not so obvious which spreadsheets to make and which ones to link.
Rym: Yeah, like you might think logically make sense to split it up a certain way but your user might not be a human.
Rym: your user might be some UI on a web page somewhere and the Kinds of questions that UI is asking might not map to what you logically think of the data as so.
Scott: over time People took this multiple spreadsheet database idea where the sheets linked to it.
Scott: They're called tables on by the way.
Scott: Yeah, no one calls them spreadsheet.
Rym: We're certain babies first But I promise we're gonna skip from that to the rid the modern usage of day.
Scott: So here's the modern usage.
Scott: right is basically over time this basic model of having Tables that link to each other to store your data.
Scott: They added features and they added features and added features and added features to where know it?
Scott: how you're gonna manage this Software with all these features they've added is a job in and of itself.
Scott: Yep Indexes.
Scott: they've added sharding.
Scott: they've added master-slave configurations and replication.
Rym: they've added transactionalism Atomic updates.
Scott: It's like there's just so views and triggers and fucking stored procedures The bane of my existence a decade ago.
Scott: They've added so many goddamn features to these things special kinds of columns that Searches, it's like the amount of features that have been added to databases.
Scott: It's any.
Scott: it's good that these features are there because if you're making software that uses one of these databases You don't need to reinvent the wheel because the database probably already has the feature you want.
Scott: You don't have to code it again.
Scott: You're to code a search because the database has a search.
Scott: Just need had to learn how to access that search function.
Scott: It's already in the database.
Rym: so without getting into the details of all those things the real gist of this is that the place you use a relational database today is when you have a large amount of Structured data that needs to be accessed by multiple different actors.
Scott: Well, I mean even if you're used just having something that only needs to be accessed by one actor Oh, yeah, you have added h2.
Scott: or if you had structured data There's a thing called SQLite which is a really it's.
Scott: you would not believe how often this thing is used.
Scott: You probably have like a hundred instances of it running on your computer.
Scott: Yeah You don't even know about it Like every browser uses it to store like your cookies and shit and like it's everywhere just hidden.
Scott: It's SQLite and what it does is it runs a relational database Inside of a file.
Scott: it so it lets people who are coding code with SQL just like they're using a relational database Except instead of having a server and all this multi-user stuff.
Scott: It just saves the whole database in a file and it's really small and fast.
Scott: So if you're ever writing like a game and you want to have a database in the game and it's just a single-player local game Like a phone or something use SQLite.
Scott: your phone probably has like a hundred SQLites are running like it's a better question.
Rym: that is What.
Rym: what are the benefits of relational database overall?
Rym: because it mostly comes down to like we said data integrity.
Scott: Alright, so the first benefit is basically that it's so used.
Scott: right.
Scott: my SQL Postgres MS SQL.
Rym: anyone who knows the basics of technology and has worked in technology knows SQL enough to write a select state, right?
Scott: So SQL is basically this language the structured query language and you use it to communicate with these databases.
Scott: You can use it to make tables, you know change.
Rym: This is important because in theory you can write the same SQL queries Against a database.
Rym: It doesn't matter what the thing is.
Rym: It's querying the database.
Rym: The idea is that any application any programming language?
Rym: You could literally be chiseling ones and zeros onto a stone and then reading them in.
Rym: somehow SQL is SQL.
Scott: the problem is a big asterisk.
Scott: at the end I like I've written the same SQL.
Scott: that's worked pretty much exactly the same with Postgres to my SQL.
Scott: There's obviously some differences but MS SQL.
Scott: I just I've had to do some of that recently.
Scott: Yeah, it's like I tried to do.
Scott: just select star limit a thousand which means select everything from this table.
Scott: Only show me a thousand rows though in case the tables too big.
Scott: I don't want to see all the rows.
Scott: I just want to get a sampling right and nope in Microsoft SQL.
Scott: It's select top 1000 star from now the way around this.
Rym: in the modern world if you're doing a big database really is that usually your applications?
Rym: Especially if it's like a UI in the web or something.
Rym: They're not like actively making raw SQL queries every time you do something.
Rym: Usually there's some middle tier in the way that presents API's and on the back end of those API's are well formatted highly optimized SQL queries.
Scott: Anyway, so SQL is this language.
Scott: I highly recommend anyone who does technology work.
Scott: You should learn it.
Scott: if you don't know it already learn the basics of it.
Rym: I don't care if you know like how to do a left out Go to terminal type SQLite.
Scott: It should show up.
Scott: It's almost guaranteed to be installed.
Scott: If it's not, it should be easy to install.
Scott: It's free.
Scott: It's open source.
Scott: and then just you know do I think it's slash question mark to bring up the help or dot help or something like that?
Scott: to bring up the help and just start reading and then get a little SQL guide and like a SQL babies first and Make a table and then like select fill the table with people like and names and contact info and then like Get all the people who live in New York or something like that, right and just learn the basics.
Scott: and it's really.
Scott: it's like plain English.
Scott: It's not something that's like select star from cities where right city Something select name phone number from contact info where state equals, New York.
Scott: It's like, you know That's literally what you type in and then it will select the names and phone numbers of everyone in that table who lives in New York.
Scott: New York in the state column.
Rym: So another big advantage of relational databases is the fact that they you sort of Intrinsically set up your cardinality as in how your different pieces of data relate to each other.
Rym: This is that question.
Rym: Like well one Scott can have many games but many games can only have one.
Rym: Scott like those kinds of questions it forces.
Rym: Does your design to address those questions?
Scott: Right.
Scott: So as you're designing your database, you know You answer all these questions and then when you're actually making your application your database will prevent you from messing up right.
Scott: even for things like okay, I've decided that names of These things cannot be longer than a hundred characters.
Scott: So that column in that in the database only supports a hundred characters and then someone tries to type one in.
Scott: that's 101 characters.
Scott: They didn't.
Scott: they mess up the validation on the on the form on the website and someone types in something's 101.
Scott: It won't get inserted in the database.
Scott: They'll be an error.
Scott: Yeah, right it forces you to stick to all your rules.
Scott: You if you make it so that you know Each person can only you know own one game and you try to add another game to a person.
Scott: It won't let you.
Scott: Right, you know your data structure is like set in stones.
Scott: You have all these rules and you're prevented from breaking them and that's actually a good thing.
Rym: Now one thing that a lot of people seem to mess up is Whether just because you have a relational database doesn't mean that it's necessarily acid compliant.
Rym: And even if that database could be acid compliant a lot of default settings will make it not compliant Yep.
Scott: So even when things are as a compliant people still have timing issues and stuff.
Rym: So I had to look it up because I never remember fully what acid stands for but I know what it is.
Rym: Do you remember?
Rym: because I just pulled it up.
Rym: I forgot the what the I make.
Rym: Yep Consistent consistent the I is the one I forgot.
Scott: item potent isolated isolated and durable.
Rym: But here's what this comes down to.
Rym: there's two fundamental ways to set up your database in this regard.
Rym: So say I am adding Scott to some like I'm making a big update where I'm gonna add Scott and I'm gonna add a bunch Of games to Scott.
Rym: Let's say that in the course of adding Scott I fail.
Rym: But then all my things to add games succeed like I put Scott's name in wrong.
Rym: So now I've got all these games that I added but they're referencing a key that doesn't exist.
Rym: There's no Scott.
Scott: That's no good.
Rym: So Atomicity or at atomic operations is the idea that you chunk several related Operations into one transaction and if any one of those steps along the way fails You back out the entire change.
Rym: so you can never get your database into an inconsistent state.
Scott: you group a hundred commands together into one big chunk and it starts doing them in order But if at any point it fails it can undo all of them and go back to where it started.
Scott: Also, let's say I'm in the middle of doing these hundred things and I'm like I'm at number 50 and things are going along nicely and someone else comes along and does a query because it's multi-user, right?
Scott: Yeah, someone else comes along and ask the database or something.
Scott: They won't see any of the 50 things that happened already.
Scott: now there's.
Scott: They will not be able to see those changes until they are all done 100% and then they're locked in.
Scott: and then from then on anyone who queries when I'll see all those changes.
Rym: Yep now that's both isolation and consistency and actually the isolation part gets really fascinating like here's that we'll go a little deeper into how this stuff
Scott: most of these things happen because you have multiple people working on the database if you ever had multiple people working on a Google sheet at the time with those little colored boxes.
Scott: But imagine if you're all working in Excel and someone just saves the fight you somewhat.
Scott: you both open a spreadsheet at the same time On your computers you save it to the shared directory and then someone else doesn't load in your changes.
Scott: They just save right over and blew it all your work away.
Rym: now Arguably that was solved by web dev.
Rym: but whoever fucking got web dev door.
Scott: No, this is salt, right?
Scott: This is why use a relational database and not a spreadsheet, right?
Scott: Yeah, like an Excel spreadsheet Spreadsheets are for accounting and math.
Scott: They're not for data.
Rym: but here's an example of two ways to handle that situation.
Rym: and this is where not every like databases are complex enough.
Rym: now to where if you're gonna use one if for real and It's not just like a local tiny embedded database that only your application is using like a real big iron shared database You should have someone on your team who is a database expert because this stuff gets real complicated in a hurry.
Rym: So there's there's a bunch of ways to handle that situation where multiple people are working with the database.
Rym: So one way is locks say I am reading it.
Rym: I have a query.
Rym: I'm asking the database a question in the middle and see my question takes 10 seconds to answer.
Scott: Well, it's a long time.
Scott: Yeah, four seconds a problem benefits.
Rym: Scott tries to make a change to the database.
Rym: So one way to handle this is that until my my select query is done the database tables I'm querying from our locked.
Rym: Scott's change just gets queued up.
Rym: You can't make the change till I'm done asking my question because otherwise I might ask for the 50 states and It just gives me Rhode Island back.
Rym: Scott inserts March and then it gives me smarts back and then Scott realized the smarts was wrong And remove smarts and I get more or fewer results than I expected.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Things could go real south in a hurry.
Rym: Yeah, but the problem with locks are that your database's performance is now garbage.
Scott: Yeah Everyone's just said everyone's trying to use this database all at the same time.
Scott: They're just waiting like you have a computer Trying to write a comment on a blog post.
Scott: You got to wait for everyone else's comment.
Rym: Yep, you know what?
Rym: It's like if your database is now boo and every time you look at him.
Rym: He stops moving.
Scott: Unless you're the only one looking at him then he'll open his eyes for so in isolated and consistent way to do this.
Rym: and this is how I back when I did some database administration, which was Before 2008. at this point so a decade ago with Postgres you can set up concurrency and clever locking.
Rym: so an example would be every time I start a Select query the state of the delve all the tables that I am looking at is almost Snapshotted and saved and its own copy.
Rym: So my query even if it's long-running can finish Against the state of the database as it was when I began my query.
Rym: if Scott makes updates He's making them to the real database, but I won't see them because his updates were after I started my select Mm-hmm.
Rym: That means Scott can write to the database all he wants while I'm reading But you can imagine there are ways for that to go south to Every.
Rym: the query makes its own snapshot of all the tables that can add up in a hurry and cause its own performance problems.
Scott: Alright, so this brings to another thing which is okay.
Scott: You've got this system that's being used by a zillion people and we've solved all these problems so they can all use it But even though we've sort of made it possible So that the data won't get messed up or anything like that or no one has to wait.
Scott: It still takes a lot of computing power to do all this, right?
Scott: So there's a lot of the things that are features of relational databases are things to just improve performance and you might not even know They're there right.
Rym: cashing indices multiple indices Pre-calculated results tables, right?
Scott: So indices are like the most common one and it's basically an index is Basically a fancy like lookup that lets you know It's the way the data is that because the data is in the end still in a file somewhere on a hard drive, right?
Scott: Even though it's not a file.
Scott: It's like a fancy server that's in between you and the file.
Scott: It's still a file or files right on hard drive somewhere where the data is.
Scott: So the index is basically a fancy thing that helps it search the data faster.
Scott: It's sort of like okay a man, you know.
Rym: It's like look at the index of a phone book and it tells you what page to start looking for a phone number on right?
Scott: It's like so if I say, you know select from the table all the you know, the names that begin with B It's like aha.
Scott: Well, I know it doesn't have to look through every single frickin name and the whole million row table.
Scott: It can do it a lot faster because it has this index files that it built and keeps updated as the data changes so that It can execute the queries faster by referring to these lookups to begin with.
Scott: Yep So another big thing which is related to a Rym is talking about before is you know, you have so many users.
Scott: your computer You know that's running the database is even though it's really not finely tuned.
Scott: You only have so much CPU so much RAM.
Rym: you want to distribute that shit across a bunch of computers.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: You got to get more computers in the mix.
Scott: You get a one database running on many computers.
Scott: that way you can get more users because you know back in the day what people?
Scott: Would do is they would just get a bigger computer.
Scott: and that was a strategy.
Scott: You know why that was the strategy.
Scott: that was the strategy because Microsoft Windows cost money.
Scott: if you had Microsoft Windows and MS SQL Server and you wanted to get two computers You had to buy licenses again, and they weren't cheap.
Rym: now like Oracle and people they link it to CPU cores for their licenses.
Scott: Right, and it's like.
Scott: well that you know.
Scott: Oracle also get to buy more Oracle.
Scott: You have to give them more money when you want to get more computers in the mix.
Scott: Well, guess what Linux?
Scott: it cost zero dollars right?
Scott: Postgres and MySQL are free unless you get the paid MySQL Which you don't want.
Rym: yep and Postgres like.
Scott: honestly Postgres is better than MySQL and it's free I've been using.
Rym: I used Postgres before.
Rym: it was kind of super production ready.
Rym: Postgres is like the one to use if you don't know what you want to use.
Scott: Postgres and MySQL are super production ready But if you're a database nerd, you'll hate MySQL and like Postgres better, but there are big-time companies using MySQL super well.
Scott: So the thing is is basically MySQL is a little bit more user-friendly.
Scott: if you're just setting up a blog Probably just go with that and then if you're doing anything serious, you better not use MySQL.
Scott: if you're a bank Don't use MySQL.
Rym: So in the old days though to get it back to Scott's distributed model Yeah, distributing a database was a giant pain in the ass.
Scott: Oh huge pain in the ass.
Rym: like to get a distributed Postgres set up.
Rym: good God We ended up in MySQL.
Scott: actually made it a little bit easier before Postgres did but now Postgres also makes it.
Rym: Postgres has this stuff built in but it used.
Rym: I used to have to do stuff like Put the binary transaction logs of Postgres on a DRBD volume and have that Replicate to another place and have a post grab another Postgres running in read-only mode.
Rym: that happened to also look at that day.
Rym: It was a mess.
Scott: So what most people do and what's sufficient?
Rym: We don't even tell you what I did for MySQL back then.
Scott: what's sufficient for most applications to have a master slave set up?
Scott: So way this works.
Scott: is you have one server that runs a database normally.
Scott: Then what you do is that server whenever it receives instructions to add data It will send those instructions to other computers also running the same exact database.
Scott: So you go to the the master and you say insert a new person into that table and it does and then it tells this Other computer hey insert this person into that table.
Scott: Okay, but that other one the slave right the the poorly named slave database Doesn't accept inserts or updates or data change SQL statements from anyone except that master database.
Scott: if you tried to go there and insert it would say sorry I can't answer I can only select.
Scott: Yeah, so that way now you can write all your applications To where.
Scott: when they need to read data or select from the database They make their selects on one of your one or more of your slave databases And then if they need to insert they send it to the master.
Scott: and now All the inserts go to one computer and all the selects go to all these other computers.
Scott: this those slaves might fall a little Like a few seconds behind the master one so you might have some data timing issues.
Scott: a lot of times you'll have a situation like you go insert and then immediately select and The thing you just insert it isn't there.
Scott: yet That happens a lot.
Rym: There's clever ways around.
Scott: there are a lot of clever ways around it, but that's not a scope for this.
Scott: Yeah the point is is that when you have this kind of setup a lot of Selects will actually use a lot of computer horsepower.
Scott: if they're complicated and Net you're be preventing people from inserting when you make those selects.
Scott: now They have people inserting all day because that's real easy to insert.
Scott: It's always real easy to insert.
Scott: It's like takes almost no computing power to insert unless you've got stupid indexes that are busted Or you've got long running stored procedures for some reason don't do that Right, and now people can select freely and if they tie up a whole computer selecting no big deal.
Scott: We got like a hundred slaves, but this only solves the problem.
Rym: where you have right few read many Architecture in your actual application.
Rym: Yeah, if you're if you have a lot of things all trying to write to the names database at the Same time this doesn't help you at all.
Rym: Oh and The solution to that are actually way even more complicated.
Scott: most applications are right few read many.
Scott: That is true, right?
Scott: You got a blog.
Scott: you got some website.
Scott: How much writing is going on?
Scott: How often do you update the website with a new blog post once a day, right?
Scott: How often do you read?
Scott: you got a million people coming to read the website.
Rym: a guy use case.
Rym: I've seen though for the situation.
Rym: We have a lot of things.
Rym: writing is usually around Disaster recovery failover environments where you want to have a hot hot system Yeah, where your primary and your backups are all hot and can be used as production at the same time.
Scott: Yep, if any if you're mad Slave goes down.
Scott: Well, you have a hundred computers or however many usually you don't need a hundred.
Scott: I'm just making up a number.
Scott: Usually it's like master and a couple slaves and that gets you a big.
Scott: that gets you a lot of users when you just have that many.
Scott: It's like oh one went down.
Scott: Well, we have a full copy of the database and the same exact software running on all these computers.
Scott: Just make another one be the master now and fix the master that broke.
Rym: but I guess well say in terms of that failover Disaster recovery thing is that hot cold is real easy to do with relational databases.
Rym: Hot warm is actually really easy to do in terms of right access Hot hot where both sides or you know end sides can all be have inserts running at the same time.
Rym: It's not hard to do anymore in the sense that a lot of databases have functions to do this built-in.
Rym: like you guys It's a configuration challenge in the old days.
Rym: It was nigh impossible the way I did it 20 or 15 years ago and you should not do it this way is.
Rym: I had to my sequel databases.
Rym: one of them It's indexing.
Rym: its indices were hard-coded to increment as Even integers.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: And the other one was hard coded to increment increment its rights with its indices odd numbered integers.
Rym: So there could never be a conflict if you wrote to either one and they both had binary transaction logs pointed at each other.
Scott: Do not do that.
Scott: No, so that does remind me.
Scott: There is the thing that's very popular these days when you get really massive, which is called sharding.
Scott: and when?
Scott: You do a sharding right.
Scott: it's like okay, it's like an MMO is actually right Right sharding is sort of what MMOs do.
Scott: Yeah, it's like, okay.
Scott: Well, we've got this huge database, but you know, it has like all the names of all our users.
Scott: But you know what?
Scott: We don't really often have to search through all the users.
Scott: most of the time We're only searching through a subset of the users divided by say region, right?
Scott: They've got.
Scott: the US office is only really searching the US users and the Europe office is only searching the Europe users.
Scott: So, you know what?
Scott: Well, it'll still be the same.
Scott: We still want to combine everything because occasionally we do want to just search everything But most of the time we're like 90% of the time.
Scott: We're only searching one section, right?
Scott: So what we'll do is we'll take the database and we'll chop it up.
Scott: Well, even though it's the same table We'll put all the US users on this server the Europe users on that server or you know You might.
Scott: how you divide it depends on your application.
Scott: right you to divide by you know region?
Scott: you could divide by Alphabetical, yeah, you divide by all sorts of things whatever makes sense.
Scott: Writing say website like reddit you might divide by subreddit.
Scott: It's like all the data for this subreddit all the comments all this stuff is in this database server and all this other subreddit is On this other database.
Rym: I read it a problem once with sharding or it was a. we were doing effectively sharding.
Rym: This is that two jobs again.
Scott: But now all the queries related to one subset of your application go to the same place and now you can balance the load.
Scott: Really popular subreddit while it gets its own database server.
Scott: all these unpopular ones.
Scott: We can all cluster them together on the same server.
Rym: So we sharted market data like market data from the stock market based on The alphabet like the letter that the ticker started with.
Scott: so all this all the stocks that begin with a or on the server All the ones begin to be around.
Rym: Yeah, that was fine.
Rym: Except that s was a problem.
Scott: Yeah, no You just you know.
Scott: I'm saying you had to give two servers to s and you can put qz and whatever all on the same server together.
Rym: Yeah, but sharding requires you to analyze and understand the usage patterns of your database.
Scott: This is why you have that person at your company.
Scott: Who is the database person?
Rym: There's a reason why you can get a degree in database Administration person if you.
Scott: if they do they'll just know to do some sharding.
Scott: They'll know to optimize some indexes.
Scott: They do all these things on the database server and all the people using the database Don't even know that any of this is going on.
Scott: all they're doing is connecting and typing SQL and the results always come back and they don't know.
Scott: any of this stuff happened because Abstraction layer going on right and but meanwhile you can have so many more users so much more reliable data So much more safety for the data.
Scott: Nothing will happen to it.
Scott: They'll always be safe and all these great things happen completely behind the scenes.
Scott: So that's why people use databases.
Rym: I spent a decade and not an excels administering databases in the course of my work and I'm glad to never do that again.
Rym: I will just share an anecdote from when I went to RIT.
Rym: I was a pre freshman and I had to decide what major Like am I gonna do IT or am I gonna do computer science or all these things and even within IT?
Rym: Now they've changed it They've split it out more but IT had all these different concentrations and one of the things you could focus on in IT Was database administration and the way database administration.
Rym: because IT you had to take classes in every discipline And then from there you'd pick a few specialties.
Rym: so we had took our initial classes on like database administration and they told us in every one of these classes if You specialize in database administration.
Rym: You will make a shit ton of money immediately out of college and I heard that I Understood that I took my database classes and I said that ain't worth it and I didn't want that money.
Rym: so I don't know if you necessarily want to be a database administrator because you will be a database administrator forever if you Get really good at it.
Scott: A lot of people who were previously database administrators are now like calling themselves things like data Scientist or you know things like that.
Rym: They do not want to optimize your Postgres database.
Scott: Right, you know this or like, you know information something something Like all these kinds of other, you know adjacent.
Scott: Yeah, you know like, you know, they're trying to you know, be like I'll be like a machine learning person.
Scott: They're trying to move away from.
Scott: you know, I'm an information manager or something, right?
Rym: Unlike a lot of things if you want if you want to learn database administration and you can't afford to go to college Databases are some of the most well documented things there are.
Scott: and free Yeah.
Rym: You can download Postgres run it on a Linux box professional enterprise quality level database the documentation.
Rym: That's free Documentation super detailed super good.
Scott: You just become a Postgres master all on your own and then easily make jobs and money.
Rym: I think you could learn Database administration on your own on the internet for free easier than you can learn most programming.
Rym: Yeah, probably Yeah, just the resources are more consistent.
Scott: SQL is Is pretty solid and it's the hard part really is learning just the fundamental concepts.
Scott: Yeah, and not because the documentation is mostly gonna tell you like here's this command Here's what it does and you might not understand all the language in the documentation.
Rym: Blah blah equals foo insert foo come in.
Scott: You might need to get like a book with an animal on it to talk about, you know, the the general like, you know Scope of things and you can literally vocabulary and then everything else will be easy.
Rym: But I guess the experimentation and like the practical knowledge is way easy to learn because kind of like a Python interpreter You can literally just log into your database from a command line and start asking it questions.
Scott: There's also tons of free GUI tools.
Scott: You can use to look at your database like it's a spreadsheet.
Scott: You don't have to even learn how to use.
Scott: You know the command line, right?
Scott: You can just use the GUI and type your stuff in there.
Rym: My real advice to you is don't use a no sequel solution unless you understand They're pretty much dead.
Rym: unless you understand why you can't use an acid compliant real relational database, right?
Scott: You'd be surprised.
Scott: like it the relational databases.
Scott: The SQL databases are so flexible.
Scott: You know that it's like almost every application out there can is like you can use one.
Rym: Well, the worst case is when you see people implement a non-relational database and then over the course of building their thing end up Reinventing acid, right?
Scott: It's like.
Rym: reinventing acid is like a thing that people do.
Scott: It's like using, you know.
Scott: Sometimes people use UDP instead of TCP because they need the performance and then they really meant TCP, right?
Scott: And they re-implement TCP only do it if you're re-implementing part of TCP Not all of TCP.
Scott: if you re-implemented all of TCP and UDP you should use TCP to begin with.
Scott: Yep, if your UDP is it your.
Scott: you know layers on UDP have made it so slow that it's not faster.
Scott: You wasted your time, right?
Scott: So yeah But you know if you're making any software at all and you suddenly Realize I need a place to store all this data and I might want to search it.
Scott: Just pick a relational database.
Scott: use SQLite if you only if it's a local one person application and use MySQL or Postgres if it's a multi-person application that has a server and Just start from there and only change if you absolutely have to and you're smart enough to realize it's not work.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night and the patreon.
Rym: patreon for this episode of GeekNights are Craig Oliver, Ellen Joyce, Rebecca Dunne, Heidi McNicholas, shimmering gruby obelisk hanging in the sky, Kajar Tovashin, MyStady.com, Jeremy Minor, Link Eiji, Roberto Kingsley, Kelly Stoder, Cold Guy, Amanda Duchette, Sean Yeager, Matthew Smith, Nicholas Brando, Mrs.
Rym: Trunks, Rachan, 421creations.
Rym: No, I never ever wonder why we're here.
Rym: semper-fi bitch, Shervin Van Horl, Rory, James David Wright, White, Rachelle Montanona, Superboy, Tripwire, Sailor Vista, Don Schleich, Joe Shiro, Joe Starr, Clinton Walton, Ren from New Zealand, Ryan Perager, Open Liner, Finn, Chris Midkiff, Daniel Redmond, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer, and Thomas Hahn, and now I leave you with.