Rym: It's Monday October 1st 2018.
Rym: I'm red.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight the scary tale of single sign-ons.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: We periodically better.
Rym: We've tried to be spooky on in October because I told Halloween's gotten really big on the internet in like the last eight years.
Rym: Yeah, like bigger than you bigger than it might have previously been and I gotta dress up my Twitter avatar soon.
Scott: Yeah, so, you know back in August it was sort of like hey, let's go, you know, let's go to the baseball game.
Scott: It'll be super cheap.
Scott: the Mets stink.
Scott: They're already out of the playoffs effectively.
Scott: Yeah You know, let's just go we'll get a hot dog.
Scott: All right, we'll have a good time Whatever.
Rym: so it was be fun.
Scott: bought some tickets and the tickets were whoa $40, which is a lot of money to seal stink.
Scott: Oh Mets in the second last game of the season Were they okay seats though?
Rym: No, you're in like the back corner.
Scott: No, this is like get into the secret club seats cuz that's It's the isn't not so secret club, but it's like there's an area with like couches and stuff.
Rym: I was about to say I would not pay $40 to sit like on the upper upper deck.
Scott: Yeah I think it's actually more like $2.
Scott: sit up there.
Scott: So back in August I buy these tickets and we're looking.
Scott: we're like when should we go?
Scott: How about the second last?
Scott: I was like, well the last game of the season.
Scott: That's a novelty, right?
Scott: There'll be all sorts of like seasons over stuff, you know, it's like a you know thing, right?
Scott: And I'm like, wait a minute.
Scott: if you go on the last day of the season, which was Sunday yesterday because we stink We're not the playoffs You get a fridge magnet calendar of the 2019 schedule.
Scott: They figure out the schedule, I guess a more than a year in advance Which other sports don't do.
Scott: but I was like, wait a minute.
Scott: if we go one day before that It's a night game and there's fireworks.
Scott: Let's do that instead.
Scott: So we had game tickets for the Saturday night, right and then like a few weeks ago It's like this announcement, right?
Scott: It's like Oh David Wright who you probably don't know who that is.
Rym: No, I'm not.
Rym: I've never really been a Mets fan until I moved here.
Rym: It's amazing.
Scott: So David Wright is this guy who played third base for the Mets for a long ass time, right?
Scott: I don't think he played for anyone else and he because he played for the Mets for so long Even though they never won even though occasionally did good and he was.
Scott: he wasn't like this incredibly good player.
Scott: he was well above average, but not like legendarily good, but Played for the Mets for so long.
Scott: He's got like all these Mets like batting record The most hits of any met, you know the right and all this thrice.
Scott: He's like one of the best players.
Scott: the Mets have ever had most strikeouts as a man.
Scott: All these right, he's like.
Scott: he's like the captain of the Mets but for the past like two years or so He's been basically so injured that he's unable to play.
Scott: So he's just been.
Scott: he's still.
Scott: he's still mad but he's wasn't on the team.
Scott: he was elsewhere.
Scott: This year.
Scott: he was clawing his way back up like in the minors after sort of recovering kinda but they announced like oh, yeah All right, his career is over.
Scott: He's gonna retire, but he's gonna come back For like a week, but he's only gonna start in one game.
Scott: and lo and behold that happened to be the game That we already had tickets to.
Scott: we do one game.
Scott: We bought tickets With the fireworks.
Scott: the second last guy didn't make it the last game in the season.
Scott: second the last game I don't know.
Scott: That's the day he chose.
Scott: So, of course what we thought was gonna be like an empty ballpark Chillin eating the hot dog was crazy crowded with all sorts of ridiculous ceremonies All kinds of nonsense all kinds of people.
Scott: I could have sold the tickets actually made a bunch of money.
Scott: But you know, I wanted to see some fireworks eat a hot dog.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, that was your utility right, so Meanwhile we go in this game and I'm like, oh, you know the night market which is just outside at the Science Center?
Rym: Oh, yeah, I never go to.
Scott: that nightmare ends at midnight.
Scott: I'm like and it just started again because it closes during the US Open.
Scott: they can't have it then right.
Scott: and I'm like, ooh, this game is gonna end.
Scott: We're gonna go.
Scott: there was zero zero until the game went to like the 13th inning.
Scott: And I'm like at what point I've never been in a game with that many innings.
Scott: I've been to a doubleheader, but that was nine and nine.
Rym: I mean I was at a hockey game that had two OTS that I've been to 10th inning.
Scott: I may have been to 11th inning.
Scott: I've never been to 13th inning and it's late at night and I want to see this fucking.
Scott: normally I could just gone home But there's fucking fireworks.
Scott: Then I paid to see.
Scott: So I'm like waiting.
Scott: I'm like at what point is it?
Scott: Like, okay, this game is a too long.
Scott: I like it a game to end.
Scott: I'm gonna go home early, but at one point is it like well, it's the 18th inning.
Scott: This is legendary.
Scott: I'm just gonna stay here and maybe the Sun will come up.
Rym: I feel like there's a there's a. there's a graph you can make of how excited you are about overtime and it starts to drop Off for a while eventually.
Scott: I don't like.
Scott: I don't like a shootout in hockey which starts this week, by the way.
Scott: Yeah, pug night but You know, I appreciate the game ends.
Rym: I can go home Like when we went to that first packs and we're at the concerts and we're like super excited.
Rym: They're gonna go till 2 a.m It's gonna be crazy.
Rym: And then 1 a.m.
Rym: Rolls around and we're fading.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: But anyway What was even worse is not only did I wait for all those innings then the fireworks come and I'm like, okay I expect there to be like a real fireworks show like the ones I'm used to right.
Scott: It's like paid for by Verizon.
Scott: They got money, right?
Scott: I figured they're gonna shoot fireworks off behind the stadium and we're gonna you know, boom boom, right?
Scott: No, no, no No, that's not what happened.
Scott: So they come there's a bunch of people open a hole And out onto the field.
Scott: they wheel out like these these like little like boards On wheels and there's like maybe seven of them and they arrange them in a circle with one in the middle and I can see You know like a more Fireworks.
Scott: mortar is like a bowling ball Ball candle.
Scott: they're big.
Scott: They're you know, at least bocce ball size, right?
Scott: They're not small.
Scott: I Look at these platforms.
Scott: They got there's not a lot on them.
Scott: Like they don't look like there's any You know actual like large mortar launcher Devices on there.
Scott: They look more like the pyrotechnics you see on like a stage situation.
Rym: Was that just the mortar tubes?
Rym: They were very far away.
Scott: No, they're not that far away.
Scott: We were pretty close.
Scott: Yeah, great seats because we bought the ticket so early to a stinky team Before the game became a big deal.
Scott: No, none of the fireworks for the kind that go up and then go.
Scott: boom It was basically all Roman candle like but that I would argue that is not fireworks.
Scott: I would say it just went And then they all disappeared.
Scott: Yeah, there was no boom not one boom.
Scott: and the whole thing It was only pyrotechnics that went up and also laser light show and they also had them on the ring.
Scott: Yeah, laser light shows roof of the stadium around the edge.
Rym: laser light shows were cool up until about 1985, right?
Scott: So it was uh, and it was it was like a. it was like a sing-along firework where they played many musics.
Rym: That is not my kind of firework.
Scott: And then the other thing that bothered me a lot is like all throughout the game and including the The fireworks show, you know, they couldn't for some reason They just couldn't play a song.
Scott: like every song Had to be like they had to switch the song so quickly and they would combine songs.
Scott: and it's like they couldn't just play a song.
Scott: It was it was you know You know, yeah, I don't know like, you know, there's the you know CNC music factory.
Scott: everybody dance now.
Scott: and then there's that other song that every stadium in the world uses since for the past However many years with the everybody clap your hands, right?
Scott: Right exactly even Rym knows it right?
Scott: They couldn't do that.
Scott: They had to go.
Scott: everybody clap your head.
Rym: That almost that reeks of someone trying too hard.
Scott: They were definitely trying too hard the whole time.
Scott: They were not.
Rym: It's like the version when you're driving who's messing with the radio and they change.
Rym: they listen to a song for like a minute And then they change to another song and anytime they played a song They did not play a single song on its own.
Scott: It was always a portion of a song cut to at least one other portion of another song.
Rym: I wonder if they didn't actually have all their rights set up for the music.
Scott: Also, all the music there is you know, non analog not like when you go to the garden ism the organist.
Scott: Yeah Which is vastly superior Appreciate the organist when you don't have it.
Rym: Yeah, I appreciate both the organist and the fact that there is still no mascot at the New York Rangers.
Rym: It'll remain that way.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Mr.
Scott: Matt was okay.
Rym: I guess he's got a good head anyway, so what he got in the news?
Scott: So there's this thing called photo Kina which happened I think in Germany.
Scott: pretty sure isn't German.
Scott: Anyway, photo Kina is basically like the e3 of cameras.
Scott: if you're a photography video person like that's where it's at.
Scott: It's pretty much just expo Hall.
Scott: It's mostly for the media as a person.
Scott: There isn't really a reason to go there You know, but if photo is your number one thing then I guess it's worth it to go there.
Scott: I you know, I guess it'd be the packs of you know They have.
Scott: you know All the companies set up also like things like interesting environments to shoot cameras in so that you can have fun taking photos I guess whatever.
Scott: So there are many news is there and since you know, we don't care too much about photography Let's go through the biggest only the biggest big ones quickly, right?
Rym: Yeah, because you care about twice as much as I do, right?
Scott: So Panasonic which we care about because I have all micro four-thirds cameras and Olympus are like the micro four-thirds Kings, right but Panasonic has announced that they're putting out a full-frame camera in cooperation with Leica and Sigma.
Rym: Oh, I actually saw this news in multiple independent channels on my own.
Scott: So it's a three company Cooperation to make this L mount right with a full-frame mirrorless camera.
Scott: now before Photokina Nikon and Canon pretty much, you know numbers one and two up there with Sony the big three, right?
Scott: Canon and Nikon both announced full-frame mirrorless cameras because right now Sony is basically the king of the full-frame mirrorless.
Scott: All right, if full-frame means that the sensor is as big as actual 35 millimeter film Photos would be like meanwhile like.
Rym: but so I have a gx1 and then I bought this new camcorder.
Scott: I got four thirds is like a quarter of the size.
Rym: Yep, and my camcorder is its big deal Is it has a one inch sense even smaller than which is smaller than both of those, right?
Scott: It's even smaller.
Scott: But yeah, so basically now because Canon and Nikon announced before Photokina they're getting in the game Everyone's got full-frame 35 millimeter size sensors on mirrorless cameras doing 4k video and photo and everything.
Scott: So it's gonna be this huge battle.
Scott: It's like well can Sony hold on?
Scott: Can Canon and Nikon with their existing, you know, you know rain over the photo world?
Scott: Can they?
Scott: but can they come in and can have this merger of three companies together?
Scott: Right - you know that are pretty big and serious.
Scott: Can they you know, can they be the king?
Scott: So it's you got four different mount lens mounts to choose from and we'll see which one is the winner.
Scott: right because the only thing that the The you know the Panasonic that we use in terms of being a you know An SLR style looking camera that shoots video.
Scott: The only reason it was Inferior to say the Sony is the sensor was smaller.
Scott: Therefore the light sensitivity was less and therefore the autofocus is worse, but in all other ways it was perfect Right, so we'll see.
Scott: who can you know?
Scott: Be the king of all these things now.
Scott: There's a four-way battle and not just Sony holding on to everything.
Scott: Yep In other news, there's some weird company.
Scott: this is like a big deal right because Leica who makes basically if you don't know like it is a company that Makes cameras that are like ridiculously overpriced because of the brand name sort of like designer handbags, right?
Scott: They're like tens of thousands of dollars, but you can get a better camera cheaper from someone else.
Rym: Like they're not bad.
Scott: cameras cost way too much Dollars, I mean you're getting.
Scott: it's sort of like buying a. you know a Ferrari about a camera, right?
Scott: It's not a bad guy.
Scott: But one of the things about Leica is that they make one of the only Full frame digital rangefinder cameras like.
Scott: the only one is the Leica M for a zillion dollars, right?
Scott: You can't really get one from anyone else, but now zenith some weird It seems like like is even Collaborating with them in some way.
Scott: zenit As made.
Scott: it's some Russian company.
Scott: They're making an M mount, you know camera.
Scott: Oh, no, is that the L mount?
Scott: Oh, it might have the L mount.
Scott: I don't know the point M with the L mount.
Rym: Yeah, L mount like a kebab a blood after announced pen.
Scott: the point is it's the only non.
Scott: like a camera.
Scott: That is a rangefinder style camera That's digital camera with a full-frame sensor on it other than the Leica M and is supposedly.
Scott: I'm sure it'll still be expensive But it will be cheaper than the Leica M which is crazy expensive.
Scott: If anyone wins a lottery feel free to buy me one.
Scott: And then you know people are like well micro four-thirds that's gonna be dead.
Scott: now, right because you know Panasonic is Olympus didn't make any announcements and Panasonic is joining this other thing.
Scott: Yeah, right is the?
Scott: is micro four-thirds gonna die?
Scott: Well, in case you thought it was gonna die, they're making a 10 to 25 millimeter f1.7 lens Which is the maybe the fastest zoom lens ever made and that's a micro four-thirds lens.
Scott: So if anyone wants to buy me that it'll probably be $2,000.
Rym: that'll probably cost as much as my entire camcorder.
Scott: Yeah, feel free to send me one of those.
Scott: it's coming out.
Scott: And the only other big news is that Fuji, right?
Scott: I have an old Fuji film camera.
Scott: It's the G. What's it called?
Scott: It's like the.
Scott: It's like the the six by nine and basically it's medium format film, but you shoot basically a you know normal two by three aspect ratio image Which is like takes up twice the normal space when you're shooting like, you know squares We know those people shoot on medium format Alright, so you can take half as many photos and it's like a giant rangefinder camera.
Scott: It's enormous, right?
Scott: Awhile ago Fuji came out with medium format.
Scott: They're like fuck you full-frame 35 millimeter.
Scott: We're going medium format digital I. but that camera was insane.
Scott: price You know, but now they have announced a rangefinder style.
Scott: it's not actually a rangefinder because you can't see through it It's just a. you know, they just position the viewfinder in the corner, but it's a medium format digital rangefinder.
Scott: It's insane.
Scott: It's like the GFX 50 ours.
Scott: I can't even like.
Scott: That's like, you know, the film one that I have was like super cheap on eBay because it's a film cameras.
Scott: It does not even take batteries.
Rym: Well, I mean click right.
Scott: I think it's just a lens and a box and it's huge.
Scott: This is digital and it takes pictures as big as Right.
Scott: It's like holy shit.
Rym: Well, there's definitely I think like there's only really three markets for cameras these days.
Rym: There's cell phone camera, which is what most people will use for most photography forever.
Scott: Now a cell phone camera is better than most cameras.
Scott: So in order for it to be worth it to buy a camera that is not a phone Yeah, it has to be an insane camera.
Rym: So market number two for real cameras That normal people have no business using because they don't need them for the kinds of pictures They're taking.
Rym: and then there is a middle ground and I've seen this partly because of where I work.
Rym: I hear a lot of the ads that are targeted at older people.
Rym: there are a lot of people who just don't understand how to use their phone cameras mostly because they're old and They buy these digital cameras that are one click with no buttons on them And there's still a thriving market for those.
Scott: Some of those are really good too because you know It's not better and better enough than a phone camera exactly.
Rym: But there's basically like if you took like my old gx1 and just put it in like auto auto auto the most auto mode.
Scott: Right, there's one more thing.
Scott: This is really fascinating.
Scott: for a long time Various companies tried to put out Android phones mostly Android phones because you can't make an iPhone that had insane Cameras on the back.
Rym: even the one I bought is like.
Scott: the big part of its advertising was the crazy Look at like the Panasonic like cm1 The ones that have like that little lens they have like a big-ass zoom lens on the back of your phone, right?
Scott: It's like it's like a actual serious camera with a giant lens.
Rym: Yeah You don't need.
Scott: many companies have tried to do that and it's always failed.
Scott: because who wants to carry around this big stupid lens in The back of your phone all the time, right?
Rym: Just see when you take a picture to be really good granted Even though I see so many people now sticking those giant suction pucks on the back of their phone to hold it easier I don't understand those.
Scott: Yeah Tried them out and someone was like, oh it'll change your life.
Scott: Once you try it, you'll understand.
Rym: Yeah, I can't put my phone in my pocket anymore.
Scott: Yeah, I took it off real quick.
Scott: Anyway I'm gonna.
Rym: I can make some GeekNights ones though If you guys want them.
Scott: Zeiss who makes great lenses announces a zx1 full-frame compact.
Scott: So this is a camera.
Scott: You can't change the lens.
Scott: No, it's a compact camera, but it's full-frame.
Scott: So like whoa, it's gonna take crazy good pictures.
Scott: It's a crazy good.
Scott: lens is 35 f2 which is a lens that you can use.
Scott: basically that's like the perfect all-around lens.
Scott: And This camera is really interesting because instead of being a phone With a big-ass camera attached to it that you would carry with you everywhere this is a camera but on the back of the camera is Basically a computer that's running Android and you can have light room Mobile lightroom installed in the camera.
Scott: Hello, that's great.
Scott: That's like fantastic.
Scott: I can't believe that's like the greatest.
Scott: I don't know why other companies are still using.
Scott: they're like very limited.
Scott: You know camera OS is and firmwares when you could just be putting Android on the camera and just have everyone have all the photo apps in their camera.
Scott: I don't get it.
Rym: No, it'd be extra nice.
Scott: This is the greatest.
Scott: why isn't?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: I've taken this long for even one company to do it.
Scott: I feel like this should bet should be the default that would.
Scott: that was established five ten years ago.
Rym: I have to use it though to see like how well the pipeline works because I'm assuming there's no special features of that OS Things like setting up Just like having an Android phone.
Scott: only it would only have Photo apps and like that.
Scott: when you turn it on the camera app is automatically open Yeah, and it's just photo library and photo editing apps and nothing else.
Scott: No other.
Scott: no web browser Right, you know, but it would still have like Wi-Fi stuff, right?
Scott: So you still upload you would still do all in all the features of those photo apps would be there But nothing else.
Scott: what you don't need web browser on there.
Scott: I guess you could have the web browser on there, but you would never use it.
Rym: Yeah, I mean it's hard to see the market of who would actually use that Because I really wanted to use like my nice monitor and my big screen when I mess with my photos And if I'm on the go, I really don't do anything to the photos.
Scott: I'm sure this thing won't be the cheapest.
Scott: I'm sure it'll be probably You know thousands of dollars because it's a got it, you know, really fancy, you know, it's a full-frame sensor Yeah, and it's a really crazy good lens.
Scott: But this would be like if you were going to if you wanted to buy a camera to carry around with you every day To use for every day better than cell phone.
Scott: photography like this would be a great candidate.
Scott: or wait for version 2 of this.
Rym: Yeah, I feel like wait version 2 or at least wait for reviews is gonna be the key here.
Scott: Yeah, but you know, it looks like that's crazy good.
Rym: So in some other non photography news if you didn't notice Facebook had a Security breach.
Rym: dun dun dun and Every day as more information has come out.
Rym: It's actually gotten worse and worse.
Rym: Like what.
Rym: this is actually a really really big deal And it's relevant to the main bit of the show because a big part of why Facebook breaches are such a problem.
Rym: on one hand you've got people putting tons and tons and tons of private information in there and Just having it available for whoever's gonna hack in and steal it.
Rym: But to a lot of people a lot of organizations a lot of schools a lot of like local government shit.
Rym: Use Facebook single sign-on.
Scott: Yeah, like you'll go for I only use it I think with Spotify.
Scott: So when I go to Spotify instead of having to remember my Spotify password I can just push the blue button that says login with Facebook.
Scott: Yeah logged in.
Rym: now I can't say like oh, I don't have a Facebook account Which I don't.
Rym: so this doesn't affect me because I do the exact same thing with Google Like.
Rym: I use Google single sign-on for almost every account I have.
Scott: I use it in a few places.
Rym: Almost everything I do as uses Google single sign-on at this point is Spotify.
Rym: I have a standalone account because I'd still don't have a Facebook account, but basically this vulnerability I didn't read all the full details yet But it looks like the access tokens that would be used for like an app or another application to interact with your Facebook account Were able to be collected and/or stolen and then used later which already implies a pretty serious But fundamental flaw in their model.
Scott: and even worse is Oh off doesn't have that fly.
Scott: I figured it was just Oh off though.
Rym: Apparently I was reading Oh off has a few flaws as well.
Rym: I found a bunch of articles implemented correctly.
Scott: Oh, yeah, I mean people implement, you know things incorrectly all the time You know, it's like oh, yes my oh SSH that I wrote is flawed.
Scott: Yeah, that's open.
Scott: SSH implements it properly.
Rym: Well, it's like the people who said oh PGP is broken.
Rym: No, PGP is not broken.
Rym: Just PGP with mime in your email client is broken.
Scott: You know that particular PGP software that's called PGP is broken.
Scott: That doesn't mean that the RSA algorithm of making public and private keys is broke.
Rym: Yeah, well you have to kind of like goes back to the fundamental point that most issues with security come down to either Something is implemented improperly compared to even like basics documentation or just bad operational security Like someone writes their password down somewhere or tell someone their pin on the phone.
Rym: But basically anyone who used this vulnerability, which it's not clear if and how it was used I would not be surprised if it had been used by say state-sponsored actors quite a bit considering all the things happen around the election and Facebook and everything.
Rym: but basically anyone who used this on your account could then use that to create or sign into accounts on anything else.
Rym: that's using Facebook single sign-on.
Rym: and Furthermore it appears based on some articles I was reading that Facebook doesn't even have Logging of when these tokens are used if the sessions are short meaning less than a half an hour or an hour or so.
Rym: so Basically, we don't know and may never know how widely this was used and it is a super super egregious security flaw Mm-hmm, so what can the average listener of GeekNights do to prevent this from happening other than just not having a Facebook account?
Scott: Delete your Facebook.
Scott: Yeah, I mean the only reason I have a Facebook account is because there's still like a GeekNights Facebook page And I'm not sure what will happen.
Scott: Like if I like my account is the only one has permission to like to handle it.
Scott: So, I don't know if it happens if I delete it.
Rym: The problem is even those fake pages like not every person who friends or whatever that page.
Rym: We'll see every update on that page because of Facebook's weird money.
Scott: Yeah, I know I don't use Facebook that much but it's like, you know, I have the account.
Scott: the stuff is set up.
Scott: I just sort of that's it.
Rym: I'm curious.
Rym: What's the difference between that much and just delete it?
Scott: Well, it's not it's just.
Scott: it's basically holding the account is basically holding the pages.
Rym: Yeah, but I mean like personally like your personal Facebook account.
Rym: What do you do with it?
Scott: Some I read other people's Facebooks.
Rym: Oh, why a little bit see I just avoid even that.
Scott: Hmm Some people there's some idiot friends of ours who keep posting their stuff there instead of Twitter.
Rym: Yep I continue to try to force those people to just email me or use Twitter or I think the thing is like they're posting their Things.
Scott: they're not because they're they're posting them there for their biological families to see.
Rym: yep, right at least I've seen the perception like definitely people younger than us do not trust Facebook and do not Use it and it's the old person social media network.
Rym: So I feel like this situation is going to over time correct itself.
Rym: Hmm, but yeah almost everyone I know who posts a lot to Facebook is doing it because they know other people who are incapable of using modern social media Usually like old relatives like even my brother like he's not on any social media, but Facebook.
Rym: So like I never see what he's up to unless I just call him and it's kind of weird.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: But anyway things of the day.
Rym: So have you ever played Mario the paper Mario the thousand-year door?
Scott: the best Mario RPG maybe even one of the best RPGs there is?
Scott: it's bad fight me on this.
Scott: It's better than Mario RPG and SNES.
Scott: It's even better.
Scott: I mean not that these games are bad.
Scott: mom saying is that Mario RPG and SNES is a good game.
Scott: Right Mario Mario and Luigi.
Scott: that series especially the first one on GBA Those are good games.
Scott: thousand-year door is even better than those games.
Scott: That's how good it is.
Scott: Yeah, if you haven't played thousand-year door on the game of cube play that shit.
Scott: It's even as a as a game that is like a JRPG.
Scott: It is still playable by old man Scott.
Scott: Never come out on the switch cuz I should probably play it.
Scott: I never.
Scott: actually might have to like pay and maybe it'll come out and if you like buy the online service.
Rym: cuz In the online service, they'll just borrow your old GameCube.
Scott: you you could.
Scott: I have.
Scott: I don't have a GameCube.
Scott: I have a Wii that plays GameCube discs.
Scott: Oh And I have the disc.
Rym: What'd you do with the GameCube?
Scott: It's gone gone.
Scott: You go.
Rym: Did what happened?
Rym: Did it die?
Scott: I think when I got the Wii, I think I just left it somewhere.
Rym: I Still have those two NES is up there.
Scott: Now.
Scott: One of those is my childhood.
Rym: Yes Yeah, the other one is the one that we won at Ohio con 2002 in the duck hunt turn.
Scott: It's neither.
Scott: one of those are your NES.
Rym: Well the one I won the tournament.
Rym: So one of those is my NES And my other NES from when I was a kid, my brother has it still.
Rym: But if you played this game There is a giant bomb guy who has a happy-lucky lottery.
Rym: We can buy a lottery ticket.
Rym: Someone Strider 7x.
Rym: I think we featured him before on GeekNights went through 13 minutes of explaining in detail how this lottery works and how Specifically it is rigged.
Rym: and basically to win the lottery in Mario thousand-year door you have to play the game for over a year of real time and Then you have to talk to that guy on the specific day between 335 and 390 something days after you bought that lottery ticket.
Rym: and if you talk to him on that day That is the day you will win.
Rym: and the four numbers They show you are random numbers and the whole system is rigged in a really like interesting and oddly specific way.
Scott: Yeah, that game even though it's like this, you know I just played it from beginning to end and only got extra stuff that was easily accessible That game has a surprising amount of like.
Scott: if you want to keep going replay value There's an area where you go down a pipe and fight some guys And then it keeps going down like you just basically just like it's a lot like the the tower of enemies
Rym: Yeah,
Scott: or you know or like get backers the anime
Rym: what?
Rym: I'm surprised did not remember.
Rym: get backers even existed.
Scott: You know, it's just like.
Scott: it's just like a tournament you go in the pipe You fight guys until you lose.
Scott: if you lose you get kicked out at the beginning But if you keep winning keep going down the pipes.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Anyway, so yeah, if you watch this You'll know to never buy that stupid lottery ticket.
Rym: because then and he also catches if you change the date to win the lottery Because when you change the bait date back the dude freaks out.
Rym: it makes you buy a new lottery ticket for like 500 gold anyway.
Scott: So check this out.
Scott: here is some sort of festival in China somewhere where they're playing some sort of flute a weird-looking flute that's fat on one side and One of the people who I think supposedly is maybe the organizer of this event is playing the flute Upside-down backwards.
Scott: You're supposed to play it with the fat end near your face.
Rym: There's a moment where she makes eye contact with guy next to her.
Rym: He keeps looking at her.
Rym: I don't know if he's trying to like.
Scott: hey, so I the.
Scott: the story that I was told I don't know how true it is is that she didn't want to like ruin the performance by like flipping it around.
Scott: You know like disturb the thing.
Scott: so she like oh, yeah, the guy like starts gesturing gesturing to her like hey, right?
Scott: So the guy tries to correct her.
Scott: like hey flip your flute around and she's like no, I don't want to.
Scott: And this is basically the story of my life and where I'm the guy Right like when you're biking over the bridge, and you're like hey young child Who's having trouble struggling up this bridge.
Rym: if you just change that gear to be an easier one this will be no problem.
Scott: Hey person who's obviously stronger than me and going slower than me Why?
Scott: but it's like hey kid who just ran into that goomba right?
Scott: This is like press a if you are wondering right as a as a recovering mansplainer If you're wondering where mansplaining comes from there is definitely mansplaining.
Scott: That is just outright.
Scott: You know You know like you're telling wrong things to people or or you know the other kind vice You're giving is an excuse to harass specifically or the kind where you're.
Scott: you know there's the kind where someone's wrong like where they go To the woman scientist and like oh, yes, did you know this and this?
Scott: it's like yes, I invented that Right.
Scott: does that mansplaining which I was not guilty of in the past?
Scott: at least I hope not too guilty.
Scott: But there is this kind where it's like you see someone doing something wrong.
Scott: right man or woman or other gender the key Objectively wrong.
Scott: exactly what I'm saying.
Scott: right.
Scott: you see someone doing something that you think or know is objectively wrong.
Scott: They could be doing better right.
Scott: not even just doing something completely wrong like this But also doing something in a not as good way like maybe they're cutting something with a knife And you're a knife master And you want to show them your knife skills and help them out.
Scott: or maybe someone's holding the chopsticks wrong And they're getting food in their mouth, but you're like listen.
Scott: They got to be parallel don't cross the sticks Right.
Scott: and it's like you.
Scott: on the one hand It's like you don't want to be some joke going around telling people how to live their lives But on the other hand you see the frustration of this dude looking at this woman playing this flute upside down.
Scott: That is the feeling that I have.
Scott: That is why it is so hard to not mansplain even when I know what it is, so I watched a dude Yesterday, I was doing a long run.
Rym: I ran over the Queensborough bridge And there's a dude who was Near the top like walking his fixie up because he couldn't ride it up and the pedals were moving.
Rym: it's a full-on fixie.
Scott: He knew it was a fixie.
Rym: yep, so he's walking it.
Rym: He's near the top and he's about to get on it to ride down.
Rym: So he passes me.
Rym: cuz he starts riding down And then I see him like force himself to a stop and get off and have to walk it down Because it was going too fast and the pedals were gonna start hitting him.
Rym: so his his bike due to his Choice in what kind of bike to ride prevented him from both riding up and riding down hills.
Rym: yep And yet he persists in riding this bike.
Scott: I mean was it a flip-flop hub?
Scott: you could have helped him by flipping his rear wheel around to the to the pretty confident That anyone who has a fixie bike has no idea what that's for.
Rym: I feel like they have never flipped their tire.
Scott: I've seen a lot of bikes.
Scott: They'd have the flip-flop hub.
Scott: you can just flip the rear tire around backwards.
Scott: It's real easy because there's no gears in the way.
Rym: I know, but I feel like You're freewheeling based on fixie people.
Rym: I've talked to.
Rym: it's still too much complication.
Rym: I Suspect that extra gear on the other side is just aesthetic.
Rym: yeah I know, but anyway in the meta moment the GeekNights book club book is still Homer's Odyssey Still not updated.
Scott: the website actually was.
Scott: at the other day I was like oh, I should do that right now, and then distracted and then didn't do it.
Rym: Yeah, we did previously talk about the Odyssey And we're done.
Scott: the last book club book was Homer's Odyssey.
Scott: in our current base book club book is Arthur C. Clark's Space Odyssey 2001.
Rym: it's getting cold.
Scott: I'm gonna be reading a lot more books.
Rym: I'm gonna read this pretty quick.
Scott: I've actually read a whole bunch of fantasy books as I'm trying to read all the books on my shelf And I have a digital copy of 2001. so it's not.
Scott: it's not something That's dying to like get off my shelf and out of my apartment.
Rym: lately my commutes is so short that I don't really read On my commute, so I only read when I'm sitting down like it's time to read.
Scott: I've been reading more and Watching crappy Korean TV less.
Rym: Oh, that's good.
Rym: That's good, son.
Rym: The problem is you could replay.
Rym: you could.
Rym: instead of watching crappy TV less and reading more you could watch crappy TV less and watch All these great animated shows that are coming out that we just talked about because we judge the upcoming season of anime.
Scott: Yeah, I'll get that video out soon because the next anime season starts in like a week the fall season.
Scott: we we judged again We'll let you know our complete guesses based on almost no information and even less knowledge about what those shows are gonna be like.
Rym: the most important thing I can say though is that The surest indicator that a show is bad is if it is based on a role-playing game or MMO of any kind.
Scott: Yes, that is you gotta know.
Scott: the upcoming season of anime is mostly shows based on MMOs and JRPGs.
Rym: So yeah, otherwise we talked about this.
Rym: We didn't do the show on Thursday because I've been busy and it's gonna take me a while to sort out the pipeline to make This work because it's the most complex Thing we've ever tried to set up to do on an ongoing basis as GeekNights.
Rym: But basically we're gonna try out a few different shows like different like maybe Thursdays to start an Alternate format for GeekNights and I know you're thinking this is crazy.
Rym: You've used the exact same format for 13 plus years and the answer is yes.
Rym: It is crazy.
Rym: This will probably fail.
Scott: We're gonna try to do a show.
Scott: that is the same format as like sports talk radio where you talk and then some crazy Kooky listener calls it and then you shut them up and then you talk some more like yeah the Mets are bums.
Scott: Hey, we're gonna hear from Joey Jojo and we lost the first game into the season.
Scott: trade everybody.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: We're gonna use that format only we're not gonna talk about sports.
Scott: You're gonna talk about nerdy shit.
Scott: Yeah, and the problem we're just gonna get some sort of technology system Whereby the listener can be that jerk who calls in and we let him talk for like 10 seconds now.
Rym: I cannot understate the complexity of this because get some maybe use discord or something.
Rym: This is the first time for GeekNights.
Rym: We've needed a PA like a production assistant because someone has to talk to the listener and figure out if what the listener is about to say is stupid.
Scott: and Figure out if they're actually gonna come on and say the thing that they said.
Scott: they're gonna say Yeah, I'd say, you know something stupid.
Rym: We need a mechanism to take the Masses the howling masses of people trying to say things and pull one out into a separate private Solo channel and have their audio come into the stream alive.
Rym: So I'm probably with delay, yep, I don't know.
Rym: I could set up a delay circuit But I'm not gonna to start because that's a giant.
Scott: don't tell them that you're supposed to tell this delay Even if there isn't.
Rym: if it's nothing but a bunch of baba booey baba booey that'll in itself be funny.
Rym: No Partly because the bit the purse the kinds of person like the person who will be listening to our stream.
Rym: We're not.
Rym: it's not like the old days where we did that you stream like we streamed ourselves live on the internet a long long time ago and For whatever reason our stream ended up on the front page of that thing.
Rym: And all these like
Scott: I'll think about how few people are on the internet then converted now Yeah
Rym: and suddenly all these like basic normal randos showed up and saw us sitting on a couch talking and our chat went from like
Scott: a Message every
Rym: like 30 seconds or so someone saying something to just a flood of what the fuck is this?
Rym: Who are these fucking nerds?
Rym: What the fuck is this?
Scott: Right imagine if you know it's.
Scott: it's the same way that things work these days.
Scott: only the bar is way hired, right?
Scott: Think about how many views you need to have on your twitch stream to get to the front page of twitch and it happens sometimes We're like a mid-tier twitch streamer or mid high tier one.
Scott: that will you know?
Scott: They won't be ninja level where they're like number one on twitch for the month But they'll have something special on their stream that brings in a crowd from somewhere.
Scott: Yeah, that will temporarily Momentarily make them the number one channel on twitch at that moment and then people who have never seen that streamer or never seen that game or both will see them on the front page of twitch next to The Pokemon marathon and click on them and then we'll get even more views.
Scott: like a second flood comes in and that's what happened us.
Scott: Only it was way easier for it to happen back in those days.
Rym: Yep in 2006 then in it was just fascinating to see like basic internet people trying to interact with something nerdy.
Rym: It was kind of awesome anyway in a weird way, but we're gonna try to do this.
Rym: so stay tuned.
Rym: You're probably gonna have to use discord because the best pipe lagging up up so far is a discord pipeline where you'll get invited.
Rym: You'll see we're gonna work it out.
Scott: We will maybe also.
Scott: maybe we'll just read what people type in on YouTube stream.
Rym: Yeah We will also use the YouTube stream chat and take comments from there that are good and either I'll read them or perhaps I'll have Amazon Polly read them.
Scott: So I tell people not to watch the stream, but that that's one time you can come.
Scott: oh Scott Oh, otherwise the show's gonna be real boring.
Rym: There's also a patreon specific streaming service that seems to have some of the stuff built in but I'm not going down that road yet.
Scott: Let's not go down that road.
Rym: Why not?
Rym: It's better on that road that the patreon content is good and is gonna accelerate.
Rym: that road goes.
Rym: No I Just watched that clip again, right.
Scott: also PAX Unplugged.
Scott: is the next packs coming up?
Scott: You should go.
Scott: if you're anywhere near Philadelphia, or you like tabletop games, or you like packs go to PAX Unplugged.
Scott: It's come.
Scott: we will be there.
Rym: We will be doing at least one panel and we will be up not gonna log into my.
Rym: I was about to log into my panel Admin account.
Rym: instead of the PAX Unplugged website.
Rym: we will be doing that one But two events.
Rym: one of them will be remember we did a learn to play and learn to win session with Carcassonne.
Rym: So we're doing it with a much more complex game now.
Rym: We're gonna be doing it with Puerto Rico.
Rym: We are going to walk through in detail the perfect best possible strategies to be good at Puerto Rico.
Rym: Teach an entire room of people how to play Puerto Rico and then have all those people knowing all these skills Play Puerto Rico against each other and it's gonna be hilarious.
Rym: We're also doing a panel and details TBD, but that panel will be in the live streaming theater from PAX Unplugged.
Rym: so single sign-on because the.
Rym: this is primarily the reason why this Facebook breach was so bad and single sign has actually meant a lot of different things over the years and There's a lot of different ways to implement it and there's no way we're gonna be able to cover all That possible scope and use case.
Scott: but the fundamental idea is that you have some sort of computer system And you got some username password login of some kind or some sort of logging into that system.
Scott: now Let's say you got a company and your company has you know?
Scott: you got an HR system.
Scott: you got an email.
Scott: You got what else.
Scott: you guys some file storage system.
Scott: Yeah You got a bunch of systems at your company and people got to make fucking username and passwords for all these fucking different things Right that are not attached to each other.
Scott: and you know what?
Scott: Microsoft if you're use all Microsoft for example or all Apple for example, right?
Scott: They have systems set up where you can have single sign on.
Scott: so Microsoft use it.
Scott: You'll set up an active directory server and then all your other which is basically just a fancy LDAP server, right?
Scott: it's a fancy LDAP server and You'll make all your employees accounts on that active directory server and now if they want to log into their Windows computer, or they want to log into Microsoft Exchange or Microsoft SharePoint or Almost any other system that you have at your company They're using that same username and password that they set up on there.
Scott: You know Active directory account and that one account controls the logging in to all the different systems of the company.
Scott: now You don't have to remember different passwords when you reset your password.
Scott: once you reset it everywhere, you know, it's it's really good It's very convenient to do.
Rym: Yep, and it provides Centralized control for things like policy like right.
Scott: I fired someone I fired this person.
Scott: I delete their account.
Scott: I don't have to delete their account in ten fucking different places.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Joey Jojo forgot his password.
Rym: You just fix it once you don't have to go to his PC physically to deal with it.
Scott: Yeah, oh I have to.
Scott: you know, this person has less access than they had before.
Scott: Well, I can change all their access to different systems in one place.
Scott: I don't have to log in on the administrator I don't have to log in now to ten different places because guess what?
Scott: My administrator account is also an active directory.
Rym: Yeah, I can go to any computer as the administrator log in as the admin and fix something locally if I need to.
Scott: Yeah Employees can just like swap computers and log in and they'll be good to go You can.
Scott: there's so many like convenient advantages to doing this assuming your active directory set up properly works properly.
Scott: Right your network is working Assuming everything works.
Scott: We're not gonna talk about when shit doesn't work this.
Scott: Yeah, that's off topic.
Scott: But the main
Rym: limitation of that is that
Scott: except for maybe the fact that it's a little tricky to make everything always work
Rym: It is like unless it is your job Like ad is kind of hard to set up and get right
Scott: but not even pretty much any system That's similar.
Scott: your is gonna have a fickle problems, right people often rarely set these things up perfectly But we're gonna assume that you did.
Rym: Yeah Good job.
Rym: Now the idea of this in terms of like the span of the history of computing is still actually Relatively new.
Rym: like early computers didn't have logons you powered them on and they just process.
Scott: Yeah, technically you could do this sort of thing with like Windows 3.11 for work groups.
Rym: That's the first Windows I had.
Scott: I think you could do it with that But you're lucky if you could.
Scott: even even Windows NT Windows 2000 if you could set up this sort of single sign-on Man, you are killing it dude.
Scott: Like they had the feature But if you could set it up properly in those days you were ahead of the curve.
Scott: You're serious.
Scott: like almost no one could do it.
Rym: probably that only existed in like big companies.
Scott: nowadays People don't even always get it right.
Scott: Yeah, even though it's much easier than it.
Rym: But in nowadays like I didn't bother but my NAS can run Active Directory.
Rym: I could totally just have a domain in the apartment and let's set up all sorts of cool admin stuff.
Rym: I just don't care.
Scott: There's no point.
Scott: It's not worth it.
Rym: But this isn't really the interesting stuff because if you work for a company that's big enough They're just gonna set this up.
Rym: The side effect is a lot of times there'll be a system that doesn't integrate that well with that single sign-on Like proprietary application like you can't tell steam to use your Active Directory server to log someone on right
Scott: or even if you could Like a lot of times you just don't Yeah, right It's like, you know maybe you've got a system where it's like.
Scott: You know, if all if you're if you're talking about this sort of thing where it's your internal employees logging in at a company Suddenly you get a system and it's like hey, well this system also has outside people logging into it.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, I've been in this situation.
Scott: This system is a proprietary is an application that we bought.
Scott: maybe you got Maybe you got Adobe accounts for everybody creative cloud accounts.
Scott: Well, you can't really have creative cloud logins work with Microsoft.
Rym: Or oh my company bought another company and now there's like four domains.
Rym: which domain am I logging into for which application?
Scott: Oh, no
Rym: So but all these concerns are primarily just like IT Sys admin network admin concerns inside of a big company and the way you solve a lot of those problems is Good operational procedures and like having someone write code and using services to like integrate single sign-on together.
Scott: Yep, if you're if you're an employee at a company who's not the IT person then as all you're gonna You're not.
Scott: even if you don't even aware you might just think think it's natural that oh I need a different username and password for everything or it's natural I use the same username and password for all the things Right and like.
Scott: you might not know that there could be a better or a worse world.
Scott: You're just used to what you have and it's not your job to do anything about it either.
Scott: So if you're an IT person, well, then you need to know about these things.
Scott: Hopefully you'd set them up properly.
Scott: Good job.
Rym: so - well two things that have changed that make this a little more interesting conversation.
Rym: That's the kind of I'm sort of outside of the enterprise now.
Rym: Is that one?
Rym: The web has a lot of things on it now.
Rym: Oh, yeah, and two even inside enterprises in the old days You'd need a computer that runs like some specialized software to do one part of your job and like a specialized service that you've paid Money for.
Rym: nowadays a lot of these things are also just web Pages or mobile apps.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Go to a web page in your company.
Rym: And that's the thing that lets you do your job.
Rym: So Web single sign-on and web service single sign-on is probably the most important area We could talk about the most common and the most relevant to what happened at Facebook, right?
Scott: so the first kind of web single sign-on there was was sort of like the.
Scott: You know your company has an exchange server setup, but there's a web gateway.
Scott: Yeah, so you go to the website for exchange or Oracle or something?
Scott: But then you use your company login to get in even though it's a web page But it's like an internal your company web page like webmail dot your company dot com Yeah, and you got a VPN before you can browse to it or something like that, right?
Scott: So those aren't really any different.
Scott: the next thing that happened that no one remembers which is still sort of a thing But you won't know it like you back in the day.
Scott: You had to know it.
Scott: now You don't even though it might still be underground somewhere is open ID.
Rym: So Oh bag, I have an open ID account tied to my old YubiKey.
Scott: still I mean your Google account is an open ID, but yeah.
Rym: But in the early days you had to find like a company that was selling open ID service, right?
Scott: so what happened was is there were all these you'd go to all these different websites and make all these different accounts and People said let's solve this we'll make open ID servers.
Scott: you make an account on the open ID server Then you go to a web page and instead of making a new account there You just say hey give me a new account This is my open ID and then the web page their server say geocities.
Scott: I don't think geocities ever supported open ID Example like in that era.
Rym: almost nothing supported open ID.
Rym: so I had one and I could only use Using geocities example.
Scott: Yeah, but geocities you would go there say I want a new account.
Scott: The geocities server would then talk to your open ID server your open ID server.
Scott: You would then go to it and log in and prove that you could log in and then there'd be sort of this triangle form Right between you the website you want to make an account on and your open ID Server and they would all.
Scott: and now you would be the login to the new site with your open ID cookie Whatever basically a delegation of the credential.
Rym: So you're saying this other guy has The credential to prove that I'm me.
Rym: so trust that credential.
Rym: trust him that I'm me, right?
Scott: So that was only a few nerds used it because it was hard to do.
Scott: you had not yet like type in a. you had Get a server make an account on it then tell the website you were registering an account on.
Scott: use this server.
Scott: This is my open ID account and here I'm logged in and you know, it's not what many places supported it but what eventually happened is the thing that you are using today without even realizing it.
Scott: is they invented based on that same exact Triangle model.
Scott: right they invented Oh off Right and Oh off is what's used.
Scott: when you says sign in with Google sign in with Facebook sign in with Twitter That's all the same exact triangle shaped model.
Scott: you log into Google, right?
Scott: Then you go and tell Geocities that you know what?
Scott: I don't want to make it.
Scott: use it easy.
Scott: username and password.
Scott: this is my Google account.
Scott: talk to Google.
Scott: if If you see someone logged in as me, then that's me.
Scott: Associate me with this account and it works and you've used it.
Rym: So post web 2.0 like in the early days of the internet.
Rym: There are very few websites you would log into Like there weren't many things where you needed an account.
Rym: Yep, and you just had a separate account.
Rym: all these websites But now we both have.
Rym: like most of the things people do online are with services that require accounts these days yep, and the web pages are basically just like apps to let people do the thing and This is mainstream.
Rym: So normal people there is no way on earth.
Rym: They will be able to remember a hundred logins to a hundred different.
Scott: so they use the same login everywhere.
Scott: I'll come when you get their password.
Scott: You can then log into all their stuff and they say they got hacked when really they're very simple.
Scott: password was merely guessed by A family member who knows them.
Scott: Well, yep.
Rym: So nowadays like I do this Scott does this.
Rym: we all do this.
Rym: the people who got burned by Facebook do this.
Rym: you.
Rym: there you can use services that most people have like Facebook and Google as a de facto Identity store.
Rym: like you can use them as the way to prove who you are to anyone else on the internet.
Rym: So my Google account is like my main account for everything.
Rym: So it makes sense to use that to prove who I am literally everywhere else I go and because Google is big enough Most people will support that.
Rym: but note.
Rym: This is all still just private profit based companies Providing this for their own purposes.
Scott: There's also another level to OAuth.
Scott: right because OAuth?
Scott: on the one hand this triangle shaped architecture is used to you know Log into a different website using the credentials from another one.
Scott: But actually what it's used for is you ever go to like Twitter and it says you've given these websites permission to do stuff on Twitter.
Scott: right you go and you say, okay.
Scott: I'll give you know Flickr permission to access my Twitter account.
Scott: right that same triangle happens.
Scott: But now when you upload a photo on Flickr Flickr will auto tweet and do stuff on Twitter as you For you, even though you didn't do it yourself.
Scott: You gave this sort of permission for Flickr right to do that thing with Twitter on your behalf.
Scott: That's also an OAuth Thing but that's the important thing.
Rym: So you have you have authorized like there's a permissioning system built into most uses of OAuth for you to say you can separate this Application is using my account versus this application versus this application Independent of the credential you personally use to log in manually.
Rym: Yeah, so if one of those things has a problem where gets compromised you can cut it off.
Scott: Yeah, but architecturally speaking You know it's the same triangle shape.
Scott: It's the same OAuth You know thing that's happening the same program the same standards Of the way the tokens and the cryptography is done and everything to do.
Scott: all these the same functions Right, you know.
Scott: and most when it's when it's developed in a in a good way You'll be able to log in to say your Twitter account Twitter does it in a good way and you can go and there's a web Page and on Twitter and your profile that lists all the apps you gave permission to access your Twitter account and what permissions you gave Them.
Scott: it's like oh I gave this one permission to let me log in with Twitter But I didn't let it read my tweets or tweet as me or any of that of the stuff, right?
Scott: It's like oh no, but I gave this photo site.
Scott: I gave them permission to tweet as me and read all my tweets and edit my profile and edit my avatar.
Scott: and you know Let me log into Twitter and all this other stuff.
Rym: So while this is deeply important to the way the web is used today and like we don't want to go back to an era Without this kind of like federated authentication.
Rym: Oh, yeah, but at the same time it's opened up.
Scott: I mean without this we wouldn't be able to have the GeekNights website automatically tweet when we post a new episode.
Rym: Yep, or if we did there'd be like a script somewhere that has our plain text password stored, right?
Scott: Yeah, even if someone hacks the GeekNights server, you won't be able to hack into the GeekNights' account.
Scott: You'll just have these keys that are OAuth keys that can be used.
Scott: You might be able to tweet as GeekNights But then I'll be won't be able to log in.
Scott: So I'll log in and I'll just remove that permission and make new keys and after I fix the service you can't get in there Right, and then that's that.
Rym: but the negative is the actual details of how these credentials are authenticated Like how the tokens are passed and how a session is maintained and torn down and all that kind of stuff is very complex And there's a lot of room to fuck it up, right?
Scott: A lot of people implement things wrongly and they send keys on the wrong portion of the triangle.
Scott: Allowing.
Scott: that's usually the number one mistake is sending keys the wrong way so that someone sees a key They shouldn't see.
Scott: yeah, right like for example The triangle method architecture is also used when you say buy something with PayPal, right?
Scott: So you go to a website and you're at you're at e-store.
Scott: So you've got you got Scott and we got in the e-shop where we're buying stuff and I gotta buy some of PayPal.
Scott: So those are the three pieces of the triangle you the customer PayPal and the store, right?
Scott: You talk to the store and say you want to buy something.
Scott: you then go they set then go to PayPal and create like this transaction and then you go to PayPal and do all the buying with PayPal and all that PayPal sends to the store is Yes, that person paid.
Scott: they don't tell them anything else.
Scott: They don't tell them your credit card They don't tell them.
Scott: All right, as PayPal is implemented properly Secure for whatever other criticisms you have a PayPal.
Scott: It's.
Scott: they implemented taking a lot their technology of purchasing things correctly at least as far as we can tell.
Scott: Yeah, no, it's.
Scott: I've done a lot of PayPal API At least from the the e-shop side anyway.
Scott: but and then you go back to the website with the store and the store recognizes that you're that person and it recognizes that you Paid and then it says congratulations you we're gonna send you this product, right?
Scott: If you fuck this up Right, if you're the person making the e-shop.
Scott: You might say send a customer some of those tokens that you were sharing with PayPal and now your customer can now see all these PayPal things that happen with your account because you've sent them a thing you shouldn't have sent them
Rym: And this is a general understand
Scott: what was going on.
Rym: This is a general concern.
Rym: in API's people very easily will send metadata.
Rym: They shouldn't either because they're not paying attention or they don't understand what that metadata could be used for by nefarious actor.
Scott: I guess you know They could use like.
Scott: I guess if I had your PayPal keys I could like start charging people money and the money would go to you.
Scott: I Could open up a store where you get all the money.
Rym: This opens up is people don't read things.
Rym: So now you'll have applications like especially phone apps but also websites and things that'll say hey click on this so we can tweet and it'll ask for like Full access to your Twitter and a lot of people just say yes.
Scott: Yeah, and then they go.
Scott: my Twitter was hacked.
Scott: It's like no.
Rym: you gave some shady spam website permission to tweet as the vampire knocked on the door and asked if it could come In and you said yes, please.
Rym: and then it bit you Yep, it threw out the garlic ahead of permission, but at the same time the other vulnerability is that you've basically Delegated this trust such that there's one single point of authentication.
Rym: So in my case Google.
Rym: if Google fucks up.
Rym: I am royally effed because Google will.
Rym: if anyone compromises my Google account They can get into almost every account I have everywhere.
Scott: Yeah, pretty much the Google cause we use Gmail, right?
Scott: Google account is the linchpin because pretty much if you have my email you can recover almost anything.
Scott: Right you is there might be some two-factor stuff You might not be able to get but almost everything else that's good.
Scott: It's gonna be relatively easy for you.
Scott: like even some.
Scott: I forgot my password.
Rym: recover go to the email Yeah, but even then like it with the single sign on I'll go to some website and it says oh you're already authenticated I know this cookie.
Rym: You're good.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: You're good.
Scott: It happens.
Rym: Yeah, it happened with Facebook.
Scott: it did so.
Scott: So another problem with single sign-on right is that not only do you have the single point of failure where if somebody were to?
Scott: Say access it.
Scott: They can now log into right.
Scott: It's like oh if you have separate sign-ons and someone busts open one system.
Scott: Well, okay, you busted open one system, but if you bust open a single sign-on system, guess what now?
Scott: You've got access to all the systems in the company, right?
Scott: If you get users credentials, you can now log in anywhere.
Scott: You don't need to guess 10 passwords to 10 system One password for 10 systems, but also if you're say active directory it goes down.
Scott: No one can log into anything.
Scott: your whole company is down.
Rym: Only people mess up.
Scott: because I'm just saying if you have a single you have a single point of failure.
Scott: You think they make you have two servers if you set it back to directory, but the plan also credential caching, right?
Scott: But say if you you know, you log in with Google for everything and Google goes down.
Scott: now You can't log into anything until Google's back up.
Rym: It is a possibility and credential caching Only gets you so far and also opens you up to vulnerabilities potentially, right?
Scott: But you get the idea is that you when you create this convenience of being able to log in everywhere with one Credential even though it's only one system with one password You're not doing the wrong thing of put of putting one password on many systems.
Scott: But you are you know being it's like I'm shut out of everything because the single sign-on Authentication server is down or oh no someone cannot access all these things because they got guessed one password.
Rym: yep, now so the important parts of this like if you ever in a position where you have to set this stuff up or Manage it is don't cut corners on implementing the API's.
Rym: Yeah, like if there's a standard follow it.
Scott: use the very very popular Systems, right?
Scott: Don't you?
Scott: don't write your own thing, you know, don't make some custom thing.
Scott: use the existing stuff.
Scott: Yeah, set things up with the default, you know permissions and every right the default configurations.
Scott: Don't go messing around right.
Rym: do it the way it's supposed to be done and wave whatever you're implementing build a very robust auditing and Authentication like management and security management and permission management system like an authorization system.
Rym: You need to have that locked down and set up right to let people Troubleshoot if something goes wrong and something gets hacked which Facebook might not have done.
Scott: So for example, like if you're adding PayPal to your website, you'll see you'll notice that when you go to PayPal's documentation They've got like multiple different tiers of like.
Scott: how good are you at technology?
Scott: Right and the first tier is like literally copy and paste this code into your page It'll make a button that lets people buy stuff that use that.
Scott: Don't don't go messing around with the higher levels of actually use using the PayPal API Unless you're super super confident that you understand absolutely everything that it's got.
Scott: this that's talking about, right?
Scott: It's like you should use one level dumber than you feel you could get away with.
Scott: It's like you might be able to successfully implement that PayPal API, but don't Right don't.
Scott: unless you are like a hundred percent understanding absolutely everything, right?
Scott: If you feel like you could use the the even more difficult one now go back one level lower Right, don't don't use the level you can do.
Scott: Yeah one level easier now at least.
Rym: one good thing though is that there was an era with Facebook where this started to pick up where a lot of Schools and like place it like government things or places where people have no choice but to interact.
Rym: we're requiring single sign-on.
Rym: they wouldn't let you make your own account and They'd only let you make an account with Facebook.
Rym: Luckily, we're kind of past that now and most major services will let you choose from a variety Usually Google Facebook and maybe one or two other common services people use and you pick which one you want to use as your primary Identity which I think is a good thing because there is no way there will be a like government-sponsored standard open ID ID anytime soon.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Rym: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are despite my sniffling Craig Oliver Allen Joyce, Heidi McNicholas shimmering groovy obelisk hanging in the sky kashar tovish in my state.
Rym: e.com.
Rym: linky Gj band scoot alone Lee Roberto Kingsley Kelly Snyder Shawn Yeager Matthew Smith Nicholas Brando, mr Strong Strachan for to one creations Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn Shervin von Horrell Rory James David White Rochelle, Montana Superboy tripwire sailor Vista dodge like joshiro Joe star Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin drew open lander Finn Chris midkiff Daniel Redman Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn sniffling.
Rym: so I'm just gonna leave you with something and I'm shocked that there are people I know who didn't know what this was.
Rym: So we're hoping that it might make a comeback in the near future.
Rym: So stay tuned.