Rym: It's Tuesday, September 25th, 2018.
Scott: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, we review Rise of Tribes.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: Alright, I did something today that I've never done in my whole life.
Rym: Oh, that could be any number of things.
Scott: It could be.
Scott: I haven't done all the things a person can do.
Rym: Oh, it's too hard for you to have skied.
Rym: Mmm.
Rym: I doubt you experimented sexually.
Rym: No.
Rym: Because it's work day.
Rym: Like, you don't have time for that.
Rym: So, curious what you did.
Scott: So, a few days ago, I noticed in the mirror, my eyeball, at least half of it, was, like, red.
Scott: And I'm like, "Hmm, that's
Scott: interesting.".
Rym: Uh-oh, pink eye.
Scott: And I'm like, "Well, let's hope that goes
Scott: away.".
Rym: Pink eye.
Scott: So then, like, yesterday, this is like, you know, two days later, you know, I thought, like, I didn't look again, right?
Rym: Me didn't look again.
Rym: I looked in the mirror at least twice a day.
Scott: I didn't think about it again.
Rym: When I brush my teeth, I see my own eyeballs.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Do you just, like, a verge your gaze every time you go into the bathroom?
Scott: I don't look that carefully.
Scott: I'm not, like, inspecting.
Rym: Have, like, a shroud over the mirror?
Scott: Anyway, my eye was, you know, after it went apple picking, you know, my eye was itching.
Scott: I'm like, "Uh-oh, I should look at that
Scott: eye.".
Rym: That still sounds like pink eye.
Scott: So I go, I look in the mirror, and, yeah, you know, the eye don't look too good.
Scott: So, uh, today I'm like, "Hmm, I should go ask a doctor about this
Scott: eye.".
Rym: My insurance has a thing where I can basically use an app and call a nurse and be like, "Hey, should I go to a doctor for
Rym: this?".
Rym: And they'll give me advice.
Scott: Right, so I didn't want to go to a doctor and leave in the rain because I was working from home.
Scott: I didn't want to go outside.
Scott: So then I realized, "Hey, wait a minute.
Scott: There's all these, like, 'See a doctor with a webcam'
Scott: things.".
Rym: I'm going to go to the pink eye page on WebMD.
Scott: Because you know that there's all these, uh, you know, you always see that on TV commercials, right?
Scott: Or at least you did when I watched TV.
Scott: They'd be like, "The future.
Scott: See a doctor with a webcam.
Scott: Don't actually go to a
Scott: doctor.".
Scott: So I'm like, "Well, is the future today?
Scott: Let's fucking find
Scott: out.".
Scott: So first, the problem I had was, is I had two choices.
Scott: There was one that was, like, my, like, if I logged into my Works HR site, there was a link to, like, "Teladoc, use
Scott: this.".
Rym: Oh, Teladoc.
Rym: That's the one I get.
Scott: And, but, but, the doctor I go to also has one.
Scott: Oh.
Scott: So I wanted to use the one for the NYU doctor I go to and not the one that was on the insurance page, right?
Scott: That way all my records would be in the same.
Rym: Scott, if this story ends with you having pink eye, 'cause pink eye is, quote, "really
Rym: contagious.".
Rym: Do you have pink eye?
Scott: Is that where this is going?
Scott: Maybe.
Scott: Don't kiss my eye.
Rym: God damn it, Scott.
Scott: You're gonna kiss my eye?
Scott: Gonna be a problem unless you, like, lick my eye or something.
Rym: Nope.
Rym: Every surface you touch can spread it.
Scott: I have not touched any surfaces.
Rym: Yeah, you have.
Rym: You touched, uh, all that stuff.
Scott: I haven't touched you.
Rym: You touched my doorknob.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Oh, well.
Rym: Thanks for the pink eye.
Rym: Sure.
Rym: So, so, so, spoilers.
Rym: Scott's got pink eye.
Scott: Amanda doesn't have it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, uh...
Rym: Pepper time.
Scott: The point is, is go open my doctor's app to, like, make this appointment, which you can make in the same day.
Scott: It's like, it's like tele...
Rym: Why did you even bother?
Rym: I gave you a diagnosis in six seconds.
Scott: It turns out I was accurate.
Scott: It's video, it's like webcam on your phone.
Scott: urgent care, right?
Scott: So I go through and it's asking me all the good info.
Scott: It's like I'm updating my insurance and I'm putting in a pharmacy and it's like, it was way good.
Scott: And then it's like, yo, warning.
Scott: If your insurance doesn't cover this, you're gonna pick $130.
Scott: If your insurance does cover it, you'll pay a copay.
Scott: So I type in my insurance and they're like, we don't know if your insurance will cover it.
Scott: Call this number.
Scott: So I call that number and they're like, we don't know, call your insurance.
Scott: So I call my insurance.
Scott: I got someone who was real dumb on customer service and couldn't answer my question, so I hung up.
Scott: I had to call my insurance again and get a different person who was slightly more intelligent.
Scott: And they said I would only have to pay the copay, so I hope that's true.
Scott: Otherwise I'll call them again angrily.
Scott: Uh, but yeah, I scheduled appointment on the phone.
Scott: At the appointed time, a doctor appeared on my phone, looked at my eyeball with the camera on my phone.
Rym: And with all that effort said exactly what I just said, you have pink eye.
Scott: Well, they said that I had, it was very helpful.
Scott: They said that it was a, there's a virus in my eye, not a bacteria in my eye.
Rym: Oh, all right.
Scott: And that I should just put like a warm washcloth on it a few times a day and not go get any medicines or anything.
Scott: And also wash my hands a bunch and, uh, don't let anyone lick my eye.
Rym: All right.
Rym: I'm, I'm, I'm just glad.
Scott: Don't like rub one eye and then rub the other eye with the same hand.
Rym: I feel like that's going to happen.
Rym: I think you touch your eyes more than you realize.
Scott: But I only use left hand and left eye and the right hand on the right eye.
Scott: I highly doubt that you ever rub your right eye with your left hand.
Rym: I rub both eyes with the right hand.
Scott: I do this right eye, right like this.
Scott: I don't do this.
Rym: How are you capable of doing right eye, right hand, left eye, left hand, but yet you can't use both right and left shift.
Scott: I don't think right shift is, is no use.
Scott: Why would there be a right shift?
Rym: Right shift is used for like 40% of all my shifting.
Scott: I should remove right shift from my keyboard because I never hit it.
Scott: It's probably has zero presses on every keyboard I own.
Scott: My oldest ones.
Scott: He's left shift for all shifting.
Scott: So there's, because we- By adding capital A, the ring finger comes over to the A.
Rym: So aside from Scott having pink eye, the primary, we've done a lot, a lot's happened since we last did the Tuesday show.
Scott: The point is that, you know, the future is here.
Scott: You can actually do webcam doctoring.
Scott: It totally works.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Don't bother going out, and it took like two minutes.
Scott: No reason to go sit and see if it urgent care.
Rym: But I feel like you could have come to the same conclusion with the most minimal of research without contacting any other human being.
Scott: Yeah, but I'm, you know, I'm paying for this fucking insurance.
Rym: Ah, true, true.
Rym: So there is a lot of gaming news because we skipped some shows due to PAX, add a bunch of work stuff and travel, et cetera.
Rym: So we're probably going to miss a whole bunch of that gaming news and just focus on the things that happened most recently.
Rym: because what do you want?
Rym: It's GeekNights.
Rym: We're not a news show.
Rym: So first things first, you can't avoid this.
Rym: It's actually kind of funny how big it's blown up.
Rym: But if you haven't run into Bowsette, I'm shocked.
Rym: And now you're going to find out that you have not been on the Internet.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Like there was a trickle.
Rym: It's like when you're standing next to a wall that's about to collapse and there's like a little bit of rubble falls out of the wall and you look at it like, huh, what is wrong with that wall?
Rym: And then like one piece of mortar like pinks out and you're like, huh, what could end on the wall just explodes.
Rym: And that's basically what happened.
Rym: As best I can tell, there is a crown that turns, I guess, Toadette into a Princess Peach clone lookalike kind of thing.
Rym: And some random dude drew one random comic about that in a funny way.
Rym: And for whatever reason, the perfect storm aligned and everyone's just drawing female Bowser.
Scott: And well, it's Princess Peach.
Scott: It's Bowser in Princess Peach mode.
Rym: It's Bowser having put on a magic artifact that turns him into a Princess Peach lookalike in some fashion.
Scott: It looks more, you know, you think, oh, well, Bowser turned in with Princess applied wouldn't look like this.
Scott: No, it looks more like Princess Peach got a little bit of Bowser with a shell.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: I think this just looks like Bowser having turned into a hot lady.
Scott: It's like 80 percent Peach, 20 percent Bowser.
Rym: Yeah, but it's got the horns.
Rym: You know what it looks like?
Rym: You know in stories?
Scott: Yeah, that's the 20 percent.
Rym: But in the stories where there's like a shape shifter, but they have a towel or like in Burning Wheel, where a dragon that's in a form of a dwarf, the way you know is that there's always a little bit of smoke coming out.
Rym: I think it's like that.
Scott: Their ass.
Rym: No, but that's way funnier.
Scott: You got smoke coming out your ass too.
Rym: But this is expanded already into a Chain Chomp, Princess Chain Chomp.
Rym: Princess Podbros, I think, is literally my favorite.
Rym: So I just had to mention it because this is way bigger than I expected to the point that non-gamer-y, non-internet-y people I know have asked me about it.
Rym: Like this penetrated into the mainstream basics.
Scott: I mean, everyone knows about Mario.
Rym: Well, that's it.
Rym: Mario's very well known.
Scott: Mario's like Mickey Mouse level.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So in some other news that's much more like actual news, Telltale Games fired fucking everybody.
Scott: Well, see, when I heard this news, it always feels like I've heard this news before.
Scott: But actually, no, they just laid people off like quite a few times, at least once in the past.
Scott: Feels like more than once in the past.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And every time it happened, it always seemed sort of obvious.
Scott: Like, yeah, there was a lack of point-and-click adventure games for a long time.
Scott: They came back with a new engine for point-and-click adventure games.
Rym: And basically a pipeline factory to just crank out point-and-click adventure games based on IP.
Rym: Right.
Scott: And a lot like what I heard was the story of Crocs, the shoe, right?
Scott: Is that, you know, the shoes are obviously ugly, supposedly comfortable, useful, whatever.
Scott: But it was originally Crocs were only available in like certain places.
Scott: And then they just sort of mass produced them and sold them fucking everywhere.
Scott: And that sort of ruined it, right?
Scott: It's Krispy Kreme donuts.
Scott: You can only get them at these certain places when it's hot now.
Scott: Nope, now you can get them at fucking everywhere.
Rym: Yeah, but as soon as you could get a Krispy Kreme anytime you wanted, you realized that they're kind of garbage donuts.
Scott: Because the ones that you ate at the gas station weren't hot now.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Right, the hot now was like, yes, hot sugar.
Rym: Yeah, I mean literally when we drove by Krispy Kreme back before there was only one, like near us, if the hot now sign wasn't on, like, didn't go there.
Rym: No, of course not.
Rym: Like, why would you go there unless that sign was on?
Scott: But if it was on, you pulled up to the window.
Rym: Yep, and ate too many donuts.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: So this was much a similar situation.
Scott: They flooded the market with point-and-click adventures.
Scott: It's like, dude, people had nostalgia for point-and-click adventures a little bit.
Scott: And some people did.
Rym: No, there's a lot more to it than that.
Rym: The nostalgia factor is probably the least important part of their success at this point.
Scott: But also those games only have so much, it's like, once you play a few, it's like you sort of get burnt out.
Scott: You don't need to play that many.
Scott: There's no one who's like hooked on and who wants to play them forever.
Rym: There are.
Scott: You underestimate- Not that many.
Rym: You underestimate the primary demographic playing these games.
Rym: It is people who are not traditionally gamers who are fans of the intellectual property like Walking Dead.
Scott: No, that is a thing that originally Telltale was capturing the point-and-click adventure market.
Scott: It just so happened that one of their licenses, the most successful, perhaps only successful one, was Walking Dead.
Scott: And that brought on people who weren't into point-and-click adventures, but were into specifically, that was like a separate market that they hit on.
Scott: And that's where most of their money came from.
Scott: because the other market of people who care about point-and-click adventures got burnt out, doesn't care, isn't buying that many, isn't that big to begin with, et cetera.
Scott: But the real story- But that Walking Dead market was basically keeping the company afloat.
Rym: Well, see, you say that.
Rym: We don't really know because we don't have access to their financials.
Scott: That's what it seems like.
Scott: That is what common sense would suggest.
Rym: I think it's a little more subtle than that because I'm pretty sure these games are profitable to make.
Scott: Well, also it seems that the company was just horribly mismanaged and they put way too much money into making the games and also mismanaged business in general.
Rym: That this is a symptom of just the insane pressures of the video game industry.
Rym: And if you haven't heard this phrase, you'll hear people who are mad about games, not gamer gators, but actual real humans who are mad about games, and they'll talk about boom and bust hiring.
Rym: This used to be a problem in Hollywood as well, but it's a big problem still in games.
Rym: And the idea is that games, much like old Hollywood movies, are big projects that have a very, very long lead time and tons of investment required before you can make your first goddamn dollar.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: So you need a system and a way to make those games.
Rym: You need the pre-funding.
Rym: You need a whole pipeline system such that you're getting funding for your next project while you're finishing the previous project, which there's ways to do that that are reasonably non-toxic in film.
Rym: There is really no way to do this in games right now.
Rym: that's sustainable.
Rym: that I've seen.
Rym: And on top of that, you only need your employees up until the game is finished.
Rym: Like you hire all these people ostensibly to make the game.
Rym: So a lot of game companies will hire a huge number of people to make the game and fire them all the second the game is done.
Scott: This is also the reason you're seeing a lot more games with lots of DLCs, games that are perpetual games that can keep existing either in an esports way or a card game way.
Rym: Nintendo trying to charge for the online service.
Scott: Or an MMO way.
Scott: Games that try to have an eternal life.
Rym: Or at least an eternal revenue stream to pay for the upkeep of the game.
Scott: As opposed to make a game, release it, you're done.
Rym: Here's an example.
Rym: If Overwatch had no loot box monetization whatsoever, it was just a one-time purchase, no DLC, no nothing, then the only way to monetize that game would be the professional scene in esports.
Rym: But instead they can also monetize it by getting people to buy loot boxes.
Scott: Which means people can keep working and patching it and patching it and patching it.
Scott: Whereas otherwise it would have been alright.
Scott: that's the final Overwatch patch, the end.
Scott: Let's go work on something else.
Rym: So why is this such a problem in games and not nearly as big a problem in film and television?
Scott: Well it's a problem in technology for example.
Scott: Lots of tech companies hire way too many people when they get all that VC money and then when it doesn't work out.
Rym: That's a little bit different though because they almost expand their infrastructure without actually having an endgame.
Rym: I really don't want to lump that into this.
Rym: The reason this doesn't happen in film is because of the unions.
Rym: Film is set up to where there's a pipeline for people to work on one project then work on the next project and have some sort of continuity of income.
Rym: The games industry has nothing like that.
Rym: Game companies will lay you off the first chance they get, they're desperate to lay you off.
Rym: And more importantly because they're running primarily on passion and burnout from the people who are desperate to work in the industry making almost no money.
Rym: I mean it's literally not an exaggeration if I tell you that a competent game developer if I hired them would probably make three to four times what they make in games doing less work in almost any other industry.
Scott: People take advantage of someone who really wants to work on a video game real bad.
Scott: Even though we tell them not to, they do it anyway.
Rym: These companies will also have this practice where if they stop hiring, smart people in the company know that something's up.
Rym: So they will keep hiring and literally lie to everyone working for them that everything's fine until suddenly they lay everybody off.
Rym: And this happens time and time and time again.
Rym: So Telltale is cut down to like 20, 25 people.
Scott: They basically got rid of everyone except the bare minimum people.
Scott: they need to finish the Walking Dead game so that they can maximize profit on that because that actually must be already a sunk cost into it and it's probably going to return on investment.
Scott: Especially when there's no employees to pay because employees are the number one expense in any business.
Rym: Employees are also the number one.
Rym: It's weird because games have this problem where they basically just want interchangeable cogs to work the development and the design and the art for the games.
Rym: They hire a lot of contractors for these purposes.
Rym: But because of this lack of investment, they never have continuity.
Rym: It's hard to have a game company have the same people working there game after game after game continuing to refine the pipeline with these kinds of practices.
Rym: But in healthy industries, you see the opposite.
Rym: Like most big companies that actually have a lot of money, it's very telling that good middle management and good engineers are worth more than money.
Rym: Like straight up, these companies would rather hire one good engineer no matter how much it costs than have like an extra million dollars in cash sitting in the bank.
Rym: So the other thing people have asked, a lot of people who aren't in the US are asking how this happens.
Rym: And that's because in countries like the UK and a lot of Europe, it's actually illegal to fire people in this fashion.
Rym: These people got no severance, no warning, they're just done.
Rym: US labor laws are so pathetic that I think they're the primary enabler of the games industry in doing this.
Rym: Because the only other industries that take advantage of people in these specific ways are the other people you brought up.
Rym: These VC startups that are just trying to like do whatever their monetization cycle is once and bail.
Scott: If labor laws in the US were actually repaired, it would probably devastate the video games industry.
Rym: Oh definitely, I think the majority of game studios, the majority of AA to A studios would disappear and you'd just have indies and the infinite budget triple A's.
Rym: I think you'd have no one else.
Rym: Anyway, it's big news that will keep festering because this is going to keep happening.
Rym: I think it's going to keep happening until the laws in the US change.
Rym: Because I don't think the culture of people who want to work in games are going to change.
Rym: I really hope that the game workers unions succeed, but I don't know if they'll be able to due to the sheer number of scabs.
Rym: It's a really messy situation with no easy way out.
Scott: Definitely too many scabs.
Scott: But maybe with scabs, unlike say the NFL scabs, where people still went to watch football.
Scott: If scabs make games, maybe they'll make real shit games.
Rym: Dude, if the NHL had a lockout and scabs played, I would watch every second of those games.
Scott: That's what happened when the NFL locked out.
Scott: The replacement players, people went to see replacement refs.
Scott: People still went to the games, they complained, but they still went.
Scott: So I wouldn't complain, I'd be into it.
Rym: Let's see what fresh hell happens tonight.
Scott: The code replacement game developers actually managed to make decent games that didn't just crap out.
Rym: I guess the final piece of this puzzle, to give a sort of finance perspective to this, is that most of the people who invest in things, like private equity, like a VC, someone who's going to fund a company, provide that pre-money, they're doing it because they want to get a return better than they can get in the stock market.
Rym: Sustainable companies that are small are not going to provide that return without exploitation, in my personal opinion.
Scott: Because the stock market return is already pretty good.
Scott: To beat that, you have to do something evil.
Rym: But that's partly why the indie studios are a little, like, they still have their problems, but they're a little more immune to this little scale.
Scott: Yeah, because an indie studio, instead of exploiting someone else, it's an indie person exploiting themselves.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: But it also means that their primary goal...
Scott: So even though it's wrong, it's somehow not morally wrong if you do it to yourself.
Rym: But at least their primary goals are, put food on the table and make a game.
Scott: They're a starving artist, as opposed to, right, working for themselves to try to make the art they believe in, as opposed to starving to make the art someone else believes in.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: The moral of this is, do not starve to make someone else's dream come true.
Scott: Hey, you can starve to make your own dream come true.
Scott: If you're going to make someone else's dream come true, don't fucking starve.
Rym: Or, like Les Miserables, you can all just die because there's literally no way to fix anything ever, the end.
Scott: Well, you could just live in the not-fixed place.
Rym: Like, watch his name, the couple running the inn.
Rym: Anyway...
Scott: Like us.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: In other news, there's some drama in the pro-magic tour.
Scott: Yeah, so, apparently, you know, I don't have all the details on this because when have I ever paid that much attention to pro-magic, other than knowing it exists and knowing some of the, you know, most basic facts about it.
Scott: But what happened is, there's like, the magic world championship was going down, and it's an invitational pro event, and only like 20-something best magic players in the world are invited, and they had to play a lot of fucking magic to become the world champion, and it's in Vegas, and one player, about a month or so before the event, decided that they were not going to go because they mad.
Scott: They're mad because the payouts for these pro-magic events have decreased greatly, even though, as of recent, magic itself has grown.
Scott: Magic is bigger than it was a few years ago.
Scott: It's been growing for like five or six years, it feels like, right?
Scott: It keeps getting bigger at PAX.
Scott: I'm seeing more magic in the game stores.
Scott: Magic is definitely on the rise, but it used to be, back in the day, you know, some years ago, you could make a lot of fucking money playing magic.
Scott: There are people, like this one Hearthstone streamer, caster guy, Kibler, who's like real famous and has a cute dog.
Scott: He's like one of the top magic money-making people ever, and he doesn't play too much magic these days, because it doesn't pay that much.
Scott: Whereas if he's like the caster for a Hearthstone tournament, he's presumably getting paid by Blizzard, right?
Scott: Real cash monies.
Scott: He makes money on Twitch, streaming Hearthstone.
Scott: I think Geico pays him to stream the new digital magic arena game sometimes, but he's not playing pro-magic anymore, because I don't think it pays enough for his house and his dog.
Scott: But he used to pay more.
Scott: He used to do it, right?
Scott: Other people used to do it, and now they do it less because they're paying less, and that's one of the main reasons.
Scott: This player, what's his name?
Rym: Oh, Gary Thompson.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Decided they're not going to go to the Magic Pro Tour World Championship, even though they were invited.
Rym: But more importantly, they waited until it was too late to replace them.
Scott: Right.
Scott: If they had announced a month in advance, "I'm not going," then Wizards would have invited the 20-whatever, the next best player, right?
Scott: By waiting until the last second and actually going to Vegas and then not playing, now Wizards has a sort of black eye.
Scott: There's a player missing.
Scott: There's an empty seat.
Scott: Someone gets a bye, I presume, because they can't get another player that quickly.
Scott: The guy flies someone to Vegas at the last second, which is a great move by that person.
Scott: So now there's this debate where it seems like most of the Magic community is supporting this guy.
Scott: It's like, yeah, there seems to be some debate in our forum.
Rym: Well, it seems like it's most of the internet Magic community that cares about the Pro Tour.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Because the general Magic players doesn't look like they even noticed.
Scott: Well, it seems to be some sort of debate about how much people care about the Magic Pro Tour.
Scott: and does WotC care about it?
Scott: Does Hasbro care about it?
Scott: Why do they still have it?
Scott: They're obviously spending less money on it than they used to.
Scott: What's the benefit of it?
Scott: Versus, hey, they do have the Pro Tour.
Scott: They sort of, not necessarily directly tell kids, hey, you can play Magic for a living.
Scott: But it's like, hey, they have events at game stores.
Scott: They try to get people to come to play Magic.
Scott: You earn points, which if you earn enough of them, you presumably go to qualifiers where you can qualify and get in.
Rym: Well, you earn Pro Points that can be used, I'm quoting this article, to reimburse things like flights, meals, hotel expenses, et cetera.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like they have this system.
Scott: It's a thing.
Scott: I guess there's at least some people in the Magic community who are in it because, at least partially to some extent, they believe that if they play hard enough, they can make it to that top level.
Scott: And about 30 people or so should be able to, at least with the current system, make money playing Magic.
Scott: The thing is, this guy's top 20-something.
Scott: He could be number one.
Scott: Maybe he would have won if he played in the tournament.
Scott: Who knows, right?
Rym: Grand Prize is only 100 grand, though.
Scott: That's what I'm saying, is like, how many, if you're- Last place pays 2,500.
Scott: Yeah, 2,500.
Scott: You ain't living on that, right?
Scott: But the thing is, in order to even come in that place, like 20th place that gives you $2,500, you have to play Magic full-time.
Scott: Like, if you're not playing Magic full-time, you're not good enough to make that 2,500.
Rym: Now, I would suspect, like, my guess here is that, like, I really think that the average Magic player won't notice or care.
Rym: And I suspect that many of the other pros will not care that much either.
Scott: Well, some of them are probably happy to have one less dangerous opponent.
Rym: Exactly.
Rym: Because this is one of those situations where there's a lot of hobbies where there's some money being thrown around in the top, top tiers.
Rym: And there is a, like, professional or a semi-professional scene.
Rym: But a lot of those hobbies, they're really just hobbies where upper-middle-class people with disposable income pay their own expenses and pay themselves effectively to be full-time players because they have that luxury and that freedom of doing so.
Rym: And it's sort of just a perk for the people who are really involved in the hobby.
Scott: Yeah, I know.
Scott: But if you look like the other, you know, similar games out there these days, I think, like, you know, definitely more people can play Hearthstone as a living because they're supported also by Twitch streaming and other things.
Scott: They also have teams supporting them, and there's a lot more events with more payouts and bigger payouts, right?
Scott: You make a lot of money if you're the Hearthstone world champion.
Scott: It's a big cash, right?
Scott: You know, you can make more money pretty much with any big esport.
Scott: You can make more money playing, you know, friggin' LoL than you can playing Magic.
Rym: Yeah, well, Magic doesn't really have a sustainable professional...
Scott: You make more money playing Counter-Strike than you can playing Magic.
Rym: Yeah, I think that's true.
Scott: Right?
Scott: So it's kind of like, "Hey, Magic is growing.
Scott: There is a competitive scene, but they're really pushing that competitive scene
Scott: down.".
Scott: I feel like if you're gonna have a competitive scene for your game, you should either A) keep it strictly non-pro.
Scott: Like, no cash payouts for anything official, at least.
Scott: Someone else wants to run a tournament with a cash payout, that's on them.
Scott: But no official cash payouts in anything.
Scott: That way, nobody would be motivated to spend their whole life doing it.
Rym: But at the same time, I am really not sympathetic to people who choose to try to live this life without having income from some other source.
Scott: Well, I mean, look, there are people who try to become pro tennis players or golfers and they get in, you know, they get a rank and it's like, well, you're not... They're never good enough to make money on it, right?
Scott: But they try it anyway because they're idiots.
Rym: I feel like it's the same thing here.
Rym: Like, I'm not gonna lie.
Scott: But at the same time, it's like, well, it's not super idiotic because if you were good enough, you're gonna get paid.
Scott: If you're the 100th best golfer in the world, no one will know who the hell you are, but you're gonna be hella rich.
Scott: You're not gonna be mega rich, but you'll be richer than us.
Scott: You'll have millions, at least.
Rym: But anyone who wants to get into golf can see that structure exists.
Rym: Anyone who wants to play Magic professionally can see what structure exists.
Scott: You can see what structure exists, but that's the thing.
Scott: The structure was bigger and has decreased and that's why this player has decided to step out.
Scott: And so I think they should either, if they're gonna decrease it now to the level where only maybe 5 people can play professionally, they should either just cut the cash out or bring it back up to where at least maybe 50 people can play and make a living wage.
Rym: Yeah, but I also just sort of see the cash prizes at this point as just a perk at the upper tier that shouldn't have any bearing on the rest of the scene.
Scott: The problem is the cash prizes are in sort of like this vague area where if you're in first place a lot you can actually make a living.
Scott: It's like bring it down to the point at which no, even first place doesn't make a living, you should only be doing this part time.
Scott: Even a small cash prize is basically okay, but none is still better.
Rym: I really cynically believe that within a month or two this will just be forgotten and nothing's gonna change in the Magic scene and most players won't care.
Rym: That's my guess.
Scott: I might be wrong.
Scott: I ain't played Magic since the 90's.
Scott: There are a lot more Magic events.
Scott: That's the thing, there's more events with smaller payouts.
Scott: So we'll see what happens at the next event.
Scott: It really depends on those, because there's only really 20 or 30 people who are even at that top level who can sort of do anything.
Rym: I don't think more events with smaller payouts will actually be healthier because the biggest barrier to entry for people is one, having time to play the games full time to get good at them.
Rym: This is generally not just Magic.
Rym: But also number two, travel ain't cheap.
Rym: The fact that we fly to every PAX, most gamers can't do that.
Scott: Well, I would agree with you because that's common sense, but Hearthstone this year added way more events.
Scott: This is basically like a Hearthstone tournament every fucking weekend somewhere.
Scott: And there are people who just freaking fly to all these freaking things.
Rym: I think the big difference there is.
Rym: I really have this impression purely anecdotal that the average age of Hearthstone players is older than the average age of Magic players, at least the ones who care about the competitive scene.
Scott: I don't know about that.
Rym: And I think the demographic is similar to me.
Rym: The people who are flying around to those tournaments, if I had to guess, they're mostly middle, upper middle class.
Scott: I don't know how much money they have, but they make all their money from playing Hearthstone.
Rym: Yeah, also there is a lot more monetization in the pool because you can monetize video games with streaming in a way that you really can't with card games today.
Scott: It's really interesting at least, I don't know about for other e-sport games, and I only talk about Hearthstone a lot because it's the digital card game that I watch and play more than other digital card games.
Scott: I play it once a day for ten minutes.
Rym: The digital card game I play the most is Slay the Spire.
Scott: Right, I play that once a day for ten minutes also.
Scott: But the people who are the top competitors at Hearthstone are not the top streamers.
Scott: The top streamers are these people who play silly decks and non-competitive modes and are entertaining.
Scott: And the people who are really, really good at Hearthstone, you only really see, I guess some of them stream, but you mostly see them on the tournament streams.
Scott: You don't see them on their own streams.
Rym: Well, I mean the streamers I watch are either people who are like the purest masters of their craft or the people who are directly entertaining to me irrespective of what they're doing.
Scott: Yeah, the greatest masters of the craft at Hearthstone.
Scott: Few of them stream and have lots of viewers.
Rym: Well, because when I do my Advance Wars streams, I give a lot of dialogue, but at the same time I only play pretty simple maps in that.
Scott: Because if I'm playing Advance Wars- It takes too fucking long.
Rym: No, for serious.
Rym: I take my turns really quick.
Rym: I ain't saying shit.
Rym: It's just going to be me staring at the screen going click, click, click, click, click, because I'm thinking.
Scott: Anyway, this is going to be interesting.
Scott: It has bearing on the future of competitive nerd gaming.
Rym: So related, last but not least, this is a little story, but it seems like there's more to it than might appear.
Rym: This little story is that basically a Swiss soccer game, well football if you don't live in the US, was temporarily halted.
Scott: So Switzerland were the chocolate and the knives.
Rym: Because the crowd was protesting the fact that esports exists.
Rym: So I dug into this a little bit.
Rym: They disrupted a football game because they're mad that esports are disrupting football.
Rym: As best I can tell, this is happening all around Europe in small ways.
Rym: There's this general undercurrent of anger, specifically at Fortnite and FIFA esports.
Scott: The only place I've seen this in the US is actually hockey people who are mad that the young players are playing a lot of Fortnite instead of getting better at hockey.
Scott: But I've heard rumblings that even some teams are banning their players and playing Fortnite.
Scott: But it's like, video games have been around for a long time.
Scott: Ten years ago those same hockey players were playing Counter Strike.
Scott: Why is Fortnite suddenly, are there people playing it more than they were playing it?
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: I think it's just because it's pop culture well known.
Rym: It's an easy finger point for old Gen Xers and Boomers.
Scott: Because they know about it, where it's like, I'm sure hockey players who are my age weren't playing Final Fantasy 7 or whatever.
Rym: One of the banners read, and I'm quoting here, "Shyce
Rym: Esports!".
Rym: You can guess what that means.
Rym: So, my read of this, after digging around a little bit and asking some people who live in Europe, because a lot of my European co-workers and people I interact with, FIFA is the only thing they care about outside of...
Scott: FIFA is game numero uno in the rest of the world that cares about soccer.
Rym: So the people who are mad about Esports in Europe, it seems that they're specifically mad that their kids refuse to play soccer because they'd rather play Fortnite or FIFA.
Rym: They don't want to play actual soccer, they think it's boring.
Scott: So that's the thing that on the one hand, it's like, woah, Fortnite is its own thing, right?
Scott: If you're a kid you're playing that game.
Rym: I was a kid, I'd be playing it.
Scott: If you're playing FIFA, that must be because you like soccer.
Scott: You don't play NBA Jam if you don't like basketball.
Rym: Ah, but there is a big difference.
Rym: In FIFA, you can't press X to pretend you were hurt.
Scott: Who knows?
Scott: Have you played FIFA?
Rym: I've never played FIFA.
Scott: How do you know it doesn't have that simulation in it anyway?
Scott: In fact, it probably does in EA Sports.
Rym: Can it hit the buttons if someone comes over with an air duster?
Scott: The EA Sports motto was, "If it's in the game, it's in the
Scott: game.".
Scott: Anyway, the point is, will there be a turnabout where they care about FIFA and then soccer becomes FIFA IRL?
Scott: Because right now, FIFA is virtual soccer.
Scott: Will it become where, no, FIFA is the default game and soccer is actually the real life version of FIFA.
Scott: Also, if that happens, will then actual soccer fade?
Scott: And if actual soccer fades, then will people care about FIFA?
Scott: People only care about FIFA because they presumably care about soccer.
Scott: If there's no people who care about soccer, will they care about FIFA?
Scott: Will FIFA replace soccer and then both die?
Scott: As kids who are then young, don't care about soccer and then don't care about FIFA and just play whatever other game?
Rym: And then they'll play Fortnite 2 and gun soccer with cars and robots.
Scott: Who knows, right?
Scott: Will there be a point at which FIFA adds something to the game and then soccer has to then modify itself to match FIFA?
Rym: So, keep an eye on this.
Scott: FIFA the game, not FIFA the organization.
Rym: Yeah, but how this evolves in Europe is a perspective on...
Scott: It's actually convenient that the NFL game is called Madden and not just NFL.
Scott: How many kids playing Madden know anything about John Madden?
Scott: Do they even know that Madden was a person or anything about him?
Rym: I suspect not many.
Scott: How many of them have ever seen John Madden?
Scott: Do they know what he sounds like?
Rym: John Madden.
Scott: I watched football when I was a kid, but John Madden was casting the games.
Scott: I'm sure people of a generation older than us saw John Madden playing football, coaching, whatever, before he was a caster.
Scott: I think kids these days, Madden just means that video game.
Scott: They don't know that that's a person.
Rym: I mean, I knew a lot of people who played football games on like the N64 when I was in high school.
Rym: Who did not know the fucking rules to football?
Rym: They didn't know.
Scott: Well, if you played 10 yard fight, then you didn't need to know the rules to football.
Scott: If you played Tecmo Bowl, you didn't need to know the rules to football.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Tecmo Bowl a little bit.
Rym: Blitz was the one most people played.
Rym: that I knew.
Scott: You didn't need to know the rules to football for that either.
Rym: No, not really.
Scott: Yeah, you know.
Rym: But for all the debates and nuance and everything about esports, this particular issue never really comes up because it's so specific to Europe.
Rym: And I think it's actually a very fascinating and interesting perspective that's really important to a global nuanced view of what the future of sport and esports is.
Scott: Also, I think we don't have a protest culture of fans in the stands so much.
Scott: True.
Scott: They will boo at someone like John Rocker, but that's about it.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: So because we don't have that, even if there is a feeling among the fans of some sort of unified... Well, that's it.
Scott: It's the booster clubs.
Rym: It's the football booster clubs that are specific like the soccer clubs.
Rym: They're the ones who are organizing this weird esports resistance.
Rym: And it seems like they're the ones who are mad that their literal children don't want to play football.
Scott: Yeah, those clubs are basically.
Scott: no one young is joining into those, right?
Scott: It's a group of old people that's aging and then going to go away.
Scott: Young people aren't getting into those clubs.
Rym: Ah, in the stream.
Rym: Someone who's not that much younger than us.
Rym: For me, John Madden equals athlete's foot spokesman.
Rym: There you go.
Scott: Yeah, I know that.
Scott: Anyone know Tommy Lasorda?
Scott: The John Madden of baseball?
Scott: What was the product that he always advertised during the prices, right?
Rym: Oh God, fuck if I remember.
Scott: It was one of those nutrition drinks.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Slim Fast feels right.
Scott: Because he was big and fat?
Scott: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: What do you got for me?
Scott: So New York City is a loud place.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: Even if I open my window and there's no sirens or honking horns or anything, people outside my window, you hear a constant...
Rym: Yup, there's a dull roar.
Scott: Most of that is the combined noise of people's electrical things like air conditioners and whatnot.
Scott: You know, machines on the top of buildings heating and cooling.
Scott: But also just the sound of tires rolling on pavement all adding together.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: Also millions of people just walking around.
Scott: Anyway, but occasionally in New York, well frequently, there are very loud noises, usually construction jackhammers, big ass trucks.
Rym: The 7 train.
Rym: Yeah, there's mega loud noises.
Scott: So this guy made a cute video.
Scott: He dressed up as a conductor.
Scott: He looks like a conductor.
Scott: He gets a little music stand and a tux and a little magic wand and some sheet music or at least a white piece of paper.
Scott: And he sets it up next to some construction and he pretends to conduct the sounds of the construction.
Scott: It's a similar joke to the wizard.
Scott: The incredible power.
Rym: It's funnier than it should be and the best part...
Scott: It's nice and short.
Scott: This video ends before it stops being funny, which is why it's good.
Scott: I love at the end the construction workers.
Scott: If they dragged it out, then it wouldn't have been good.
Scott: But because it's such a short video, it's like, here's the joke.
Scott: You got it.
Scott: Okay, we're done.
Scott: And that's why it's good.
Rym: So I've done some escape rooms and I've also played a bunch of escape room tabletop games and reviewed some of those games.
Rym: But I noticed a pattern pretty early on, like a very specific one, that pretty much every escape room puzzle comes down to this very simple set of heuristics.
Rym: And you can solve the puzzles kind of with brute force just by following this really core set of heuristics.
Scott: Well, part of it is the Scooby Doo factor where the things that are interactable sort of stand out.
Scott: And you can just focus on mixing and matching those things together.
Rym: But it also comes down to, like, look for a puzzle, figure out the number and type of inputs it requires, and then look for something in the environment that has that number and/or type of outputs.
Rym: And that's the answer.
Scott: Right, it's like, oh, this needs keys.
Scott: Is there anything that outputs keys?
Scott: No.
Scott: Oh, there's something.
Scott: It needs colors.
Scott: Where's colors?
Scott: Oh, there's a bunch of flasks with colors in them.
Scott: All right, let's, you know.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But even worse...
Scott: Oh, this needs letters.
Scott: This is a weird box that has an input of letters.
Scott: Oh, this needs four numbers to open this.
Scott: Let's find four numbers, everybody.
Rym: So even worse, there's a relatively small number of game designers making escape rooms and escape room adjacent co-op games, like tabletop games.
Rym: And they all kind of use the same design patterns, down to the point that this... So this video is basically the speed running hints for just beating escape rooms guaranteed knowing nothing.
Scott: Escape rooms are really just a series of riddles.
Scott: I feel like, you know...
Rym: They're not really riddles, they're puzzles.
Scott: Puzzles, riddles, some combination of the two, right?
Rym: I have yet to find an escape room that I would classify as a riddle.
Scott: Let's make one with a sphinx in it.
Rym: Just all riddles.
Scott: It's just sphinx, and then you get past it, it's another sphinx.
Rym: And if you get... But the only, like, one design pattern...
Scott: And then the last sphinx isn't a riddle, you just have to fight it.
Rym: Well, like, in particular, this video points out...
Scott: And it's a lion in a sphinx costume.
Scott: Get ready.
Scott: We didn't sedate it.
Rym: The consensus design for escape rooms...
Scott: We spray meat on you.
Rym: Is that people are very unwilling, at least the majority of them, to put red herrings and dead ends, which further exacerbates the problem if all escape rooms have the same answer.
Scott: If you're running an escape room business, you don't want red herrings and dead ends, you want people out so you get the next group in.
Rym: Well, no, they're in there for the same amount of time.
Rym: You get kicked out at the end of the time, no matter what, usually.
Scott: Ooh, that's good.
Rym: Usually it's you got an hour, can you beat it before then?
Rym: Otherwise, they open the door and say, "Yeah, you're
Rym: dumb.".
Scott: Good.
Rym: That's how it works.
Scott: But the point is, it's just so disappointing that it's escape room.
Scott: You could just give someone the puzzles on a piece of paper to solve a test.
Rym: Well, they did.
Rym: That's that exit the game, which is pretty good.
Scott: Right, but I mean, literally, you could make it really boring and it would be functionally equivalent.
Scott: Literally just a written test, right?
Scott: Like, "Solve this
Scott: cryptogram.".
Scott: "All right, now solve this
Scott: one.".
Scott: "Now take the first digit of each cryptogram and put them in
Scott: here.".
Scott: My
Rym: thing of the day, to not derail the show too much, because we've already gone 45 minutes and haven't even gotten to our review,
Scott: is
Rym: this
Scott: video is
Rym: literally everything I thought about escape rooms, but researched and based on something other than just my own butt and my own anecdotes.
Rym: So everything this video says, I agree with, and that's all I got to say about that.
Rym: If you watch this video, you can probably beat any escape room in under the allotted time, guaranteed.
Rym: Partly because escape rooms are designed for basic people with basic capabilities.
Scott: I would hope that any intelligent person could beat any escape room.
Rym: You'd be surprised.
Rym: I've watched people struggle with answers in escape rooms.
Scott: We should make extra hard escape rooms.
Rym: You're just locked into a room, and there's a guy with a knife, and you have to convince him to let you out of the room, and that's it.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: In the meantime, the Book Club book is apparently still Homer's Odyssey, because Scott has still not updated the website.
Scott: No, no, it's no longer a Greek Odyssey, it's now a Space Odyssey.
Rym: Yep, 2001 is Space Odyssey.
Rym: We are going to be live at PAX Unplugged doing at least one event.
Rym: We're going to be teaching people not only how to play Puerto Rico, but how to be good at Puerto Rico, and then how to be perfect at Puerto Rico, and they're going to make them all play Puerto Rico.
Scott: At least three player perfect Puerto Rico.
Rym: Yeah, I think we've got to play some four and five player.
Rym: I got the heuristics down, but I've got to prove them out.
Rym: We'll play some before Unplugged.
Rym: Anyway.
Rym: We will likely be doing other events at Unplugged, but details TBD, this is only the first one.
Rym: Otherwise, tune into the GeekNights stream on Thursday, the day after tomorrow, because we will be interacting with the audience in some capacity, details TBD.
Scott: You're going to want to install probably like Discord or something.
Rym: Yep, well we'll play it by ear, but we're trying something.
Rym: So let's get right into it.
Rym: I played this game once.
Scott: I played it two times.
Rym: Yep, Rise of Tribes came out in 2018.
Scott: It's a board game, I think it was Kickstarted maybe.
Scott: We played it at PAX.
Scott: It's a game.
Rym: It's uh, it's alright.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: It's okay.
Rym: I don't ever need to play it again.
Scott: The way I feel about this game is it seems like someone like took or came up with and combined a bunch of okay to good to sometimes slightly clever game mechanics and mixed them up into a perfectly average generic board game that is so like run of the mill.
Scott: There's nothing exciting about it.
Scott: It seems just like every other, you know, Euro-ish board game.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Like there's nothing that stands out.
Scott: It's like, you know, you think about a board game that's really great and there's something about it that's like clever or different, right?
Scott: Like for example, Dominion basically invented deck building, right?
Scott: T&E was like, aha, your lowest points is the ooh, right?
Scott: There's no ooh in Rise of Tribes.
Scott: It's literally just like take actions to get the most victory points on your turn.
Scott: the game.
Rym: I mean the rules were described and I looked at the board and I looked at what I had and I looked at the and a very small number of very direct heuristics immediately became apparent and everything beyond that was random or political.
Scott: Yeah, so basically the way the game works is you put some dudes onto a hex map.
Scott: You're trying to take over spaces.
Scott: You're trying to do things.
Rym: Well, you're trying to get points and there's a bunch of ways to get points but the default way is to build huts and every hut you have gives you a point.
Scott: The hut gives you a point every turn.
Scott: It's sort of like settlers a little bit, right?
Scott: Imagine it's a little like risk plus settlers.
Scott: You get your guys on the board, take over some spaces.
Scott: That way you can get some resources.
Scott: Use the resources to put huts on the spaces.
Scott: Defend them.
Scott: The huts spit out a point every turn and eventually the first person to 15 points wins, a lot like settlers.
Scott: The two interesting mechanics in the game that I noticed that were cool is number one is this dice thing going on.
Scott: So on your turn you want to take an action.
Scott: There's four actions to choose from, right?
Scott: There's always going to be an action that you want to take the most but each action has three dice on it.
Scott: Two of them are sort of locked in and the third one is sort of like you roll, right?
Scott: You sort of roll one.
Scott: Oh, that's right.
Scott: I remember now.
Scott: It's been a few weeks.
Scott: You roll two dice and you take two actions, right?
Scott: That's what it is.
Rym: Yep, and when you take an action, you put the die you rolled which either has a sun, moon, or nothing on it into the spot of the action you took displacing one of the dice that's already there.
Scott: Right, so each action already has like three dice on it.
Scott: So one of the actions might have like sun, sun, blank.
Scott: So you put your dice in there and kick out the oldest one.
Scott: and maybe of the three dice that are there now that you've displaced one, maybe you've got sun, blank, sun in which case you do the action slightly better.
Scott: Maybe it'll be blank, sun, moon.
Scott: Alright, you do it normally.
Scott: Oh, that'll be moon, moon.
Scott: Ah, you do the action slightly worse than normal.
Scott: There's like three levels to each action and it provides this randomness to where you can choose whatever action.
Scott: you can use any two of the four actions you want.
Rym: But you have to balance what you need to accomplish with what will you enable another player to do.
Scott: Right, based on what you do and what previous players have done what dice have been put in you might be doing actions slightly better or slightly worse.
Scott: So it's variance.
Scott: It's not huge variance.
Scott: It's not game swingy variance.
Scott: It's just a little bit of variance to mix things up which is pretty clever.
Scott: But it's also because it's so constrained.
Scott: it's not exciting.
Rym: Well, because every interaction is hyper generic.
Rym: So while there's a bunch of stuff that has like a lot of...
Scott: Move dudes, put more dudes out.
Rym: But there's a lot of fun flavor text nonsense like oh, the cougar or whatever, the mountain lion appears and he moves around the map beating people.
Rym: It's purely like the most minimal political remove a guy from whatever players in first place.
Rym: Nothing does anything interesting.
Rym: Everything just does these very like plus one, minus one political actions.
Scott: I feel like whoever made this was like alright, we gotta put in randomness and fun to spice things up.
Scott: but we don't want to put in too much because it's too swingy and the game becomes too luck based.
Scott: Settlers let things be a little more luck based whereas this constrained all the luck into this narrow controllable band which is kind of okay for a competitive game.
Scott: but what ends up happening is everything's so constrained and there's no skill testing way.
Scott: there's no difficult to figure out moves so everyone gets about the same number of victory points every turn and progresses at about the same rate.
Rym: except when I played the first time I got a ton more than everyone else because I just built a bunch of huts while you were all fucking around.
Scott: I tried to build some huts.
Scott: I built as many huts as I could.
Scott: There's different players to choose from different tribes.
Scott: Each tribe needs a different recipe of resources to build a hut and I was like woah, woah, woah.
Scott: I was like I'm not picking one that needs three trees if anyone else has one that needs three trees.
Scott: there's a little bit of that going on at the start.
Rym: so there's also a thing you can do where you can basically unlock more advanced technology that gives you more powers.
Rym: but again, super generic and super constrained.
Scott: you have this deck of cards and one of the actions lets you flip over the cards.
Scott: it's sort of like getting routes in Ticket to Ride where you spend an action to get more routes and then if you can fulfill them they activate, either giving you victory points or giving you powers like basketry, gather one additional resource.
Rym: so when I gather I get extra resources and it costs me two stone and a wood to build it and I guess it's worth a victory point.
Scott: the other thing is this is an event deck where if somebody rolls two identical symbols you then start flipping over cards from the event deck and that sort of mixes things up.
Rym: I like events except the events are all just politics attack the player in charge or attack someone on a particular hex.
Scott: there were some events that were like the next few players get some extra resources or like the barbarians come on the board and just do nothing.
Scott: yeah, the barbarians fill up one space and clog it up and in the two games I played the barbarians came out, clogged up one space and everyone just ignored that space.
Scott: the rest of the game.
Scott: in the end it's nice to spice things up with an event system of randomness but there weren't enough different events and the events weren't consequential enough that you actually had to do anything about it.
Scott: it's sort of like you can have a game with no randomness.
Scott: you have a game with a lot of randomness where then suddenly your decisions matter less.
Scott: but at least there's crazy fun things happening.
Scott: this tried to strike a balance between not too much randomness so things get mixed up but it didn't have.
Scott: there's not enough complex interwoven systems to make decision making difficult so that little bit of randomness ends up being what matters.
Scott: but you lose out on the fun of randomness because nothing is extreme everything's tiny and it ends up being.
Rym: I think it's a good game for kids to introduce them to more complex games.
Scott: I do think this is actually a great game of intro to euro games in general maybe even better than Settlers because it has more interlocking mechanisms that are all themselves simpler.
Scott: it basically has all these basic pieces from ticket to ride there's dice rolling, there's things from Settlers there's things from Risk, there's things from Small World.
Rym: there's really good little pieces to stack the people and pieces are really good.
Scott: it's like the generic mechanics the fundamental mechanics of the main euro games of the world sort of combined into one in a really flat kind of way.
Scott: it could be exciting for someone who hasn't played tons of euro games and seen all this before but for anyone else, looking for a hard game looking for a complex game looking for an exciting game
Rym: if you're skilled at games at all the game just breaks down to being 100% purely political.
Rym: whatever event happens just use it to hurt whoever's beating you as much as you can, or help yourself and get the most points.
Scott: it's like one of those games where there's a map and you can go around attacking people if you want to but it doesn't really get you anywhere and it just costs you a lot.
Scott: so everyone just sort of expands into a bunch of hexes at the start and then locks themselves in the end as opposed to, say, tempest or dingy where you're constantly bashing on other people.
Rym: anyone who tried to break out or fight just sort of petered out victory point-wise because you lose all your dudes and I literally won because people didn't attack me enough.
Rym: so I just got no points.
Scott: there's a limit, a number of dudes in a space.
Scott: you move all your dudes into a space and crowd someone out and try to kill them, and then you lose your dudes also and now you have to spend an action the most limited thing in the game, your actions getting more dudes whereas if you had stayed put, you could have spent an action flipping over some cards.
Scott: that might have been worth points or getting some resources to build a hut.
Scott: that would have been worth points.
Rym: the other problem is that it's one of those games where there's nothing to do when it's not your turn nothing at all.
Scott: at least people's turns are short because they're two actions, but I think it actually would have been better to just do 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1, 1 to make the game go around faster.
Scott: ever since Ticket to Ride, I've noticed and still harp on this that a modern game a good tenet of modern game design is where players either A, play simultaneously going constantly so you're always engaged with the game or B, lots and lots and lots of short actions you're going around taking turns.
Scott: those turns better be very very small and if you want to have different kinds of turns have different phases in your game.
Rym: there is a weird C alternative that I've seen particularly in 18XX games a game where there's nothing you can do when it's not your turn but there's so much planning to do that every second you have.
Rym: when it's not your turn, you're engaged with the game thinking and planning and counting things.
Scott: or Bonanza, it's not your turn, but you can engage with the player's turn.
Scott: it is, even when it's not your turn.
Scott: but the point is, games where you're taking one player's turn and everyone else is taking a nap.
Rym: that's not good for any genre of board game anymore, in the present day speaking of which, as much as I want to play Samurai Sword / Shogun / Ikusa it's pretty much, Scott's taking his turn, everyone just go eat.
Scott: well, that's true to some extent because before it's your turn part, there's the bidding part which is simultaneous and then well it's the combat phase, the combat phase is.
Rym: I put on the board the twenty fights I'm going to start and then we do all twenty fights in order also.
Scott: that's an old game.
Rym: it is a very old game.
Scott: also, if that was a new game I wouldn't cut it any slack.
Scott: also, when you're fighting someone at least they're also rolling d12s even though the other people at the table are sleeping.
Scott: two people are rolling d12s together so it's not 100% sleep mode.
Rym: so yeah, this game, if you have kids or you're introducing kind of basic not super gamer-y friends
Scott: I say if you don't have a Settlers, you don't have a Ticket to Ride you don't have any of the basic Euro games you can get this one and save yourself the trouble of all the other
Rym: ones,
Scott: but I think actually any one of those other ones might be more fun than this.
Rym: this has to be for people who are younger.
Scott: this game isn't bad.
Scott: the problem is it has nothing exciting.
Scott: it's just a straight "meh".
Scott: there's no flaw in its design, I can say "oh, the game's broken over there" because it's not, right?
Scott: there's no, other than the slow turn-taking thing.
Rym: and actually, once you know how to play the game the turns go real quick, too.
Rym: it's not even that big a concern.
Scott: yeah, it's easy to learn, the rules weren't written.
Scott: maybe there was one or two things in the rulebook we might have questioned, but nothing huge and devastating like other games.
Scott: I can't find any fault in it.
Scott: that's devastatingly bad.
Scott: there's just nothing about it.
Scott: that's really great.
Scott: that makes me want to play it.
Rym: yeah, I never need to play it again and I feel like I've plumbed the fullness of its depths after two plays after one play but the two plays was like a confirmation.
Scott: the second play was not different from the first play
Rym: and the fact that you played without me and you feel the same way confirms my feelings, so yeah, if you have kids or you play with people who are not gamers this is a good
Scott: game, otherwise
Rym: it's not for
Scott: us.
Rym: this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott, special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows, SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: and now I leave you with...
Scott: I'm laughing for real right now.
Rym: I'm laughing for real right now.