Rym: It's Wednesday, February 6th, 2019.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We review spider-man into the spider-verse.
Rym: Let's do this So, uh in case you didn't notice Or are a complete tool.
Rym: global warming is kind of a problem like we got to do something about being climate change climate change Which is which is effectively global warming.
Rym: Mm-hmm Good like hey, no, it's pretty much never good.
Rym: We don't want to change the climate.
Scott: It's good if it's warm.
Rym: It's good in New York.
Rym: It is good in the Lewis blackaway.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Exactly, right.
Scott: and for me, they'll be less if it the entire world on average gets warmer.
Scott: I don't care about those in the world.
Scott: New York will be warmer more often.
Scott: I can go outside more often snowed on less off until New York starts having malaria and bedbugs That will be bedbugs.
Scott: I mean that hasn't happened yet.
Rym: So I'll put it this way that thinking is obviously a joke, but that thinking is the same thing.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: The same thinking is.
Rym: it's the same thing.
Scott: It's a joke when I say it, but this problem is other people say and they're not joking and they're just morons.
Rym: Well, here's the thing.
Rym: It's the same as I both do not want people to be hurt by tornadoes and fucking love tornadoes.
Rym: so if a tornado happens and I did not cause that tornado I can enjoy the existence of the tornado with Independent of the fact that I am sad people are in the path of that tornado.
Rym: Mmm, like I didn't make the tornado happen.
Rym: if I did there's a whole other problem going on.
Rym: So I skied this weekend right top man.
Rym: Yeah, so I skied this weekend and we'll put the flute away link two hours from where I live.
Rym: I went skiing and it was negative six degrees while I was skiing Fahrenheit woman like.
Rym: so I ski like I like winter sports.
Scott: What is negative six F and C?
Rym: It's It's just F. Negative six.
Rym: C is F you.
Rym: So negative six.
Rym: F is the equivalent of literally if any skin one square Centimeter of your skin is not covered by something for you for you international people who are like saltwater freezes.
Scott: Negative six.
Scott: Fahrenheit is negative 521 Celsius.
Rym: That means that salt water.
Rym: you put salt out to prevent ice from happening.
Rym: The salt will be frozen in the ice Mm-hmm.
Rym: That's what it's.
Rym: so I went skiing.
Rym: It was negative six when I started skiing that morning.
Scott: Well, I guess it must have been some great skiing cuz everything snow was gonna melt.
Rym: It was and every was too cold.
Rym: No one else was skiing.
Rym: So the mountain myself.
Rym: Yeah by the afternoon.
Rym: It was 35 degrees F.
Scott: Let's add that snows gonna melt yo.
Scott: Well, thank you slowly.
Scott: It's a little bit above.
Scott: It's like single-digit Celsius.
Rym: I mean, I don't want to get into the nuances of skiing But 35 is actually pretty good skiing weather for reasons, but just don't let's not derail here a Couple days later as in yesterday, so I skied on Saturday.
Rym: yesterday was what Monday.
Scott: yesterday was Tuesday.
Scott: Wednesday.
Scott: Today is Wednesday Today's Wednesday.
Scott: Yeah, it's a Wednesday podcast.
Rym: I originally said Thursday and it was now.
Rym: take.
Rym: Okay, I'm a little tired.
Rym: So I went running last night in shorts and a t-shirt because it was like 60 degrees.
Scott: It was like 58 59.
Rym: Yeah, it was in the it was near 60.
Rym: So the thing is for me that's still cold and for me that is running shirtless.
Scott: It's like obviously much much warmer and more comfortable than negative six.
Scott: I will gladly take it over negative six.
Scott: I'm not complaining but it's still cold.
Scott: I need to be one.
Rym: Scott You have gotten weak.
Rym: I remember weird RIT.
Scott: Let's remove all your hair and we'll see what you think.
Rym: Oh true.
Rym: We both had hair back then.
Rym: now only one of us has hair At least on the top bit, but I remember in those days and RIT I just transplant all my not my bottom hair to my top.
Rym: if it hit 50 degrees Fahrenheit shorts weather Like the Sun is out.
Rym: so anyway So a thing about skiing is that ski resorts have to tell you the snow conditions the snow report.
Rym: that's the thing.
Scott: Yeah, it's not like ice skating.
Scott: We can go ice skating in the summer.
Scott: Yeah, it's like there's a. you know, we're swimming pool.
Scott: That's always just one.
Rym: like if you're gonna go out on the ocean.
Rym: Yeah Like when we were in you gotta check the bacteria the tides the waves.
Rym: when we were in Australia the hotel gave us a report.
Rym: That's like here's the tides for today.
Rym: Here's the weather conditions.
Rym: Here's the storm that's coming Etc.
Rym: So skiing is the same thing.
Rym: You can every snow mountain will have a report the snow report, but the thing is Ski resorts never want to tell you shit sucks.
Rym: Don't come.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: So there's actually since they're seasonal, right?
Scott: It's like all summer shit sucks.
Scott: Don't come.
Scott: so except unless it's a super tall mountain or something.
Rym: So luckily there are some standards so people they will.
Rym: there are names of particular kinds of conditions and They'll write a bunch of paragraphs that are basically trying to Imply to you that skiing will be great.
Scott: Well, don't?
Scott: they usually just tell you like the number of open trails?
Scott: And then that is like that is enough to go on because the trails are always open.
Scott: Oh, they open them even if there's like just grass there.
Rym: Well, no if there's snow on it It'll be open but that snow might be.
Rym: there's many kinds of snow.
Rym: You see for example, solid ice is a kind of snow.
Scott: Well, they keep it open with solid ice.
Scott: So sometimes that sounds not good.
Scott: one time at Killington I was sounds like you're good trying to get a lawsuit because like you shouldn't have kept you good They you shouldn't have kept that trail open.
Scott: It was just deadly.
Scott: They won't call it ice, but I digress it was solid ice followed by jagged rocks.
Scott: Why did you keep that trail open one time?
Rym: I was at Mount Killington and I went on a trail called bunny buster, which is like a blue like an intermediate trail.
Rym: It was the end of the day.
Rym: The weather was shitty and I was just like I'm just gonna ski down this one run and I'll be done.
Rym: I fell over near the top because it was just solid fucking ice and I slid the entire way down the mountain.
Rym: It was so slippery.
Rym: I could not stop myself.
Rym: I slid like 3/4 of a mile.
Scott: Did you see anyone else sliding?
Rym: Uh, no, but I saw a few people who were kind of like near the edge of the trail watching me Debating how they themselves were gonna get down.
Scott: Oh, so you're just like alone.
Rym: I was alone just Slowly.
Rym: people on the other less shitty parts of the mountain.
Scott: Okay Everyone else got word that that was not a good.
Rym: actually Kate Adam and Emily were with me on this trip.
Scott: Do they go slide down?
Rym: that Adam slid down us?
Rym: So I think he actually also slid down buddy buster before me, but we didn't meet up.
Rym: He didn't.
Rym: I did not see him.
Rym: so he could warn me to stay away from bunny buster.
Scott: They busted more than but busted my bunny.
Rym: But anyway, so hunter mountain.
Rym: now Where was negative six when I was skiing?
Rym: tomorrow is going to be?
Rym: 50 degrees and raining so no skiing.
Rym: so the snow report Is trying to.
Scott: even if they use their snow machine it would just melt.
Rym: I'm gonna read a sentence from the snow report and you see if you can tell how they've massaged this quote.
Rym: Our snow makers have put down a ton of snow this season and we are confident that this brief rain event Will not impact our conditions significantly.
Scott: That sounds like a lie.
Scott: I know it's 50 degrees.
Scott: Here's how about?
Rym: expert skier reads this our conditions are so shitty that this rain doesn't mean shit.
Rym: They can't get any worse.
Rym: I'm not going skiing on Saturday.
Scott: I mean even if they keep using the snow maker wouldn't just be mush.
Rym: They can't use the snow maker to be gone above a particular temperature.
Rym: But just that phrase will not impact our conditions significantly.
Rym: that it takes an expert to understand what that sentence me.
Scott: What if they use the same technology they use in an ice skating rink, right?
Scott: Except they just put it on the side of the mountain to that would be too energy intensive.
Rym: It would be literally infeasible.
Rym: But anyway the technical term for the conditions is frozen granular and that is a. they can't lie about that.
Rym: So smart people just read the thing that says this many lifts this many trails base depth And what is the technical name of the surface?
Rym: So yeah in actual animation news.
Scott: so every year the New York International Children's Film Festival comes to New York and Provides us with.
Scott: you know, it's Children's Film Festival in name But it has a lot of animations and also non animations films to show Among which is usually some top tier anime movies that you can't see anywhere else in English.
Scott: Also, just at least not for a while.
Scott: It used to be that you'd see it.
Scott: that would be like your only chance to see that movie in English in the u.s.
Scott: But more lately it's.
Scott: you see it at the film festival and then like three to six months later it's in US theaters.
Rym: so that a lot of Will be that it's there first or it's there early or like the directors.
Scott: We've seen a lot of like, you know premieres there.
Rym: Yeah, we've seen a lot of anime directors Talk about their movie at this film festival exactly including the best moment ever where that kid was like What's your favorite character?
Rym: And I hope it's King Cosmo.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: We saw summer wars there hosted.
Scott: It was there, right?
Scott: So anyway, we've been going to this thing for a long time.
Scott: So it's it's an early part of the year.
Scott: It's always great.
Scott: It's coming up and the two big animes they're showing is one of them is called Oko's Inn Which I guess is about a girl who runs it in or something like that.
Scott: I don't know much about it other than the name.
Scott: Yep, the girls named Oko She's got it in.
Scott: and the other one is what penguin?
Scott: something?
Rym: penguin highway.
Rym: It's based so it's written by the same person who wrote eccentric family the book that was turned into the utterly Fantastic anime, right?
Scott: So the same author wrote, Tomohiko Morimi, has written eccentric family walk on girl, the night is young Walk on girl, etc, etc.
Scott: They also wrote penguin highway and this anime is based on penguin highway.
Scott: But as far as I can tell it doesn't seem like this movie was animated either by the people who animated eccentric family.
Rym: It says, uh, Hiroyasu Ishida Okay, did they?
Scott: were they the person who animated eccentric family?
Scott: I don't think so.
Scott: I don't remember offhand.
Scott: Yeah, and I don't think it's made by.
Scott: it's definitely not made by Masaaki Yuasa who animated to Tommy Galaxy and Walk on girl, so it's like a different anime studio animating another book by the same author.
Scott: But there's also news penguin highway will be in US theaters like April ish.
Scott: So, I don't know if I'll see it at the film festival or just wait until April and see it in a story.
Rym: Yep, there's also a there's other great animation at the film festival.
Rym: tons Yeah, the New York International Children's Film Festival If you live anywhere near New York City, like it's worth a trip into the city to see a couple movies.
Scott: They also.
Scott: they have this really cute opening like short animation with the like stop Right with these little drumming guys.
Scott: I
Rym: love those guys and
Scott: so we see this animation a lot because not only do you see it when you go to the film Festival every screening but also a lot of other screenings in the city for animation are Sponsored or brought to you by or related to the film festival even if they're during other parts of the year.
Scott: Yeah, and that little animation still plays and they mix it up a little bit every year, but it's the same song with the same little stop-motion drumming guys and It's like a thing, you know, if you're in the New York animation scene But you don't you it's like it would be completely new to you if you weren't.
Scott: Yeah, it's like this inside joke and like we're like, oh here they come There's all.
Rym: Moomin Valley is gonna be like.
Scott: there's a bunch of new Moomin movie that CG That's.
Scott: I heard at least one positive comment about it.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I think that one's actually screening at the Scandinavia house And the IFC Center and the SVA theater There.
Rym: you see it there and also eat early dinner there because Scandinavia houses really good food.
Scott: the Swedish meatball.
Rym: Yeah And then the fish and such Something like that.
Rym: So in some anime news Just it like you might have seen rumblings about this But I'm not gonna go into all the details because we're commentary not news, but yes Hey for background people who don't know this is dude Vic Mignogna.
Rym: Anyway full disclosure I've met him I have met with him.
Rym: I've never liked him I have never observed I have personally never run into a specific behavior.
Scott: I could have called him out other than him just being kind of break Yeah, but basically this dude is an anime voice actor most famous for being the voice of Edward Elric in the u.s Dub of Fullmetal Alchemist.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: He appeared at many many anime conventions and still does.
Scott: Yep, and Basically, you know, he was a kind of person who would pander to fans Big time right.
Rym: his panels were basically he would say something to get all the girls in the room to scream at the top Of their lungs and that was the entire panel.
Scott: Like.
Scott: he was basically like like, you know Rym disease, but a worst-case.
Scott: He is like, you know reveling in the fact that teenage girls are screaming for him Even though he's like an old man, basically.
Scott: Yeah, who you know acts like he's younger than he is and He was always sort of like, you know, at least from my perspective.
Scott: Yeah, I don't want to be near this guy.
Scott: I don't like this guy.
Rym: make this guy go away You know now think that interestingly because we don't go to any anime cons anymore And we don't run guys not entertaining, but we're also not in charge of any cons anymore.
Rym: There's actually a lot of video on the internet of me like doing stuff with him in panels And yeah, and then I found out he was just very clear.
Rym: I Do not endorse him at all.
Rym: Yeah, then I found out a video of me on a panel with him.
Scott: I also found out that he was very Jesus II or pretend.
Rym: Oh, you didn't know that.
Scott: Yeah, there's a no I didn't find that out recently.
Scott: I found that out a long time ago.
Rym: He's got like this weird Christian band.
Rym: He's like he's done a bunch of really homophobic stuff.
Scott: Yeah, but anyway.
Scott: So when I found that out, I was turned off to him even more than I was before.
Rym: What's weird is he is not by a long shot The only American anime voice actor who has a really like weird culty religious aspect to his career.
Scott: No, not at all.
Rym: I can name two others who are still active.
Rym: Yeah
Scott: So anyway,
Rym: basically there were always as there are with people like that You know vague suspicions and rumors and people like oh, yeah, he's a creeper and I always got a creeper vibe But
Scott: I always got a vibe, but I never witnessed him doing an actual creepy thing personally.
Rym: Yep So basically a bunch of people to whom he he has done creepy things have stepped forward to Explain and describe the creepy things he has done to them.
Scott: and those things are I believe them a thousand percent because not only Do they match my existing?
Scott: You know impression of him being a creepy dude.
Scott: Yeah, but their description of They're like detailed descriptions of the exact turns of events.
Scott: it tracks exactly exactly match the Personality that I have observed him exhibiting.
Scott: Yeah, so it's like I can imagine this dude doing that exact thing and it totally fits.
Rym: Knowing the other things I've seen that dude do more in the way I know that person behaves and even more to the point Scott and I were having conversation earlier and what came out of it was in 2019.
Rym: Nobody gets the benefit of the doubt, especially white dudes.
Scott: Yeah So it's like.
Scott: it's like there's a imagine.
Scott: if there's a dude and I saw that dude fart a lot and he smelled like farts And I'd be like, oh, yeah that farty dude.
Scott: and then someone came and told me farty dude farted on me I'd be like, I believe you.
Scott: Yep, even though I'd never saw him fart on a person I see him frequently fart and he smells like farts.
Rym: Yep I guess the only time I would give the benefit of the doubt in that situation is if the person who told me they were Farted on was a known fascist a known farter Farter someone who did not subscribe to the Anyway who denied it.
Scott: so now be basically some good people right who have been Abused or harassed or in some way the seal was.
Rym: more and more allegations are coming out Like people are stepping forward.
Rym: I just saw a voice another voice actor step forward.
Rym: Apparently like I just saw some tweets about that.
Rym: Yeah, some people I know personally have stepped out about this.
Scott: so But basically people are like, alright, let's parade out all the bad things This guy did just like we did for all the other bad guys.
Rym: So what's notable here is that there appear to for the first time in this industry in a while be Consequences.
Rym: he has been kicked off of at least one project apparently two projects.
Rym: He's multiple cons have disinvited him as disinvited him as a guest except anime Montessori Which is like the poster child for bad cons, which doubled down on.
Rym: we're not gonna.
Scott: Basically now you can tell which cons are good and bad based on which ones have kicked him out and which ones are still Letting them come in.
Rym: yep, so You can read all the details of this terrible.
Rym: I think it was a video of him like crying apologizing, but I did not watch Link to it and I was like, nope, you can read all this stuff and decide what you want to decide but What I don't understand.
Rym: well, I guess I do understand but the broader Problem I see here is not just that.
Rym: Oh, no, another older white dude is a creeper.
Rym: The problem is that anime cons for a long time now have drawn a like heavily girl represented younger audience and Because of the there's like this feedback cycle where the cons will invite American voice actors because they're cheaper.
Rym: They're easier to get Fans are Obsessed with the characters that these voice actors played and they transfer that obsession to the voice actors.
Scott: Yeah, I don't understand like.
Scott: I guess it's because I don't watch dubs.
Scott: Like.
Rym: I don't think Nicolas Cage is noir spider-man because he voice acted to our spider-man.
Rym: Yep, I won't like like.
Rym: it is weird that that transference occurs.
Rym: Well, I think it's like a baby duckling.
Scott: I mean, it's like it's hard for me to understand period because I've never had that celebrity fan mentality.
Scott: Like I could meet someone that I'm like a true my tremendous fan of like I figured I don't know I could meet like Dr.
Scott: Rainer can is he?
Scott: I'd be like, hey, what's up?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: How you doing, right?
Rym: Like sir, I respect your work.
Scott: I don't get that feeling of like.
Scott: I'm gonna get my game again.
Rym: This is specific.
Rym: this is beyond that.
Rym: this is the like.
Rym: people who are fans of a character Treat an American voice actor.
Scott: I mean, I don't know if Rainer can is and that's why I'm saying I don't know if Rainer can is.
Scott: he is a even a good person.
Rym: I don't think that Rainer fan of games that he has made but I don't think that Rainer can is yet is the dude on The cover of the Puerto Rico box.
Scott: He didn't make a Puerto Rico like a safe art made porter.
Scott: Yes, I never say for the dude on the cover of the almond ray box or res publica.
Rym: I don't think he's the Viking in res publica like.
Rym: I'm not a fan of that Viking and as a result a fan of him because he Like.
Rym: this is a weird thing.
Rym: that seems to happen primarily in anime fandom Specifically and I think the reason it happened is that anime cons Encourage this behavior and as a result the con saw this feedback loop of the fans act like this.
Rym: So these people are popular.
Rym: so we need to encourage this and bring more people like this.
Rym: and the cycle continued until Half the panels and anime cons.
Rym: are American voice actors being treated like this, right?
Scott: It's like hey, I can bring this person to my con.
Scott: It's not that expensive.
Scott: It'll drag.
Scott: It'll increase attendance at my con.
Scott: It will be profitable.
Scott: Why obviously you do that, yep.
Rym: And as a result anime cons across the board have excused not let's forget the harassment thing Just in general really shitty behavior by not all but many American voice actors not just Mary But I have a lot of that conventions.
Scott: in general Con guests particularly the American voice actor guests are deaf are in a great Guess at any convention of any kind especially the nerdy conventions are always in a position to where?
Scott: They can behave poorly and get away with it.
Scott: Yep They're not going to be kicked out.
Scott: They're being paid to be there.
Rym: Why is notable in the packs is kick some people out?
Scott: Yes, but it's like you paid someone to be there.
Scott: You're not going to then throw them out on their ass.
Scott: You have like a contract with them, right?
Scott: You know, it's like it's if you're in a tough position, especially when you're a small anime con and not a pack.
Scott: But look at how like and that present that person is usually going.
Scott: if they're a guest They're usually someone who has fans that they have a great deal of power over.
Scott: Right because those people do have that.
Scott: I'm a guy feeling right.
Rym: I have a huge number of like first-hand accounts myself that I interacted with an experience to observe of a lot of anime voice actor guests at a number of conventions acting like complete pieces of shit to the Volunteer staffers trying to help them out Showing up late to panels and not in the funny like you expect Duke Nukem to show up late and hung over to the panel.
Rym: That's part of his shtick like that.
Rym: That's fine but I'm talking like just doesn't fucking show up to a panel that are being paid to do until like an hour later and Nonsense like that and just demanding staffers like go out and get them sandwiches and things like really weird stuff.
Scott: Very Hollywood attitude which they're actors, but it's like, you know You're not that big an actor and even if you were you would still be an ass.
Scott: Yep, right It's like if I become super famous, I'm not doing that shit.
Rym: So I wouldn't be surprised if there were a number of other people Rym would tell someone to get him a sandwich.
Rym: Uh, no Who would have.
Rym: let's see I've been in situations where I've had like the green room and the pampering treatment.
Rym: I don't think I've ever asked anyone for anything.
Scott: Usually cuz I'm thankful for what I can get.
Scott: Yeah, I think part of his unique.
Rym: when kai-fu like the last time kai-fu flew me out flew me out to Oregon to give a Speech they were they bought me.
Rym: I didn't even ask.
Rym: They just took me to dinner and like bought me a beer and I was like, oh awesome.
Rym: Cool.
Rym: Thanks.
Rym: This is really fun.
Rym: I was almost like I almost tried to pay cuz it was awkward that they were buying me dinner.
Rym: But anyway things of the day.
Rym: I've been rewatching Star Trek Voyager.
Rym: It's way better than I remember partly because everything better to watch.
Rym: So it's a show I watch when I'm like exercising downstairs like if I'm on the exercise bike because it's why don't you watch the time of galaxy?
Scott: so we can you know, Why?
Rym: because there's no internet downstairs in the gym.
Rym: Oh and like the internet super slow, like it won't work like LTE won't even work that well in that room You could do the the the save offline.
Rym: Yes crunchyroll doesn't really work like that.
Rym: So I can only really watch things that I can download via Netflix and cash and Star Trek I can download.
Rym: I've been watching Star Trek But I think the reason I have fun I like Star Trek Voyager now and I didn't like it when I was younger is that when there aren't Commercials that show is way better.
Scott: I mean there aren't commercials.
Scott: any shows way better Yeah, but the you can't erase his laugh tracks, but that's not a comedy.
Scott: So not a problem.
Rym: Yeah, there aren't really laugh tracks not Star Trek.
Rym: But I was also.
Rym: I did because it was an earlier era and I was more tolerant of commercials I did watch.
Rym: like most of the next generation and You know lieutenant wharf is a character.
Scott: the clip the head.
Rym: yeah the half-cling on guy cool, dude.
Scott: Uh, I thought he was a full-cling.
Scott: I'm pretty sure it was a half-cling.
Scott: I know I don't have.
Scott: I'm the non Star Trek nerd.
Rym: Yeah, well, all right.
Rym: was Spock a full Vulcan or half Vulcan.
Scott: I'm pretty sure he is a full one.
Rym: What about to buck?
Scott: I don't know who that is.
Rym: He's the Vulcan in Voyager.
Scott: I don't know that.
Rym: Okay, you're anyway, you're wrong, but so this video is 15 minutes of wharf getting told to stand the fuck down and shut the fuck up.
Rym: It's basically every time wharf is like commander will do this and someone is like nope the lay of that order.
Rym: Nope What you said is being taken under advisement.
Rym: It's just wharf getting shut down again and again and again for 15 full minutes.
Rym: It is glorious to watch.
Scott: I mean, that's right.
Scott: So shows have tropes right usually like that, you know, like.
Scott: But if a show has that many episodes like next generation does how many episodes have?
Scott: like a hundred there's a lot of.
Scott: It's like a fist of the North Star Number of episodes, right?
Scott: It's like now you have the power to make a montage like that Just showing every single or a compilation not a montage.
Scott: Whatever Mosaic, I just I've always enjoyed the the put them on a grid like a mosaic and the play ball Simultaneous the compilation video of all the times.
Rym: a thing happens in a thing.
Rym: Yep, and this is one of those Points out in the chat wharf is in fact a full Klingon Tom Hanks raised by humans.
Scott: Tom Hanks peed in a movie.
Rym: Oh Tom Hanks peed in movies.
Scott: That's a classic geek.
Scott: best thing of the day.
Rym: Tom Hanks peed in movies was the thing that made me realize that This kind of compilation could be any in a more recent movie.
Scott: I feel like I assume he did.
Scott: he peed in it.
Rym: He had to have.
Scott: I don't there's no way you didn't pee.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: So what do you got?
Scott: I forget what did I have?
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: Yeah, so New York City has a lot of fancy stores.
Scott: I actually work.
Scott: I The first job know.
Scott: the second job and my current job in the city Are very close to the or in the fancy clothing district.
Rym: my previous job before I moved to my current job We actually our office moved to the fashion district, right?
Scott: So there's.
Scott: there's actually three this sort of three different fashion districts, right?
Scott: There's Fifth Avenue.
Scott: Yeah We're like You know the Apple store and like touristy zone and that's where like ultra expensive stores are like Bergdorf Good man and shit, right.
Scott: then over and like Sixth Avenue is the fashion district Which is where you pay less taxes if you're in a fashion business.
Rym: Yep So there's a lot of wholesale places selling fabric and accessories like are we were a tech company today?
Scott: That's where there used to be like textile mills.
Rym: Yeah We were a tech company in a building that everyone else was a fashion company of some kind.
Rym: So all that meant was literally everyone in the building was way better dressed than anyone who worked in my company.
Scott: And then where I work down in Soho is basically lots of little boutique II fashion stores, right?
Scott: But anyway up in the In the more closer to the Fifth Avenue area, right is an Eve st.
Scott: Laurent, which is I guess some fancy French Fashion brand of some kind.
Scott: I've heard of it You can always heard of it so that I enough that I can kind of pronounce the big shelves that have a bunch of really Tiny individual handbags where there's just one of each one sitting.
Scott: now I've seen stores where it's a big fancy store and there's like three things.
Scott: No, there's like a table in the middle with like one thing on it, but it's a thousand of the same thing.
Scott: Yeah, and that's it.
Scott: The whole rest of the store is just like lighting and deck anyway.
Scott: So in the front of this store, they had a window display as is often right.
Scott: this window display.
Scott: However was Amazing.
Rym: It's pretty great.
Scott: It was a dance dance revolution machine and the details on it are Make it clear that whoever made this DDR machine knows DDR.
Scott: The lights at the top the buttons for changing songs the bar There's a little grip on the bar the crew everything about this is somebody actually either was a DDR fan or spent the time to study real DDR machines and with that knowledge they created this Game, you can't.
Scott: it's not a game.
Scott: It's just it looks like a DDR machine like an art installation that's all fancy and completely has as completely perfect mirrored surfaces and then The has instead of DDR.
Scott: There's just a TV playing ads for the store, right?
Rym: It looks so good.
Rym: Like if I ever made a custom DDR machine, I want it to look like this.
Scott: Yeah It's like they should make the DDR machine look like this only actually have DDR in it.
Rym: if I ever move to a bigger place I'm getting a fucking DDR machine if I have to make it myself.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So this some crazy nerd like us who's a big DDR fan heard about it went to the store took a video of it Which is great because now I don't have to make a trip in the cold to see it in person.
Rym: It's not cold.
Rym: It's like 50 degrees out there.
Scott: It's still too cold.
Scott: Why should I make an extra trip?
Scott: Just look at this thing in the meta moment.
Rym: The GeekNights book club book will be 2001 2001 A Space Odyssey, so I have not yet continued reading it.
Scott: But last night I said to myself, huh?
Scott: I should read which means we're getting closer to me.
Scott: actually I'm remembering to read is the first step towards reading.
Rym: two of our recent panels are on YouTube nostalgia versus game design from Pac South and The 40 games you must play from mag fest both on YouTube.
Rym: You can just watch them.
Rym: It's totally cool.
Scott: They also judged the most recent season of anime, you know a couple weeks ago.
Scott: Yeah, so that's on my youtube channel.
Rym: Yep, I'll link to that to remind everyone especially because it's a Wednesday.
Scott: It's a Wednesday shows why I brought it up and we will.
Rym: we can announce at least one of our packs.
Rym: East panels.
Rym: We will on Friday at 3 30 p.m That's a real good time.
Rym: That's a good time.
Rym: Also.
Rym: It doesn't overlap my enforcer shift.
Scott: Nah That's right.
Rym: Yeah good.
Rym: Yeah, that's like perfect storm.
Scott: Go do the panel Friday then go do my enforce.
Rym: It's just like Pac South.
Rym: our power.
Rym: Friday is basically to be keynote Q&A Lunch panel enforce like it's gonna be a great day.
Scott: All right, so we wait but PAX East starts on Thursday.
Rym: Yeah, so we got a whole.
Rym: we actually right god damn it.
Scott: We're actually gonna see that keynote on Thursday and we're gonna do this panel on Friday.
Rym: Ah four day packs is I forgot?
Rym: cuz I Just went to two three day packs.
Rym: We go to a lot of goddamn taxes, okay, so this panel will be a brand new panel.
Rym: the real harm of games.
Scott: Oh, yeah, I finally got the panel.
Scott: I wanted to do on the schedule.
Scott: Yeah, cuz you know we put it up doing them boring Rym panels.
Rym: There's always a Panel with every packs of like.
Rym: what panel do we do?
Rym: Like which one do you want?
Rym: and sometimes packs will surprise me?
Rym: Like I've got two panels that I think are like the highest brow like this is some serious heavy shit.
Rym: And they're like, we really want the top 40 panel because that that like that's for this con.
Scott: I'm just really curious how it's gonna go over when I go to this game positive Convention and just say games are bad for a whole hour.
Scott: Look at all the bad things games do.
Rym: The thing is these are conversations we need to have about gaming.
Scott: we sure do.
Rym: there's a reason I have not opened the like 581 loot boxes.
Rym: I've got an overwatch.
Scott: I thought you said he had thousand loot boxes.
Rym: No, I'm gone.
Rym: I'm going for a thousand.
Rym: I've got like 581.
Scott: I wonder if who has the most unopened loot box in the world.
Rym: I wonder if anything is.
Rym: you could just buy loot boxes, but that would be cheating.
Scott: But Pete someone who pays for them is gonna open them.
Scott: No one's buying loot box.
Scott: No one's buying a thousand loot boxes and holding on to them.
Rym: Yeah, I wonder does anyone have more loot boxes than me I'm gonna?
Rym: I'm gonna try to find out.
Scott: you should just post on the overwatch reddit.
Rym: I will like.
Scott: I have 581 open unopened loot boxes.
Scott: Does anyone have more?
Rym: Yeah without paying Honestly, the only reason I do.
Rym: it is because it really angers people who see me streaming overwatch.
Rym: Mm-hmm And that alone is worth.
Scott: How do they see if you're playing the game how many loot boxes you have?
Scott: I guess they'd only see when you like when I'm in the menu before I go in.
Rym: Okay, and sometimes between matches I'll just go look at him Like I'll go through it.
Rym: I'll like hover over the open button like nah So, let's talk about spider-man into the spider-verse.
Scott: so this movie was high.
Rym: So no spoilers.
Rym: when we're gonna will warn you before we spoil can't really spoil.
Rym: anyway I mean, she turns it Peter Parker.
Scott: If you don't know the story of spider-man and that spider-man fights a bad guy and beats them I don't know what to tell you.
Rym: There are moments to spoil but we'll avoid spoilers.
Scott: But that's I mean, that's what happens in the movie, right?
Scott: It's good bad guy spider-man wins.
Scott: It's good.
Rym: If you don't know who the other villain is, right?
Scott: Anyway, so This movie was hyped big time and usually me Scott is like no superhero move.
Scott: Yep for someone who reads superhero comics That's pretty interesting.
Scott: Like why does Scott not want to see the Marvel?
Rym: superhero movies are largely very boring in my opinion.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, I mean I have an even worse opinion of.
Scott: you know I saw that first spider-man one that we saw back at RIT where he hangs upside down and kisses.
Rym: That was all I like that movie.
Scott: That's the first Sony one.
Scott: I like that one.
Scott: Yeah, I mean it wasn't bad, but it wasn't like wasn't great.
Rym: Yeah, I don't need to ever see it again.
Scott: I've seen.
Scott: I like 1989 Batman.
Scott: You know, it's in Burton Batman.
Scott: I I mean but most you know, if you're going back Like I like beat ass a thousand times more.
Rym: mask of the phantasm was probably one of my favorite superhero movies of all time and
Scott: continuously have hyped up other superhero movies like those newer Batman's like the Batman begin and then Dark Knight is like people fucking are like Lose their shit over Dark Knight, and I saw that and was like
Rym: Me, I think the Tim Burton.
Scott: I thought the one before Batman begin right was was just bad.
Scott: Yeah, we did an episode about it way back.
Rym: It was too many movies crammed into one movie.
Scott: Anyway, so because other people's opinions have frequently clashed with mine and the feeling I get when I see the few superhero movies I've seen is nothing like the feeling I get when I read a superhero comic book that I like.
Scott: Yeah I basically just not bothered to watch any of them and I've seen actually Breathe glimpses of some of them seen here seen there like it's on a TV.
Scott: I'm in the room or I see it on someone else's TV on a plane or something like that.
Scott: and everything I've seen has Only cemented my opinion that yes I don't need to watch any Avengers or any Iron Man's or any of that nonsense.
Rym: So me and Emily went to see spider-man into the spider-verse and when we came out of it What I said to Scott was it's the best goddamn superhero movie ever made.
Rym: the hype is 100% real.
Rym: it exceeded expectations And it is the times I can think of where Either Scott or myself have gone into any form of media a game a movie anything and had our expectations exceeded.
Rym: It's happened like twice.
Scott: so I was already I was already planning to make an exception for this movie because a it was animated and to the animation from the teaser looked Phenomenal well and B because I had heard that spider-man 2099 Is in it.
Scott: if you don't know when I was a kid I went to comic book store and I bought x-men with no adjectives.
Scott: adjectives x-men up because it's early 90s And I bought spider-man 2099. and the reason I bought spider-man 2099 is Because when I was a kid Amazing spider-man was issue like a bajillion or something and I was like I. I felt I got to start at number one.
Scott: I can't be starting at some Random crazy number and I know what's going on.
Scott: I gotta start at number one.
Rym: I did the opposite.
Rym: I just started with random x-men whatever and I also know what the fuck was going on.
Scott: and also 2099.
Scott: It's like oh, it's the future.
Scott: I love that.
Scott: I'm a nerdy kid.
Scott: I love the future right and that is why I didn't read William Gibson Neil Stevenson shatter-run cyberpunk anything until RIT days.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: I knew all cyberpunk shit Thanks to Peter David's spider-man 2099 that I read religiously and bought every single issue.
Scott: as a kid Even when the comic book store went out of business, I went to great lengths to get every single issue I could.
Scott: I have every single issue.
Rym: and when I'm so when I told Scott I was like I like I basically the hype train is 100% real.
Rym: Holy shit.
Rym: All Scott said all Scott asked was is Spider-man 2099 in it.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: And my answer was yes But anyway So I eventually also was able to see it on Christmas.
Scott: like a good Jew.
Scott: I went to the movie theater.
Scott: So I went and saw as I was planning to do.
Rym: I went and saw it again in the theater on Christmas.
Scott: I was not in any great hurry.
Scott: I saw it one time.
Rym: Yep, but uh I went to a theater to see a movie twice While it was out.
Rym: This isn't like going to the theater to see like Star Wars Episode 4 again.
Scott: It was the last time I did that I went to the matrix twice.
Rym: I Maybe I think that was the last time.
Scott: Oh, I've been to the matrix twice because I saw it when it was new and then we saw it again in that I'm ex Theater at Tinseltown.
Rym: Yeah, I saw it a third time.
Scott: then that was my second.
Scott: I might have been my second in high school.
Rym: I went to it and I was like, whoa, holy shit.
Rym: And then I got all my friends.
Rym: like guys you got to see the matrix Because I want my friends the first time.
Rym: well Cuz when I went with some of my friends then I went with the rest of my friends But I went into the matrix not actually knowing what it was about.
Rym: Mmm, so it helps anyway, so Spider-man into the spider-verse is easily the best spider-man movie ever made.
Rym: that's easy from any Generation any country any perspective any measure of greatness?
Rym: It is the greatest.
Scott: and two, I think it is the greatest Video animated or live-action spider-man Thing of any form.
Rym: I think that is true.
Scott: I think there may be Spider-man comics that are better.
Scott: maybe but it's close.
Rym: Yep I can also say that this might be it's too soon to say There is a tiny chance.
Rym: Spider-man into the spider-verse is on the very short list of movies where I will watch it anytime and never get sick of it.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: It's too soon.
Rym: But this is a list that has things like I mean Star Wars Episode 4.
Rym: Yeah, I mean the only in the Holy Grail.
Scott: Yeah, those are the only kinds of things I could watch repeatedly.
Scott: I don't know ultra top even if I go to things that are really good, but our second tier Yeah I have a hard time watching them repeatedly.
Rym: But when I went to see it again in the theater the second time not that long after I saw it the first time I Wasn't super hyped because I've seen it before like I was going just because a friend of ours Hadn't seen it and it was Christmas and wanted to do a thing About two minutes into the movie.
Rym: I got real hype again, and I did not expect to feel that right.
Rym: So I also noticed a bunch of stuff.
Rym: I didn't notice the first time.
Scott: Oh, that's definitely gonna happen.
Rym: and I saw it 3d the first time 2d the second time.
Scott: Oh interesting.
Rym: So it works in 2d.
Rym: I It is objectively better in 3d.
Scott: Yeah, I mean if you watch it at home, how you gonna watch in 3d?
Rym: You can't.
Rym: so you gotta at least see it in the theater once if you want to see it in 3d.
Rym: Yes, it is still in the theater, holy shit.
Rym: right now we could go see it in 3d at the legit normal theater around the corner.
Rym: Yeah, how much is 40
Rym: p.m.?
Rym: 3. there's like four showings.
Rym: There's a showing.
Rym: we could go see it tonight At the coffee story.
Scott: Are we gonna be done with the show?
Scott: Anyway, so the main thing that there's really two main things.
Scott: They're sort of tied together.
Scott: Anyway The first thing is that when you look at a lot of the superhero movies, right?
Scott: It seems like what they do.
Scott: is they take the core truth of the original comic, right?
Scott: Spider-man is a dude named Peter Parker.
Scott: He's a photographer for the newspaper.
Scott: He's got a girl named Mary Jane.
Scott: Yeah, right the bad guy.
Scott: It looks like this, right?
Rym: These core facts.
Scott: but then they with those core facts, they tell a story and In you know both the cinema the writing and also the cinematography They tell a story in the Hollywood blockbuster way.
Rym: Yep, right There's main villain sub villain potentially tertiary villain that will be in the sequel movie.
Scott: They and also, you know nerds, you know We always rag and rag on nerds for complaining about this.
Scott: Right because it is just sort of a nerdy thing to complain about.
Scott: but they get lots of details and they change them for seemingly No reason right?
Scott: It's like why is spider-man's web shooters biological in the comic book?
Scott: They were mechanical, right?
Scott: It's like why did you change the costume?
Scott: Why did you change the dude?
Scott: Right?
Scott: You change all these little things, right?
Scott: Just you know, and nerds get upset even though those aren't really, you know of severe consequence, right?
Scott: yet spider-man into the spider-verse comes along and Even though it is an animated movie it tells a story Cinematographically and also in terms of the writing.
Scott: the same way a comic book tells a story.
Rym: It doesn't feel like a Hollywood movie.
Scott: it feels like I'm reading the comic book only I don't got a fucking read.
Rym: Yep and what's even crazier is that it tells a Spider-man origin story and the traditional wisdom is there are two kinds of superhero movies.
Rym: either We're gonna do the origin story that's been done a hundred times again, or we're gonna.
Scott: we're gonna skip it.
Scott: You already know.
Rym: Yep, or we're gonna well or we're gonna skip it.
Rym: You know who the fuck spider-man is.
Rym: or the third one of we're gonna make as many sequels of the one we made with the Origin story as we can before it runs out of steam, right?
Scott: So what they do is that not only they're telling a story in a comic book way they're telling the kind of crazy story that a comic book tells the kind of story that if you tried to put it as a Screenplay for a Hollywood movie blockbuster.
Scott: They would say no It's a story about multiple universes with crazy characters coming together in a big jumble the kind of thing that you see in comic books.
Scott: And you never see a crazy multiverse nonsense crazy story in a movie.
Scott: They always grow in theater and You don't see that.
Rym: that's that's the kind of story that's only in comic books And it does but it does this in so many layers like it does it in a meta level it opens with this trope of Hey, y'all know the story is spider-man bit by a spider It said like.
Rym: it tells the origin story of spider-man like really quick in a comicky way.
Rym: But then the movie itself is the origin story of another spider-man.
Scott: like if you read even a random spider-man Comic-book right you like an old one.
Scott: It's like even you'll see you buy a spider-man I don't know like 80 or something right.
Scott: the first page I'm willing to bet says like Oh bit by a radioactive spider Become spider-man and then it picks up wherever the last issue left off.
Scott: yeah, right It's like.
Scott: and that's exactly the kind of storytelling mechanic that is directly transferred from the comic to this movie But not other movies.
Scott: right it's like origin of spider-man, and we're go yep spider-man pick up where we left off.
Rym: So in terms of visuals no movies ever looked like this before.
Scott: Yeah, if you go online as all sorts of things the animators have been surprisingly open.
Scott: I don't know if someone's allowing them to be or encouraging.
Scott: I think Sony realized, but it is very intelligent.
Scott: They're like.
Scott: they're like check out this scene That's like on screen for like a couple seconds of one of the characters like playing the drums During a flashback.
Scott: let me tell you how hard this was to animate and here's all the crazy tricks.
Scott: I did appreciate my work, please and it's like oh my god.
Scott: We appreciate your work.
Scott: Oh my god.
Rym: So I want to read a quote for Wikipedia because this is a really one about the shader on penny Parker.
Scott: Yeah, that was like a low.
Rym: it took around a year for two animators to create ten Seconds of footage that they were happy with and then they made the movie.
Rym: based on the technique.
Rym: They developed two animators for a year and when you look at the credits for this movie.
Scott: They long.
Rym: Oh my god.
Scott: Yeah, also so many people had to poke computers and weird software just as this movie.
Scott: It's like you thought Toy Story was like holy shit right and like now.
Scott: We're just sort of used to CG movies.
Scott: you take it for granted Yeah But it's like actually this may be more of an animation accomplishment or just as equal to feels like Remember when Jurassic Park came out like you'd seen movies with dinosaurs before.
Rym: when I saw Jurassic Park in the theater the entire world said Holy shit.
Rym: Yeah, these are different from this day forward, and I think that's the sort of thing.
Scott: It's like you look at Jurassic Park those effects.
Scott: It's like we had seen a Star Wars already.
Scott: We had seen a Ray Harryhausen already, but they just took it to the next level right?
Scott: so if Toy Story is The Ray Harryhausen you know.
Scott: stop-motion of CG that this is like the Jurassic Park taking it to the next level.
Scott: Yep, right every other Computer-generated animation movie is like at least one or two levels below this.
Scott: I have at least I haven't seen one.
Scott: That's on this level.
Rym: I think what someone said best what bar has been raised?
Rym: as because then there's now there's that other spider-man movie coming out and Someone's a trailer came out and all the comments.
Rym: I saw were along the lines of where are the colors?
Rym: yeah like it Did two animated superhero movies that are based on comic books what Breath of the Wild did to open-world games right?
Rym: It was like wow here's a different way that is objectively better.
Rym: So it does this like crazy combat chromatic aberration thing.
Rym: it looks like a comic book and in 3d It's actually even more pronounced.
Rym: it almost looks like a shadow box of like a layered comic book the entire time and like words will appear Like the Spidey's at the very at the earliest parts of the movie in the early scenes.
Scott: They're actually like bringing in you know a little bit more of that free comic book panel frames And you know text boxes and stuff.
Rym: It's the little time I've ever seen that not like look and like act on.
Scott: yeah like word sound effects like a manga a little Bit like that comic zone game for the.
Scott: yeah This is a little bit like that at the very beginning of the movie But then they pull back on that a little bit But they don't pull back on it completely and you sort of get that.
Scott: you know that same feel for the rest of the movie.
Scott: But it's not over yeah, but well.
Rym: I think it's that it's so well integrated into the aesthetic that it doesn't feel cheap.
Rym: It doesn't feel like a gimmick.
Rym: Yeah, a lot of movies that have tried to do this just felt like a gimmick.
Scott: part of it's also like just the speed Right.
Scott: it's like if you had a cheesy like page turning like oh my god I'd be like all slow.
Scott: you'd be like it really grabs your attention right, but with Like like comic frame comic everything is so fast so that like if there's a cheesy thing.
Scott: It doesn't like distract you from the action right.
Scott: so it just you know gives you this comic book feel in the background But your eye is always on the actual action.
Rym: that matters yep, and meanwhile like the character arcs are fantastic every character is great Right.
Scott: so this is the thing right is like you know I talked about like.
Scott: hey You know nerds always complain about this inconsequential stuff.
Scott: They get wrong right, but actually this movie It's like they could have gotten nerdy stuff wrong.
Scott: It wouldn't have really been a big deal.
Scott: It's inconsequential But the amount of nerdy stuff.
Scott: They did that actually almost exactly matches the comics is Shocking and they didn't have to do it, but they did it right.
Scott: so here's the is the deal right.
Scott: in real spider-man comic books Right there was amazing spider-man.
Scott: That's the real spider-man Peter Parker.
Scott: right in the early 2000s They made this other series called ultimate spider-man And the I. they made this actually whole separate Marvel Universe called the ultimate universe ultimate x-men ultimate Avengers ultimate everything.
Scott: and the idea was hey People like Scott want to start with number one.
Scott: They don't want.
Scott: that's why they bought spider-man 2099 Which is also another universe.
Scott: so sort of it was the distant future of the regular universe whatever They want to start in number one.
Scott: There is no number one.
Scott: We can't let go of these old comic book nerds who if we just delete all the Marvel comics That's not gonna go too.
Scott: Well right, so let's just make new comics and Start at number one with those and a completely separate universe, so they did those.
Scott: ultimate spider-man and Ultimate spider-man is actually not spoilers really because it happens right at the beginning of the movie is The spider-man who dies at the beginning of this movie.
Scott: hmm, and if you read ultimate spider-man what happens in ultimate spider-man?
Scott: There's a spider-man.
Scott: he dies and miles morales is the new spider-man.
Scott: He is ultimate spider-man.
Scott: this movie is in the ultimate universe pretty much exactly Right and all these other spider-men that come in from other universes are actually from other spider-man comic books and are largely faithful to Exactly what happened in those other spider-man comic books right?
Scott: It's like you can go buy the original Penny Parker comic book.
Scott: she doesn't look like that right, but at least her basic story is pretty much exactly What they said in the movie.
Scott: you can go buy the spider-man noir comic books.
Scott: peter porker Spider-ham.
Scott: those are comics that existed way back.
Scott: those are old as hell, and it's like.
Scott: I'm surprised people didn't know about them.
Scott: They're also just as funny as peter porker is in the movie.
Scott: Exact same kind of joke exactly the same.
Scott: his story is exactly the same.
Scott: I'm gonna save because I don't want to explore, but so I'm pretty sure that the the the the dumpy spider-man I'm pretty sure that's just the regular spider-man.
Scott: y'all the real Peter Parker from Bro, Cobo Bro, Cobo spider-man, I'm pretty sure cuz I haven't read spider-man in a long time so but I remember reading.
Rym: You can figure out which spider-man is which based on the details of like every single one of those spider-man's is a spider-man from An actual spider comic book just pretty much exactly as they are in this universe.
Scott: They didn't change shit.
Rym: It's a PDNY instead of NYPD.
Rym: so you can figure stuff out from that right.
Scott: also the company That is the bad guy company in this movie is alchemax.
Scott: That's the company the spider-man 2099 worked for and was super evil.
Scott: Yeah, it's like they didn't change shit.
Scott: They just brought it straight from the comic book, and it's like hey look at you all you Hollywood people You keep changing something that people like you know some of.
Scott: it might seem small, and it doesn't matter.
Scott: But it's like look you didn't change it, and there wasn't a problem.
Scott: So why were you making those inconsequential changes however small and meaningless?
Scott: They may be if there was no reason to so?
Scott: also the story was already written.
Scott: It was already good.
Rym: the music the score is Fantastic all right.
Scott: well it is fantastic.
Rym: It's not Star Wars fantastic But it is.
Rym: it's not Marvel Cinematic Universe boring like.
Rym: here's the song for the part fan.
Scott: It is a. This movie is made by Sony Sony music Sony records.
Scott: let us promote our hit song.
Rym: notice not notice.
Rym: I said the score not the soundtrack the soundtracks good, but I'm talking like the song they use the motif for Prowler Like that was.
Rym: that's the kind of shit that MCU movies Don't do right that song with that like the MCU movies.
Scott: You've already seen the video talking about how they're all boring Hans Zimmer.
Rym: I'm just talking about the score.
Rym: you want to talk to the soundtrack Score.
Rym: the soundtrack works and also the soundtrack does work.
Scott: They made whoever was selecting those so you know they tracks that song a good job.
Scott: But it still sort of stands out as like I see your placement of your hit pop single in this movie.
Rym: Well, what about the song that they basically made for the movie the one that he's humming.
Scott: That's also a song.
Rym: yeah Yeah, that song got stuck into everyone's head on earth not mine.
Rym: It's stuck in mine.
Scott: I don't remember it all.
Rym: The only one I remember is I do really like the closing credits song - It's alright.
Rym: I would both.
Rym: the closing credits are one of the best closing credits animations I've ever seen.
Rym: I love the shit out of those.
Rym: closing credit Is a crime that you can't watch them on YouTube because it's Sony.
Rym: so copyright like I. Those closing credits are phenomenal.
Rym: They they pump you up, which is not what closing credits should do.
Rym: I was more pumped up by the end of the credits, but I wasn't the end of the movie.
Rym: And then we got to see the after credits thing which was There.
Rym: I was surprised they went there, and that was really good.
Scott: Yeah so also right is the Bad guys in the movie?
Rym: well one they didn't do the problem almost every superhero movie does in America of having too many villains.
Rym: They have one villain Who's the main villain?
Rym: and a one other villain teamed up with that.
Rym: there are four villains.
Rym: well two main villains?
Rym: But the maybe five?
Rym: yeah But I think but the point is every sub villain was directly tied to the arc of the main Character and the story as opposed to oh and here's scarecrow.
Rym: for some fucking reason right.
Scott: so first of all they didn't Try to bother putting tons of effort into creating lots of motivations and things around all the villains.
Scott: right.
Rym: well They all had good motivations because of the plot of the movie itself right the the king.
Scott: and also they weren't afraid of using villains That the mass populace had never heard of.
Scott: yup like kingpin spider-man most of spider-man's villains.
Scott: It's not like Batman where people know like the Joker.
Scott: Yeah, it's like most of spider-man's villains are not anyone?
Scott: anyone knows He's got like the lizard and it's like Mysterio.
Scott: yeah in electro It's like the only ones anyone knows are like the people even know dr.
Scott: Octopus or Green Goblin.
Scott: even those aren't like big is you know?
Scott: it's like.
Scott: those are like the big spider-man villains Right.
Scott: so people don't know spider-man villains.
Scott: Yeah kingpin is like a general Marvel villain.
Scott: Who's like more of a daredevil villain, but also spider-man.
Scott: cuz he's a New York.
Rym: But let's talk a bit about that.
Rym: cuz that he's a good example.
Rym: cuz if we talk about all the other villains it gets into plot spoilers stuff.
Rym: but Kingpin as a character design is Phenomenal.
Scott: he looks exactly like it does in the comic book.
Rym: He's just this giant Black brick with this little head on top white.
Rym: no don't like.
Rym: his suit is black.
Rym: He's wearing a black suit.
Rym: the suit is white.
Rym: I feel like there's a bunch of scenes where he's wearing a black suit in this movie.
Scott: kingpin is like That's his thing is he has a giant white suit.
Rym: It's not always a white.
Rym: He's a giant white square.
Scott: He's a giant black square in the white square with juggernauts bald head on top of it.
Rym: I'm talking about in the movie.
Rym: in the movie.
Rym: He's wearing a white suit.
Rym: not every scene.
Scott: I mean you can't watch the movie right now to verify their black suit.
Rym: every image of him is in a black suit.
Rym: like I Said goddamn Scott you just saw this movie anyway.
Scott: anyway They change something.
Scott: they bad.
Rym: they use kingpin so well like on screen.
Rym: He takes up the entire frame.
Scott: He's just a giant Terrifying monster which is exactly how that.
Scott: if you read a comic book at least a good one with kingpin in it.
Scott: That's how he's framed in the panels like there's a norm like it does.
Scott: if you want to read.
Scott: there's like a famous series where daredevil fights the kingpin.
Scott: it's like.
Scott: it's like maybe the best daredevil comics there are and From like I guess the 90s ish.
Scott: I don't remember late 80s Maybe I forget, but it's like the kingpin the way he's drawn in that it's like this huge kingpin.
Scott: It's like what is the superpower?
Scott: being a really big mafia boss, but also just having an enormous body.
Rym: He's big and strong and has a gun.
Scott: that's pretty much it.
Scott: It's like he.
Scott: I don't know if he has any other superpowers nerds.
Scott: Don't call me out on that.
Scott: Yeah, it's like daredevil who's gonna beat him and daredevils his little dude.
Rym: But also they'd like they just like the store like what kingpin is after is a very simple direct and misguided motivation.
Rym: It's not overwrought.
Rym: the story is not about the villains.
Rym: the story is about Miles Morales and the people in his life as he becomes spider-man.
Scott: there are too many stories.
Scott: not that they not that none of them work.
Scott: Right that are that focus on the villains as like the main characters Star Wars or you know the those Batman movies are the Joker's or the focus than Batman.
Scott: They're basically Joker movies right, but those movies often have people wanting to wear Darth Vader costume And now Luke Skywalker costume.
Rym: right you don't want to be kingpin in this movie.
Scott: No one watches this movie wanting to be any.
Scott: maybe someone does but most people watch this movie wanting to be spider-man right.
Scott: yep Spider-man is cool.
Scott: villains are not cool.
Rym: Well.
Scott: I should want to be good guys.
Scott: good guys should be cool.
Scott: It's hard to make good guys cool.
Scott: They actually made good guys cool.
Scott: That's a good job.
Rym: Well because they made kingpin so Chilling that moment.
Rym: That's how he is where.
Scott: that's exactly how he is.
Scott: Yeah, and change, but that moment where spider-man says why is good?
Rym: when spider-man is explaining that your plan It won't do what you think it didn't make mess with a good formula And how he reacts and what he does to spider-man like like that moment was just a an amazing chilling moment.
Rym: There's so many moments like this in this movie, so all you know another thing right.
Scott: so the villains right.
Scott: you got the doctor octopus.
Scott: Also from the comments past this point assume.
Rym: We're gonna spoil some stuff.
Scott: So I think but there's a henchman right in this movie who they do not name the henchman in the movie.
Scott: So a nerd will be like ah Right, but you look at that guy.
Scott: It's tombstone.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: It says a guy is it's it's a. it's like a throwaway Marvel villain character named tombstone.
Scott: He's just like a basically a strong dude who's all white and has white hair and looks like a tombstone And he's in the movie.
Scott: He's just like a gennaro henchman.
Scott: that like keeps recurring like you see him over and over as a henchman doesn't do it.
Rym: He's just.
Scott: if you're not a nerd you won't know that that's a particular guy.
Scott: But they put him in there and didn't.
Scott: that's like yeah, that's.
Scott: he's basically just like a for hire Extra henchman plus plus in comics.
Rym: That's how you do it.
Scott: That's how to make these movies.
Scott: They didn't mess with it.
Scott: They're like.
Scott: Oh, what's good at a Marvel Comics.
Scott: Let's take exactly that and not fuck it up.
Rym: They made him.
Rym: so what's his motivation?
Rym: kingpin fucking paid him?
Scott: He's on a salary how many times right are we?
Scott: and not just superheroes, but like anything where it's like man.
Scott: You know Hollywood always does this and that and people are like oh, but you know they have to do that.
Scott: You know it won't work.
Scott: You know there's like these.
Scott: you know sort of like.
Scott: I don't know what to call it.
Scott: There's like a term for it right sort of like accepted truths right that you know where it's like people.
Scott: You know they do.
Scott: oh, we can't have a we can't have a female lead.
Scott: We'll sell less tickets.
Scott: right It's like.
Scott: well.
Scott: Have you have you tried.
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Scott: Oh, we got it.
Scott: We can't just turn the comic book.
Scott: Americans won't read subtitles right Americans won't read so it gets a good one.
Scott: right where it's like People just believe that and they just accept it and they won't risk.
Scott: not you know going against this sort of.
Scott: you know You know this sort of like.
Scott: you know assumed belief.
Scott: But it's like.
Scott: have you ever tried?
Scott: is where it's like do it the other way to prove me to me that it won't work.
Scott: Right it's like look You just made a superhero movie without changing shit from the comics and doing it exactly what the comic does and the world agrees.
Scott: It's the greatest superhero movie ever made and it was better than all those other times you tried.
Scott: So I guess you were wrong.
Scott: stupid Hollywood.
Scott: Yeah, you just proved you were wrong.
Scott: good job, so I was right all along I guess.
Rym: spoilers past this point cuz I was not much to spoil.
Rym: Yeah, of course it's a spider-man movie.
Rym: I want to talk about a few things.
Rym: so we'll spoil this up.
Rym: if you haven't seen the movie just stop listening.
Scott: It's a happy ending kids movie.
Rym: all we're gonna do is And then end the show.
Rym: cuz we've been going for an hour.
Rym: I think we spend enough time telling you to go see this goddamn movie like go see everyone's already seen it.
Scott: if you haven't seen It is listening to someone talk about the thing They've already seen.
Scott: they already like.
Rym: if you haven't seen it the hype train is real And it's still in theaters.
Rym: You could just go see it at a normal theater like tonight.
Rym: hmm So spoiler wise I think the moment that my favorite moment in the movie is the Doc Ock reveal because Like it really set you up as like oh that scientist cuz you see her in the thing before like the school thing.
Rym: Oh, she's probably like just working for this company.
Rym: He doesn't know what she's doing.
Rym: and when she's like oh spider-man I'm a fan, and he's like oh hey, and they're talking the slow reveal of who she is.
Scott: that was a plus I guess I already knew But I saw that they were doing.
Scott: I was like.
Scott: so when I first saw right I was like.
Scott: I was like oh, it's dr.
Rym: Octopus, but then I was like oh They're not telling anyone So clever also and may and Doc Ock were definitely in a relationship at some point Convinced.
Scott: so the Aunt May right is like when they were like oh, that's the best and may I've ever seen.
Scott: well That's what I'm saying is like when they were gonna go see Aunt May.
Scott: I was like what Aunt May are they going to see?
Scott: yeah, right?
Scott: I was like it's yeah I was like.
Scott: I was like it's the old cuz.
Scott: I hadn't read enough ultimate comics to know what the ultimate and may was like.
Rym: She's a badass right.
Scott: and I was like it's not gonna be old decrepit and may Like oh some villains are here again.
Rym: It's not gonna be dead and Doc Ock shows up, and she's just like live.
Rym: That was the funniest moment in the whole movie.
Rym: Yeah Uh Prowler like Prowler's arc was good.
Rym: I saw that come in the whole movie.
Scott: like I mean Cuz.
Scott: I mean if that's the thing is like.
Scott: you know the story of spider-man, and it's like it's spider-man's uncle.
Scott: well Yep, I was like.
Scott: Oh, that's your uncle vote.
Scott: He is also.
Rym: He is bad and Beauty this movie even if you don't know that there's.
Scott: there's so many like it's spider-man's uncle Ben.
Scott: I wonder what will happen to spider-man's uncle Ben in a different universe.
Rym: Let's say you don't know any of that.
Rym: you don't know who Prowler is or anything.
Rym: it sets it up the cop dad Doesn't trust the uncle.
Rym: yeah for a reason.
Rym: so he just doesn't.
Scott: Spider-man's uncle is not.
Scott: if you find out tomorrow like if your nephew if anyone has a nephew or a niece and they come to You and they say that they are spider-man or a woman get some kind of protection plan.
Rym: But then You know obviously like he's probably got some criminal thing going on like you get that sense.
Rym: the movie Just like if you don't anything else spider-man, but then he gets that phone call is like oh I gotta go take care of something.
Rym: and then he's not in the movie anymore.
Rym: and Like it's it is very easy to connect the dots even if you have never heard of spider-man.
Rym: What's gonna happen in that art?
Rym: I appreciate that.
Rym: and again his light mode like his motif his his song is real good.
Scott: So the only thing missing from this movie for me Which makes sense because it's Miles Morales is the spider-man the main spider-man right is The the the only spider-man you know.
Scott: the I guess core aspect is Daily bugle J. Jonah Jameson.
Scott: yeah, man's got a you know.
Scott: get some pictures of spider-man Parker, right?
Scott: You know all that stuff was not in the movie because it wasn't journalist Peter Parker.
Scott: spider-man.
Rym: Yeah, it's a man.
Rym: so because it's the Miles Morales spider-man movie.
Scott: all the other spider-man are part of his origin story right so But the thing is as someone who was reading spider-man comics J. Well, it's like I wasn't missing it during the movie.
Scott: right it's like during the movie I didn't feel like there was a missing gap because obviously this kid is not a Journalist right.
Scott: so it you know he didn't have you didn't need to make money or anything.
Scott: so it didn't feel like something was missing.
Scott: But then after the movie was over my brain was like oh that spider-man was missing something.
Scott: It's like oh, and I'm like ah, but I'm like.
Scott: I wish it was in there, but there's nowhere to put it in there.
Scott: it's like.
Scott: it's like it's like you finish the puzzle and The puzzle is complete and has no missing pieces, but there is a piece on the side of the puzzle Yeah, and it's like.
Scott: is that from like another puzzle.
Scott: They just got in this box.
Scott: well Cuz and it's like you kind of want to use it.
Rym: well cuz the movies But there's no it the puzzles done cuz the movies dense and complete.
Rym: every arc every Characters arc like completes as much as it needed for something.
Scott: That's all.
Scott: What's it?
Scott: two hours?
Rym: Yeah?
Scott: They managed to fit a lot like there's a usually like you know sometimes movies I'll have like an early scene where it's like in a school, and then the school's forgotten and you're away from it, right Yeah, they managed to get that school part going.
Scott: It's like yeah, eventually they get away from the school And it doesn't matter anymore right cuz he's still a kid in school.
Scott: a lot of high school scenes but the high school scenes were is or they lasted deep enough into the movie and Were substantial enough that it doesn't feel like the way Naruto feels where it's a funny Ninja school for four episodes never funny ninja school again.
Scott: It's like no.
Scott: It's like there was enough of it in the movie that it wasn't just some throwaway leaping off point.
Rym: well That's it.
Rym: Nothing was a throwaway.
Rym: everything matters everything like everything moves quickly.
Rym: Nothing is left unresolved.
Rym: Nothing is left unsatisfying.
Rym: the movie is dense And I struggle to come up with even a single complaint even a minor complaint about the movie, right?
Scott: That's that's like the excellent of like perfect editing right.
Scott: It's like you cut out all the crap You don't need.
Scott: it's like all just good stuff, right?
Scott: Just only even spider only we know.
Scott: chaff and squeeze it real tight like you think.
Rym: oh How are they?
Scott: spider-ham has a like real little arc and he's in the movie I bet for like less than a minute, but I can't You add up all the spider-ham scenes.
Scott: I bet they're like less than like a few minutes.
Rym: The right amount like a good spice.
Scott: but yet you watch this you would never forget spider-ham.
Scott: Yeah They managed to do all spider-ham necessary things in an extremely should small amount of screen time.
Rym: spider-man is Spider-ham.
Scott: they turn people into spider-ham fans with like a minute of a video.
Scott: Yep It's like the voice actor who do voice.
Scott: the spider-ham was probably like and I'm in Like a one-day deal for them.
Scott: right got paid probably not enough.
Scott: Hopefully they get a royalties deal and not just like a flat rate.
Rym: spider-ham Resonated emotionally in this movie.
Rym: That is magic.
Scott: Well, I think people just didn't also had never heard of spider-ham before.
Scott: Yeah, he was in a lot of the advertising I saw on the subway even though I knew what spider-ham was.
Rym: Yeah well I guess what I The thing I like the most about the movie like is the way it framed itself in that it starts with the hey You know the spider-man origin story and then the trope where when the other spider-man appears you get his origin story And then when the three appear it's like here's the three origin stories.
Rym: and then like the the turning point of the movie like the P The moment before we get into the finale is the climax is the moment where the comic book for Miles Morales Falls onto the screen and it's just like here's the spider-man origin story.
Rym: Like that was the moment that the whole movie hinged around and that was that's just such good editing and such good writing.
Rym: So yeah spider-man This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and make comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the GeekNights patreon.
Rym: patrons for this particular February 6th episode of GeekNights are Craig Oliver Alan Joyce Heidi McNichola just like a dude guy kajar Thompson link eg Jennifer Hitchcock Chris midkiff my steady calm j band scoot alone Lee Roberto Kingsley Shawn Yeager Matthew Smith Nicholas Brando, mr.
Rym: Strong's traction for two one creations Chris Reimer and Thomas on Sherman von Horrell Rory Rochelle, Monta, Nona Superboys sailor Vista.
Rym: Gotta scroll this down.
Rym: Okay, here we go Don Schleich Joe Joe Joe star Clinton Walton run from New Zealand Ryan parent through open Lander Finn Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer Thomas Hahn.
Rym: And now I leave you with a blast from the past that may give you a little bit of weird nostalgia.
Rym: Take over the world Exactly, and then we'll sacrifice the world to the monster.
Rym: so magoo star?
Rym: Um, actually, I just want to use the army to take over the world and sooner or later The only threat to my plans will be say room Not only do you wish to take over the world you want to sacrifice it to a monster?
Scott: Your father may forgive you but Amelia will not just the words I was waiting for.
Rym: guards capture this girl.
Scott: Oh, I'm the king Martina.
Rym: So maybe I should father shut up.
Rym: Yes