Rym: It's Tuesday January 29th 2019.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm scared and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We are reviewing the 2014 board game.
Scott: La Cosa Nostra Let's do this.
Rym: We're finally fully back from all those Pax's all those mag fests all that biz.
Rym: All we got coming up is Pax East which won't significantly disrupt GeekNights.
Rym: Mm-hmm We would have done a show last week, maybe two shows, but I did get a Pax Fox.
Rym: It took a few days to kick in but I got a full-on Pax Fox.
Scott: There's a Pax Fox Twitter account.
Scott: if anyone it's pretty good.
Rym: I tweeted at that Twitter account and was like yo, I got the Pax Fox and it actually was like, thank you It's pretty good account.
Rym: I'm still fighting off the tail end of that Pax Fox.
Scott: Oh, why am I here?
Rym: Well, we'll see if Emily comes down with it.
Rym: Why am I here?
Rym: I don't know.
Scott: I'm unboxed.
Rym: Don't don't touch anything Okay.
Rym: Well, yeah, the thing is when I was sickest was when we skipped the show last week.
Rym: So stay tuned.
Rym: our next Wednesday show will be Spider-man into the spider-verse.
Scott: I have basically no plans until like weekend plans until Pax East except for a few small things Nothing.
Scott: So there's gonna be a Consistent yeek nights now until March ish.
Rym: Yeah, so that'll be good times.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: So I guess president's day I don't have to work.
Scott: We'll see what goes around.
Rym: Yeah, I'll probably go skiing that whole weekend.
Scott: See what goes on there.
Rym: Yeah, but we're gonna be playing a lot of games.
Rym: I'm gonna.
Rym: I'm gonna actually start streaming some advanced wars.
Rym: I've just been feeling that mm-hmm Might stream some other games.
Rym: I've been playing recently.
Rym: I will not stream VR chat because good fucking God.
Scott: So I got kicked off to it.
Rym: What do you got in the news?
Scott: Well, so first of all I just want to briefly cuz you're gonna probably do a full episode on this at some point if I can get Rym to actually Play it.
Scott: There's a hot new thing called auto chess.
Scott: if you haven't heard of it It is a mod for dota 2 which is totally free because dota 2 is free and the mod is free on the steam workshop.
Scott: And basically it's a game where you draft units from a common pool but you spend money you put the units out in the field and then they fight and Then you draft more units and they fight and if you get three of the same unit they combine.
Scott: So if you get nine of the same unit you get three level two guys.
Scott: They combine to a level three guy.
Scott: you get the idea and you get up.
Scott: you're up against copies of other people's armies that come To your battlefield every round and there's no reason for the other person to be sitting there, right?
Scott: You don't have to do any micro because it's auto chess.
Scott: They just fight you.
Scott: all you do is position them.
Scott: You know you draft dudes make armies manage your resources sell dudes put them in the field See how they fight rearrange them by different guys, right?
Scott: And you're all drawing from the same pool of dudes.
Scott: So if Rym buys all the warlocks guess what?
Scott: there's a lot less warlocks in the common pool.
Scott: My odds of drawing a warlock to buy are less.
Scott: there is some RNG But this game is way fun, but also way jank because it's a dota 2 mod.
Scott: Yeah, so if anyone out there is a game developer make a non jank elegant version of auto chess.
Scott: I can totally help you.
Rym: Yep doesn't even have to be that great.
Rym: Just be the first one to make a polished experience.
Rym: if you just take this.
Scott: like this core concept is Relatively new and unique even though it combines some existing mechanics like drafting.
Scott: Yeah If someone makes a polished version of this core concept You will kick ass the same way.
Scott: fortnight kicked pub G's ass in terms of polishing a turd Not like, you know polishing something that wasn't as good.
Rym: I feel like this will scratch the same itch in some ways because remember all those kind of janky PC games that were like Make an army of liches or whatever in a stacked order and they'll kind of auto fight against other people's armies.
Rym: But they were all like text-based websites like no graphics.
Scott: This would make a great tabletop game.
Scott: This is like it's got a lot going for it.
Scott: It's really good.
Scott: Definitely try it out.
Scott: the bad UI almost had me quit early on as I have done many times But I'm only playing this enough to review it.
Rym: I ain't gonna play it long term I don't think.
Scott: I've almost gave it up after like round the first play.
Scott: I was ready to bash the developers face in for making such a bad UI But then I got it in round two.
Scott: in round two I didn't.
Scott: I fucked up way less and was able the fun was able to shine through over the UI.
Scott: that still makes me want to kill somebody.
Scott: so There you have it.
Scott: You got to check.
Scott: the auto chess is the new hotness.
Rym: We didn't say hey, maybe we should.
Rym: we said you should because I ain't got time.
Scott: I ain't got time for that.
Scott: Yeah I already got.
Scott: I can.
Scott: I can consult with you in exchange for a fee and I'll tell you a guarantee.
Scott: if you follow my Advice you will make an amazing game.
Rym: We already got like 1.25 like games.
Rym: We're actually working on it.
Scott: All I got time for is advice.
Scott: Anyway, so real news.
Scott: So we already talked about in a previous ignites episode about the epic stored right other stores trying to compete with steam Right in the whole deal with having too many game stores or not enough game stores and
Rym: all this nonsense like people thinking that Influencers will be the way to get people to buy their game
Scott: anyway.
Scott: So what's happening now is for there's.
Scott: there's now going to be this game called Metro Exodus Which is there's a FPS called Metro.
Scott: It's a FPS series called called Metro that involves like FPSing and sort of a post Apocalyptic Russian ish kind of space with like monsters and shit.
Scott: I played one of them once.
Scott: I got it for free or something I don't know.
Scott: But anyway, the new one is coming out and you can pre-order it on Steam.
Scott: But they just announced.
Scott: guess what this game is going to be exclusive to the epic store.
Rym: Well for one year, right?
Scott: Which means so?
Scott: this is because the steam store charges the developers 30%.
Scott: So if I sell a game on Steam for 10 bucks Valve takes three bucks and I get seven bucks.
Scott: if you sell a game on the epic store The epic store takes what 10 or 15 percent?
Scott: I think 15.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I already forget.
Scott: I think it's 15.
Rym: So definitely a lot less.
Scott: It's a lot less than what steam takes.
Scott: so But here's the thing.
Scott: so they announced we're gonna be exclusive on the epic store.
Scott: So all the people pre-ordered on Steam are still gonna get the game on Steam and people are in a rush to pre-order on Steam today.
Scott: so they get it on Steam so they don't have to use the epic store.
Rym: But and physical copies will include steam keys.
Scott: That's good to know.
Rym: But anyway, I think that's just because they already printed them and it's too late - I think so, too.
Scott: But if you want to get the game starting tomorrow digitally, you have to go to the epic store now.
Scott: Here's the thing.
Scott: They're like, it seems like they made this deal right because They'll save a lot of money.
Scott: They'll make more money if they sell it in the epic store.
Scott: taking that epics taking less of a cut.
Scott: but The thing is on the epic store.
Scott: Game is $50 and on the steam store.
Scott: It's $60.
Scott: So per copy the developer is gonna make 50 extra cents per copy if they sell.
Scott: if you buy in the epic store versus the steam store That's I guess that adds up if you have like thousands of sales But it only adds up to like hundreds or thousands of dollars.
Scott: It's not like a shit ton of money, right?
Rym: Granted the margins in gaming are not great.
Scott: No, it adds up, you know, whatever but I don't know how many sales Those games can expect.
Scott: I have no idea.
Scott: But it's like hey, well clearly this is a move that favors not the developer so much.
Scott: But the epic store is doing this to try to get people to come over to the epic store.
Rym: The thing is it's also the fact that they're still hedging their bets.
Rym: It's a Time limited exclusive which is always like.
Rym: I'm really really suspicious of time limited exclusives because it's not an exclusive.
Rym: Anymore, it's just a delay.
Rym: Yeah, like honestly, I would probably just wait a year And then buy the game on Steam directly.
Scott: Yeah So most people are saying hey wait a year or two and get the complete redux gold game of the year edition for $7.
Scott: And then the cut reply to that is on GOG where there's no DRM because this game is gonna have mad DRM, by the way
Rym: Yep,
Scott: I was actually looking at Resident Evil 2 because that just the remake came out and it's supposed to be pretty sweet compared to Playing actual Resident Evil 2 which is tank controls and sucks to play.
Scott: I was eyeing that but it has met it right on Steam.
Scott: It says yo this shit has mad DRM.
Scott: So what happens is usually after a while they remove the DRM.
Scott: So I'm gonna wait for them to remove the DRM and then I'll play Resident Evil 2.
Rym: Meanwhile, so Regarding that DRM, you know, we did our panel and we talked about retro games and we talked a lot about Bionic Commando.
Rym: So I had this urge to play Bionic Commando Rearmed.
Rym: I bought it on a store that hasn't existed for a long time.
Scott: Oh, you didn't buy it on Steam?
Rym: I bought it a long time ago like direct.
Rym: Oh, no, uh, but I bought it in a place that didn't have DRM.
Rym: So I just had an EXE that's still on my NAS that downloaded.
Rym: It worked.
Scott: Yeah, I have that's having me.
Scott: I have a Blood Bowl the first Blood Bowl PC game Not the super old one the more right because the Blood Bowl 2 is out now has been out for I think years already.
Scott: But I bought that in some weird-ass store that doesn't exist anymore, but I saved the EXE in the key.
Scott: So theoretically I believe I could install and play it.
Rym: So it's interesting because on one, you know, we've talked about this a lot But this issue is only gonna get bigger.
Rym: on one hand as a consumer Not looking at any other considerations.
Rym: I only want to go to one place to buy my games.
Scott: Yeah, it is very It's inconvenient to have to have multiple accounts and multiple stores, right?
Rym: It's like I get like I hate the oculus store my oculus store Literally my oculus account exists solely for me to launch Steam VR.
Scott: It's not even really that I don't mind having more than one store, right?
Scott: It's like going to different places to get the games is fine.
Rym: I only want one launcher.
Scott: I want only one user interface that lists all the games, you know It lists all my software to play.
Scott: if that I wish people would still use say the start menu Then I wouldn't need to use a separate interface, but everyone's decided to make a separate interface.
Scott: So it's like I have all these games I got for free in the twitch store.
Scott: I have a bunch of GOG games But when I sit down in my computer to play games I open steam and all those games and the other interfaces don't get played because I don't think to look there, right?
Rym: Well, I open steam and blizzard launcher specifically.
Rym: Oh, right.
Scott: I have a blizzard battle net also Watch.
Rym: it's literally just the overwatch launcher.
Scott: compared to say on my iPhone or my iPad all the games are just icons.
Scott: They're all together.
Scott: I don't need to like.
Scott: I have a separate, you know If I had to open the steam app to play games on my iPad I would have a steam icon and all those other games wouldn't get looked at.
Rym: there are ways to make that work.
Scott: All these stores could have made say APIs to their launchers that someone can make a universal game launcher.
Scott: I would totally be willing to make a universal game launch.
Rym: So there are a lot of ways.
Rym: like.
Rym: you can just have steam launch games that are just from the desktop.
Scott: Oh, you could do that.
Scott: It's a pain in the ass.
Rym: You can make links that'll launch steam games from the desk.
Scott: There's It sucks.
Rym: Well, the thing is all those ways take a minimum amount of effort.
Rym: that when I was younger I was willing to do in the same era when I was willing to customize the shit out of my desktop.
Scott: But nowadays I guess I could write a script.
Scott: maybe that does it right?
Scott: I kind of semi automate like finds all your if it makes a folder in your start menu Finds all your steam games make icons for them finds all your games and all your others like GOG or just DRM free.
Scott: So it would go to your GOG library get all the games Yeah, and they make a folder full of icons for all your games and then make a separate interface for searching that folder.
Scott: That's full of shortcuts.
Rym: Here's the thing.
Rym: if I'm looking universal game launch if I'm looking for a game to buy Kind of like when I just go to Amazon I just want to go to one place and type the name of the thing I'm looking for.
Scott: it would be annoying to have to open like five stores though there.
Scott: cuz someone could just make a website.
Scott: I'm sure there are websites.
Scott: this track the prices of games on all the stores I already don't care like and then you just you that would be your place would be that website Here's the and then you would go there and it would.
Rym: there's the non-video game thing.
Rym: So what I want to watch the next episode of a show like some show or some movie.
Rym: What I do is I log into Netflix That's the one that's just there and open on the HDPC and I type the name of the thing.
Rym: if I if it doesn't show up there Maybe I go to Crunchyroll and type the name of the thing there.
Scott: You know what I do.
Rym: if it also doesn't show up there I type the name of the thing into Pirate Bay next.
Rym: You know what I do even if I pay for it.
Scott: I go I go to google.com and I say where can I stream X and I look at what it says And if it doesn't say one of the things I'm currently subscribed to I go to Pirate Bay.
Rym: I'm not even willing to put the effort in to find out where it is first.
Rym: I just type it into the streaming services.
Rym: I'm already paying for.
Scott: that's too much effort because then I go to go three places.
Scott: I start by going to the Google search immediately.
Scott: I just skip past step one, but maybe I have to do that for games now also.
Scott: But the thing is if I have to do it for games right Streaming services when you pay for the streaming service you get everything on that service for free and you have this Pirate Bay Alternative for games.
Scott: the Pirate Bay alternative is not the greatest like it is for say just a file.
Scott: I'm a lot less willing to pirate a game because that's software.
Rym: they could jack up my computer, so I only Pirate streaming media even if I'm like already paying for it on a service just because it's convenient.
Rym: But with games piracy is not convenient at all.
Scott: right exactly.
Scott: and the thing is let's say I go to that website And I search where can I buy game X and it's available on five different games.
Scott: It's available on GOG and steam and epic and ea origin or whatever in that case.
Rym: I probably buy it on steam.
Scott: It's cheaper on.
Scott: you know about getting the epic one.
Scott: I don't have an account on the epic store right now.
Scott: I'm gonna go out Google make an account on the epic store just to buy one game and then Remember that to play that game have to open the epic store and not see I'm not motivated by price Just like online.
Scott: this is why people are paying 10 extra dollars to get metro on steam things.
Scott: You know it's 10 extra dollars.
Rym: a lot of things I buy on Amazon cost more on Amazon than they would cost in a local store.
Rym: I just don't want to go to a store.
Scott: well You're getting an extra service with that which is exactly what the extra service here is.
Rym: it's just in steam yep.
Scott: So actually dad I guess though if you were starting today And you didn't already have a steam games going back to literally the day steam launched in 2004 or whatever then you could start with the epic store today.
Scott: be fun right.
Rym: so dazzle points out in the chat.
Rym: It's actually a pretty good thing that we can mention here.
Rym: The advantage of having a game launcher is the integrated online features like chat community parties voice chat.
Rym: I want to say I don't use any of that in steam.
Scott: I don't use any of that, but you know what's really annoying you?
Rym: that in Blizzard I don't know game launcher has anything better than just discord.
Scott: That's what I'm saying.
Scott: It's super annoying that now when I open up a game There's like a steam overlay and a discord overlay And it's like it's like overlay central right with all these things piled up on top of a game.
Rym: It's like if someone messaged me.
Scott: One at least at least the Microsoft one died and went away.
Rym: Yeah, if I get used to be a Microsoft one my reaction is what why are you using steam to talk to me?
Scott: I occasionally get steam messages.
Scott: It's weird you get.
Scott: I got steam and battle net and discord like all layered on top of each other.
Scott: It's like no murder.
Scott: all of these.
Scott: there can be only one.
Rym: like when I play overwatch either I use discord just because that's what I happen to have open or sometimes I've literally just like made a direct Google chat call to someone Because people abandon Federation.
Scott: we should have gone full-on with the Federation.
Rym: well because no one can make money in Federation.
Scott: That's too damn bad.
Scott: You're not making money with your battle net chat.
Scott: That doesn't make you money.
Scott: selling games makes you the money.
Scott: Why do you even have the chat in there?
Rym: So well so speaking of chat I have a brief geek bite.
Rym: all right because I have been poking around in VR check.
Rym: cuz I got VR play around with this Alright, so what is it?
Scott: You just put the VR helmet on you walk around.
Scott: what like a cyberspace like second life.
Scott: and yes and chat.
Scott: Yes, there's no games.
Scott: There's no nothing.
Scott: well.
Scott: There are chatting there are games like what.
Rym: so here?
Rym: So here's the deal with VR based games like no No like full-on capture-the-flag fucking FPS.
Rym: Let's go.
Rym: It's just in there really in the world.
Scott: You can just program games in it.
Rym: Yeah, you can prove the deal with VR chat.
Scott: That's pretty good is one?
Rym: It's not the.
Rym: its primary Function is that it is an SDK to make VR shit, okay?
Scott: That is it?
Scott: so it's like Gary's mod of VR.
Scott: Yeah, but if I'm playing CTF can I just like spawn like a bomb and I blow it up.
Scott: and no Cuz you use the physics engine to send people flying.
Rym: it depends on the room.
Scott: So you can make a room That has whatever you want in it and then someone's the admin of the room and the other people can't mess with it.
Rym: Basically, but people can make a mod like the mod of the IRC channel And people make avatars that do stuff and there's like yeah, my avatar is an enormous wall.
Scott: Yep, so I spy I wait until my team moves the flag pattern and then I spawn.
Rym: so if someone's avatar is shitty You can block it from interacting with you and just walk through it.
Scott: Ah, oh, but then I can block walk through the person who's blocking me from capturing the flag.
Scott: Oh, yeah, so block the entire enemy team so they can't block me Maybe.
Rym: so it depends on how someone made the game.
Rym: Anyway the deal with it is that it's also you can make your own avatars just import stuff.
Scott: So it's a willing Gibson style cyberspace.
Rym: Yes So oculus has it's like social nonsense through Facebook to like hang out in rooms with people steam has it like ever.
Rym: Everyone has their hangout in VR space.
Rym: So it's it's it's third life because you already had second and no one uses any of those things because they're hard to use and They suck and they're very gated.
Scott: That's good.
Rym: The reason VR Chad has exploded so big like it's big a lot of people are in there.
Rym: How many people own VR headsets that are in so you can also enter it without a VR headset?
Rym: Oh, that's why okay There's a desktop client just works.
Scott: Oh, that's why everyone's in there and Picking.
Rym: and so if you make an avatar give it whatever emojis you want or if you meet someone who has a cool avatar I guess if you're using VR you wouldn't see your own avatar?
Rym: No, but you can look down and you see your body there.
Scott: Guess you would.
Scott: hey, yeah, and you can abuse in the desktop client.
Scott: You're doing third-person You're not doing first person.
Rym: Most people seem to do first person, but you can do third person.
Scott: I would do third person with a desktop client first person via.
Rym: so in VR The avatar will just move with you, but you can also program things like do a backflip or do a dance.
Scott: So you can sort of tell if someone's VR and cuz they're moving differently.
Scott: Yeah if people are VR guess I could like get a VR controller and not use the headset and then get the Right.
Scott: get the realistic VR movements without.
Rym: yeah, the problem is you'd need the head movement to make it all really feel.
Scott: I could just get people use nerds for playing military FPS is use those head trackers.
Rym: Yeah Sensors to make those work.
Scott: Yeah, it's a sensor thing you buy.
Rym: If you're going to start an effort just wear the real VR headset at that point a little.
Scott: it's a little weightier than Anyway, so all VR chats.
Rym: India like this is the jankiest one But all of them the one thing they do really really really well, but the jankiest one is the most popular one.
Rym: Yeah, is that the way the movement works?
Rym: It's really immersive and you really feel like there's a real human being right there in the room with.
Scott: it goes in the shell time.
Scott: Let's go.
Rym: So the deal with VR chat is that all the other things are like make this space and like invite people to the space.
Rym: It's just fucking anarchy.
Rym: in VR chat you walk into a hub and there's just people on and around.
Scott: That's how it's supposed to be.
Rym: you can be like wander to a random world.
Scott: That's the cyberpunk vision in a world.
Rym: You can drop a portal to another world and be like everybody.
Rym: follow me Is there?
Scott: how do you get a list of worlds slash list?
Scott: There is sort of.
Rym: there's just a list But it's so long you could never like.
Scott: you can search it though.
Scott: Barely barely.
Rym: You got to just fucking explore.
Rym: So you browse yeah or find a friend or go to a world meet someone cool.
Scott: Can you know if you're in a world?
Scott: Can I just can I?
Scott: is there an easy way to teleport like go where Rym is?
Scott: Cuz you're my friend.
Scott: Yes Okay, that's or you're in a world.
Rym: You made some cool people.
Rym: You're like, hey, I know a cool world.
Rym: You follow me.
Rym: you can drop a portal and you jump through it.
Scott: Oh, everyone physically walks through the portal in the game.
Scott: Yeah, if they want to I choose a world and I make a portal and now people can walk into it and I'll go to Same place together.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: See can you form a party like so that you can like suck it help your friends get to this?
Rym: Yeah, if you kids really easy to get your friends together, okay And some of the what it's really hard to like find a specific world if you don't know the name.
Rym: Same thing with avatars.
Rym: you want an avatar.
Rym: You can dig through menu But it really the way to find an avatar.
Rym: if someone has a cool avatar just steal it from them.
Scott: now your website.
Scott: I can just search for an avatar.
Scott: No click.
Rym: so you can go to an avatar world Thousands and thousands of them and find an avatar world that it's like the the Pokemon avatar world.
Rym: I went in there and someone just made avatars of every goddamn Pokemon every single one.
Scott: Yes, there is Spiritomb.
Rym: Yeah, I have the Spiritomb avatar.
Scott: I'm gonna be spirit.
Rym: I was a Spiritomb.
Rym: I was wandering around.
Scott: that's I want to be.
Scott: so I wanted to be a Spiritomb and walk around.
Rym: Here are the avatars.
Scott: That's what I want to do.
Rym: I like borrowed and Rym's avatars.
Scott: dragon furry Not yet.
Scott: No Something with some sort of tour so of some kind.
Rym: so here's what I have in order.
Rym: one Unity-chan, which is this cute anime girl because that's because that's the only default avatar that isn't ugly as shit Okay, and also it's cute.
Scott: Whatever what else would remake?
Scott: my second avatar was Bulbasaur And then Spiritomb.
Scott: That's a Rym thing.
Rym: Then the Hachiroku full-scale.
Scott: Just a Hachiroku.
Scott: Yeah, is it?
Scott: is it like on its hind wheels standing up or is it just driving?
Rym: Just a car like flap the headlamps open and close.
Rym: It is it's just anarchy in there.
Scott: All right, so it sounds like my kind of place.
Rym: it is worth Poke it around in its race gets totally free.
Scott: I'm going to get the desktop when I go.
Rym: Yeah, it is.
Scott: It's just can't make a GeekNights world GeekNights world.
Rym: I think we should.
Scott: what's in the GeekNights world?
Rym: So here are the.
Rym: before we move on my last bit of the geek bite.
Scott: Here are the places I ran into broadcast every night's episode in VR chat and could make a stage with a desk.
Scott: I went into a world that was and then it'll be a screen that shows the YouTube stream on it and then they'll be Some people can sit.
Scott: I went into a back of the back of this.
Scott: seats will be a dig-dug machine.
Rym: I went to do a world that was called running in the 90s and it is the song.
Rym: It's that song running in a loop and it's basically like Part of Mount Akina and everyone was just dressed as initial D cars Except a bunch of people who were dressed as Pokemon and they were just arguing about random internet shit hanging out.
Scott: I would I would be dude and I would stand on the side behind the guardrail and pump my fist.
Rym: Yeah So then I went to a world that was called karaoke world.
Rym: It was just a bunch of people legit singing karaoke and taking turns so you can use microphone action.
Rym: It just works.
Scott: But what if you're in a room with a lot of people?
Scott: How does that work?
Rym: audio proximity?
Scott: The closer you actually have that program.
Scott: Yeah, that's good.
Rym: It's it's Just what if I yell real loud if you annoy people.
Rym: So the one thing that really but the reason I'm talking about VR chat is because This is this is a place that is rife for like 4chan style abuse.
Rym: Yeah it Anti harassment features are first and foremost really by default.
Rym: your shield level is to two people You haven't friended meaning their avatars can't do crazy shit Like.
Rym: they can't spawn particle effects that you would see they can't be too big.
Rym: They can't play audio They can only talk and it is real trivial to block someone.
Rym: they just disappear You just don't see him anymore.
Scott: Mm-hmm Was there a Nazi Channel?
Rym: I assume there is in there somewhere, but I did not encounter any Nazis.
Scott: It's not just like deleted.
Rym: So here's the trolling I encountered.
Scott: Are there any?
Scott: are there any sexy sexy channels?
Rym: Yes, there's a million of them.
Rym: Good fucking God.
Scott: All right Which one are we going to be?
Rym: as NSFW as you wants?
Rym: you can't bring that shit into a public channel.
Rym: Uh-huh, you can have the boobiest avatar you want.
Scott: But how do I get into the private channel?
Rym: find it?
Scott: I need a password or know what you need to know the name private world.
Rym: get invited to it by a friend I don't know.
Rym: meet somebody and they password it.
Scott: or can I just click on one?
Rym: Uh, I guess just click on it.
Rym: meet some dude in a shady.
Rym: I was like, hey kid, you want some goofballs?
Scott: Oh, man, I could I could.
Scott: I could roleplay as you Ray I got dude.
Rym: So here's the trend.
Scott: I can hand out invites to the porn channel.
Rym: I turned shields down.
Rym: I went to a room.
Rym: I was hanging out and this kid is just like hey everybody follow me and he drops a portal.
Rym: I'm like, all right.
Rym: I got my shields down.
Rym: I go into the portal.
Rym: it's just this black world where you're falling to the void forever and then his avatar was like this Thousand-foot Godzilla that starts screaming.
Rym: It almost made me sick.
Rym: I had to like jump out of the room in a hurry.
Scott: Oh cuz you're a VR.
Scott: Yeah, I was mean I was falling through Desktop, that would just be hilarious.
Rym: Yeah, it was still hilarious because I don't get VR sick, but We'll talk about VR chat in the future.
Rym: But it this is where post-millennials are hanging out.
Rym: This is like the place that people are just socializing on the internet only cyberpunk place.
Scott: Well, that's great, but I'm still not buying some oculus headset.
Rym: No, so it also works with oculus go which is the light headset that doesn't need sensors and doesn't need a computer.
Scott: That is vastly superior, but still too big.
Scott: I've seen it.
Rym: Yeah, it's pretty good.
Rym: So one last gaming news.
Rym: really briefly that took longer than I expected.
Rym: if you didn't notice There was a sports ball game a football game, right?
Scott: So that basically here's the deal in the NFC championship game Which is a game that they play and the winner goes to the Super Bowl.
Rym: That's a big deal game.
Scott: It happened two weeks ago because the Super Bowl is this weekend.
Scott: The winner of the game likely won because the ref did not make a call They should have made.
Scott: had the ref made the call the other team probably would have won.
Scott: Therefore the legitimacy of the Super Bowl is in question.
Scott: now It should be a different team in the Super Bowl this weekend.
Rym: in a lot of Lee in a lot of other big major sports There are more games and fewer opportunities.
Rym: Yes one bad call in one game base literally determine who gets the Stanley Cup baseball.
Scott: the National League Championship Series is four out of seven.
Scott: So if there's a no call in one of the games and you still lose the series say five one Guess what?
Scott: Yeah, you can't really complain but football with it for four.
Rym: I mean for one American football for a variety of reasons.
Rym: one bad call literally could determine it goes to the Super Bowl.
Scott: now They do have lots of rules for replay and challenging But they are not extensive enough as that you could run out of challenges or in this case There was a no call.
Scott: So it's like.
Scott: you're not allowed to like you challenge.
Scott: if like you think the ref like, you know Didn't made a wrong call.
Scott: not if they just didn't call something.
Scott: There's nothing to challenge.
Rym: Yep, right like in hockey You can't just be like hey that was sparing and you didn't see it.
Rym: They might find the guy after the game, but it's highly unlikely.
Rym: They're gonna back up and say, okay There's a two-minute minor from five minutes ago.
Scott: There's also a lot of hypocrisy on the part of the NHL.
Scott: for example There was a guy who committed a hit to the head right and got a fine after the game But in the game, it was not penalized.
Scott: So so they missed that call, but they sought to rectify it after the game.
Scott: But here they miss a call that actually affects the result of the game.
Scott: They don't rectify it.
Scott: also to add to the arrogance of the the NFL right.
Scott: the commissioner hasn't even made a comment on it.
Scott: He's not going to make a comment until the Super Bowl press conference.
Scott: No, he's basically just ignoring it Like I don't have to do to you, you know, please I ignore.
Scott: I ignore I feel like he'll get away with it in the right, but the the basically regardless the the consequence is unavoidable.
Scott: Is that the integrity and credibility of the league has taken a lot of damage?
Rym: So here's the news attorney Frank DiMaggio D'Amico.
Scott: that sounds like the name of an attorney like Vinny.
Rym: Vinny someone right so Says he has filed a civil suit in New Orleans on behalf of Saints season ticket holders.
Scott: That's the wrong person to file on suit behalf of yep.
Scott: So legally I think he's got nothing.
Scott: so not not a lawyer But I feel like he's got nothing.
Rym: So there is a lawsuit that is actually moving.
Rym: The lawsuit has now been moved to federal court.
Scott: Yeah, I Think it'll be dismissed or won't win.
Scott: Yeah NFL lawyers.
Scott: Yeah, so I don't because going up against NFL lawyers your rich season ticket holders But you're up against NFL on one hand.
Rym: Yeah, the like a bad call was made.
Rym: and yeah, because this is a big-money sport There are real-world consequences for players not for fans.
Scott: The only consequence that they have gambled yep the industry the city.
Scott: well one's gambling is legal.
Scott: suddenly then Real that the bookie can sue and they have a case but the team that might not go to this is out.
Scott: The gambler has a small case, but the bookie has a big case.
Rym: So there's a lot of money involved.
Scott: So season ticket holder has a small case.
Scott: There's like oh you got denied Super Bowl tickets But you know what denied the right to scalp Super Bowl tickets, right?
Scott: But the if the team sued which they won't but they could then the players could sue.
Scott: they have a bigger case But they're not suing.
Scott: They're just complaining.
Rym: So I am 100% unsympathetic to the fans like don't especially yeah Because the sports ball game didn't go the way you want it, even though that sucks.
Rym: Yeah, but in Terms of the rest of it.
Rym: There are real-world consequences.
Rym: So you could almost see where like where a lawsuit like this go ahead.
Scott: I don't want sports gambling to be legal actually, but you know what?
Scott: I say make it legal just so I want to see the bookies sue the leagues for fucking up.
Rym: Yeah, but here's the other thing.
Rym: It's the NFL.
Rym: They can do whatever the fuck they want.
Scott: Yeah legally.
Rym: They probably got a contract League and Commissioner Rym and Commissioner Scott say you know what this team wins because I don't like your hat There's actually people were claimed.
Scott: There is a clause actually in the NFL whatever Whatever, you know, I guess it has a charter.
Scott: I don't know a lot about the NFL Charter Some kind of document because NFL is a nonprofit right itself.
Scott: Just the individual teams are for profit, right?
Scott: But anyway the the oh the Commissioner can actually just Unilaterally change the result of a game.
Scott: the Commissioner could have said, you know what Saints win Don't is never.
Scott: I don't think he's ever done it and he didn't do it in this case.
Rym: So I'm also pretty confident.
Rym: all the contracts within the NFL probably together have clauses that effectively say The NFL can do whatever the fuck it wants.
Scott: I'm also curious.
Scott: Conspiracy time.
Scott: the Ellie.
Scott: the LA Rams who recently moved to LA from st Louis are the team that beat the Saints because of the no-call.
Scott: was the fix-in?
Scott: because LA is a bigger market than New Orleans.
Rym: You know what?
Rym: I bet there's.
Rym: no I bet they could do that if they wanted to.
Scott: was the fix-in?
Rym: I Doubt it.
Scott: if the no-call had been the other way would they have done something to put the Rams in the Super Bowl over the Saints?
Rym: I mean, I remember a time where the Red Wings are on the way to get a Stanley Cup and they were sweeping people.
Rym: and Then in the Stanley Cup Finals, it was or was?
Rym: it was the semi-finals the finals.
Rym: They won three games in a row Ridiculously.
Rym: the fourth game was away and then the fifth game would have been at home.
Rym: They lost that away game after winning three ridiculous games in a row just by a little bit And then they crushed in the home game.
Rym: So did they just try to bring the cup home?
Scott: Maybe yeah, I just want to say though There really is that all sports all professional sports are not using replay technology Effectively enough or creatively enough, right?
Rym: I think the enemy the NHL is pushed it way further than other sports, right?
Scott: But what I'm saying you could do that no one does is have separate people watching basically every part of a game On video right the whole time.
Scott: not you don't even rest on the ice They're asking the ice can be looking out for the basic stuff, right?
Scott: Yep, and call things just as the game is going on, right?
Scott: All rules in real time.
Rym: so it's got have one lot one like linesman version two.
Rym: We'll call him a. screens min one screens min per player.
Rym: Yeah, and they just watch each player and be like up he hooks.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: He got hooked exactly Why not?
Scott: and then in real time they could just call right you don't even to stop play.
Scott: You can just be like put that guy in the box.
Scott: You open up the box.
Scott: people are still playing.
Scott: he skates over to the box gets in Especially for a game like soccer where they don't even stop the clock.
Scott: Yeah You can just have guys watching every all 22 soccer players cuz it's 11 on 11 right all the time and call everything perfectly perfectly.
Rym: Yellow cards just start falling.
Scott: Just have people watching every second of every game, especially, you know doing that to great lengths for just a regular season game.
Scott: Alright, maybe that's too far.
Scott: Maybe it cost too much.
Scott: Maybe it's too resource intensive.
Scott: You guys have a couple people doing it.
Scott: Just look a little bit more closely, but for the NFC championship game and the Super Bowl and the World Cup Why would you not do this?
Rym: Yep I mean, there's a reason why for important hockey games Toronto is reviewing every goal regardless of the situation what I'm saying.
Rym: So yeah, this will be funny to follow.
Rym: But anyway, it's time for Things of the day.
Rym: I am finally disposed toward randomizers But I haven't watched a lot too deeply until now.
Rym: Holy crap this Final Fantasy 4 free enterprise randomizer.
Rym: It was way better than I thought it was gonna be.
Rym: I'm gonna play this randomizer.
Scott: Holy crap I watched.
Scott: part of that speedrun is pretty good.
Rym: This is from AGDQ 2019.
Rym: It's a four-way race in Final Fantasy 4 where everything's randomized and they're all playing the same seed.
Rym: It's pretty intense and the commentary is A+.
Scott: if you're wondering how the hell do you randomize a JRPG watch this speedrun.
Rym: They explain it and like you watch you're like wait a minute.
Rym: There haven't been any random encounters and as soon as you think that the commentators like so you might have noticed there's no random encounters.
Rym: well They can.
Rym: the players can turn on random encounters if and when they choose.
Rym: if they want to level something up I need that It's.
Rym: I'm playing this.
Rym: This looks good.
Scott: Anyway, should we do a GeekNights race?
Rym: The problem is no 40 hours.
Scott: No Anyway, so speaking of football.
Scott: Here's a great thing of the day.
Rym: Oh, this is so good ESPN.
Scott: What they did is they went on Twitter and they saw this during college football.
Scott: You know where people are not as professional and not as good at playing as professional football.
Scott: When kickers missed.
Scott: they would see fans of the team tweeting things like.
Scott: I could have made that you bum The kind of thing that I would say like I you know Right yelling at the team stuff that we in the old days and in the current days We would just yell at the TV.
Scott: people were typing their yell at the TV things on Twitter.
Rym: I have in fact yelled the words I could have made that shot in hockey.
Scott: I only say it on the rare occasion But I know it's like when it's like empty net and he's five feet away and they still miss.
Rym: but the thing is I Say that in the privacy of my own home.
Rym: I don't say it to the person who missed the shot Definitely not.
Scott: But anyway, there are people on Twitter who are tweeting like at college kicker her.
Scott: I could have made that you bum that kids got homework, right?
Scott: He's got a finish.
Scott: that guy's not going to the NFL probably but anyway.
Scott: So they called these Pete the contact of these people and they're ESPN.
Scott: they're like, hey, we're ESPN We're gonna give you money right.
Scott: come and fly out to be on a TV show.
Scott: You see you're a football fan of this college team.
Scott: You seem like a real passionate fan.
Rym: It sounds like a trap.
Scott: We're gonna make a video thing.
Scott: Come on out.
Scott: Well, we can't tell you what it is.
Scott: It's a prize, but it's it's a thing related to your extreme fandom of this college Football team right?
Scott: It's ESPN.
Scott: You're gonna be on TV or on YouTube or whatever.
Scott: Come on out.
Scott: So the people in exchange probably for money came on out and they brought him out onto this indoor Field area and they showed them their tweet like I could have kicked that you bum.
Scott: And then they're like, alright, go ahead It was what that kick that they missed in that 31 yard line was a 31 yard kick All right.
Scott: Here you go.
Scott: Make this 31 yard kick.
Scott: Look there isn't even anyone in the field.
Scott: It's gonna be even easier than the actual college kicker had to deal with.
Scott: you're just in this no wind right indoors No one rushing at you.
Scott: You got all the time in the world and everyone Failed spectacularly.
Rym: they kicked about as well as I would yep The woman being like doing the the the shake with them.
Scott: She's like holding in her laughter.
Rym: Her face is great.
Rym: She is she is.
Rym: she is also a plus in this.
Scott: But yeah, maybe you know watching this gives you that sort of like.
Scott: haha you you you jerks.
Scott: But it also gives you that respect for the people who actually kick the football to the field goal.
Scott: Like yeah, it's fucking hard.
Rym: Like yeah a 30-yard field goal is relatively easy.
Scott: It's like it's routine for NFL dudes to kick like 40 50-yard field goals.
Scott: They're supposed to make those burning wheel.
Scott: It's like yeah, you can't kick a 10-yard field goal.
Scott: Look at holy shit.
Scott: That person's gonna keep it like burning wheel.
Rym: It's a it's an OBS three or four.
Rym: They just have a b7.
Scott: Yeah, it's like he's like he's like g7 and kicking.
Scott: That's why I think right but the college people don't.
Scott: they're like b5.
Rym: And I think g7 was that guy who was missing the front half of his foot and had that special shoe that basically turned his Foot into a hammer.
Scott: He wasn't as good as current day control, but in his era because it was different in his era He was unbelievable.
Rym: But you know in the meta moment the book club book is the 2001 space.
Scott: I guess I should read bugs.
Rym: I will read it soon.
Scott: Coming up this is approaching like the longest not read Book for the book one.
Rym: We've been busy - there's been a lot of quality television that I've been watching.
Scott: It's not too much television.
Scott: But finally there is a large gap here between now and PAX East where I don't have many plans.
Rym: I will say there is a TV show on regular fucking TV.
Rym: That is actually good.
Scott: Yeah the good place Everyone keeps talking about I don't care.
Rym: so the all also the deal all those I got a deal is it's a show that acts like the kind of crap someone to watch on TV and then it actually just teaches Them moral philosophy like for real.
Scott: I already know moral philosophy though.
Scott: Do you really I mean, I know my moral philosophy?
Rym: Well, but I don't need to know anyone else's It addresses the trolley problem in the correct way.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Rym: So Anyway, we'll do that book at some point.
Rym: We put two videos on YouTube.
Rym: So if you want to see our pre-judging of all the anime, they're out.
Rym: now it is on Scott's YouTube channel.
Scott: I was watching a Dororo.
Rym: I was too.
Scott: I think there's a newer episode I can maybe watch.
Scott: I don't know when new episodes come out, but I'm sure there's one I haven't seen.
Rym: now I think Dororo is good enough to where I'm just gonna watch the whole thing and we can review.
Scott: I read the whole manga and so far it's the same but without the Tezuka silliness I did.
Scott: we will do a Wednesday episode on it soon.
Scott: Yes
Rym: We're doing spider-man first
Scott: sure
Rym: and also our most recent packs panel nostalgia vs Game design is on YouTube in its entirety with for the first time We have our full complete new production process in terms of how the slides get put into the panel the camera a versus Camera B the color and the temperature and everything is set.
Rym: This is like how all our panels will look from now on and also it's a pretty good panel.
Rym: people seem to like it.
Rym: The first one of the comments on the panel after we put it up was literally please come back to ConnectiCon.
Rym: Another one was when will you make the next do ten a chapter?
Rym: Both of those may happen in the nearing future.
Rym: I don't know if Scott will go to ConnectiCon, but I will.
Scott: hopefully depends on the circumstances.
Rym: I'm probably gonna only go for like Saturday and having the thing is ConnectiCon doesn't sell out, right?
Rym: Yeah, you don't have to decide till right before.
Scott: so if there's already a hotel just like waiting for me in case yeah I can be like oh, it's raining this weekend.
Scott: I don't know can't go biking.
Scott: Let's go to ConnectiCon.
Rym: Yeah, cuz if I go I'm gonna roll in like Friday night.
Rym: I do like a full day Saturday and then leave like Sunday early afternoon.
Scott: I can't even just go for like one day like I can go to like Connecticut and then go there like early Saturday morning And then
Rym: it's not a bad idea cuz it's a good excuse to go to Connecticut anyway like yeah, yeah
Scott: anyway
Rym: Beyond that look for our stuff on the internet.
Rym: It's time to talk about not good critters Which we also played but La Cosa Nostra all right a 2014 board game that is Relatively new to us.
Rym: I'd played it a couple times.
Scott: I played it one time.
Rym: then we got Scott to play it.
Rym: It's pretty good.
Scott: Yeah, we got a friend who really likes mafia themed games and I like mafia thing, but I don't really like mafia things right.
Scott: I just I regular like mafia things hiding in the stove.
Scott: But yeah, so this game the way the fundamental concept is that you're a mob boss And there are other mob bosses, and you got people in your mob because that's what a mob is.
Scott: you get some drug dealers You got some fences you got some I don't know.
Rym: Oh, no is board game geek down just as I'm trying to do the show.
Scott: you got some hit man You know.
Scott: you got all the kinds of.
Scott: no you got all kinds of like the no-do gooders that you would have in your mafia Crime squad.
Scott: right, but you can only have so many bad dudes right working for you.
Scott: Everyone else is bad dudes working for them, too.
Scott: You can hire more dudes with money sure But you got jobs you need to do to get money and each job requires a set of dudes.
Scott: Yeah, so in order to do this job.
Rym: I need a nightclub I need a pimp and I need a shitload of drugs.
Scott: right.
Scott: so it's like I only have a nightclub.
Scott: hey Rym Can I have your pimp?
Scott: I need his help to do some work.
Scott: Hey Joe Can I borrow your night?
Rym: your your drug dealer and my response might be?
Rym: Yes, Scott you can use my pimp at some point in the future if you will let me at an undetermined point use your loan Shark yep, but my response might also be you know what fuck you in fact?
Rym: give me $4,000.
Rym: I'm gonna kill all the other pimps on the table.
Scott: Use my nightclub, but I understand that you were using my nightclub for a very lucrative party.
Scott: You will have to give me half the revenues of the party that occurs in my nightclub.
Rym: How about how about I'll just give you six grand cash Right now?
Scott: that tells me that the party you are going to do in my nightclub is going to make you more than $12,000.
Scott: so now I want even more.
Rym: yep, so we say we make our deal, and we're like our deals.
Rym: fine We're both gonna make a lot of money, then it's our friends.
Rym: You're Joe Joe's turn.
Rym: He's like Rym and Scott.
Rym: you both have to give me five grand or I'm fucking killing Scott's pimp right now.
Scott: Yeah, you can kill people yep and then the job won't happen.
Rym: and The game is pretty like we're not gonna go through the rules because the game is actually pretty complex.
Rym: There's a lot of phases, but it's not complex to play.
Rym: the complexity just makes the game work because Everything happens.
Rym: you just keep going clockwise Sequentially and first you're taking your mobsters and some of them are smart and some of them are kind of shitty Yeah, and they make money for you.
Rym: Yeah So you got some mobsters and every turn it comes to your turn all your.
Rym: every round it comes to your turn and all you Is you put a mobster down and you say Smiley two-face is doing this job, and you put the mobster face up and the job face down mm-hmm.
Rym: And then it goes around again.
Rym: You say Tommy two toes is doing this other job.
Scott: you put the job face down and some of them are better than others.
Rym: Yeah, so one job might be like wreck somebody.
Scott: so the job of the like five gun strength super mobster Right the guy in the white suit.
Scott: He's doing the most important job.
Scott: Yeah, but the job that the one gun guy is doing is probably like some lame-o job.
Rym: Some of the jobs are public like I might put Joey Jojo Shabbat ooh down is one gun mobster and be like he's just buying that nightclub.
Scott: legit He's buying this for I sent him out to go buy a nightclub.
Scott: That's all he's doing.
Scott: He's Johnny.
Rym: Johnny Can't fuck this one up.
Scott: He's going to buy.
Rym: He's buying a pimp.
Rym: like there's a new pimp in town.
Rym: We're gonna buy him.
Rym: get him get him into first.
Scott: But he's gonna buy a caravan from some.
Rym: but the jobs might be things like this job will pay out 20 grand But you need a nightclub and a senator and a shitload of cocaine.
Scott: Yeah, you need like the jobs that pay out a lot.
Scott: the requirements are big.
Scott: so the way to win this game is To get lots and lots of people to agree to do things with you right like if I make a deal with Rym and I Make a deal with every other play like one deal with each other player.
Scott: I'm now doing four deals I'm making bank right.
Scott: you want to get as many things to execute as possible and You got to look at who's winning and you you can just direct screwing right in terms of murdering people.
Scott: So you look at who's winning and you target their shit.
Scott: so it doesn't happen and make sure that you're the person who successfully executes the most deals, but Everything is.
Scott: all that matters at the end of the game is how much money you got.
Rym: all you want at the end is money.
Rym: Everything is transaction.
Scott: just mobster wins.
Rym: well you do get some bonuses for if you still have all your mob.
Scott: Turn into money though.
Rym: I yeah everything turns into money and for mobsters you have killed yep So you got.
Rym: there's a little bit of an extra incentive to kill some people toward the end Because I sensibly if you have more mobsters alive, and you've killed other mobsters It makes your mob in like a better position.
Scott: It's also a side effect like if you've done if you're if you're in the position where you've killed more and have your guys killed Less you've probably completed more jobs.
Scott: Oh, yes done more stuff.
Rym: So like some jobs are like whack like literally just kill some right some other mobster.
Rym: Some of them are like bust somebody up like bust up someone else's pimp.
Scott: Yeah, so they're like they're out of commission, but then they come back.
Rym: Yeah, this is oh, here's a specific job senators party.
Rym: This is what I was thinking of.
Rym: it'll pay out if you get two successes 24 grand.
Scott: Yeah There's a little bit of randomness going on if you get one sick.
Rym: But you can mitigate that randomness by putting the better mobsters on something or like putting a henchman down and you roll more dice.
Rym: Yeah, if it's only one success 18 grand, but you need a politician a nightclub a pimp and a drug dealer All the things you need for the senator's party.
Rym: It's very thematic.
Rym: Like the theme of this game is a plus.
Rym: Yeah, so you go around putting all your guys on the jobs and then you go around again executing the jobs.
Rym: So I might I might have a job that when I trigger it thought I need a nightclub and a pimp.
Rym: What if I trick don't trigger that job right away on Scott's turn?
Rym: He just murders the pimp.
Rym: Now my job is gonna fail if I trigger the mobster.
Rym: Now I'm gonna make a deal to get another pimp in a hurry.
Scott: So if you're gonna do the senator's party, which is worth a lot of money You're gonna want to do that when you're gonna go first so you can do it before anyone kills the senator.
Rym: So a lot of games that have this like a scenario confluence Let's say where you can just make binding deals with everybody all the time forever.
Rym: They tend to bog down in the deal-making phase.
Rym: Yeah, this game avoids that because every player takes a short simple action and you just keep going around and going around and going around and going around.
Scott: That's a nice modern design there, you know, wait, no waiting constant doing game doesn't feel long, but it also means that Negotiations will happen when they're relevant.
Rym: I might make a deal in advance.
Rym: I might make deals.
Scott: You're usually only making a deal relevant to if it's relevant to the one simple action.
Scott: You're about to take.
Scott: Yep, or Have a deal in my hand and during the before it's time to put out the deals.
Scott: That's what I'm like.
Scott: Well, I want to make this deal happen this turn.
Scott: I'm missing these two things.
Scott: Let's see who has those two things.
Scott: I'm gonna try to deal with those two things.
Scott: Yep
Rym: so the player whose turn it is to do their action is likely to be making the more urgent deals and capturing the attention whoever they need but simultaneously if Joey Jojo is taking a long time on his turn because it's a complicated turn or he's negotiating a big deal Me and Scott on the side might just talking about start talking about like hey Let's trade pimp for pimp for the future like things like that.
Rym: Mm-hmm The mechanic of the deals is really elegant to the.
Rym: if you want to use someone's thing You get the right to put a deal marker on that thing.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: The other player Can't renege on that deal.
Rym: Nope, nor like I can use that pimp for whatever I want, right?
Scott: It's like Rym says okay, you can put your marker on my pimp.
Scott: I put the marker on his pimp now.
Scott: That means I can use it once and remove the token.
Scott: But now everyone else when they're like killing they look around the board and they see like a pimp with like three tokens on it.
Scott: They're like, I guess I'm killing that pimp.
Scott: Yep That's gonna kill like mess up three other people's plans, yep, so it's it's.
Scott: on this one hand It's like a good mechanic, but it's also a great indicator and really mess with people's heuristics You don't want to like.
Scott: do I really want to ask him if I can borrow his pimp if it already has a marker from Someone else on it.
Scott: Oh, right.
Scott: That's gonna get that pimp killed.
Scott: There's no point.
Scott: Do something else?
Rym: No, no, I want to use.
Scott: maybe I'll buy my own pimp from the middle even though it cost me money.
Rym: No, no, I want to use your other pimp Scott not the one you're loading up that other pimp.
Rym: That's right Give me your good pimp.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: And then when I go around then I say oh which pimp do I want to kill?
Scott: Well Rym's losing the game.
Scott: I don't really need to kill any of his stuff.
Scott: Oh, but what's that?
Scott: I see Joey Jojo's got a marker on Rym's pimp and Jojo does win in the game.
Scott: I can hurt Joey Jojo and Rym by attacking that dude.
Rym: Yep so despite being highly political the politics is deeply constrained by the Realities of the game and the deal-making ends up being the right level of complexity like the kinds of deals I've seen having played this game a few times are things like here's God if you let me use your pimp I'll cut you in 50% on the deal that that pimp facilitates.
Scott: That's perfectly fine deal Especially if you make such deals frequently with a lot of players and most of them execute.
Scott: You will end up on the plus side because everyone else will have executed one deal and you'll have executed three or four.
Rym: Yep, or I might make a deal like listen Scott.
Rym: Let me use your pimp I'll give you five grand in cash right now because if you have a deal that pays out Until you trigger the deal as one of your actions, you don't have that money.
Rym: So getting cash up front might be very valuable to be able to afford the business.
Scott: I forget if you can kill your own dudes Yeah, you can bash your own dude, I think right.
Scott: so maybe not?
Scott: I don't remember.
Scott: if you could.
Scott: I don't think I did.
Scott: no one did.
Rym: I don't think I would.
Scott: I think I might have asked But it's like I could make a deal or like alright, you can use my pimp Give me some money and then I shoot my pimp.
Rym: Yeah, but that generally like the other thing I've seen happen is the because this thing is just keeping the pimp.
Scott: He does spit out money all the time and because it's a real transactional negotiating game.
Rym: I've found reliably that players who act in good faith tend to get ignored by the other players or just attacked outright.
Rym: and Revenge is a powerful mechanic in the context of this game in a way that I haven't seen play out in other games that have Similar themes and mechanics.
Rym: Yeah, this game is just a very Well-crafted Perfect storm of the right mechanics the right turn length the right level of interaction To give you all that fun feeling of a kind of serious and realistic mafia game Without getting too bogged down in details and without being just advanced werewolf.
Scott: Yeah, the thing about the other thing about this game is that it's just cards.
Scott: Yeah, it's just all cards So it's real cash.
Scott: It's all.
Scott: the cash is a little is papers.
Scott: It was not the greatest.
Scott: I think I might replace it.
Scott: wasn't see.
Scott: usually when I see paper money.
Scott: I'm like.
Scott: But actually I thought that when I saw the game set up on the table But actually when I was playing it was never a problem.
Rym: Oh, it feels good.
Rym: when you like I asked someone to go.
Scott: I think I would still replace it with chips just because you know Right, but I don't know.
Scott: I feel it didn't upset me like bad paper cash.
Scott: in other games.
Rym: Something felt good about getting a fat stack of cash and then doing the one for you one for me.
Rym: Yeah, I want to do for me one.
Scott: It's two for you one two for me.
Scott: But anyway, but the If you made chips or replace the money you could really pack this game small.
Rym: Yeah, sighs the games already really small.
Scott: I'm saying size per game really good ratio.
Rym: It also ain't that expensive like I forget.
Scott: I'm saying it's a lot of game in a small package And it doesn't take that long to play but you get a lot when you do play it.
Rym: All right Oh, yeah, and there's an expansion that adds more mobsters that are powers which also it's very easy to expand.
Scott: a game Stack of cards.
Rym: you want to just buy this on Amazon.
Rym: It's like 40 bucks that this game is worth 40 bucks.
Scott: Yeah, that is a lot for a stack of cards though.
Rym: It's a it's a heavy stack.
Rym: There's a lot of car It is true.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Also, I'm pretty sure at a game store.
Rym: You'll find this at a much significant discount.
Rym: Okay at PAX.
Rym: It was on pretty big sale.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: In fact, I was gonna go.
Scott: It's not a big hit game.
Scott: So it's because it's from 2014.
Scott: Oh So maybe the price is up is hard to find now, uh, there's 19 in stock on Amazon.
Rym: Amazon from capstone games right now Expansion.
Rym: there's only one left in stock.
Rym: Maybe I'll just buy this right after the before I put the episode up.
Rym: Yeah Say this games worth playing if you want like this kind of mafia if you want a game that involves deal-making and threatening Direct attacking other players.
Rym: Yes or threatening people in a way that will actually elicit a response other than fuck You it's risk.
Rym: You're gonna attack me.
Rym: Anyway, right?
Scott: It's a vote who wins game, but also has significant like, you know Mechanic stuff going on.
Rym: if you can make good deals like structured deals.
Rym: You can use this in the game.
Rym: I've seen people make pretty complex deals, right?
Scott: I'll let you borrow this guy and this guy But then you're gonna give me half the money from that deal and I get had the money from that.
Rym: in one game I sold insurance to people where if they gave me five grand then I would give immunity from certain kinds of negative activities And protection rackets work in this game.
Rym: And sometimes it's worth it to pay the protection racket.
Scott: do what mafia would do.
Rym: Yeah This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patreons for this episode of GeekNights.
Rym: Ah Craig Oliver, Alan Joyce, Heidi McNichol just like a dude guy Cuz.
Rym: art option link eg.
Rym: Jennifer Hitchcock Chris midkiff my Stady calm.
Rym: Jay Vance scoot alone Lee Roberto Kingsley Shawn Yeager Matthew Smith Nicholas Brando Mr.
Rym: Strong distraction for to one.
Rym: creations.
Rym: Chris Reimer and Thomas on.
Rym: Shervin von Horrell Rory Rochelle, Monta Nona super boy sailor Vista Don sh.
Rym: like Jojo Joestar Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin drew open Lander Finn Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas on.
Rym: I am partially recovered from the PAX pox and as you might have noticed if you watch the livestream We recorded this episode yesterday and I was the hockey game and it wasn't a great hockey game.
Rym: So now I leave you with.
Scott: You want to buy organ fresh and cheap ready for transplant?
Rym: What's this?
Scott: Ah, it's x-ray.
Scott: I see through anything.
Scott: Wait a minute.
Scott: This is zero.
Rym: C is just as good.
Rym: In fact is better is two more than X.
Scott: Is that a hobbit over there?
Scott: No, that's a hobo and a rabbit, but they're making a hobbit.
Scott: Buy my book buy my book buy my book.