Rym: It's Tuesday May 7th 2019.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: Are you playing to win or are you playing to just play it?
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So yesterday I was playing some beat saver in VR.
Rym: that game is crazy fast.
Scott: that VR rhythm game, right?
Rym: Yep, the only weird thing I guess.
Scott: what do you do?
Scott: You just like swing as you swing the VR sticks to the rhythm.
Rym: Yeah You basically have two lightsabers and blocks will have arrows on them and they'll be red or blue.
Rym: Gotta hit the red ones in the direction of the arrow with your left hand and the blue ones in the direction there with The right hand and they match music.
Scott: do?
Rym: they put blue ones on the left and sometimes they'll swap and move around and big walls will appear.
Rym: they got a Yep, and you're like stepping around.
Rym: you gotta move.
Rym: you gotta move quite a bit.
Rym: It's actually very just.
Scott: you're swinging virtual sticks to the beat.
Rym: Yeah, but what's weird about it is it's super fun But it feels wrong if you've ever actually fenced because holding two swords like this Just a metaphor.
Scott: It's move your hands to the rhythm.
Rym: It is you got to get a Train yourself into not thinking of them as swords, but it has a mode.
Rym: You know DDR has all that because it's the songs are well-crafted like in good DDR Like the arrows feel right and they do clever stuff like they'll be arrows in a pattern if you recognize the matter.
Scott: How much movement can I just be like?
Rym: Yeah, you're just a lightsaber.
Rym: it goes right through the block as it's coming at you.
Scott: I mean, you know do I have to like get up and move a lot?
Scott: Can I just be like me me me me.
Rym: you'll have to be standing because sometimes a big wall will be coming and you have To like stand to the side.
Scott: I just roll my chair.
Rym: you could There might be one too high to hit.
Rym: some of you got a stab Mmm, but and they're all over the place.
Rym: But it has a saber mode where you only use one stick.
Rym: that sounds like baby mode except It's kind of like DDR challenge mode.
Rym: it has you know, it is like like medium-heavy like a similar thing.
Rym: It's the equivalent of it a number of hands instead of feet.
Rym: No, it's actually just like Easy medium hard expert extreme like something like that.
Rym: But if you put it in saver mode, it's expert.
Scott: only is there song.
Scott: is there some song?
Scott: That's the equivalent of like the impossible song.
Rym: Yeah And I was like, nope, no Matt Morgan's fairly really good at it.
Rym: But as I was playing and then Emily was like imagine when it gets really fast.
Scott: It's similar to like just drumming right only drums all over the place.
Rym: Well, here's an example of clever errors.
Rym: now DDR.
Rym: There's arrow combinations like in our favorite song music where if you don't know like notice the pattern and learn to like do the spin Or the torso torso twist.
Rym: It's really hard.
Rym: same thing.
Rym: You notice a pattern.
Rym: you're like.
Rym: that pattern is just swing the sword like this Like twirl it like that.
Rym: kind of figure this out.
Rym: So I'm playing and then Emily taps me on the shoulder which is always terrifying in VR and it's like hey I got to do my I got to do a thing on my computer and I can't just be here like swinging around swords with a blindfold on.
Rym: So, uh, I get her up to leave and then Emily's is down and then she says whoa What the fuck's wrong with my computer?
Rym: You notice her surface laptop is not sitting there right now.
Scott: She just take it with her to do work.
Rym: So the top of it the surface is a pretty cool device because the top part is the computer and it.
Rym: you can use it As just all computer the pro surface.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know if they still make the pro one like that or not.
Rym: I haven't had which has the newest the second newest one.
Scott: It's I haven't looked at the newest newest ones.
Rym: Basically.
Rym: It's the laptop I would buy if I had to buy a laptop today.
Scott: Actually.
Scott: I have a spare AC adapter for a surface Just lying around.
Scott: Oh you want it?
Scott: Maybe.
Rym: But so the top part is like a pretty good serve like tablet computer like really powerful.
Rym: But if you plug it into the bottom half, then it's a laptop with a real ad.
Rym: It's got a 1050 bottom card.
Scott: bottom part is pretty much just a video card.
Scott: Video card like a black card video card.
Rym: I just a 1050 which is not a terrible video card.
Scott: It's not a 10 10, but he didn't exist.
Rym: when the yeah, it's a 1050 You get a 950 or a 1050.
Rym: Mmm.
Rym: It's a pretty good video card.
Rym: Like it'll play overwatch It'll render video like better than my previous computer with the 760.
Scott: I was a 1050 doesn't sound right, but if the last one was it is a GPU in there.
Scott: Yeah It's pretty much a GPU a keyboard and some connectors and more battery.
Rym: Yeah, so what what you we saw was that the whole bottom had just like bowed down Like they're like the bottom was about to like pop off and you couldn't push it back up.
Rym: and I peeked inside the entire battery pack had expanded mmm and because And because now the computer still worked just fine.
Rym: the top part Yeah, the top part not the bottom part though plugged into the bottom part.
Scott: It still worked fine But but the bottom part wasn't doing anything though.
Scott: It was just operating.
Rym: as I imagine if we did anything that invoked the video card It would have been a problem.
Rym: Anyway, so, uh, he's had to take it to the Microsoft Store and they were like, yep batteries fucked.
Rym: We will give you an entire new surface for free.
Scott: That sounds good.
Scott: The newest a newer one or the same one Same one, which is still pretty new.
Scott: I'm always surprised at how like I've been to the Apple Store for like Apple care stuff They will have like the exact models of things.
Rym: Yeah, they'll never be like, oh you're going way back.
Rym: Your one-year-old iPhone is like.
Scott: well in like and then and not only that but they'll have them in like this Non-retail clearly meant for replacing things packaging.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: So it's like oh, yeah this old thing that we don't sell in the store anymore But yours broke.
Scott: we have that exact one in the back.
Scott: Yeah, here it is, but you don't get it extra.
Scott: You don't get all the retail packagings You don't get extra cables or anything.
Scott: You'd get just the thing that you're replacing.
Rym: Meanwhile cameras really like every time I gotta get a camera or something repaired or I know people who have had to deal with They want to repair it.
Scott: They don't.
Scott: actually they don't want to give you a new one Fix the one you got because
Rym: they can't give you the same one you have because I usually don't do that long of a production Run of any particular camera and they don't want to give you the next one up.
Scott: Even if they do they want to repair the one you have.
Scott: they don't want to make anything.
Rym: I'm still waiting for him to fix my lens, but they did find the problem.
Rym: So they'll fix it.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: And so yeah The laptop just expanded the battery in the bottom half of that probably because it has to power a video card.
Scott: He didn't start a fire.
Rym: Yeah, we are really lucky.
Rym: It didn't start a fire explode.
Scott: It was.
Rym: it was like puffed.
Rym: if you if you've ever seen of naked lithium-ion cell Yeah, I seen it puffed like that.
Scott: It was that I had little tiny GoPro batteries that puffed.
Scott: Yep Got rid of those.
Rym: I had a GoPro battery puff.
Rym: I was skiing and I was videoing and then I saw the GoPro to stop.
Scott: I was like, how come I can't get the back onto the battery cover onto this old GoPro hero - oh the battery is puffed Goodbye.
Rym: I took the big GoPro out of the case.
Rym: This is the old one that had like the case and then you had to open the camera itself separately from the case.
Rym: Now GoPro's are just waterproof on their own But I open the back and the back just pops off and the battery just goes whoop.
Scott: and I'm like, oh shit Yeah, my new my GoPro.
Scott: I guess I have a GoPro 5 now.
Scott: I think the newest one is like 7 or so.
Rym: Yeah Yeah, the new GoPros are great like I feel like Newer than 5.
Scott: the benefits are only incremental.
Scott: They're all yeah that the newer GoPros You only need if you're doing like really high FPS Like when I got the 2 I was like when when I replace this and then I was like, oh, yeah I got the 5. it's like alright now.
Scott: I'm really not gonna replace this.
Scott: Yep I mean, I'm in a definitely a no replacement mode.
Scott: My iPhone 7 is still going.
Rym: Yeah, dude, not only is my two-year-old Xperia like awesome phone still going but I do own another identical phone.
Scott: I'm sure if I want to I can get an iPhone 7 that is new and unused.
Rym: Yep So when this phone finally dies, I'm just going to swap my sim into an identical phone that I own that's never been used.
Rym: Hmm cuz it's the last good Android phone.
Rym: I'm not I'm not replaced.
Rym: I'm just trying to keep everything I got.
Scott: Oh, there's a new Android phone.
Scott: They announced today.
Scott: This seems okay pixel 3.
Rym: It's the 3a the pink camera and that thing is bullshit compared to the camera on this phone.
Scott: The 3a supposedly has like an amazing camera on it.
Rym: We'll see.
Rym: I saw mixed review.
Rym: Well when you when you were talking about that in the discard, I looked at some reviews and they were all over the place.
Rym: Anyway, we'll see.
Rym: We'll see in the news.
Rym: If you didn't know there's a game called Uno.
Rym: that's really popular among I guess families.
Scott: It's actually been coming up a lot recently.
Scott: what hat there was?
Scott: a there's a. there's a great Twitter account bootleg stuff that post bootleg stuff mostly anime bootleg stuff And they posted a picture of a bootleg Pokemon Uno.
Scott: and I replied and I was like, you know That is a bootleg you posted but there is a real Pokemon Uno.
Scott: There's a real Mario Uno.
Scott: There's a whole bunch of themed Unos that are whole totally legit and nerdy and awesome.
Rym: Uno is basically Monopoly.
Scott: Uno is a better game than Monopoly.
Rym: Yeah, but in terms of there's a monopoly for every conceivable thing that is licensed.
Rym: There's a monopoly for like every damn city every movie franchise.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, there's a Uno has a similar thing going on, but The Uno the official Uno Twitter account tweeted something and I was confused by it because it said it was a rules Clarification.
Rym: it said if someone puts down a plus four card, I'm just assuming you know how Uno works You must draw four and your turn is skipped.
Scott: Yeah, that's the rule.
Scott: if Rym is sitting to my right or left Well depend and the play is going clockwise and Rym plays a plus four I draw four because he attacked me and you skip your turn.
Scott: fucking the next person on the other side of me is now.
Scott: It is now their turn.
Scott: that is correct.
Scott: to Uno.
Scott: play the next.
Scott: apparently some people just made up rules of Uno.
Scott: Yeah Out of nothing.
Scott: to where Rym would play an attack card making me draw say four or two.
Scott: Then I would be able to play another attack card and thus both Attack cards would apply to the person to my left.
Scott: That is bullshit.
Scott: You made up.
Rym: Here's the thing.
Rym: I played Uno a lot as a kid with That ever.
Rym: I'd never heard of that.
Rym: the fact that the official Uno account is like you can't put down a plus two to make The next person draw six.
Rym: Well, you know, you've tried.
Rym: who has tried that?
Rym: Who are these fucking people?
Rym: and the answer is look at the people replying to this account.
Rym: Apparently everyone plays Uno in this ridiculous made-up nonsense way.
Scott: I do love that.
Scott: The Uno account is defending the rules.
Rym: There's a tweet here.
Rym: Someone responded with a screenshot of the rules and said guys it's right in the rules.
Rym: I went out inside and bought another deck to make sure like Apparently people believe this nonsense rule and here is the genius part.
Rym: This is why I love this Twitter account.
Rym: All these responses are wait What about blah?
Rym: What about blah?
Rym: and the Uno account just keeps responding.
Rym: No, no Nope No You cannot.
Rym: that is stacking.
Rym: Nope.
Rym: You cannot stack.
Rym: Yes, one person was like, can I win by using a wild card?
Scott: and they're like, yes Yeah, if you're if you have Uno and your last card is wild you're just gonna win and you play it you win.
Scott: That's how Uno works.
Scott: you go down to one card you say Uno and then you empty your hand and you win.
Rym: Yep, so apparently people just play Uno with made-up nonsense rules props to whoever runs the Uno account props for being pro rules.
Scott: I want to see the Monopoly Uno now, I feel like I want to.
Scott: I don't have an.
Scott: I don't think I have an Uno currently.
Scott: I've had one in the past.
Rym: Well, cuz if I want to play that kind of game I'm just gonna play like Shaquille or something.
Scott: Yeah, but I kind of want to find the bet.
Scott: It's so cheap to buy an Uno so that's fine.
Rym: I'll probably have an Uno deck.
Rym: I gave my mom just mail to me.
Scott: I have probably have one to somewhere.
Scott: but I kind of want to find the best themed Uno and buy just that Uno.
Scott: Right, maybe there's like a Mega Man Uno or something.
Rym: Oh Mega Man Uno.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: there could be anything.
Rym: We could just make it Uno and I could just get it printed.
Scott: Yeah, but you're gonna find a better one.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Well if I'm gonna do that, I'm gonna make a clod.
Rym: So in some other news, uh Sports are games and we'll talk about this briefly.
Rym: But in the sport of horse racing, which is more a sport for the horses than the jockeys, but the jockeys play a role lot of Things we could talk about is
Scott: one positive thing I can say about the about horse racing is that they treat the horse as the champion.
Scott: Yeah, like this horse one They don't put too much emphasis the horse They do.
Scott: they do interview the jockeys and and and they get money and stuff and they're well.
Scott: I mean the owners are also right but most of the attention is on the horse.
Scott: They consider the horse to be the winner.
Scott: the horse won the Triple Crown not the jockey not the owner Like.
Rym: that's why I know the name Far Lab But I have no idea who the hell rode Far Lab.
Scott: Right, the name of the movie is Secretariat.
Scott: The name of the movie is not something else.
Rym: And regardless of your controversial feelings about exploiting animals in this way at least the animals are getting the fame?
Rym: Not there are worse ways to exploit animals Yes, but if you didn't watch the Kentucky Derby a horse won by a lot and then someone who did not win issued a challenge because that horse broke a rule?
Scott: that is disqualifying and According to people are experts in horse racing cuz I'm sure as hell not I know That.
Scott: yes, indeed that horse did break a rule and therefore should not have won.
Scott: So here's even though if that horse didn't break the rule It probably still would have won because it was the fastest horse.
Scott: people said it was the fastest horse before the race.
Scott: It has the shortest odds.
Rym: if you're the best hockey team and you keep hitting people in the face with your sticks You're not gonna win the Stanley Cup, even if you are in fact the best at hockey.
Rym: But
Scott: I do actually want to congratulate the sport of horse racing whoever officiates it because you know They have done the right thing the same thing that bicycle racing did right because bicycle racing does a lot of things wrong Cycling right in that when someone cheated or broke a rule the penalty was losing.
Scott: Unlike football or in someone cheats or breaks a rule the penalty is like you get a fine you get a suspension You lose some draft picks, but you're still the Super Bowl champions.
Scott: Yeah, the penalty for cheating must be losing.
Scott: Otherwise cheating is just an avenue for pay to win.
Rym: Yep, or in the context of hockey because you get a two-minute penalty for slashing.
Rym: Slashing is part of the game.
Rym: You can just slash.
Scott: Yeah, if someone's about to score you it's a good idea to like say, you know interfere do some interference or cross-check them Or whatever
Rym: and then hope you win
Scott: Right hope if they're gonna score a goal on a breakaway You're better off knocking them over even though they get a penalty shot.
Scott: because well now you got a chance to block that penalty shot Right.
Scott: Oh if they're gonna score a goal, okay, you might be able to kill a two-minute power play, right?
Scott: It's part of the game.
Rym: Yeah now that part of the game.
Rym: Maybe you should change a little bit, but maybe it should.
Rym: I Mean, what do you make a team?
Rym: That's just a bunch of monsters and you have the best penalty killing squad in the league Like you could.
Rym: that could be a strategy.
Rym: It is a strategy.
Rym: I know it shouldn't be.
Scott: why not?
Rym: So anyway, even better the attorney for maximum security the horse that was disqualified Or is that that would have won if it didn't break the rules?
Rym: filed an appeal and the Racing Commission responded denying the appeal saying that Stewards decisions are not subject to appeal.
Rym: There is no appeal process.
Scott: well I mean that's a problem.
Scott: but the thing is even whether it was an appeal process or not.
Scott: As I said everyone who knows about horse racing seems to be mostly in agreement.
Scott: Well, this is a correct ruling.
Scott: Here's what's extra from what I have gathered.
Scott: Maybe someone else gathers differently.
Scott: Let me know.
Rym: horse racing is one of the earliest sports to use the photo finish meaning.
Rym: Hey cameras exist.
Rym: We're gonna fucking use this to know exactly.
Scott: You know why?
Scott: because fucking money's on the line, yep soccer.
Scott: That's why all these other sports have gotten away with all kinds of bullshit.
Scott: And as soon as we betting is at least, you know, they legalize sports gambling.
Scott: that will suck.
Scott: But at least they're gonna start.
Scott: but that'll force the replay to come into everything so that people who bet don't sue dude.
Rym: last night In the Bruins game where they limited the eliminated the cabbages the CVJs From from the playoffs The first goal scored in the game was actually under review in Toronto for a while at least.
Scott: they review it.
Rym: They were watching that replay over good over.
Rym: It's over a playoff goal.
Scott: You better be fucking watching that in an elimination game Yep, and the chat like it was just.
Rym: they disallowed the goal in the end.
Scott: Good job.
Rym: It was interesting because that goal in the 90s would not have been disallowed.
Scott: Hell no.
Rym: Yeah In the 90s, it was only goalie interference.
Rym: if you like punch the goalie out.
Scott: Well, there was the arrow where it was goalie interference if any part of any offensive player's body was in the blue paint And it was also while the goal was scored even if it wasn't interfering with the goalie in any way whatsoever.
Scott: And then there was a situation I remember reviewing it every time and disallowing all the goals.
Rym: I remember being at a Red Wings game where Sergei Fedorov skate was like in the edge of the crease Nowhere near the action.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So the goal was disallowed even though it had nothing to do with the play Yep, so yeah Props to horse racing for following their own rules and not bowing to public pressure or all this nonsense.
Rym: And that sucks, but them's the rules In some other news right.
Scott: so scrabble a game that we're not big fans of because it is a game of mostly Memorization and not a game of any of the other.
Scott: right if you play it with people who haven't memorized the scrabble dictionary Then it is a good game because it's about positioning And You know sort of creativity with words sort of like banana grams.
Rym: right if you replace the letters with Like squares that have four different colors on the sides, and there's rules about like matching colors to play things it would also work.
Scott: Yeah, a banana grams forces you to use speed to sort of eliminate the memory problem But in the end pro scrabble ends up being a game of memory.
Scott: how much of the scrabble dictionary?
Scott: Have you memorized and then you win?
Scott: so then my news is actually pretty interesting.
Scott: They just added a fuck ton of words to the scrabble dictionary 2862
Rym: new words
Scott: including lots of two-letter words that were previously not legal like okay And you like EW as well as words that are very Modern like genderqueer or the gender neutral pronouns a or words like fleek.
Scott: All right, so I think that's pretty cool that scrabble despite being a meh memory game is actually willing to a Challenge the pros by forcing them to memorize 2,000 more fucking words.
Rym: Here's the thing.
Scott: you might also make itself more accessible to people who are probably not playing with the scrabble dictionary.
Scott: Handy are gonna put in fleek and then be like argue about it.
Scott: And there's gonna be like a grandma who's like that's not a word and the kid is like it totally is.
Scott: and then look up The word and grandma's wrong, and that'll be the best.
Scott: quid you bow.
Rym: That's right Perfectly chromulant word.
Scott: my way to a triple word school a Big dumb balding hairless a.
Rym: yeah with I mean with a with a fat head.
Rym: in the meantime I forget the quote.
Rym: you know anyway.
Rym: That was a long time ago, but different.
Rym: Actually understand How much of a change does adding about 3,000 words to a game that already has 276,000 words matter?
Rym: it matters a lot and completely changes the meta of the game.
Rym: scrabble is now a completely different game.
Rym: I'm gonna read a quote from this article Quote one of the most impactful changes to the game.
Rym: One of the words some of the words they added because it ends with the letter K. It used to be that if you put a K down you knew your opponent couldn't play across the top of it.
Rym: It'll be a change of mindset.
Rym: He said he predicted the inclusion of the word would outrage some fans, but and here's the money shot quote.
Rym: That's the joy of it.
Rym: So the fact that these extra words exist Really changes the strategy of scrabble.
Rym: It's not just memorize the words It's consider how each and every one of these words opens up Potential new play strategies.
Scott: It's basically a new meta for scrabble, which is news for any nerd game.
Scott: It's like oh a new meta for magic.
Scott: Yeah, that happens all the time.
Scott: Yeah a new meta for hockey.
Rym: There's a new meta for ice hockey right now.
Scott: Yeah, no matter for overwatch alright Oh scrabble finally got a new meta.
Scott: welcome to nerd world boys.
Scott: Yeah Welcome to nerd.
Rym: Oh total aside before we get to the things of the day.
Rym: I learned something interesting.
Rym: You know we had an expansion draft and the NHL recently.
Rym: yeah Yeah There's another kind of draft that hasn't happened in a long time.
Rym: when a team is shut down There's a reverse draft for everyone to steal those players.
Scott: No team is gonna get shut down.
Rym: so it almost happened To a team in the 70s.
Scott: there are teams that like didn't draft because there were issues.
Rym: Yeah No There was a team that was so performing so poorly Financially that it almost shut down mid-season And there was a plan to have a reverse draft to steal all the players from this team into the rest of the NHL.
Rym: but anyway it is time for It's time for things of the day.
Scott: what he got.
Rym: so I'm sure people most people know the word culvert right But I don't think most people do because when we had up when scojo moved to his new house that was next to that culvert.
Rym: I said well, you're next to a culvert and Half our friends were like a what?
Scott: so if you don't know what a culvert is Basically in situations where there's water and it might say flood right you don't want a flood.
Scott: I don't know on a road that cars have to drive through right and then go sploosh Yeah So what you do a culvert is pretty simple.
Scott: is you maybe just put a bunch of fucking pipes under the road so that the water when it comes to the road goes up under The road and out the other side?
Scott: and now your road is dry and the water continues to flow.
Rym: so back up a little bit.
Rym: So when you have roads that don't have rainwater drainage systems on them like old roads rural roads often what you'll have our ditches Mmm rainwater systems are basically just covered ditches like you cover the ditches turn them into pipes And then you put drains in the road.
Rym: mm-hmm where do those drains go?
Scott: they go down the hill yeah down somewhere Yeah, so especially if you like a mountain road You know you don't want to have like a grill in the mountain road that then you have to put a pipe under.
Scott: you know You get the idea anyway, so this kid I don't know if it's a kid or whatever But he's talking about riding around with his dad.
Scott: so it must be someone who lives with their dad Or it needs.
Scott: it needs a ride from their dad at least anyway Noticed that this drain in a small lake slash large pond kind of place Was all clogged up and The culvert wasn't really flowing and the lake level was kind of high.
Scott: And you can see that the drain was like all clogged up with all kinds of garbage.
Rym: Yep, because there's a cage there to prevent the clog from getting into the culvert right because that's a lot harder to clear out.
Scott: Yeah, you didn't get to go in the pipe clearing shit out.
Scott: You don't do that.
Rym: go find any culvert like a big one And you'll see like a big metal cage under the water usually anyway.
Scott: He tells his dad.
Scott: Hey bring me back there later.
Scott: I want to clear that out.
Scott: so he goes back there with a whole bunch of gear to make himself dry and protected from dangerous bits and Also a camera to post a video on YouTube that you're gonna watch.
Rym: it's a real satisfying video.
Scott: It's one of those like real satisfying things.
Scott: or this dude who doesn't seem you know I guess he seems slightly like a weird dude cuz he's spent his time doing this I mean if you're in the covers also sort of like an unsung hero.
Scott: right as he goes and he removes all the garbage from the top of this drain and The water starts off flowing.
Rym: That's a good feeling.
Scott: He's good, and you could keep.
Scott: just don't stop watching this.
Scott: you might think oh Whatever, but no it keeps going.
Scott: anything like he comes back later And you can see the water level went down overnight like multiple inches.
Scott: this video is the definition of wait for it And he shows you like where the water flew like went to deck in a swamp way below the road down the hill somewhere.
Rym: So my thing of the day f1.
Rym: if you don't know one thing about f1 cars Is that the steering wheels are like 20 to 30 thousand dollar pieces of technology?
Scott: Car you're in a really tight space right and you've got pedals down by your feet.
Scott: You maybe got some levers to your side, but you can't really move around too much right in a little tiny cockpit.
Rym: Yeah, you're also experiencing extreme g-forces And you can't really look around much and you can't.
Scott: you got to wear this helmet.
Scott: you wedge yourself in there Right.
Scott: so you got this really expensive really fancy car with all sorts of crazy features Right on it that you need to control and since you don't have a giant Dashboard like whatever SUV you're probably driving you suburban.
Scott: What was All?
Scott: the controls go on the steering wheel mostly yep, and they have to be.
Rym: they have to be usable by someone driving a car at high speed under pressure and They have to do a lot.
Rym: Yeah, they literally cost 20 or 30 thousand dollars to make.
Scott: they're all custom-made for the car for the driver whatever.
Scott: I've seen lots of videos in the past of Drivers showing off their steering wheels being like this button.
Scott: does this this button?
Scott: does that right?
Scott: Remember one with Kimi Raikkonen specifically?
Scott: I watched the whole thing.
Scott: Yeah, he told every single part of the steering wheel he explained.
Scott: What the hell it did.
Rym: so One driver takes an older steering wheel from some years ago back when traction control was still allowed.
Rym: Oh, and he walks you through in detail what every one of the fucking buttons does.
Rym: and it's fascinating especially because a few of them are blanked out and A few of them are not legal anymore.
Rym: Like traction control is not allowed in f1 not anymore.
Rym: Yes, you can't have like controls to enable and disable like different types of traction control.
Rym: Somebody walks through like what everything does but then he does something.
Rym: I've never seen before because usually when he watched these videos The person asks hey, so what's on the back?
Rym: and the answer is always I can't show you the back.
Scott: and they like studiously Like the camera, I don't know why but they never show you the back and they're basically like yeah, it's proprietary trade secret.
Scott: We can't show you the back of the steering wheel.
Scott: I'm like what the fuck could be on there.
Scott: There's just some shifting paddles and like some sort of cylinder where it connects to the the drive shaft Connecty thing like sorry doesn't what could possibly be back there?
Scott: a gun to shoot the other?
Scott: You're hiding, you know, I don't like performance enhancing drugs.
Scott: What the hell you hiding back there.
Rym: So I'm half watching this video and I'm playing some overwatch and then it gets to a point like around eight minutes in where he's like, okay now I'm gonna show you the back and I'm like what what the fuck?
Rym: finally and You get to see the back and they talk about it in detail and there's eight paddles back there but Says something interesting.
Scott: Does he tell you why no one else wants to see the back?
Rym: No, he says usually we can't show you the back And then he turned but I can show you this one because it's a few years old and I think okay That's still cool.
Rym: And then he says something fascinating.
Rym: He says and I removed the top-secret stuff.
Rym: So now you see the back and there's eight paddles back there and they're like Customizable and like you just get to see like the details of the back and he explains what all the paddles do and like this Fancy connector you can even see inside the connector.
Rym: But he did say there is something top-secret that they removed before they let us see it.
Scott: What the fuck are they keeping on the back of these wheels?
Scott: And if every team no team will show you the back.
Scott: so they all know their secret Team has secret stuff on the back of their wheel.
Scott: What the fuck is back there?
Rym: Here's the thing.
Scott: the next time possibly be the next.
Rym: The next time a driver has that hissy fit where they crash and they get out of the car and they throw the steering wheel.
Rym: I want to analyze frame by frame every video angle of that.
Rym: I
Scott: want to bring the zoomiest zoom zoom fucking lens to an f1 race with the Ultra slow-mo camera to zoom in on the back of some steering wheel when a guy gets out of the car
Rym: Because he literally is like, oh, yeah, we removed the top-secret stuff and he's like dead serious about that.
Rym: Is this just a long-running prank where there's nothing secret back there?
Rym: and they all agreed to pretend
Scott: every single formula one team as Since they invented fancy wheels and instead is having normal steering wheels
Rym: like imagine if everyone who plays competitive Smash Brothers all agreed that there's a special controller they use when they're playing it in tournaments and No one's allowed to see the back of it because there's something secret there.
Rym: That's only for pros.
Scott: and if this is an old-ass wheel then like what the fuck?
Scott: I mean there are people who have purchased old.
Scott: no, right.
Scott: f1 cars change every year.
Scott: There are people who purchased old cars and who are not associated with the teams or the drivers.
Scott: Surely they know what's on the back of the wheel.
Scott: or did they give those people a wheel that they could drive the car with?
Scott: That does not have top secret stuff on it.
Scott: Yeah, so they get less than the original car.
Scott: They just get like some replacement wheel.
Rym: I have no idea.
Rym: but I'm like I'm even more invested in what the hell is on the back of those wheels now that I've ever been.
Scott: It's like it's not even valuable information to me.
Rym: No I did means nothing to me.
Rym: I just that's the kind of thing where if it wasn't secret I would go.
Rym: I find one YouTube video that explains what the deal is and I'd go.
Rym: oh.
Scott: And then I just remember that drivers and other employees of Formula One teams move from team to team.
Scott: Right they don't have like.
Scott: no they debrief them.
Rym: They're like listen if you talk about what's on the back of this fucking wheel.
Rym: We will kill your family.
Scott: It's like the driver knows what's on the back, and they don't have some sort of no compete.
Scott: They move from team to team all the time.
Scott: It's like I Don't know.
Rym: I want to know.
Rym: I want to know more than anything And once I find out.
Rym: I know what it would happen probably disappointing and lame.
Rym: yeah, I would go oh, okay cool And I would just proceed to never care again In the meta moment.
Scott: the gig nights book club book is a painful pages.
Rym: Troy Dennings Planescape branded novel pages of pain Which is one of two books that introduced most people to the deal with the planescape setting.
Rym: it's a painful book.
Rym: I just got to the part there in the maze.
Rym: They're following the thread they.
Scott: I just got to a part where you like cut off some giant finger in the maze.
Scott: I'm right.
Rym: I'm so I'm not at that part yet in the reread, but I remember that part.
Rym: okay I remember that part from a kid.
Rym: What's weird is I didn't remember the fact that the thread existed at all.
Rym: Okay, cuz this new this book just goes like here's a scene.
Rym: that's happening and then something hard to explain happens.
Rym: now They're in a different place and a different thing is happening.
Rym: mm-hmm that that seems to just happen.
Rym: I like how the elf is like what Dabu.
Rym: What do you mean?
Rym: a wall?
Rym: who built a wall?
Rym: We're not in the maze Mm-hmm, so yeah, we'll be doing this book pretty soon.
Scott: Wow the paperback I'm about halfway done.
Rym: Yeah, I'm a little bit behind Scott.
Rym: I'm just at the part where they're in the hot part of the maze with the hail and they froze it.
Rym: They turned his foot to stone.
Scott: I'm past that yeah, but I remember.
Rym: I remember some stuff past that also.
Rym: He is clearly Theseus.
Rym: It is ham-fisted Lee just telling us hey.
Rym: Here's all these hints.
Rym: Maybe you can face Theseus.
Rym: They're saying that it's fucking.
Rym: Theseus came to the pages of pain.
Rym: Theseus is just in Planescape.
Rym: Yeah, that is what it is saying.
Rym: otherwise a bunch of our recent panels are on YouTube.
Rym: you can just go watch them and Let's go right into it.
Rym: So the reason we want to do this show is partly because we talk about this a lot.
Scott: Well, this is some idea that I've been espousing for years now.
Scott: I feel like I must have talked about on the show at least once and it applies to a much broader Like, you know, hey, it's it's.
Scott: it's a huge issue that applies to I guess all communities.
Scott: Yeah, right and not just gaming.
Scott: but it is most prominent and recognized in gaming Whereas in other areas is not recognized so much.
Scott: But people are seeing this.
Scott: the gaming is the area where people are seeing it and simply not Recognizing it and zooming out.
Scott: Yeah, but I think gaming is where it actually matters more because it doesn't matter more in gaming Which is also why I think people recognize it there.
Rym: because there's an example say Game of Thrones like it's had a final season or whatever is happening right now and people are watching that.
Rym: Some of the people watching it are just watching it because yeah medieval fighting and stuff.
Rym: I wonder what happens.
Rym: cool and some people are like Trying to analyze the allegory and symbolism and details and figure stuff out and look at the Cinematography and like there's all these different communities who are watching Game of Thrones for different reasons.
Rym: Those communities don't actually have to interact and do not actually affect each other in any meaningful way.
Scott: Well, it's like I said, uh, you know in the world we organize, you know, at least in our Western capitalist societies We organize our communities especially fan communities But also all communities in general right based on the wrong things.
Scott: Star Wars fans will get together at Star Wars Celebration.
Scott: there will be people there who like making robot r2d2s that are like perfect replicas and there are people there who like Writing Star Wars fan fiction.
Scott: those people actually have almost nothing in common Whereas if the Star Wars fan fiction writer got together with say a Harry Potter fan fiction writer.
Scott: They would even though the Harry Potter person might not like Star Wars at all And the Star Wars person might like Harry Potter at all.
Scott: those people have more in common than the Star Wars person does with the r2d2 robot person because We're not more organizing our communities based on what actually makes people like each other and get along right, but even look at We're organizing people based on brands or properties.
Rym: or here's a great example.
Rym: look at an anime con.
Rym: we go to an anime con and we want to like do panels and learn stuff about the Industry and learn stuff about animation and that kind of thing.
Rym: and some other people go because they want to cosplay as Dragon Ball Z and watch Dragon Ball Z and Neither one of us actually interfere with each other's fun.
Scott: for the most part we can also choose But we also have nothing in common.
Scott: Well.
Scott: We have a lot less in common than you would think.
Rym: but Fortnight and games like it overwatch any gaming this problem.
Rym: You have to play the game with other people and all the people who play the game Play the game together.
Rym: yep, so here's the problem.
Rym: We're.
Rym: we'll start with the fortnight story because the fortnight story is the linchpin of all this.
Scott: For now it's just the latest incident that has brought this to light again.
Rym: Yeah But it brought us to light and probably the big like writ large.
Rym: yes because more people play fortnight than anything.
Rym: Yeah, fortnight like this affected a lot of people who don't think hard all right about games.
Scott: So here's what I've gathered from the story.
Rym: right it was hard to figure out which update it was because there's anger about literally Some sort of patch to fortnight.
Scott: and what the patch did is it changed the game so that when you killed someone They would drop loot of some kind.
Scott: I don't know if it was the loot they had or additional loot but you do be loot and This was not true before.
Scott: it used to be that you had to do like pub G where you have to go around Collecting loot and then start shooting people with the loot you gathered.
Scott: yeah, right, but you would kill people They would drop their loot and or maybe new loot I don't know the point is.
Scott: it was such.
Scott: it was enough loot that you could at the start of the game Just start killing people and you didn't have to go and farm for any stuff or search for anything.
Scott: You can just start killing people and if you just kept killing people with your good shooting skills You could win the game.
Scott: and that was actually the strategy to win the game.
Scott: because of this patch They made they may it ended up making fortnight more of an e-sport more of a real game where you could try to win and Skill was rewarded and people tried to kill each other in order to win.
Rym: now the people who play fortnight competitively or wanted to play fortnight can learn very happy with this patch because that changes the game - yes there is like a Very clear path to victory.
Rym: if I am better at killing people because it is a you know one man a million people enter one person remains They can play the game to win and their skill will matter.
Rym: yep They by killing more people by doing the thing they're supposed to do They will become better at in the context of that instance of the game doing that thing and eventually it's a snowball and someone will win.
Rym: Yep, most of the players of fortnight hated this because the way most people play fortnight They don't actually try to win.
Rym: They kind of just like fucking around in fortnight.
Rym: Yep, killing people is like the thing that the serious people do at the end, and they don't really care that much.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Scott: yeah people the vast majority of people in general it seems based on you know I guess Experience I've had right are not injured.
Scott: there are people who are interested in playing games Competitively to win and treat games that way, but it seems the most majority people just like playing.
Scott: They just like to play which is perfectly valid.
Scott: is that right?
Scott: It's not like there's a right or wrong way.
Rym: well like I was a kid I'd play Zelda 2 when I was young my kid brain.
Rym: I didn't try to beat Zelda 2.
Rym: I just played it.
Rym: I don't know I was doing.
Rym: I just like wandered around.
Scott: Maybe you think about.
Scott: it's like you play with your action figures.
Scott: Yeah, just playing it's fun.
Scott: that's what people do.
Scott: play is great right play is a good thing and Even though there are games that are constructs in which there is some sort of victory condition Right you know even if people don't even recognize that their decisions don't matter like Candyland a lot of adults don't realize.
Rym: No, right is oh my god It packs that we were.
Rym: we were literally arguing with this dude in line who didn't understand.
Scott: Yeah shuffling cards.
Rym: Yeah He literally could not fathom the idea that if you shuffle the cards or if you don't shuffle them Or if you shuffle them every turn the outcomes the same.
Rym: in a random game of candy like it was it was a weird situation.
Scott: anyway.
Rym: the point is I'm still mad about that conversation with that guy.
Scott: I don't know there was no way to get through to him because he didn't have the mental capacity to understand what we were Saying.
Scott: yep, or at least not in the short amount of time we had Fundamentally did not have a concept of statistics.
Scott: No none.
Scott: What's it?
Scott: most people don't yeah?
Scott: The point is most people just like to play and even if they happen to be playing something where there is a way to Win they right they don't really care too much about it.
Scott: They just want to play.
Rym: now for most of gaming history This is also fine because if I'm just playing Zelda 2 to win No one else is affected by that who plays Zelda 2.
Scott: yeah I mean you would have some occasional Situations where you'd go to an arcade and try to play street fighter And you would lose to someone immediately and then have to walk away But you know you would just wait until there wasn't anyone there.
Scott: But if you weren't good enough right because he was gonna cost you money to fight against that really good guy You're not gonna do it.
Rym: I always go play the Mortal Kombat 2 machine when no one was around because I just wanted to play the single-player version.
Scott: right yeah So these didn't really.
Scott: and even when multiplayer gaming became a thing right it was like Goldeneye in your house.
Scott: It was.
Scott: you know Even if you if you had to be really smart to be able to play quake online or right multiplayer gaming wasn't really competitive.
Scott: you know multiplayer gaming wasn't huge and accessible to most people until like way way later way later back to fortnight.
Rym: when this update happened, and he made the game more skill based a Thriving competitive community emerged instantly like the competitive set Double down on fortnight and loved this update because I think serious the fortnight is maybe the first like mega game that is Competitive online multiplayer.
Scott: yeah, right, it's like.
Scott: before that you had minecraft which was just playing.
Scott: yeah, right There's no competitive minecraft.
Scott: and before that all the games that were online multiplayer even the mobas They were niche core.
Rym: even League of Legends is small compared to fortnight Yep, lower like even in the old days when like get like one like quake to quake.
Rym: one deathmatch was a huge game.
Rym: That is among gamers among this tiny subset of human beings who had a computer and a video card Almost nobody right yep.
Rym: So the vast majority of players hated this update because now anytime late fortnight people would kill them.
Scott: Yeah, they like right away They couldn't play because they were being murdered and someone else was trying to win.
Scott: there was an incompatible play group Right.
Scott: so fortnight made a new update Stats that people were like they were losing engagement or whatever ever they measure it and they decided well We got to remove this patch.
Scott: It's no good for us making money.
Rym: So they reverted it.
Rym: a2o Undid this competitive change, and they pretty much said they will never bring back these changes.
Scott: right.
Scott: but meanwhile at a fortnight eSports event The top fortnight players when interviewed at the end after winning or whatever were like yeah, I'm gonna give up fortnight.
Scott: This is bullshit.
Scott: It's not a really an eSport anymore this.
Scott: and then they're like okay the interview guy was like alright I'm just gonna go past you and ask the next guy.
Scott: the next I was like yeah I'm also gonna say probably not playing this game anymore.
Scott: It's not really competitive.
Scott: So even though they're making tons of money playing it, and it's the biggest game on earth.
Scott: They were just like nope I'm done.
Rym: I'm gonna read this quote because it actually sums everything up about the update.
Rym: Everybody enjoyed receiving health and shields for eliminations after we introduced the changes to the core modes.
Rym: But there was an unexpected consequence players at large grew more frustrated with fortnight play feeling they had less chance Due to encounters with high skill players with full health and shields.
Rym: ultimately Siphon increased engagement for the highest skilled 10% while the remaining 90% of players were more frustrated and Played less yep, so that's because fortnight is so big.
Rym: I would say this is the stat 10% of players of any game try to win and the remaining 90%.
Scott: The sample size is enormous right.
Scott: so that's the best we've got the remaining the best stats.
Scott: We've ever had on this issue.
Rym: I actually I thought it was gonna be more 80/20.
Rym: I'm actually really surprised Less.
Scott: I thought it'd be like 50 95.
Rym: so here's the fascinating five 95 that 90%.
Rym: What we don't know.
Rym: there are I think two communities in the 90%.
Rym: I think group a people who just want to play and they don't want some high skill jackass killing them mm-hmm.
Rym: The other half are people who want to play competitively, but suck mm-hmm, and they don't realize they suck Mmm.
Rym: Those are you know basically those are the people the scrubs who complain the most Because those are the people who think they're platinum and overwatch.
Rym: They're actually silver.
Rym: They won't admit it if you get rid of that top 10% of players.
Rym: those scrubs feel like they're good because Half the people they're playing with aren't even trying to win right.
Rym: well I mean there's an old Good enough to frustrate the people who aren't trying to win right.
Scott: the old story about this comes from the magic world right where?
Scott: Talk about what.
Scott: is it Johnny Timmy and Spike or whatever?
Scott: yeah something like that.
Scott: And I you know the model that they use.
Scott: those three models of kinds of players I don't think are exactly right.
Scott: no the general the first like series attempt to categorize the general idea though I think is is close to the mark.
Scott: right.
Scott: yeah, is that you?
Scott: they have their idea?
Scott: I'm not remembering it exactly right.
Scott: I think spike was the kind of player who just wants to win.
Scott: They don't care how they win.
Scott: They don't care.
Scott: What kind of evil bullshit.
Scott: They got to do.
Scott: That's me.
Scott: They'll play channel fireball.
Scott: They don't give a fuck dude when overwatch first easiest nastiest way to win They're gonna do it.
Rym: when overwatch first introduced deathmatch I chose Bridget because she had this stun ability and you know what is bullshit.
Rym: So in a one-on-one fight like where there's no one else around It's just me and someone else I could 100% of the time kill another person.
Rym: okay, so I just I only played Bridget.
Scott: Now they say they nerf that and then I forget which Johnny or Timmy or whatever.
Scott: Johnny I don't know, but there was one where it's like.
Scott: They just want to play big stuff like they just want to summon the classes of sardia.
Rym: It's a fucking 1212 bitches And then the force of nature 8/8.
Scott: eat it a trample and the other kind of player.
Scott: the third one Was the kind where it's like.
Scott: I just want to do this really clever fancy magic woo combo Right.
Rym: it's like a cycle through my entire magic deck in one turn because I got this really clever thing.
Scott: I just want to do it right.
Scott: and The fundamental problem is that no matter what game you are making no matter what the rules of this game are These players are incompatible.
Scott: even though they're playing the same game Them being in the same community and playing against each other is simply just gonna create conflict.
Scott: It is not those people shouldn't even be.
Scott: it's like yeah, okay, you both play magic But actually you have the guy playing spike.
Scott: Magic.
Scott: where he just tries to win has more in common with Rym playing Bridget and overwatch.
Scott: Then he has with the other person playing magic to just summon the biggest creature.
Rym: Oh, yeah, it looks like Rudicron our good friend actually posted a link that I will bring up the Bartle taxonomy of player types.
Scott: I guess that's what it was killers achievers socializers and explorers.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: I've seen this chart before.
Scott: yeah I don't agree necessarily with those four you know Categories.
Scott: well the general idea is is correct.
Rym: well They're on an axis of do you want to act versus interact?
Scott: and there's also obviously people who are mixes of all the the few.
Scott: But I also like doing stuff, but here's the stat that matters.
Rym: Here's the focus of what we're gonna talk about in this panel.
Rym: I Think this 90/10 number is going to be the most important discussion in the next few years of multiplayer gaming.
Scott: I mean I've been having the discussion, but no one else seems to want to have it.
Scott: Yeah, but I'm having it with myself.
Rym: I think there is literally no way to make a game that caters to a competitive community and The remaining 90% of gamers?
Scott: no I think you got to go for one of the other and abandon the other.
Rym: I think overwatch needs to abandon the casual players.
Rym: I think fortnight needs to abandon competitive play.
Scott: yeah a lot of these companies that are They're making games.
Scott: They're trying to be everything to everyone and you.
Scott: they all like.
Scott: hearthstone Basically just made all the eSports people.
Scott: they've always been angry all the time.
Scott: They've always said something to complain about all the time.
Scott: They keep staying for some reason or another right for but some of them don't.
Scott: a lot of them keep quitting and falling off.
Scott: But you know they hearthstone people have always gone towards the 90 and not the 10.
Rym: But I think short of only playing games with individual people who together all agree to play a certain way.
Rym: This is an intractable problem and no game can solve it.
Scott: I think it is mathematically basically impossible to make a game that just makes everyone happy.
Rym: I mean look at look at old Starcraft or Command and Conquer.
Rym: when I used to play command and conquer online with a fucking modem There were two kinds of people the people who played seriously to win and the people who made you agree in advance 10 minutes No rush
Scott: yep, because
Rym: they wanted to build a base first there is literally.
Scott: no I always wanted to make a game for those people which was also me cuz I. yeah It's funny that in RTS is I'm that guy because I'm bad.
Scott: at RTS because I'm bad I'm not any good, so it's like well I can't compete, but it's still fun to build a base.
Scott: yep, right Which is sort of why the games are fun even for the people who are really good.
Scott: because yeah They're really good, and they build the base in the winning way, but building the base is still fun to do in the winning way.
Scott: Yep, I'm just not good enough to do in the winning way But I still want to be able to have that fun of building the base.
Scott: So I want to play against someone who isn't gonna just destroy me in five seconds.
Rym: So let's I'm gonna zoom into an overwatch example to really show how impossible this is.
Rym: so in overwatch There's a character Torbjorn or Torb the dwarf guy and one of his main thing is he can make it like her.
Scott: is he from Warcraft or something?
Rym: no.
Rym: He's just a dude.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: He's just he's a dwarf.
Scott: I thought all the overwatch characters are from other Blizzard shit.
Scott: No they're from overwatch.
Scott: I thought they were like from other blizzards.
Rym: No they got their own universe.
Rym: They got their own overwatch universe with nonsense in it.
Rym: No.
Scott: I thought it was like a warcraft character fights a Starcraft character.
Rym: No, it's not bad.
Rym: Oh, you should really play overwatch.
Rym: You would love the hell out or just not you would really when it's free to play you should play it.
Scott: Yeah, anyway auto chess.
Rym: so here's yeah, I'm I'm starting to fade on auto chess.
Scott: Oh, they made a good patch though And he did.
Rym: that patch is night and day night and day.
Rym: good guy anyway.
Rym: So in Fortnite in Fortnite in Overwatch this character's thing is they make a turret.
Rym: You know like in all those FPS's you put a turret down like near the flag room.
Rym: All these complicated FPS's have the concept of a turret.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: It shoots on its own.
Rym: so The way the game is if you make the turret really strong It matters more than the player who's playing the character right.
Scott: well if you think about it, right?
Scott: So let's say if you're playing an FPS And you're good at aiming right any sort of Automatic turret that you just put somewhere if it's better than the best players.
Rym: it will kill everyone and no one can stop it.
Scott: It has aimbot power where it just automatically shoots at anyone and kills them.
Scott: then it's too good.
Scott: Everyone will just use that and there's no point in shooting the gun you're holding.
Scott: but if you make it less good than the top 10% of players and the top 10% of players have no use for it because The gun they're holding and their awesome aim skills are better than this worthless turret.
Rym: But that turret is an undefeatable god to the rest of the player base.
Scott: right if you're bad at aiming and everyone playing the game Is bad at aiming but you just switch to turret guy.
Scott: if that turret aims better than you do and better than all the other Players do that turret is now the best player on the map and it requires no aiming skill to deploy the turret.
Scott: You just push a fucking button
Rym: so you can make that turret anywhere between Better than 0% of players at aiming and better than 100% of players at game at aiming and there is no place you can Put it where it will be where everyone below that line will always use it and
Scott: Never
Rym: use
Scott: it.
Scott: a mechanic itself is unbalanceable.
Scott: Unless you you.
Scott: the only way to do it would be to automatically Scale the skill of the turret to be in alignment with the skill of the player that deployed it.
Rym: So it gets more complicated, which is impossible.
Rym: No one's even tried that Overwatch is on both PC and on Consoles.
Rym: yes, so they did pick about because there are other factors.
Rym: the character can do other things than just make the turn.
Scott: obviously Otherwise be really hella boring to be that character.
Rym: Yeah, so Torb's actually really fun to play behind the turret.
Rym: wait yeah, so Torb's really fun to play and is in like the general meta of the game and Pretty much in the PC game does work Except it is like to power like if you play with silvers.
Rym: Torb is an undefeatable fucking god.
Rym: Like cuz I'm good at aiming so I can shoot with Torb with really good aim while simultaneously Using the turret.
Scott: that itself is better than like having an extra player on your team Who's better than most of the other team, but you're also better than most of the other team.
Scott: Yeah, so that's really strong, but console players Cannot we?
Rym: if you have a controller you can not fight that turret right.
Scott: most console FPS is right.
Scott: Don't lots of games these days allow console players to play against PC players like rocket league or whatever.
Scott: right cuz it doesn't really matter.
Scott: You're using a gamepad to play rocket league in your PC anyway alright, but for FPS is whether they want to keep fighting this fight or not.
Scott: PC keyboard and mouse is vastly superior to gamepad.
Scott: for FPS control it is undebatable.
Scott: every console FPS implements lots of Significant but invisible to normal people changes that make the game playable with a gamepad Because aiming with a gamepad is less precise and less good than aiming with a mouse.
Rym: While they even the characters play the same no matter what skill you are.
Rym: if you're ranked like Platinum or you're ranked wood tier the characters all work the same way.
Rym: It's the same game at every level Except on the console.
Rym: they had to make the turret way shittier because no console gamer could deal with that turret.
Scott: otherwise Yeah, they all stop.
Scott: There's also lots of auto aim like not not perfect auto aim But like aim help right like sort of light snapping.
Scott: and there have been lots of things I've read about that.
Scott: different FPS games have done on the console to make the games Playable.
Scott: and if you were to say if you were somehow able to play like the console version with your mouse and keyboard you would Be a god because it's helping you so much.
Rym: Let's back away say Oh epic brought back these changes that made the game more competitive But they did edit.
Rym: a ranking system like overwatch does some sort of matchmaking system.
Rym: You only get matched with people who are around your same skill level.
Rym: that still doesn't solve the problem Because the matchmaking system has to converge and players will more likely than not encounter good players At various points.
Rym: any game that has even one good player in it will devolve into that good player fucking murdering everybody.
Rym: That happens in overwatch.
Rym: that happens in every game.
Scott: one person who's?
Scott: imagine you're playing a board game.
Scott: if you're playing seven wonders Right with yup, seven people sitting around a table.
Scott: if everyone else is like la la la and one person is trying to win They will ruin everyone's fun.
Rym: Yep They will win and you can.
Rym: there is no way to detect that a player is good at the game or not Except with a very powerful matchmaking system, which can be circumvented by a player making a new account.
Scott: It's not even just that the player wins.
Scott: It's that the way most games are constructed.
Scott: It's that when someone else is playing well, right?
Scott: Even if you don't care about winning you just want to play and have fun, right?
Scott: It's just playing like let's say I want to play fortnight.
Scott: I just want to build a cool base because that's the thing you can do, right?
Scott: Yep Actually I want to explore the map and build a cool base.
Scott: I don't care if someone kills me, right?
Scott: Well, the way the game is made someone kills me.
Scott: I can't explore anymore and I can't build my cool base.
Scott: they just destroyed my cool base and I lost all my stuff.
Scott: and it's like It's like it prevents me from playing.
Scott: your play is ended or cut short.
Scott: They're like netrunner decks magic decks right where it's like.
Scott: hey, that's a deck that wins games.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: It does.
Scott: It makes you discard your entire deck and there's nothing you can do about it.
Scott: It prevents you from.
Scott: It's like I don't care if I lose this game of netrunner.
Scott: I just want to play my cards and then lose.
Scott: It's like nope Their deck is so good.
Scott: you lose before you can play your cards and none of the cards you can play.
Scott: Not only will they not help you win, which I can accept They won't actually do any.
Scott: every single card in your deck is now ineffective and useless.
Scott: It's like there's no point in playing any of them.
Scott: They do nothing.
Scott: You're just shut down right and magic like try play.
Rym: Here's an example.
Rym: try playing Carcassonne with me or Scott or our friend Anthony.
Scott: in the earliest days of magic.
Scott: in the early 90s There was a card called stasis.
Scott: Yeah, stasis.
Rym: Oh boy.
Scott: There were stasis decks.
Rym: I played blue decks.
Rym: Do you know why?
Rym: because fuck you bring up?
Scott: Let's read the text of stasis.
Scott: God, right?
Scott: It was like you can only untap if you like.
Scott: You basically can't untap anything, right?
Scott: I forget the exact text.
Rym: each player skips his or her untapped face.
Scott: You don't get to normally in magic, right?
Scott: If you don't know the game of Magic the Gathering for any I'm sure most people do.
Scott: when you use a card That's on the table.
Scott: You have to tap it that card now once it's tapped You can't do anything with it until it's untapped.
Scott: But at the start of your turn you get to untap pretty much everything for free and then you can use everything again Right.
Scott: So basically use all your stuff once per turn or you save it on your turn.
Scott: Don't tap it and use it during your opponent's turn right and then at the start of your turn everything resets If someone plays.
Rym: I'm looking at all the different versions of this card because I love the art on it.
Rym: Yeah, that's really good.
Rym: But at the beginning of your upkeep sacrifice stasis.
Rym: unless you play pay blue mana.
Rym: Then they updated to during your upkeep pay blue mana or bear.
Rym: they keep changing the second sentence.
Scott: the point is if you play stasis, it just stays there and Nobody untaps Anything like no and no one can use their cards anymore because they don't get to untap them for free at the start of their Turn.
Scott: so the game just locks and you just have to.
Scott: as long as you can keep paying that blue mana to stasis It's not cumulative.
Scott: update right.
Scott: as long as you can keep paying that one from somewhere and of course you have a somewhere because you built your deck around This card to lock your opponent in.
Scott: Yep, then you're.
Scott: they can't untap anything and you play.
Scott: of course when you play a stasis deck you play lots of cards that don't require tapping like creatures that can attack without tapping and spells from your hand that just do a shit ton of damage and sources of mana that don't really need to be tapped or other cards that let you untap things outside the untap phase and Now your opponent no matter what the hell their deck is.
Scott: It doesn't fucking matter, right?
Scott: They cannot do anything because it almost certainly unless they're playing a stasis deck also.
Scott: Yep, all their cards are they.
Scott: you play them they tap them now they're locked and they can't untap them no matter what.
Scott: There's no card in their deck that will help them.
Scott: They might as well just quit immediately.
Scott: They can't even play and have fun.
Scott: It's not even that they will lose.
Scott: they cannot play and have fun.
Rym: So to get back to the matchmaking a matchmaking system only works if all players try hard to win so that their skill can be appropriately determined.
Rym: if Even one person is trying hard to win it ruins the fun for 90% of players.
Scott: one person is playing a stasis deck.
Scott: it ruins the fun for every opponent.
Rym: and even worse if you have a Matchmaking system and there's any sort of ranking the scrubs who are at least half of that community that 90% They will be mad that their rank is too low.
Rym: if you show them the ring Yep And if you hide it from them They will say that the ranking system is bullshit because it's putting them with the wrong players because they keep losing Because they're scrubs and they suck.
Scott: So it's also the problem that at least with online play as opposed to say real-world play like in real-world play for ranking systems Let's say the tennis ranking system.
Scott: There is a world tennis ranking system, right?
Scott: The number one players are people like, you know, Roger Federer Serena Williams, right or whoever.
Scott: I don't know who's number one now.
Scott: Yeah, you can look it up.
Scott: if you go to your local tennis club, right and you start playing real tennis You get put on the same exact fucking ranking chart as those people you can just like.
Scott: they'll be like.
Scott: Yeah, you're ranked like a million, right?
Scott: Whatever it is You're on the same chart and the professionals are at the top of the chart.
Scott: and if you keep playing tennis in your local tennis places and maybe bigger places and someone You could like go to like the US Open US Open is open, right?
Scott: You're high enough rank like you can go.
Scott: you can play.
Rym: as opposed to an invitational right.
Scott: if you win It's like you'll go way up in rank.
Scott: It's like a real thing, but there's no way for you to fake it.
Scott: They know who the hell you are.
Scott: you're right there.
Rym: if Tiger Woods shows up at like my like the high school tournaments They'll be like you're Tiger Woods.
Scott: You're the best golfer.
Scott: We know who you are and this is easily solved.
Rym: you're playing among friends Like if our group of friends is like, oh, we want to play a light game like we might all agree like, okay Let's just play this game for fun.
Rym: or a Rym and Scott are not allowed to play in this game right now.
Scott: They recognize their Rym and Scott are coming to the table.
Scott: If you're playing an esport in the eSports League.
Scott: They know who you are.
Scott: Oh, it's overwatch League.
Scott: I see you sitting right there in this LAN party.
Rym: That's why if a professional player gets caught smurfing they get in trouble because that's free for free online play.
Scott: Smurfing is a serious problem if you're good But now your matchmaking is putting you against people who are also good and you're not winning so much.
Scott: But you care about rank and you care about winning because you're the kind of player who cares about winning.
Scott: That's why you you're carrying right?
Scott: It's why you're up there in the high ranks.
Scott: So you just make a new account even if it costs you money.
Scott: It's rank zero and now you're playing as people who suck and you're winning because now it's more fun for you to play and beat Up and bully around people who are way less good than you because at least you win because you care about winning Right, and then when you get to high rank again You make a new crappy account because you can't compete against people really.
Rym: But even if you're not smurfing if there's a matchmaking system your honor bound to try your hardest to win And that ruins the game.
Rym: You'll stop.
Rym: so I think there's an even worse implication of this.
Rym: if the split is 90/10 then The only money you can make by selling your game Really is to cater to the 90% and make sure that 10% of competitive players won't play your game.
Scott: Or you need to make the game Completely segregate them in all ways To like just split your player base 90/10 and make sure those 10 never interact with those 90.
Rym: Yep, which is difficult for a lot of reasons, but I don't think it's difficult.
Scott: I think people just aren't willing to implement Scott solutions.
Rym: Well, what Scott's a little bit overwatch.
Rym: It's just it.
Rym: you log into overwatch and say I want to play.
Scott: No, I have a solution.
Scott: All right solution is if you want to play to win.
Scott: Right, there is no ranking on just but you click I want to play.
Scott: none.
Scott: None whatsoever.
Scott: There's no rank There's no matchmaking.
Scott: There's no nothing.
Rym: Okay, every game is just play around whatever but in that situation I would still try to win every game.
Rym: I joined.
Scott: Well, here's my solution.
Scott: the competitive play Will be much like competitive play in the real world Actual fucking tournament.
Scott: you open up overwatch and it's like alright, here's an overwatch tournament.
Scott: It costs $5.
Scott: Join it.
Rym: that doesn't sound fun though, cuz I want to just play overwatch.
Rym: I want to sit down after the show and just jump into a game overwatch.
Scott: If you win you get the $5 from everyone else who joined that turn.
Rym: I don't want to deal with a tournament.
Rym: I just want to join a game of overwatch where I can try to win.
Rym: That's all I want to do.
Rym: Well That's what I want to do in board games.
Scott: I want to play.
Scott: when I play netrunner It's like when you go to the local netrunner, you know meet up every week.
Scott: You just play a netrunner, but then you go to the netrunner tournament and you try to win.
Scott: It's a different setting at the tournament.
Scott: Some of the players at the tournament might not be the kind you try to win and end up losing.
Scott: They understand that in the tournament setting.
Scott: this is for serious Like here's when I was in middle school.
Scott: This is not just playing around.
Rym: When I was in middle school playing magic I always tried to win no matter what the context was.
Rym: I'd swap decks and change stuff, but I always wanted to play to win.
Rym: But I didn't want to travel to tournaments all the time.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So every game I played I just tried to win and I won a lot.
Scott: my other idea Which is similar is to have a mode that's like serious mode.
Rym: That's what Overwatch does you can?
Rym: you can say quickplay?
Scott: No, no, no.
Scott: serious mode has to be right.
Scott: you play can you know, you click competitive mode?
Scott: But that's not.
Scott: I'm talking serious mode.
Scott: Like you put huge gates around it to make sure that anyone can you use pay money to get in?
Rym: What to each game?
Scott: May each game or just to get in Huge fines for misbehaving in there or not trying to win.
Rym: So Scott, you know what happened then or surfing?
Rym: all the people are pretty good But not good enough to be like pro enough to do that.
Rym: They would just play in the fun mode, but also try to win in the fun mode.
Scott: Yeah, but they're not good enough to make the people who suck upset.
Rym: Yes, they are.
Rym: There's the problem.
Rym: It's not a matter of them being that good if anyone in overwatch or in like fortnight even if even if that 10% of high school players quit if Anyone tries hard to win even if they're not that good They will harm the fun of the other players.
Rym: and the final aspect of this can't ban people trying hard.
Rym: All you can do is reduce the impact of skill on the outcome of the game Which is what overwatch what I keep saying over on that's what fortnight did they got rid of that 10%?
Rym: Not by doing anything prescriptive like you're talking about.
Rym: They just removed the thing that made the game skill based.
Scott: and here is the final aspect of these of these ideas, right?
Rym: Because I think there's a. I have a final.
Scott: you have an even more final aspect.
Scott: Yes.
Scott: This is the final aspect I have to offer final final AAA final dot P. Anyway, this is the final idea Scott had.
Rym: Okay, if you look at magic the gathering, I think we can turn this to a panel.
Rym: We had a lot more to say.
Scott: magic the gathering has many game modes Right.
Scott: Yeah, the solution that they've come up with is different modes.
Rym: Scott overwatch did this.
Rym: They they have the arcade and they have competitive mode.
Scott: You got that like this four-headed ogre, whatever the fuck it is giant Magic the star planeswalker bullshit.
Scott: they got standard.
Scott: they got legacy They'd always monitor and all these fucking modes right now.
Scott: Some of those modes are competitive mode.
Scott: They got the cheapo mode.
Scott: You don't pay a lot of money.
Scott: They got so many variable ways to play the same game.
Scott: Yep, right.
Scott: So if you take my previous ideas of tournaments pay separated pro mode, right?
Scott: What I would do is I would make the game that is not competitive and unranked would not even be a competitive game.
Scott: It would be like minecraft.
Scott: It would literally be like if you play fortnight in the non pro mode.
Scott: There is no killing people Scott really just playing around Overwatch does this.
Rym: so they have the quick play the competitive which is like the normal game mode.
Rym: just like serious They're like.
Scott: there isn't even winning and losing.
Rym: Aha.
Rym: So then there is the arcade and we're like in the arcade.
Rym: one of the standard things in the arcade is mr Heroes.
Rym: what it is is who what character you are is random.
Rym: You can't pick and every time you die Random character again, but is there winning?
Rym: there is but you everyone tries hard to win because it's fun to try hard to win In that context, but no one takes it that seriously because it's fucking random characters.
Rym: You might get four mercies.
Rym: the fuck you gonna do You're just gonna lose and everyone has a good time because no one takes it that seriously.
Rym: But trying to win does not harm the fun of the other players Even if they're not trying to win.
Rym: mmm that would that like.
Rym: that's a decent way to go Like.
Rym: I think there is some area to explore it.
Scott: So I mean part of the mode of the not winning is also handicapping, right?
Scott: It's like if you're so good, we're not gonna do matchmaking to keep right.
Scott: We're just gonna make your aim is gonna be all over the fucking place.
Scott: Yeah, so good, right, but you know if you're saying, you know to use the overwatch example Why not have it?
Scott: Oh, if you're not playing overwatch matchmaking, there's no ranking.
Scott: There's no winning.
Scott: There's no losing.
Scott: You just run around and shoot people.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: No one wants to play it.
Rym: They want the structure of the game Even fortnight, they want to just run around and have fun, but they also want someone to get the chicken dinner.
Rym: Mmm, they still want there to be a win.
Rym: They just don't care that much if they win Here.
Rym: my final thought is much more on the game industry.
Scott: if this is the 90/10 split But it like if I'm if you fortnight, right?
Scott: You can have a fortnight where if you're playing you open up fortnight and click play you play fortnight.
Scott: If you click play competitive then it's the kind where when people die then stuff spawns out of them.
Rym: Right that patches on or off but then it's just two different games.
Scott: Yes, exactly.
Rym: But there's the problem.
Rym: Those are two fundamentally different games.
Rym: Yes The problem with that is that but it takes a lot.
Scott: let it's not to make those two different games takes a lot less Resource, here's the problem.
Rym: Here's the problem with that.
Rym: I'll get to my final point.
Rym: You I. if you make a game that caters to the high-skill 10% You only make money from a professional eSports system, yep, if you make a game that Prevents the 10% from wanting to play your game Then you make money from selling the game to the remaining 90% of people.
Rym: If you make a game that's aimed at the 10% the skill based people and you want to have a version of that game for The 90% that won't work because if fortnight if there's competitive fortnight and the rest of fortnight The competitive fortnight will not have a serious audience because the audience wants to see the same game They play.
Rym: the four people don't watch overwatch.
Scott: They're not gonna watch Fortnight, I've heard this argument before and I don't buy it.
Rym: I don't think we will.
Scott: here's.
Scott: I've heard this argument because the people right I've heard it from soccer people who say look Soccer is so great when you play soccer as little kids.
Scott: You're playing the exact same soccer that adults are playing.
Scott: That's why we can't add instant replay.
Scott: That's why we can't do all the stuff I would say all those changes.
Scott: Meanwhile, meanwhile kids right who play basketball have lower nets smaller courts kids playing Little League have t-ball Right softball.
Scott: people are playing lots of games that are pale imitations of the real game But they have not lost any interest for the real competitive game that they will never ever ever play in their whole lives.
Rym: I'm however, I would argue that the patch for fortnight is more Structurally fundamentally changing to the meta of fortnight how it looks how it acts how it plays.
Rym: then every change We've wanted from soccer combined would be to soccer.
Scott: I'm just saying little kids playing ice hockey where they can't hit each other and they're using half the ice have not lost any Interest in real fucking ice hockey.
Scott: Yeah doesn't matter You can play baby fortnight and get plenty of enjoyment watching big boy fortnight.
Rym: I am pretty confident that the people who want to watch fortnight would rather watch the casual mode.
Scott: And I don't as you can watch a streamer do it.
Scott: You don't have to watch the eSports for yes You can watch a streamer play fortnight.
Rym: I'm saying epic would make No worthwhile money even bothering engaging with that high-skill 10%.
Rym: Maybe there is no reason to do it.
Rym: if I were the product manager at epic I would literally just say we will not.
Rym: we don't care about.
Scott: the competitive craft is doing fine without an eSport.
Rym: Yes All right I think we can definitely turn this into a panel because I got more to yell about but I'm hungry and this shows already gone Along so we're just gonna stop right here.
Scott: I want to yell more about non gaming things that have the same problem.
Rym: I think we're gonna make a pax panel out of this.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music.
Rym: cat leave for web design and brand.
Scott: Okay for the logos be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows it's actually recorded at night
Rym: and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Craig Oliver Allen Joyce hiding for nickel just like a dude gags your topish in linkage you Jennifer Hitchcock Chris midkiff my state do dot-com J
Scott: band scoot
Rym: alone Lee Roberto Kingsley Shawn Yeager, man Nicholas Brando, mr Strong stretch in 4 to 1 creations, and I am also known in the Northeast as guys menace my star Sherman von Horrell Rory Rochelle, Montana Superboy sailor Vista Clinton Walton run from New Zealand Ryan parent rope and lender Finn dread lily tenebrae Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas on.
Rym: And now I leave you with something from a long time ago.