Rym: It's Monday September 16th 2019.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: smart watches.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So I don't know who deleted the smartwatch episode.
Scott: Rym deleted the smartwatch episode.
Rym: I was 100% sure we had done a show on smartwatches me, too.
Scott: Yeah, I'm also still 100% sure that you deleted it.
Rym: best I can find is we've done shows on like Google Glass Specifically it doesn't count and we've sort of talked about wearable tech But we've never talked about like smartwatches Which is kind of good because only recently as five smartwatches sort of really matured into an offering anyway.
Scott: So it's been a long time since we did a GeekNights episode because of too much stuff going on.
Scott: there was mostly Pax West Pax West and then My office moved to a new office and
Rym: then yeah, you're also in apartments
Scott: And then I'm also moving apartments and Rym went to Europe,
Rym: yep I was in London for three days and then Frankfurt for two days, and I have a fucking story about
Scott: how I got home.
Scott: The point is I'm still I'm still moving.
Scott: I'll be done moving like in a week or two.
Scott: But anyway We've built up a shit ton of opening bits and things of the day and all that but we all know what's gonna happen.
Scott: We're gonna pick only one of the opening bits from that like several week-long period.
Scott: Use it today and then all those other opening bits we're gonna completely forget about.
Scott: Wednesday when we do another show we're gonna talk about like some bike or some train thing that happened on.
Rym: So I was biking to work today.
Scott: I saw someone riding a trike and I was like So anyway, so, you know so we each between all those things.
Scott: right I have to talk about the thing that happened yesterday Which is that I went to see Live in person babymetal for the second time.
Scott: Oh, yeah Right, so, you know, I was.
Scott: I wanted to tell people to go.
Scott: Well, I think the person who wanted to go the most is Chase Gordon who is on the other side of the world.
Scott: He's in Singapore.
Scott: He could have seen them in Singapore, but I guess he didn't.
Scott: I don't know Hermit, I know he's a big fan and they're not good.
Scott: They last came in 2016.
Scott: So yeah, you know, I guess soon they're gonna come again in 2022. anyway You know the band had changed a bit.
Scott: right, you know, there's been a lot of things going on with them.
Scott: There was an opening band, which there wasn't last time it was a terminal 5 which is a shitty venue Right.
Scott: So I was sort of like, you know, the opening band was his band called avatar Which was better in person than went on when I checked them out on Spotify.
Scott: They weren't amazing.
Scott: the lead singer You could you could be that guy if you put on that costume and makeup.
Scott: You could be a lot of metal guys, I mean long hair.
Scott: metal guy is something that Rym can easily transform into.
Rym: Yeah, the only problem is I can't play any guitar nor can I sing even like well this person.
Scott: well this person sang But I sang.
Scott: the highlight was if you need a metal clean.
Scott: He played trombone.
Rym: Whoa Moderately, wait, what is the sky?
Scott: No, no, no, it was just.
Scott: it was just like he got metal.
Scott: He was mostly singing 90%.
Scott: It was one point.
Scott: where he comes he goes back it comes out with a trombone and he plays what I must.
Scott: I guess I Can refer to only as a little ditty on it because he wasn't like an amazing trombonist He just played metal.
Rym: band needs someone to play a metal trumpet.
Rym: I could do that.
Rym: I think that's.
Scott: I'm sure that band exists.
Scott: But anyway, so they open and people are just sort of you know Lightly to normally moshing like you do and I'm like man.
Scott: when I saw baby metal in 2016 People lost their fucking goddamn minds Right.
Rym: So you're worried now.
Scott: So now I'm like, I know I paid here not to see the same band again.
Scott: It's only gonna play like, you know It's a really fucking short show and you see them.
Scott: there is you get like an hour and that's it for 60 bucks.
Rym: It's like, you know, it's not like going to see meatloaf.
Scott: No you you there.
Scott: they don't stop and talk.
Scott: They have this defined set.
Scott: they play it non-stop and then it's like boom done over.
Scott: go home Honestly.
Rym: Maybe it's just because I'm in my 30s, but I prefer that kind of concert.
Rym: I don't want meatloaf to come out on stage for an hour to talk about his crap and then do for me.
Scott: No, a little bit would be okay time.
Scott: You don't even get one encore, right?
Scott: Yeah Yeah, exactly the same thing as every other goddamn city, but I'd be fine if on course disappeared.
Scott: The point is I'm there because for some reason when people go to see this band Even compared to say like if you go to see fucking bit Metallica, yeah, people do not lose their shit the same way.
Scott: Yeah, they seem to lose their shit.
Scott: Stupid baby metal concert, right?
Scott: So I'm like, huh?
Scott: Are people gonna lose their goddamn minds like they did in 2016?
Scott: I don't know what's gonna happen.
Scott: and then three seconds after they come out.
Scott: It's like oh shit Right, I'm old good time.
Rym: Oh God the I'm old feeling comes strong when I go to a good concert.
Rym: So for my opening vid because there's so much happened like I got a lot of stories.
Rym: Do you want to hear about me meeting the Bundesliga?
Rym: say how?
Rym: My foot getting infected to the point that I had to go to the dock.
Scott: I know that your foot get infected when you're poking at it at PAX.
Scott: and yeah I was like what the fuck's wrong with you.
Scott: Stop poking at that.
Rym: Yeah, because it was basically it was getting stupid poking at your foot.
Rym: No, it was all right.
Rym: I went got antibiotics for it.
Rym: cuz it was.
Scott: maybe you shouldn't have poked at.
Scott: he wouldn't had to do that.
Rym: No, I would.
Rym: I was.
Rym: it was.
Rym: that kind of infection happens no matter what you do.
Scott: Uh-huh How come it hasn't happened to me cuz you haven't had a wound.
Scott: Yeah, don't wound.
Scott: I got a wound.
Rym: don't do that and I got a wound that because antibiotics exist I was fine.
Rym: But in an older era that was probably like a 40% chance of death for in the wound to begin with and it wouldn't Actually, maybe not Neosporin not great on wounds, especially foot wounds.
Scott: Yes points good.
Scott: Nah depends.
Rym: Anyway, anyway, so my brief story is I got home from Frankfurt three hours early.
Rym: Okay, because I flew like to London and then to Frankfurt so it was very easy to book that as a right.
Scott: That's the place of an airport.
Rym: Yes, Frankfurt is notable in that it has as a city an international airport in international airport.
Scott: It is Rochester, New York.
Rym: Yes, Frankfurt is much bigger than Rochester, New York.
Scott: I'm sure it is a giant Airport, but I'm aware Frankfurt has this reputation for being kind of because not a lot of other places in Germany have airports.
Rym: Yeah, actually they all do it.
Rym: They all have airports.
Scott: It's just people kind of the kind that you're gonna fly to from America.
Rym: Ah, I've flown direct to Hamburg.
Rym: I've flown direct to Munich.
Rym: I've flown direct to Berlin.
Rym: I've flown direct to Dusseldorf.
Rym: Yeah, you forget about it.
Rym: forget about Dusseldorf.
Rym: Have you been to Dusseldorf?
Scott: No, I haven't been to Europe.
Rym: I've spent actually a weird like a lot of time in Germany over the years, but I like Germany.
Scott: I've been in Europe in the sky But I'm not on the ground.
Rym: every time I ever went to Frankfurt I always came back with two impressions.
Rym: one the city's kind of low-key and feels boring Like just very very pleasant and boring and to Frankfurt's Airport sucks balls.
Rym: Like I'm always delayed.
Rym: security is always a nightmare.
Scott: customs takes forever like Europe had better security.
Scott: That wasn't stupid.
Rym: They do except Frankfurt Especially if you're flying to the two places that are bad about security the United States or London.
Rym: and I was flying to The United States via London.
Scott: how?
Scott: what if you're flying someplace like I don't know China.
Rym: Oh, then you're fine.
Rym: You really only have a problem if you're flying from anywhere to either the UK or the u.s.
Rym: Like when I'm in India, you have to go through security three times.
Scott: all these like the even more evil places on earth.
Scott: They're easy to go to.
Scott: Oh, yeah, you want to fly to like I don't know Eritrea.
Rym: They're like, all right, dude, like fine-tuned from Singapore.
Scott: It's probably no flights there ain't even security into your game.
Scott: I don't think anyone has flights to Eritrea.
Rym: Yeah But like in Mumbai you go there's security to get into the airport.
Rym: then in the airport There's security to get into the terminal.
Rym: then if you're flying to the u.s.
Rym: There's another security run by the TSA.
Rym: Mmm, it's awful.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: But anyway, so Frankfurt, I'll skip all there.
Rym: There's my story, but I got to the airport like three hours before my flight.
Scott: because why so early miss?
Rym: because I extortionist because Extortion victim there ain't no TSA pre check or anything in Frankfurt Extortion victim There ain't none of that.
Rym: They're just the same line for everybody and there's always crazy delays.
Rym: I did not want to have to worry about that.
Rym: Like that's just that Airport.
Rym: So I get there early get through security sitting like just hanging out waiting for the flight.
Rym: That's in like two and a half hours because security actually wasn't a problem for once Mm-hmm, and then I get a notice in some kind of lounge or something.
Rym: I was I was in a lounge hanging out because it's for work, right?
Scott: So they're paying.
Rym: Yeah, they're paying They.
Rym: yeah If I'm flying like all these places work is flying me somewhere.
Scott: I gotta make them pay.
Scott: get the fancy shit.
Rym: Yeah, because it like I flew to Frankfurt in the morning to work that day.
Scott: So fuck if I'm gonna be like on an uncomfortable also if I travel for work, that means I'm spending hours I usually wouldn't be at work.
Scott: technically at work I better be living life of luxury to make up for the fact that I am doing work that like You know past five o'clock or on a Saturday.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Rym: so Basically, I get this message and I'm sitting in the lounge with my boss and I get this message like oh, yeah Your flight to London is delayed.
Rym: Okay delayed to the point that I would miss my connection to New York Okay.
Scott: Well, I mean, I'm sure that you're very wealthy company will just take magically fix it.
Rym: No that I got to deal with that money.
Rym: There's a travel agent.
Rym: I'm not gonna call them.
Rym: So I'm already at the airport.
Rym: So me and my boss we go up to the desk and we're like So we're not gonna make our connection.
Rym: and they look and they're like, oh, yeah So there's no point in sending you to London.
Rym: Let's see if we can help you out because you know They basically there's gonna be a shit show with this delayed flight.
Rym: Anyway, the more people they can deal with by not sending them to London the better Mm-hmm, so they send my boss off to get like some other flight to London that will connect a different flight.
Rym: He'll be fine.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Scott: And then the dude tried couldn't they do the same thing for you?
Rym: So he leaves But he's gonna get home later than he expected.
Rym: He still has to transfer to London Like we were gonna do I could.
Scott: they have two people.
Scott: they couldn't do the same thing for two people.
Rym: No, cuz this is ad-hocs.
Rym: They turned to me.
Scott: They found one seat.
Rym: Yep, and he's my boss.
Rym: He gets precedence.
Rym: They deal with him first then they turn to me and the dude literally looks up and says you are spry.
Rym: No And I'm like, I guess and he's like listen, there's a direct flight So I won't even have to go to London.
Rym: direct flight to JFK.
Rym: get me home like three hours earlier.
Scott: You go in like a cargo plane a direct flight.
Rym: look Fonza like fancy fancy.
Rym: Okay, class upgrade.
Rym: All right, but it takes off in an hour From a different terminal and you're not even checked into this flight.
Rym: So he basically said run To this other terminal.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: I couldn't even wait for the train to take me into that terminal.
Rym: I didn't know time.
Rym: cuz think this is a an international flight to the US that takes off in an hour Mm-hmm.
Scott: How far could it be?
Scott: It's in the same Airport, uh, Frankfurz Airport is a Gigantic, I mean even if I was in JFK and I was at say terminal 2 and I had to get to like terminal 6 I feel like I could make it in an hour.
Rym: Maybe the problem is that internal air train does not actually run that often.
Scott: No But a lot of them have like buses that drive around the airfield run that off and I've been in that boat before and also Even a shitty LaGuardia.
Scott: I had to take a bus on the opposite side of security to get between the several terminals and it just worked immediately.
Rym: So but the other problem is because it's a flight to the US I have to be checked into the flight Signe like a significant time before it's boarding even like ends and before the gate closes and everything.
Rym: Okay, cuz the US is weird about that stuff.
Rym: So I Run at full speed.
Scott: Oh, please stop because you are running.
Rym: Yeah, so no no, so I run at full speed To get on a train to get me part of the way and then I run the rest of the way I get to the Los Fonsa desk and there's a line of people even Waiting for the like.
Rym: first-class like you are the most expedited possible person.
Rym: So I talked to some random like employee and I'm like, so here's my situation.
Rym: He said wow Yeah, if you try to wait for this desk, you're just effed.
Rym: Run to terminal Z and they'll deal with it at the gate.
Rym: Okay terminal Z is The last one.
Scott: so I the last one.
Rym: it said I ran Over a mile wearing a suit with all my luggage all the luggage.
Scott: None of it was checked.
Rym: Yes I ran at full speed.
Rym: I am drenched in sweat.
Rym: I get to terminal said I Do not have a boarding pass.
Scott: final terminal.
Scott: There's nothing beyond that.
Scott: It's just a hole.
Rym: the flight leaves in 25 minutes, that's a lot of time and I have to go through security to get into terminals head.
Rym: Oh, okay There is a line for economy There's a line for business class and I see there's a line of like five people for first class.
Rym: So I talked my way past the person who is mad that I don't have a boarding pass To get into the line and I'm in the first class line and it doesn't move for 20 minutes.
Scott: You have five minutes left.
Rym: Yeah, there's no one to talk to.
Rym: the line is just not moving.
Rym: No one will tell us why it's a giant shit.
Rym: show the lines getting.
Rym: people come up behind me like hey Can I cut in line?
Rym: my flight takes off in an hour and I'm just like son.
Rym: So, uh.
Rym: Then finally I get to the front.
Rym: I go through the security line.
Rym: Like the clock is ticking my first bag comes through.
Rym: my second bag comes through my tiny little laptop bag that has nothing in it But like an Amazon Kindle gets shunted off to extra screening.
Rym: Okay, so they pat me down abandon it.
Rym: They pat me down.
Rym: the dude comes over.
Rym: He goes through my bag.
Rym: He pulls everything out and swabs it.
Rym: You know the check for explosives that I know that thing works.
Rym: So yeah, I'm skeptical.
Rym: then he looks at me and He very obviously like hits a button under the desk a bunch of times.
Rym: Mm-hmm and won't say anything.
Rym: Okay, just standing there like won't say a word just keeps hitting this button.
Rym: And then eventually someone comes over and he tries to say to the guy he assumes they don't speak German.
Rym: I don't really speak German, but I hear something something something buns police say which is like the German Federal Police.
Rym: Something something.
Rym: buns police say something something buns police say, okay.
Rym: And then I hear behind me and I kind of look and out of the corner of my eye two heavily armed like Army-looking people because you're all sweaty.
Scott: They thought you were nervous So that they thought you were maybe a terrorist Because you were sweaty when it was actually from running and not from nervousness.
Rym: so they stand behind me.
Scott: Is that what it was?
Rym: not yet?
Rym: Not quite the sweaty had nothing to do with it.
Scott: You had bombs on your hand behind me out of arm's reach.
Rym: You got your bowling ball candle and then another an officer comes up in the front this woman.
Rym: They're all heavily armed.
Rym: the people behind me are like guns at the ready, but not pointed at me.
Rym: I'm like they're standing there menacing like and I just pull my hands in my pocket and I just stand there like, okay Let's see what's going down.
Rym: and the guy pulls out my Amazon Kindle like this $40 piece-of-shit tablet and he hands it to her.
Scott: Oh, you're reading a contraband book.
Rym: and he says In German and then he says it again in English after she like looks at me and looks at him.
Rym: It tested positive for explosives.
Rym: He said some kind of expose guy and The buns police.
Rym: a person like looks at him looks at me looks at this tiny shitty Amazon Kindle Rolls her eyes and gestures for me to go make my flight.
Rym: So I run at full speed now Like carrying my like barely packed together shit and I hear people in the distance yelling, New York, New York Run run and I run and I run every telling you to run.
Rym: Yes, I get to the gate.
Rym: There is.
Rym: I literally like get on the plane.
Rym: They close the gate behind me.
Rym: How do you start taking off?
Scott: How did you didn't have a boarding pass though?
Rym: They just dealt with it.
Rym: The plane they're like, okay, so who are you?
Rym: After you got in the plane because it was they'd upgraded me to first class So it was basically no.
Scott: How did they know that if you had no boarding pass cuz they were told I was coming?
Rym: Okay, another like 40 people missed this flight because they were all in that line.
Rym: Okay, I was the last person to make it on the flight in the flight.
Rym: Just fucking wait, there's no because there were a ton of people on that flight who would have missed their connections at JFK.
Scott: Uh-huh.
Rym: So I got home three hours early and I was drenched in sweat and I sat down.
Scott: I guess your boss your boss wouldn't have made it.
Rym: Nope, my boss saw he barely made it to his flight and got home like three hours later.
Rym: cuz he had the connection.
Rym: I got the good flight home.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Well, your boss could probably couldn't run.
Scott: Yeah, you are spry.
Scott: No No one's ever asked me if I was spry but a bicycle in there.
Rym: Okay, let's talk some tech news.
Rym: now that we're back, all right, well we during.
Scott: while we were away There was a big Apple deal.
Scott: cuz yeah, if you don't know September is back to school Which is when they used to announce iPods and that was when they announced new iPhones.
Scott: They announced iPhone 11s, which seemed to be the same thing as the previous iPhone with a much improved camera yeah, and colors and No, it's just a better iPhone.
Scott: I mean the camera seems way good because it's got several cameras working in tandem plus software post-processing that's automatic and intelligent.
Scott: So it you can take amazing photos without a lot of photo knowledge and skill.
Rym: Yep The dual camera system and they're branding that slow you get the three camera system.
Scott: Yeah, yeah You know.
Scott: But yeah, why would you buy this iPhone if you if your iPhone is very old?
Rym: Yeah, if your iPhone is very dead or very old or you are buying your first iPhone and you don't want to wait.
Scott: I guess that's a good.
Rym: how's the time?
Scott: Well, you know a couple weeks is the time.
Rym: Well, yeah now ish.
Scott: Yeah, don't buy an iPhone.
Scott: I mean all the major things are gonna be in the iOS which you're gonna get.
Scott: even if you have an iPhone 6 You will still get the newest iOS with all its updates.
Scott: I mean iPhone.
Rym: one's not getting that iOS.
Scott: No, I think six is the earliest.
Scott: Yeah, I have iPhone 7 so I'm good.
Rym: Yeah, I saw the.
Rym: apparently I don't know why.
Rym: I'm surprised that this is one of the headlines.
Rym: I'm seeing the new iWatch hasn't always on display.
Scott: That's the biggest feature.
Scott: The newest Apple watch has is it just not have that before even?
Scott: Well, I just moved my arm so you can see my Apple watch is displaying something.
Scott: but here look look at it now Look, it's just dark.
Scott: Yeah, you have mine and my.
Rym: all my Android watches have always had the option of show nothing or Show a lighter like limited version.
Rym: Oh, I mean you could turn.
Scott: you could turn the brightness down But yeah, the the Apple watch you cannot unless you have the newest one Which has I guess superior battery and I guess less more energy efficient display.
Scott: It turns off in order to see.
Scott: to get something to show up on the screen You got to shake your arm or pick your arm up.
Scott: You can't just sort of look out the corner of your eye You'll just see a black screen.
Rym: I'm just saying with Android.
Rym: I've always been able to do that.
Scott: Yeah, well, that's why those watches are crappier.
Scott: Even if I got the newest Apple watch I would turn off the always-on display.
Scott: So I actually experiment.
Rym: because I have a new smartwatch.
Rym: I left.
Rym: I turned.
Rym: I left that on because it's on by default.
Rym: Batteries still last all day.
Scott: You're hurting the main bit.
Scott: Yeah, we'll talk about that later.
Scott: But yeah, there's not really.
Scott: it's like They really did not have a lot of new features going on here.
Scott: I don't even know why this really wasn't even keynote worthy.
Scott: I feel like they just had to do it because they always do it in September to try to sell their phones.
Scott: But it's like, you know, no one's by.
Scott: you know that no one's buying your phones.
Scott: You talked about how no one's buying your phones and then you have a chance to put out new phones and you don't make any major new feature or thing.
Scott: Well, because I makes it so people need like really badly to go in up.
Scott: It's like before.
Scott: it'd be like oh new iPhone.
Scott: Ah shit.
Scott: My car and iPhone is garbage.
Scott: Look how much better the.
Scott: the difference between the iPhone 5 and iPhone 4 is.
Scott: the problem is different.
Rym: There are not like Features that are feasible.
Rym: that would be a massive shift in smartphone technology right now.
Scott: They're also Removing a feature which is amazing.
Rym: what the headphone jack?
Scott: No, that's been removed.
Rym: Headphone jack.
Scott: I don't need to have fun.
Scott: J. Anyway The they added a feature.
Scott: It's really funny because it took them years to develop this feature The ability for touch the touch screens to figure out how hard you're pressing.
Scott: They've had this for years on iPhones, right?
Scott: It took them many years to come up with it.
Scott: And so you it.
Scott: there are certain things where like you press hard and you can get like a context menu, right?
Scott: But You can do the same thing by just pressing for a while.
Scott: Yeah but also my problem with that is that pressing hard you can just press for like a few seconds and then open so context.
Rym: my As a UX professional and very leery of any mass-market like comp like daily use device having pressure Sensitivity honest.
Scott: No, that wasn't the problem.
Scott: The problem is there was no way to tell which things you could press hard on to get different options.
Scott: Oh, so basically no one ever pressed hard No one ever did it ever.
Rym: and then now they're just removing the press hard ability and replacing it with pressing for a long time which is smart because Watching adults like people who are slightly older than us and kids use their smartphones a lot.
Rym: One thing I've noticed is that most people have terrible manual dexterity and you're lucky They're even capable of hitting the icons on there.
Scott: so that you know, I think it's just that Apple loves To Everything.
Scott: All right, they don't want to have displayed contract They don't want to have buttons and they don't want to have clutter.
Scott: So they end up in the UI having like hidden mystery features like to lock your home your screen.
Scott: on your Mac You move your mouse into the corner, right?
Scott: You know as it's like everything's always try to make these invisible controls or you know things like that.
Scott: Oh, it's like, you know Sometimes that becomes elegant because you manage to learn the thing you use it and their interface isn't Cluttered and it works out great and other times it's just fucking hidden and no one knows the buttons.
Scott: They're like a fucking kaizo block in Mario.
Scott: Sometimes you bump into a accident and like whoa and sometimes I just start using that as an anti pattern.
Rym: kaizo block.
Rym: kaizo design.
Rym: It's a kaizo blocks.
Scott: That's what they are.
Scott: But yeah, there's really like.
Scott: they're coming out with the Apple arcade, right?
Scott: Yeah, so it's basically a cheap subscription service where you get a bunch of like.
Scott: it's like a Netflix of video games for iOS and Apple TV Really cheap.
Scott: So I guess that makes it okay because it's cheap.
Rym: but going into beta Yeah, and it's not even listed as one of the top five announcements No, but it's like.
Scott: I guess if you're the kind of person who like isn't like, you know hardcore in the games You're like maybe uh, you know someone who's a candy crush kind of person But you want variety and you're candy crushing instead of just playing any crush over and over again.
Scott: Or maybe you got some kids and they're not you know, like Console or PC gaming kids.
Scott: They're just tablet gaming kids, right, you know, they Maybe it's good for them.
Scott: I don't know who this is for but at least it's cheap.
Scott: so I think the cheapness actually gets people in the door, but it's like.
Scott: Even gaming sites hardly cover iOS.
Rym: Yes.
Scott: It's like, you know and every time Apple has a keynote It feels like every single time they always show a game.
Scott: ever since way back when they showed, you know You know, was it Doom 3?
Scott: Yeah, John Carmichael's in the stage and they were showing Nvidia.
Scott: and it's like they keep showing games at Apple keynotes.
Scott: And then after that keynote, no one ever fucking talks about the games on Apple devices.
Scott: ever fucking again.
Scott: You never hear about that game ever.
Scott: Yeah, right Like I feel like there was a racing game they talked about at a recent not the current one But like maybe a year or maybe two year ago.
Scott: You haven't heard shit about that racing game.
Scott: I'm sure it's out and you can play it but no one's fucking talking about that.
Scott: What's sad though is that games At WODC this year they talked about a bunch of iOS games.
Scott: No one's talking about those fucking games.
Rym: Games are one of the few things on smartphones that would actually require a lot of the power We're building into these devices to do something cool.
Scott: Well, cuz that's you know They mostly use the game as a way to talk about it.
Scott: the phones guess what.
Scott: they're faster and have longer battery life.
Scott: It's like okay.
Scott: Well, they're already fast enough and have long enough battery life.
Scott: Yeah, and unlike a PC where like there are going to be newer applications that require there's more power.
Scott: Not so on my phone, you know, I the phone runs Twitter just fine.
Scott: I don't need a faster phone CPU for a faster Twitter, right?
Scott: And then they're doing their Apple TV plus thing, which is old news.
Rym: Five bucks in a month slightly cheaper.
Scott: I think you know what that way we got to say is if you have if your phone is Busted or you getting an iPhone for the first time.
Scott: Yeah get the new one that's coming out in a few weeks.
Scott: Otherwise the rumor is new iPhone SE Early next year.
Scott: Hopefully the small iPhone.
Scott: Hopefully that that will be the real deal.
Scott: Yep, if that doesn't happen I'm gonna wait all the way until next September.
Scott: the iPhone 12 is supposed to see is gonna hopefully be USB-c because and also a major leap in other areas and You know any improvement they made with the iPhone 11. however minor iPhone 12 is obviously gonna be better in every way.
Scott: That's gonna have at least the same camera and at least the same CPU and it or cameras.
Scott: So like yeah, probably ten cameras.
Scott: who the fuck knows one Gillette model who knows what the hell it is.
Scott: But it'll obviously be better in every way.
Scott: So Hopefully my iPhone 7 can hold out another year.
Scott: But the thing is I think even if I reach those iPhone 12s and they come out and my iPhone 7 is still going strong, right?
Scott: I might be then Even if I don't really like the cut of the iPhone 12 jib be forced to get that the smallest iPhone 12.
Scott: Yeah, because 5g will become a real thing and that will be a significant feature.
Rym: We'll see.
Rym: because the problem with 5g.
Scott: 5g is not a real thing in my iPhone 7 still works.
Rym: Oh, baby My problem with 5g is solely that I don't have any use cases for it other than Potentially a use case that I doubt will work.
Scott: use case is live faster faster treatment.
Rym: I'm already fast.
Rym: I'm as fast as now.
Scott: you can treat even 5g.
Scott: you can see real fast.
Rym: What 5g would let me do would be to like use the phone to live stream like panels we do at conventions.
Scott: I mean you could do yeah You could do all kinds of.
Rym: the problem is 4g is fast enough to do that.
Rym: The problem is that at any convention the 4g cannot work Using old TV UHF band?
Rym: Ah, but the problem is It's powerful 5g still have that amount of bandwidth and for the amount of money Verizon's gonna charge me for it.
Scott: If I get it it better fucking.
Scott: yeah.
Rym: But will it be at a convention when there's an extra 100,000 people?
Scott: So you can do it there.
Rym: Oh, yeah, we could just dream on the Wi-Fi But again, I don't have a use for 5g all that.
Rym: Well, here's my problem.
Rym: Everyone in the industry talking about 5g are really selling these kind of bullshitty use cases that are really Overvaluing what 5g will do.
Rym: Make an app that uses 5g Yeah, but everything everyone's talking about our own.
Rym: we can do more Internet of Things things which bandwidth is not the limitation on Internet of Things.
Scott: No, it is not All right.
Scott: Anyway, that's your Apple news for September 2017. check back I guess.
Scott: WWDC next year early next year for iPhone SE news and we had some other news.
Rym: I think we'll skip it and get into the main bit cuz we talked a while and it's time for Things of the day.
Rym: What do you got?
Scott: So for once I've got the rollercoaster thing of the day.
Scott: Rym's always a rollercoaster person.
Scott: I got one now.
Scott: It's a real short video.
Scott: The video originally had stupid music.
Scott: Thankfully, it seems YouTube copyright has removed that music except for the first two seconds of the video.
Scott: Yep, so you are spared from the the you know pointless music over the top.
Scott: Anyway, all this is a real simple video.
Scott: It's a video of someone riding a rollercoaster.
Scott: So it's not too often people video themselves riding a rollercoaster, right?
Scott: So that's already the odds of this video existing or you're pretty low.
Scott: Most times a rollercoaster runs people don't take and record and save the video, right?
Scott: Especially not video of facing at the people's faces - it seems like this is pretty common.
Scott: Someone riding a rollercoaster stupidly with their phone loses their phone and it goes flying and never to be seen again.
Scott: That happens a lot.
Scott: What are the odds that someone would be riding a rollercoaster with a camera facing them?
Scott: Recording someone in front of them would lose their phone and the person being recorded by the video would catch Phone is amazing.
Scott: Not only it's amazing that the person even caught the phone but the odds of it being captured on video so well are so low.
Scott: it's Definitely doesn't seem fake to me.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: I'm usually the first person to say fake doctored video.
Scott: This really seems real to me.
Scott: It's really great way to spend the next 45.
Rym: Nobody would have believed that if there wasn't video.
Scott: Yeah Considering how much change and how many sunglasses I've been hitting the face with over Nobody because nobody would think to fake this video and if they did it wouldn't look like the way this video looks.
Rym: You know what if someone did think to fake this?
Rym: My head is off to you.
Scott: You know, if you thought to fake it and faked it this.
Scott: well All every hat I have ever owned is off to you.
Scott: Score three goals.
Scott: we can have all the hats.
Rym: So my thing of the day because most of my things I've been kind of rotating through these same five genres lately.
Rym: So I wanted something very different.
Rym: So this is my most favorite recent Twitter account.
Rym: Yeah, I'm a fan of those Twitter accounts that do something very specific.
Rym: Scary toilet, cursed cons, toilets with threatening auras Yeah, cursed rhythm game controllers Yeah, but this one is near and dear to me because it is cropped boomer.
Scott: Have you seen horny fight sticks?
Scott: Yes, okay.
Rym: But So cropped boomer images is very specific.
Rym: it takes those memes that your racist Nazi like distant relative keeps posting on Facebook and The rule is they will take one of those Facebook conservative racist Whatever memes and all they will do is crop it to make it.
Scott: so make no other edits besides cropping.
Rym: Yep, all they're allowed to do is crop one crop not like several crops in a collage one crop one crop only and The results are kind of amazing.
Rym: I'm just gonna just you just gotta go look at these.
Rym: You'll see what I mean.
Rym: And I feel like what I want to start doing.
Rym: is any of you who have a crappy Relative who post this kind of stuff every time they do?
Rym: take one of these tweets and respond to them with it.
Scott: You didn't like my one crop only joke One crop only.
Rym: the shits gonna get out of hand All right in the meta moment.
Rym: You may have noticed we didn't do shows for two weeks.
Rym: So we're back.
Rym: We're gonna be doing shows.
Rym: I assume we'll do a show on Wednesday though.
Rym: Scott hasn't watched Carolyn Tuesday yet.
Scott: No, I haven't.
Rym: it's real good.
Rym: You should watch it.
Rym: Okay, but if you didn't notice we're at PAX West.
Rym: I have posted video of our panel that no one's ever seen before because we redid a lot of it the 40 games You must play.
Rym: click on YouTube along with the slides.
Rym: We didn't upload video of the 40 tabletop games.
Rym: He was played.
Scott: yet because it is You have to worry about now is PAX Unplugged in early December, I believe.
Rym: Oh Wendy.
Rym: All I know is we're going.
Scott: we are going for sure I put in panels.
Rym: We will be there.
Rym: Hell, we're proud.
Scott: December 6th through 8th in shitty ass, Philadelphia.
Rym: Philly is not that bad as bad.
Rym: Philly is one of the bigger cities in America by far It doesn't.
Scott: it doesn't matter.
Scott: if it was the biggest it would still be shitty.
Rym: All right, would you rather live in Philly or Frankfurt?
Scott: Frankfurt?
Rym: You sure I would rather live in Philly or Buffalo.
Rym: I Would rather live in like the desert Philly or anywhere in the state of New Jersey, New Jersey.
Scott: Yeah, really really New Jersey or Philadelphia easily.
Rym: I would rather live in Philly than literally anywhere in New Jersey.
Rym: No, literally anywhere.
Rym: But yeah PAX Unplugged and then right after that is pecs out in San Antonio Which we will also be had.
Scott: you forgot the in-between those.
Scott: the mega fest mag year man, New Year's is on New Year's Day is what Tuesday and Magfest begins Thursday.
Scott: It is going to be the year of the mag.
Rym: You know when I was younger, there was always like school like fall was no New Year's Day is Wednesday.
Scott: New Year's Eve is Tuesday.
Scott: So you New Year's Eve Tuesday.
Scott: You have your New Year's Eve party Wednesday, New Year's Day.
Scott: Then Thursday magfest.
Rym: it used to be that fall was always the time where summer ended and school started.
Rym: But now thanks to a clustering of all the conventions we perform at fall is when convention season starts for Rym and Scott.
Rym: It's like September through March.
Rym: We're doing conventions and then we don't really do many the rest of the year.
Rym: We once again forgot to even submit anything to anime NYC.
Rym: No, I want to go over here and I just forget.
Rym: Also, I haven't written any new anime content in a long.
Scott: Anyway, the book club selection is a book that I started reading a little bit.
Scott: It's long.
Scott: Yeah, it is the tale of Genji.
Scott: I wonder if we could like maybe figure out which volume was the first volume and only read that because it was several volumes over a long time.
Rym: Scott on a bridge ads.
Scott: I know on a bridge I feel like what we gotta get the honor bridge deluxe edition of the tale of Genji by Murasage Shikibu.
Scott: It is the first Novel in human history Period.
Scott: there were other fictional literature before them, but they were not novels.
Scott: They were like epic tales or novel.
Scott: smaller thing.
Scott: There were no novels before this book.
Scott: Arguably, yep, pretty much.
Scott: It's the first.
Rym: now I feel like as we start really reading it will like we'll sort of Occasionally talk about it because it'll be a while before we do a booklet book on it.
Rym: I encourage you to read this along with us starting now ish.
Rym: Yep Otherwise, that's it We're gonna actually be doubling down on content again.
Rym: now that we're back Most of our big life changes and moving and traveling.
Rym: everything are gonna calm down other than conventions in a couple weeks.
Rym: Yep So, uh, stay tuned.
Scott: mostly October and November are gonna be normal.
Scott: But of course November always has a lot of Thanksgiving shit going on and October has the Halloween shit.
Rym: But there will be no like unexpected or unplanned like big hiatuses for a while and then December is gonna be unplugged.
Scott: Holidays mag here packs out.
Scott: Yeah, then a quiet period then PAX East again already.
Rym: Yep The good news is and then fucking summer while we tend to skip a lot of shows during that time of the year We make up for it by having a shit ton of panels to put on YouTube.
Rym: Yeah, and it's usually that's when we're doing all the new stuff that we haven't done before.
Scott: Anyway, let's let's see starting to.
Scott: you know, whatever.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: So smartwatch Campbell it We definitely did a show on this that you deleted.
Rym: Uh, so Scott, I guess we got to back up.
Rym: This is not like a review of the iWatch or anything.
Rym: What is a smartwatch and why should we care?
Scott: Well, I mean a watch is a thing is a relic from an ancient age.
Rym: Yes, that's relegated to history.
Scott: I am NOT a fan of what I mean, I enjoy the crest.
Scott: it is a very nerdy and respectable thing.
Scott: You know to make watches right and the craftsmanship of watches I have high respect for.
Scott: right to just take some fucking gears and a small power source Whether it's you know a mechanical wound-up spring or whatever It is a battery right and somehow create a device that will keep perfect or close to perfect time.
Scott: That is incredibly small and intricate is Worthy of much praise.
Scott: Yeah, but the culture of people who Collect spend as much money on watches as people would spend on cars and do all sorts of other Wear giant fucking gaudy ass watches on their wrist.
Rym: Yeah, right be wearing a giant chronometer Like yeah, what do you use?
Scott: Oh, you know, they have the watch, you know good to a zillion meters diving watch.
Scott: You never go in the water with it ever right or like, you know, you see Odell Beckham jr Who's you know sent to the the Cleveland Browns is wearing like a watch that several hundred thousand dollars while playing football Which is against the rules.
Scott: even you're not allowed to.
Scott: but we ignore hate that watch culture.
Rym: But we're talking about this from a technology standpoint solely and in technology the wristwatch Much like the pocket watch were made entirely obsolete by the smartphone except in very specific circumstances for many years.
Scott: So in my earliest days, I mean I had you know, like time X Y Mickey Mouse watch.
Scott: Yep, learn how to tell time That's a great one.
Rym: I wore watches when I was young because oftentimes there was no way to know what time it was.
Rym: Otherwise, yeah, then as you were in school where there's a clock in every room Yep, then I had time X watch which is that?
Scott: the two buttons on the front Iron Man one?
Scott: Which is a great watch because it had also a little alarm right and I would.
Scott: it has stopwatch Which you would play with when you're a kid, but it wasn't really useful for much.
Rym: The one thing I did I always used a watch with a sweeping secondhand always Even when I was very young not the ticking kind.
Rym: Nope ticking kind sucks.
Scott: I like the digital kind
Rym: sweep Yeah but sweeping kind for a reason because what I did in school all through elementary school all through middle school is I would figure out the Timing and when the bells would actually ring and I would synchronize my watch to that exactly So I would know the exact instant the bell would ring.
Rym: So occasionally I could do funny things like in a random class in middle school Get up and start walking toward the door.
Rym: The teacher just would be about to be like hey worry.
Rym: and then the bell would ring just as I get to the threshold of The room like I do that with a ticking secondhand also Yeah, but the ticking secondhand watches tended to not be as accurate.
Scott: Anyway, anyway, the point is once you had smartphones We're now carrying or even not even smartphones just cell phones Yeah.
Scott: And like Motorola star tech phone and especially ones that had a little tiny display on the outside like my little Samsung or LG Whatever the fuck it was my old flip my little.
Rym: it would last like a week unless I talk.
Scott: I had a little flippy phone had the time on the outside.
Scott: So now I don't need a fucking thing on my wrist anymore, especially since I always lose the wrist watches.
Rym: Anyway, because now basically everyone effectively had a pocket watch.
Rym: Yep, whether they wanted one or not.
Rym: You just had a pocket watch.
Scott: So now what's the point of fucking watches?
Scott: You don't need those.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So basically as soon as I got a cell phone, I took my watch off and I never wore a watch again, right?
Scott: But then what you know, we had this problem that came up later Which we had smartphones and all kinds of notifications coming in And even though I managed my notifications very heavily as much as I manage like my email filters So hardly any notifications happen.
Scott: the ones that do happen are important.
Scott: So when my wife my phone goes ding I take it out of my pocket and look at it and for several years That's what I was doing iPhone 3g 4 5 6 I was taking my phone out of my pocket every time it went ding to see what the hell it was.
Rym: Which is a little bit of a problem, right?
Scott: Even if it's something important It's kind of annoying to read, you know, constantly be taking the phone or
Rym: importantly not in necessarily for us all the time But definitely for a lot of people once you take the phone out to look at that Notification and for security you probably got to unlock the phone before you see the notification.
Rym: Yeah, otherwise people can steal your 2fa codes.
Rym: Yep Now Twitter's right there and maybe it checks something you know poking at your phone.
Scott: Also, you've now turned the screen on on your phone killing its battery.
Rym: Yeah, and until recently smartwap smartphones batteries didn't often last all day if you use them, right?
Scott: So this is so.
Scott: when the pebble watch came out.
Scott: I was like hell.
Scott: yes.
Scott: This is the thing I want.
Rym: It is a watch right but the fact that it's hold time was like Literally the last feature I gave it shit about.
Scott: oh, I had a whole bunch of features.
Scott: You can even get games on there customize the software.
Scott: It was nice to be able to customize the screen stuff But the main feature the only one I cared about was that I would get Notifications on the watch so I could if it went ding I could look at the watch and not have to take my phone out Of my pocket.
Scott: Yep, not taking the phone out of the pocket means saving battery.
Scott: It means saving time.
Scott: It means saving a lot of things worth going back to having a watch on my wrist And that's literally take it out of the pocket to look at the time.
Rym: I don't need to use my watch to like look at a map or watch a movie or any.
Rym: I just wanted it to give me Notifications because if I was going to do anything from there I will get my phone out because now I'm actually gonna use my phone like a little computer.
Rym: The only other thing I cared about was you know, I run a lot and I do a lot of sports.
Rym: I like to be able to use Strava and things to track my runs.
Rym: I use the smartwatch.
Rym: I don't even need a watch that on its own will do GPS partly because they tend to be not that good at it Even the fancy ones compared to a phone for reasons.
Rym: I don't want to get into right now about antennas.
Scott: I'll do it.
Rym: Well, we'll get into that when we talk is even the fancy smartwatches tend to be a little less accurate than also having the phone In your pocket, but I wanted to be able to just hit a button on my watch and then immediately start running Instead of like carrying my like pulling my phone out of my pocket Starting the Strava putting the phone into like that I can't keep in my pocket when I'm running so putting in like an arm strap or something.
Rym: So I wanted to be able to.
Rym: I basically just wanted my wrist to have a screen for Notifications with a couple of buttons to trigger things on my phone.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: That's it.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: The pebble was enough.
Rym: Yep, the pebble still I think is the best smartwatch anyone ever made.
Scott: Well, because it's wisely, right?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: yeah, I really like the OLED screens.
Scott: OLED is the best screen you can get.
Scott: It's really nice on the Apple watch, but I don't need the OLED.
Scott: I want the OLED screen on my phone Every other thing.
Scott: I want an OLED TV.
Scott: I want OLED computer monitors.
Scott: I don't want I don't need the OLED on the watch.
Scott: It doesn't make a big difference there.
Scott: If a smartwatch, I would rather have the LCD crapo screen of the pebble on my wrist.
Rym: So if a smartwatch is designed to be a screen for notifications and maybe a place to have some buttons to trigger things Then what's the user experience?
Rym: You need the battery to last for fucking ever.
Rym: Mm-hmm, and you'd like the screen to always be on.
Rym: Yep, that's something the pebble did.
Rym: but when I watches and Android wear watches and all these sort of real smartwatches came into the Market, let's not talk about pure fitness devices because you know, this is I don't get it's kind of out of scope for this.
Rym: Then if I feel like the entire industry was trying to shoehorn all these other use cases That weren't why actually useful to people I think that's the thing.
Scott: is you even you know, like I was just talking about the new iPhone 11 It's like they.
Scott: I feel like they've never actually known like.
Scott: what things are people actually gonna use.
Scott: We don't know.
Scott: Well, let's make every feature.
Scott: We possibly can make every app We possibly can and just see what people use.
Scott: Yeah, it's like oh shit The thing people use most on their phone is like the camera.
Scott: All right, let's focus on that.
Scott: Yep Yeah, so that's what's happened with watches is they're in that phase where it's like let's make the watch do every possible Conceivable thing that we can imagine and see which ones people actually end up using.
Rym: But the problem with that is that as a result you have all these half-baked Experiences or these things that aren't actually that useful which almost drive people away from smartwatches.
Rym: I've seen so many people get a smartwatch like in the early generations and then decide that it doesn't do like the the the Capabilities they were sold aren't really that useful.
Rym: and then they decide smartwatches aren't useful and they stop wearing.
Scott: I think it's more.
Scott: the attitude I see more often is and my day I had just had a regular old watch to told the time and that was it.
Scott: That was enough, you know the same kind of Luddite attitude You see like a smartphone where it's like I just phone.
Scott: it made phone calls.
Scott: That's all I needed.
Scott: I don't need this.
Scott: Well, you know what?
Scott: It's alright fine.
Scott: Well don't have that then and if you ask me for directions, fuck you.
Scott: It's like with good.
Scott: See what happens asshole.
Scott: Google glass.
Scott: You should be fucking grateful.
Rym: Google glass had a great user experience and did really well at very specific tasks at making you look like a douchebag.
Scott: Almost as bad as vaping.
Rym: we both wore them.
Scott: Yeah Like almost as bad as someone who vaped in a fedora.
Rym: It's funny when I find old panels because we wore those things for like a year and a half.
Scott: Yeah, I would be utility at the same time.
Scott: Yeah And then I wasn't.
Rym: Most of the complaints people had that weren't kind of ridiculous like nonsense.
Rym: privacy concerns around Google glass Because that camera wasn't different mother cameras.
Rym: But I digress.
Rym: the people complaining about the user experience were mostly complaining about Things that Google glass was never intended to do.
Rym: like.
Rym: I watched video on it and it drained the battery.
Rym: Like why the fuck are you watching a video on that tiny ass display?
Rym: Yep, like watching a video on your watch equally stupid.
Rym: Yep so Now we're in an era where fifth-generation like Android watches came out.
Rym: They're finally above the line where they're not just garbage and the iWatch has like.
Rym: it is a good piece of technology.
Scott: It is way better than every every Android watch.
Rym: I think the fossil watch is fun.
Rym: The current fifth-gen Android wear Android watches are really good.
Rym: They're on that level.
Rym: the problem is most watches are running some proprietary non Android wear nonsense or They are running like some bastardized like old version of Android wear and they're underpowered.
Rym: There's a lot of bad watches because I can't get the pebble.
Scott: that just does exactly what I need and nothing else Which is still what I want.
Scott: Yeah Because it died I went and got the Apple watch and I got the third-generation Apple watch.
Scott: They're already on fifth-generation, but I really don't see any difference meaningful between three and five.
Scott: I actually got the LTE one, right?
Scott: So this is this is really like a key feature.
Scott: It cost me ten bucks a fucking month from Verizon.
Rym: I thought about that.
Rym: I cannot come up with a use case for an LTE enabled watch because I never do not have my phone with me ever I.
Scott: but that's the thing is because now right?
Scott: I don't have to have the phone with me, right?
Scott: I Intentionally be like, oh I'm paying for this LTE.
Scott: I don't need my phone.
Scott: leave my phone.
Scott: before I needed the phone I had to have it so I would bring it.
Rym: but now LTE it's like oh, so here's my main Leave the phone behind.
Rym: So alright if I just have my watch am I actually gonna type like Responses or talk to this thing?
Rym: to talk to people if they message me?
Rym: So why not just have my phone?
Scott: so the app first of all the Apple watch has three different ways.
Scott: You can reply people easily and elegantly is the same thing.
Scott: I need to.
Rym: the typing actually works.
Rym: The voice dictation is like perfect.
Rym: It just works.
Scott: I've done it occasionally.
Scott: Yeah, I even make you can.
Scott: also my watch is a phone.
Scott: It has its own phone number.
Scott: I can make phone calls If you were to call my my phones.
Scott: You don't even need to know the number for the watch even though it does have its own number.
Scott: if you just call my phone My watch will ring.
Scott: I can pick up and talk to you.
Scott: The one thing added a walkie-talkie feature.
Scott: if you also had a watch I could talk to you.
Scott: These are like the crazy things.
Scott: They're like, I don't need Ever use those features.
Scott: I've you any all the things I've mentioned.
Scott: I've used at least one time one time.
Rym: When was the last time you did a walkie-talkie call from your watch?
Scott: I've done a regular phone calls though.
Scott: Uh-huh Like, you know, I for example, I just leave my phone behind I go biking around I get a call I stop and I talk.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So one thing I've noticed with the eye watches in particular though My main use case for not having my phone because my phone is tiny.
Rym: I always have my phone and my phone has things like full Google Maps If I like need to figure out directions or so my watch has full Apple Maps.
Rym: Yeah, my watch has full Google Maps.
Rym: now to cash even but I want.
Rym: the only real use case I have for a standalone watch without the phone Is that I'd like to be able to do runs and track Strava GPS without carrying my phone.
Scott: Strava Does that exact?
Scott: I can you know.
Rym: so I've looked at the even modern eye watches and people who have who bike and what the GPS line shows with Smartphone like even Android phone or Apple phone versus just watch even newest I watch the newest I watch is definitely less accurate than the phone.
Scott: I'm accurate Do you need to be?
Rym: uh, because I'm tracking my run times like over time I've looked at using this watch using other.
Scott: why don't use the stopwatch feature?
Rym: Because I'm doing it.
Rym: I want to track my distance.
Rym: I'm running like a half marathon.
Rym: I have found that the watch is Consistently significantly inflate how far you went because the trackings worse and it gets a lot of jitter.
Scott: Well, I've noticed that yes the watch gets jitter, but my phone also gets jitter.
Rym: I don't does not my phone compared to the watch?
Rym: massive difference, you know, it's really perfect.
Scott: at GPS.
Scott: My standalone fancy bike computer basically draws a perfectly straight line.
Rym: Yeah, so fitness device is the way to go with that.
Scott: but any of the point is is that it's like.
Scott: yes The watch can do Strava all on its own.
Scott: with LTE.
Scott: It can upload all on its own doesn't need anything else, but that will kill the battery on any watch.
Scott: Right your basis?
Scott: That's the thing that I want.
Scott: to go back to the pebble because the pebble battery lasts several days But the pebble battery watch the Apple watch battery lasts like a day and a half.
Rym: If you do Strava not a day pebble battery only lasted several days because it it's GPS It wasn't doing any of this stuff was passed through to the phone.
Rym: Yeah I still think the right move for the future of this technology is the phone has a big battery and a lot of horsepower And the watch is a semi powerful standalone device coupled with a link to that thing.
Rym: Yeah, you're carrying both.
Scott: Well, I mean that's the thing I don't understand is like there are times where if I push the Strava button on my watch, right?
Scott: It'll.
Scott: even if my phone is nearby it will still do it on its own.
Scott: I have to if I want my phone to do it.
Scott: I have to push start on the phone.
Scott: It's like the watch should be like hey is the phone nearby?
Scott: No, I guess I'm on my own.
Scott: or hey is the phone nearby?
Scott: Okay phone you take care of it.
Rym: So get this.
Rym: that's one big difference what my what this Android watch does is it just uses both.
Rym: it just whichever one's more accurate at the time Mmm, like automatically if I have my phone in my pocket and I use the watch to trigger it.
Rym: It's just perfect.
Rym: No jitter.
Rym: if I don't have my phone it does the shitty jitter.
Scott: Well, it's it.
Scott: there's no reason that the Apple watch can't do that.
Scott: It's just this.
Scott: people who made the Strava Apple watch app didn't program it that way, right?
Scott: But yeah, it's.
Scott: you know, there's other stuff going on.
Scott: So what else?
Rym: basically the difference between the pebble like minimalist watch and a current like because I have a modern fifth generation Android smartwatch which has all these extra features.
Rym: The only other feature I use is the real-time directions Because they are fantastic.
Scott: I don't use the directions too often, but they're on there.
Rym: I especially walking directions because I tend to be like in London.
Scott: Usually I'll just put the directions in on my phone But then like as I'm walking the watch will announce the direction.
Rym: Ah, I mine does that by default But I can also hit a button and then it'll just show the streaming directions with the arrows and the top-down map on the watch.
Scott: All right, so other features on my watch.
Scott: I actually use right.
Scott: the number one thing actually that I use on there is QR codes to get into things.
Scott: Yep, right At the movie theater beep at the.
Scott: even at the airport beep.
Scott: So I can go to Madison Square Garden to show my wrist beep.
Rym: So Scott, two of the airports I've flown in recently specifically will not let you use your watch.
Rym: You have to use a phone.
Scott: I haven't had that problem.
Rym: Yeah, they won't let you use the watch or the watch though.
Rym: No watch screen will scan.
Rym: specifically I watch screens will never scan at these airports anyway.
Rym: Spotify I can control my music just by looking at the watch One the big one I use actually is I bound because that my watch has two hardware buttons.
Rym: I bound it to the Google Authenticator app.
Rym: Mmm, so I can hit a button and I see all my codes.
Rym: That is killer.
Scott: instead of taking my phone out or getting my yubi key I can pay for stuff with the watch with Apple pay.
Scott: That's pretty good.
Rym: I can do that with Android pay.
Rym: now I like that but I never use that.
Rym: I use it because I just use my credit card everywhere.
Scott: No, I use.
Rym: I use Apple pay a lot which a lot of places I go don't take Apple pay.
Scott: I mean most restaurants I go to don't take it.
Scott: tons of places I go now use.
Scott: I use it a constantly.
Rym: Yeah, most restaurants.
Rym: I've been to do not take it.
Scott: Well, I mean no only restaurants or they bring a thing to you.
Rym: Yeah, so as a result, I have to have my kind of like.
Rym: my watch does not let me go without my credit card So I still have to bring my wallet until I buy the Apple pay.
Rym: or the Android pay would mean I can do Everything I would do I mean without my wallet.
Rym: It's worthless.
Scott: even so it's like yeah I have my rely on it.
Scott: No, but even though I have my wallet with me, right?
Scott: It's faster to just pay with the Apple pay.
Scott: It's true I just use it if I can which is a lot.
Rym: but I found that most places I pay for something Do not take it.
Scott: most places I pay for something.
Rym: most markets I go to my you take as I go to lunch restaurants.
Rym: I go to lunch almost every day every drug store No lunch place.
Rym: I got to take every lunch place.
Rym: I go to take like literally none of them Except like the Pret.
Scott: I don't know where you're going but the places I go almost every place takes it.
Scott: now Grocery store takes it every place.
Rym: I don't think our grocery store takes it.
Scott: our girls several grocery stores Take it and all the ones I go to yeah, my haircut place.
Scott: I think maybe you're not realizing that places take it.
Scott: when they do.
Scott: I think people are like surprised because there's some places that Are like Apple pay here and announcing it.
Scott: There's a lot of places where they're just like a little wireless symbol and you're like, is it gonna work?
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: And so you don't try it.
Scott: Now you don't see the logos.
Scott: you're not sure.
Scott: but guess what?
Scott: Oh, it fucking works if you try to use it.
Rym: It's funny because most of the places when I ask they specifically don't take it.
Scott: But the places that tend a lot of places don't think they take it cuz they don't know either.
Rym: the places that tend to take It and it just works are the places that have like a square device that they're using as their payments.
Scott: It works and it's like places that don't even realize they take it.
Rym: actually take you know where it doesn't fucking work Overseas like anywhere.
Scott: Oh, no.
Scott: Yeah, that's not good.
Rym: Yeah, but that Like once you get out of the u.s.
Rym: Like good fucking luck doing that kind of thing in a lot of places.
Scott: Yep Yeah, I got.
Scott: I got an app for timers when I'm cooking.
Scott: yeah So I'm gonna take my phone out and get it risk getting messed up cooking.
Rym: Yep, uh seeing the cool like the upcoming weather That's something I stick in there.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, that's the thing You know.
Scott: a lot of people get those old watches with like weather and stuff.
Scott: It's like no no I get real actual live weather like, you know exact what temperature is it here?
Scott: What temperature is it gonna be?
Scott: every everything and I get the sun exactly.
Rym: the only only other features I use they're only two and 99%.
Rym: what a smartwatch could do kind of like a smartphone not actually useful is Google Keep.
Rym: so I can take a quick note.
Rym: when someone says the name of some movie at a party Yeah, I'm gonna forget to watch that movie the next day.
Rym: or I have an idea for a show I just really quick like stick it into Google Keep on the watch.
Rym: That's actually been really helpful to remember to talk about stuff on GeekNights.
Scott: Yeah, that's good.
Rym: And number two is the button to find my phone if I don't know where my phone is.
Scott: Mm-hmm That's it.
Rym: That's good, too Yeah But I find that a lot of people treat their smartphone and their smartwatch in the same kind of wrong way Where they always ask the question of what cool apps can I get on the device?
Scott: Just a problem.
Rym: in general when they should be asking what do I want this thing to do then can it do this thing?
Rym: I wanted which app does that thing?
Scott: Yeah, if you can't think of the thing to do, right?
Scott: It's like whenever I get a new computer I don't install any software besides the OS and the web browser and then what I do is I Use my computer and I say and it's like alright, I want to play a game now.
Scott: Well now I will install steam then right?
Scott: Yep.
Scott: It's like until I actually want to do a thing I don't get an app to do a thing.
Scott: people go out and they like install a fuck ton of apps and it's like Using those apps.
Rym: well thus here do not get a smartwatch if you don't know why you want a smartwatch like you Articulate what you want other than it's a smartwatch like specifically like for us.
Rym: I wanted to show me notifications and do like four other things and I was willing to pay money For those things.
Rym: if you don't have a thing you need it for.
Rym: just use a regular watch and your phone or just your phone.
Rym: Fitness tractors, I guess are a very special-purpose thing But I don't.
Rym: I think that like I said, that's kind of out of bounds for what we're talking about today.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: I do wish there was a mod like a new equivalent of Google Glass.
Rym: I'd like to still have that screen and I'd like to have.
Rym: the one thing I'd like to be able to do is just really quick Take a picture without getting my phone out and I don't want a camera on my watch.
Rym: I feel like that's gonna be a pain in the ass.
Scott: I can remotely control fire a camera from my watch I can set my phone up somewhere and then be like pew.
Rym: I would like to have a like a Google Glass too with a better design because I would use the Just take a picture by wing.
Scott: It needs to just look like glasses.
Scott: So no one knows.
Rym: Yeah, mostly because stupid people got mad about it Even though getting out your phone and doing the exact same thing did not bother them.
Scott: Nope, or the fact that there are security cameras everywhere did not bother.
Rym: Yeah, also the fact that they're not mad about that Instagram glasses.
Rym: They're only mad about Google Glass.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know people.
Rym: Yeah, but smartwatch, you know design.
Scott: design makes all the difference.
Rym: also though My smartwatch has a feature that is ridiculous.
Rym: It has a full-on speaker in it.
Scott: Yeah, so does mine.
Rym: Yeah, it can just make noise like lots of noise.
Rym: It's really loud and I turn the shit off.
Scott: I can play music on mine.
Scott: I can stream music directly to the watch from the internet and play it I can.
Rym: I can load like music into this thing and even without the LTE And it'll just cash it and play music for me either out of the speaker or directly via Bluetooth to my Bluetooth headphones.
Rym: Yep, you can do that And I don't really need that feature because I always have my watch with me and I don't ever listen to music when I'm biking Or running because that's kind of dangerous.
Rym: and also I don't need to fill every gap in my life with background noise.
Scott: No, but it is an option.
Rym: It's there.
Rym: That's a perfectly valid use case for a smartwatch.
Scott: Well, yeah, it's like basically every you know feature from the phone that could be minified has been minified.
Rym: Yep, do you need another screen that's easier to see quickly?
Rym: then get a smartwatch?
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Rym: It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Craig Oliver Ellen Joyce Heidi McNichol just like a dude guy kashar tovish and William Isen.
Rym: rose link Iji Graham Finch Jennifer Hitchcock Chris mint give my state II calm.
Rym: J Ben Shawn Yeager Nicholas brand out.
Rym: Let's see if Rym says Toronto properly for two one creations now.
Rym: This is a story all about how my life got flipped turned upside Shervin But horrible.
Rym: Rory Superboy Clinton Walton rendering friend from New Zealand Ryan parent drooping lender Finn dread lily Tenebrae Sean Klein Chris Reimer Thomas Hahn and I cannot tell you how good it is to be back from our long hiatus.
Rym: We will be doing a lot of content.
Rym: We got some rebranding coming.
Rym: You're gonna see some new GeekNights logos new GeekNights art assets eventually a new website.
Rym: You might have seen us slowing down on the content and skipping shows off and on for a little while But that's mainly because we've been charging the laser to do a big big rebrand and jump out strong.
Rym: So stay tuned and be ready to start Spreading the word if you want more GeekNights.
Rym: Once we redo the website and everything We're gonna need your help to sort of step up our game and a bunch of exciting new projects.
Rym: But anyway for now, I leave you with.
Rym: The legends have to survive.
Scott: We'll never come undone And we will be forever.
Scott: young Vampires in Helsinki Come alive.
Scott: I am a vampire.
Scott: I'm a slave a slave to the daylight hands my grave In the darkness in the shadows.
Rym: I want you to be forever mine together until the end of time like a nightmare Never-ending, let me change your world.
Scott: The legends have to survive.
Rym: We'll never come undone And we will be.
Rym: We will be forever You.