Rym: It's Monday June 24th 2019.
Rym: I'm Rym knows good, and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We are talking about computer mice.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So I actually got my bike back from the shop And it is that you so good.
Scott: too much money to fix.
Scott: I don't think I paid too much.
Scott: you could have just bought a new bicycle probably.
Rym: uh so I could have bought a new bicycle.
Rym: The parts to replace.
Rym: basically I replaced $4,400 worth of parts on my bike to buy the same bike in 2019 dollars.
Rym: because I went and looked around.
Rym: I was at the shop.
Rym: so while they were giving figuring out the estimate I went and looked at like equivalent bikes would have been about sixteen hundred bucks.
Scott: No, how much would it cost to buy the same bike?
Scott: What year is your bike from?
Scott: 2010 ish 2010 by.
Rym: I found a blue book quote like bike site that tracks like who knows if that's accurate for shit.
Rym: So I looked at it, and it said where do they get their data from?
Rym: looks like they scrape it.
Rym: So what I found is that my current bike Which is a Trek 7.6 FX you can get that exact same bike like refurbished for around 1,300 bucks.
Rym: No, cuz they stopped making that particular bike a while ago like even when I went to the bike shop.
Rym: I went to the Bicycle what a bicycle habitat and the guy was like whoa the Trek FX.
Rym: They don't make those any sounds Don't think?
Scott: how could they not?
Rym: they do.
Rym: they make similar bikes But they don't think they got rid of the hybrid bike trick.
Rym: their trick makes a bunch of hybrids.
Scott: but point is my the fancy.
Scott: the bike I just bought to replace my Trek FX that was all busted was 1,500 new for a brand new 2019 model fancy bike.
Scott: so it makes no sense that your bike would be less money than that.
Scott: I mean close even.
Rym: I mean a hybrid like the nice hybrids Trek has are from 1,000 to 1,600 depending on which models you look at Like four to six hundred dollars yeah.
Rym: So instead I spent four hundred dollars in parts to basically make my bike brand new And it'll probably last another eight years and by then who knows what the world will be like mm-hmm.
Rym: so Bike to work today, and it felt good felt good to have a chain that is actually not stretched out and actually fits over by Gears that are themselves not completely ruined Mm-hmm.
Rym: so uh I wanna go right into the news cuz there was a big internet outage.
Scott: I woke up this morning, and I go and I bring on my iPad and I start reading some internet And the first thing I notice is I try to play my stupid balloon popping game with its little daily challenge.
Rym: Wait this sounds like Jerry's game from Rick and Morty.
Scott: no It's.
Scott: it's a tower defense game.
Scott: okay with the monkeys the pop balloons.
Rym: cuz in Rick and Morty There's a dumb character and his thing is he plays this iPad game all the time.
Rym: That's just click on balloons to pop them.
Scott: No.
Scott: This is not that.
Scott: okay It's tower defense game if I play it once every morning.
Scott: You know whatever.
Scott: anyway There's a screen that loads to show you the daily challenges was just white and not loading.
Scott: I was like huh, I guess they fucked up their daily challenge thing.
Rym: It's funny cuz this morning I was getting ready to get in the shower and before I get into the shower I like look at the news and bunch of websites I tried to go to on my phone just like wouldn't load.
Scott: then I open the feed the app and the feed the app we Rss reading thing.
Scott: it doesn't.
Scott: it just doesn't load.
Scott: It's just like hangs on the top screen.
Scott: I'm like huh What's up with that?
Scott: Yeah I said just start searching Twitter And I search for feed Lee on Twitter and someone's like feed Lee is down.
Scott: Then I found one of those websites where people report you know put in manual reports of sites being down.
Rym: Yeah Usually I use I type the name of a site on Twitter and be like see if our people are complaining about right.
Scott: and this Is that they like aggregate user reports of sites being down and show little graphs of like how many reports there are and there?
Scott: Several sites with spikes.
Scott: I noticed discord was one of them, so I open up this.
Scott: Gordon sure enough It doesn't fucking work.
Scott: Yeah, and I'm like well.
Scott: I think there is a larger internet problem here.
Scott: That is what my spidey sense tells me.
Rym: Yeah and probably some sort of issue with the Internet at large or a large provider like maybe Oz or something like that and for reasons I won't get into but I Was well aware of this because of the nature of my work.
Scott: Yeah as soon as I woke up this morning at like 7 I found this I saw things were wrong, and I guessed exactly right within like 10 minutes.
Rym: yep So this article will talk about the details of what happened And it's pretty funny actually right.
Scott: so the long and short of it this article is written by someone at Cloudflare Not the hugest fan of Cloudflare although I do use a small number of their things because
Rym: I'm a fan of some aspects of Cloudflare like They do good load balancing stuff And they do good like they
Scott: have smart people working there and a lot of their technology is legit.
Rym: the problem is one They won't ban Nazis from using their platform.
Scott: I thought they slightly did once yeah, but not completely yeah.
Scott: and two Some of the things.
Rym: one service they offer them some of the features They offer which granted should only be used by people who already cannot solve their own technology problems kind of defeat the purpose of TLS.
Scott: Yeah, anyway, so Regardless this article is written by someone who works at Cloudflare who is obviously a very smart internet engineer Who was able to figure out what was wrong and started calling up the other networks to get things straight.
Scott: now?
Rym: It's cool.
Rym: Is?
Rym: this is the kind of problem I went to school to learn how to solve like I learned about this shit at RIT.
Scott: you couldn't have solved it.
Scott: You're not as good as Tom Whatever his last name is pronounced.
Rym: I don't know leaked routes are not uncommon inside of corporate network.
Scott: Anyway, here's what is what happened in somewhat non-detailed terms because I don't I also did not learn the complete details of BGP.
Rym: Right and also to be clear I can talk a big game But I knew well I knew the ins and outs of BGP and excruciating detail, and you don't know any as of 2003 when I took classes on it specifically.
Scott: so anyway here's the situation.
Scott: you have the a couple networks right small time networks But still networks on the internet meaning like 10 11 20 dot 0 slash something Network and they have routers.
Scott: and those routers you know are routing the traffic of those networks users But also routing other traffic because that's how the internet fucking works.
Rym: now How does the router know where to route a particular packet?
Scott: It's got it.
Scott: just has as this IP addresses go that way.
Rym: that is something called a routing T's IP Addresses go that way.
Rym: in the old days of the internet our router would literally have Basically a text file.
Rym: that said if the IP starts with four send it on this pipe right.
Scott: say it starts with seven Send it on to detail for a news here.
Scott: It's not the whole it's not the main bit.
Scott: save it for the main bit.
Scott: Anyway, the point is these tiny networks they fucked the fuck up and they advertised basically putting up street signs that said hey Packets headed for these IP addresses.
Scott: This is the fastest way over here.
Scott: now those messages were supposed to stay within their network.
Scott: You know those road signs were only for the packets in their network zones because if packets were say in some other network That wasn't the fastest way.
Scott: go the fastest way was not through the tiny network.
Scott: Yep the fastest way was through the big networks on the internet until you get somewhere on the other side.
Rym: imagine if in your subdivision you had like a bunch of private roads and You put up a little sign inside of your subdivision that says hey to get to the freeway Go this way.
Rym: and then someone picked up that sign went out to a different freeway And just stuck it there.
Scott: and now people from like a major road are going through your subdivision To get to the freeway because they think that's the way.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: That's that's the best way to analogize this.
Scott: anyway, so This person for Cloudflare, you know Clearly the people at the small networks did fuck up, but the person who wrote this article Hilariously and perhaps truthfully didn't put too much blame on those tiny networks because they're tiny.
Scott: It's like they should.
Scott: you know.
Scott: should they have known better?
Scott: maybe?
Rym: Well like here's the case in point a freeway has very like the size difficult to put up a fake freeway sign.
Rym: That's convincing.
Rym: So if a bunch of drivers see like my hand-painted sign and believe it It's more their fault than anyone else, but what happened in this particular case is Verizon which is basically top of the internet.
Scott: Yeah, right in terms of network like it or not, right?
Scott: They Also fucked up and if they had not fucked up These small networks fucking up would not have fucked up the entire internet.
Scott: So this person at Cloudflare puts all the blame on Verizon plus.
Scott: it seemed that they were mad that Verizon didn't return their phone Call but luckily one of the smaller networks did return their phone call and fix the problem and saved the internet.
Scott: There was like basically 15% of the internet was like fucked for some time this morning at least like an hour.
Rym: There's two like important things going on about this story because again We don't want to get into all these details because you can read this article.
Rym: it goes into more detail than you're probably gonna be comfortable with.
Rym: but the two points that come out are that one.
Rym: the Internet's like routing infrastructure is Actually, terrifyingly fragile.
Rym: Oh, yeah Like people like to believe that the internet is this massive network that can like route around damage.
Rym: The reality is looking at it crosswise can cause it to completely fail.
Scott: It's really good at routing around damage.
Scott: It's really bad it when it says hey send things there when you just give bad directions.
Rym: a lot of the routing Protocols that are still in use to this day sort of assume that everyone's competent.
Rym: And like there's a lot of.
Scott: it's like if those like if Verizon just went down Yeah the packets would route around it and find their way to where they're going as long as they weren't trying to go to.
Rym: but if Verizon is just telling people to do the wrong thing because it listened to the wrong person.
Scott: Yep, then it's gonna fuck the fuck up.
Scott: Yep, everyone has bad directions.
Scott: Everyone's gonna go the wrong way and get lost.
Scott: You know what?
Rym: It's like it's kind of like when you have a disaster disaster recovery situation like you got server a and server B and if server a fucks up you want to be able to route everyone to server B Like that kind of thing.
Scott: That's all.
Scott: that's what the Internet's great at.
Rym: Yep, but there's a reason why Most serious systems use stoneth methods to make sure that you don't get into a weird situation.
Rym: Stoneth is a hilarious acronym that stands for shoot the other node in the head Which means effectively if you're gonna fail over Fucking kill the primary node.
Rym: So there's no way it can come up in a bad or non deterministic state and cause weird problems.
Rym: So the other thing this raises is that and I'm seeing this just across Networking industries in general people like me went to school and learn this stuff.
Rym: But you'll notice I don't do this as a job.
Rym: Most people who have a degree like what I have do not do this as a job.
Rym: Most of the people who do networking as a job did not go to a university and learn like Theory of networking and all these details because anyone who goes to study computers doesn't say I want to be a network engineer.
Rym: I did.
Rym: I thought I wanted to be a network engineer and I learned how to be an extremely skilled network engineer And that doesn't pay shit.
Rym: So I never took it as a job.
Scott: the people who run the internet be paid a lot.
Scott: You'd think that like if you're if you're that guy cloud player Tom Sticks should be getting paid big bunnies, you know, we you'd think teachers would get paid a lot.
Scott: Well, that's it like.
Rym: But the people who know the most about networking theory are not the people actually doing the day-to-day networking jobs in the world as a whole.
Rym: and I feel like this is only getting worse like I'm finding just in my professional life that People entering the industry as a whole doesn't matter.
Rym: Any technology industry know less and less about how the internet actually works and they have more and more focused knowledge on how to write JavaScript and They don't understand what a subnet mask is.
Rym: or they know like Babies first like they know what a subnet mask is and have no idea what cider is because some of that mass are fucking obsolete.
Rym: And if you think subnet masks are how the internet works, you're wrong.
Scott: But they're not how the internet works, but they are how your little end might work in your house.
Rym: Yeah, I Even ran.
Rym: I ran into multiple professionals in recent memory who were really confused when some 172 dot something IP addresses were flagged as internal.
Rym: they were like How do you know these are internal?
Rym: and I hit my forehead so hard.
Scott: people heard it begin with 172.
Scott: Yeah, is that a good reason?
Rym: They they thought it was the I know 192 dot something because they were already wrong about that.
Scott: You've never seen 172 Three.
Rym: those are only three, uh So Scott your knowledge is out of date.
Rym: There's another one.
Rym: There are more.
Scott: Some of them are new.
Scott: I've never seen any more than those three one of them and all my life.
Rym: Uh, there are more.
Rym: Okay, there I will pull some up as examples.
Rym: Yeah, but basically I guess you own some IP.
Rym: then These are ranges that are either reserved for nonsense like, you know about multicast like that's a reserve whatever.
Rym: And you know, there's this class II like special reserve nonsense Even though clad.
Rym: there aren't classes anymore because of classes that remain routing or cider.
Rym: but There are ranges that are defined for like carrier grade net.
Rym: like.
Rym: these are the ranges that are used for the netting that ISPs do as opposed to the I. the netting that like this thing does Is router over here.
Rym: and there are other ranges like slash 31 subnets, which if you do the math Involves zero hosts like it's just a network.
Rym: Those are used between big routers so they can negotiate their own crap without needing like real IPs to be wasted.
Rym: So there are other ranges and it gets complicated and no one learns this stuff unless they go to university for it And most people don't as professors of the university who know it.
Rym: Yeah And none of those people end up entering the workforce to be like the person who actually Configures the routers at a company.
Scott: isn't that like Cisco certified whatever supposed to teach you?
Rym: Yeah And in my experience Cisco people know a lot about how Cisco works and they don't know isn't that also how the internet works?
Rym: Yeah, but there's also there's all.
Rym: there's non Cisco technology out there.
Rym: GP is a generic
Scott: Understand that even if you understand how to configure a Cisco router You should also night by you know Association understand the core concepts of writing Learn how to use a different route or you should still understand the concept, you know what it's like need to learn a new syntax.
Rym: It's like the difference between the people who know how to code in several languages versus the people who actually learn computer science.
Rym: It's that kind of situation.
Rym: So you can read this article to learn the details.
Rym: But really though the main point is that first fucked up this morning and this particular kind of fuck-up happens all the time.
Scott: This one was just a particularly Than usual one Yeah, but how many times for example right does a tiny network fuck up in this way?
Scott: But the bigger network isn't Verizon and thus we are shielded from its arms.
Rym: Yep like if you really want to see like how this stuff can go wrong run wireshark on like your home network and you're gonna see a Lot of fucked up broken shit even on your own tiny internal network that if it leaked out to the world could cause problems.
Rym: You'll see weird stuff like V lands getting appended to package that shouldn't be there.
Rym: all sorts of nonsense.
Rym: So in some other tech news, there's a. I saw this making the rounds and I just want to address it very briefly But it's a story about how Walmart and Amazon and maybe Google want to quote see inside your house creepy.
Rym: The idea is that I'm gonna cool get out my house.
Rym: It's even worse.
Rym: I'm just gonna quote this article in home cameras and audio sensors would look at the objects in your house Create a detailed profile of your tastes and your potential desires and then serve up ads and content that fit that profile.
Scott: why would I do that?
Rym: in one of the example scenarios a smart video camera sees that you have a paperback copy of The Godfather on your bedside table and then feeds that information back to a local processing hub.
Rym: that then tells you that there is a Screening of the movie based on that book today at a theater near you.
Rym: That sounds like a recipe for a literal hell.
Scott: Why would you get this?
Rym: Uh, Yeah, I get the impression that this is the final stage of surveillance capitalism that Walmart seems to be pushing this Amazon seems to be pushing.
Rym: is that getting people to opt into intense analytics?
Scott: Oh, what's the benefit for you?
Rym: Nothing?
Scott: So why would you do it?
Scott: Well, because the better for you is either they will be still up for all the shit in the world They still not.
Scott: don't live in a society where this can be forced to Scott.
Rym: What is the benefit to anyone of seeing an ad?
Rym: I Mean, you know you are paying by seeing the ad in order to get access to quote unquote free sir, right?
Scott: But here what are you getting access to?
Scott: You're not even getting access to like a crappy TV show.
Rym: Yeah, so, you know what I feel is gonna actually happen with this.
Rym: most people don't understand how any of this stuff works and they'll get.
Rym: they're gonna have a smart TV and like two Amazon echoes and a Bunch of nest cameras like all around their house and They're gonna click through agreements and Google and Amazon and companies are just gonna mind that data and start targeting ads based on that.
Rym: Okay, I think it's gonna happen to normal people without their consent and it's not gonna happen to people like us.
Rym: I even saw someone we know recently on Twitter say that they jokingly said Amazon changed the channel on their TV and they don't have an Amazon device and the TV change channel anyway Mm-hmm, and then they discovered that they had a smart remote that they didn't realize actually had Amazon integration and they just never looked at It.
Scott: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So this is just a terrifying future that we need to.
Rym: if you're listening to GeekNights, you can protect yourself from this and Godspeed to your grandparents.
Scott: I did see something that people would think is creepy But actually isn't?
Scott: someone in our forum, which you should come and join Received a package because they bought something on Amazon and then there was a photo.
Scott: Amazon sent them a photo of The package on their doorstep.
Scott: I like that and they were like, whoa, that's creepy.
Scott: And I'm like that is actually not creepy.
Scott: It's a picture of the outside of my house.
Scott: That's a picture of the outside of your house.
Scott: We have no expectation of privacy.
Scott: anyone driving by can see that.
Scott: It's a picture of the same thing the delivery person saw.
Scott: they're not seeing anything not creeping in your window.
Scott: They didn't open your house they didn't come inside.
Scott: So now if I come delivering a package that you bought and end they're confirming with that photo that a was delivered.
Scott: B you can see in the photo if that's your house.
Scott: if it's not your house, you know, they deliver the wrong place.
Scott: Yep, if it was maybe stolen or moved, you know, aha.
Scott: Here's a photo of that package in that spot.
Scott: I don't need to go hunting for it.
Scott: You know that.
Scott: I know it was stolen by someone cuz I came home.
Scott: I have a photo from when it was there and it's not there now.
Rym: and I know the dance.
Rym: you have a delivery.
Rym: your Web the website says it was delivered and you didn't see it on your doorstep.
Rym: Well, what happened to it?
Rym: Like there's a song and dance you got to go through before you realize it was right.
Scott: Did they bring it to the wrong place?
Scott: Was it actually not delivered?
Scott: and maybe it's still at the post office and the post office just marked it as delivered because they're jerks.
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Scott: but if there's a photo like that That's perfectly not privacy.
Scott: invading data collecting photo of the outside of your home of a package and whatever a public stuff That's actually pretty great.
Rym: Yeah Now if it's a picture of me sleeping in my bed that says we missed you didn't want to wake you up left the package On your doorstop, that would be creepy.
Rym: That's no.
Rym: that is now what's happening.
Rym: No.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I thought that was okay.
Rym: Yeah, I was 100% okay with that.
Rym: so last at least before we get to the main bit and actually not least at all if you happen to live in New York City and More importantly if you happen to live in Queens, I don't know who's running in any.
Scott: I don't know what primaries are in any of the buries I don't know any other primary in any other borough or any other Kind of big one going on in Brooklyn - but I think it's only one part of Brooklyn.
Rym: I don't live there, so I'm ignoring it.
Rym: I got too much to pay attention to but Queens actually has a really important primary right.
Rym: queen is tomorrow the 25th, right?
Scott: So Queens if you don't know is the most Diverse urban place in the entire United States.
Rym: perhaps world like Queens is a great place.
Scott: Two million people over two million people here and the DA of Queens has been the same person for a hell of Fucking long time some crusty old dude.
Scott: and he done.
Scott: And now we have to vote for the next DA.
Scott: Whoever is.
Scott: the Democratic nominee for DA has like a ninety nine point nine percent chance to win in the general election Which means the election tomorrow is the real election where there are like many several choices to choose from.
Rym: so point number one If you live in New York City, I don't care what your politics are.
Rym: I don't care.
Rym: if you hate the Democratic Party you have to join the Democratic Party because otherwise you can't vote in the primaries.
Scott: and the Best you live in Staten Island.
Rym: Yeah, if you live in Staten Island get the fuck out.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: But uh or stay the fuck there you piece of shit.
Rym: Yeah, I Just remember seeing this stag years ago that Staten Island generates more trash both per capita and in total volume than any other borough.
Scott: I mean it is trash.
Rym: Yeah But Just self-replicating like Staten Island.
Rym: It's weird because culturally it's nothing to do with New York City.
Rym: It's like isolated and separate.
Rym: It's New Jersey, but it counts as New York for some stupid reason I don't know.
Rym: I feel like we should give it to New Jersey and just let Yonkers be the sixth borough They can have.
Rym: Yonkers is way more, New York.
Rym: Yonkers is basically just Bronx - yeah.
Rym: So anyway, uh, if you can't vote in the primary for the Democrats you literally can't vote like nothing matters The primaries all that matters - people tend not to vote in primaries because they don't pay attention.
Rym: It's tomorrow.
Scott: Yes, I looked up the ballot.
Scott: There's some.
Scott: there's a choice of three judges and you must choose the rejudge.
Rym: two of them are Democrats.
Rym: One of them is a Republican.
Rym: I'm only voting for the two Democrats and you do that.
Rym: Yeah, okay, you can just choose.
Rym: you can just not vote for a third one.
Rym: It's up to three.
Scott: Okay, they're gonna avoid my ballot.
Rym: I'm gonna.
Rym: I know you could write in a third person.
Scott: The real election is choosing the DA and the person you should choose is Tiffany Kavan Apparently a. I decided way at the beginning when like months ago I looked at all the people and I said up this Tiffany person is clear that the best person you have a public defendant As the D a public defender as the DA
Rym: Prosecutor because there's a prosecutor running - yeah
Scott: anyway.
Scott: and Melinda Katz is currently the borough president is running But I've met her several times and she is annoying and fake.
Rym: also Elizabeth Warren who GeekNights has endorsed for the presidency of the United States has endorsed Tiffany Kavan.
Rym: So is Bernie Sanders?
Rym: So has AOC so the.
Rym: so has Cynthia Nixon.
Scott: the Bar Association of Queens said that she is not qualified.
Scott: the Bar Association.
Scott: That is a bunch of old white dudes.
Scott: So that's basically a certified staff of approval.
Scott: So white old guys say your bad must be good Even better.
Rym: New York Post which is a fucking rag has this to say Tiffany Kavan would turn Queens to a giant brothel.
Scott: That sounds great.
Rym: Let's go.
Rym: That's all right.
Scott: Let's get rid of Now the thing is.
Scott: the only negative thing I can say about our friend Tiffany is that her campaign is Annoying as they've knocked on my door, which is illegal because I live in an apartment Money's long ago before her campaign was even doing anything and give someone money.
Scott: that usually says hey, I'm voting for you.
Scott: Why are you knocking on my door?
Scott: Mailing me shit in the mail Emailing me texting me.
Scott: It's like back the fuck off.
Scott: You're gonna make me want to not vote for you.
Scott: if there was another candidate who was even close to progressive I would have switched simply because your campaign is so fucking annoying.
Scott: But here's the problem.
Scott: there is not.
Scott: all the other candidates are garbage But also at least relative guard.
Rym: the fact is you and I and hopefully the GeekNights listener Care enough about politics to where we're gonna vote for the right people But the average common clay of the new west they vote based on.
Rym: I don't know when like knocking on doors and bothering people is more effective than anything I knock on the door of the person who is already voting for you.
Scott: Please knock on the door of the cranky old person down the street, you know, we need Scott.
Rym: It's a modern Passover.
Rym: We just need to all agree.
Rym: There's a thing you put on your door that says listen, I know what's up.
Rym: I'll bother my racist neighbors.
Scott: I put up like one of those I guess and you know, we can't do those lawn things.
Scott: Yeah, they have in the suburbs with the two sticks, right?
Rym: I just need to put a little sign on my door that I'm voting for the most progressive candidate.
Rym: I already gave money.
Rym: leave me alone, right?
Scott: It's like if I just put a caban sign on my door.
Rym: some lambsblood just get some lambs.
Scott: The problem is they rang the thing at the front of the building.
Rym: Oh See that the difference is my building.
Rym: if you don't live here, you can't come in.
Scott: Mmm We have a doorman and such into mine either.
Scott: You need someone.
Rym: Yeah, they got into my building.
Scott: They've been knocking on the door like well, then you could put a caban sign on your door.
Scott: exactly wouldn't knock.
Rym: They'd be like, okay But the reality is the only way to get the common clay of the new west to vote is to bother them and trick them.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Just don't bother the person who's already voting.
Rym: Yeah, but bothering us is it's not like I'm gonna be like.
Rym: well fucking I'm voting for a Republican now.
Scott: Well, but you could vote for like.
Scott: less accurate basically is a Republican?
Rym: yeah, right Yeah, like I'm gonna vote for anyone but Tiffany cabana seriously The only the one good thing is that other than the pseudo Republican running and the fake one All all of them really saying the right things like they're going really far left and progressive.
Scott: Well, there was the Lankman guy who was the most the second most progressive candidate, but then he basically bailed out and endorsed The fake one Like.
Scott: wait a minute, but that makes no sense clear.
Rym: There's some backroom shenanigans going on, but seriously Like wherever you live I don't care if it's like the dumpiest primary like you have to vote at all these weird little Elections because that has way more effect on your actual as people vote in them.
Rym: Yeah, so your vote matters way more dude you vote in some of these off your elections like You'll be like literally the ninth person to vote in your whole district.
Scott: I know other countries have way better general elections than we do.
Scott: do those other cut like.
Scott: are there primaries in like, you know, Spain it parties don't.
Rym: American parties are pretty unique in how we work, right?
Scott: It's like.
Scott: do they have extra tiny elections in these other countries?
Scott: or is it just the one and that's it?
Rym: Yeah, most.
Rym: I mean You're thinking of our parliamentary systems.
Scott: Yeah, but wouldn't they still have to?
Scott: it's like, okay We're gonna have someone from our district go to Parliament and there's like what they got.
Scott: I guess thing in UK.
Scott: It's what Tories and labor.
Scott: well Scott, but like you got to choose the labor It's gotten in the Tory person, but no like you don't vote for who's gonna be Prime Minister.
Rym: The party decides on their own.
Rym: you just vote for the local rep who will then give that party more power.
Scott: But I'm the coalition is like three people who want to be the local rep.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know that work.
Scott: They got to have another a smaller election, right?
Rym: Yeah, I have no idea how that works.
Rym: or they just compete in the general against each other and Depending on how dire 2020s look and I'm gonna have to learn how Australia Germany in the UK actually do those elections.
Rym: I'm gonna have to make a decision about that.
Rym: but anyway, it's time for things of the day, so If you didn't see it yet, it's only like five like it's a really short.
Rym: It's like five episodes long, but that HBO series Chernobyl is crazy.
Scott: Good Yeah, I watched a nonfiction documentary in middle or high school.
Scott: I don't feel like I need to watch a fictionalized documentary.
Rym: So it's.
Rym: it's only fictionalized in the sense that it's like obviously dramatized like detailed events But it doesn't follow the typical like so-called plot of those kinds of dramatized documentaries.
Scott: Well, I mean they can't really divert from the plot too much Yeah, but also like a lot of the retone saved it.
Scott: it was a cool guys.
Rym: Here's the big difference.
Rym: most of those documentaries are like long and Boring and like Lead up to the accident.
Rym: and then there's the episode about the accident and then they do the aftermath.
Rym: This one literally just starts in the actual control room, which you can see pictures of like tourists go to see it and It starts with like the people sitting there covered with like a lead dome or whatever.
Rym: The control room is not the reactor.
Rym: Also, you realize the other Chernobyl reactors kept running until recently.
Scott: Yeah, but they weren't like they were.
Scott: you know, they're like a mile away.
Rym: no, they're next door.
Scott: I thought they were in like, you know, it's a big area of emptiness.
Scott: No, they got shit tons of land.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, I remember seeing a photo where there was like one reactor and a bunch of land and then another one.
Rym: Go look at the photos that complex.
Rym: They build the sarcophagus partly to protect the people who are working like next door at the other reactors that were still.
Scott: Remember seeing guys like hanging out in the parking lot showing you like here's how much radiation is still hanging out in the parking.
Scott: There's like no one.
Scott: there was like all deserted.
Rym: Yeah, because right next door people are just working.
Scott: Mmm the parking lot.
Scott: No cars Yeah Anyway, it looked like a deserted area and they were like, ooh We're going here to you know to see how much radiations left after all these.
Rym: the documentary is really good because it really focuses on Sort of the reality of what happens and the real like what like how it affected the actual people who live there.
Rym: And it's really good.
Rym: and the only part that we're sort of over dramatized was the last episode which is sort of the like Court case that went through what happened right in court.
Rym: it Condensed the events of how the world found out about these flaws in the react Soviet court.
Rym: Yeah But this video my thing of the day is a vlog brothers video that because there's this point in the documentary Dramatized and the point gets spread widely.
Rym: But people always talk about the graphite tips at the bottom of the control rods that cause the scram button to fail Which is technically true But it's a little bit misleading.
Rym: So this video in about 13 minutes Explains in detail what those graphite tips in the control rods Actually did and it's a little more nuanced.
Scott: Also, I just want to you know, take this occasion to remind everyone who might not have you know large, you know knowledge of disasters Chernobyl was the worst human-made disaster in history.
Rym: No wasn't I think.
Scott: so What's no?
Rym: first of all unless you count World War two, okay?
Scott: We're talking about disasters which were not wars.
Scott: Yeah, we're just like.
Rym: not natural disasters either, right?
Scott: No, not natural disasters by humans directly like a factory exploding or something.
Rym: Bhopal is pretty bad right.
Scott: this Bhopal gas disaster is way worse than Chernobyl But that's debatable because Chernobyl affected a huge number of people.
Rym: The number of people who were killed This is like talking about a mass shooting like yes only eight people were killed But the 40 people who were injured but survived their lives are drastically changed regardless.
Scott: Both of those are dwarfed by.
Scott: I forget the name of it.
Scott: There was a dam in China.
Scott: That was And flooded and killed like some ridiculous number of people in a giant flood and flooded an enormous area.
Scott: this hide This what it's called hydroelectric dam.
Scott: I forget the name of it.
Scott: Look for Chinese hydroelectric dam.
Rym: There's actually a Russian dam that killed Directly more people than Chernobyl.
Scott: I have never read a story about anything nearly as bad as what happened with the fucking dam.
Rym: There's a Russian dam that was pretty close where they messed up Started free flooring.
Scott: so I bring it up simply because I would like to say hey people who have brought attention to Chernobyl with your Documentary, please make further well fictionalized documentary.
Scott: Please make one about Bhopal gas disaster and Chinese dam.
Rym: Yeah I think they should because a lot of people are paying attention because the Chernobyl documentary is please make people more scared of things that Are scarier than nuclear power, but the thing is if you watch Chernobyl, it's not saying nuclear power is scary.
Scott: No, that's fine.
Scott: But it's actually really nuanced.
Scott: You know what it says But people we won't even see it.
Scott: people still get scared.
Rym: Yeah But if you watch it It's crazy because what it really puts a fine point on is Other than the fact that the bookshelf behind the guy in this video is almost identical to your bookshelf.
Scott: No, not really.
Rym: I see I see a couple of overlaps.
Rym: You don't have I see.
Scott: I think that looks like Sandman there.
Scott: Which is you watchman hanging?
Scott: I don't have Sandman.
Scott: Yeah, I read someone else's Sandman.
Rym: Oh wait, I see wool here.
Scott: I don't have a wool anymore.
Rym: Yeah, I got rid all my wools.
Rym: I found I had three fucking copies of wool.
Scott: Luigi.
Rym: he does have a Luigi.
Rym: But anyway, it points out that even with all the ridiculous like safety problems and poor design of the reactor.
Rym: Chernobyl still wouldn't have happened if it weren't for the fact that the people who made the decisions moment by moment Arrogant, not just arrogant It's they made like eight decisions in a row all of which you had to choose the worst possible option.
Scott: Alarm is going off.
Scott: ignore disabled right not do with it, right?
Scott: Yeah, like a power plant and one on one warning is going off.
Scott: I'm like shut it down till we fix that.
Rym: Yeah, the problem was at the end.
Rym: pull out them rods at the end that well don't pull them out.
Rym: fuck Scott Do you know what a control rod does?
Rym: pulling it out as the worst possible thing to do?
Scott: I'm not a nuclear engineer.
Scott: putting the rods go in and out.
Rym: control rods Reduce the reactivity in the reactor.
Rym: They slow down the reaction.
Rym: pulling them out speeds the reaction up.
Scott: I thought the rods were the plutonium and you put more you put in.
Rym: those are the fuel rods not the control rods Fuel rods.
Rym: you just pull in and out.
Rym: the fuel rods are in there Semi-permanently.
Rym: unless you're looking at the scariest nuclear reactor in history the windscale reactor Which was air-cooled and you just use tubes and just like pushed hunks of nuclear material through it Like this like with your hands like with coal.
Rym: Yeah on a shovel The windscale reactor is far scarier and it also had a shitty disaster.
Scott: I could see why.
Rym: yeah but this video is good because basically it explains like the actual full technical details of that.
Rym: Graphite tipped control rods point in there in the like.
Rym: it explains this in interesting detail.
Rym: You should watch it.
Rym: So what you think of the day?
Scott: so I was just going on Twitter and I came across a funny little four panel comic.
Scott: And then I looked into that the funny.
Scott: I had never seen this.
Scott: we did a whole episode of Twitter comics Yeah, and this one was not mentioned at all.
Scott: This one would have been perfect.
Scott: I'd never seen it before and I it was a really it was above well above par funny little four panel comic.
Scott: and then I clicked on the account that it came from to say hey there any other funny four panel comics and There were so many and they were all so good.
Rym: mousetrap is the first one I saw four days ago And that's the one where I thought oh, wow, that's really good and I didn't follow up on it.
Scott: Yep So yeah.
Scott: So the account the whole owner of this account is someone named Mikey Heller.
Scott: the Twitter name is yo-yo robot And this person Mikey is actually the lead writer on a Cartoon Network Cartoon called we bear bear which is adorable which I have not seen but have seen screenshots of Scott.
Rym: I will send you a link to.
Rym: just well, you just have to watch the initial D parody one.
Scott: Anyway, uh And apparently that in addition to being the lead writer for an actual running cartoon on Cartoon Network This person also makes little four panel comics that are a plus tier like a new.
Scott: follow Mikey Heller on Twitter and you will gain much joy.
Rym: The Isaac Newton one is too real.
Scott: Isaac Newton one is so good.
Rym: The vacuum one is like Rym style here Only the recent ones.
Scott: It's like I feel like I want to scroll all the way back But it's too much.
Rym: every one of them is great.
Scott: the I hope he makes a book so I can just buy it instead of Scrolling.
Rym: the one that is the most too real is the one just titled mousetrap.
Scott: Maybe does have a book and I could buy it.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Anyway, it's uh in the meta moment the GeekNights book club book Which we just did was Troy Dennings pages of pain, but I've done it.
Rym: It is done If you want to read this book.
Rym: You can then know everything we have to say about this book.
Rym: is it is on our website Reviewed in full.
Scott: the next book club book Which I should put a reminder to update the website is the first novel ever written in human history The tale of Genji, you should check that out.
Rym: It's gonna let you wield multiple weapons attack multiple times.
Scott: Make sure you buy the particular whatever.
Scott: Royale Translation is the penguin deluxe unabridged edition.
Scott: Don't buy any other edition.
Rym: Got a link to the good one kind of like how if you ever read the count of Monte Cristo There's this one penguin translation.
Rym: read that one.
Rym: Not the old one sadly.
Scott: We do not have a new Emily Wilson translation.
Scott: She doesn't know of Japanese.
Scott: I imagine Emily will.
Rym: She knows Greece more than we need the Emily Wilson equivalent for Japanese literature.
Scott: All right Maybe there is one but that person's original language is like French and maybe the French people Have like an Emily Wilson equivalent tale of Genji written in French, but there's no English.
Rym: It's crazy.
Scott: how even are people now translating the Emily Wilson Odyssey from English into French Spanish German Italian Whatever?
Rym: that would be exciting.
Scott: That's a or would.
Scott: there are there are there of Emily Wilson's doing it straight to from Greek.
Rym: Right, it's crazy how even in the modern world like those kinds of translation language barriers are still a big problem.
Rym: Oh, yeah, like it was only in the last couple decades that Primary sources from Japan about World War two were translated into English.
Rym: So English scholars would like study them and add them to the canon of World War two.
Rym: Yeah Otherwise Let's see Emily and I total aside.
Rym: We've been talking about this for all.
Rym: we actually launched it.
Rym: It's on the patreon now and on July 4th the first episode will go live publicly on the patreon But public you don't have to pay or anything, but we are going to review in detail Every Disney animation theatrical release in chronological order snow white starting with.
Rym: Actually, there's a theatrical release of shorts that came out before snow white and then snow white.
Rym: All right This does include victory through air power because that was released in theaters But also all the ones you can think of.
Rym: we're gonna do an episode fun and fancy free.
Scott: Yeah, hell yeah Hell yeah puppets.
Scott: In between the cartoons
Rym: we're figuring out we have a list and we're paring it down because we're not gonna do Pixar We're not gonna do like the goofy movie but this will be interesting because We're gonna talk about them before we rewatch them and then watch them and talk about them after we've seen them.
Scott: You can talk about even the ones you haven't seen ever before you realize.
Rym: yes Because I fun fact never actually saw Pocahontas or the hunchback or Hercules.
Scott: I saw Hercules.
Scott: I didn't see the other two.
Rym: Yeah, Pocahontas.
Rym: I've there was the error where I was like, yeah, I'm too cool for Disney Did not see Mulan.
Rym: I did not see Mulan either.
Scott: Yeah, what about some live?
Scott: you're not doing live-action.
Scott: I'm gonna go black hole.
Rym: no, we're not doing love live-action.
Rym: We're doing like Disney animation primary theatrical releases.
Scott: No Aladdin - Aladdin - so good though.
Rym: I let him do is pretty good - even those.
Rym: no Robin Williams Scott, how about you and I let's just watch Aladdin - again and do a Wednesday episode on it.
Rym: Hey, I could watch it again.
Rym: I worry That is not as good as I remembered Because Aladdin one already.
Rym: I like it.
Rym: still not as good as I remembered.
Scott: No, you know now my adult brain sees, you know racism and sexism.
Rym: Yeah, my brain is like Meanwhile even my kid brain was like yeah hunchback.
Rym: this feels exploitative and Pocahontas.
Rym: I was like, what the fuck?
Scott: Yeah, really honest was the one that Was like oh At the time even at the time At the time Aladdin didn't you know do anything wrong in my brain, but Pocahontas sure did.
Rym: Yeah, it was.
Rym: I feel like my favorites before we go back into rewatching them other than like Zootopia and modern stuff Really?
Rym: Like I really liked a little mermaid.
Rym: I really like Beauty and the Beast and I really like the rescuers.
Rym: Remember you see both of the rescuers.
Rym: Yeah So, yeah, that'll be on the patreon and you can enjoy that.
Rym: starting July 4th It'll be public.
Rym: But if you're a patron of the GeekNights patreon, the first episode is already up there in a preview mode Mm-hmm, and I think we can get right into it because we have no conventions till Pax West and then conventions He's.
Rym: it starts to do so back on July 23rd 2007 12 years ago.
Rym: Grim is huh.
Rym: Rym and Scott of GeekNights didn't even do a full episode on this.
Rym: We used to do these episodes called specials which basically men we couldn't be asked to do a real episode of GeekNights.
Scott: So we just like well, you're doing for a week.
Scott: So sometimes, you know, we need we couldn't rather than cut the whole episode out We just did the special.
Rym: Yeah, we did four episodes a week for a long time.
Rym: So we did a special the 10th special called computer mice.
Rym: we talked about computer mice back in 2007. we've never done like a real and two years.
Scott: We did ten specials.
Rym: Yeah, that's saying something and I got a lot of thoughts about mice.
Rym: So I feel like we should actually talk about Computer mice.
Scott: Well, I mean, you know What is it say about fucking mice?
Scott: you hold it you move it around you point you click.
Rym: So let's go back to you know Like classic GeekNights because the Monday episodes people liked when we kind of got into history when computers first came out They had keyboards and that was it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean the first time I ever saw a mouse I didn't understand it and it like.
Scott: it took me a while to figure it out.
Scott: It was like some Mac 512 K and it had the mouse with a ball in it and one fucking button.
Rym: in my elementary school There were computers and they had applications on them.
Rym: There were mice plugged into the computers But there was nothing you could use the mice with.
Rym: so they didn't do anything We had.
Scott: only they were like, you know, there was like a mix of computers going on, right?
Scott: so it's like only the fancier computers had the mice because they were like max but the other computers like apples that didn't have mice but and eventually like mice kind of became the standard way people interact with a computer.
Rym: and then there was an error where people tried to get away from the mouse saying it's archaic and Most of the attempts to get away from the mouse involved turning all monitors into touchscreens Which ended up being mostly fucking terrible UX.
Rym: so the mouse persevered until the tablet era and People tried to make tablets and they sucked.
Scott: until the iPad came around.
Scott: pretty much No one there was like a. there were plenty of tablets that just like ran windows on a really Low-res touchscreen with a battery that ran out in five minutes.
Scott: You had a huge bezel around the screen.
Scott: I remember playing with them in like computer stores and yep, you know comp USA or whatever And no one bought those fucking things.
Scott: So garbage.
Rym: So I think we're limiting our scope here.
Rym: We were only talking about primary Tracking inputs for computers like pointing input.
Rym: So we're not talking about drawing tablets.
Scott: Well, the original mouse the way they worked the values the original consumer ones, right because there were like fancy non consumer mice Ball like an actual ball rubber ball kids will remember.
Rym: but that ball had two rollers inside, right?
Scott: Inside the mouse were two spinny things And when you move the mouse around The ball would roll and the ball would roll against the spinners.
Scott: and one spinner would move the mouse cursor horizontally and one vertically and thus you would when you would move the ball the mouse around into two-dimensional space those two spinners would Move the arrow around the screen.
Rym: This also meant if you lifted the mouse at an angle You could still move the like.
Rym: you could move the pointer in a very precise way.
Rym: So when I was like sniping in games I would like lift the mouse to like move a few pixels over.
Scott: first mouse I bought for my when I built my computer.
Scott: not the first mouse ever had but the the first mouse I bought for my good Computer.
Scott: Yeah was like this logitech wingman gaming mouse.
Scott: It had three buttons.
Scott: Holy shit That was advanced and a big ball in.
Scott: it was still a ball underneath.
Rym: bigger balls were just better.
Scott: It was a big ball.
Rym: big balls were better for a lot of reasons.
Rym: Yep But like you literally would have to like every few weeks Open the mouse pull the ball out and clean all the guys off the rollers.
Rym: Yep, the rollers are getting covered in garbage like they got disgusting.
Scott: then eventually one day somebody came up with the idea for the scroll wheel.
Rym: My shit like forgetting the archaic era where like mice had one button and max which had one button.
Scott: until recently I'm not a hundred percent sure about this But I was always under the impression that it was the movement from ps2 to USB That allowed for the addition of all the extra buttons.
Scott: scroll wheel I think ps2 only supported what like three buttons and two axes and most mice.
Scott: I could be wrong about that.
Rym: So yeah ps2 mice.
Rym: yet Basically, you'd have the mouse with two buttons and typically people would their index finger on the left mouse button.
Rym: They're middle finger in the red mouse button.
Rym: And then if some fancy mice had a third button in the middle like I just said yeah But those were rare usually more expensive.
Rym: not every application would work.
Scott: It was for games.
Rym: Yeah, like gaming was really the only thing that would use it.
Rym: Yep, and That like it took me a while to even get used to having a third button.
Rym: Well, I started with the third button, yeah, I started with two buttons.
Scott: Well, I mean I started with one button really on the Mac 512 whatever Yep, then I went to two, but then I went to three but then yeah one.
Rym: But then eventually the third button got replaced by a scroll wheel that you could also click in.
Rym: Yep, and that became the third button.
Scott: I was always annoyed with the scroll wheel in the early days because clicking it in would often scroll but nowadays that is mostly fixed on better mice.
Rym: Yeah nowadays clicking in is actual third click.
Rym: Yes, and Then we had the proliferation of more buttons and nonsense on mice most of which are literally useless for anything but gaming.
Rym: yep and Here we are.
Rym: I get a lot of opinions about mice now.
Scott: The other thing that changed was they found a way to get rid of the ball by inventing the optical mouse.
Rym: well So I there was an interim step where there were mice that had balls in them But instead of the rollers tracking the movement they had like a little sensor that would track the rolling of the ball.
Scott: That is actually how a lot of scroll wheels these days work like the scroll wheel on my mouse is Actually an optical sensor aimed at the scroll wheel.
Scott: It's not physically clicking anything inside.
Scott: Yep, right And it works fine most of the time.
Scott: But yeah The optical mouse.
Scott: the idea behind the optical mouse was that you would have Basically like a light similar to the lights that they used to scan QR codes at the grocery store Yep And it would just sort of scan the table underneath the mouse Right and when you move the mouse well the whatever it was scanning would move Obviously in relation and basically just by look like if I'm looking outside the window of a train And I see trees moving to the left I know that I'm moving to the right assuming the train is doing the moving and not the trees.
Scott: Yeah, so if you're a mouse you can assume the table is not doing the moving.
Scott: so if you see the table moving up You know that the mouse is moving down right.
Scott: you don't need like a full-on camera to see this.
Scott: you just need a really rudimentary optical system.
Scott: and over time those optical systems became better and better and better and better and better.
Scott: and now optical mice work perfectly on way more Surfaces.
Scott: mice with the ball had a lot of problem on different surfaces And you know where the ball wouldn't roll very nicely or get stuck or whatever, but also that's why you needed mouse pads.
Scott: but the Optical mice also had in the early days a lot of issues on different surfaces glass surfaces And also early mice.
Rym: in that day they either they use lasers or LEDs or whatever.
Rym: But they had a bright usually red light coming out of them.
Rym: to make it work.
Scott: They still kind of have a light coming out the bottom.
Scott: all modern mice or modern mice know modern mice Can you pick them up are a lot better about turning the light off immediately.
Rym: no modern mice used non-visible light, too.
Scott: That's occasionally true.
Rym: That's most mice like.
Scott: I see a lot of mice with lights coming out the back usually shitty mice.
Scott: No, my arm.
Scott: I think them up and light goes away right away.
Rym: most mice I've owned for a long time don't have any visible light coming out of the bottom.
Scott: You sure it's not just turning off real fast.
Rym: I'm a hundred percent sure.
Scott: because like for example this Apple watch, right?
Scott: You think oh, it's like.
Scott: you know It's not nothing that comes out of the bottom.
Scott: if you trick it you can see there's like a bright green light coming out the bottom.
Rym: Well, cuz that's the only way it's like your heart rate Rob.
Scott: I'm saying you like it does you can't?
Scott: it's so smart about turning it off lightning.
Rym: I see that green light all the time on people's wrists.
Scott: It will only come out if you if you trick it into coming out.
Rym: So there was an error where I remember.
Rym: people kept making 3d mice that you hold and they were garbage.
Rym: They never worked.
Scott: Well, I saw gimmicks in CompUSA in the 90s.
Scott: Yeah, like you put your finger on it and it would like sense like your electrical Signals in your body and you control the mouse with your mind or whatever as a bunch of bullshit.
Scott: Yeah, it didn't work for shit.
Rym: But the word all the 3d like free space mice.
Rym: when people trying to reinvent just the same problem that monitors that were touchscreens had Was that it is actually very inefficient and fatiguing to be waving your arm around all the time Arm on the desk reading it's relaxed.
Rym: Yeah, if you're using a mouse correctly kind of like using a keyboard correctly, you're not moving around that much.
Rym: It's a very efficient way to interface with a computer.
Scott: that should be.
Scott: crank that sensitivity up.
Rym: Yeah and I'm actually like.
Rym: I think the mouse will persist in workstations for the lifetime of anyone listening to GeekNights like.
Rym: it's a hyper efficient way to interact with computers.
Rym: Life times too long for our lives short of a brain implant.
Rym: What's gonna replace the mouse brain implant?
Rym: Yeah short of a brain implant.
Rym: And we are making in.
Scott: I just don't want to rule out brain implant in my lifetime.
Rym: Yeah, I'm hoping for brain implant.
Rym: Yeah, so the alternative to the mouse like the only real alternative to what a mouse does specifically is the trackball.
Rym: Some people use trackballs for accessibility reasons like trackballs like depending like depending on a wrist mobility thumb mobility arm mobility.
Rym: trackball is a Functional equivalent to a mouse and it's a matter of preference taste and like ability to use.
Scott: also You know, there are certain times you need to have a trackball like let's say you want to play golden tea.
Rym: Yeah, let's say you want to play my part You'll play centipede our friend can at RIT and when I was in high school Marvel Madness Can.
Rym: the one thing that I remember the most about him is that he was crazy good.
Rym: FPS is like we played all that like.
Rym: that was what we did in high school.
Rym: He was a sniper mostly he was really good at it.
Rym: dude played a sniper in mega TF and weapons factory with a Fucking trackball instead of a mind.
Scott: now there was.
Scott: originally there were the big trackballs Atari style, right?
Scott: But there were also these other trackballs.
Scott: You can still get these where it's.
Scott: it's shaped like a mouse But you don't move the mouse.
Scott: Yeah dead in the thumb zone is a little red ball about.
Scott: it's maybe smaller than ping-pong ball But I sit like a rose and you just move that with your thumb and then you the rest of the mouse is the same.
Scott: You just don't move the mouse around.
Scott: This is really good for people with a lot of hand mobility But not a lot of arm mobility Right because even if you use the big trackball, you still gotta have to move your arm right to get going.
Scott: But with just the thumb ball you can just keep rest your hand there and move your fingers only.
Scott: What do you know in high school?
Rym: what I always wanted me and Ken both one and we talked about it a lot Was I always wanted a mouse that had a normal mouse with like the the bottom movement and everything But it also where the thumb goes had a trackball.
Scott: sure it exists somewhere.
Rym: Yeah Cuz I want.
Rym: my dream was to use the mouse for like broad strokes movement and FPS and use the wheel for like really fine.
Scott: If you plug two mice into a computer.
Scott: it just works.
Scott: it just works and they'll compete against each other.
Scott: But if you were say using them cooperatively, right they would and you could even have them at different sensitivities.
Scott: They would work cooperatively both influencing the mouse movement.
Scott: They're all relative movement not absolute.
Scott: So you absolutely could you know move the big mouse and then move little mouse totally what I found the ps2 spec, so By two is just X movement.
Rym: by three is just Y movement.
Rym: Yeah, and by one has it a bite.
Scott: They would.
Rym: I don't want to get into the details of ps2 Yeah, but it old signaling protocols are stuff that you don't need to know how it works.
Rym: Good fucking God You can one one measure.
Scott: how many buttons did it support?
Scott: There's a bite.
Scott: you have a whole bite.
Rym: So bite two is just X movement.
Rym: by three is just Y movement.
Rym: bite one.
Rym: Bit zero is left button.
Rym: So binary on or off bit one is right button.
Rym: bit two is middle button.
Rym: Bit three is just a one.
Rym: all the time I guess.
Rym: okay, and then bits four five six and seven are something to do with the signs of the X&Y movement.
Rym: So they're all.
Rym: they're doing more.
Rym: They're overloading the output of bit two bites two and three into by one point.
Scott: is you had left middle and right?
Rym: Three bites you can sample to figure out what the fuck the mouse is doing.
Scott: right three bites.
Scott: But if you have three bits for the buttons, that's actually two.
Scott: to the it's two for six.
Scott: You can actually have six button.
Rym: Well, you could but here's the problem.
Rym: bit zero is either one if it's no no eight button.
Rym: one Bit zero way returns a one if the button is pressed and a zero if it is currently not press.
Scott: Yeah, you can just change, you know, you just write your software to interpret that differently.
Rym: Yeah Sounds like a pain in the ass.
Scott: Yeah, you could have eight button mouse with that.
Scott: Because eight different comedy if you wrote a special custom driver that nothing would support different combinations of the three mouse buttons.
Scott: so if Somebody could like push buttons one and three at the same time to trigger button for the problem is what I don't remember is the details Of like how the sampling works.
Rym: that might not work for practical reasons.
Rym: Anyway, cuz this is some old shit here.
Scott: Yeah, there's six pins with regardless there isn't any room for the analog sort of analog miss of the scroll wheel.
Rym: Yeah, like USB came and changed everything when it came to mice.
Rym: now, you can have a hundred fucking buttons.
Scott: I remember lots of really stupid mice coming out in the MMO days.
Scott: I'm sure someone is gonna tell me they were actually useful for MMOs, but I find that hard to believe.
Scott: I still feel like never not having played in those MMOs.
Scott: I still feel like regular mouse plus keyboard.
Scott: You know, there were mice I saw.
Scott: they were so dumb.
Scott: They had like a whole calculator worth of buttons in the thumb area.
Scott: all these tiny.
Rym: but what I would rather That is a custom keyboard with like custom keys for all that nonsense.
Rym: not to put them on the mouse.
Rym: Yeah, just have a giant keyboard like a piano of options.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Yep, but we ain't talking about that.
Rym: We're talking about mice can't talk about keyboards.
Rym: That's the scope creep here.
Scott: So if you look at modern mice They're all pretty much the same except it for they're not Apple mice.
Scott: They're all magic or whatever It's just.
Rym: do you want a mouse that has a bunch of buttons for gaming an optical sensor?
Scott: It's got a wire or not?
Scott: It's got two buttons and then a scroll wheel in the middle.
Scott: that is also a third button.
Scott: Some of them have stupid thumb buttons.
Scott: some of them have an area to rest your thumb.
Scott: Some of them don't.
Scott: But the ones that really I don't understand are the ones that look like Rym said a pile of.
Rym: oh, dude I just learned something interesting in early mice.
Rym: for a long time like in the ps2 era Normal mouse if anything had a 3d component Forward went down and back went up like flight stick style what we would call inverted.
Rym: today.
Rym: all Drivers and early games if you said invert the mouse did the opposite of what invert does today?
Rym: Uh-huh.
Rym: So what we call inverted was the default until well after Apple decided to invert the scroll wheel also.
Rym: Yeah, cuz Apple always just makes the weirdest possible decision.
Rym: I mean Apple had one button mice long into the era where we had discovered that you can put more than one button on a Mouse.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Well, then they made a fancy ways to click more than one button.
Rym: Yeah instead of just having multiple buttons.
Rym: Yeah, so Another advance that came was the wireless mice which until kind of recently like in the last decade were garbage Like early wireless.
Scott: my aid maybe early wireless mice.
Rym: We're just like.
Rym: the batteries would run out really quick and they were like a laggy like you notice Visible lag when you use them.
Scott: Mmm, really that I probably lived in beacon when GeekNights started.
Scott: There were good wireless mice.
Scott: Yeah, now they're actually even better wireless mice.
Scott: It's to the point at which like if you're pro gaming It's like maybe there would be a tiny tiny and presentable difference if you're super pro gaming But you could actually probably get away with it for all.
Scott: but like the most elite counter-strike, whatever I would still use wired mortgage because they'll use wired for many reasons.
Rym: one because you don't want to risk Interference.
Scott: Yeah, like you don't under is the battery running out while you're gaming.
Rym: Yep And that wire like.
Rym: I'm not walking away from my computer with the mouse.
Rym: It's not like I'm ever unplugging the mouse.
Rym: mouse and keyboard are plugged in tables that are hidden.
Scott: it is nice to have the wireless mouse because it is so comfy.
Scott: the wire never like tugs on you or Bumps into stuff on your desk, but that doesn't happen to me.
Scott: I'll put stuff on my desk and it gets on top of the wire.
Rym: See, I have a shelf for my keyboard and mouse underneath the rest of the desk So there's literally nothing my mouse could ever bump into the boys.
Scott: There are nice reasons to have a wireless mouse and you're not super pro gaming.
Scott: There's no reason really not to get the wireless mouse, but always gonna have a wired one is backup.
Scott: You never know.
Rym: Yep, I use wired mostly because I didn't mouse.
Scott: I got one at home.
Rym: I got wireless at work I got wired at work and everywhere.
Rym: cuz I just I don't want to ever think about Having to deal with wait is my mouse out of battery?
Scott: that's something that's really interesting.
Scott: I've noticed is co-workers of max most of them, right?
Scott: They always got these Apple wireless magic mice and they're constantly charging batteries and swapping batteries all the fucking time.
Scott: Yeah When I had a wireless the wire with a triple-a battery in it and like eight years later a wireless mouse that I have at Work has the original batteries.
Scott: I've had it for a fucking long at least a year and I've never had to change them.
Scott: Yep, I don't know what the problem is, I don't know Apple people I Apple people.
Rym: Yeah, so these days in terms of a mouse pretty much I just use like the Logitech whatever like I use a Logitech g502 which funnily enough.
Rym: I was not the razor blade one.
Rym: Yeah, I don't mind the razor blade.
Scott: Oh god Cut your hand.
Rym: Here's the thing when I want a mouse.
Rym: what I want is really good click action on my primary button.
Rym: Like if it doesn't feel good like I don't hear that like nice I got a feel tactile.
Scott: clicking on the scroll wheel Yeah, but no don't move scroll wheels I don't mind.
Rym: if you can put this like.
Rym: I can hit a button and my scroll wheel is smooth.
Scott: That's a nice feature.
Scott: I enjoy.
Rym: Yeah, cuz I use that like browsing the web.
Scott: Let's not be the only option.
Rym: Yeah, because when I'm playing Counter-Strike it is Weapon weapon weapon weapon.
Scott: Yeah, it has to be click click click discrete or I'm gonna go crazy.
Rym: That's right.
Rym: I need really good buttons.
Rym: Mm-hmm And I need a thumb shelf.
Rym: Like I'm addicted to the thumb shell.
Scott: I don't need thumb shell.
Rym: I really like the thumb shell Partly because I don't actually move my arm or wrist at all.
Rym: I pretty much just move the mouse with my fingers alone Mm-hmm.
Rym: So I like to rest my thumb on that shelf while I'm moving it around.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: And in terms of sensitivity I like my mouse.
Rym: to be.
Rym: my mouse even at work is Sensitive to the point that when a normal person sits down at my computer, they cannot use it.
Rym: They move the mouse and the cursors top corner bottom corner top corner bottom quarter and they don't know what to do and they walk Away, it's really funny.
Scott: Don't you have a sensitivity changing button on the mouse at home?
Rym: I do not.
Rym: at work I get like my boss at work has generic scroll real button button and that's it.
Rym: So I actually went to the registry and just crank the sensitivity all the way up.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, so I work.
Scott: I have a wireless mouse like I just said but before I had a different mouse that had like a scroll wheel issue where you would.
Scott: It was like fucked up and because of that I got angry.
Scott: so I didn't buy another one of those mice.
Scott: So at home and I brought my mouse from home to work Right because I was tired of having the wireless one at home with the gaming situation, right?
Scott: So I bought the good.
Scott: the mouse at work was busted.
Scott: It was flawed like manufacturing flaw.
Scott: So I brought the wireless one from home that I didn't want to use wireless at home anymore to work.
Scott: And then I bought.
Scott: since I was mad at Logitech for making broken mice I bought the default razor whatever.
Rym: so I had I used to have a steel series death adder Steel series doesn't.
Scott: razor is the death adder steel series.
Rym: Oh, yeah steel series was the side else.
Scott: Yeah something I don't fucking know.
Rym: Yeah, but that's dead.
Scott: I bought the default razor death adder for home and as a weird-looking shape It's not razor blade.
Scott: It's just sort of curved in the front and I didn't notice it and I was actually using it.
Scott: It's just fine.
Rym: Yeah, like the razor blade aesthetic when I'm using the mouse I don't notice so I'm fine with it.
Scott: the rate all the razor blade aesthetic.
Scott: I do notice.
Scott: How do you notice it?
Rym: I've used them at like demos and the only thing I can't stand is the mouse that has a big hump that like Fits into your hand like fully like I don't like my palm to touch the mouse ever.
Rym: my palm never touches a mouse.
Scott: I rest I'm like leaning.
Scott: I'm just you know, plop my hand.
Rym: I'm also up like this Like it's just fingers touching the mouse.
Scott: That's a lot of energy to hold your arm in there.
Rym: no, because the bottom I my wrist is touching the mouse pad and My hand your hand is like crook like this.
Rym: Yeah, my hands up like this the whole time.
Rym: Uh-huh resting on the mouse Uh-huh, actually pointed my for the live stream.
Rym: I just.
Rym: I just plop my arm down like plop I do but my palm does not.
Scott: my palm is a good inch over the mouse And it's only being used energy in your fingers or wrist to keep your palm up in there.
Rym: No, I don't because they're all just touching the mouse like arched.
Rym: So the only things touching the mouse are the tip of my thumb.
Scott: the trim just likes to be weird.
Rym: Oh, this is weird, this is how you hold this mouse.
Scott: no one else does that.
Rym: I feel like this is how anyone holds his mouth.
Rym: because this mouse you can't get your whole hand.
Scott: You're the only one who does it that way.
Rym: if I put my whole hand on it Then my fingers like sticking past the front of the mouse.
Scott: Different to be different.
Scott: No, this is just comfortable.
Rym: You're the one with the weird like front part of your mouse.
Rym: Your mouse has a weird front.
Scott: Yeah, the part you don't touch cuz it's so far away from.
Rym: why don't you touch it?
Rym: Why do you even have it then?
Rym: Why do you?
Rym: why did you get different mouse?
Scott: Because I don't touch that part.
Rym: Anyway my point is I pretty much only buy Logitech default mouse or razors Because all the other brands like SteelSeries.
Rym: like everyone who's made a special mouse I did.
Rym: They wore out like they were just like not that well made like they all wore out.
Rym: Meanwhile my piece of shit like cheap Logitech has lasted forever.
Scott: Microsoft is actually making a official surface mouse that is two buttons and a scroll wheel.
Scott: that seems really good If you don't care about gaming or whatever I mean when this thing finally dies cuz actually I did from playing overwatch.
Rym: I broke the scroll wheel.
Rym: Good job, but but I fixed it by shoving some paper in there to like.
Rym: basically I made I made a paper bushing And that has actually made the mouse wheel work fine.
Rym: Uh-huh, rather than replacing the mouse like you wouldn't unless you look in there and you see this bushing I made parents breaking his mouse by anyone, but I didn't buy a new one.
Rym: I'm still using the same shitty mouse.
Rym: Apparently I Repaired it.
Rym: cuz that's how I do.
Rym: I repair things if I can.
Rym: So, uh In terms of sensitivity though in FPS is I've actually made a big leap in the last couple years.
Rym: When I used to play FPS is I also forced myself to play an extremely high sensitivity.
Scott: Your pros have low sensitivity.
Rym: Yes I have since moved back to low sensitivity and I've actually moved further into.
Rym: I use the Sensitivity swapping features on modern mice.
Rym: So depending on the character.
Rym: I'm playing I the game I program to have different sensitivities and depending on what I'm doing.
Rym: I will swap between different sensitivity modes.
Scott: This is why it's good the gaming mice do, you know, they got rid of a lot of the other stupid buttons They used to have but they've kept the sensitivity changing button.
Scott: It's usually not below the scroll wheel.
Rym: So I got to below the Sensitivity mid game.
Rym: so below the scroll wheel I can swap between four different profiles of sensitivity.
Scott: You can fully configure if use the software.
Rym: then there's two buttons that I could bind to things.
Rym: But instead I bound to increase and decrease sensitivity just ad hoc.
Rym: and there's another button where if I hold it down with my thumb Just cuts my sensitivity down by a tenth Mm-hmm, that's the like.
Rym: I've really got a snipe and I hold it down and I just like track someone's head very carefully Hmm.
Scott: See if you want to see the very first mouse that was ever made you can see the mother of all demos.
Scott: I think we've talked about it in GeekNights before Perhaps thing of the day or maybe on its anniversary or something.
Scott: But you should go check.
Scott: if you haven't seen that you should check it out anyway.
Scott: But that's pretty much the first mouse.
Scott: effectively speaking I found actually the first mouse but it's effectively.
Rym: I found a picture here of the first wireless mouse from 1984.
Rym: Okay, which had two buttons.
Rym: take that Apple.
Rym: Yeah wireless and two buttons two years after I was born.
Scott: ever windows like 1.0 1984.
Rym: who even knows with the logitech metaphor Oh Logitech was around then.
Scott: Yeah, Logitech's no company.
Scott: Was it like infrared for its wireless?
Rym: I assume so.
Scott: infrared wasn't using Wi-Fi Or anything like that, so I had to be using infrared right?
Rym: Yeah, I guess you could use our effectively a remote control.
Rym: Yeah, everything wireless was that back then effectively.
Scott: It's like wireless.
Rym: Nintendo controllers were garbage.
Rym: I are back then.
Scott: Did you ever hold your Gameboy Pocket or color next to another Gameboy Pocket or color to give?
Scott: Pokemon presents to the other person and Pokemon gold and silver.
Rym: I never did that but I had a wireless SNES controller that you had to point at a thing the entire time or it broke.
Rym: Mmm, I got it at a garage sale.
Rym: It was a piece of shit.
Rym: Yep, I sold it at a different garage sale for more money than I paid for it.
Rym: Good job.
Rym: But so actually someone in the stream asked about what about those vertical form factor mice the handshake style?
Rym: Never see those.
Scott: I mean, that's just an idea for people who need it, but I don't see.
Rym: Those exist for one purpose.
Rym: if you have mobility problems or like carpal tunnel syndrome There's a reason you need it.
Scott: Then you need it if you don't need it.
Scott: That's just weird.
Rym: I feel like you would never want to use one of those unless you had a specific reason to write.
Rym: It's like nothing and for me like holding my hand like that is way harder and more stressful than using a normal mouse.
Scott: right weird things in the world exist because Someone has a weird case like they legitimately need that weird thing.
Scott: If you don't need the weird thing Don't be that weird.
Scott: Oh who just insists on using the weird thing or holding your mouse in a weird way like Rym?
Scott: Do things in a normal way like a normal person.
Rym: stream can decide.
Rym: I've been pointing the camera at how I use my mouse.
Rym: This is like the second half of this episode.
Rym: You can see exactly what I do.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: I don't think it's weird.
Rym: Oh Here is a picture of the first computer mouse.
Scott: Yeah, there it is.
Rym: It's got like a wood case.
Rym: Yep We should get that.
Rym: get it to work.
Scott: It's in a museum.
Rym: Yeah, we could make this.
Scott: Oh you want to make a replica?
Rym: You have to plug it into an Arduino.
Rym: I guess probably the easiest way to make it work.
Rym: with a model you do an Arduino in it.
Rym: Uh, it's big enough.
Rym: Anyway, so how about the mouse pad?
Scott: There was a time when mouse pads matter needed the mouse pad for the when you had the ball because you in if your table Was not good getting good traction with the ball, right?
Scott: Yep, and then you needed the mouse pad with the The optical sensor when the optical sensor was garbage.
Rym: But now like my mouse works fine on a completely uniform white surface like mice got real good.
Rym: The only reason I use a mouse pad is that it's more comfortable on my wrist to have like a soft surface there instead of just the table and It prevents the pads on the bottom of my mouse from wearing out as fast from scraping against a hard table.
Scott: Yep, the other thing with the the mouse pad actually stopped using the separate mouse pad.
Scott: But now I know I just use a play mat.
Scott: Yeah, I get a play mat that is designed for playing collectible card games.
Rym: That's what I got right here.
Scott: I get that I laid out a cover like my whole friggin table.
Scott: I'm shifted over to the right.
Scott: So half my keyboard is on it, but then there's a huge area for the mouse.
Rym: That is exactly what I do.
Rym: I'm done with mouse pad is a separate thing But I don't even use the huge area because the stream you can see I only have like a few inches of play because I Don't move my mouse that much.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: Like that's all I need.
Rym: Well, if you go low sensitivity in an FPS well when I'm playing an FPS I push this keyboard up and I pull out the smaller gaming keyboard because I like the cherry MX blues.
Rym: You don't want to play in a key boards.
Scott: Really?
Rym: You don't want to play an FPS with the cherry MX blues.
Rym: That could the heavy click that sucks for an FPS.
Rym: That's gonna cause problems.
Scott: Daddy, two keyboards daddy two keyboards.
Rym: I just I have a keyboard with the cherry Reds that are linear.
Rym: No click.
Rym: Okay, because they just they're just you touch him instantly take effect.
Scott: I mean, yes, the red is better for gaming than blue but having two keyboards really why not?
Rym: When I'm typing versus when I'm gaming and when I'm gaming it gives me another six inches because I don't need a numpad when I'm No, that's true.
Rym: Like what do you if I'm playing a game that needs a numpad?
Rym: It's not a game that needs cherry Reds.
Rym: I can use my regular keyboard.
Rym: if I'm playing like command and conquer using the regular keyboard that that other keyboard is only for FPS.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and brand.
Scott: Ok for the logos be sure to visit our website at front row crew dot-com for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Rym: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this particular episode of GeekNights are Craig Oliver Alan Joyce Heidi McNichol just like a dude guy.
Rym: kashar tavish in linky G Jennifer Hitchcock Chris mink if my steady calm Jay Vance scooter lonely Roberto Kingsley Shawn Yeager Nicholas brand now, mr Strong distraction for two one creations and there may be other secret names.
Rym: You do not even know Shervin von Horrell Rory Rochelle, Montanona Superboy sailor Vista Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan Perrin true open Lander Finn tread you Lily Tenebrae Sean Klein Chris Reimer Thomas Han.
Rym: and now I leave you with something that you probably wish I and you had forgotten.
Rym: Well, mr.
Rym: Burns had done it.
Rym: the power plant had won it with Roger Clemens clucking all the while.
Rym: Mike Socia's tragic illness made a smile While Wade Boggs lay unconscious on the barroom tile.
Rym: We're talking softball from Maine to San Diego talking softball Manningley and can say co Ken Griffey's grotesquely swollen jaw Steve Sachs and is running with the law.
Rym: We're talking Homer Ozzie and the straw.
Rym: We're talking softball from Maine to San Diego talking softball Mattingly and can say co Ken Griffey's grotesquely swollen jaw Steve Sachs and is running with the law.