Rym: It's Monday February 4th 2019.
Rym: I'm Rym and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We are talking about cheating mostly in school with technology.
Rym: Let's do this.
Scott: So get on the train to come home like you do and you know I barely notice.
Scott: but as I enter the train right across from me is some sort of panhandling gentleman Yeah, usually you notice it enough who I completely ignore and then and go about my business elsewhere in the train.
Rym: So no warning signs no like might be a stabbing hobo saying just saying I just ignored as usual.
Scott: I just noticed.
Scott: I didn't can't even tell you what it looked like.
Scott: I just noticed there was one.
Scott: and then At the next stop as they do they get off and go to the next car because you know You already panhandle the people in this car.
Scott: You gotta go get some fresh some years and you know to their credit.
Rym: in this case Waiting for the next stop is the right idea because a lot of people get seriously hurt trying to walk through the subway cars like Those doors.
Rym: Oh, yeah, that is way more dangerous than people realize.
Scott: people die going between the like.
Rym: I am a pretty you're like non risk-averse person.
Rym: I would not walk through those doors of a moving subway train.
Scott: No, anyway, so it goes in the next car to get the rubes in the next car.
Scott: No and another Panhandling gentleman enters who I wouldn't have noticed because I was already in headphone land elsewhere in the car.
Rym: Yep, you already assessed the situation of the train.
Rym: now, you're just headphone land.
Scott: like this gentleman was yelling Angrily and scarily Mmm-hmm.
Scott: So I'm like, well, that's definitely not the one that was just here.
Scott: That is the second one.
Scott: one got off and one got on huh?
Scott: How about that that huh?
Scott: You don't see that every day.
Scott: and then at the next stop that one got off And a third one got on.
Rym: so at this point is there a schedule.
Scott: I I was three four three three stops three panhandlers Okay.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Now I'm taking notice cuz this is unusual.
Rym: Yeah, cuz like one time a second mariachi band came on to the seven train when I was coming back from flushing But that was just awesome.
Scott: I was like what - yeah, this is unusual but not yet thing of the day worthy.
Scott: Yeah, okay, so that they get off and I don't remember there may have been a break of one stop, but At most one stop later.
Scott: Kid sound fruit snacks.
Scott: Haha fruit snack kid comes All right.
Rym: The only thing that could have made this better is if the next stop was showtime.
Rym: Hold on.
Rym: Oh
Scott: After fruit snacks kid There was another hobo who I would not have noticed and I'm using hobo now instead of panhandling gentleman because this person stank big time and Creepily was like on their knees when they found a location with enough room to be on their knees in the middle of the crowded train Near me so I could smell it but luckily they got
Rym: off
Scott: when they're when their time was done
Rym: interesting.
Scott: So that's already for panhandling people for begging people and a fruit snack.
Scott: and then of course, yes as it was foretold At 59th and legs it was showtime showtime.
Scott: I've never been on a train With that much annoying activity that is single train ride.
Rym: Not one of them was the best possible outcome, which is mariachi band?
Scott: No There was zero.
Scott: if there was a mariachi band I would have had a complete set and it would have been like the.
Scott: it would've been like jackpot.
Rym: at that moment Everyone on the train would have been like whoo money like at that point.
Rym: Gothamist would want to interview everyone on that train.
Scott: Yeah, I know all the all.
Scott: the windows and the train would open and like coins would start pouring.
Scott: Yeah, you know you won complete set.
Rym: now to be fair Like don't think that Scott?
Rym: not, you know living in New York You have to like for real harden your heart to the cruel realities of an evil world Because there's no way to live your life otherwise.
Rym: But at the same time you probably vote for Democrats.
Rym: so maybe we can address the root cause of this situation.
Rym: just saying So, uh in the news actually, so we were thinking about doing a show on Overclocking and Scott asked the question because he was like, oh, that's a better show than your idea We should have.
Scott: we probably did it before though.
Rym: Yeah, so I look and sure enough We're on such a goddamn schedule.
Rym: This happens more often than you'd think.
Rym: but Well, basically whenever we have an idea that feels like oh, yeah, I wonder we ever did a show on that.
Rym: That's a good idea.
Rym: Usually we've done it either.
Scott: Exactly one year ago exactly exactly one year ago is tech news roundup Yeah, by the way should be coming up in like a month.
Rym: Oh, thank Jesus.
Rym: Thanks Satan I can finally do the easiest possible Monday show like two or three Monday shows for now.
Scott: It'll be tech news, right?
Rym: I don't think you understand how I. all I do is pull away.
Scott: I know my memory could be wrong.
Scott: My memory is telling me March, but it could be May.
Rym: I feel like I feel like it's between like late March.
Rym: It starts with M.
Scott: Go check it.
Rym: Yeah stupid smarch weather.
Rym: But Scott was like overclocking and I searched and sure enough we did talk about overclocking Almost exactly ten years ago.
Scott: Not nothing new to say Monday, January 19th.
Rym: So ten years ago and like a couple weeks tonight on GeekNights.
Rym: We explain why overclocking is no longer practical.
Rym: That's still true though.
Rym: It once was.
Scott: that's also true.
Rym: Yep, like back in the day of the k7 Overclocking a 600 megahertz computer to an 800 megahertz computer.
Rym: That was a big goddamn deal.
Rym: That was a lot of performance.
Rym: It sure was but overclocking a 4.8 gigahertz computer to a 5.0 gigahertz computer doesn't do shit.
Rym: Nope Oh and in the news they are trying to take away Obama's Blackberry and an interview with an adware developer.
Rym: And our things of the day were reforming the FCC and something that's called freaky world war one photo which Doesn't go anywhere.
Rym: So there's no way to know what that picture was.
Scott: Maybe internet archive.
Rym: I will try.
Rym: I will try to find out what the for you.
Scott: If you really want things on the internet to not randomly disappear and to instead be stored in the Internet Archive Please go to archive org where you can make a monthly donation.
Rym: I will link to that.
Rym: So instead we're doing a show on cheating because I feel like what we said in 2009.
Scott: It's all Rym.
Scott: I got nothing.
Rym: Well, it's like I can update.
Rym: here is the update to the 2009 show Even though I have no idea what we said.
Rym: I'm just guessing the update is.
Rym: Overclocking is kind of automatic.
Rym: now if you just make your computer colder your chips will be faster.
Rym: if you have good chips and Doing anything more than that is great for a hobbyist, but as zero practical application whatsoever Mm-hmm, and I say zero including the idea that you might mind bitcoins.
Rym: So anyway, we're gonna get in the news because there's a big news.
Scott: Yeah, so check this out that I want to explain this in case people don't understand what happened in this news, right?
Scott: So Apple you might see.
Scott: news is like Apple pulled Facebook certificates and then pulled Google certificates and then gave them back Right.
Scott: So here's what happened, right if you want to make apps
Rym: for
Scott: iPhone Right, you can't just install them on iOS unless you do a whole bunch of crazy hacking bad stuff because it'd be hardware and saw And I an operating system are designed in such a way that will only run software That has been digitally signed and it must be digitally signed with
Rym: the root
Scott: iOS certificate which is a private key that Apple owns and you could never guess.
Scott: and if you could that would be the end of iOS security.
Rym: Now there's a lot of reasons why they do this.
Rym: I don't think we want to debate the like philosophical and moral and practical like reasons why people do.
Scott: They tried to do this on PCs and people were like, no Y'all won't be able to run any of my existing software or open source software.
Scott: That will never be signed.
Scott: I bought this computer.
Scott: I should be able to run whatever code I want on it But in making the brand new iPhone out of nothing they were able to enforce that from the start.
Scott: on OS X You'll see a lot of warnings.
Scott: That's like you're about to run software that hasn't been signed.
Scott: It's basically a way for them to be like make sure that this device will only run software That some authority has checked out that software to make sure it's cool Which you know, we talked about that in the past.
Scott: Yeah, but regardless the system is in place in iOS.
Scott: You can't by default or without great effort illegal, perhaps illegal definitely hacking Unofficial efforts, yeah run software that has not been approved by Apple on an iOS device, right?
Scott: So if you want to get your stuff in the App Store, right you have to get you know.
Scott: Make an Apple developer account.
Scott: you get some keys then they like sign your key with their key And then you can use those keys that you got, you know that have been signed by Apple.
Scott: So it's like Apple get you make a key.
Scott: It's sort of like the way you do SSL on your website.
Scott: You make a secure private public key pair then Apple approves your key with their key and now iOS will run the software that you sign with your key.
Scott: But you can only with that software that you sign with your own key run it like, you know for development purposes.
Scott: Right, like I'm making the software.
Scott: I need to be able to edit code run on my iPhone right now.
Scott: Yep, just like every time I change a line of code send it to Apple.
Scott: Or you know, I need to test myself or I got a bunch of testers coming in like 20 people at my company.
Scott: They're all gonna test the software.
Scott: I had to distribute copies to everyone with test flight, which is the official.
Scott: It wasn't an Apple thing originally, but Apple bought it and made it official because it was the best Way to distribute your software to testers.
Scott: sometimes people, you know Well, like like I was do using some netrunner tournament software and I would get faster updates like beta updates because the person with their key Gave me in a in on their test flight.
Scott: So I was getting the you know, the software that they were signing.
Scott: right but to actually get you're in the App Store You got to sign it then send it to the App Store where Apple will guess like approve it even again.
Scott: So we can.
Rym: I think we could actually even do a show on like code signing Instead of a show on cheating.
Rym: Not right now.
Rym: I don't know about right now, but okay I got.
Rym: I don't have enough to say.
Rym: I gotta think about it right regardless.
Scott: Right you you can't run software on iOS unless Apple's private key that you can never guess has in some Directly or indirectly been used to sign that software.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So even big companies like Facebook and Google Are getting their keys to make their.
Scott: you know iOS apps have.
Scott: Apple is like approving and signing keys So that Facebook and Google can make and develop and run iOS apps.
Scott: What happened is is that there's like an agreement you make with Apple, right?
Scott: Like there's a you know terms of service developer agreement developer account that you pay money for.
Rym: I won't use this to make malware that bricks phones.
Rym: I won't give this.
Rym: I won't sign shit for other people.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: it's like yeah.
Scott: I agree that I'm not going to like
Rym: sign
Scott: a thousand copies of software and sell it in some other shop and avoid the App Store, I'm not gonna use this to make shady ass software that does certain things You know to make softer that sort of does, you know that I wouldn't get away with in the app.
Rym: Yeah, right and that dot that thing probably has a line that says out We reserve the right to revoke your certificate at any time for any reason, right?
Scott: Yeah, so what Facebook was doing at least was they had a program where they paid you money Cash money and then you would use test flight or equivalent to run software that did not get approved into the App Store But was signed with Facebook's like developer key.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: No, this this suffers.
Rym: bad fucking news.
Rym: There's other news about that.
Scott: and everything you do is like.
Scott: they were telling you it was like a VPN But really just spying and everything your phone did.
Scott: Yeah, really all your traffic.
Rym: It's a whole.
Rym: there's a whole Like.
Scott: it was basically hey pay us we'll pay you money to give us even more of your data like literally all of it from your phone and You'll have to run this software that Apple won't approve but we can get it to run on your iPhone by using these keys.
Scott: And then as soon as Apple found out about this, they're like, hey you're violating your agreement We will just revoke your keys.
Scott: So now once they revoke the key what happens is basically all iOS devices because they get the new updates.
Scott: Do you know - what's you know - the - the you know key database or whatever which keys are approved and not approved?
Scott: Yeah, right Now reject those keys.
Scott: and no no iOS devices will run those softwares.
Scott: It will still.
Scott: it will still run the official Facebook app from the App Store because that key wasn't revoked, right?
Scott: It was the developer key.
Scott: So basically everyone at Facebook who is say having to work on iOS software couldn't work Any apps that Facebook made that were like for internal Facebook use only up for iOS.
Scott: all of those Immediately stopped working on all.
Scott: that is the part that was the bigger Impact let's say to So Google was also caught doing some shady biz and got similarly temporarily revoked.
Scott: So for example, Google had like internal only iOS apps for like doing Google stuff like, you know The only Google employee like.
Rym: here's an example.
Rym: I work for a big company.
Rym: Maybe we need an internal app on iPhone.
Rym: So anyways, an iPhone can like reserve conference rooms.
Scott: Yep, or like look up where someone's desk is Regular old App Store would use these keys to make apps that don't go in the App Store but are for their employees or for development and basically all iOS things at Google and Facebook just Refused.
Scott: you couldn't open those apps anymore or they got deleted or whatever.
Rym: Props to Apple for sticking to their guns and using the revocation Appropriately.
Scott: the cynic would say props Apple for wielding or technological power and the unbeatable power of encryption Over your competitors, but also props because the two cases they did it for seem pretty justified.
Rym: Oh, yeah, like.
Rym: here's an app that spies on kids like okay pay money to kids to spy on them.
Rym: apples like no Yeah, so I believe they I haven't read all the fun.
Scott: I think the main takeaway really is also behold the power of real encryption.
Rym: Yeah You can't just crack it.
Scott: Apple Google and Facebook We're just at the mercy because of a single file.
Scott: and if that single file got out into the world Anyone who had that file could run could do anything to any iOS device like basically make it run any software They wanted.
Scott: yeah, but would have to use that power to make every iOS device that wasn't already compromised reject all existing software Yup and start signing a new one.
Scott: sign every step in the whole App Store with their new key.
Scott: I'll just have a number.
Scott: It's just a number.
Scott: if someone figured out that number the havoc that would be reeked.
Rym: and this is the exact same Technology.
Scott: without that number you are powerless before the person who has that number.
Scott: they are god of iOS.
Rym: This is the same technology that if you go to your bank's website the web browser knows that your bank Yep, because that bank knows the number and no one else does yep.
Rym: So in some other news Two numbers, maybe.
Rym: yeah prime numbers related to big ones related to big numbers.
Rym: So bitcoins a scam.
Rym: just got to make sure all kinds of scam.
Rym: Yeah bitcoins a scam in my personal opinion.
Scott: Yeah, the ones I sort when I get home you and your fiat currency.
Scott: So there's a story here only kind of coin I can spend in exchange for so sandwich.
Scott: That is the only coin that man.
Rym: I take this story with a grain of salt because the king's tender I'm not implying anything.
Rym: I'm not.
Rym: I'm not Saying that I have knowledge about this situation.
Rym: I'm not trying attempting to defame anyone Or libel anyone.
Rym: I don't know any details beyond the headline But there's a story here where I my gut feeling says there are one of two things that happened.
Rym: thing one is Person legit died and company was stupid and now they're fucked.
Scott: also relating to keys.
Rym: Yeah or Option to Person may or may not have died but story is designed to hide.
Rym: Do you think there is a fake death either a fake death or a real death that was used as an excuse?
Scott: It is a fake death.
Scott: There's person is now changed from Moron possibly evil moron to genius hero.
Rym: But in either in either one of those scenarios in case two the reason for it would be and again I'm not liable or defaming anyone.
Rym: This is pure speculation to hide the fact that they lost 137 million dollars worth of bitcoins.
Rym: Yep I might be some other coin.
Rym: I don't know or care but basically there's a great legit crypto exchange in Canada that Said it lost a hundred and thirty seven million dollars of its customers assets when its founder died and Its founder was the only human being who knew it was only in his brain.
Rym: It wasn't written down anywhere the password to decrypt the offline wallet that stored most of the money.
Rym: Yeah, so and because bitcoins and coins like them are basically Encryption and I'm waving my hands because I don't want to go through the whole what is blockchain?
Rym: again?
Rym: It's basically a bunch of magic numbers where you need another magic number to find out what those numbers are.
Rym: and because no Human being knows the magic number one The all those bitcoins are just gone.
Scott: if you could guess that magic number Why would you?
Scott: you could just guess the with the key to all iOS devices?
Scott: Which would be even more valuable than the hundred whatever million dollars that are in that Bitcoin.
Scott: Yeah
Rym: so basically supposedly the exchange kept a bunch of like a reasonable lot of money in a hot wallet like a wallet that had the Transactions in it to do like customers are buying selling their stupid coins But they stored most of the money they own which makes sense.
Rym: Like this is how you would do it in an offline like secure encrypted backup.
Rym: So they only go in there if they got to like.
Rym: bring more coins Into the hot wallet because they're selling more than they're buying like that kind of thing.
Rym: that makes sense.
Rym: But supposedly that there's like the encryption for that was just known by one person who just died suddenly and mysteriously I think in India.
Rym: and Also, they got his laptop and apparently his laptop is also encrypted.
Rym: No one knows the password to that Data encryption.
Rym: people were like, yep, it's encrypted.
Rym: You're fucked.
Rym: Someone's got to figure out the password.
Rym: So once again legit encryption is not beatable by most reasonable means.
Rym: This is why backdoors into encryption are such a bad idea.
Rym: So the story here is either company had a Terrible disaster recovery plan none and a terrible business continuity plan none.
Rym: or company straight-up scammed Possibly via murder or possibly by via taking advantage of someone's untimely death possibly by faking someone's death.
Scott: Hopefully the third one.
Rym: Every one's really the best outside of the death because death is tragic.
Rym: But outside of that all the other aspects of this are pretty funny because this I'm saying hopefully the third one because that means no One died.
Scott: Yes means a bunch of Bitcoin morons got scammed.
Rym: That's the greatest because all positives on the fake death story It's a I feel like every time the court the stupid crypto coins come up the story is the same and the story is always Decrypt that laptop.
Scott: It says haha.
Scott: I got your coins bitches.
Rym: Yeah But it's like everyone involved in crypto currencies, it's just like I guess no step-by-step learning why financial regulations exist.
Scott: I just I just made myself sad.
Scott: The person probably is dead because if they ran away with the coins People you have to cut.
Scott: no because it's Bitcoin or because it's a bit of blockchain.
Scott: Yeah, people would see those coins being sold true.
Scott: People would know they know which coins they are.
Scott: So if someone ran away with them in a fake death They would have to sell them and they would see on the exchange those coins being unless they.
Scott: if you see the coins being sold That means they did.
Rym: unless The death fake or not was facilitated by a third party to cover up massive fraud and other theft Like maybe the exchange didn't actually
Scott: have them you would slap to see those coins being sold
Rym: Unless there aren't any coins
Scott: But you could see on the existing chain those coins going into that wallet.
Rym: possibly I don't know how they set it up because they have a hot wall in the gold wallet.
Rym: We have no idea how they did their stupid transactions and I didn't even read this article to see what coin it is Because I don't care.
Rym: Okay, the moral is don't use these crypto currencies don't mess around with bullshit.
Rym: So, I guess in one other news making fun of crypto currencies even further there's an article here pointing out that as of now the caught the average cost of Mining one Bitcoin is like four grand.
Rym: the value of one Bitcoin is Less than four grand.
Scott: so it is not possible to mine bitcoins for money anymore unless you had like you decrease the cost somehow by like Stealing GPUs from people.
Rym: That's it.
Scott: Unless you're crooked or using like solar panels Unless you're crooked.
Rym: There are only two Legitimate and I'm making finger quotes ways to mine bitcoins based on this information.
Rym: My method number one is you honestly believe and my soul is laughing at this that the bitcoins you might now will be worth More money later.
Scott: So you're rude making someone else money.
Rym: Yep, or You are stealing that electricity somehow Either via corruption or whatever.
Scott: Oh steal it from your neighbor.
Rym: Yep, maybe get a shady deal with like a Chinese.
Scott: Hey, my Con Edison bill is like 400 a month and someone told me that's not normal and I'm like hell.
Scott: no, that's not normal Yeah, someone was like, yeah, I had that problem.
Scott: It was because there was an illegal studio apartment underneath my apartment and I was getting out put on their bill.
Scott: Yeah so that's the kind of shit they have it in New York.
Rym: when I moved out of an apartment a long long time ago the place I moved out of I shut down the Con Edison but they did some shenanigans and got it turned back on and I kept Getting billed for the electricity that department that apartment used for like three months.
Scott: I wonder if there's a way I can like go into the into the building the wall and Trick the meters in the building to like give half my kilowatt hours to my neighbor.
Rym: there is a long and storied history of people messing with those meters with varying levels of success.
Rym: I Know more about that than you'd think because I had a. there was a friend of a friend Who's dead?
Rym: I knew in high school who fucking did that for a living.
Rym: he would come and He would go to.
Rym: he would literally in the suburbs like go to your house and you have him some cash and he'd fuck around With your meter and your electric bill would go way down.
Rym: and it was super goddamn illegal.
Scott: Of course.
Scott: It's super illegal.
Scott: This seems illegal.
Rym: the same dude also sold Satellite decryptors.
Scott: Yeah, this dude basically dude also had a boss named Tony.
Rym: Uh, no, that was a different dude There was.
Rym: this guy was not mob connected.
Rym: This guy was just like low-key local shady like local shady handyman who will run the extension cord to the neighbor's house effectively.
Rym: He would also do unlicensed electrical work Like you could pay him to fix.
Scott: When you sell the house you like Electricity cost half in his house.
Rym: Yeah Maybe winking an odd winks is good of an audio blind bad a so you mean while you're selling the house to someone from power Company.
Rym: so this article basically goes on to say that the only people who can really mind Bitcoin profitably right now are Chinese miners.
Rym: why we're getting subsidized and or corruptly cheap electricity Via corruption.
Scott: Well, someone's paying for that still even if like the power plant is paying.
Rym: You know who's paying for it earth and the Chinese people.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Yeah, someone's paying for it via corruption.
Scott: But Chinese Bitcoin miners are also Chinese people.
Rym: Yeah other Chinese people One person is on.
Rym: a large number of Chinese people are being defrauded.
Rym: So a smaller number of Chinese people can mind bitcoins and sell them to rubes in the United States is my guess.
Rym: this article has more about it, but the Coins are dumb.
Rym: Stay away from these coins because it's time for things Of the day.
Rym: What do you got?
Scott: So, you know Fonts for computers.
Scott: They're just a bunch of pictures, right?
Scott: We've all used a wing ding.
Scott: You know the letter a could be a smiley face.
Rym: It's a little more complicated than that.
Scott: But yeah You get the idea a font could be anything doesn't have to actually look.
Scott: the letter a doesn't got to look like the letter A. you make it look like whatever the hell you want.
Scott: Yeah, so And more, you know in recent years We've made it possible to actually like get fonts and web browsers that aren't just aerial and courier.
Scott: Yep So someone made this pretty cool website.
Scott: They made a font and in this font every letter of the alphabet is a picture of a tree But not just a picture of a tree a picture of a New York tree.
Rym: They're really good pictures.
Scott: Yeah, because you know different parts of the world.
Scott: you got different species of trees birds plants, right?
Scott: So there are trees that live in New York, I guess I assume these are maybe like 26 most common New York trees.
Scott: So They made a little picture of each New York tree and also a big version for capital capital And they assign them to the 26 letters of the alphabet and you type in this box and you can see a whole bunch of New York trees.
Scott: It's pretty good fun.
Scott: It's pretty cool.
Scott: Like artsy thing that you could put in a museum I think is a little exhibit me.
Rym: I like it.
Scott: I like it.
Rym: So last night while we were watching literally the most boring Super Bowl I've ever seen in my life It was the worst Super Bowl ratings in ten years.
Rym: I think there were exactly three plays that occurred Really, maybe among the worst halftime.
Rym: I think it was the lowest scoring Super Bowl in history.
Scott: No, no, I think it was these.
Scott: no, there were definitely lower ones like Super Bowl 7.
Scott: Maybe I think maybe lower.
Rym: It was the lowest scoring first half of a Super Bowl.
Rym: I'm pretty sure maybe probably.
Rym: uh, it was boring.
Rym: But toward the end of it I mentioned casually to the room that magenta doesn't exist.
Rym: And of course that started a giant shitstorm because no one believed me.
Rym: So here's the video, berries part three.
Rym: So to head this off.
Rym: This is a video that will explain to you a very fascinating phenomenon where There are colors.
Rym: and when you think of a color, what is the color?
Rym: A color is a particular frequency of light, right?
Rym: Yep So that is every color in the rainbow has a particular frequency that'll make that color appear.
Rym: And what you what a human would see isn't that frequency?
Rym: so much as the fact that we have three types of structures in our eye That will respond- Rods, cones, and the other ones.
Rym: Well, no three kinds of cones plus rods.
Rym: Okay And these three kinds of cones will detect different sets of frequencies and our brain Looks at the output of these three plus the output of the cones or the rods For brightness and figures out what color we should think we see.
Scott: Right, they're sensitive to frequencies of photons.
Scott: So they get stimulated and then the stimulation goes through nerves and then your brain decides well that stimulation equals this.
Rym: Yep Now there are a number of colors that are called extra spectral colors.
Rym: The video doesn't get into that much depth about this but like look at Wikipedia There's there's deep explanations.
Rym: These are colors.
Rym: where there is there is literally no frequency of photon that will make that color appear under any circumstances.
Rym: It does not appear in the rainbow.
Rym: There is no way to make that color come out of a prism.
Rym: Yeah, anyway, no single like magenta.
Rym: There's no goddamn such thing as magenta.
Scott: What's the frequency of magenta?
Scott: It's not.
Scott: it's not a frequency But what it is actually is it's just like red and blue sort of mixed together.
Scott: So some photons are at this frequency and some photons are at the other frequency and they're all packed close to each other and they hit your cones at the same time.
Scott: and So your brain is receiving like red blue red blue red blue red blue and your brain is like fuck it magenta.
Rym: So basically what's crazy is for spectral colors.
Rym: Our brain actually figures out the right color to show because if you mix two actual colors like you'll get a third color.
Rym: You know color theory stuff.
Rym: I hope you learn this in like middle school.
Rym: But our brain is really good at filling in and figuring this out like our brains model works really well.
Scott: Well, I mean if you think about it Like is white even a frequency?
Rym: No white is an extra spectral color.
Scott: White is just fucking all fucking crazy kinds of photons at all different wavelengths all at the same time.
Scott: the whole rainbow jammed together.
Scott: So a whole rainbow of photons hits your eye really fast all together and your brain just like oh my god There's way too many different frequencies.
Scott: Fuck it white.
Rym: So basically like the moral of this video is and it explains it in enough like detail at a sufficient level that pretty much Anyone can understand it.
Rym: magenta literally only exists in the human brain.
Rym: Yep through multiple layers of abstraction and it is Shocking how consistent our brain is.
Scott: Point out the thing.
Scott: I always point out which is well known obvious and pointless.
Scott: Well, you know I could look at some red and point at it and say that's red.
Scott: You look at it and say that's red but there we could be seeing completely different things.
Rym: Oh Scott I feel like we're.
Rym: it's it's high school and we're all laying Backs in the bleachers at night on the football field outside of the school.
Rym: Yeah, one kid is smoking a joint No one else is because that's the dumb kid.
Rym: That's right.
Rym: And we're all sitting there and we're having that exact conversation.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: And you know what animals they see.
Scott: if we could they see like, you know, we see some ultraviolet.
Scott: We can't even see that shit.
Scott: some animal looks at ultraviolet.
Scott: They see something.
Scott: We know that they can see ultraviolet because of science and we did experiments But what does it?
Scott: what do they see actually look like?
Scott: where the fuck we know?
Scott: So we just know that their eye responds to it.
Rym: The other thing is if you watch this video You should be able to figure out on your own how those magic glasses that let colorblind people see color work Like.
Rym: you can figure that out from the information you'll get from this.
Rym: coupled with a rudimentary Understanding of colorblindness This is just a really well done video.
Rym: Like.
Rym: they explained this in five minutes and it's a moderately complex topic and they lay all the foundations.
Rym: a really good video.
Rym: It's like I subscribe.
Scott: Why don't we just get like seven cones up in that way?
Rym: You know, there's some people who can.
Rym: actually they have a fourth type of cone.
Rym: They can see more colors than us.
Scott: I didn't know it was cuz they had a fourth type of cone.
Rym: Some of their cones respond different.
Rym: I forget the detail.
Rym: I don't actually know a lot about that safety cone misstated it but Theoretically we could replace our optic nerve with something that's way more sensitive or way more complicated.
Rym: Yeah, we it's just.
Rym: it's just our brain figuring stuff out based on frequencies that detects and photons that bounced off a shit.
Rym: So in the meta moment the book club book we still we've been too busy to read anything.
Rym: No, read a book says ribbon Scott.
Rym: I haven't read a book in a while.
Scott: Oh, no.
Rym: Hi What have I been reading?
Rym: I've been reading nonfiction and like manga.
Rym: Yeah Websites, so we're gonna read 2001 a space.
Scott: I'm gonna make an actual reminder right now because we have fucked up big time.
Scott: There is no running in from that fact.
Scott: Yeah, I'm going to add a reminder.
Scott: I'm doing it as I'm speaking right now.
Rym: But what I will say is that read the fucking book.
Rym: if you want to be an intelligent erudite person who knows things about things you should read books.
Rym: and While we have not yet done this particular GeekNights book club because I added it to my remember the milk thing Because reasons the GeekNights book club has been going for a long time since.
Scott: Despite that long time the number of books in the book club are depressingly low.
Rym: There are five pages of the archives.
Rym: So that's pretty good.
Rym: I'm gonna link to it.
Rym: I think the way you should handle the book club club until we start reading again is go to the archive of episodes We already did for a book Read the book and then listen to that episode if history is any indication.
Scott: as soon as we finish reading 2001 Rym will immediately read 2010. yeah And I will not because what happened?
Scott: we were satisfied with my watching of 20, so let's see we did.
Rym: the Shattered Earth trilogy you we both read the first book.
Rym: Yeah, I read a little bit the second one.
Rym: We met the hottest fictional character ever written yep, and then I immediately read the next two books because it's Evangelion and oh my god It's crazy good.
Rym: We decided to read the Wheel of Time because we had to know what the.
Scott: I decided to read the Wheel of Time and Rym.
Rym: I did go uh and we read the first book and you made it a little further.
Rym: you I read a Handful more.
Rym: you rate you got up to like hat like the beginning of the fourth book.
Scott: I want something like that.
Rym: I just kept soldiering on.
Rym: I finished the whole goddamn thing and I know the deal went around the whole wheel I did.
Rym: I know the full deal.
Rym: I know what I earned.
Rym: I know what's on the other side of the Wheel of Time It's uh you know what it is a bunch of stuff happens And then eventually it just stops happening because that has tower with snake bone people in it that you never find out about.
Rym: Yep, I know a lot of details about the bone tower snake people.
Rym: the only thing I cared about There's two kinds of those snake people.
Scott: I know yeah, that's part.
Scott: I read.
Rym: I know the whole deal.
Rym: I know about the cannons.
Rym: I know about.
Rym: I know every.
Rym: I know everything you can possibly know about the fucking Wheel of Time.
Rym: Scott will never know.
Scott: no I will not be regretting that on my grave should have read Wheel of Time.
Rym: I feel like should have read.
Rym: the Wheel of Time is really low on the list of life regrets.
Scott: That will not come to my mind.
Scott: however I will say what's.
Scott: the name is so clever and somehow manages to live longer than me And he said I'm and I'm in the hospital.
Scott: if my dad was like should write with a time The I'm out living you cuz I read.
Rym: really It gave me a gnosis.
Rym: the one thing I will say about that.
Rym: all that though is that I'm continuing in my policy of Never getting past the first book of any long-running series where it is.
Rym: I unless it is done, or the author is dead one of those two has to be true and That I think will serve me well, so I'm not when another Kingkiller book comes out If it ever comes out now that I not that I even really want to read it that much.
Rym: But I might just to find out the second one and then dispose them.
Rym: I would own out reading it.
Rym: I would only read the next one that comes out if he is dead after it is written.
Rym: I hope not.
Rym: he's a pretty cool guy or He says that's the last one.
Rym: He is a pretty cool guy.
Rym: I've seen him do a bunch of talks effects They have.
Rym: he is really funny in person.
Rym: Yeah Also, it sounds like his daughter's really cute mmm I guess good stories about trying to write and but anyway Those videos are probably on YouTube because those weren't like secret pegs dev talks.
Rym: They were just fun.
Rym: pegs dev talks go look for Patrick Rothfuss like pecs talks.
Rym: You might find something on YouTube.
Rym: Anyway, so I was thinking about this because I I've read this article a little while ago about how rich kids are cheating in school with Apple watches.
Scott: Major League Baseball people are cheating with Apple watches till they got caught and yeah They can't have Apple watches in the dugout anymore, but what's interesting is that poor kids?
Rym: It's not just that they like poor kids Probably like everyone with a lot of people know a cross-section of society would cheat if they could.
Rym: it's not just That rich kids can afford eye watches and poor kids can't.
Rym: it's that the kinds of rules that schools enforce Tend to be highly weighted towards socioeconomic status.
Rym: So they won't make the kids in a rich school take off their eye watches.
Rym: Yeah The rich school doesn't have a no Apple watch rule.
Rym: so the poor kids in the rich school don't have the eye watch and they just Get worse grades on average because the same percentage of them want to cheat.
Rym: But only the rich kids have the opportunity to cheat.
Rym: And simultaneously the poor schools will often enforce rules like can't have a goddamn cell phone in school.
Rym: Sorry kids no laptops.
Scott: and the New York schools.
Scott: They have a thing where I get I've seen these things.
Scott: It's like a little van.
Scott: It's like it's actually a private company.
Scott: There is and it'll sit outside the public school and kids on their way into school will go over to this van.
Scott: That is a privately owned business.
Scott: Give them money and their phone.
Scott: that that van will hold on to the and it's like it's like a coat check for phones.
Scott: And then when the kid comes out of school They bring their ticket and get their phone back because they're not allowed to have the phone in school now.
Rym: one.
Scott: that's bullshit.
Scott: I don't know if the rule has changed But I've these.
Scott: they were definitely a thing that existed.
Scott: if it doesn't still exist those Rules tend to own like.
Rym: where those rules exist or are enforced is highly dependent upon Socio-economic status of the area and the students.
Rym: Yep, and to make it even worse Access to technology is often an issue for kids with disabilities where some kids need some technology.
Rym: But only rich kids can get the doctor's note that says why they need the technology.
Rym: So poor kids who need the same technology, even if they have the technology can't actually get everything together.
Rym: So the school will let them use the technology.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So this is like a this space.
Rym: people don't talk about it a lot.
Rym: There's a lot going on in the like.
Rym: how kids use technology in school.
Scott: Balancing games only balancing school.
Scott: Yes replace game with school.
Scott: Nothing changes.
Rym: So Did you ever cheat with technology when you were in school in the era of TI calculators?
Scott: The only cheating I did is because I was angry that they were like you may not have programs on your calculator.
Rym: Oh, I was so funny.
Scott: Can you think they were like you?
Scott: can you first of all?
Scott: I was mad when they said no calculator at all.
Scott: That was bullshit.
Rym: So one only the only the normal kid classes had that rule the so-called accelerated classes.
Rym: You gotta have a calculator.
Rym: You can't be in the class.
Scott: Well, no there were.
Scott: I mean there.
Scott: I was like in a class where the calculator was required.
Scott: But for certain parts of the curriculum, it was like alright these tests no calculator and it was bullshit.
Scott: Anyway, I was like that's bullshit in my whole life.
Scott: I'm gonna have a calculator and a computer.
Scott: Yeah, why would I you know?
Scott: but anyway But when they did allow a calculator the teacher would be like, hey we're not gonna allow you to have any programs on your calculator.
Rym: because well programs usually men you someone had typed a bunch of Stuff into a text editor.
Scott: Well, no, but we had a whole.
Scott: I had.
Scott: we had Kate you had we had serial cables and all sorts Sophisticated.
Rym: Oh, yeah, so we passed.
Rym: get like that pong game around.
Scott: Oh, ti colic org was like my most visited website.
Scott: I still have all my stuff in my drawer at home.
Rym: I didn't have the cable to get the stuff onto my calculator directly.
Rym: So I had a copy from other people.
Scott: That's because the calculator came with the calculator to calculator cable.
Scott: I had these cereal and also I now have a USB to calculator cable.
Scott: But anyway We would use these to get software from ti colic org some of it written in basics I'm written in assembly loaded onto the calculator, but me and my friend together mostly my friend, but also not completely not me We wrote programs that would do things like factored polynomials Allow you to pass a test on factoring polynomials really easily.
Scott: Like if it was saying like if it was like ax plus ax squared plus BX plus C. Yeah, we had a program that we made where you just literally typed in a B and C and pressed enter, you know It's funny.
Rym: I wrote one for Calculus class because remember this was before even like the ti-89 were like no kids had like Fancier calculators that did more.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Well, we had.
Scott: most kids had ti-83 because that was required by school Had ti-86.
Rym: So ti-86 came out later.
Rym: We had so in our school normal kids had to have the ti-83 and the school would buy it for you if you couldn't afford It.
Rym: but if you're in the accelerated program, you had to get a ti-85.
Rym: See the 86 was too new.
Scott: It wasn't I was out but Like there was this.
Scott: basically the school just wanted everyone to have 83, right?
Scott: But it's like smart kids didn't buy 83 because they knew better.
Rym: the 85 was better in every possible way.
Rym: 86 had way more memory.
Scott: I saw nerds with 85s, but then when I went to the store I saw an 86 which is just an upgraded.
Scott: 85 is two.
Rym: more of the next is better.
Scott: And then there was the 89 that came later.
Rym: So in high school, there's one kid.
Rym: He was kind of rich and smarmy and then I got a bunch of stars not worth telling on this show.
Rym: Kid had a fucking ti-90.
Rym: Well, I saw kid which was older than the 86.
Scott: Well, there's like the 92 right just a big one.
Scott: The 90 was like the big one.
Scott: The 92 was the Upgraded 90.
Rym: I forget the difference But basically he had this thing and it would do some calculus.
Scott: and like 89 basically did this stuff.
Rym: the 90 did almost Yeah, but it would do like symbolic math which they five and 86 could not do by themselves.
Scott: There's a huge scam going on because those things still cost a fortune which is ridiculous.
Rym: But you can get an app on a phone that does it for free.
Scott: Yeah, it's like why?
Scott: But there's no reason for those z80 processors to cost that much money.
Scott: They should be like five hours.
Rym: So what's funny is I did the same thing.
Rym: I wrote some programs.
Rym: what based on the types of problems people would commonly get in like trig and Calc classes that would Do like symbolic math.
Rym: as long as the problem with it was in certain parameters It would do the math and it would even show the work.
Rym: so it would print out like here's the work to show.
Rym: here is the answer.
Rym: and I Got a talking to by the school.
Rym: But they couldn't actually punish me because it wasn't against the rules to write the write the program.
Rym: It was only against the rules for some other kid to use the program.
Rym: And of course my name was all over the fucking program.
Rym: It's like you could just have made this right y'all right at the start of the test.
Scott: Even if you had a blank calculator, you could start typing in the program.
Scott: Yep, right if you memorized it, but anyway.
Scott: So what we did is we had the program we wrote But they wanted us to like erase our calculators before the test.
Rym: We did that.
Rym: my school did that to get around the fact that I had distributed this program so widely.
Scott: So we there was another program we got from the internet that would basically Display on your calculator screen the message that said this calculator had just been reset.
Scott: Oh, yeah, it was light up those pixels the same pixels that would be lit up if you legit reset your calculator.
Scott: You'd show that to the teacher.
Scott: They'd say okay.
Scott: I believe you reset your calculator.
Rym: So the one we downloaded that we all shared was a little bit better than that.
Rym: You basically would hit a button when you wanted it to activate and it would go through Emotions like it was erasing and even show a progress bar Because there was that little like single pixel.
Scott: ours did the same thing the calculator did when you legit reset it not some fake.
Rym: Oh, no.
Rym: so when you did the reset there was this one pixel progress bar for like a second or two and then it would be like Erased.
Rym: it even emulated that.
Rym: That was the important part.
Scott: So I would let a teacher believe you reset the calculator You'd make that go away and then your calculator was not reset and you would have your program Yep, and then you would take you take the test finish it really fast then play Tetris.
Rym: So I even went one step further because I wrote another program that I used myself That would show like physics equations in detail and all this stuff, but I put copy protection in it.
Rym: So if anyone else messed with the code like remove my name from it or anything.
Rym: It looked like it still worked but it gave slightly wrong answers And some kids got busted around that.
Rym: But I used the hell out of these programs and I totally got away with it.
Rym: And actually my school ended up giving up on enforcing and they like basically because of the programs I wrote the school sort of changed his policy to.
Rym: you can use whatever programs are on the calculator and the test should just reflect a mastery of skills as opposed to just like knowing equations or like they Do in these days with their Apple watches.
Rym: So as best I can tell kids just like look things up on Wikipedia Like we've could say here's the thing in the old days you on Apple watch.
Rym: in the old days We could only use programs like this to quote-unquote cheat in math class.
Rym: Maybe physics class maybe certain science classes.
Rym: because I remember I was sitting in French class in 10th grade and this one kid Sean busted out his ti-85 and started like typing something.
Rym: and the teachers like What math are you doing in the French test?
Rym: bring your calculator up here right now?
Rym: And He'd legit like typed a French dictionary into a program.
Scott: He just like typed a bunch of shit The words that from that we learned in that section of the.
Rym: so he typed like the parts that were relevant.
Rym: like he basically he didn't Really understand the calculator.
Rym: so he wrote a program, but the program was not a program you could run.
Rym: He just typed a bunch of shed that he needed to remember.
Scott: so we could take the program editor basically using it as a text.
Rym: Yep Yeah, he got busted instantly.
Rym: so like I couldn't use the calculator unless I had a plausible reason to use the calculator.
Scott: Yeah, and it's not like I had a phone with a computer in it in 1990.
Rym: Whatever I mean in 1997 I had a cell phone that I brought to high school with me, and you could not install software on it.
Scott: It could make phone calls.
Rym: It did not have a screen of any kind.
Scott: the Motorola star tech I had Could display web pages in sort of a worse than links web browser at great expense to the phone plan.
Scott: that phone I did not have till 2001. yep.
Rym: So kids see.
Rym: it's interesting because kids can't really cheat with their phones Because it's really obvious if a kid pulls out a phone like.
Rym: that's an easy rule that a non Technologically savvy person can apply to a classroom of.
Rym: you can't pull your phone out of your pocket during the test.
Rym: Yep a Savvy kid could make something with vibration nonsense like chess masters.
Rym: No one's doing that in high school.
Rym: if you are I feel like you deserve it.
Rym: Yeah, like you won.
Rym: Good job.
Rym: You have a skill that you can apply to real life.
Rym: But the I watch I think presents a specific problem.
Rym: I don't think a lot of teachers understand the capabilities of smartwatches and It's really easy to kind of slyly look at a watch.
Scott: you got a multiple-choice test You can easily use.
Scott: Apple watch is just text with a friend.
Scott: the minimum cheating I would do is like we're not even gonna cheat I'm just gonna.
Scott: I'll do all the even questions.
Scott: Rym do all the odd ones.
Scott: It's a little choice.
Scott: I messaged you 1a.
Scott: you messaged me to be.
Scott: I messaged you 3c.
Scott: yeah, we get the test done in half the time and I trust Rym to do his half and he cuz he has to trust me To do my half.
Scott: Yeah, he's better do a good job.
Rym: Or you get someone who took the test earlier in the day and they start texting you answers from their tests that they already took.
Rym: Mm-hmm, they're like.
Rym: it's real easy to get away with.
Rym: and I feel like because it's a watch a lot of teachers Don't like.
Rym: they don't understand enough to be like, all right Everyone has to take their watches off during the test.
Rym: Yep, and coupled with everything else we talked about It seems like this is pretty rampant cheating now.
Rym: And I guess what I find philosophically different about this is that with older shittier technology The act of trying to cheat taught you as much as the cheating like it taught you as much as the class.
Scott: Yeah, it was.
Scott: I had to write a program.
Scott: Yeah to make my program that did some like simple symbolic I had to at least download and install a program onto it, which is like oh anyone can do that onto a TI calculator.
Rym: Yeah with what looks like a headphone cable like.
Rym: But I like I had to learn symbolic math enough to write a program in basically Q basic.
Rym: That could do it on my calculator.
Scott: type it all in my hand type it on a calculator Yep, not on a computer.
Rym: and I had to figure out how to hide the fact that this program existed from my teacher.
Rym: So I learned more doing that.
Rym: but nowadays with the watch situation like real easy to cheat Hard for teachers to deal with and I worry that it like I don't know what schools should do about this situation.
Scott: I know exactly what schools should do about the situation.
Scott: All right, you need to make tests Such that the test itself is invulnerable to cheating.
Rym: Yes, the idea that I would argue that in the modern world most tests in school You should have a computer with access to the full internet during the test.
Rym: Yep, and the test should be such that Just reading wiki if you go to Wikipedia learn the thing to answer the question.
Rym: That was the test you were able to get a correct answer while using the internet like that is.
Scott: I mean not just that but it's like just the kind of questions you got to ask.
Scott: Be things where it's like, okay.
Scott: Yeah, good luck.
Scott: You got the internet.
Scott: You're still not.
Scott: Let's see if you even with the internet.
Scott: Can you do this?
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Can you huh?
Scott: Can you?
Scott: it's not just like what was what?
Scott: Year, it's like, okay.
Scott: I looked it up.
Scott: I typed it in.
Scott: I get correct.
Scott: It's like no.
Scott: no, you can't ask a question like that.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: The question has to be like, alright, here is a here's a Complicated right word math problem, right?
Scott: Okay.
Scott: I got the whole internet.
Scott: Do you even know what math you need to do?
Rym: Yep, do you even?
Scott: can you even figure out what it's like?
Scott: Okay, you have the gods calculator.
Scott: Do you even know what to type into it?
Rym: And thus we need to also for the situations where it does make sense to deny technology We need pretty universe like standardized testing.
Rym: You need pretty standard like universally applicable ways to enforce that regardless of socio-economic status or act or act.
Scott: Access to said technology like a test where it's like, alright, we're asking you this question about the book.
Scott: You got a whole copy of the book.
Scott: Yep, and you hear kids a cliff notes, too.
Scott: Let's see you answer the this, you know quite complicated question.
Scott: So, you know the feelings of the characters in the book.
Scott: you're gonna read the whole book while you sit here.
Scott: We got a time constraint 10 minutes.
Scott: Let's go.
Rym: So I remember one time this was in 10th grader at the book.
Scott: It would be easy would take one minute.
Rym: in 10th grade I was an AP Western sieve and a lot of people in the class despite it being an AP class were I think the technical definition of this person is chuckle fuck.
Rym: so they they were like They were shitty at this class and there was trouble.
Rym: and the teacher was like, you know What everyone had trouble with the last test the test tomorrow.
Rym: God.
Rym: Guess what?
Rym: open book?
Rym: I'll let you use the book not changing the test at all.
Rym: open book.
Rym: Mm-hmm and Basically all the people who had been struggling struggled just as much.
Rym: they are still all failed.
Rym: Yeah the same way and he proved his point.
Scott: and there's also lots of other anti cheating techniques that teachers have used for a long time like Multiple-choice give everyone the same multiple-choice questions, but randomize the order.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: So when people are like looking at the other person's scan Tron, let's say go 5c It's like but there five was your ten.
Scott: You didn't know.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Everyone was random.
Rym: I think like it's pretty easy to prevent this kind of cheating.
Rym: You just need teachers who care and reasonably uniform ideas of how to approach it and it shouldn't involve such draconian things as Dropping your technology off at the door when you come in.
Rym: Yep, but we need somewhere.
Scott: These days are taking a lot of tests like on their computer or there's like, you know, they're going to some website.
Scott: They had to take the website, you know It's like yeah, they're doing a study from home like college course and all the tests are on the computer.
Scott: They got to do it at home and it's like as soon as they start tests like this timer happens.
Scott: It's like just hack that shit.
Scott: Yeah, it's like you can't lose some JavaScript.
Rym: The other side of this then I think we'll be out of time so we can wrap it up is the Cheating via like the heuristic detection of plagiarizing in tests.
Scott: Oh plagiarizing is totally like, you know, the other kinds of cheating are much more cool within like plagiarizing Especially.
Scott: that's like.
Scott: that's like we're not cuz we're not you.
Scott: those are you?
Scott: plagiarism usually comes into play Not on a test you take in a room But when you have a project yup, like make a program that does this or write an essay about this.
Scott: You can't cheat on that because you go home and work on it.
Scott: It's like you have the full internet.
Scott: You can talk to people you can you can.
Scott: basically you can stack overflow and ask for help.
Scott: It's like you can.
Scott: the whole resources of the world are available to you when it's a take-home project paper Thing.
Rym: so I have an anecdote.
Scott: Problem is plagiarism where you literally just you know You take someone else's and turn it in.
Scott: so and that is not cool.
Scott: when
Rym: I was in elementary school I remember this moment so clearly because another bullshit thing happened that day This is in third grade where a kid used the word expel as As like part of a little essay they wrote and the teacher was like there's no way you know that word and failed him that I was really mad because that kid was smart.
Rym: But in the same day we had all had to write an essay on Mahatma Gandhi.
Rym: Everyone had to write an essay the whole week on Mahatma Gandhi and then on Monday Everyone's gonna read their essay out loud.
Rym: So we just went down the road and the first kid read their essay.
Rym: Mm-hmm the second kid read their essay and it was very similar.
Rym: Like Very similar the first couple of sentences were different.
Rym: the last couple of sentences were different But the middle sounded like exactly the same.
Rym: Mm-hmm teacher didn't seem to notice anything like teacher didn't.
Rym: just don't faced it.
Rym: the third person starts reading the rest say and it's pretty much the same essay and They stumble over a word and some other.
Rym: a kid in the class provided the next word Looking at their own essay and the teacher was like everyone pass your essays forward.
Rym: Most of you are probably failing Mm-hmm, and then the next day the class got a lesson in.
Rym: why not to just copy the encyclopedia article on Mahatma Gandhi?
Rym: They had physically copied it by hand from the same encyclopedia because everyone had the same encyclopedia Except you except a couple of people.
Rym: No, I just actually wrote an essay.
Rym: I read the way I've read that encyclopedia and I wrote my own essay.
Rym: That mostly said that but I use different words.
Scott: I would have just watched Gandhi the movie and then written an essay.
Scott: Easier that way.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Rym: It's actually recorded at night in the patreon page runs for this episode GeekNights in order of you on when you give us on the continued basis with one Inception because of a thing that happened before.
Rym: I'm trying to read fast this time.
Rym: Craig Oliver Allen Joyce, Heidi McNichol just like a dude guys are topish in linky G Jennifer Hitchcock Chris midkiff my state II calm j-band scooter lonely Roberto Kingsley Sean Yeager Matthew Smith Nicholas Brando, mr Strong distraction for two one creations Chris Reimer and Thomas on Shervin
Scott: about her Rory
Rym: We're show Monta known as Superboy sailor Vista dodge like Jojo Joestar Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan parent or open letter Finn Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn.
Rym: We should be doing shows on a regular basis for a time to come.
Rym: now that we're back We skipped the show the other day because it was cold.
Rym: our next Wednesday show which is this week We're gonna talk about spider-man into the spider-verse because we saw it in the theater and it's good.
Rym: And now I leave you with.