Rym: It's Monday September 30th 2019 I'm Rym, I'm Scott and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We are back from a kind of long hiatus to bring you the global positioning system.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: So we uh We had a hiatus because of conventions and travel and all this stuff and then we tax.
Rym: that's already beginning of September And it's already October like tomorrow And this is already the season where traditionally we tend to have a lot of disruptions to GeekNights.
Rym: But as you may have heard or noticed we had a much more significant disruption for than usual Because Scott has a new fancy apartment.
Scott: I moved down the street.
Scott: It took a while.
Scott: I got a lot of nerdy shit.
Scott: It's hard to move.
Rym: moving sucks.
Rym: I when you were talking about moving.
Rym: I literally was having flashbacks to us trying to get out of beacon From the movers, it was pretty easy for me.
Scott: Yeah But uh, well you hired three shady Russian do Eastern European dudes.
Rym: Yeah, they weren't Russian.
Rym: They were Georgian, right?
Scott: but I Hired fancy moving company.
Scott: Yeah, it was much more Like if I if and when I ever my head and have hired that fancy moving company to do this move.
Rym: I would have been fine If I ever move again from this apartment to anywhere even like in the side can recommend the fancy moving company Which they were great.
Rym: I was looking at.
Rym: I was looking at the prices for this.
Rym: It's not as expensive as I expected but it is expensive The div to pay a moving company that doesn't just move the stuff you packed.
Rym: they come into your apartment pack everything Oh, yeah And unpack it all according to your specifications while you're on vacation.
Scott: The one that we hired would offer those services.
Scott: We did not pay for the pack our stuff service But basically when they showed up my stuff was as packed as I could pack it They came in and they basically packed it further of their own.
Rym: it's amazing.
Rym: like you think Oh, I did a good job of packing this stuff.
Rym: Then you watch a professional take your shit.
Scott: Yes, it took me like all like a whole week to pack up what I packed.
Scott: in an hour They emptied my apartment of everything.
Scott: I wanted out of there.
Rym: Yep How long did it take us to move all our shit out of that truck into the house and beacon like a day?
Scott: It was just to get boxes from a truck Company that I hired would pack your stuff right bring it and then unpack it if you paid them more monies.
Rym: Yeah, if I ever move again, I'm just gonna leave my apartment and expect you come home to my new apartment.
Rym: Yeah, like after a vacation.
Scott: They will do that for you.
Rym: Yeah moving socks.
Rym: I've stayed in this apartment for almost 10 years.
Rym: I don't plan to leave anytime soon because it is rent stabilized.
Rym: So There is a ton of news.
Rym: a ton has happened in the tech world.
Scott: in the world We have a huge pile of stuff and we forgot most of it.
Scott: because when we open up our computers to say What are we gonna talk about today?
Scott: All the websites have recent things and unless you tag and save a whole bunch of older thing Which
Rym: we do not do because as you know geek
Scott: nights, I do it a little bit
Rym: we do zero Pre-production we do like a Minutes worth of semi-automated post-production and we go live to tape meaning we don't even edit.
Scott: so So yeah, basically all the good stuff.
Scott: We could have talked about in the past month or whatever.
Scott: We're not gonna.
Scott: we're gonna.
Scott: good news is the one of the opening bits just lost into the wind.
Scott: Yep, cheers Somebody so many things of the day.
Scott: just you'll have to find them on your own.
Rym: I'd quote Roy Batty because actually one thing that Emily and I just watched that we hadn't seen until last night was Blade Runner 2049.
Scott: Oh, I didn't see that.
Rym: It's real fucking good.
Scott: I'm sure it is.
Scott: The thing is I want to rewatch I guess figure out which old edit of the original blade.
Rym: Yes, a rewatch the old Blade Runner again first if it is not fresh in your mind.
Rym: Well, I mean it was fresh in my mind.
Scott: It's half fresh in my mind.
Rym: It was fresh in my mind because I watched it again on a plane.
Rym: I could tell you the plot because I was thinking a lot about being puppycat and I want I could actually name one character Roy Batty and Deckard.
Scott: Yeah, those ones.
Rym: Can you name anyone else?
Rym: No, Rachel.
Scott: I guess that's her name.
Rym: I can't name all the other goons like all the all the sub bosses and such.
Rym: No, I can't name that many other characters.
Rym: But uh, all I will say for Blade Runner 2049 which kind of relevant to Monday gig nights.
Rym: I'm sure sure when you watch it we can do a show on it.
Rym: Is that one?
Rym: If you don't know anything about it, like you don't know what the plot is do not read anything about it just going cold Having watched the original Blade Runner because it is basically a direct sequel And it is yeah, like it's the same year.
Scott: does original Blade Runner take place in like 20 20 something like it's.
Rym: it's 20 to 30 years after that movie.
Rym: Okay, arguably depending on how you look at it But it's it's in that same timeline - it basically has three acts because it's three hours long.
Scott: That's my kind of move.
Rym: Yeah, it is.
Rym: It is long and slow in the way that you will love.
Scott: Yeah, give me that long fucking movie three.
Rym: It is in every conceivable way a Worthy successor to Blade Runner without just being Blade Runner again.
Rym: like when I think of that movie and I think of Blade Runner, I feel like they're equally worthy as Blade Runner movies and When you say it you see it.
Rym: So of all the news we could talk about the one thing that we have to say something about Is the fact that the week we happen to not do GeekNights happened to be the week that the entire US government entered Possibly one of its literally greatest crises.
Rym: We are in the process of impeaching the president of the United States like literally it's moving so fast I don't even feel like I can talk about it.
Rym: a bunch of breaking news happen between When I looked at the news at work and when we started recording the show.
Rym: So all I'll say is that if you do not leave in the United States, basically, you're very lucky.
Rym: Yeah, cuz I don't know what's gonna happen.
Rym: But if we fail to impeach this president our government is basically failed and I don't know what happens after that.
Scott: Like I said before the show and the microphone wasn't on it's like in civilization When the little partisan shows up outside the city makes a little gun noise like ticket ticket ticket, you know Like a big red flag.
Rym: Yep, it's like.
Rym: wait those look like barbarian units But they're way powerful and there's like five of them and that city is nearly not producing anything.
Scott: What's up with that?
Scott: Yep, how come no one's going to work?
Rym: Yeah, how come I don't have any military over by that city.
Rym: What's going on?
Rym: Oh now that city is just a barbarian city WTF?
Rym: But the way you are the barbarian city the way this goes down and I'm also kind of aiming this at Americans because I've realized Most people don't actually know how impeachment works because hasn't happened that many times?
Scott: I knew how it worked since eighth grade when we had the Constitution.
Scott: I had enough brain to understand it.
Rym: Our government has three co-equal branches and one of those branches has two Co-equal bodies that have suddenly different mandates and responsibilities.
Rym: So in our Congress, we have the House and the Senate.
Rym: the house Has is Responsible for and this is like, you know, you talk about like what are the powers of government and what's up?
Scott: Just lay this up.
Scott: Do you really need to teach it to them?
Rym: I feel like we do.
Rym: It's like rule one of the Constitution
Scott: House says yes We're gonna impeach and if they vote yes Then the Senate actually does the
Rym: trial and the trial it ends either in But literally the removal from office of the president and or vice president or not or nothing
Scott: or nothing.
Rym: Yeah, like it is a fair like there is no debate about the constitutionality of how this works like Supreme Court has no say In this.
Scott: well, this is the this debate.
Scott: There's a lot of leeway in terms of okay, the Senate will have a trial.
Scott: How does it conduct this trial?
Scott: the Senate just fucking decides how to have the trial?
Rym: Yes with one with one important caveat.
Rym: a lot of people don't know I don't think definitely you even know this who presides over the trial Supreme Court justice.
Rym: So if it's chief justice of the spring if it's an impeachment of anyone but the president Fucking like Mitch McConnell would do it only because it is the president himself Does it mean that it would be the chief justice of the Supreme Court, right?
Rym: Just he walks on over but there's no appeal There's no lawsuit.
Rym: It is it.
Rym: it is literally.
Rym: if they vote like impeachment and then they confirm it Is the immediate and automatic removal from office in the permanent lifetime ban with no recourse Yeah from any public office.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, well, it's a pretty high bar.
Scott: You need a two-thirds vote.
Scott: Yeah, right and like.
Scott: it's.
Scott: like.
Scott: it's like yeah If you're that bad that they effectively had enough votes to amend the Constitution to get rid of you.
Scott: You're out.
Scott: Yeah, it's like it's a. it's enough votes to amend the Constitution to kick you out.
Scott: So that basically is the equivalent of writing an amendment in the Constitution that says Rym cannot be president.
Scott: Yeah, like yeah, okay.
Scott: If that if the if the country hates you that much or you're that bad that you got that many no votes then yeah.
Rym: But the reason this is such a big deal then we'll move on cuz I don't want to dwell on this is simply that There's a big difference between talking about impeachment or having investigations or hearing in the u.s.
Rym: Versus the house formally saying we are drafting articles of impeachment.
Rym: as soon as they do that No one can avoid answering their questions because not answering their questions is itself worthy of impeachment.
Rym: So it's a tricky situation.
Rym: That's gonna be really interesting.
Rym: The entire fate of the US government hinges on like the next two or three weeks.
Rym: So, uh, the reason I think this is funny the other thing I was alluding to is that While we were on the hiatus because Scott couldn't do shows while he was moving You might have noticed that I started making a whole bunch of YouTube videos and patreon things.
Rym: But as a result of that I listened to a lot of old episodes of GeekNights.
Rym: partially like to find that like to find the main bit in these old episodes of GeekNights.
Rym: and if you listen to the news for GeekNights between like 2005 and 2009 to 2010 ish we talk a lot about politics every fucking episode.
Rym: like a lot.
Rym: I have all that like.
Rym: I listen to Scott going on and on and on about like surprisingly specific areas of US government government and governance in like random episodes of GeekNights like Anime episodes where we review an anime that I literally did not remember existed.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Do you remember?
Rym: The show the movie the boy who saw the wind.
Scott: Is it the one with the circus?
Rym: no, maybe.
Scott: no, what's the one with the circus?
Rym: kids know the circus cat that is.
Rym: Wow, I Forgot that Jeff.
Rym: Yes brave story.
Scott: Emily has a better memory.
Rym: Emily from the kitchen remembers.
Rym: we do not.
Scott: that's the only thing I remember from brave story is the circus.
Rym: Oh, you saw the wind.
Rym: I Listened to our 10-minute review of this movie where you and I talked about a lot of details of this movie.
Rym: I literally do not remember this movie.
Rym: I went into why do you remember?
Scott: there were some anime movies with wind in the title?
Rym: I went and watched sections of it.
Rym: I still do not remember this.
Rym: I remember nothing about it yet.
Rym: We did a long-form review of it.
Rym: Yeah, okay But this episode of GeekNights was 10 minutes of us reviewing this anime and like 40 minutes of us talking about politics.
Rym: So in some actual technology news, that's pretty important.
Rym: RMS Richard Stallman who is most Notable for eating something that he picked off of his own foot while on a panel.
Scott: Well, he wasn't on a panel.
Scott: He was like lecturing in front of a classroom sitting in a chair with his second Whole room of people looking at him and he takes off his shoe and his sock and he picks something off his foot and he Eats it and swallows it suppose.
Scott: I guess I can't tell.
Scott: yeah It's anyway, so RMS if you don't know we can't.
Scott: you know.
Scott: If you want to learn a lot about this person you can with the internet.
Scott: I don't know if it's worth your time But basically it was a person who had a large hand in.
Scott: you know, the open source software movement you know made Emacs type things and You know was the head of the free software foundation was the person who would pedantically argue about.
Scott: it's not Linux It's new Linux.
Scott: Yeah, right the new herd and all right.
Scott: Well, the new herd was like the kernel they wanted to make.
Scott: yeah not to be like not use Linux, but that never got anywhere.
Rym: You know like you would beef even with Linus Torvalds.
Scott: Anyway, this is just.
Scott: he was uh, you know, basically the classic right That guy.
Scott: Yeah, or you know beard a beard.
Rym: Oh Unix II guy who has really strong opinions and is super toxic to work with.
Scott: It was notoriously bad dude, right?
Scott: So what happened?
Scott: Well, you know, it was what happened recently.
Scott: was there was the whole deal with like Epstein the pedophile, right?
Scott: Yeah, and he made some comments regarding Minsky which is a related person in that whole fiasco and regardless of the specifics of those comments because His comments were like, you know that guy ish, you know I'm not gonna get an argument about the right.
Rym: the point is I would say RMS is like the archetypical that guy, right?
Scott: Everyone came out of the woodwork with like, all right, we haven't paid attention to you in a long time And in the time since we stopped paying attention to you me too is a thing.
Scott: by the way Here's a million stories or a million people about how much of a disgusting human being you are like.
Rym: you've been a problem For the open source community for as long as anyone has known your name right beside the foot eating and these other that guy tendencies.
Scott: it's like oh, yeah, we forgot about you, but you're awful and Basically he has been good and well pushed out of like every position he had.
Scott: I think I was like a visiting professor at like MIT or something.
Rym: Yeah, he resigned from that.
Rym: He resigned from the FSF.
Scott: Yep so I just wanna you know the related, you know lesson to learn from this is You know something I've learned recently because you know and on there's always an ongoing discussion about like Oh the great Pete the awful people who do great stuff, right, you know, but I heard you know There's always been like the same talking points in that discussion, right which is like Oh appreciate the thing the person did even though while at the same time, you know You recognize the person was bad and stuff like that, right?
Scott: But I heard a point recently which is like, you know with only regards to if the person is still alive You know should you you know, cancel quote cancel them push them out, you know, get rid of them right ostracize them.
Rym: Yes,
Scott: right, but the reason that the argument I think Undisputable argument for why you should do this is you know, people will say well well, but wait you're gonna push this person out You're gonna miss out on you know, this genius who's who's doing all this great work You're gonna you know, even though they're an awful person You're gonna miss out on all the great stuff They do.
Scott: if you kick that, you know that pro athlete off your team You're gonna miss out on all their home runs and it's like yeah But if that person is so disgusting and abhorrent how many people are there?
Scott: that would be contributing and maybe coming to hit Rome runs for your team who Refused to come because they don't want to play with that disgusting human being.
Scott: how many people didn't go and write code at MIT or go into computer science because There's this disgusting RMS guy walking around eating shit off his feet and that makes them go like well, I'll go somewhere else I don't need to be here right?
Scott: you're losing all those people.
Scott: So whether it's art or technology or whatever it is your field, right?
Scott: You even if someone truly is a genius which I don't think RMS really is no But you know if you have a person like that around even if they are a genius How many people are now not being around?
Scott: Right.
Rym: Yeah What would Linux on the desktop have looked like if like a lot more people with a lot more varied opinions were contributing to open Source and weren't driven away by this shit, right?
Scott: So whatever he did it's like yeah I think we would have been okay without this dude and he was a bad dude.
Scott: and we finally remembered Oh, yeah, that's a bad dude.
Scott: Hey, no, so if you can think of any other dudes, right?
Rym: Like for example in the voice acting community Vic like we're getting rid of him, right?
Scott: It seems like every time there's a story about a bad dude who needs getting rid of it's always like oh, yeah Have you would have just told me he was a bad dude.
Scott: I totally would have believed you.
Scott: Right now you show me Bridget still I don't even need any evidence to know.
Scott: I just know cuz I know that dude and I can just tell he is that vibe.
Scott: but it's like I sit here and I try to think now and I'm like I should be proactive and try to think.
Scott: what dudes do I remember that give off that vibe?
Scott: Yeah, right and it's like I try to think of some and it's like I can't think of any but we definitely didn't get them All.
Scott: no, right.
Scott: It's like so everyone.
Scott: I want everyone to think real hard about dudes who give off a bad vibe Where.
Scott: if you heard in the news tomorrow that that was a bad dude, right?
Scott: That should be quote canceled.
Scott: You would have been like, oh, yeah, obviously that guy.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, right, but try to think of those dudes now so that we can cancel them faster.
Scott: We don't remember them.
Scott: I just a memory.
Scott: I saw an anime.
Scott: I can't remember.
Scott: I also can't remember.
Scott: I Need someone else to help me remember the bad dudes.
Rym: So in some other technology news if you haven't been following this it is kind of a big deal Irrespective of your feelings on smoking which is disgusting and vaping which is disgusting and you can tell what our opinions are on these things, but There is a big problem going on with the vaping industry and it's dangerous and it's killing people.
Rym: Like if you vape I would suggest that you stop for the time being.
Rym: Maybe talk to your doc like if you're vaping nicotine juice Because you're trying to quit smoking.
Rym: smoking like talk to your doctor and figure out what you should do.
Rym: But maybe you can.
Scott: can you like just put water in a vape and vape?
Rym: No No, no.
Rym: No.
Rym: So here's the God.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: I'm glad I'm doing this then.
Rym: So here's the deal.
Scott: if you just cuz you some people have like, you know They're not like.
Scott: actually addicted to Nick I mean are.
Scott: a lot of people dig to nicotine know they get addicted to the ritual, right?
Scott: But there are people were just addicted I know to at least partially to just like, you know The ritual and affectation of like putting something in your mouth like a pacifier or going outside and taking a break.
Rym: Oh, yeah studies show that nicotine addiction goes away pretty quick compared to the like Other like habitual addiction to the rituals around smoking, right?
Scott: So it's like.
Scott: I feel like if you could just put like a nothing in the vape that would actually now So the products of some people.
Rym: so the problem is the nothing.
Rym: so here's the deal.
Scott: when you vape from these vaporizers It's basically a coil that heats up some juice sort of like the little the lighter in the in the in there in your car.
Scott: Yeah, it's the electric coil.
Rym: Yeah, but it's in some juice and it vaporizes that juicy and inhale it.
Rym: It's not water vapor because for a lot of reasons.
Rym: Well, I would just electrify like to turn or to turn to heat water to the point that you get a vapor out of it.
Rym: That's gonna be too hot to just inhale into your lungs.
Scott: Yeah, inhaling steam.
Scott: Yeah, it's bad idea.
Scott: And if you made a cold vape hello Legionnaires disease Okay.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Yep, but also you got to get the chemical that vapes at the right temp.
Rym: But also people vape either flavor or nicotine or THC.
Rym: All
Scott: three of those things or come or combinations of all the
Rym: Combination of all three all three of those things need a solvent to be able to be put into so that when that when you vape them the salt the Phenols and the chemicals and all these things can get into your mouth and lungs to taste and/or experience effects based on them.
Rym: Can't just use water for that.
Rym: if you don't understand why I suggest you take a high school chemistry class.
Rym: But basically there are not that many kinds of solvents or kinds of things.
Rym: You can put other things into solution with my.
Scott: so even if you see if you find a chemical that vapes It might not be a solvent that you can dissolve Nicotine.
Scott: or maybe you found a solvent you can dissolve nicotine into but oh it won't vape.
Rym: Also those phenols and things themselves Like thus should say a phenol chemical that is cherry flavor That is generally recognized as safe meaning the FDA said yeah You can just put this in food and there's really no evidence that it hurts anyone.
Rym: so kind of go nuts with it.
Rym: Yeah, but That doesn't mean that it's safe to vaporize and inhale into your lungs.
Rym: Yeah, here's a specific example of that if you Inhale an oil like vitamin E for example into your lungs.
Rym: You can get something called lipoid pneumonia Lipoid yeah, well depending on did.
Rym: I've heard I've already heard professionals pronouncing this both ways.
Scott: Okay, but the deal it cuz I mean lawyers can't even decide if it's pled or plead guilty.
Rym: Yeah What about the original form of ouster and how that's actually the correct?
Rym: it's not the ousting of it's the ouster of for reasons I don't want to get into.
Scott: You didn't know that I had not heard that one.
Rym: really how that's like.
Rym: ouster is like front and center Impeachment is an ouster.
Rym: Anyway, so if you inhale oils into your lungs as opposed to other things your lungs Do not have a whale to do.
Rym: what we have to deal with that shit.
Rym: It is super dangerous.
Rym: It can kill you.
Rym: that is why a lot of drugs that say things like if you overdose do not under any Circumstances try to vomit it up.
Rym: go to a hospital because they need to get it out of you in a safe way.
Rym: If you vomit it up even aspirating a little bit of it could literally kill you.
Scott: Cuz I already hit the acid in your stomach and now it's like right.
Rym: Oh, well, you could get acid into your lungs, which is that's also really really bad.
Scott: Basically, the lungs are not meant to have anything to win them but air.
Scott: Yeah breathing in literally anything.
Scott: That's not just like, you know There are great for you.
Rym: there are nebulizers there are Inhaled medicines that are safe and effective because they're testing thoroughly.
Scott: I'm saying the number of things like random shit going into your lungs is just generally bad.
Rym: Yeah, but here's the deal.
Scott: campfires not good.
Rym: So Inhaling a lipid can fuck you up.
Rym: Inhaling a lot of things can fuck you up.
Rym: when I was a kid I had asthma treatment or I do inhale drugs with these very expensive medical devices that would nebulize the medicine.
Rym: So I inhaled it.
Rym: The average vape that some kid is using and probably buying bootleg carts for Not as expensive as that very expensive nebulizer and probably not as safely designed and not as Keverely regulated.
Rym: Mmm.
Rym: So the deal is we don't know what is calling causing these serious and deadly illnesses and people who vape or vaping.
Scott: But I can guess Yeah hard.
Scott: Could it be the shit?
Scott: They're just breathing.
Rym: So here's the.
Rym: there's the likely factors.
Rym: one lot of bootleg THC carts from China Yeah, make to a lot of people who are vaping or hobbyists who are modifying their vape kits.
Rym: That is not tested by anyone.
Rym: Good luck.
Rym: Have fun.
Rym: Don't fuck with your vape shit.
Scott: I mean people fuck with their bongs for decades.
Scott: No problem.
Rym: That's a little bit different because bongs tend to vaporize material from actual plant matter, which is highly unlikely to have propylene glycol and vitamin E and shit in it, I guess To the salt.
Rym: the solvents themselves are often bootleg and dodgy.
Rym: the processes involves can be bootleg and dodgy and Even a lot of these flavor chemicals not really tested by the FDA to be deemed safe for inhaling or if they are Ostensibly safe for inhaling the models used to test that probably don't cover Vape.
Rym: Lord who inhales like metric liters of this on an hourly basis because they're taking something else that people don't realize, right?
Scott: Let's say that the FDA discovers that chemical X right now is safe As long as you have less than I don't know a milliliter a day.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: It's as long as you have less than a milliliter a day.
Scott: You won't face no harm.
Scott: So if you got what they do is they say, okay, that means you can put chemical X in food.
Scott: However, the amount you can put in food is not a milliliter.
Scott: The amount is like a milliliter divided by like a thousand or something.
Scott: It's your Combinations of your body weight your I'm saying the limit that the regulators will say hmm All right, it's like oh, it's safe to have a milliliter of this per day.
Scott: So they don't say okay put a milliliter of this in your milkshake.
Scott: they say no, no, no, you can put one one thousandth of this in your milk tank because Somebody could theoretically have a milkshake with the chemical eat a cake with the chemical.
Rym: Well, like the level of lead that starts to cause problems.
Rym: pretty low the the maximum lead That's allowed to be in anything not that much higher than the head.
Rym: but still there is a difference.
Rym: You still don't want any lead.
Rym: no amount of lead is safe, right?
Rym: It's negligible enough, right?
Scott: But I mean, you know even you know Even things that are super safe and like you could have a gallon of this a day and be fine They still make the legal limit in a food a fraction of.
Rym: don't go buy Concentrated cherry flavor phenols and just drink them because you could be.
Scott: you know Having so many different foods in a day.
Scott: that thing could be in all the foods You need to the subtle total.
Scott: Here's an example be less so that for the vapes.
Scott: It's like yeah, okay The one vape is fine, but you vape 20 times today.
Scott: Yeah, but that's not if they're not cutting the fractions small enough or like case in point.
Rym: a lot of vape models assume people are puffing into their mouths like you would with a hookah and Like having the flavor and not like fully inhaling it into their lungs.
Rym: But then you watch some kid vape Lord and he fully inhales into his lungs and blows out a giant dragon cloud.
Scott: Yeah, those are very different use cases.
Rym: That's like the difference between drinking liquor from a shot glass and a pint glass or the bottle.
Rym: Yeah the bottle or the tap.
Scott: so This like those summer break things with the hose.
Rym: This shit is not as regulated as you think it is and I highly suggest you do not vape anything from a solution Until the real regulatory frameworks are in place, which is gonna take two to three years.
Rym: that is my advice to you and if you're a connoisseur of nicotine or THC I recommend you consume them in more traditional routes for the time being.
Rym: but anyway things Of the day what do you got?
Scott: Check it out?
Scott: Someone tweeted these.
Rym: photos of these are so good.
Scott: some prototype computers from back in the day Looks like maybe 80s time.
Rym: Oh, look at those days.
Scott: These look like 80s to me.
Scott: I don't know if these computers actually worked.
Scott: this looks like early late 70s early 80s, right color, but these are designs at least of Hypothetical computers from the Soviet Union.
Scott: I definitely feel like it's 80s.
Scott: But anyway, it's yeah, I don't know if any of these computers actually functioned or had computers in them, but it's just the designs themselves are.
Scott: They look like something that would be like in a movie like as a prop You know like a movie about the like Tron or something, right?
Scott: Yeah, but no these were actual design Manufactured prototype like computers from the Soviet Union and I don't see why like why wouldn't you just make a brand new computer that looks Just like this.
Rym: We totally can't love a laptop that looked like.
Scott: they totally have the technology to make any of these now No problem.
Rym: Yeah, so I do want a QWERTY keyboard, but otherwise you don't want it.
Scott: the Cyrillic keyboard.
Scott: No, I don't want Cyrillic grid keyboard.
Rym: Yeah, this grid is my phone the telephone part either.
Rym: I don't think I need the telephone part, right?
Scott: But the point is we could make these now someone should.
Rym: Yeah, I would love to just even.
Rym: it was just.
Rym: you know what I'd love to you.
Rym: know What is your mission if you're the kind of person who goes to like the penny arcade expo and you hang out in the bring?
Rym: Your own PC area.
Rym: I want to see a BYO PC that looks like this shit.
Scott: Good luck.
Rym: If you do if you make this tell me So real brief thing of the day to do a non technology thing.
Rym: There's a character that has appeared in more Disney things than you realize and is the most recent DuckTales.
Rym: Most people know this character either from the most recent DuckTales or from the three Caballeros But this is the character Jose who is that green parrot guy from Brazil?
Rym: This is the evolution of that character from early concept designs basically in chronological order of every appearance in Disney media.
Rym: Mm-hmm a lot.
Rym: this this these kinds of videos are my jams and this character is not that commonly known.
Rym: And I like this character a lot Probably mostly for nostalgia reasons, but it's a pretty well put together video Especially considering how relatively obscure these sources are in some cases.
Rym: Mm-hmm in the meta moment unites is back.
Rym: The book club book is currently the tale of Genji.
Rym: We're both reading it.
Scott: It's gonna be I stopped reading it and it's long.
Scott: I'll start reading it again.
Rym: I'm gonna stop not gonna read anymore until you tell me you're reading it again.
Scott: I mean, I'm busy unpacking every time I go home.
Rym: Yeah, but we're gonna read the tale of Genji and we're gonna talk about it.
Rym: It's a spicy tales of core drama and romance.
Scott: the first novel ever Period ever.
Scott: the first one the first one not the first story.
Scott: There's like, you know Gilgamesh is older, right?
Scott: but it's the first novel.
Rym: if you saw us from packs our Panel the new one with well actually a pretty new list of games.
Rym: the 40 games you must play is on YouTube.
Rym: But a new thing while Scott was on hiatus.
Rym: I'm gonna continue to do.
Rym: I know there is an appetite out there for this.
Rym: So if you subscribe to the GeekNights patreon, even you don't pay any money.
Rym: the feed there will have this.
Rym: There's a main bits feed now
Scott: and
Rym: I am taking old episodes of GeekNights where our main bit was interesting or notable as a topic and I'm extracting it from the episode because you might want to hear our review of say neon Genesis Evangelion from like 2007 but you don't want to hear us talking about 2007 era, what did you do today in beacon?
Rym: And what is the anime news from Otakon?
Rym: Like you just want the review.
Rym: So I'm taking all these main bits.
Rym: I'm focusing on board games and anime.
Rym: anime is the new one.
Rym: I'm making a YouTube feed and I'm making a patreon feed for all these main bits And I see people watching them.
Rym: So I've already put up Our knee our Evangelion review our Evangelion final thoughts our big o final thoughts and our review of that movie that neither of us remembers at all The boy who saw the wind, okay.
Scott: So once I've got my new apartment set up, I have the files now with the really good upload.
Scott: So I'll be able to use stream and upload to YouTube much more easily and I'll have new furniture and more space to make it Much more conducive to film things in general.
Scott: So that's yep, that's a few lines a few months out.
Rym: things like gig nights presents utenna things like a new thing We're working on.
Rym: that isn't really shit talk is we're fucking doing it because it's it's too close to our wheelhouse And it's while.
Rym: it is gonna be a lot of work It's a lot less work to do this kind of thing.
Rym: being the kinds of people that we are We really need to have secrets.
Scott: It's like a stealer.
Rym: No, no, no one is capable of doing this but us.
Rym: But a stay tuned because I want to do like an episode of it first and like work out the pipeline anyway.
Scott: Yeah, so the next convention is Pax unplugged.
Rym: Oh, baby is coming up.
Scott: So here's the deal.
Scott: It's like a month away.
Rym: No two month away yep, so Pax unplugged is coming.
Rym: we're gonna do in now probably a panel or two and Very likely at least one learn and play session because as you guys know play and win.
Scott: Yeah learn and win.
Rym: But if we get our way we're doing a learn and win play learn and play session.
Rym: that is not one Not two, but three games in the same session.
Rym: Oh, baby I'm actually pretty excited about this.
Rym: Okay Cuz we used to have a lot of fun doing panels that were three mini panels in a row To do the ideas where we had 20 minutes of content, but we didn't have an hour's worth of content.
Rym: Uh, not too long after that we got packs.
Rym: are we got magfest?
Rym: we got packs.
Rym: me mag year Mag year super mag year PAX South which is coming up like panel submissions are closing soon And then pat East was just announced and it is.
Scott: I knew the dates I saw.
Scott: they announced the dates officially just now.
Scott: recently like a day or two ago.
Rym: We've known those dates for a long time.
Scott: I went to my calendar.
Scott: There was already there and I'm like, okay Yes was correct.
Rym: All I'm gonna say is that based on the information that was leaked publicly not by packs, but by other organizations a long time ago It is pretty common knowledge the dates of most PAX East for the foreseeable future.
Rym: if you just poke around a little bit.
Rym: Yeah, it is not hard to find this information.
Rym: No So, uh, if you have found that information in the past But were dubious of its Providence use this sort of things as proof that it is accurate, right?
Scott: It's sort of like Apple rumors.
Scott: It's like they keep being right.
Rym: So Yeah All right, so we have some other ideas for shows but I figure we go back to our old old ideas.
Rym: We used to a lot of shows talking about Basic technology that we knew enough about to explain how it worked in the history of it in some fashion And I've realized Scott and I both it was Scott's idea, but I was thinking about this a lot.
Rym: GPS Like just in like our own lives went from something I do not have access to right.
Scott: It went from like this cool thing that like the government has that's super rare like or like satellite phones.
Scott: Like if you're super rich or have super fancy equipment You can use this GPS thing that will tell you your latitude and longitude wherever you are on earth.
Scott: Yeah, and then it got you rare and now everyone has it in their fucking watch.
Rym: Yeah, but then it went through this progression.
Rym: So I want to kind of walk through the high-level history.
Rym: We're not gonna go into too much specific history.
Rym: Okay, you all I mean I do but like you can read Wikipedia to get exact years and like all the fiddly details.
Rym: But here's the deal.
Rym: GPS is a concept is very new.
Rym: like this was not a thing until the 70s.
Rym: Yeah the 1970s.
Rym: what before then?
Rym: there really wasn't a good way to know where you were.
Scott: had to use old-school naval shit.
Scott: You know Reckoning sexton's stars who the fuck knows.
Rym: Yeah, like navigation like ocean navigation Naval navigation air navigation even ground navigation These were difficult.
Rym: if you wanted to drive from point A to point B You better know how to read a lot of that.
Scott: You had a map and road signs, right?
Scott: You know the road signs you'd look at the map.
Scott: You have a compass.
Scott: you'd orient yourself with a compass.
Scott: All right, I grew up, you know as a kid the cars fit a lot of cars and I was in the 80s and 90s Compasses in them.
Scott: Yeah, so that when you were in you use it.
Scott: looking at your paper map book You would know which way the car was facing.
Rym: when you reference the street signs I mean, I literally like learned orienteering.
Rym: cuz when I went hiking.
Rym: there's no GPS.
Rym: if I get lost fucking die.
Rym: So even as late as high school I would like carry a compass and like terrain charts and maps and plot courses and do real orienteering.
Rym: Now Emily and I just did a long hike through the wilderness this weekend.
Rym: GPS just there Strava tracked the whole thing.
Rym: Yeah, Google Maps.
Rym: I could zoom in on the trail.
Scott: the maps There's.
Scott: people got to understand the maps are separate from the GPS.
Scott: right totally separate, right?
Scott: So the GPS all it does is it tells you here's your latitude and longitude bro the end.
Scott: Yeah, it doesn't get you any other information.
Scott: But if you have a map and the map has latitude and longitude on it You can just draw a dot on the map of where you fucking are.
Scott: And then if you have a compass you can draw an arrow sticking out of your dot Showing where you're facing.
Scott: and now you've got a really useful map.
Rym: so here's you know what this means for you.
Rym: Let's say you have a smartphone But you do not have global roaming and you're in a country that you don't live in.
Rym: if you pre-cache the Google Map and You just leave your phone in a mode where it can't connect to the internet Your GPS will still just work with Google Maps because GPS And this is like the most common misconception about it is 100% one way.
Rym: the GPS system literally cannot know anything about your phone.
Rym: all it is doing is Broadcasting information and your phone uses that information to be able to calculate your latitude longitude and altitude.
Scott: It's as free as and private as radio.
Scott: There's basically just these satellites in space Broadcasting.
Scott: now that a for by primarily the US Air Force.
Rym: well GPS came out of the same kinds of things that gave us the internet GPS system.
Rym: one is owned by the United States Government.
Rym: it is not a public ring.
Scott: It covers the entire world.
Scott: It's owned and controlled mostly by the United States government almost entirely Entirely almost entirely because the US government.
Scott: actually are even the other countries using it.
Scott: They're just using it from us for free because it's useless if it doesn't cover the whole world.
Scott: Yeah, it's like even if you're in an enemy country like North Korea, you can just use GPS and the US can't stop you Yep.
Rym: Well, so the UPS can't stop you because GPS until the year 2000 was not really that usable for civilians.
Rym: No, in fact when it was invented, it was not usable at all by civilians.
Rym: It got to a point later where degraded Forms of the Jeep basically the GPS network, it's hard to explain how this works like getting new tech.
Scott: Oh, I can explain how it works very easily.
Rym: No, no, but in terms of the selective availability idea GPS satellites are out there broadcasting but the technology to use that information was really only available to the US military and Civilian receivers.
Rym: you got degraded quality.
Rym: They had much less accurate information.
Rym: It was not until the year 2000 that that went away and The military grade like accuracy is the same accuracy that you with your shitty smartphone can get.
Scott: All right, so here's how it works.
Scott: It's real.
Scott: It's really simple.
Scott: when we ended a program called selective availability, right in space The the US has launched like it's almost 30 something.
Scott: I mean, I think there's 24.
Rym: There's 33 now.
Rym: Yeah, there's like a.
Scott: there's like a promise that they will always have a certain number available Which is like the number needed but only 24 are needed.
Rym: I think there's 31 in orbit.
Scott: There's more than that many just in case something happens.
Scott: They can turn on a backup or something, right?
Scott: Yeah, they got more than they need, right?
Rym: They think they need 24 But anyway at 24, I think is the bare minimum to provide global service.
Scott: No matter where you are on planet earth You will have line of sight to four of these fucking satellites.
Scott: Yeah anymore is better.
Scott: bottom of the Arctic South Pole North Pole China middle of the Pacific Ocean doesn't matter.
Scott: you will be able to Basically fire a laser beam if you wanted to and hit at least four of these things.
Scott: Yep, they're geostationary.
Scott: They just stay put so that if there was one directly above New York, right?
Scott: It would always be directly above New York.
Scott: It just goes around with the earth.
Rym: No, I want I want I want to say that six is like the magic number for having faster sync and accuracy Whatever.
Rym: but more is the minimum.
Rym: with less than four GPS doesn't really work that well.
Scott: So you turn on a little radio right basically and you listen for these things because they're just shooting down at the earth They're signal right and they're broadcasting information.
Rym: That's basically just coordinates and timestamps and identifiers.
Scott: Just saying I am satellite number X right and it is currently this time.
Scott: and a little bit more metadata, right?
Scott: It's a metadata.
Scott: It's not much.
Scott: It's really very small amount of data.
Scott: crazy simple, right?
Scott: You turn on your little radio and your radio hears satellite.
Scott: Oh, I'm hearing news.
Scott: I'm hearing broadcasts from satellites one two and three and the times that they're sending me are this time this time in this time Right.
Scott: Let me do some math and it does some math and the math is really complicated.
Rym: I don't understand it.
Scott: I'm not gonna try to explain it how what the math does I can Number.
Scott: so what the math does is okay.
Scott: satellite one is this far away from me.
Scott: Satellite two is this far away from me and satellite three is this far away from me, right?
Scott: Well, I know that satellite one is Hearable in this sphere.
Rym: if you're anywhere and more to solve the equation you actually do need four.
Scott: I thought you only need three.
Rym: so so here's oh, so here's the P Here's the magic.
Rym: and I know this a lot because in the early days of smartphones doing this smartphones are really shitty at it.
Rym: So I had an app that would show me which that like all the raw satellite data and it was really cool.
Rym: but basically if you have three GPS satellites It'll Basically only be able to project your latitude and longitude.
Rym: But to solve the equations you have to assume that you're at sea level.
Rym: meaning if you have three satellites and you are at sea level your Position will be pretty accurate like it'll be out.
Scott: But if you're up in the air you need the fourth.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: So if you're up if you're high or low, you're.
Rym: your latitude and longitude will be wrong.
Scott: But more importantly I such a small amount.
Rym: no by a pretty big amount Or two your altitude cannot be calculated right regardless kind of important for a lot of reasons.
Rym: So you need four satellites to actually solve the actual number.
Scott: Altitude is different.
Scott: your distance from the satellites will be different exactly which is what you're using to figure everything out.
Rym: That's why your Strava if you like record a run it actually shows like your altitude over the course of the run.
Scott: Anyway, so what happens is mathematically it says, okay Well, here's the sphere of coverage for satellite one is the sphere of coverage of satellite two, right?
Scott: Here's the sphere of coverage for satellite three.
Scott: They're this far away from you Right.
Scott: So these three spheres if you were this far away from the three of them, right?
Scott: You would be in and it sort of combines them all.
Scott: and the intersection of all of that is where you are Right, and that's all there is to it.
Rym: Yep, but the actual numbers math.
Rym: the reason we're not talking about it is it's pretty complex and It like to give you a sample of this.
Scott: it may there's a lot of calculus involved plus yes relativity is yes Literally fun part.
Rym: This is like literal relativity matters here.
Rym: The fact that radio signals travel at the same speed regardless of two in terms of you your phone Regardless of how fast that satellite is moving literally matters in these equations, right?
Scott: The satellite is in space.
Scott: It has less gravity.
Scott: Therefore the time is off by a tiny bit, right?
Scott: I think like the time of the things in space is going a little.
Scott: it looks is slow or fast.
Scott: I don't remember right but the point is the times need to be ultra ultra precise.
Rym: the new nanosecond precision right.
Scott: the newer GPS satellites have better atomic clocks in them and Therefore give better timing.
Rym: Oh, there's more to it than that.
Scott: But the point is you need super if you don't have accurate time on your device.
Scott: You're not getting shit, right?
Rym: To it to a degree that did that.
Rym: the cool thing about GPS is that for the calculations?
Rym: It relies on all the timestamps from all the satellite data.
Rym: Even if your phone's like local time is not super hyper I don't want to say accurate but it's not super precise because your phone's processor is not a real-time device, right?
Scott: But anyway, you need it has to account for the fact that the times coming from all those satellites are moving faster Slower I forget because of literally.
Scott: Yeah, he goes empty.
Rym: So here's here's why the history of this is important area of relativity.
Rym: the Internet and GPS are both things that were developed solely for military use.
Rym: that were so Useful that the United States government graciously decided to let the world use them.
Scott: the whole world.
Rym: and today like GPS is a US thing.
Rym: So if you've ever heard of GLONASS GLONASS is a completely separate parallel system that the Russians launched because the US Strategy today the US relies like our military relies heavily on GPS.
Rym: We have fail-safe systems to deal with like if GPS is disrupted, but they learn.
Scott: they learn how to use a sextant.
Rym: Yeah, well, there's other things.
Rym: I don't want to get it I don't want to go off on a tangent, but the way nuclear warheads Navigate is fucking insane and they do not rely at all on GPS.
Scott: Well, they got to go real fucking far.
Rym: One of the ways they navigate is they have cameras pointed up that navigate based on the fixed positions of stars images of them.
Scott: what if they go his star?
Rym: we had to update that if the stars go out if a star blows up If a bunch of stars blow up and that happened at the right time in history to where a nuclear warhead is in the air At that exact moment that the light changes here.
Rym: Yeah Trouble, but there are.
Rym: they also use geo.
Rym: Oh, I forget the term for this.
Rym: there's like these mass maps of the earth like where there are gravity hotspots and They also use that data Because they have to be able to navigate based on first principles derived solely from the data They can collect independently on their own while traveling at high speed.
Rym: Anyway, I'm digressing here, but so the Russians developed GLONASS.
Rym: Europe still doesn't really have like its own GPS if the US and Europe went to war like Europe's just kind of effed.
Rym: I think they're building something called Galileo.
Scott: What's our what's our strategy like encrypt the GPS in such a way that only the US military can use it?
Rym: Uh, so we'll just fucking.
Rym: yeah we can basically turn off the signals that all civilian devices and all foreign devices use and Instead only the encrypted signals that only the US military can interpret can be used.
Rym: Mm-hmm, that's I'm Really really really generalizing because some of this is secret and also I don't understand it that well.
Scott: I mean you can go to GPS gov and read all the public information about it.
Scott: There's a ton of it.
Scott: There's even like show you the lot the locations of the satellites which models they are What teachers they have.
Rym: the old model was more like what you described were basically the US had this idea of selective Selective availability which meant we could degrade the quality globally.
Rym: So if there was a war the US basically flips a switch and the entire GPS network goes to a degraded mode Where the US military still gets the hyper accuracy and everyone else's accuracy goes to shit, right?
Scott: All right.
Scott: So let's talk about some like, you know GPS everyday life stuff, right?
Rym: Yeah, it is hard to express to you how radically Civilian access to GPS changes the world, right?
Rym: So like as much as the internet, right?
Scott: There's like the privacy and location data situation, right?
Scott: It's like okay you have the power to know exactly where you are on earth to help you with mostly navigating Yeah, also maybe remembering where you were or finding other things because now those things know where they are.
Scott: But the fact that you can do this one finding your friends finding things you lost if they are right things like that.
Scott: But now if that if you write down where you were at given times Right now this information about where you were you can be tracked everywhere on earth as well.
Scott: Yep, even though the GPS system itself is completely private.
Scott: It's just a broadcast to find out where you are, right?
Scott: Creates no new information that can track you.
Scott: your phone happens to just write down.
Scott: Oh, yeah You were this glad it didn't launch you to this time.
Rym: A bunch of stuff.
Rym: so it's sharing it with a bunch of apps and even if you don't share anything even if you 100% lock down your phone providing any data about where you are It's still connecting to cell towers and your cell phone can itself be uniquely identified Which can still find your position.
Scott: also lots of devices like cell phones and computers use other additional supplementary systems to sort of help the GPS thing.
Rym: well, here's the.
Rym: the problem specifically is that the radios and the calculations and all the ways to figure out which satellites to look for because they're all on different frequencies and programmable antennas work is kind of complicated.
Rym: It's very hard for a small antenna device with limited capabilities to scan and find All the different signals and figure out which one to use.
Rym: that's why on old cell phones when you turn it on in a new Place it takes it a long time to actually figure out where you are.
Rym: You can bootstrap that process by using other easier things like Scott described like oh what Wi-Fi things are nearby cell towers.
Rym: Am I connected to your computer right?
Scott: You just go on your desktop computer.
Scott: It doesn't have any GPS or radio receivers and Google Maps still shows you kind of where you are.
Scott: It kind of shows you what you know how it does.
Scott: it looks your IP address and it knows.
Scott: Oh, yeah Okay, I kind of know where that IP address is.
Rym: You're really close.
Rym: That's why if you turn off Wi-Fi
Scott: your cell phone knows what cell tower you're connected to and it knows what Wi-Fi access points Are nearby and it you know someone at some point use GPS while and they said, okay Well when that person used GPS they were at this latitude and longitude and these Wi-Fi access points were in range.
Rym: Not even once you connect it to just once you get just one.
Scott: just these SS IDs were in range.
Scott: Well, let's look at Scott.
Scott: Oh that exact same list of SS IDs were in range.
Scott: when Scott's asking where he is Even though he's not looking at any satellites whatsoever.
Scott: He's probably really close to where that other person was.
Scott: What are the odds of there being two places on earth with the exact same list of Wi-Fi access points in range?
Rym: That is why Every now and then if you reboot your cell phone and you look at Google Maps like right away It might for a like a few like 30 seconds or so show you in like Chicago or New York or some generic place.
Rym: You can actually if you wanted to Because there's like a bunch of hotel Wi-Fi that happened to match up with where you are currently in some different place And then it corrects itself as soon as the GPS data comes in, right?
Scott: You got to think there's like maybe a Holiday Inn.
Scott: and it's got Holiday Inn Wi-Fi, right?
Scott: And there's no other Wi-Fi's in range because it's the middle of nowhere, right?
Scott: And so it's like, okay, how many places on earth have that exact same as well?
Scott: There's another holiday in the middle of nowhere.
Scott: Yeah, so if you're trying to figure out GPS based on that alone Well, there's a lot of choices.
Rym: Yep, right.
Rym: That's also why you'll see your GPS Have that big range that gets smaller and smaller and smaller.
Scott: Yep, because it's using all this data plus What's your IP address and what cell tower you connect to do?
Scott: Ah, I know it's holiday and that is yeah.
Scott: Oh and it's like super accurate.
Scott: and then you look at the satellites and suddenly your latitude and longitude of like a hundred decimals Points or whatever the precision is.
Scott: I don't know anymore.
Scott: There's a lot of precision going on But
Rym: the precision is a big thing because the year 2000 is when GPS became useful to civilians because that is when you got the real accuracy of the old system Which is about a 16-foot window meaning it
Scott: knows if you get a few meters It's pretty much what you need for to do any real thing.
Scott: Yeah, if it's bigger than that, then it could be like you could take a turn too early.
Scott: Right, you can think that a business is actually two businesses down you start but as long as like, you know a few meters It's like okay.
Scott: That's like the size of a car or two.
Scott: You can navigate with this now.
Rym: now There's some crazy new developments because there's a bunch of like.
Rym: it gets complicated.
Rym: There's a bunch of bands and like.
Rym: there's different types of GPS service But basically the new l5 band that's currently being deployed like just like.
Rym: I think it'll be fit Like it.
Rym: one of the last satellites was launched for this recently and there's upgrades to the system That will bring the accuracy down to under 12 inches.
Rym: Yeah, but as per all new receivers no existing device.
Rym: Like.
Rym: I think some of the newest GPS devices as of 2018 will even start to use that new band.
Rym: Yep 18 like 12 inches.
Rym: that is amazing.
Rym: Can you can do think about you could start making games based on GPS data with that level of precision?
Scott: Yeah, yeah, but so back and also, you know used to be when you want a GPS like at least for navigation You had to buy the standalone GPS device.
Scott: Yep, and then like I remember like the earlier 2000s you'd buy like a Garmin thing.
Rym: Yeah, right Garmin still around they make yeah But those devices would basically just tell you your latitude longitude altitude.
Scott: All those devices were were just a GPS and maps and nothing else.
Rym: most of those devices used to be just Latitude longitude altitude and then you had to either buy a data set that oh, yeah Yes and charts or usually you do a mapping charting or navigation system subscribe to the map thing, right?
Scott: Yeah, but now Everyone just got it in their phone.
Scott: It's way easier.
Scott: Yep, you don't got to pay shit Google just give it to you for free in exchange for all your data.
Rym: But that shows the kind of like how the internet was just this Network to connect very large computers to each other and keep them connected even if a city disappeared.
Rym: GPS was a technology that was just designed basically, so that American bombers and warships could figure out where they are and target weapons and then Coupled that system being released to the public.
Rym: coupled with these free data sets like Google Maps those two technologies existing together in a public space allowed this explosion of Capabilities that hardly anyone had ever even imagined radically changed the way we interact with the world.
Scott: Well, look the military made both of these things the internet and the GPS and then made both of them just yeah for everybody Right.
Scott: Imagine if the entire military budget was spent on making things like that and not just some of it.
Rym: or Imagine if our government was more functional and more of these kinds of things were turned into public services.
Scott: Yes, the public service aircraft carrier way better than the airport.
Scott: It just comes to you and you get on in the plane takes home.
Scott: How great is that?
Scott: Man, we should just get rid of it.
Rym: I could see something.
Rym: I feel like US military drone technology could be leveraged in the civilian sphere and kill a lot fewer people.
Rym: Yeah, okay, but like GPS Really is a big deal.
Scott: I think what happened is that when it was really new I think is when it was first made away when people first became aware of it and had access to it.
Scott: It was amazing and now people don't understand how it works At least always.
Scott: I guess that you know.
Scott: back in the day when it was new the people who did have it did Understand how it works.
Scott: is it was only nerds who cared a lot?
Rym: Yeah Like on my phone it would take my phone like five plus minutes to actually get a GPS sync.
Scott: Right, like when I got my smart, right, but now It's like yeah, there's still that those still those nerds still understand how it works But there's just so many more users who don't right now So many users who don't understand and don't appreciate.
Scott: So there's this impression that like people forgot how it works and it's like no It just has a bunch of users now that weren't users before right that don't know or don't care.
Scott: They just take it for granted.
Scott: and it's like you need to realize.
Scott: this is like a military project that you were using when you're like How do I get to grandma's house that relies on general relativity and Einstein's crazy theories that have been proven to have practical?
Scott: Applicability the internet which has now been you know corporatized and internationalized to some extent at least DNS GPS has not.
Rym: the US military continues.
Scott: All those satellites are launched by the Air Force from an Air Force base on an Air Force rocket.
Scott: Right that huge military budget.
Scott: We're like, oh the military budget is so big.
Scott: Well some small portion of that is putting all the satellite.
Rym: Go to the Wikipedia page and look up the emblem for the US Air Force 50th Spacewing.
Rym: their icon is it's just says master of space and it's like a Griffin.
Scott: Yeah See if I could see that's the thing is if I could sign up for the Air Force and be guaranteed To be in that section only and not have to kill anybody Right, then I might be okay with that.
Rym: Yeah, but you're in direct.
Rym: I mean GPS.
Rym: GPS Existed first and foremost to allow our weapons to be able to more effectively kill the right people.
Scott: I would say ah blow up when you are in this place, which is the enemy city.
Scott: How will I know when I am in that place?
Scott: Well, we have launched 30-something satellites.
Scott: Yeah, that will help you figure out when you're in the right place.
Scott: So when you get your latitude is X and your longitude is Y blow the fuck up.
Rym: So the key takeaways here are one the whole Private military like hidden military secret project to public service.
Rym: That is a pathway We need to exploit more to.
Rym: GPS is fucking amazing.
Rym: And I don't think you understand how new it is.
Rym: and Three it is one way.
Rym: GPS itself is literally a one-way thing.
Rym: The GPS system cannot track you, right?
Scott: You can get a GPS device that will tell you where you are And if it's not a cell phone It won't tell anyone else where you are either.
Rym: for if there ever is a serious major war in the world GPS will probably be turned off for a period for at least for us.
Scott: Well for everybody except the US military and lazy NATO or anyone who has stolen military GPS devices, yeah And has probably you're probably gonna need like codes to enter into them or something to like turn on the secret mode or some shit.
Scott: Yeah, you know how they work.
Scott: We don't know.
Scott: It's secret.
Rym: I do also imagine that a lot of military things will use a lot of first principles navigation techniques that are super classified.
Scott: I still make everyone learn them.
Rym: Yeah, I mean if you're like if an aircraft carrier is out in the ocean and GPS goes down They still gotta fucking be able to navigate.
Rym: and you know if they're gonna do they're gonna bust out sextants and shit and radar.
Rym: Yep Compasses like ship captains still know how to navigate.
Rym: They got an aircraft carrier.
Scott: They can have a plane take off and look around.
Rym: When I was doing my like kid like space camp stuff I learned how to navigate an airplane using all that old technology.
Rym: and like dead reckoning and airspeed stuff I know how to navigate an airplane.
Scott: You have a compass and you look out the window And you say what's that down there?
Rym: All right, what's that down there?
Scott: It looks like that looks like my map.
Rym: What's that down there?
Rym: blue ocean in every direction?
Scott: Oh, fuck me.
Rym: Do you know how?
Rym: In World War two before we had any of this shit, you know aircraft found their way back to aircraft carriers.
Scott: They sent a smoke signal or something flags.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Uh, it's it's actually really fascinating Big horn, so they flashed a light at him depending on what year it was.
Rym: The answers ranged from it.
Rym: better not have moved to to good luck To.
Rym: they're gonna turn their lights on.
Rym: I hope you got close enough.
Rym: I eventually guess the light method now - well everybody landed on a different aircraft carrier.
Scott: because fuck me or I don't go back to the aircraft carrier I go back to land somewhere land or I go I fight until I run out of fuel or die and then get out.
Rym: Oh, I crash in China and try to make my way home on my own.
Rym: When radar appeared it turned into.
Rym: they will point radar in the direction of the target and the plays will follow the radar back.
Rym: But guess what?
Rym: Anyone can follow that radar back.
Scott: I followed it back to the enemy base.
Scott: Yeah Like well, I guess I'm here.
Scott: I can drop the bomb on it, but Then I'm in trouble.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening.
Rym: music can't leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and make comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Rym: It's actually recorded at night And the patreon patreons for this resumed episode of GeekNights.
Rym: Now that we're back from our head is our Greg Oliver Allen Joyce, Heidi McNichol, JustLikeADooGuy, chartovision, William Eisneros, Link Eiji, Hydrated Gannon, Boogaloo, Graham Finch, Jennifer Hitchcock, Chris Midkiff, mystati.com, Jay Bans, Shawn Yeager, Nicholas Brando, Let's See If Rym Says Toronto.
Rym: Properly, 421 Creations, Now This is a Story All About How My Life Got Flipped Turned, Upside, Shervin, Von Orl, Rory, Superboy, Clinton Walton, Rym From New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, Drovenlander, Finn, Dreadily Tenebrae, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer, Thomas Hahn, We're back baby and now I'm gonna leave you with a song that you'll think you recognize but you won't be able to say what it's from and it's going to haunt you and I'm not gonna fucking tell you.
Rym: I leave you with...