Rym: It's Tuesday February 26th 2019.
Rym: I'm Rym, I'm scared and this is GeekNights tonight.
Rym: We are reviewing war groove.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So as you all know I'm not a young man anymore.
Rym: so it got warm out like weirdly warm when Yesterday Oh is inside all day.
Rym: It was like 50 degrees like I was out.
Scott: That's cold.
Rym: that's warm for winter that's warm for February It's cold.
Rym: so I was outside decided to go for a run because it was warm outside.
Rym: So I went outside and I was gonna run a short distance.
Rym: I ended up running a half marathon because that's what I do and today Feeling a little bit.
Rym: I like to say that 35 ain't 25, and I'm a few years past 35 at this point Mm-hmm.
Rym: But weirdly enough despite like the first run of the season on this weirdly warm day in the middle of nowhere I still got my third best time ever.
Rym: so maybe there's hope for this old man By the time it's undefeated.
Rym: Yep, but I'm gonna put up a good fight, okay?
Rym: So you got any news on this gaming day?
Scott: Yeah, there was a huge gaming news between our last episode and this one probably because we bailed on one And that is that Reggie the famous Reggie Fils-aime Pronounced.
Scott: I still can't remember 15 years.
Scott: I can't pronounce.
Rym: I was listening to a gaming podcast like gaming news and two different people on this podcast Pronounced it different ways as of last week, so hey, we'll just call him.
Scott: This is why everyone just calls him Reggie.
Scott: anyway He is retiring and he is gonna go to the beach like a wise individual.
Scott: It doesn't seem like he has plans to go work anywhere else, so if you don't know I mean I can't imagine you wouldn't know.
Scott: but way back in the day Right nobody knew anyone who works at Nintendo except basically Miyamoto, right?
Scott: That's like if you knew any name in Nintendo.
Scott: That's the name you knew.
Rym: if you're every window power you knew about.
Scott: you know a few more.
Rym: You know you will you knew?
Rym: You know at most two names Because of that Nester comic.
Scott: the point is that people would all these kids in elementary school would be like oh Yeah, my uncle works at Nintendo is like this old joke like my girlfriend from Canada.
Scott: It's the same kind of joke right?
Scott: cuz no one knew who worked at Nintendo or like you know.
Scott: kids imagined Nintendo like you know they had like this.
Scott: you know it's like a Willy Wonka situation right you know they imagined It was like some incredible place, but nowadays We know that Nintendo Japan is where all the actual stuff happens Nintendo of America Nintendo of Europe all those places.
Scott: all they do is distribution mostly marketing Also some translation type stuff occasionally making terrible mistakes customer service Logistics these sorts of things.
Scott: you know.
Scott: just to take the product.
Scott: their job is to take the product that real Nintendo in Japan is made and deliver it right to other places on earth.
Scott: yep, and The thing that Reggie has done in his 15 years on that job is somehow Make that job Matter.
Scott: the person who had that job before was a Japanese person that no one remembers the name of and no one cares, right?
Scott: Reggie was like this you know he somehow managed to over his 15 year career Never crossed the line to where he would upset the Japanese who were actually his bosses.
Scott: Well at the same time Pushing the line enough to get the right things to happen ever once did he do anything that would actually make them upset that anyone Knows about because obviously they never got fired or in trouble You know.
Scott: so he'd always like talk in a very political business II way But yet he would go basically as hard as he could to be fun.
Scott: I'm this.
Scott: I'm the president of Nintendo.
Scott: Before he was president He was still like the face of Nintendo America even before then because I remember him when he was just you know that the VP of marketing or whatever for Nintendo or whatever.
Scott: his previous job was some VP job, and he was still the face of Nintendo America at that time, right?
Scott: He's like.
Scott: we knew him before he was president and now He's retiring to go to the beach as you should yep, and the guy who's taking over the internet had a field day.
Scott: Cuz his name.
Scott: he's the ease.
Scott: I think he has the job that Reggie used to have like no Marketing because the job is mostly a marketing job.
Rym: all that says is this nominative determinism.
Scott: the guy's name is Doug Bowser And in the back of a photo of him and presumably in his office there were some Nintendo plushies and the Mario and Luigi Plushies were tied together with like a controller a Kidnap back-to-back
Rym: hostage style
Scott: saying he knows what his name is and what his job is.
Scott: But since he's not a person who like we've ever seen or heard from before in public I'm wondering if he will be as public and you know outward in the position as Reggie was.
Rym: I Imagine they want to keep this like the relationship.
Rym: They've got going now with the American audience alive.
Rym: I feel like that was part of the job description now.
Scott: I wonder also You know how public Reggie will be in his retirement, or will he be you know hidden away and disappeared like oh?
Scott: Whatever happened to him?
Rym: I mean I feel like the only ways to go.
Rym: if you step down from a position like that or either You just disappear and enjoy your life on the beach Yeah, but you go on it like a speaking this.
Scott: things he can do without you know working too much Right like do interviews and tell well that's a little before going.
Scott: you know speaking gigs.
Rym: option Two is the low-key speaking gigs that do not rock the boat.
Scott: You know the kind of stuff that like former presidents do.
Rym: option three is former presidents tell all here's what I would have done.
Rym: mother Three let's go right.
Scott: You know he can be like.
Scott: you know.
Scott: yeah, you know they tell.
Scott: you know I'm sure he has some.
Scott: you know ndas and stuff.
Scott: They could sue him if he's too bad.
Scott: Yeah, you know you get the idea, but yeah I guess you know even if you don't care about Nintendo right it's weird like do you know who the president in Nintendo Europe is?
Scott: Right?
Scott: no because I mean I think I've seen their name in some articles before but clearly they're doing a much shittier job Than Reggie did.
Scott: right you know Reggie is someone who will be I guess missed and was maybe under-appreciated until now.
Scott: you realize like uh yeah Cuz we had it we had a good for 15 plus years.
Rym: Yep, Nintendo's been doing the right things as far as the North American market has been.
Scott: I mean he has never done wrong With regards to the things he had power to do.
Scott: true true And the only really come.
Scott: any complaint that anyone could levy a Reggie about how he did his job Were things that were beyond his control because like I said he never pushed the line and upset the Japanese people.
Scott: It's like bring us mother three.
Scott: It's like he could have got.
Scott: how do we know he could have gone to the Japanese people and said like bring mother three like A hundred times, but they make they call it shots and everything.
Rym: yeah, what are you gonna?
Scott: Do I heard I've heard rumors of stories where he said things in meetings and the Japanese people just like scoffing.
Scott: nor him or I think the only I think someone said the only influence Reggie ever had in the product is one time He said hey, maybe you should sell switch doc separately, and they did.
Scott: that's the rumor I've heard That you know.
Rym: so I guess it'll be interesting to see What public persona coalesces around Bowser right.
Scott: is he gonna be like a Tim Cook or he's not quite a Steve Jobs situation?
Rym: I feel like that's nothing I get.
Scott: it's like it's hard.
Scott: It's a hard shoe to fill.
Rym: I feel like he's got a curry bow shoe is the hardest shoe to fell right.
Rym: I feel like Because of the name.
Rym: you gotta lean into that.
Scott: But he could end up being corny with it and not you know sincere and do it in a good Sincere but with like a slight evil edge like a little.
Rym: you got to play the evil like subtle and appropriate Like the year of Luigi.
Rym: I feel like you're gonna have the year of Waluigi.
Rym: Just like sneak its way in.
Rym: Nobody wants the year of Waluigi.
Rym: no so in some other news you might have noticed We're not gonna talk about all this, but there have been a ton of layoffs.
Scott: We talked about the Blizzard.
Rym: one Yeah But not just Blizzard like basically as far as I can see like half the Australian game dev scene Just got laid off like tons of layoffs in the video game industry, which ah There's a lot of reasons for that.
Rym: I don't want to speculate publicly too much.
Rym: part of it might be that Stock markets globally not doing great for a lot of reasons a lot of companies not as profitable as the market wanted them to be Even if they were otherwise very successful.
Rym: a good way to get more Investor interest is to have layoffs to reduce cost etc.
Rym: etc.
Rym: But a quiet layoff happened that the GeekNights listener might care about quite a bit.
Rym: So this is Kotaku dateline for theater.
Rym: at 30 p.m.. Eastern Standard Time today GOG just laid off like a day yesterday.
Rym: ah Yes yesterday.
Rym: well This happened.
Rym: dateline for 30 p.m.. On the 25th, which is not tonight when we are recording this show.
Rym: So GOG laid off apparently a dozen people and what's interesting?
Scott: They're not that big so it doesn't a large percentage of their people.
Rym: yeah GOG is the DRM free like cool kids place to buy your games.
Scott: The main thing about GOG is like they do sell some newer games and some other stuff.
Scott: Yeah, it seems to be some relation between GOG and humble bundle.
Scott: That's vague.
Scott: I'm not sure about that, but They main thing that they have going for them that say steam You know does doesn't have going for them so much is that there's a lot of way.
Scott: old DOS era type PC games that are available on GOG that you can buy on GOG DRM free and They include DOS box and everything else already set up ready to run, so they're pretty cool.
Rym: Yeah So they've laid off a bunch of people and what's interesting and they're making that much money.
Rym: Yeah, well now.
Rym: So if you didn't know they're by.
Scott: it feels like people bought their DOS games from GOG and then didn't buy anything else there.
Scott: I mean on steam they only.
Scott: so I only go to GOG.
Scott: calm when I see a link that says Something's free on GOG today.
Scott: I go there I click the link to add it to my GOG library and then I leave.
Scott: of course even then I forget to go play it.
Rym: Some of the things I would have bought on GOG I just forgot to and then they ended up on steam.
Rym: and I bought him on steam because it was just easier.
Scott: Well, that's the thing is buy them on steam.
Scott: It's easier and also you buy it on steam.
Scott: It's usually cheaper, right?
Scott: I mean GOG does have some crazy sales just like steam, but it's like, you know steam DRM free.
Scott: It's like I've had steam account for as long as Reggie was president.
Scott: So I'm not.
Scott: well, I'm not too worried about the DRM aspect of steam.
Rym: So GOG said that quote.
Rym: we've been a rearranging certain team since October 2018 Effecting and closing around a dozen positions last week blah blah blah.
Rym: They basically said that.
Rym: despite that they've welcomed nearly twice as many new team members as they laid off and they currently have 20 open Positions, it's always interesting when a company lays a bunch of people off and simultaneously has a whole bunch of open positions to fill.
Scott: Well, I mean it could just be that like hey They decided they want to do less of X and more of Y. so it's like.
Scott: well I want to do.
Scott: you know, if I'm making a video game for example, right?
Scott: I'm a video game studio and maybe I realize like hey, I don't need you know, the markets changed.
Scott: I don't need fancy graphics to sell my games anymore.
Scott: I need Microtransactions and gambling.
Scott: so I fire all my artists and I hire a bunch of psychologists and people from the gambling industry To make them help make my loot box better, right?
Scott: Yeah, I'm laying pla 20 people love and I heard 20 people.
Scott: It's a problem.
Rym: So here's an alternative perspective.
Rym: I'm quoting Kotaku here because this is relatively breaking news.
Rym: One person who was laid off from GOG last week offered a different perspective Saying that laid off staff were told that this was a move made by a company in dire straits.
Rym: That person estimated the layoffs that hit 10% of GOG staff.
Scott: That sounds right.
Rym: Yeah, so it's likely that GOG not making money Potentially losing money May be growing in terms of like its costs.
Scott: Well, it could be that the people they just hired, right?
Scott: It was like oops too many.
Scott: and then companies even that will often put up lots of open positions.
Scott: They won't suddenly like take those down because then it looks like they're in dire straits.
Scott: So they companies will often have open positions listed and simply not hire anyone.
Rym: I know for a fact that certain unnamed game companies in the last few years have done just that.
Rym: they have literally Hired people who because they had open positions while they were planning to lay off a large number of people Including the people they just hired they continued hiring for positions that were already Flagged as being redundant or going to be removed.
Rym: that is not uncommon in the games industry.
Rym: Yeah I'm not saying GOG did this.
Scott: I'm saying that happens because if you suddenly take down the open positions You're like revealing your financial in news - at the wrong time for Wall Street or whatever.
Rym: Yeah, or not even Wall Street.
Rym: if you think people don't notice that people who work for companies like this There they know when something's up and they're like one person will notice that a job posting Like fell through or disappeared and then suddenly literally everyone will know.
Rym: So in some other brief news, I got a little geek bite that I want to share.
Rym: So, uh, you know, I got a Oculus Rift and I play a whole bunch of VR games.
Rym: There's a little game that you might not notice.
Rym: There's a non VR version.
Rym: I guess I don't see why you would ever want to play this game not in VR.
Scott: I think it's on the same reason like you would never play the bomb game.
Scott: Don't talk it.
Scott: No one explodes.
Scott: Play that and not VR.
Rym: Yeah, like if you got like that's a game that's a must play game.
Rym: If you got VR not worth it.
Rym: Otherwise, yeah thumper if I hadn't after the rabbit, uh So it's hard to say why it's called thumper.
Rym: But the gist of this game is that it is a VR spiritual successor to Vib ribbon.
Scott: All right, so it's a rhythm game.
Rym: It's a rhythm game, but the shtick the reason why it's interesting music is good.
Rym: The music is fantastic.
Scott: You're loading your own music.
Rym: not that I'm aware of but I don't want to give ribbon on ps1.
Scott: I'm pretty sure you could take the river of in discount putting your own audio CD Yep with the red book audio and you could and I remember one time we did that at Luke's house back at RIT And had a really good time with it.
Rym: But thumper is a psychedelic experience.
Rym: It is like It's scarily immersive and intense to play.
Rym: the rhythm game component is very simple and much like Vib ribbon It starts with a very simple like.
Rym: you only have two buttons.
Rym: you can use the stick to turn your direction on a track and you can Hit a button and the button will do a thing and bit by bit it increases the complexity.
Rym: It increases the complexity in a really nuanced and clever way.
Rym: but the shtick is that you're basically in this infinite crazy not like four dimensional space-time and You're basically fighting the Cthulhu style.
Rym: old gods one by one with your rhythm skills.
Scott: sounds like rez Yeah, so maybe like something I'm surprised.
Scott: rez is the one that came with like that vibrating thing, right?
Scott: Yeah, especially so it's like why doesn't someone just make a game where you get an old rez controller and it's in VR?
Scott: It just sounds pretty close.
Rym: Uh, I think this is better than rez.
Rym: I think it's more fun to play rez.
Rym: I've seen people play rez.
Rym: I've seen video of rez.
Rym: This looks like it's better than rez.
Rym: Anyway, I mean someone could prove me wrong.
Rym: I haven't actually played rez, but this game is real good.
Rym: So if you have an oculus then you should just like.
Rym: this is one of those games.
Rym: You should just buy and play.
Rym: but anyway things of the day.
Rym: What do you got?
Scott: so an Instagram right if you take photos of like the story mode of whatever you can like put stuff on The photos like text and emojis and effects and all kinds of stuff.
Scott: What I didn't know is that you can totally do that in like videos in Instagram and they added a feature apparently where you can pin things to objects in the video.
Scott: so I for example, I could take a pic a video of like the back of Rym's shirt and Create like a virtual kick me sign and even though I'm moving around and Rym's moving around It will stick that you know, it'll recognize Rym and try to keep that kick me sign on his back All right.
Rym: Yeah, not bad.
Rym: Like that's.
Rym: that's moderately easy to do in like Premiere or After Effects.
Scott: You can do it in Instagram like in real time while you're like.
Rym: It'll be a little janky, but it'll work for the purposes of a meme.
Scott: Anyway, so it's the it's like called the pinning tool.
Scott: So this dude he's demonstrating the pinning tool and to demonstrate the pinning tool.
Scott: He's in New York.
Scott: clearly he videos some pigeons and he puts funny text on the individual pigeons and That and that funny text is both a funny showing you how to creatively use the pinning tool for humor But also it instructive and shows you how to use the pinning tool Effectively, right.
Scott: so you can now make your own similar videos.
Scott: Well and not crapily.
Scott: so Maybe I'll make if I get some ideas.
Scott: I'll make funny videos at the pinning tool and This person for creative inspiration and also technical know-how.
Rym: So when Scott sent me this as this thing of the day the first thing I thought was really a tweet.
Rym: But I laughed out loud at the first one the winner for best sidewalk.
Rym: I laughed out loud.
Rym: So if Scott's thing of the day is a really good tweet my thing of the day is an hour-long video.
Rym: great However, so SB nation has a bunch of good sports videos and it's Tuesday.
Scott: So small down all they do.
Scott: Yeah, maybe they're hiring They who got laid off from GOG.
Rym: They have a really good series.
Rym: I think I linked to is the thing of the day a while ago on weird rules and sports.
Rym: They're like, this is why you can't make a snowman In front of the net before you run away to pull the goalie like they made a rule because someone literally did it one time.
Rym: Yeah, this video is an hour long and it is a data-driven search for in the entire modern NFL The saddest punt ever.
Scott: I mean, it's I don't need a like a survey.
Scott: I can just tell you it's Matt Dodge.
Rym: Well, it's not.
Scott: how is it not?
Scott: they're wrong.
Rym: So here's the thing this video.
Rym: It's a goddamn hour-long video that gives a lot of context about every like the 46,000 punts in recent history in the NFL.
Rym: in detail as to what would make a punt said Why do you punt?
Rym: when do you punt?
Rym: when do people normally punt?
Rym: when have teams fucked up and punted when they shouldn't have?
Rym: Etc.
Rym: and eventually it settles on at about the 20-minute mark the mathematical formula to determine the Sadness of a punts.
Rym: and then from there For example, if you punt on the third like third and five when you're losing that's pretty fucking sad.
Rym: Like yeah, why don't you try to get yardage?
Rym: Like why are you punting?
Rym: and it goes on like the further down could be a quick kick situation.
Scott: I've seen that a couple times in my life.
Scott: Oh, yes.
Scott: I've seen Tom Brady do the the quick kick Yep.
Rym: So it covers that.
Rym: it's basically this combination of field position distance to first down the current score.
Rym: Like are you losing by a lot versus?
Rym: are you losing by a little versus?
Rym: are you up a little bit?
Rym: How much time is left on the clock?
Rym: and then there's a magic veto.
Rym: for was there an extenuating circumstance?
Rym: Like was it a clever quick kick?
Rym: and then the formula determines a sadness rating.
Scott: Usually you do the quick kick is like where the quarterback will do a crappy punt because they're quarterback Yep, right on third down because the other team has no idea you're punting.
Scott: So basically you kick it downfield not very far But now there's no way the other team will not won't have a return man down there?
Scott: Yeah to get the punt so there's no way they can return.
Scott: is that that's a quick kick for any football nerds?
Scott: So a typical punt in a football I'm sure on YouTube if you type Tom Brady quick kick You'll see it.
Rym: So a typical punt in a football game in the modern NFL will get a sadness score of between one and three based on this math.
Rym: Then for the rest of the video we go through the ten saddest punts in history, which have scores in the upper three hundreds.
Rym: It's really funny.
Rym: this is a really engaging and fascinating video.
Scott: I don't know how Matt Dodge wasn't number one, but it's got to be up there.
Rym: Yeah, you should watch the like.
Rym: this video is actually in my opinion.
Scott: Is Matt Dodge even mentioned?
Rym: Watch your video.
Rym: It's an hour long.
Scott: You can.
Scott: now it's an hour fucking long.
Scott: It was someone posted a video on the other day where?
Scott: Someone was riding a motorcycle up a Japanese mountain and on the side of the road on the Japanese mountain was a statue of Sonic the Hedgehog on a snowboard Just randomly on the side of a mountain.
Scott: and this this Motorcycle guy stopped took a photo of his bike next to the Sonic statue and there's a 15-minute video of like.
Scott: Why is this statue there?
Scott: And I'm like, I'm not watching a 15-minute fucking video.
Rym: There's a chance.
Scott: Fuck the statue is there.
Rym: there's a chance.
Rym: There's a 15-minute long explanation.
Scott: No So someone one person in the comments was like we actually don't know.
Scott: the guy just speculated and his number one Speculation was the town Bought it after like it was used as like a display at some game packs equivalent game fair type thing in Japan and then they just stuck it in the side of the road because when it snows it looks like he's snowboarding.
Scott: So this video has been sitting there ever since.
Rym: this video is not like an hour wasting your time just for the list.
Scott: This video is mostly an explanation of like the statistical mechanics Statistics to know that mad dodge is the saddest part of all time.
Rym: It's fascinating though to look at like all these methods your piece of shit Eagles Like.
Rym: it talks about how up to a point the pooch punt was a pretty valuable thing and then for various reasons It suddenly became non-viable and then it talks about the last fucking attempt at a pooch fund.
Rym: this is this is just a really fun video that I enjoy deeply because it's so statistically driven and you get to see a lot of footage from like Early 2000s football which again reminds you that TV looked like shit.
Scott: TV look like garbage.
Rym: yep, the other funniest part of this video is there's a Rada in the YouTube comment because in a video this long you're gonna make some mistakes and At 40 31 I'm gonna read the quote.
Rym: as to the errata for this video because they made a mistake about the city of Buffalo quote.
Rym: I can't believe I did this.
Rym: the bills are not Buffalo's only major sports team.
Rym: I forgot about the NHL's own Buffalo Sabres.
Rym: sincere apologies.
Rym: He literally forgot SV nation forgot that Buffalo has an NHL team.
Scott: Well, I mean, it's a football expert.
Rym: Yeah, but you forget that the Sabres exist.
Scott: I mean Not everyone knows every sports team.
Scott: Yeah, can you name every sport every NFL team even hell?
Rym: No, mr.
Scott: Mr Punting thing of the day hell.
Rym: no, I can probably name two-thirds of them.
Scott: I could I could do it, but I'm pretty sure I could do it, but it would be slow.
Scott: Yeah, I had to go I had to look at a map and like really yeah, even NHL I could do it.
Rym: But I get a look at a map of cities to remind.
Scott: I just have to look at it.
Scott: I just I just need a graphic of the u.s.
Scott: So I can go state-by-state.
Scott: I don't even need any lines on it except for the state lines For the NFL.
Scott: definitely don't need any words on it for the NHL.
Rym: No, I just need a map so I can go like west to east to like remember where I am.
Scott: But the Canada map though - yeah, yeah, can you find Winnipeg on a Canada map?
Rym: Yeah So my trouble would be the the NBA.
Rym: I probably couldn't name more than like 20 teams and baseball 10 maybe I just don't.
Rym: The other funny thing about SB nation is a lot of their videos the they have this running gag of The.
Rym: the primary goal of anyone playing baseball is to find an excuse to sneak out of a game and not get noticed.
Rym: They really don't like baseball.
Rym: So anyway in the meta moment, we are actually doing the book club.
Rym: We're both.
Rym: I have.
Rym: I am nearly I'm like halfway through reading The book club book.
Scott: it took me exactly the amount of time that the Kindle predicted it would take me.
Scott: It was like a six seven subway ride book.
Scott: Maybe seven.
Rym: I started reading it on Sunday and I'm already about a third of the way.
Scott: This is the longest we have gone Book club wise without doing the book club.
Scott: Not that I didn't read any books that within that time period actually read like Yeah, that wasn't for the book club like six novels worth.
Scott: but Yeah, it didn't take very long to read 2001 a Space Odyssey which we will discuss this Thursday Yep, and this Rym fails unless I fail to finish the book by that.
Rym: I think I'll finish it unless things are real short.
Scott: I read it like so fast.
Rym: No, I burned through like two chapters just while I was pooping today.
Scott: Yeah, that's about right.
Rym: So otherwise we will be live at two upcoming conventions gig nights not Scott just rain will be a zinc icon doing a bunch of Panels, I don't remember which panels I'm doing nor do I know when they are but I'm assuming someone will point me in the direction of the panel room.
Rym: It's funny.
Rym: when I'm at a non packs I will be at home sleeping me like when Scott and I are at pax's.
Scott: it's warm enough to maybe start biking.
Rym: We've gone to so many conventions over the years.
Rym: that packs and magfest.
Rym: We're like.
Rym: we're so into that.
Rym: like we show up to the panel room like an hour before the panel We're like, you're not that early.
Scott: Well, exactly.
Rym: Well 40 minutes because then at a half hour, they let it in I'm like 30 or 20.
Rym: Well, we don't let us into the room until 30 minutes before and then we have to set up all the cameras and do all The crap and get the pre-roll go in.
Rym: but any non packs non magfest I feel like.
Rym: I feel like that anime guests like the voice actor who just kind of staggers into the con and is like So, where am I going?
Rym: What am I doing?
Rym: What city are we in?
Rym: But Zenkai Con is a fun con.
Rym: I do like performing there because the people who see us perform at Zenkai Con are not the kind of people who go to packs or like anime Boston when we used to go there and it's like this entirely new audience where I Can amaze them with things like.
Rym: I can show them that slide from that Game panel where we show like the two ponds and the chutes and ladders thing and ask the question Which one of these ponds is currently winning the game and blow everybody's mind?
Rym: I can I can bring out like packs gems Like.
Rym: does anyone know the real rules to monopoly?
Rym: and no one knows and I get to explain that whole thing all over again.
Rym: It's like babes to the slaughter.
Rym: It's a good time.
Scott: PAX East is way soon.
Rym: We're gonna be there Yep, and we're doing at least one panel.
Rym: We were gonna be doing the real harm of games.
Scott: I got this whole panel.
Scott: It's it's.
Scott: I just gotta actually construct it.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: What harm to games cause.
Rym: do they make school shooters?
Rym: Do they make Satanists?
Rym: I would argue Satanism isn't even a harm But in fact a boon.
Rym: what?
Rym: what did gate?
Rym: a lot of people thought games harmed us a whole bunch of different ways.
Rym: Did they actually harm us?
Rym: Is there any evidence of harm?
Rym: Well, yeah, probably and we're gonna talk about it.
Rym: It's gonna be a good panel.
Rym: Hmm.
Rym: So yeah, let's get right into it.
Rym: We well me I Have been desperate for a long time for a game to replace the hole in my heart that is advanced.
Scott: Well, you've been desperate for just more advanced war.
Rym: I fucking love advanced wars to a degree.
Rym: That is unhealthy.
Scott: It's been like one of our top game Franchises since college when I was brought to the United States.
Scott: I have played if you don't count that NES desert whatever was but I have played that.
Scott: in fact, I played desert.
Scott: I saw it in a magazine.
Rym: I rented desert commander from a non National video rentals chain that also had beta tapes.
Scott: Yeah, so people don't know.
Scott: the series started off way back.
Scott: There was Famicom Wars.
Scott: Yeah, it was Game Boy Wars.
Scott: There was Game Boy Color Wars.
Rym: I have played literally all of them.
Scott: I don't know if there was Super Nintendo Wars.
Scott: I have played never seen it if there might be it, but I never seen it.
Rym: I'm not beating them have The?
Scott: actually the Game Boy Color Wars is really fascinating.
Scott: I read an article about it and I've played.
Scott: I've tried to play the ROM of it on my DS lite which has achieved a piracy card and I couldn't figure it out.
Scott: And if you read the article about it, it was really crazy system wise compared to the other ones.
Scott: But the first one that came to the US was advanced wars on the GBA on the GBA Which is why it was called advanced wars and then because it was so relatively popular I guess compared to what they expected because it was an older advanced wars.
Rym: It was like a weird Famicom Wars, it was like the special one.
Rym: Well, it was.
Scott: I think it was a Game Boy Advance game, but it was called something else.
Rym: Well, cuz it was a Famicom Wars.
Rym: We're like all off or what's I got?
Rym: It's been so.
Rym: I'll forget some of the character names.
Rym: the one evil dude is dressed up as Santa cuz.
Scott: there's like if you like if you took Parodius the parody Gradius game and and reskinned it to actually be a serious Gradius game and released it as like Gradius in the US instead of you know, but anyway Yeah, there was Olaf.
Rym: Yep, anyway, so I have played literally every one of these games and I have perfect.
Rym: I have unlocked everything gotten every possible s-rank in every one of them.
Scott: I've also played all these games but far less well and far less thoroughly than remes.
Scott: Yeah, I got to the point to weigh less hours like in advanced wars days of ruin Which I would argue like I beat the bosses of them and did not get all s-ranks even though I got some s-ranks.
Scott: You know some s-ranks.
Rym: I got to the point where I could beat some like pretty big maps in like three turns with clever bullshit.
Rym: I I love obsessed with these games and I love them, right?
Scott: So for a while since Nintendo stopped putting out games in this series I guess entirely because I haven't seen any come out in Japan either Even though the switch would be great for them and the Wii would have been anyway And the DS would have been DS anyway.
Scott: So because Nintendo has stopped this series effectively Many many people especially in the US have been trying to recapture the magic.
Scott: there is a game for iOS It might be on Android also called war bits that I've played.
Scott: I have on my pad.
Scott: It's alright, it's it's pretty close to advance wars, but it's just missing something right?
Scott: There was that tiny metal and I guess no one even though it came out.
Scott: No one really got that excited about it.
Scott: I seen this one with hexes.
Scott: I played.
Scott: There's like a quite a few turn-based strategy games That all try to capture that advance wars, you know magic thing And none.
Scott: even though some of them Visually came close or mechanically came close or mechanically like super copied advance wars None of them really captured that magic and got people excited.
Scott: even advanced or his fans played them over like Right, yep, so finally this one comes War groove and I'm looking at and I'm like, well, I feel like this is just gonna be another one of those trying to be Advanced wars games that's not advanced wars and is gonna end up in the bin with tiny metal and war bits and all the others.
Scott: You know, how's this gonna go?
Scott: and so far?
Scott: I can't say that it's advanced wars, but it's done better than all the other imitators.
Scott: So it's like the best Elvis impersonator.
Rym: So I will say I already beat it.
Rym: I've already beaten every mission.
Scott: I've only played like a bunch of a handful of missions.
Rym: I just I beat it as fast as possible.
Scott: I got past the grass people.
Scott: That's about it.
Rym: So What I will say is that I've been playing auto chess instead.
Rym: That's why if you'll enjoy if you enjoyed advanced wars Particularly the first two advanced wars on the GPA not days of ruin But the like earlier advanced wars in the US favorite ones the DSM with the enemy dual strike.
Rym: That's the.
Rym: I think that's the most fun and the most broken one that I enjoyed it the most.
Rym: Yeah days of ruin was a better war game, but it wasn't as fun in that Ridiculous way as DS.
Rym: equally good but different.
Rym: Forget days of ruin all the previous advanced wars.
Rym: This is as close as anyone's ever gotten and it is clear the people who made war groove thought a lot about why people liked advanced wars and tried to make a game that Addressed those desires without just cloning advanced wars.
Rym: Like many of the units in the game have a pretty near one-to-one analog with units in advanced wars.
Scott: Yeah, like a knight is.
Scott: obviously it's a fantasy theme instead of a modern military theme.
Scott: But it's like yeah a knight is a tank.
Scott: the sketch the regular old Like what's it called the sword man?
Scott: That's an infantry.
Scott: Yeah the pikeman That's a mech.
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Scott: we know dog is a recon.
Scott: Yeah, you can.
Scott: every mission every unit pretty much has an analog unit Is analogous to a unit in advance wars, but not a whole neo tanks though, really?
Rym: No But it's not a hundred percent.
Rym: because so that some of the units function differently like for example the air units There's a harpy.
Rym: the harpy is arguably the.
Rym: it's like it's across for each.
Scott: It's actually it's not see That's what it's a bad right in advance wars all the different Militaries all have tank or neo tank or medium tank or whatever it is, right helicopter and they function differently and have different stats.
Scott: But they're all called the same thing and have the same icon in War bits.
Scott: this different orbits war groove or groove They all have a different theme even though they're the same.
Scott: so for example you got the harpy which is the helicopter of the bad Guys, yeah, and then no that's helicopter of the good guys.
Rym: All right, these are good in this game.
Scott: The good guys have the harpy as their helicopter, but on the evil nation, it's the.
Rym: it's the vampires, right?
Scott: It's functions the same mostly different stats.
Rym: Nope.
Rym: Same stats.
Scott: Oh is it?
Rym: Yeah, okay, but the harpy is identical to the vampire is identical to the whatever.
Rym: It's the air unit.
Scott: They don't but like there's not like.
Scott: nope.
Scott: There's no situation.
Scott: We're like not all those guys are at Sammy.
Scott: So the infantry is stronger or that's max of the tanks are stronger zero of that.
Scott: Ah, I didn't realize.
Scott: yeah But they do have a different icon.
Rym: They do have different icons and they do have different animations.
Scott: I said animation.
Scott: at first I was like, you know They got all these made all these new animations and they're super cute all these nice Graphics that are really cute and well animated even though they're pixely, you know, but advanced wars is pixely.
Scott: So that's what they do.
Scott: and right I'm gonna keep these animations on.
Scott: so I'm like, all right I kept them on.
Scott: then they were slow.
Scott: So I made them faster.
Scott: then I turned them off.
Rym: Yep I turn them off too, but before I saw them all because it's just.
Rym: but it's interesting because even in advanced wars Like you gotta have them there because they're super cute.
Rym: But anyone who plays the game seriously is gonna turn them all off.
Rym: after they see them all once Let me turn them off.
Scott: Good job.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So, uh If I had to give the high-level review like for real if you liked the early advanced wars games up through days up through Dual strike and you
Scott: played them all and don't have any you can't play anymore anymore because you beat them all with s-rank and everything.
Rym: These are a 90% like replacement for that.
Rym: They're a full spiritual successor.
Rym: You will enjoy war groove as much as you joined advanced wars.
Rym: It is the combination of that's kind of war gamey But also puzley coupled with really cute characters and that yay war aesthetic.
Rym: We're two generals will like have a dialogue of hey, you want to have a battle?
Rym: We haven't fought in a while.
Rym: I miss that.
Rym: Yeah, let's have a fight and then you have a war where people fucking die Like all over the place and then at the end the generals like oh man, that was a real good war.
Rym: Yeah Good times It's that it's that combination of the two.
Rym: He's got a pretty simple plot.
Rym: It is it is an advanced wars plot With the square boss, etc.
Rym: Like it follows the formula of advanced wars with anime characters.
Rym: Yeah, it's great.
Rym: If you like advanced wars you like this.
Scott: All right, so let's get some nitty-gritty, right?
Scott: So some mechanical differences between this and advanced wars that I noticed that are good and bad.
Scott: The number one is the critical hits.
Scott: that is but by far the Thing that I would say should even be added to advance or as good as it is such a good idea.
Scott: The way it works is each unit, you know does its normal damage when it attacks and fights.
Scott: You know the advantage to the attacker like in advance wars, even though I think it might be even in greater advantage.
Rym: Definitely feels like it's well in general more groove.
Rym: So in war groove if I had to because I'm actually gonna do well I've been live-streaming myself playing the game again.
Rym: I bought it on switch.
Rym: I beat it on switch now.
Rym: I bought it on steam so I gotta beat it again on steam so I can see the whole thing cross play.
Scott: so the only reason not to buy it on switch or steam or whatever platform is best for you is I bought it on steam just because.
Scott: but the only reason not to do that is because if you're worried that in 15 years They're gonna close the switch e-shop and you'll lose your game.
Rym: Yep, but I bought it on a switch because I wanted to play it portably.
Rym: Yeah, then I beat it like immediately.
Scott: I might re-buy it on iOS if it comes out in iOS.
Rym: No but So yeah, I'll be streaming it and talking about the detail.
Scott: So the point is critical hits.
Rym: but critical hits are part of a series of changes that all do the same thing.
Rym: They give a little bit of an advantage to the person who's taking risks being aggressive and attacking to avoid static fronts and the kinds of Static degenerate strategies that will rule the day in advance wars if you are a jerk who is highly skilled, right?
Scott: So for example critical hits.
Scott: the way they work is so each unit has a different way to critical hit.
Scott: So this pike man is the simplest.
Scott: if a pike man attacks while standing orthogonally adjacent to another pike man That is on your team.
Scott: It will do more damage than normal like a lot more damage like a hundred and fifty percent Like a shit ton more, right?
Scott: So each unit has a different way of scoring a critical hit like the basic sword man.
Scott: If the basic sword man attacks while standing orthogonally adjacent to your commander unit, it will do crazy more damage.
Scott: No, if a dog recon attacks a unit while you have another recon orthogonally adjacent to The unit that you're attacking it's like you're flanking, you know, this this guy with your your recon does way more damage.
Scott: Yep, all right.
Scott: So each unit and they get clever like battleships.
Rym: They do two more damage if they're on the beach because they're intended to attack the land like bombardment.
Scott: Yeah the knight does more damage if you attack something at maximum range and it does a Charges the full distance it can charge and then hits again.
Rym: Now, that's the only one I don't like because while I could Take advantage of that I'm not willing to put that much effort into making sure your nights at theory figure out where will be my opponent be next turn.
Scott: I will put my night exactly six seven, whatever spaces away.
Rym: I'm not willing to do that.
Scott: Yeah, I'm willing to move.
Rym: if I have 40 units on the board and I'm one turn away from victory I'll still move all 40 toward my goal just in case but I am not willing to make sure my Knights always hitting at six.
Scott: Yeah anyway Another major change from advance Wars Is that an advance was when you capture buildings you stand on them and sort of stomp on them until you convert them here to conquer buildings.
Scott: You state you can't stand on top of any building.
Scott: You can only attack it from the side.
Scott: So if you attack like an enemy city, it sort of defends itself a little bit and shoots back at you and then to capture it once it's neutral you just walk up next to it and then capture it.
Scott: and Almost any land unit can sort of attack the cities, but only certain ones can capture.
Scott: and it's a little bit different.
Scott: And as a result the bases, you know The barracks that build units since nothing can be on top of a building.
Scott: when you build a guy you choose which of the four Orthogonally adjacent spaces that guy will appear in and that doesn't matter too much.
Scott: Usually you do it in the most forward position But I guess when the fighting is near the barracks that can matter a shit ton.
Rym: No So There are other subtle changes like fog.
Scott: Those are the biggest one.
Rym: Yes fog of war works kind of differently.
Rym: I don't like it that much but it's it's barely used at all in the entire campaign, right?
Scott: You're the commander is at is instead of just being this vague, you know character is actually a unit on the board.
Scott: That's way strong.
Rym: you start with it, which is similar to what days of ruin does.
Rym: but in days of ruin You can put your commander in a regular unit right it died.
Scott: if it dies you lose When it fights in You.
Scott: so you think oh if it dies, I lose.
Scott: I'll just keep it back safe near my HQ, but no if it fights and gets in the mix That's how you build up your power meter.
Scott: And then the commander unit itself is the one that actually executes the special move In its near or on its location on the map.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So the commanders only have a local effect.
Rym: So it's sort of like this powerful unit.
Scott: Yeah, there's nothing like Andy heal all my units on the whole fucking board.
Scott: Yeah, like heal all the units close to my commander.
Scott: And the only way you can even get that power is if the commander goes around fighting.
Scott: So you got to get this unit in the mix fighting, but always keep it safe.
Scott: I've lost a lot of missions including against Rym.
Rym: Yeah That live stream.
Scott: I was basically dominating or almost sure to win against the computer or Rym and then just one turn.
Scott: I moved my commander into a stupid spot without Realizing how badly it can be damaged in that spot and it dies and I lose even though I was totally winning.
Scott: So I feel like what you want to do is you want to get your commander in the mix on pretty much most things and use that power when you need to.
Scott: but if you're ahead and You don't need the commander and the power in the mix.
Scott: Just pull it back and be safe.
Scott: Yep Surrounded with four pikemen high corner as soon as you're ahead and winning and you feel like you can roll the rest of the map.
Scott: But just your regular units.
Scott: just pull the commander away from the scene.
Scott: the commander You only need it early.
Scott: or if you're behind you don't need it.
Scott: If you're ahead play conservatively and hide the dude.
Rym: now like advanced wars playing playing in the arcade Equivalent like playing in like a symmetric map against the AI or playing against a human.
Rym: The strategies are very different from what you will do in the campaign because the campaign there's often tricks.
Rym: It's asymmetric.
Rym: There's like a mission like there's escort missions and all sorts of nonsense.
Rym: So they're very different but the campaign is real fun.
Rym: It's as fun as an advanced wars campaign.
Rym: The missions are pretty varied.
Rym: There are only Two annoying missions in the entire campaign and there are both side missions.
Scott: Oh, that's good.
Rym: Yeah You can just skip them if you want.
Rym: they're annoying because they're kind of like a lot of the campaign feels like the campaign of the first GBA advanced wars that came to the US.
Rym: They're that level of like puzzle.
Rym: the only difference is in advanced wars games the campaign is a little bit tighter in that there is all.
Rym: there is always like One particular trick you can do like.
Rym: there's always a clever way to beat the map Sammy usually Yep, and the normal way to beat the map.
Rym: There's pretty much only the normal way to meet the bat beat the map.
Rym: in this game Like you might see interesting terrain features and you might think oh Maybe there's a clever way to like send a guy around the walls.
Rym: now that never works in this game.
Rym: Don't even try it Yeah, but against the human it'll work.
Rym: Well again Scott it'll work.
Scott: You Know there's other small differences you'll notice.
Scott: like the wagon is a little more opie Oh God, so the APC is the wagon is the APC.
Scott: it moves so far also your unit can get.
Scott: so in advanced wars.
Scott: I'm pretty sure Rym will correct me if I'm wrong.
Scott: to get a unit into an APC.
Scott: Let's say an infantry moves three, right?
Scott: Sorry.
Scott: Yep they then the APC must be three away.
Scott: so the infantry ends its turn on top of the APC to enter it in the Wargroove.
Scott: the infantry can move three and then if the wagon is one more space away You can effectively get one free hex square of movement because the infantry will sort of jump into the adjacent wagon and then you can get a free movement at the end.
Scott: obviously when it jumps out and Also, the wagon feels like it moves way farther than the APC moved.
Rym: Yep so when like in regular advanced wars one of the one of the things a pro would do like the way you Need to have
Scott: if
Rym: you have a certain number of infantry you need to move you can use a Smaller number of APCs in conjunction with infantry by shuttling and moving in a correct way Even though you're not moving APCs the full distance they could move.
Rym: you can move a bunch of infantry together faster than any of them could move on their own.
Rym: and It's it's like this complicated trick you can pull off and it gets more complicated the more units you move.
Rym: That doesn't exist in this game because the APC moves so goddamn far.
Rym: You literally can just move someone all the way to the other side of the map and you sort of need to right.
Scott: because the Limiting thing in this game is that when you capture cities they give you money, but if you capture barracks They don't give you money.
Scott: yep, so you capture all the cities to get money.
Scott: But most of the maps I've played in the campaign even though It's mostly early campaign all the there's not a lot of barracks on these maps.
Scott: There's a map editor where you can make different maps But the barracks are near your HQ and there aren't a lot that are out in the field.
Scott: So the result is that you end up You know building guys moving him towards the front and then it takes a long Supply chain to get more guys to the front yo, and then unless you got a wagon to get them up there, right?
Scott: So speaking and you can you're really limited on how many guys you can make each turn.
Scott: You're using that wagon to get them up to the front all the time.
Rym: So speaking of supply chain one other major difference is there's no concept of unit fuel.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: I forgot about that.
Rym: So APCs are less valuable than they would be in advanced wars.
Rym: cuz advanced wars you use the APC to fuel units up.
Rym: Yep in this game if you build a witch which is the equivalent of a fighter Just fucking fly around forever people forget it.
Scott: like there's a lot of stuff for you.
Scott: think of advanced.
Scott: Where did you think?
Scott: oh simple turn-based strategy game.
Scott: advanced wars had two complicated like you know a few complicated tricks things going on With mostly the fuel.
Scott: that fuel system was kind of a complicated Advanced kind of thing.
Rym: Yeah bill like you got a fighter jets flying around you got to refuel them.
Rym: It's like combat air patrol refuel and re-ammo your stuff.
Scott: So like, you know, it's like you had the fuel and ammo for all these units.
Scott: It's like you send out your tank to the field and suddenly you can't do anything out there.
Scott: It's got to come back Even if it hasn't been damaged.
Scott: and also there were a lot of weird like people a lot of people in advanced wars.
Scott: don't remember.
Scott: You can put the helicopter on the destroyer Anything else on it But you can use a destroyer to move a helicopter way far and then it hops out and it's like, you know It's such a tiny tiny thing, but it's a real thing.
Scott: There's nothing like that in war group.
Scott: There's no fuel.
Scott: your night can just go around stabbing things forever.
Rym: Yep But what the game does kind of better than most advanced wars.
Rym: the only advanced wars that did this Well was days of ruin.
Rym: all the other advanced wars did this poorly.
Rym: this game has made sure that Navy's Like naval combat matters a lot in Conjunction with land combat if the if the map has me if the map has it But in the sense that naval units aren't just rock-paper-scissors among themselves.
Rym: It's actually much more complex than that and Naval units are sort of designed with the purpose of coming in like bombarding the shore and everything else is to protect the bombardment units.
Rym: It's a different dynamic than advanced wars that meant that and then early advanced wars.
Rym: that makes naval combat interesting, right?
Scott: I mean there was some of that in advance wars because the battleship could do some series.
Rym: It was pointless though until days of ruin.
Rym: Navy stuff was just bullshit.
Scott: But the battleship could do serious bombardment, but you just had you just build rockets - yeah Hey, they're almost as good right like a lot cheaper.
Rym: in Advanced wars up until days of ruin the land theater and the sea theater tended to be separate from one another.
Scott: in this game You can get a little bit anti-air in the sea.
Scott: it's also.
Scott: the map design matters a lot, right You know, you could make an advanced wars map.
Scott: We're like guess what?
Scott: It's a big fucking ocean between you and the other guy.
Scott: Deal with it and suddenly the Navy theater matters.
Rym: You haven't seen the naval units yet, but you'll see what I mean.
Rym: There's an.
Scott: I use them in a multiplayer.
Scott: There's a Navy infantry and oh, I didn't know that.
Rym: Yeah, and there's naval cities that are their own cities that can only be captured by Navy infantry.
Rym: Yeah Believe me when you get the Navy, you'll see I don't want to spend a ton of time on it right now.
Rym: But if you watch my live streams I'm going to literally make a video of every single map in this game and me beating it because I already beat it.
Scott: Yeah, the one thing that this has against every advance wars regardless of his quality is that it has online multiplayer crossplay between platforms.
Rym: It just works.
Scott: totally seems to work just fine.
Scott: We tried it a couple times and it worked mostly.
Scott: And you.
Scott: it's like one person on the switch one person on Steam.
Scott: you play against each other and you're good.
Rym: I am more than willing to get some multiplayer games going online with listeners.
Rym: Yeah, like that's something I want to do.
Rym: So anything else to say about live war groove unless I start getting into the like deep deep details of specific units.
Scott: We went into this the mildly deep details.
Scott: I think that's enough.
Rym: Yeah, this game like seriously if you've never played an advanced wars game just play this Works on a modern platform and you can see the deal.
Rym: if you enjoy this you should basically start working Backward through the advanced wars games in reverse chronological order of release Because they're not as good the older they get but they're still good.
Rym: But play it.
Rym: starting like if you like this game go play all the advanced wars games.
Rym: if you're desperate for more advanced wars.
Rym: Wargroove is so close fancy side note.
Scott: If you're interested in programming and making video games They just released like today or yesterday the engine for this war groove.
Scott: It's called like Wally or something like that.
Rym: Oh, yeah, you sent me a link to that right the source code for the engine.
Scott: not the source code for war groove But the source code for the engine.
Scott: war groove is made on.
Scott: it's a c++ game engine was put on github So you can take that engine there.
Scott: The documentation is like being filled in.
Scott: but you know, what's there is good documentation.
Scott: It's just incomplete.
Scott: And start making a game that is you know cross-platform and has network stack and the graphics and the audio.
Scott: It's got all the pieces you need to make a modern game.
Scott: It might even be a good choice.
Scott: I think yeah.
Scott: So, you know check that out.
Scott: game developers.
Rym: Oh, and I won't go through all the details now.
Rym: But there's already a major patch coming to the game because Chucklefish the company that made it.
Rym: they're pretty.
Rym: They seem pretty invested both in sequels and in supporting this game hard.
Rym: So there is a giant patch that has a ton of quality of life Improvements things like adding CPU players to online multiplayer games.
Rym: good idea Preventing the problem where you can accidentally end your turn by double-clicking too quickly.
Scott: that happens.
Rym: a lot happened to me Playing against Scott.
Rym: that almost caused me to lose.
Rym: Yep they're fixing some problems with fog of war and They're changing the difficulty system.
Rym: They're adding a checkpoint system which would have been real nice for some of the later missions.
Rym: Yep, but yeah, they're all.
Scott: Wait for that before I finish the game.
Rym: You probably should because the last mission in this game is The same as the last mission in every Advance Wars game.
Scott: It's just an enormous map with an enormous man with ridiculous bullshit and a very specific Conceit and a boss that does like it drops bombs on all your shit all the time.
Rym: Yep, and you have no Regular units, it's only hero like only commanders on your team.
Scott: Oh, that's the last map.
Scott: So it's sort of like one of those Warcraft maps where it's like in you.
Scott: instead of building a base You just moved this tiny troop of dudes around.
Rym: Yeah, something like that It was moderately.
Rym: it took me about seven tries to actually beat.
Scott: Hmm.
Scott: I mean, I'm sure it's beat up.
Scott: Oh, that's what matters, right?
Rym: Yep, I beat it in seven or eight tries without a checkpoint system.
Rym: Okay, basically the first two moves of it were annoying like the first two days But if you got past that you could just like steamroll the rest of it.
Rym: So yeah, it's really good.
Rym: It's really fun and you should all play it.
Rym: I can't recommend this game enough.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and make comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Rym: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Craig Oliver L enjoys hiding McNichol just like a dude guy chartavish in linkage You Jennifer Hitchcock Chris midgiff my stadium calm.
Rym: J band scoot alone Lee Roberto Kingsley Sean Yeager Matthew Smith Nicholas Brando Mr.
Rym: Strong stretch in 421 creations Chris Reimer and Thomas on.
Rym: Shervin Von Harl Rory Rochelle, Montanona Superboy sailor vista Joe Shiro Joe star Clinton Walton Ren from New Zealand Ryan parent rope and Lander Finn Daniel Redman Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomas on.
Rym: this has unfortunately been stuck in my head with these lyrics.
Rym: So now it can be stuck in your head.
Rym: I leave you with Security.
Rym: get a team to the mess hall right away.
Rym: He's been seized by the pond far.
Rym: a neurochemical imbalance is driving him to mate.
Rym: we won't be able to reason with him To fuck.
Rym: I understand you are a Vulcan man.
Rym: You have just gone without for seven years about Paris.
Rym: Please find a way to load a hypo spray.
Scott: I will give you the sign.
Scott: just aim for his.
Scott: behind Hormones are raging Synapses blazing.
Scott: it's also very Illogical Illogical Illogical.