Rym: It's Tuesday, June 18th, 2019.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, cadence of Hyrule.
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So normally when I buy things, many stores from the time I was a kid to today will try to sell you a scam extended warranty of some kind.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: The only scam extended warranty that I'll buy is AppleCare scam extended warranty.
Scott: All scam extended warranties can eat it.
Rym: Like I would go to Best Buy and I'd buy a video game and they would be like, "Do you want the extended
Rym: warranty?".
Rym: And I'd be like,
Rym: "No.".
Scott: Or even like on Amazon, I'll buy like a USB cable and a pop-up will appear like, "Hey, do you want to double the price of that USB cable for like a
Scott: warranty?".
Scott: And I'm like, "No, I could just buy another USB
Scott: cable.".
Rym: Yeah, what?
Rym: Am I going to accidentally choke on the USB cable?
Scott: Right, it's like anything.
Scott: It's like constantly popping up when you add to cart like, "Hey, give us more
Scott: money.".
Scott: It's like,
Scott: "No.".
Scott: However, it kind of looks like-- Hey, you're buying planes because you want to insure them.
Rym: You want to pay $14 to insure this one-hour flight?
Scott: Right.
Rym: No.
Rym: But there is a situation where I will buy those things.
Rym: And it is usually when I buy a very expensive piece of technology that I carry around and use heavily that I may drop or something.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Well, I mean, I got the AppleCare for like my very expensive iPad that I expect to last a long time.
Scott: That totally worked out because at one point it broke due to Apple's fall and they just gave me a brand new one.
Scott: Way back when I bought my-- There's no way I could fix my own iPad, vote for right to-- push your local representatives to get right to repair laws and such.
Rym: Way back when I bought my first fancy laptop, like the Ultrabook that I spent over $3,000 on back before Ultrabooks were a thing.
Rym: This was a long time ago.
Rym: This was a tiny laptop.
Rym: That Fujitsu thing?
Scott: I had one too.
Rym: Yeah, those are real good.
Scott: Because we were copying Steve Pomeroy who had one even before us.
Rym: Yeah, I love that laptop.
Rym: I only recently threw it away because it's worthless now, but it still works.
Rym: Well, it worked.
Scott: What happened to mine?
Scott: I forget.
Scott: I gave it to some of me.
Rym: Well, I threw it away.
Rym: I put it in one of those eRecycle things after wiping that spinning disk hard drive.
Rym: That thing had a Core 2 Duo in it, I think.
Scott: Thank you, Derek.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So I got it on that and then one time like the hinge broke because it was a little flimsy and just no questions asked, replaced it.
Rym: The like $30 I spent on that insurance was worth it.
Rym: But when I bought my big, my 4K like camera, the one I was going to use for GeekNights for Everything that I started videoing battles with, I bought that Amazon like, "Hey, three years, replace this thing.
Rym: No questions asked, even if you are
Rym: negligent.".
Rym: It cost me like 70 bucks for that.
Rym: And it would cover it.
Rym: So I figure if I'm spending more than $3,000 on a camera that I'm going to carry around and use a lot, and they will, no questions asked, fix it, if I just like drop it in the river in San Antonio, I feel like that's worth it.
Rym: And it did break in a way that was weird.
Scott: In a way that Rym did on purpose.
Rym: Why would I do it on purpose?
Rym: I love that camera.
Scott: I can see like a comic where like Rym's camera, his DS, his bike wheel, all this stuff is like sitting around like, you know, like wanting to murder, you know, as trying to ghost trying to haunt the prosecutor.
Rym: You know, I just want to go back to a day.
Rym: You always accused me of breaking things, but this is a story from before.
Rym: we were really even doing GeekNights.
Rym: Scott had an iPod mini.
Scott: I was demonstrating its durability.
Rym: And Scott would always, because I had a...
Scott: I already had an iPod nano at the time.
Rym: I had a non-iPod MP3 player that broke and Scott accused me of breaking it.
Rym: And he also accused me of buying something fragile.
Rym: And he said he constantly brings up how his iPad mini is invincible.
Scott: The iPod mini was invincible.
Rym: So to demonstrate this at one point, he tosses it on the carpeted floor and taps it with his foot and the screen just goes and shatters like comically shatters.
Scott: It was a comic event indeed.
Rym: Like as much as I want to make fun of you for breaking it on purpose, maybe in a drawer, in your drunk drawer.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: But it was like the fact that I had seen Scott like drop this thing in ridiculous fashion at the time.
Rym: So, you know, like it had survived ridiculous situations.
Rym: And then it shattered when lightly tapped with a toe in a sock on carpet.
Rym: But yeah, basically the camera broke in a weird way and I had this like insurance.
Rym: So I went to their website and I was like, yo, my many thousand dollar camera broke.
Rym: You said you would fix it.
Rym: No questions asked.
Rym: And I was 50/50 on whether or not this insurance I bought by clicking on something on Amazon would work or not.
Rym: Like I was pretty much waiting to just either go to Amazon and be like, yo, replace it.
Rym: This insurance was fake or just sue them in small claims court and get the money back.
Rym: They were super responsive.
Rym: Their website is like garbage tier, but like it's got clear stock images on it.
Rym: Like pretty sure I know the enterprise software this company bought to drive this customer service portal.
Rym: Pretty sure most people who buy this kind of insurance never actually try to make a claim with it.
Rym: So I made the claim and took them a while, but and they weren't that responsive.
Rym: So today I was like, you know what, I actually want this camera back.
Rym: Like I need it for Pax.
Rym: Pax is a few months away.
Rym: So I figure I should I should escalate and figure out if I have to go to small claims court or not.
Rym: And I called them on the phone today and I was like, look, you guys haven't done shit.
Rym: Where's my camera?
Rym: And they were super apologetic.
Rym: And they instantly figured out the problem.
Rym: And the problem was their service center is incapable of fixing this because the cost, the labor cost of taking the lens assembly apart to replace the part that was broken was more than the cost of just buying the entire lens assembly brand new.
Rym: And they didn't seem to want to deal with it.
Rym: So I was like, so what are you going to do?
Rym: And they were like, we are going to mail you a check for what you paid for the camera.
Rym: You will get it this week.
Scott: All right.
Rym: So sure.
Rym: Then I go look at Amazon, the camera I bought that I paid a lot of money for.
Rym: I am getting a check for the amount of money I paid.
Rym: I can now buy that camera and have money left up.
Rym: I can buy that camera for like eight hundred dollars less than what I paid.
Scott: You can buy a GH5, though, which I have, which doesn't have a lens.
Scott: You can just put any micro four thirds lenses on it.
Rym: It is good video lenses.
Scott: You can just get them there for how much money?
Scott: Which one do you want?
Scott: As many as a wide selection.
Rym: I would not get one as good as on this camcorder.
Rym: And then I'd also have to buy an XLR adapter, which also ain't cheap.
Rym: So I'm going to buy the exact same camera.
Scott: All those things together would still be less than that giant camcorder.
Rym: That giant camcorder is like twenty six hundred on Amazon.
Scott: And it'd probably be a better camera to not for video, much larger sensor.
Scott: What are you talking about?
Scott: It's like capable of making like actual films for like the theater.
Rym: Yeah, that's not what I need.
Rym: I need things like XLR and all the like run and gun, like ease of use capabilities.
Scott: You know, if you look at people outside who are running and gunning people making films, no one's using camcorders.
Rym: Yeah, you know who's using camcorders?
Rym: Journalists, mostly.
Rym: So basically, even better, the check I'm getting is for what I paid, but I got a five percent discount because I used an Amazon card to buy it on Amazon and I'm going to buy it again.
Rym: I'm going to get the five percent discount again.
Rym: And all I mailed back to them was the camera, meaning I'm going to get the brand new camera again with the multi hundred dollar, extremely fancy battery that lasts forever.
Rym: So I'm going to have two of those batteries, two of the chargers, two of everything plus the camera and I'll have made a profit.
Rym: So that worked out.
Scott: Rym keeps breaking his stuff on purpose because it keeps being rewarded for doing so.
Rym: I would rather this camera not have broken because there were multiple instances where I would have used it, but they weren't like critical instances where I needed the camera.
Scott: Anyway, let's talk about a whole bunch of gaming news.
Rym: So gaming news, a lot of gaming news, gaming news.
Scott: Number one, auto chess has exploded.
Scott: Here is the cars predicted go back to keep nights.
Rym: It's on record.
Scott: We predicted that you wouldn't even know an auto chess is a thing even now if it wasn't for me.
Rym: Auto chess isn't even that fun.
Rym: I'm already kind of done with it anyway.
Scott: So here's the current state of auto chess.
Scott: The original mod is still around, still guess being worked on, but it's sort of like, well, who knows how long it's going to live.
Scott: People are sort of fleeing it, even though it might still be the best game wise, even though the UI is obviously still poopy.
Rym: I would normally say it's going to be like the pub G, but it's not like.
Rym: pub G was already pretty polished by the time they were competitors.
Scott: The Chinese company that made the mod like Drodo or whatever the hell their name is, they made a different auto chess, which is basically great UI, you know, all new graphics, not dota license, but basically the same characters.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's on mobile.
Scott: It's on your tablet.
Scott: They're going to put it on PC, but only in the epic store.
Rym: Yeah, I've avoided the epic store so far.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But you have to either to play this game and to either make a Dragon Nest account, which is I got a Chinese website and I looked at that website or link to Facebook.
Rym: I don't have a Facebook account.
Rym: Right.
Scott: So it's all right.
Scott: So that's that game.
Scott: Right.
Scott: People are into that one.
Scott: It's probably the most advanced auto chess right now.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Then Valve made one based on Dota called Dota Underlords.
Scott: If you want to play Dota Underlords, you can either a pay ten dollars for a dota battle pass, which I did because I figured what the hell or people who have the Dota Underlords battle pass are getting today.
Scott: They actually got codes to share with their friends.
Scott: I'll share that with the room, I guess.
Scott: Yeah, you can play Dota Underlords.
Scott: It's super beta.
Scott: It's a little bit different from the regular auto chess, which is fine.
Scott: It's faster and has a better UI.
Scott: It's got some issues, though, in other departments.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So that's Dota Underlords is progressing rather quickly.
Scott: It's made by Valve.
Scott: It's a real deal.
Scott: Then the low valve making a game.
Scott: Then the Lowell company Riot has made one called Teamfight Tactics, which is part of LoL.
Scott: It's using LoL characters, League of Legends, by the way.
Rym: You know, to this day, if I look at a random character, I will know that is clearly from a MOBA, but I don't know which MOBA they're from.
Scott: It is to play this game, you need to have a League of Legends account with something called honor level three, which I've been told takes a long time to show me your honor.
Rym: Right.
Scott: So if you don't have a LoL account with honor level three, you have and you want to play this game, which is somewhat significantly different.
Scott: The people, the NDA is lifted.
Scott: So people who can play it are like talking about YouTube.
Scott: You can learn all about it.
Scott: It has a hex map.
Scott: It's a little it's.
Scott: it's you know, it's still.
Scott: it's got like some more real drafting mechanics.
Scott: Maybe we're like, you know, it is like a carousel of characters and everyone picks one in order, right?
Scott: So like that, you know, so it actually seems like a more maybe more interesting game, potentially also still super beta alpha.
Scott: But in about some number of weeks, maybe a month, that'll be open to everyone.
Scott: The Underlords should be open to everyone also in some short period of time.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: So those are all the major competing auto chess games that aren't just garbage you can ignore.
Rym: So this is to the expansion as predicted.
Scott: We're going to see which one comes out on top and then that's going to be the one everyone's going to play, which could be one of these or it could be a dark horse coming out of nowhere.
Rym: Like this is this is the you're getting to watch in real time the earliest days of a basically new genre of gaming, kind of like the Fortnite like it's basically just sort of seven one.
Rym: Well, it's a new genre of gaming for people who only play video games and have not experienced actual modern.
Scott: It's a real.
Scott: it's a fad.
Scott: It's a. basically it's a. it's a board game that could not.
Scott: it's a video game that is mostly a board game because it's mostly about making decisions.
Rym: See, also sooner it's like sooner.
Scott: Well, but the automatic combat would be very difficult to implement in a board game.
Rym: Yeah, I've tried to.
Rym: I've workshopped like five different ways to make an actual board game with this.
Rym: It just doesn't work.
Scott: It's not fun, but it makes you take your turn fast.
Scott: In fact, the Underlords is even though the actual game itself takes about the equal amount of time to regular original auto chess, the timers are shorter.
Scott: So you Satan, but you're still sitting there for 30, 40 minutes, but it pushes you faster.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, so that's auto chess news, Pokemon news, right?
Scott: I knew this.
Scott: I always question this.
Scott: And now my question has been answered is there's so many fucking Pokemon.
Scott: They keep adding more.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And even though in any individual Pokemon game and generation mainstream Pokemon game, there are only so many Pokemon in that game.
Scott: You can still import Pokemon from old games and trade and do all sorts of shenanigans and get every Pokemon ever.
Scott: Which means every new Pokemon generation, somebody working a game freak redoes all the art, all the noises, all the animations, all the everything for every single fucking Pokemon in the Pokedex from fucking what Bulbasaur,
Rym: which
Scott: leads to all the way up to fucking legendary bullshit in the new game, which
Rym: leads to interesting weird problems similar to an RPG is where people will never use their elixirs and their special items.
Rym: People will like, will you even use the new Pokemon?
Scott: It's like someone spent all that time to animate and make that new update Tangella for the newest generation.
Scott: And it's like someone collects a Tangella, so they have a complete Pokedex and they never use it again.
Scott: Anyway, the point is, is I always said, man, it must take a fucking long ass time.
Scott: It was like an army of people drawing all these Pokemons.
Scott: It's like, I guess it's doable because it's on like the DS and they're not that high res or high fidelity.
Scott: But now the newest Pokemon game is on the switch and it's like they're adding more Pokemon.
Scott: It's like, really, is somebody going to make fully animated 3D models of all thousand whatever fucking Pokemon there are?
Rym: The answer is no.
Scott: The answer is they're done.
Scott: They're like they knew they couldn't keep that up forever until computers can do the work.
Scott: Humans, too much work for humans.
Rym: I think this is good news, actually.
Scott: I think it is also good news.
Rym: Pokemon games start to feel a little stagnant when you keep seeing the same Pokemon, like.
Rym: you're not that inclined to use the new ones.
Rym: You'll collect them, but then you go to like Pikachu, right?
Scott: It's like, come on.
Scott: Anyway, but the point is, I hope there's no Pikachu.
Rym: I hope you can't get Pikachu.
Scott: That'd be great.
Scott: But it would be amazing.
Scott: It's not true.
Scott: In Pokemon Sword and Shield, they are not going to have the laborers at Game Freak, the artists, make 3D models of three and full animations and full noises and full everything for every fucking Pokemon that's ever existed.
Scott: They are picking a subset of the world of Pokemon, and there are going to be Pokemon that have existed in prior generations that you simply cannot get in Sword and Shield.
Scott: They're not in there.
Scott: Maybe they'll add them later.
Scott: Maybe they'll just never add them.
Rym: This is fine.
Rym: It means people who have played Pokemon their entire lives, maybe there will be a way to get Spiritomb.
Scott: Who knows what the final Pokemon list is going to be.
Rym: But you'll be able to re-experience what it's like to have a world of all new Pokemon, and every Pokemon you find is like, whoa, what's this thing?
Scott: It's still going to have way more Pokemon than Generation 1, so I don't know what you're complaining about.
Rym: People are really butter about this.
Scott: There was a funny meme going around where some, you know, some stupid person was like, whoa, what does it take?
Scott: Five minutes to draw Pokemon?
Scott: It's like, come on.
Rym: And people, a bunch of... Well, that's the same.
Rym: That's the same reason why people say Barclay 2 raised one hundred and twenty thousand dollars and they couldn't make a AAA game.
Scott: Well, they also fucked up.
Rym: But one hundred and twenty thousand dollars in the game industry rounds down to zero dollars.
Scott: The point is, a bunch of 3D artists went and tried to 3D model Pokemon in five minutes and then posted what they were able to accomplish in five minutes.
Scott: And there were some really awesome Pokemon, five minute 3D Pokemons.
Scott: Look them up.
Scott: They're really good.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: All right.
Scott: What was the next news?
Rym: Well, you know, it's funny because I was looking for this news and I found an article on Kotaku from 2011 that is titled, There are far too many Pokemon to care about.
Scott: I agree.
Rym: And I feel like it's time to move on from the original 151.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: So in some other news, this isn't really this is very good gaming news at all.
Rym: Gaming related.
Scott: It's not gaming news.
Scott: I can make it.
Rym: I can make it gaming related.
Scott: Anyway, so the point is, there's a story going around around about the recent Supreme Court decision, which reaffirmed what we all knew.
Scott: But it's good to have it reaffirmed that there is no writer free speech in sort of a private context.
Scott: Right.
Scott: If I have a private club, I can say in this club, no one may say any word beginning with the letter C or if I own a company and you wear a green shirt to work, I can fire you for it.
Rym: As long as it's not in a protected class of very specific things.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: The Congress, the First Amendment says Congress shall make no law if the government isn't doing the censorship.
Scott: If, you know, here on the GeekNights podcast, I can censor any, you know, guests who come on.
Rym: It's like the GeekNights forum.
Rym: If you say fascist stuff, you're immediately banned.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: I hope we pay for that forum.
Scott: It belongs to us.
Scott: We can.
Scott: we are the rulers there.
Scott: There is no freedom of speech there.
Scott: that was reaffirmed in this decision.
Scott: And that is correct.
Scott: However, all these articles are pointing out that this correct decision was reaffirmed and making that the headline.
Scott: And then in the very last paragraph, they're burying the truth, which is that actually this Supreme Court decision, while reaffirming a true thing, that is correct, is probably bad news in this particular case.
Scott: That's not.
Scott: the ruling is totally wrong.
Scott: So here's the case was involving a public access TV network in New York and the public access TV network in New York was managed by a nonprofit, which is a private entity.
Scott: But it's still a public access network.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: That is a public thing.
Rym: They're basically saying if you subcontract, if the government subcontracts, the subcontractor now can totally violate the First Amendment.
Rym: Right.
Rym: That's basically what this ruling says.
Rym: And it's notable that the conservative piece of shit justices on the Supreme Court were the ones in the majority on this and the good Supreme Court justices dissented.
Scott: Right.
Scott: The dissenting judges weren't saying the wrong thing, which would be like, no, you get freedom of speech even in a private context.
Scott: That's not they were saying at all.
Scott: They were correctly saying, this is a public access TV network.
Scott: That's a government thing.
Scott: It just happened to be subcontracted to a private nonprofit.
Scott: That doesn't.
Scott: that's still a government thing.
Scott: You still have to have freedom of speech on the public access TV network.
Scott: Now, this is getting really private TV network that is completely owned by a private entity because there's a broader issue right now where there wouldn't even been a Supreme Court.
Scott: They would have just said, OK, well, they wouldn't have brought it up.
Scott: Conservatives and fascists are basically arguing for and as if they're not the same thing.
Rym: I repeat myself.
Rym: They're generally arguing that free speech must be protected on private social media networks.
Rym: But they're doing this because conservative talking points tend to get people banned because they're racist.
Scott: Well, I mean, it's everyone there's no point of even discussing.
Scott: It's just so obvious.
Scott: Everyone knows that there are people of principle.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: And then there are people who just bring up whatever principle, you know, helps their side win in whatever the argument is.
Scott: They'll be like, you know, playing a hockey game.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And they'll say, oh, the tripping rule says this.
Scott: You go in the box and then they'll trip someone and then say, no, no, no, that's not tripping.
Scott: Even if it's identical, just they're just always arguing for the other team to go in the box and then not to.
Scott: There's no principle involved.
Scott: So you just they're not in good faith.
Scott: You just ignore whatever they say.
Rym: Well, like case in point, and they got last week's episode on breaking up tech companies.
Rym: People like us want to break up big tech companies because they are a danger to society.
Rym: But at the same time, conservatives also want to break up big tech companies because they fear the power of big tech companies who tend to side with not necessarily leftist, but at least more liberal or progressive policies because that's what they're employed.
Rym: So it gets into a weird situation where two people want the same thing for opposite reasons.
Scott: My point here is my beef is with every single news article I've seen about this story getting it wrong.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And I want everyone to now hear the correct way the story should be read.
Rym: It's notable that Scott, who never wants to talk about politics anyway, isn't about politics, is about the Supreme Court.
Rym: The Supreme Court is pure politics.
Scott: We talk about Supreme Court decisions on that all the time.
Rym: The Supreme Court.
Scott: That is the thing we talk about.
Scott: government wise.
Rym: Go back to 2006, and it's Scott being really mad about Rumsfeld.
Scott: All we talk about is, you know, I think we were just talking about how he's a nut job who has a conspiracy nut style power points.
Rym: Oh, you brought him up a lot.
Rym: So if you are a subscriber to the night's page around, you can actually listen to all of the beta episodes of GeekNights with commentary.
Rym: And the point is Supreme Court talks about politics a lot.
Scott: GeekNights will always talk about Supreme Court decisions.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But I'm just pointing out that the Supreme Court is one hundred percent a partisan political entity.
Rym: It is not special anymore.
Rym: And currently it's compromised.
Rym: I think the most recent two appointees of the Supreme Court should be removed from office.
Rym: And I think the Democrats should stack the court in 2020.
Scott: Go to move them.
Rym: I don't have that power.
Scott: You do.
Scott: I do not.
Rym: You do.
Rym: How do I have that power?
Scott: You do.
Rym: Do I think by voting in New York?
Rym: No.
Scott: In a district that goes like there is only two ways to remove a Supreme Court justice from office.
Rym: Don't go down that path.
Scott: I'm just saying you have that power.
Rym: The correct way to remove Supreme Court justices from office is to mitigate their power by doing what FDR threatened to do.
Rym: And I want to bring back.
Rym: Let's just put like 20 more people on the Supreme Court.
Rym: Once the Democrats have control of Congress again, they can't stop us.
Rym: But anyway, keep an eye on this sort of thing, because generally the people who are freaking out the most about free speech, especially in the context of video games, are people who want to say the N-word and the F-word and the R-word in video game platforms and don't want their, quote unquote, free speech rights to be impinged upon by private entities who don't want them to say the N-word in video game platforms.
Rym: In one last piece of news, that is really good news.
Rym: Bloodstained ritual of the night.
Rym: I kickstarted this thing.
Rym: It feels like an infinite time.
Scott: I kickstarted this as well.
Scott: If you're not familiar, Iga, the creator of the real Castlevania Symphony of the Night, the, you know, Iga-venya master, decided to make his own game.
Scott: He left the house that, you know, Simon Belmont built.
Scott: Yeah, he went on his own with a Kickstarter a few years back.
Scott: I kickstarted it.
Rym: And not technically Castlevania, it's Byman Selmont fighting Alucard.
Scott: Right.
Scott: They released a game called Ritual of the Moon something something that was like an NES style tiny game.
Scott: But I got that because I was on the Kickstarter.
Scott: But now, finally, after long last, the actual Bloodstained ritual of the night.
Rym: I got an email with a code on Steam today.
Scott: I did not because I chose the Switch version.
Rym: I regret not choosing the Switch version.
Scott: The Switch version is coming out next week.
Scott: I'll trade you.
Scott: I'll give you my Switch code if you give me your Steam code.
Rym: Yeah, but I didn't know about the 30 FPS thing.
Rym: And now that I know that, I kind of don't want to switch.
Scott: Apparently, people are saying that the Switch version is 30 FPS locked in.
Scott: So maybe I'll pay money for the Steam version when I get home.
Rym: I bought Wargroove on Steam to stream it and on the Switch because I prefer playing games like that on the Switch.
Rym: You know, maybe I re-bought Slay the Spire on the Switch.
Scott: I'm just going to wait a week and get the Switch version I already played for and just deal with it.
Rym: Here's the reality, Scott.
Scott: I have enough games to play for the next week.
Scott: I don't need to buy.
Rym: 30 FPS does not matter to people like you and me for a game like this.
Rym: It matters to one class of people, speedrunners.
Rym: That's right.
Rym: That is something we are not and never will be.
Scott: But anyway, so the game is out now, except on Switch.
Rym: Pretty hype about it.
Scott: It'll be out on Switch next week.
Rym: I've been waiting for this for a while.
Rym: It's good to see.
Scott: It's supposedly, on paper, a game much like Castlevania, the Symphony of the Night, only much larger with a lot of extra things.
Scott: They're giving you a ton of free DLCs, you can customize your character.
Rym: I mean, Wikipedia even says genre Metroidvania.
Scott: This game is supposedly lit.
Scott: People are playing it right now.
Scott: I can go watch on Twitch.
Scott: I'll see if we're going to find out how good it is.
Rym: Yep, because like I say, off and on gig nights, there are a few things that I want unique experiences that I want to walk away from those experiences.
Rym: But then there are some things where I just want that same thing forever.
Scott: I didn't get enough.
Rym: Like a good cookie?
Scott: I'll just keep eating.
Rym: If there's a good sugar cookie, I'll just keep eating sugar cookies.
Scott: Right.
Scott: There's a limit.
Scott: There's a limit at point at which I'm sick of cookie.
Scott: But it's like one delicious cookie.
Scott: It's like you got to make that same delicious cookie you made last time.
Scott: I got it.
Scott: I got to have some more of that pie, tree trunks.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: It's like I finish all the Metroidvanias that were good and my brain just said, yo, you need some more of that.
Rym: I watched all the ghosts in the shell standalone complexes there are in my brain.
Rym: Just said, yo, you need some more of that.
Scott: It's like you don't need to make 10 of them at some point.
Scott: It's like, all right, just make one more.
Scott: Just one more.
Scott: So here we go.
Scott: We got our one more Igavania.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: If if this does well, we'll see if it's actually any good.
Scott: It could be garbage.
Rym: If it's actually really good.
Rym: Who knows?
Rym: This bodes well for the future of me getting even more good Metroidvanias.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: But now it's time for things of the day.
Rym: So what do you got?
Scott: So you could imagine if you were in the Navy, perhaps the Royal Navy or the U.S.
Scott: Navy, you know, one thing that you have to train for in the Navy is what if you're on a fucking boat that's sinking?
Scott: Damage control.
Rym: It's weird because I know a lot about like naval aviation and naval damage control in the context of World War Two, but only from like this high level of like the differences in like how Japan approached it versus the United States.
Scott: The point is, is that that is the thing you have to be prepared and trained in.
Scott: If you are going to be in a Navy as a sailor, right.
Scott: What to do if the boat is sinking, there's holes in the boat, waters coming in.
Scott: What do you do about it?
Scott: That is like one of your jobs is to deal with that situation.
Scott: But on a high level, you obviously are going to need training for that situation.
Scott: It's not something you can wait to learn.
Scott: And I mean, even if you learn it on paper, you can't wait to, you know, actual get real world experience doing it in when it actually happens and your boat got torpedoed.
Scott: You also can't go out in a real fucking boat torpedo it.
Scott: And then because that would be dangerous and stupid and a waste of a boat and a torpedo.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Also, it's the kind of thing where you need muscle memory, like you have to react to this very quickly or the ship will sink and everyone dies.
Scott: You have to get really good at it.
Scott: So apparently they have these simulators, which is basically a complete reconstruction of exactly what the fuck it's like in a Navy ship.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And they friggin break holes in it and blast water into it.
Scott: And they can raise the water level, lower the water level, adjust the temperature.
Scott: They can rock the boat, do all sorts of ridiculous shit to, you know, blow smoke in there, do everything to completely simulate what it's like to be on a boat that just got fucked the fuck up and give you the tools and whatever so that you can try to repair it and not drown and not die and keep the boat float.
Scott: And this is exactly one of those series of video showing complete amateurs doing exactly that, going inside the thing and trying not to drown.
Rym: I love how they put it on like baby mode.
Scott: They put it on easy mode and it takes them like 20 minutes.
Scott: And then they show they briefly show some people on promo doing it in like almost no time at all.
Rym: But I guess what I was getting at is that like you read a CS Forrester book like Horatio Hornblower and you read all this like naval stuff.
Rym: You're like, oh, yeah, this makes sense.
Rym: But then when you think about it, you can't actually describe what people actually specifically did at any point in that book.
Rym: So when you think about how do they stop a ship from sinking when a hole got blown in the side, the fuck do they actually do?
Scott: Apparently, you take wedges of wood and hammer them into the hole and they fill the hole up enough to stop the water.
Scott: And I guess you come back later and put in a real fix.
Scott: It's very low, probably involves welding, I imagine.
Rym: But the fact that it's very low tech, because that is still the most effective way to do this kind of thing.
Scott: You're in a fucking hurry.
Scott: There's a hole in your right.
Scott: It's like, yeah, you got to imagine if you shove a bunch of wood and you hammer it into a hole, it's going to fill it and it's going to block the water.
Rym: Yeah, as long as you just got to block it enough so the ship doesn't sink so you can finish the battle and then go deal with it later, drain out the water, not die, keep the boat afloat.
Rym: This like this would be an amazing thing to do.
Rym: Like I would love to go into the simulator.
Scott: Well, go start a water park and make one of these as an attraction at the water park.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: I mean, this is cheap.
Scott: You can buy one of these, right?
Scott: You can afford it.
Rym: I mean, Tom Scott got his friends to go and do it, but I'm sure we don't have as much clout as him.
Rym: He's got one million subscribers.
Scott: Tom Scott person is apparently some British.
Rym: I like a lot of his videos.
Scott: OK, I never heard of him before.
Rym: And if you if you want to get a good last name, if you watch a lot of videos that are like, hey, here's how this thing works, you'll start to see Tom Scott videos popping up a lot in a general sense.
Scott: He doesn't seem to be a YouTube shouty man, at least not from this video.
Rym: It's pretty chill.
Rym: So this is just a really cute comic that a Twitter person did a long time ago back in 2012.
Rym: It's short.
Rym: It's like two tweets worth of.
Rym: It's basically a really short indie zine and it's just about Sonic and Tails getting rings.
Rym: And it's just like.
Rym: it's the kind of thing that an old movie like I might have seen this at a mocha.
Rym: You might have.
Rym: It's just.
Rym: this is exactly the kind of thing that if I saw it at a mocha, I'd be really excited about and have a lot of good things to say.
Rym: It's short to the point.
Rym: it captures some of these like very specific feels from playing old Sonic games in a really earnest, heartfelt and succinct way.
Scott: I thought you hate old Sonic.
Rym: I like old Sonic games to a point.
Rym: There are two and a half good Sonic games that were ever made.
Rym: That's what I'm going to say.
Rym: And I just I really like this comic.
Rym: It's really cute.
Rym: And I think you should like it and you should follow this person on Twitter.
Rym: In the moment, the GeekNights Book Club book was the pages of pain this Thursday.
Rym: We're going to talk about this book.
Rym: Finally, it's I hope you read it.
Rym: We're going to assume you read it.
Scott: There is might have been too painful.
Scott: Maybe the people who read it are not listening because they're dead.
Scott: There is no or in pain.
Rym: I saw a handful of people liked my tweet about King of the Hill describing this book.
Rym: So I assume those people read this book.
Scott: Maybe they read it just because they're D&D nerds.
Scott: Maybe because it's book club.
Rym: I feel like most people who read this book or read it in the 90s because they were D&D nerds.
Rym: Not me, but I I got a lot to say about this.
Rym: And there is no world where I will explain to you the plot of this book.
Rym: We are just going to react to it, assuming you read the same painful pages we read.
Scott: We've all experienced the same pain.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: We can now share our pain together on Thursday.
Rym: Foot for a leg.
Rym: Here we go.
Scott: And literally hand for a foot.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Hand for well, hand for a foot.
Rym: And I'm not sure like how far up the ankle that went.
Scott: foot for a leg.
Scott: That's not a thing.
Scott: No, the hand for a foot.
Rym: No, you remember.
Rym: Yeah, there was the.
Rym: I forget the quote where there was the guy that Dr.
Rym: Nick fucked up real bad in The Simpsons, Mr.
Rym: He did a rhyme and I forget the rhyme.
Rym: Anyway, it's not on the level of seed and feed.
Rym: But otherwise, we don't have any console packs.
Rym: We're just hanging out.
Rym: We're going to judge some anime coming up soon.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: That's all we got.
Rym: We're just hanging out, making content.
Rym: Well, whenever it's going to be rainy for like the next two weeks.
Rym: So we might start streaming some games because what else are we going to do?
Rym: Can't go biking.
Scott: No, we can go back in this weekend.
Scott: It'll be Saturday and Sunday.
Scott: It's going to be not raining.
Rym: Oh, my bike will be back from the shop by then.
Scott: Let's bike far.
Rym: Maybe I will.
Rym: OK, people are saying I got to look into.
Rym: there's a bunch of parkways get closed in the Bronx and north of the Bronx on particular Sundays, apparently or something.
Scott: I'll show you how to go to the good path.
Rym: Well, I know one good way is the way I didn't know before is instead of going to Randall's Island and then going over the RFK into the Bronx, you go off a Randall's Island, a different way, and it goes under.
Rym: It doesn't go over the RFK, but it goes to the Bronx in like a secret way and connects to a bike path.
Scott: Yeah, that's where I go all the time past the New York Post, the Bronx connector.
Rym: Yeah, the Bronx connector.
Rym: That's the best path.
Scott: If we go where I want to take you.
Scott: That's where we're going to go.
Rym: I run over there actually kind of often as part of my half marathon route.
Scott: If you should follow me on Saturday or Sunday, we'll go some.
Scott: I'll take you to a good place.
Rym: So games of Hyrule, the back story is there is a game on PC.
Scott: Oh, no, there's more back story than that.
Scott: We were at a PAX years ago and we saw this game in an indie booth or some shit.
Scott: And I said, what the hell is that?
Rym: And it was someone was on a DDR pad.
Scott: It was on a DDR, but I was like, so that got my attention right away.
Rym: And they were playing a rogue like rhythm game.
Scott: And I said, holy fuck.
Scott: I took the card.
Scott: I took a photo.
Scott: I was all over that jam.
Scott: Holy shit.
Scott: I was all over that.
Scott: And then the game finally came out.
Scott: And when it finally came out, I was into it for like a week and then I didn't stick with it.
Scott: But Rym stuck with it and is maybe are you the top rhythm dancer on earth?
Scott: Maybe.
Rym: No, I'm real good at this game.
Scott: The top necro dancer.
Rym: But I'm probably in like the top several hundred because I've seen some AGD cues.
Rym: Holy fuck.
Rym: Yeah, I am not like that.
Rym: I've beaten the game.
Scott: So there are people who have truly become necro master dancer.
Rym: I have beaten the game all the way to the end.
Scott: I have not even done that with every character except one.
Rym: Fuck that character character, the one that dies in one hit.
Scott: Oh, no, no, no, no.
Scott: I would not be able to beat the game with that character.
Rym: Basically, imagine like the final form of this game is beat it.
Rym: You can't like pick up a lot of things.
Rym: If you ever miss a beat, you die instantly.
Rym: If you ever get hit, you die instantly.
Rym: Yeah, fuck that.
Rym: I've seen speed runs of people beating the game with that character.
Scott: Whoa.
Rym: But the important I'll link to our review of this game from twenty fourteen, because the important yeah, the important parts of necro dancer.
Scott: Five years ago, it actually came out.
Scott: What packs did we fucking see it?
Rym: Oh, my God.
Rym: Time is moving.
Scott: Six, seven years ago, it affects.
Scott: Oh, my God.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Back then, you know what panel we did?
Rym: How to win every game.
Rym: The precursor to the much better play dirty to win panel.
Scott: So at a recent Nintendo was, you know, thing they.
Scott: now they showed this game and we're like, holy fuck.
Scott: The people who made Necro Dancer made it officially licensed Nintendo Switch exclusive game called The Legend of Zelda Cadence of Hyrule.
Scott: It is just crypt of the necro dancer with a Zelda theme on it.
Rym: The last time this happened were the Phillips CDI games.
Scott: And well, I mean, this you know, this that came out for a different platform.
Scott: Yeah, this was made with Nintendo's supervision.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Nintendo asked for this to be made.
Rym: Yeah, but they asked for this to be made.
Rym: But it's basically just necro dancer with a Hyrule theme.
Scott: And it just came out for the Nintendo Switch.
Scott: What, two days ago?
Rym: Yeah, I have already played it a bunch.
Rym: I beat one of the dungeons.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I really like it.
Scott: I played it a whole bunch yesterday and today.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: So I went and the day it came out, I played a little bit.
Scott: So if you have never actually might have been late last week, it came out.
Rym: So if you have never played Crypt of the Necro Dancer, then all I will say is that this game is probably good and you will like it.
Rym: But if you've never played Crypt of the Necro Dancer, this game will be hard as balls for you until you get used to it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So here's how the game holds.
Rym: No punch.
Rym: Right.
Scott: Is that you walk around and if there are no bad guys on the screen at the present time, you can just walk around and do whatever the hell you want.
Scott: Yup.
Scott: However, it's basically sort of like a Zelda game, except every time you move, you hop exactly one space because it's a grid.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: But as soon as there is at least one enemy on screen, there's a rhythm thing appears at the bottom and the music cranks up.
Rym: So you play like up, left, sword, up, up, bomb, sword, fight.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Once that appears, it's not like DDR where there's like some sequence or anything.
Scott: It's a steady rhythm and you must press buttons, right?
Scott: You can stop pressing.
Scott: You can just like let go and the world will just be like, well, we're going to keep going.
Scott: The world will just move on the beat.
Scott: So on the beat, the enemies move, they move.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And then on the beat, things happen.
Scott: And if there's a projectile, it moves one space on the beat.
Scott: But you're expected to, if you put inputs in the game, to put exactly one input in at a time and depress the inputs on the beats.
Scott: If you press the inputs in between the beats, then it says you're off the beat.
Scott: And if you stay on the beat, that helps your character greatly increases damage and it's just generally good to do that.
Scott: Right.
Scott: If you want to, you can play not a worst game, not a baby game, not easy mode.
Rym: Just a different game.
Scott: Just a different game.
Scott: You can turn off the rhythm.
Scott: And in which case that will put your game into a different mode where nothing moves.
Rym: It's like playing as Monk in NecroDancer.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Nothing moves.
Scott: And if you press an input, then everything will move one space when you put an input in.
Scott: It's actually a significantly different game because you sort of lose the ability to wait.
Scott: I think maybe you can push a button to wait.
Scott: I'm not sure.
Rym: You can only push a button to wait if you have an item to use that will waste a beat, like the drum.
Rym: Like the drum is so important because you can just drum, drum, drum and stand there and wait for something to happen.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Anyway.
Scott: But yeah, it's a different game.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But the enemies have the same behaviors and everything.
Scott: So it's a roguelike game.
Scott: The map, I think, is procedurally generated.
Scott: But then it just stays that way because the map we were just playing co-op just now.
Scott: That map was different from the map in my game.
Scott: That was not the same map.
Rym: But it seems like it's procedurally generated for each play through.
Rym: Yes.
Rym: So you can basically play a Zelda game with a kind of a random seed.
Rym: But it's all magic.
Scott: If you got a whole overworld and the over when you say new game, you start a new save file, it creates a whole overworld within certain constraints.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, certain things have to exist and you play it.
Scott: And then if you start a new game, you get a new map.
Scott: So you can beat the game and replay it and get a new ish experience each time.
Rym: So in terms of the details, how you play, because if you've never played Necrodancer, it takes a little bit of getting used to because you can't just fight a monster by stabbing it a bunch like you would in, say, Zelda three.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You don't even have an attack button to attack.
Scott: You just move into a monster.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: And different swords and weapons will attack in different patterns.
Scott: In fact, if you move in a direction and it is such that your weapon can hit an enemy in that direction based on what weapon you have equipped, instead of moving, you will simply turn and attack instead of moving.
Rym: But what playing this game is really like is more like there'll be a bunch of monsters on screen and some environmental hazards and things and or a dungeon to explore or whatever.
Rym: And you basically to beat a monster, you have to figure out the pattern that monster exists in.
Rym: Right.
Rym: And then rhythmically deal with that monster.
Rym: Like some monsters will go move, move, wait, attack.
Rym: So you want to go like move, attack, attack, and then move away before it attacks.
Rym: Right.
Rym: Some monsters, you got to get behind him and hit him.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Every monster has a visual set of animations and poses that signal what it's about to do.
Scott: So, for example, there is a mushroom monster.
Rym: He goes like, wait, wait, I'm going to explode, explode.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So he doesn't move at all.
Scott: So what you have to do is you have to approach him so that you land next to the mushroom monster.
Scott: Right.
Scott: With it, you have to move such that you land one space away from it on a frame in which it is not exploding.
Scott: So that way on the next frame, you can just attack it and kill it.
Scott: If you move into it at the wrong time, you move in like if it's in the car, if it's currently in the about to explode phase and you're two spaces away from it and you move towards it, you get hit.
Scott: You have to move, say, down so it explodes.
Scott: You don't get hit, then move towards it, then up.
Scott: Now you're next to it and then you can hit it and it's not exploded.
Scott: Now, before you think this might sound simple that there are if you only had to deal with one enemy at a time on the screen and just a big old empty screen, the game would be easy as balls.
Rym: You could beat the biggest, badest boss right at the start to a degree, because the bosses and even like a lot of the monsters, there's a huge variety and they exhibit sometimes extremely complex behavior.
Rym: They do.
Rym: The patterns may be very long, may like some monsters are very difficult to deal with even by themselves.
Scott: Some of them, you got to use items on this.
Scott: You know, it's like a Zelda game.
Scott: You still have items like bomb, boomerang, all kinds of stuff.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Now, one thing that's very different from Necrodancer, other than the fact that, you know, all the Zelda stuff in the overworld and everything is better.
Rym: The music is just a road like go to a dungeon, then another dungeon and then another dungeon.
Rym: This game has an overworld with Zelda puzzles like Zelda three style and dungeons and all the trappings, but projectiles in Necrodancer are basically all just hitscan.
Rym: In this game, projectiles have a variety of complex behavior, which is something I am not used to or prepared for.
Scott: You got to get the boomerang.
Scott: It is like essential.
Scott: It makes everything so much easier.
Rym: The bow is really good, too, but it takes some getting used to.
Scott: And you got to get arrows.
Scott: Yeah, there are consumable items.
Scott: There are weapons you can get.
Scott: The weapons are just constantly used weapons.
Scott: But some weapons are glass weapons, which are super strong, but they eventually break and wear out.
Rym: Yeah, like there are it's got all the tropes of Necrodancer.
Rym: There'll be shops.
Rym: You can buy items.
Rym: Items wear out and eventually disappear.
Scott: Consumable weapons like shovels, torches, things like that, which you constantly use.
Scott: They wear out.
Scott: You got to get more.
Rym: But then you get permanent things like the down stab or the hook shot.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: There are bombs which are consumable as you use them.
Scott: Right.
Scott: There's such a wide variety of just stuff, just like, I don't know, a fucking Zelda game or a road like.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Now, the thing that really stands out because the game's like good.
Rym: It is very hard.
Rym: Like, do not go into this thinking it'll be easy.
Rym: If you do not like very difficult games, you will get sick of this after an hour.
Scott: Another thing is that this game, you know, you just can sort of go.
Scott: every it's like there's.
Scott: it's not really that it's hard as it is hard, but it's like Zelda one.
Rym: You can go to really dangerous places right away if you're dumb.
Scott: Super hard.
Scott: It's just a learning curve on.
Scott: it is busted.
Scott: There's a tutorial that is literally like less than a minute long.
Scott: that has you fight like the most basic bad guys one on one, and then they throw you in the fire.
Scott: Go, go, go.
Scott: You're on next thing.
Scott: you know, you're on a screen with like.
Scott: they're simple bad guys, but there's like eight of them and they're all mixed up together.
Scott: So even though you could deal with any one of them individually, no problem.
Scott: There are eight coming at you all together.
Scott: There's all kinds of other crazy shit on the screen.
Scott: Each screen is like a big mess of stuff you got to deal with.
Rym: It feel it gives me a lot of the feels I had when I first played Zelda one as a kid, because I wasn't good at video games yet.
Rym: So like I'd go to a screen when suddenly I see all these mob limbs.
Rym: I've never seen a mob limb before.
Rym: I was my nocturox.
Rym: I'm like, oh, shit.
Rym: And they feel real dangerous.
Rym: This game gives me that feel all over again.
Scott: So the other thing is that, you know, you start out on these screens where everything's grass themed.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's like I started walking around in like these rock themed areas on my game and I was dying like crazy.
Rym: That's a dangerous place.
Scott: It's like, yeah, it's like you can just go wherever the hell you want in this.
Scott: There's no limitation.
Scott: I suggest if you are not the best at this stick to the try.
Rym: You can stick to the grass and take care of some dungeons.
Scott: The map can shows you what's up.
Scott: You can easily not go to screens that aren't grass.
Scott: Go to all the grass screens you can.
Scott: And then maybe once you're getting good at the game and you're done with the grass screens, go to the desert screen.
Rym: And just like Zelda three, if you're stuck, go to the fortune teller and they'll basically tell you where the next puzzle is.
Scott: I went to the fortune teller and the fortune teller said, hey, go to the windmill.
Scott: And that was great.
Scott: Then I went back to the fortune teller.
Scott: They said, hey, go to like Mount Doom.
Scott: And I'm like, what the fuck?
Rym: I went to Mount Doom and I got into that dungeon.
Scott: That was good times.
Scott: I was like, oh, Death Mountain, Death Mountain, not Mount Doom.
Scott: They throw the ring into Ganon's mouth.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: But the thing that really stands out about this game to me is that it feels very much like a NecroDancer game and like a Zelda game.
Rym: Like, and they do this both by the gameplay itself, but also just the theming is spot on.
Rym: The music is fantastic.
Scott: It's somehow they've managed to combine the aesthetic of Link to the Past and also the soon to be remade, Link's Awakening.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: Coupled with the music, which is all right, which were made one after the other anyway.
Rym: But the music is like remixes of classic Zelda music with the great music from the NecroDancer game.
Scott: And they merge really well, like, you know, the same as like the shopkeeper from NecroDancer who sings.
Scott: But also you go to like the Gerudo or the Bomchu bowling, but then there's Octorocks and there's all kinds of like, you know, like.
Scott: they're such a perfect merger of the two in every way.
Rym: I would never have expected them to merge so well.
Rym: The soundtrack is worth having and listening to by itself, even if you never played this game.
Scott: Well, I mean, NecroDancer soundtrack as well.
Scott: It's a rhythm game.
Scott: Music is core.
Scott: Right.
Rym: Don't make a rhythm game with bad music.
Scott: So if you have a Nintendo Switch, I rate this as must have.
Rym: Absolutely.
Rym: This is a Switch game.
Rym: Buy it, play it.
Scott: Is it a reason to buy an Nintendo Switch?
Scott: No.
Scott: But if you have a Nintendo Switch, perhaps because you bought Breath of the Wild, you should also be having this.
Scott: Yup.
Rym: Now, if you have played NecroDancer, it'll be way easier because at least in the early part of the game, you will see a lot of monsters and they will map to a monster that exists in NecroDancer that you already know how to deal with.
Scott: I think if you have played NecroDancer and enjoyed it, you got to get this because it's more and more NecroDancer.
Scott: But if this is your first exposure and you're all into this, I don't necessarily think you have to go back to play NecroDancer unless you're super into it.
Scott: If you're super into it, you can know, ah, there's more for me out there.
Scott: You know what it's like?
Scott: But if this is your first show, just stay with this.
Scott: You don't have to go back and play the original.
Scott: Not necessary.
Rym: Like if you've never played an Advance Wars, just get Wargroove on the Switch.
Scott: Yeah, you don't need to go back and play old Advance Wars on the GBA.
Rym: Unless you play Wargroove and then you turn into someone like me and then you just go deeper and deeper and deeper.
Rym: Same deal.
Scott: This has so much replay value, especially with the procedurally generated map.
Scott: You can just start over and you can also, we cannot mention, we can't fail to mention the most important thing.
Scott: This has, we played it before the show, a very excellent co-op mode.
Rym: It's real fun.
Scott: Now, when you first start playing, I brought my Switch because I thought we were going to need two Switches.
Scott: No, to play the co-op mode, it's 2P1S.
Scott: Two players, one Switch.
Scott: You're going to want to do that on a television, not huddle around a tiny Switch.
Rym: Now, when you first start playing, the flaws are.
Rym: it's very easy to walk off the screen and disorient the other person.
Scott: Either player walks onto a new screen, goes into a room, falls down, goes down the stairs.
Scott: The other player is immediately dragged into that other screen.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It doesn't matter who did it.
Scott: So that can be good because it's like, well, I'm hanging on the left side of the screen.
Scott: We want to go right.
Scott: You go right.
Scott: Great.
Scott: We're now both, we both move.
Scott: That's convenient, but it can also be disorienting and annoying.
Scott: If you are not the player who moved off the screen, removed off the screen off by accident once that was annoying.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But that's the really pretty much the only problem.
Rym: It'll take you about 10 minutes to get used to it.
Rym: And then it's way fun.
Rym: It's way good.
Scott: Like I think it doesn't, I don't think it makes the game any more difficult.
Scott: They don't add more enemies or anything.
Scott: It's literally just you have an extra person.
Scott: You can clear the screen twice as fast.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Everything's great.
Rym: You can be clever, like get on opposite sides of a monster that has a lot of health and hit him at the same time.
Scott: Some things are shared.
Scott: I think like the diamonds, but something, most things aren't shared.
Scott: I get a weapon.
Scott: Rym doesn't have the weapon.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: But, but the intrinsic weapons, like if I get down stab, you also have down stab.
Scott: So it's exactly, I got the power glove.
Scott: We all had the power glove now.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But I had a torch Rym.
Scott: Didn't have one Rym had a shovel.
Scott: I didn't have a shovel.
Scott: Also, what else is great about the co-op?
Scott: It's just great.
Rym: Like it's like this game.
Rym: I cannot stress enough.
Rym: It's a must have of the swish library.
Rym: And if you've never played Neckerdancer, it is unique.
Rym: You have never played a game like this before.
Scott: This is literally the only game in the world like this.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So buy it.
Rym: Go play it right now.
Scott: That's right.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: All right.
Rym: The Patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Craig, Oliver Allen, Joyce, Heidi McNichol, JustLikeADudeGuy, Kishar Toppeshen, Linki G, Jennifer Hitchcock, Chris Midkiff, MyStady.com, J. Bandz, Scootalone Lee, Roberto Kingsley, Shawn Yeager, Nicholas Brando, Mr.
Rym: Strong Stretching, 421 Creations, and there may be other secret names you do not even know.
Rym: Sheriff of Unwhole, Rory, Rochelle Montanona, Superboy, Sailor Vista, Clinton Walton, Ren from New Zealand, Ryan Parent, Rope & Lander, Finn, Dread Lily, Tenebrae, Sean Klein, Chris Reimer, Thomas Hahn, It's Raining, and now I leave you with my favorite song of the year.
Scott: Hello,
Rym: hello, hello, hello, hello,
Scott: hello,
Rym: hello, hello, hello, hello, hello, hello, hello,
Scott: hello, hello, hello,
Rym: hello, hello, hello, hello, hello, hello, hello, hello, hello, hello, hello, hello, hello, hello, hello, hello, hello, hello, hello, hello,
Scott: hello, hello, hello, hello,
Rym: hello, hello, hello,
Scott: hello, hello, hello,
Rym: hello, hello, hello, hello, hello, hello, hello, hello, hello, hello, hello, hello, hello, hello, [BLANK_AUDIO].