Rym: It's Thursday April 25th 2019.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights tonight us the 2019 horror film.
Rym: Let's do this as opposed to unmet a show about us.
Rym: Yes, we've done enough of those in the old days.
Rym: You can find them.
Rym: GeekNights have been going for like 15 years.
Rym: So what do you got?
Rym: a bike home in the rain today?
Scott: Oh do you wet a little bit?
Rym: I'm glad I got that roll-up fender though because I don't care like I will bike.
Scott: I checked the weather and therefore did not bike.
Rym: when I got up the weather said it will rain it like 8 p.m.
Scott: When I got up, and I checked the weather it said it will rain on your way home.
Rym: Yeah, when did you get up?
Scott: cuz I left for work it like not just the way home to here But also the way home from here.
Rym: Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah, it would have rained then but when I checked the weather It said no rain is like 8 or 9 p.m..
Scott: Anyway So it's a new year of a bike commuting time.
Scott: finally It's warm enough, so I you know my plan was you know I got the road bike But I want to commute on the road bike yeah, and I got you know the new office There's like a bike room, and I managed to get the key to it by by you know luck.
Scott: I don't know if anyone else in my office is gonna be able to get a key, but we'll find out anyway.
Scott: So I'm like now want to put my nice bike road bike in the bike room.
Scott: So I'll use my keep using my commuting bike.
Scott: and I was like commuting bike.
Scott: You know it's a little old as 10 years old.
Scott: It was only like $500 10 years ago, it's gotten beat up a lot.
Scott: the seat has like holes in it.
Scott: Yeah, it's always been like an inch too big for me right.
Scott: I always needed like one size smaller, but it's still rideable.
Scott: You know it still goes Alright, so I'm like.
Scott: you know what you know for my last year of this bike.
Scott: I'll take it in and I'll get like some real maintenance.
Scott: So it's super smooth, and I can like drive it like crazy.
Scott: this last year I was thinking I'd get a new chain.
Scott: you know make sure the.
Scott: you know maybe new brake and shifting cables You know make everything real good.
Scott: You know true the wheels if they need it, so I bring it in.
Scott: guy looks at it.
Scott: We talked about some problems.
Scott: You know and then he's like alright.
Scott: I'll work on it later.
Scott: He doesn't start working on.
Scott: it's like 530 when I get there.
Scott: But you know he's going to true the wheel, and he's like well hold up this this rear wheel.
Scott: Check this out, and so I thought the rear wheel was out of true.
Scott: It actually wasn't.
Scott: despite being ten years old both wheels were actually pretty damn true Spoke-wise yeah, because you don't bike that aggressively.
Rym: and especially I'm like a commuter like cheaper bike.
Rym: so I could see why.
Scott: You know, but I only own my wheels cuz I keep popping spokes going in the shitty roads of Manhattan and such.
Scott: anyway He's like the rear axle is broken.
Scott: I'm like what?
Scott: So he shows me and is sure enough even though the quick-release skewer is like intact and good Right which is why I didn't have any problems riding or die.
Scott: The skewer was basically holding the wheel together And was keeping it secure on the on the frame.
Scott: But the actual axle you could spin the bolt on one side of the wheel and the one on the other side Did not turn.
Scott: so this is funny because I go and you can feel that the axle was like two different pieces Inside the wheel not touching each other.
Rym: so I just googled like broken rear axle to try to find like.
Scott: so I didn't bother to do that.
Rym: so get this.
Rym: the first result is a stack exchange where someone says broken rear axle.
Rym: Why does it happen and is it worth trying to repair?
Rym: This is really short?
Rym: So I'm taking the time to overhaul my bike.
Rym: whole drivetrain was full of oil road salt, etc.
Rym: So I started taking stuff apart.
Rym: once I got the back wheel off I ended up with half the rear axle in my hand and a bunch of ball bearings on the floor.
Scott: Yeah, he's bait.
Scott: the guy was basically telling me like yeah if I go to true the wheel I got to take the skewer out.
Scott: if I take the skewer out the wheels gonna fall apart.
Scott: And then you had to buy a new wheel, but he's like as long as I don't take it apart It's safe to ride for now.
Scott: Yeah, I'm like I can ride this home safely, and he's like yeah And I'm like all right do not take my $80 for a tenure to fix a ten-year-old $500 Right just you know.
Scott: make sure the brakes are good so I can ride home safely and I'll be on my way.
Rym: So I think we're both because I got to replace my rear wheel my cassettes and my chain probably.
Scott: so on Saturday I think I'm gonna go to some Brooklyn bike shops that have better selections for the kind of commuting bike I want and Replace my ten-year-old bike with hopefully a bike that will last 20 year.
Rym: You can check out.
Scott: I still have to bike.
Scott: it's worth checking out REI because I doesn't have the kind of commuting bike I'm looking for now.
Rym: have you looked?
Rym: because they also been there recently because they will also ship bikes in from other re eyes.
Scott: Yeah, but the REI only has like a lot brand and some other.
Scott: you know they don't have the kind of bike I'm looking for.
Rym: I've never actually shopped for bikes there because I tend to pick the manufacturer I want.
Rym: well.
Scott: I don't manufacturers for bikes don't really matter.
Scott: It's like there's actually a ton of manufacturers who make the kind of bike.
Scott: I want.
Scott: it's the kind yeah, right.
Scott: So it's like you know the kind like the kind of bike I have for a road bike.
Scott: There's actually tons of choices, but for the commuting bike that I want There's only like maybe you know five or six choices and most of the bike shops don't carry that kind.
Rym: I am continuing to idly look at mountain bikes because I'm not getting a road bike.
Rym: I'm just keeping like the road bike performance hybrid that is light like a road bike with the twitchy tires But it's not a road bike.
Rym: It's still got bullshit handlebars.
Scott: Yeah, just you know for going a long way.
Scott: You know it's yeah.
Rym: Yeah, there's a reason why I don't do the century.
Scott: There's a reason I got two bikes right to go a long way.
Scott: I mean, I can't go a long way even on a better commuting bike.
Rym: I mean really I I'm a perfect world.
Rym: I would have three bikes.
Rym: I would have a I would have a a full suspension mountain bike I would have a hybrid and I would have a road bike.
Scott: you should try you should rent a road bike.
Rym: one time I've ridden road bikes before I know the feel but for a long ride.
Rym: Yeah, I thought about it.
Rym: I found some places that'll random, but it ain't cheap.
Rym: No, it's cheap.
Rym: Goodbye.
Rym: It's cheap to rent a road bike for like a month But to rent it for like a weekend like one long trip and now worth it ready for a month.
Scott: then You could just rent a road bike every summer and always have a great road bike and then a winner you don't need you have To store it.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: The real problem is because I primarily ride on mountain bikes and hybrids.
Rym: I still have mostly mountain bike and hybrid physical reactions and reflexes.
Scott: But yeah, I'll probably you know, go get some bike on Saturday But that I'll probably keep poking around most like it.
Rym: at my met.
Rym: my current hybrid repaired It's just.
Rym: it's accumulated a lot of wear and tear over the last decade.
Rym: So in some other news Not to get it into all the great parts for mine all the ridiculous politics right now because it's uh, there's a constitutional crisis Ongoing in the US for the past.
Scott: how many years.
Rym: it's worse now because now you've got even.
Rym: here's the summary.
Scott: It's even worse.
Scott: We're still not doing anything and it's even worse.
Scott: They're still not doing well.
Rym: The problem is we can't do anything.
Rym: We already vote for people or who could do the right thing and we have no other political power.
Rym: But the the deal that's going on right now it for those of you who don't live in the u.s And actually those of you who do in the live in the u.s.
Rym: Because a lot of people don't know how this works.
Rym: there's three branches of the US government and They are co-equal in power and ostensibly they have checks and balances against each other.
Rym: Oh, he says they taught us the school like any two of them can technically like override the third.
Rym: but For various reasons one of those branches is split in two the house in the Senate That's Congress and they have different powers.
Rym: And right now the broken evil party controls one of those and the actually good political party The Democrats controls the other one.
Rym: So the Democrats control the part the part of our Congress that is allowed to basically investigate things.
Rym: so they started investigating a bunch of things and Our executive branch just said nah, we're just not gonna answer your questions.
Rym: What are you gonna do about it?
Rym: fight me and the Constitution Makes this a weird problem.
Rym: That's gonna be hard to resolve.
Rym: so independent of all that because this isn't GeekNights politics As you may know we tend to endorse candidates on GeekNights for various things.
Rym: Rym does well GeekNights does officially.
Scott: We should endorse candidates for things that aren't political but do involve voting.
Rym: That's a good idea.
Rym: We should endorse like Joey Jojo for head of panels at some convention we go to But in the Democratic Party's primary has begun even though the election is not for a long long time.
Scott: I don't know why they do this shit So early.
Scott: they should like have some sort of rule that like you can't do this until you know What exactly would the rule say?
Rym: what if I'm not technically running for president?
Rym: I'm just going around like giving speeches about great stuff.
Rym: I care about in my own opinions Like what's the line?
Rym: That's why it's hard to legislate that I Mean.
Scott: there are countries that don't have freedom of speech But heavily regulate political campaigning like Japan where it's like.
Scott: really I remember learning I don't know how true this is anymore where it's like you can only send X Flyers out.
Scott: They're like a specific number like they really live like.
Scott: specifically They were like you can drive your van around with megaphones on it for this much time during these hours like Everyone was limited to exactly the same amount of campaigning Resources.
Scott: like to like really specific details.
Scott: right so we could we could go to that far.
Scott: I have no.
Scott: actually don't have a bunch of a problem with that as long as you're not.
Scott: you know some principled For you know free speech person right.
Scott: so yeah, you can say whatever you want, but you may give ten speeches You may have five rallies you may have you may be on TV for ten hours total right.
Rym: so what if I don't declare?
Rym: That I'm running yet, and I just have a big party?
Rym: Like?
Rym: I just throw a giant house party.
Rym: I ran out of convention center and have a party.
Scott: Well, it's we check you go.
Scott: You're a candidate.
Scott: now Let's see how many parties you've had in the past.
Scott: You know well all that.
Scott: all the stuff you've done that may contribute is now gonna count.
Scott: You know it's like okay You drove your campaign van around all last year and now you want to run.
Scott: oh actually you can't run because you've already gone over The limit and as soon as you go over the limit you're kicked out.
Scott: You're not even the ballot.
Rym: the end the other.
Rym: the other problem.
Scott: If you did the exact limit, and you've used it all up, it's like oh you've already met your quota.
Scott: I can't do it anymore, but you're running so you got to use the other stuff now.
Rym: Yeah, but then here's the problem.
Rym: This is this is sort of a fundamental problem in American politics.
Rym: someone else who is a fan of you Does not?
Rym: they just throw their own parties, and they like you as they give their personal opinion.
Scott: I wonder how Japan gets around that if they still do have these cells from.
Rym: Generally the reason this is not as much of a problem everywhere else in the world is a combination of Democracy isn't as direct in those places clearly.
Rym: It's on a lower like a smaller scale Mm-hmm.
Rym: there's fewer people involved and fewer people who vote actually give a shit about issues Like.
Rym: it's very contentious right now, so our participation rates are rising and And America has a lot of unique problems as well, but I digress.
Rym: I'm gonna say is that there are like 4,000 people running for the Democratic nomination for president right now.
Rym: too many and a lot of them are pretty good And I'm gonna be blunt.
Rym: There's not a lot of awful ones.
Scott: There's just some that are clearly better than others.
Scott: It's like well look at all these chocolate bars.
Scott: even the Hershey bar still tastes good.
Scott: Yeah, cuz I'm not gonna buy it, but it I'm not gonna poop it.
Rym: We're basically we're voting on.
Scott: if it was the only one I would totally eat it and go mmm delicious.
Rym: We're voting on which candy bar of any kind is gonna run against a literal piece of shit, right?
Scott: So we're trying to find you know the golden you know Swiss chocolate bar.
Scott: That's the one we want, but we'll take pretty much any chocolate we can get because right now We have shit yep.
Rym: So in that primary with a lot of people like I will vote in the general election for literally anyone the Democrats nominated.
Scott: I will take the Hershey's chocolate yep.
Rym: Yes, but I Would prefer and I think as GeekNights tasting dark chocolate 88% cacao.
Rym: We're going to endorse Elizabeth Warren in the Democratic primary because she has actual well-thought-out policies.
Rym: that are Scott ideas But with actual numbers and plans behind them and no other candidate has this.
Scott: it's like voting for me only.
Scott: Yeah, smarter more serious like Bernie Sanders.
Rym: I'd be like bro.
Rym: We should.
Rym: we should blow up the blah and change the blonde free college for everyone's voting for angry old man Scott.
Rym: Yeah, but Elizabeth Warren is more like let's break up Amazon.
Scott: trying to be reasonable Scott.
Rym: let's break up Amazon in these way like for these reasons or Let's forgive college debt.
Rym: and here are the numbers.
Scott: how to do it.
Scott: the only politician I've ever heard say you know that was pretty much the moment I decided like all right you are now the tastiest chocolate for now.
Scott: Yeah, right because the only politician I've ever heard say let's bust up Amazon with Zephyr.
Scott: teach out who in was a New York Someone who ran for governor of New York and did not do that.
Scott: well Yeah, but you know was sort of a more out there candidate still even though she's really smart and cool.
Scott: Yep, right I like her a lot, but then to have someone running for president with a good chance You know come out with the same kind of position in a more reasonable less far out way.
Scott: Just you know like I saw a tweet like Elizabeth Warren just says I want to break up Amazon, and I'm like.
Scott: well Yep, I saw the college debt person with Amazon credit card and prime account and bought her buys everything on Amazon You know votes for Canada.
Rym: who says let's break up Amazon and says Amazon get out of my neighborhood Yep, so yeah If we would recommend that you also support Elizabeth Warren in the primary with the caveat that we all understand.
Rym: now if you're saying I don't care if a Snickers bar three musketeers gets the nomination We're eating it now.
Scott: if you might be saying well wait a minute the primary is like when?
Rym: Well forever right.
Scott: and you might be saying well.
Scott: Why does this matter now?
Scott: this primary is so far out?
Scott: I'm gonna vote then if I probably might even get to vote for her.
Rym: if she loses like voting is the least important part of The she might drop out in some earlier round.
Scott: Yeah, and I will tell you exactly why this matters right now.
Scott: because like we said you know We don't have those restrictive rules of Japan or anything like that right you know you can do right now.
Rym: You can give Elizabeth Warren money right now Or you can also talk about her on social media.
Rym: like that sounds dumb and silly But that is what gets people to pay attention.
Rym: It's weird, but it works anyway.
Scott: So if you have money yeah, and you got money to spare or you might be saying well I could just give my money directly to something cool like you know Planned Parenthood Which you could do that too.
Rym: You should maybe but all those things will be destroyed if the Democrats don't retake power.
Rym: That's right.
Scott: This is an indirect right.
Scott: so you can give like $20 to Elizabeth Warren and if she somehow wins you effectively then Multiplied your money because that will then redirect trillions of dollars in the US budget.
Scott: Yep, and then you won't need to be given $20 to.
Scott: you know whatever it is You're gonna give you $20 to yeah some fight cancer fund because the NIH will be funny.
Rym: Instead the bajillion dollar also a secondary reason that we're for her.
Rym: I just clicked on her webpage randomly, and she's just holding up a microphone.
Scott: I can see her webpage say give me money on it.
Rym: of course of course It's American politics, but you vote with your dollars and your social media.
Rym: actual voting is like the least important part of our process.
Rym: But she's holding what looks like either a sure SM It might be a sure beta 58 a I can't tell.
Scott: It's one of those two, okay She knows how to use a microphone.
Scott: yep, that's a big plus.
Rym: What do you got in the news?
Scott: What do I have in the news?
Scott: Let me see what was my new?
Scott: So you know we often talk about scenarios where someone is out there making usually a video game and that video game is new and it's usually a remake or a remix of some kind and has a blatant complete disregard for all copyright and trademark law and Property.
Scott: intellectual property rights is across the board for example.
Scott: It was like a Metroid remakes.
Scott: Yeah, 3d chrono trigger remake.
Scott: right.
Scott: things along that line have happened many times and on this show long ago I would maybe Rym can find the video again and and link it.
Scott: Someone gave the excellent advice which is also my advice that they just made a video expressing the advice better than I did.
Scott: Maybe find the GeekNights episode where we had it as thing of the day News whatever it was and basically they were saying hey if you're making one of these things Shut your fucking
Rym: mouth Don't tell
Scott: anyone you're making it until it is done done done, and then release it and then even if it gets taken down It's okay because everyone has it
Rym: right.
Scott: so Here we go.
Scott: somebody made and this isn't a big deal.
Scott: It's not something you're actually maybe gonna want to play.
Scott: It's a big deal.
Scott: from a like technology stand It's like I want to play the Metroid remake and the chrono trigger remake that got posed.
Scott: Yeah, but I don't really want to play this so much, but what it is?
Rym: they remade Super Mario Brothers 1 For the Commodore 64 and if you're old enough to have YouTube like be from that era that is shocking to hear.
Scott: it is Incredible that they were able to make that hardware play that game.
Scott: considering other games for that hardware From when that hardware was popular we're nowhere near as good as any s games.
Scott: Yeah, right, so they were able to do this pretty incredible.
Scott: Jana sisters for Commodore 64 Which is like all.
Scott: even that was getting you know sued by Nintendo Was nowhere near as good as this thing looks like.
Scott: you know.
Scott: it's like incredible looks.
Rym: It's shocking how smoothly it plays.
Scott: yes, so it basically looks like Mario Brothers with slightly met colors.
Scott: Yep, right and it plays super smooth.
Scott: It looks exactly right.
Scott: It plays exactly the same.
Scott: the levels are the same.
Scott: it's obviously a blatant copyright trademark infringement on Nintendo's property.
Rym: It's also the kind of thing that I think needs to be protected by a modern revitalized copyright system.
Scott: But regardless the people who made this we're very smart, and you know what they did.
Rym: they shut the fucking mouths.
Scott: They released version 1.0.
Scott: It's out.
Scott: you can get it from someone else who got it and then Nintendo came and shut them down And it was like okay, we that was surprising that you even this Commodore 64 thing and in 2019 you're shutting down really, okay?
Scott: But I guess you're Nintendo.
Scott: That's what you're gonna do, but guess what everyone has this.
Scott: now you can get it.
Scott: Yeah, it's not you know gone gone.
Scott: It's not stopped before it was finished.
Scott: development.
Scott: what I think it was like one dude spent like a shit ton of years working on It.
Scott: it's amazing.
Scott: you can go get it if you really want to or at least watch a video of it.
Scott: And Nintendo got burned because someone followed the correct advice.
Scott: So if you're doing anything like this follow the same advice.
Scott: yeah, it works.
Rym: So I don't have any news cuz.
Rym: as much as I would like to hurry like yell about politics I'll just yell into my pillow.
Rym: tonight It's got Star Trek.
Scott: Voyager is a show isn't that a really old one.
Scott: It's a really old Star Trek.
Rym: it's the one that came after.
Rym: basically there was next generation in d-space 9 and then this was the one.
Scott: and The reason.
Scott: here's what Scott who doesn't like Star Trek knows.
Scott: right all right the old Star Trek the original one Right that was like Captain Kirk Yeah But that was the one where it was like alien babes on alien planets old-school kind of pulp sci-fi Galaxy Express like land on a planet.
Rym: There's a crisis.
Rym: we deal with it We leave right you know.
Scott: and then next generation one.
Scott: that one was more When I watched some episodes back when it was on the TV in the old days and that one at least to me felt more Like daytime soap opera.
Scott: only everyone happened to be on a spaceship and occasionally they would be aliens.
Scott: But not really.
Scott: I didn't really feel any different watching that than watching like any of the things that would be on after the price Is right hmm right, but it was just you know in space, so I guess that made it more acceptable to watch Even though it's basically the same thing and it had a shit.
Scott: too many episodes.
Scott: And then the DS 9 one which I watched maybe one episode of ever.
Rym: people have described it as the wire in space The one.
Scott: what I know about that is they weren't on a ship they were on a space station Yep at the edge of like Federation.
Rym: Well.
Scott: I didn't know that part.
Rym: It's called deep space 9 because it's in deep space It's way out there.
Scott: I just realized that just now.
Rym: And the Beatles isn't the bug it's the musical.
Scott: I learned that long time ago, but also okay same kind of real thing.
Scott: Yes, it had a guy with real big ears on it And I think it was basically you know like a sitcom.
Scott: only they were on A space station that didn't move.
Scott: so I guess they didn't have aliens visiting and ships shooting at them.
Scott: so in 1995 so this is one I know that there was one called Voyager.
Scott: they came after yep And I know nothing about it other than I assume there was some sort of voyaging going on.
Rym: so the shake of Voyager Is that there's this rebellion.
Rym: so there's all these settlers?
Rym: Colonizing like illegally colonizing territory that isn't in the humans or this amelian humans.
Rym: Okay, and like basically Federation ship bags are colonizing planets.
Rym: They are they getting there on in spaceships?
Scott: How do they have spaceships if they're bad?
Scott: well the spaceships all belong to the good.
Rym: you know lots of people have spaceships, okay?
Rym: Anyway, they're there.
Rym: There's a whole like thing going on and Voyager is a new ship that was developed with new technology And they send it to go deal with them, and it was just like the humans are gonna Go shoot other humans.
Scott: basically yeah, okay, so it's like a mad warship unlike that like the Enterprise like an exploring ship.
Scott: Right yeah, this is like a warship sort of.
Rym: it's got a little more going on But it's designed for like these special kinds of missions.
Rym: It's new technology.
Scott: It has human killing weapons.
Scott: Yes, it has weapons And the weapons don't just go pew like this the end.
Rym: It's more.
Rym: It's pretty powerful.
Rym: They go to deal with this thing and It's a star destroyer.
Rym: They get transported to the opposite side of the universe By accident.
Rym: yeah some alien technology happens.
Rym: some of the rebels and them get transported like further away than anyone has ever explored.
Rym: Okay, the Delta quadrant like way out middle of nowhere.
Rym: Because of it because of random because of alien thing that happens uh-huh.
Rym: so then Basically the whole thing is them flying back home them and the rebels just all get on the one ship and the goal is how The fuck do we get home even at our maximum?
Scott: So the whole plot of them being rebels and them not being rebels goes away because like well We're all in this together now.
Scott: It doesn't matter that your rebels Yeah, we're fucked now.
Rym: But you can settle in the Delta quadrant if you want even at warp 9 like many many times the speed of light It'll take us like a hundred years of direct flying to get home.
Scott: Well, I assume they do the hundred years of direct flying.
Scott: it just takes a hundred years.
Rym: So their goal is just to not die and get home right.
Scott: so I would just do the direct flying in a hundred years.
Scott: Just try to live a hundred years.
Rym: Oh, yeah, but along the way they try to like can we make our engines better?
Rym: Can we find a thing can we get a message to?
Scott: they try to stop and like at place?
Rym: Yeah, they basically they continue their mission of explore.
Rym: like do the thing of Explorer?
Rym: Well, it wasn't explore.
Scott: their mission was kill the rebels.
Rym: well Yeah, but the general mission of Starfleet is to explore Oh, you know to go where no one has gone before and all.
Scott: I thought that was only big a bold enterprise.
Rym: this mission That's that's the Federation's mission, okay?
Rym: Anyway, that's the show, but it came out in 1995 and ran till 2001.
Rym: I didn't know I ran that late.
Rym: Well, it has like two hundred and seventy episodes.
Rym: all these things have too many fucking episodes, but it was the era for in my life and in the life of many people around our age that it straddled the.
Rym: I Still watch things on TV, and I don't even have cable anymore Which made it interesting because as a kid I remember really liking the beginning of it And then just stopping watching it even though I really liked it because I didn't watch any TV anymore cuz fuck TV Mm-hmm, and I decided to watch it again because I needed a show to watch like on my shitty Kindle fire while I'm like Running on the treadmill in the winter
Scott: to read a book instead of why I can't
Rym: read a book while I'm running on a treadmill.
Rym: not I Dare you to run on a treadmill and read a physical book at the same time.
Rym: You could not yeah, I'd hold a book.
Rym: All right, you're wrong.
Rym: Yeah, I want.
Rym: I want to see video We will video this for GeekNights of you running at nine miles an hour on a treadmill.
Scott: I don't know if I can run nine miles an hour.
Rym: all right We'll figure out how fast you can run.
Rym: and you've got to run at that speed for like 20 minutes while reading a book.
Scott: I don't know if I can run in any speed for 20 minutes.
Rym: Yeah I'm picking a walk for 20 minutes.
Rym: Yeah, I could read a book while walking.
Rym: Why would I walk on a treadmill?
Scott: Cold outside.
Rym: The whole point of being on a treadmill is to exercise.
Rym: I'm gonna run it like nine or ten miles an hour on the treadmill.
Scott: not a thing I do.
Scott: Yeah, anyway, so I watched all the Voyager okay, and I guess it must have been good enough for you to keep watching It.
Scott: here's the problem is bad.
Scott: I imagine you would have just stopped.
Scott: Here's what's fascinating a hundred something episodes.
Scott: Here's what's
Rym: fascinating I I realized re watching this show with
Scott: adult brain
Rym: and then and also like with adult brain and Continuing to watch the show beyond where I stopped watching I Realized that the show is actually really good and the only reason I stopped watching and remembered it being boring.
Scott: You stopped watching TV.
Rym: Yeah, it was commercials.
Rym: That's true, too I had because when I watch these episodes every time like I see the moment coming of it's gonna come to commercial break.
Rym: fuck this I realized when I was a kid as soon as the first commercial break happened.
Rym: I turned off any TV show Just instantly, so I remembered the first setup of every single Star Trek Voyager episode up until like the year 2000 And I don't remember how it resolved cuz I turned it off or fell asleep as soon as the first commercials came on.
Scott: Yeah, I'd only ever watched Ten Commandments on television, and I'd never watched the whole thing in one go.
Scott: Yeah, I always what.
Scott: but I've seen all of it Moses Big fan hot
Rym: yule Brenner
Scott: right, but I watched it again because it was Passover and I downloaded a 1080p HD And I watched it all at once and it is this 1080p I downloaded even included like this introduction at the beginning is basically what you would have seen in the theaters in 1956. it included intermission and the overture Yeah, and it no commercials.
Scott: and the fact that there are no commercials made it way easier to watch and understand more impact.
Scott: It's just better in every way.
Rym: I Nothing but smoldering pictures of yule Brenner.
Scott: There's no such thing that you could just type you'll Brenner because there is not a non smoldering.
Rym: You'll Brenner picture might have been the hottest one of the hottest men to ever live.
Scott: He's up there.
Rym: Yeah He's definitely up there.
Rym: Anyway, my law my geek bite is by the way, you'll Brenner smoke themselves to death.
Scott: We have on cancer.
Rym: don't smoke don't smoke.
Rym: But Star Trek Voyager in a moderate like watching it on Netflix where there are no commercial breaks really good Really tight Tells.
Scott: only they could remove track from other show.
Rym: I know but because it's not a comedy There's no laugh track and as a result, I was good.
Rym: I will say that Voyager is actually one of my favorite Star Trek's now that I've watched it in a modern post commercial post television Context.
Rym: and the best characters are the non human characters.
Rym: Basically, the doctor who is a hologram and the Borg are the only two actually good characters Yeah, and all the like human or effectively human characters.
Rym: pretty boring and a boring human arcs.
Rym: but the non human characters actually have pretty good arcs and pretty interesting stories.
Rym: and if you thought that Voyager was boring because you Tried to watch it on TV.
Rym: I would recommend giving it a second go because Commercials ruin everything that is good and ads are a cancer upon entertainment.
Rym: and now it's time for the wings of the day.
Rym: so Scott say you've got a Cube Okay, that weighs like a kilogram all right, and you got another cube that weighs a kilogram and you got a wall and you'll push what the one one cube.
Rym: add another cube and It'll hit that cube and then that cube will hit a wall and bounce back toward the thing.
Rym: You just knocked Like you understand this this concepts.
Rym: Yeah in a physics world.
Rym: They're both one kilogram Yeah, or two kilograms or some number of kilograms.
Scott: both the cubes are the same The same same man, let's say they're the same right.
Scott: the first cube hits the second cube Yeah, it stops moving.
Scott: The next one carries all the energy.
Scott: Yeah goes into the wall.
Scott: Yeah bounces off the wall goes back into the first cube Then the first cube is moving and then eventually runs out energy and you got to push that first cube hard enough.
Scott: Well, it might stop somewhere in between.
Scott: Other than the friction heat and wind air resistance energy that gets lost.
Scott: Right, you know all the energy is going into the movement of the cube.
Scott: It would be the same if you just push the one cube against the wall and it bounced off Right.
Scott: So what if let's what does like when you have all the balls on a string and you hit one at the end You let it go and then the one on the other end jumps out and all the rest of them is not moving.
Rym: So let's assume there's no friction.
Rym: So it is just one to one.
Rym: you hit cube one and it's cube to cube to bounce off the wall comes back.
Rym: How many collisions occur?
Scott: Let's see cube one hits cube two.
Scott: Yep one two hits wall.
Scott: Yep cube two hits cube one.
Scott: Yep, that's three three three.
Rym: All right three.
Rym: What if the first cube weighs more like two kilograms or 16 kilograms or 64 kilograms?
Scott: All right.
Scott: Well the first cube comes in the.
Scott: so the first cube is bigger.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: All right The first cube is bigger.
Scott: So it comes in.
Scott: it hits the hits the second cube.
Scott: I guess the bigger first cube would not would keep moving along right.
Scott: it would keep going.
Rym: So it's getting closer and closer and closer, right?
Scott: So the second cube Cube is gonna fly towards the wall, but the first cube isn't stopped.
Scott: It's gonna keep moving along Slower than it was but still moving.
Scott: It just put a bunch of its energy into that for a second cube Yep, and then the small one is gonna bounce off the wall come back and hit again Yeah, and then so there's a lot of collisions.
Scott: actually probably Yeah, you're probably gonna get like a ding-a-ding-a-ding-a-ding-a-ding-a-ding any situation and they eventually stop.
Rym: So what if I told you that if you calculate for this situation?
Rym: The number of collisions the bigger the first cube is compared to the second cube it The number of collisions ends up being PI.
Rym: It's the digits of PI.
Rym: It is the digits of PI.
Rym: if it's a 1,000,000 kilogram cube and a 1 kilogram cube the number of collisions is 3140. and if you keep increasing this it converges on the digits of PI.
Rym: It sounds crazy.
Rym: That is the answer.
Scott: That's just an artifact of how we do math and not an artifact of the universe.
Rym: No, it is an artifact of the universe.
Rym: So if it is a 1 oh Kilogram cube against a 1 kilogram cube.
Rym: the number of collisions is three three million one hundred forty one thousand five hundred and ninety-two.
Rym: It does in fact calculate PI.
Rym: this video is called.
Rym: So why do colliding blocks compute PI?
Rym: and in 15 minutes?
Rym: The answer is amazing and terrifying.
Scott: What if the mass of my cube?
Scott: Was e?
Scott: Would it bounce negative one time?
Scott: Then anyway, no the mass I think has to be negative one then it would bounce e times.
Rym: Yeah can't have negative mass.
Scott: Or yup, I bounce a black hole into a Rym's face.
Rym: Anyway, this video is you know that numberphile channel.
Rym: we link to it kind of often because it's a really fun channel.
Scott: They've been making a little less videos lately, but they did put it out recently.
Scott: They're not dead.
Rym: Yeah, they make really good stuff.
Rym: But numberphile is like here's a cool math concept explained at Rym and Scott's like current understanding of math.
Scott: Explain it to educated person who can do basic arithmetic and knows like algebra, but who hasn't actually done much serious math since college.
Rym: Yeah, so or ever Three blue one round is a channel that basically is numberphile for people who actually continued to study math.
Scott: Oh, so I can't understand anything in this video.
Rym: You will it's just you have to give this video your full attention.
Scott: But I'll just trust you on the PI thing.
Rym: It's kind of amazing.
Scott: the explanation good fucking God that is an amazing colliding block is amazing.
Rym: if true calculates PI and The reason it calculates PI actually does make sense.
Scott: What about spheres?
Scott: always fears instead?
Rym: They do the same thing because they're wouldn't they calculate some square.
Rym: Here's the problem Are they the same physical size just with different masses?
Scott: Well, no, they're not sliding.
Scott: They're rolling as opposed.
Rym: We already said perfectly elastic no friction, so it wouldn't matter.
Rym: But if one's bigger than the other one, it matters a lot because now their center is in a different position.
Rym: So the first one might like bounce over the top water.
Scott: What if I got us?
Scott: I hit a small thing into a big thing, but I hit it fast enough.
Scott: So the big thing moves and the big thing starts out close enough to the wall that it still bounces back.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Anyway, they calculate PI and it's fucking amazing.
Rym: What do you got?
Scott: What do I have?
Scott: so, you know in the world we have lots of languages and alphabets.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: and then we have ways of music notation.
Rym: Yeah, pretty much convert right.
Scott: you draw dots on sticks on bars, right?
Scott: You know how music looks like when you're writing sheet music.
Rym: Yeah, I've studied music theory in detail.
Scott: even I know how to read that.
Scott: You know, there are other ways of writing musical notation.
Scott: There's like guitar tabs, which are slightly different, right?
Scott: They're pretty much still dots on bars kind.
Rym: Yeah, you know, but not exactly the same.
Rym: I've always considered tabs to be Guitar.
Rym: players want to play chords, but don't actually want to learn how to read music.
Scott: Yeah, basically.
Scott: But you know there have been other musical notation systems in history.
Scott: There still are many in use in some places But pretty much the normal one that you think of with treble clef's and shit is the one in most of the world.
Rym: Yeah, right, but a comic combined with Italian language like that's what we use.
Scott: Yeah, but here is one that I'd never seen before and this whole article about it.
Scott: That is really amazing and not mostly amazing just because it looks fucking awesome.
Scott: Yeah, like it's a work of art.
Scott: Like if I look at some sheet music sheet music can occasionally be a work of art But it's generally kind of meh.
Scott: It's a better heard than seen.
Rym: Yeah of all people.
Rym: so you want to know a side story.
Rym: I've heard tell that Wagner would write certain notes or certain parts in different colors Just for reasons.
Rym: I'm gonna make sure that's actually true and not just something a music teacher told
Scott: me I just checked that you'll render did die of lung cancer After he quit smoke like a few years after he quit smoking and then after when he realized the smoke and killed him He was like god damn it and made like anti-smoking ads.
Scott: no like don't die of lung cancer like I didn't.
Scott: I'm like.
Scott: I'm going to All right anyway, so anyway, so this is a Tibetan way.
Rym: That might be a myth.
Rym: the color thing is not on his Wikipedia page anyway.
Scott: This is a Tibetan way of a musical notation And it looks fucking awesome and regardless of what it sounds like it is beautiful to behold like.
Scott: I kind of want to get one Of these just hanging on the wall or something.
Scott: but actually I also learned from this that this is used to denote a type of throat singing that sounds a lot like Mongolian throat singing.
Scott: so I guess those places in the world Tibet and Mongolia are pretty close to each other.
Scott: So I guess there is some sort of shared Ancestry or shared cultural ancestry related to throat singing.
Scott: that's pretty cool.
Scott: And once you know that this is denoting throat singing.
Scott: you sort of make sense When you look at it why it's you know denoting that kind of music.
Rym: yep also singing is really awesome.
Scott: Yeah, I also like throat singing a lot.
Scott: like I just go and Spotify type in some throat singing.
Scott: There is a metal band, I think it's called the who band.
Scott: it's a Mongolian throat singing metal band.
Scott: They're fucking awesome, and I think they've been a thing of the day before.
Scott: But I was reminded of their existence recently and this is relevant.
Scott: So I figured why not bring up that awesome throat singing metal man so funnily enough?
Rym: I got it in high school.
Rym: You know I talked about like.
Rym: I got whistling lessons in high school because we wanted to perform a thing like they did a whistling Clinic we have.
Scott: did you see the world whistling championships?
Rym: I know of the world whistling championships.
Scott: I watched a video.
Scott: some people who like went there and made like a mini documentary about it.
Rym: whistling is Difficult to do well, but anyway.
Rym: so we had another clinic for a song We were gonna do.
Rym: that involved throat singing and we had a throat singing expert.
Rym: come in awesome and give lessons in throat singing.
Rym: I was unable to do it.
Scott: I feel like that takes a lot more practice to even make any sound.
Scott: So basically for sound.
Rym: so we did a clinic with anyone in the class able to make the right thing Like six people who were able to pull it off like at all.
Rym: So then they got a much more intensive class to be able to do it for a song we performed.
Rym: It was really fun.
Rym: I really wish I was able to do it, but I couldn't make it work.
Rym: so and we were under pressure.
Scott: So they like all right who can throat sing?
Rym: yep, who?
Rym: who is most likely be able to pull this off Rym?
Rym: Nope, you can't do it.
Rym: stick to your fucking whistling.
Scott: Yeah, did you combine the whistling in the throat singing?
Rym: I can do.
Rym: I can your job fitting.
Rym: I can do that I can do the hum and whistle at the same time, but I can't do In the.
Rym: but this stuff's really cool.
Rym: in the meta moment.
Rym: the GeekNights book club book is the most painful book We have ever chosen.
Rym: It is Troy Dennings pages of pain Currently consuming some painful pages.
Rym: I am at the part where the tiefling calls him zombie.
Scott: I'm at the part where they are on.
Scott: they just they were on like a cart full of dead bodies And they just got off the car right.
Rym: so then you met the the crazy centaur kind of guy.
Rym: the good Maybe not.
Scott: maybe that's on the next page.
Rym: Yeah, the one who thinks the whole world's a dream Yeah, not.
Rym: He's about to appear.
Scott: if I recall correctly They just got off a cart of dead bodies.
Rym: I didn't write didn't get past a zumba yet because I've been biking to work, so I haven't been reading on the subway.
Rym: yep But we'll read this book pretty quick.
Rym: I'm gonna update the page tonight.
Rym: Geena's book club.
Rym: It's uh We'll see how painful this book is.
Rym: I got some thoughts already.
Scott: I have a lot of thoughts already.
Rym: thoughts about the threson The amnesiac hero.
Rym: yeah the amnesiac hero, that's very relevant to the story here.
Rym: Our bunch of our bunch of our panels are on YouTube.
Rym: you can just watch them.
Rym: real harm of games rare game mechanics Etc.
Rym: we don't have any conventions till pecs.
Scott: if you PAX West that is yes.
Scott: by the way PAX West ticket be on alert.
Scott: Yep, these are the times.
Rym: if you Want us to do more content the best thing you can do to make that happen is to take the videos we upload to YouTube.
Rym: so judge anime real harm of games rare game mechanics the three videos we just made and seriously Post them on the reddits and all the places you do your internet shit like the forums and reddits you hang out on that We don't hang out on because we do not go shamelessly self-promote our videos.
Rym: We just promote directly from our source, so if you want us to make more things like that Promote them for us.
Scott: You know I already tell you not to give Rym your patreon money.
Scott: Why are you doing free labor for him to promote his content?
Scott: And he should be hiring a PR firm or a marketing firm or something like that.
Scott: Don't give your labor freely to Rym.
Rym: I am saying or your money.
Rym: I'm just saying if you want us to make more videos the best way to get us to do that I'm not making more videos no matter the view.
Scott: count on the videos will not determine how many more videos I make.
Rym: you're just saying that cuz real harm of games is getting way less views than a rare game mechanics Despite being equally promoted.
Scott: I mean I didn't even know what the views were.
Scott: yeah, I don't look at views.
Scott: Yeah My only way that it would ever change than the amount of content I make is if it made you enough money to where you could quit your job, right?
Scott: It's not like I check the views or the money.
Scott: someone have to come to me and be like hey Did you know your thing made a bunch of money?
Scott: You don't have to go to work tomorrow?
Scott: Right cuz I don't look at it ever.
Rym: I'm just saying views are like buying lottery tickets Probably not gonna change anything in our lives, but it only takes one thing going viral to be good.
Rym: hmm We have now the bay.
Rym: the biggest thing I've ever made in my life is a My Little Pony mashup.
Rym: So yep.
Scott: Oh no no actually the biggest thing the most The most viewed content I've ever made is a video of Rainbow Dash going.
Scott: oh my gosh Oh my gosh.
Scott: Oh my gosh.
Rym: Oh my gosh the most viewed thing I ever made is a goodies Game of Thrones mashup.
Rym: I made when Game of Thrones was still in like season one.
Rym: It's still up.
Rym: It hasn't been copyrighted.
Scott: isn't that ending soon?
Rym: Uh yeah?
Rym: Maybe I'll watch it all.
Scott: that was zero of it, and that's I plan to keep it that way.
Rym: I would put it this way Scott the if you watched the first season of Game of Thrones for Shane long You would probably really like it Because it'll scratch a lot of the same itches that like Prince of Nothing kind of thing does the pry hand.
Scott: And it always seemed more like a l5r to me.
Rym: Well I guess the way I'd put yeah with the wall and those yeah I can see that like the little I know Or care about Game of Thrones it basically felt like l5r with different skin on it.
Rym: I'll put it this way season one is pretty good mostly because There's a hand there's smart care the characters even the good the good ones the evil ones everyone.
Rym: They do the smart thing and It's pretty good, and then Wheel of Time also have a wall with bad guys on the other side.
Rym: You can sort of in the Northeast yeah It's got a couple things like that.
Scott: uh-huh fucking Wheel of Time any fantasy things have a wall with bad guys on the other side because that's it.
Rym: the kaiju wall is a fun Thing to have.
Rym: I remember when Yorkie when you encountered the kaiju wall when we were playing that l5r game The first thing you did was like Time.
Scott: I had ever encountered that trope wasn't a trope.
Rym: then it was fresh, but you got really excited about the wall.
Scott: You're like what's on the other side cuz it was new now.
Scott: It's a trope.
Scott: I've seen like four walls now I don't need anymore.
Scott: I remember you was only exciting the first time were you're like crab clan.
Rym: I forget what you were but you grandpa ninja Yeah, you ran to the other side of the wall sort of roll around in the dirt to see if it would do anything to You.
Scott: yeah, someone said it was evil on the other side.
Rym: Yeah, but uh I. Anyway the last episode of season one does something really surprising and shocking and good and interesting.
Rym: And then after that it just got kind of boring and I stopped watching.
Rym: So you can watch just the first season.
Rym: you get everything you need to get out of.
Scott: just watch something else.
Rym: That's pretty good.
Rym: It ain't that long.
Scott: I'll watch.
Scott: he who punches only one time.
Rym: Oh, yeah, or I'm gonna finish.
Rym: door row row row row row row row row and there's gonna be.
Rym: there's the new horror anime.
Rym: There's stuff to watch Adventure times done so you don't have to watch that anymore.
Scott: Nope.
Rym: All right, let's get into it.
Rym: I Am a huge huge fan of horror movies.
Rym: There are not that many good horror movies in the world.
Scott: I am also a fan not huge but a regular sized fan of horror movies.
Rym: I spent my whole life watching horror movies from a very young age because my mom also likes horror movies.
Rym: That's why I want and also my mom also likes the harm.
Rym: I like torture porn gore movies Movies slasher movies every kind of horror fiction.
Rym: I am down.
Scott: My problem is is that you know, I tend to only it's like I really like Horror movies when they're good.
Scott: They are just extremely rarely good now.
Rym: also there are very very different subs.
Scott: It's like how can it's everyone's like you're a horror movie fan, but like you only like like a handful.
Scott: it's like yeah Well, ninety nine point nine and nine percent of them are really kind of lowbrow crappy cheaply made Blah look like.
Scott: and it's not the fault of the genre It's the fault of the fact that you know, it doesn't make the biggest money.
Scott: So they don't invest the biggest money into making horror films that often Budget lower production value.
Rym: I'd say it's - it's two factors.
Rym: It's the factor of one They don't make.
Rym: it's like even a great horror movie just won't make that much money compared to like another movie.
Rym: And horror is like comedy and that it's really fucking hard to do.
Rym: Oh, yeah, like it is real hard to make a good horror movie.
Scott: It's real hard to make an actually funny movie Yeah, but like my you know, my top ones are like alien.
Scott: Yeah, John Carpenter is the thing.
Scott: Yeah, it's like.
Scott: those are pretty much the best ones.
Rym: but it also look at subgenres like horror is one of those things where?
Rym: People who are aficionados like really get granular about the subgenres.
Rym: I should watch anyway Or like like slasher matrix and again, oh we were talking about watching The Matrix.
Rym: the other day I I watched a Clip from The Matrix because someone did a thing of like how they did this scene that I didn't think about.
Rym: guns lots of guns Yeah, no that scene.
Rym: I know what they did it But it was it anyway, I saw trying to hit me and hit me.
Rym: I saw this clip and I was like, oh shit.
Rym: I just want to watch The Matrix.
Rym: Of course.
Rym: Oh, no Oh, no, if I should I show you a Star Wars clip, but no I got shit to do tonight.
Rym: Scott let's watch just one episode of cowboy bebop and stop as long as it's the last episode.
Rym: Even then I'll watch the end of it and I'll be like who I should watch the beginning.
Scott: Let's watch for some of the image.
Rym: Oh, no No, the first episode the the moment where Evangelion grabs me.
Rym: if I watch the very beginning I'm fine until you see that end to palm bomb go off and then you see the nuke like explosion.
Scott: I'm fine until the shot where the car is driving towards the city and the building start coming up.
Rym: Yeah, that's pretty good too for me.
Rym: It's the moment where the bomb goes off and then the the old men are like we did it we fucking nuked it.
Scott: I know needed to shit.
Rym: Yep, and then you just see the alien.
Scott: They're still walking.
Rym: Yeah, I'm just still walking.
Scott: Anyway, let's get on topic.
Rym: but like slasher movies the first slasher movies were good at what they did.
Rym: And then there are a million clones.
Rym: a lot of times when a horror movie is good There will be a million knockoffs of that particular sub-genre of horror.
Rym: They're all.
Scott: and even though a lot of those movies were good in their day For me at least a lot of them have not aged well, right?
Rym: Like I can recognize the Evil Dead is a is a product of its time.
Scott: I can recognize You know the quality the the legacy all the.
Scott: you know The parts of say a Friday the 13th or a nightmare on Elm Street or a Halloween,
Rym: but I play one
Scott: Right, but any of those while I can recognize and and respect them like to watch them now for me is kind of a
Rym: yeah Yeah,
Scott: but I was right.
Scott: It's not like watching alien.
Rym: I watched them mostly the way I watch old movies that don't hold up where I'm watching them like as an exploration of that era of cinema.
Rym: But yeah us is a good modern horror movie That is hard to put in a genre of or a sub-genre of horror.
Scott: Well, we got to talk about get out first.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Okay.
Scott: So yeah, so is Jordan Peele, right?
Scott: Yeah of key and peel the great comedy duo.
Rym: Yeah, if you do not realize Jordan Peele is responsible for both get out and us, right?
Scott: So, you know It's like.
Scott: I remember key and peel when they were comedy dudes doing funny comedies that I like and are hilarious human beings.
Scott: But I guess they stopped doing that show.
Scott: and now Jordan Peele's producing slash directing horror movies.
Rym: Total aside you ever watch Fargo the TV show?
Scott: I watched Fargo the movie.
Rym: Yeah Fargo the TV show There's three seasons is a plus like a plus television.
Scott: It's just like retelling the movie or what?
Scott: No, what is it?
Rym: Well, let's say lady to the movie in any way Yes, well, we should.
Rym: we'll talk.
Rym: we should talk about this separately.
Rym: We'll go on for a while.
Rym: They're real good movies good, but They are in one of them as FBI agents.
Rym: Oh, that's funny and they're a plus.
Rym: I can imagine Independent of the show being a plus.
Scott: so he made the movie get out which was much lauded.
Rym: We went to see in the theater and it was a combination of horror and social commentary Which I shouldn't need to say because all good horror movies are some form of social commentary, of course.
Scott: Yeah, it was actually get out was way good.
Rym: get out is scary as shit.
Scott: It's not scary.
Rym: It's a horror movie.
Rym: It's scary It's suspenseful.
Rym: It's got it's got.
Rym: it's got suspense scenes.
Rym: It's got good jump-scare scenes.
Rym: It's got good like existential scene.
Rym: It's got all the trappings of a horror movie.
Scott: I mean it is a horror movie doesn't trappings of it is.
Rym: well you have this weird thing If you say that no movie is scary, it isn't scary.
Rym: All right, what?
Rym: what's a movie?
Rym: You've ever seen that was scary?
Scott: because your definition of scary is ridiculous and I digress I mean when I was a kid, I was scared of mr.
Scott: Boogity, which isn't even a I'm not anymore.
Rym: If we ever make a Small if we ever make a GeekNights movie club to go alongside the book club.
Rym: Mr.
Rym: Boogity is good I'm sure it's just on YouTube.
Scott: Anyway, he's googling.
Scott: All right, so The mr.
Rym: Boogity whole movie there you go on YouTube.
Scott: Okay, anyway commercials no.
Scott: Anyway, so get out was real good.
Scott: and because get out was so good.
Scott: I'm like, well that was so good.
Scott: I will go see us.
Scott: your new horror movie, you know, not it's not a sequel It's not related to get out directly other than another movie in the same genre made by the same people in the theater again.
Scott: Yes, I will go see that just like you write a good book and you may write another book I'll read that one too, right same deal.
Scott: So he went to see us and Us is also real good.
Scott: I don't think it's as good as get out, but it's still real good and I will still go to Yet another horror movie if they make another one.
Rym: I mean, I think the main difference around gonna spoil anything It's a movie.
Rym: just go watch it and it's a horror movie where there are twists.
Rym: You'll probably see him coming.
Rym: Maybe you don't saw him coming.
Rym: Yeah, though I actually expected a deeper twist of like one of the two people Changing as opposed to have anyway, I there was another way that could have gone.
Rym: that would have been a very similar twist.
Rym: Yeah, yeah, and I I thought it was going more in that direction But it was obvious at a certain point with a certain thing Where we both said this is getting dumb.
Rym: Oh, wait.
Rym: No now it's good again.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Yep so the theater read.
Rym: the good points about this movie are that number one the Score and soundtrack are just perfect.
Rym: Hmm They they use where.
Scott: so I remember during like while watching it.
Scott: right not not the score the the orchestral music.
Scott: Yeah, right But the you know the tracks that they you know of popular music that they selected and inserted into the movie.
Scott: We're always the most appropriate song possible Yep But they weren't.
Rym: they served a good purpose in the sense that the movie is both a horror movie with various kinds of scariness And such.
Rym: but it is also funny and it does.
Rym: it's.
Rym: it's the kind of horror movie that has some dark humor and some just straight-up humor all interwoven and It's sort of a. it has a complex palette of emotions while you're watching
Scott: right and most of it was that the music they selected Was not only super appropriate and super great music But also it wasn't what happens in a lot of movies where they selected like the brand new hit song For promotional
Rym: purposes.
Rym: No, no, no, fuck the police.
Scott: They were selecting the song for you know, for the movie purposes.
Rym: There's it like there's a moment that there is a serious Horrifying scene happening and a character basically does the equivalent saying Alexa call the police and Alexa's like playing Fuck the police by NWA And then fuck the police just starts playing right.
Scott: and that brings me to my second point about this movie.
Scott: Is that perhaps better than any movie I have ever seen ever horror movie at least Where characters are in a difficult situation?
Scott: and it takes place in the present day Like everyone's got cell phones.
Scott: There's Alexa right there There's cars this boats this.
Scott: every conceivable modern technology is available.
Rym: They're in like a beach town with a lot of people.
Rym: they're not even that isolated not isolated at all.
Scott: They're not right.
Scott: and yet despite all that the horror scenario and the thing the course of events are Such that a no one does anything stupid.
Scott: and B. They don't need any contrivances whatsoever To say oh, why don't they just solve this problem by using their modern technology?
Scott: Because the problem is such that they do try to solve it using their body technology in the same reasonable ways Anyone else would.
Rym: and it doesn't matter character encounters something creepy.
Rym: They are reasonable adults and they're like, yeah, that's crazy.
Scott: No, there's no scene where it's like, oh man, no cell service.
Scott: I guess I can't call the police.
Scott: Yeah, there's no scene where it's like, you know, why didn't they just call it?
Scott: They literally just like call the police.
Scott: Yeah, and they called them that moment.
Rym: And again, we're not gonna spoil anything but the dead.
Rym: the kids like why is there a family standing outside our house, right?
Rym: Dad's like there ain't no family standing.
Scott: Oh, there's no nonsense.
Scott: for like one character sees something that no one else see.
Rym: Everyone tells everyone everything they could.
Rym: the dad's like there's no families.
Rym: That's stupid.
Rym: Then he looks out the windows ago.
Scott: Everyone sees everything.
Rym: Everything is real family standing outside and he doesn't like.
Rym: obviously that's creepy.
Rym: But if I everyone's working everyone's working together He goes He goes outside and he's like.
Rym: I will go deal with this because even though it's creepy The world is not filled with ghosts and monsters.
Scott: Right that we think might be a ghost or a monster who knows what?
Scott: because the horror movie.
Scott: and we hear Reasonable people in the real world these characters in this movie.
Scott: They just go take a baseball bat and try to hit it.
Rym: Yeah, well first he goes outside like okay.
Scott: No tries to talk to it.
Scott: Then he tries to hit it with a baseball.
Rym: Yeah, right everything for guys.
Rym: They come back and call the police.
Rym: They do everything.
Rym: everybody does everything reasonable at every point in this movie.
Scott: And I think that is like the number one thing that this movie does better than any horror movie ever.
Rym: The number two thing that it does is it really sets up a mood and a place Like the atmosphere is set correctly and all the Chekhov's guns are lined up in a row But it escalates faster.
Rym: a lot of horror movies fail because they ramp up really slowly.
Rym: This movie hits a point pretty early on where it goes from like one mile an hour to 100 miles an hour.
Rym: pop up go go go.
Rym: Yeah, and it never slows down after that point.
Scott: Yeah, there's a lot It's true.
Scott: I didn't even think about that.
Scott: Is that you know, there's a lot of ones out there where it's like, okay Even the thing like the or you know alien like the two that I mentioned is being the best right?
Scott: It's like We're gonna be all crying and even after the thing bursts out of the chest and it's quiet This one's like.
Scott: no this does not follow the dread tower model of build suspense Collapse build suspense collapse when people die, right?
Scott: This is what's going on here.
Scott: They're clearly setting up spooky stuff right from the beginning you know and then the spooky stuff unleashes and it's crazy for the rest of the movie.
Rym: crazy crazy in your face and When characters get a rest constant chasing running fighting monsters.
Rym: Oh my god The tension still does ratchet down.
Rym: but unlike traditional like slasher movies where situation doesn't unfuck up Nope It's more like torchbearer Where you're still in the dungeon and you're just like getting an hour's respite before you continue to try to carry the tapestry out.
Rym: Yeah, like no one's fresh again at any point in this movie who listen to this understands that reference Tapestry carrying and It gets without spoiling anything at all.
Rym: it gets the appropriate amount of surreal and Weird at the end without going overboard and not making sense.
Scott: Yeah, the explanation of about what's really going on is similarly surreal to the explanation of what's really going on and get out.
Rym: Yep, it also goes in on the social commentary, but it's a lot less than get out It's more like you can read like you can interpret a lot of very heavy.
Scott: It's like what are you?
Scott: it's like we're American.
Rym: That's.
Rym: that scene is actually one of my favorite moments because it's such a weird answer that even the theater I like I wanted to laugh but it almost wasn't fun.
Scott: And then it makes sense when you In the scene it's like what.
Scott: and but it's like in the scene It seems like a social commentary but also like a what what.
Scott: but then when you zoom out and see the whole movie It's like oh Yeah, they are Americans, yeah, they are Americans but also they're Americans.
Rym: yes, there's there are Americans.
Scott: Yep, that's what the movies trying to say, by the way.
Rym: Yeah But The shit.
Rym: the other great part about this movie is that it lines up all the check kinds of Chekhov's guns that happen in horror movies and they do all fire but the results of them firing are Widely varied And I'm not even gonna hint at what I'm referring to.
Rym: to see the movie It's really good.
Scott: Like I I even though I did see this in the theater.
Scott: You are okay not see.
Scott: This is not a must see in theater.
Scott: It's okay to see in theater Yeah, but it's not a must.
Rym: see it.
Scott: the best part Thanks or a DVD or waste your money on Voorhe.
Rym: We saw it with our friend Judith who's on the podcast a while ago.
Rym: Just me Scott and Judith because uh other friends of ours didn't want to see it until we had seen it to tell them Cowards, yeah, but also because you know, they might have some specifically triggering things in it.
Scott: That's also a reason.
Rym: Yeah, Fred, if you're not okay with the Foley of someone getting stabbed like do not see this movie.
Scott: If you're not okay with like, you know people getting beat up with golf clubs or run over by cars.
Scott: You know, it's a horrifying horror movie with horror stuff in it.
Scott: Yeah, considering that I've seen like, you know, each of the killer and Ebola syndrome.
Scott: I can watch anything.
Scott: Yeah There's an ad.
Scott: in fact, I would say, you know If you can deal with the alien coming out of the guy's stomach an alien then you can watch this whole movie.
Scott: There's nothing as bad as that.
Rym: but this one the three of us went to see in the theater like pretty recently.
Rym: That's why we're only reviewing it now like near the end of its run.
Rym: So there was like almost no one else in the theater with us.
Rym: Yeah there was a family like kind of behind us like to the right and there's a moment in the movie where something creepy happens to the Dad and the dad in
Scott: the family just said
Rym: he basically just says oh hell no And we and everyone in the theater just started laughing.
Rym: It was real like you'll get that interaction if you see this in a movie theater.
Scott: It does have some comedy and it does, you know as a good horror movie shit.
Rym: Yes Good horror movies will jump-scare you also separately make you feel existential growing dread and Tension that does not get released until way after you wanted it to and will also make you laugh out loud.
Rym: That is like the mark of a truly great horror movie.
Rym: I Will watch this movie again someday Right now but I could watch it again.
Rym: I feel like I'd notice things.
Scott: I know it's not like a matrix situation where it's like if I turn it on you're stuck.
Rym: But if you were a fan of scare spooky scary horror movies, this is a top tier.
Scott: What other horror movie you get in besides this recently?
Rym: Like I'm already reaching way back when I'm thinking about a whole like proper horror movies.
Rym: I in fact, most of the good horror I get is on pseudopod, which is written fiction.
Scott: Are you still listening?
Rym: Yeah, pseudopod is great.
Rym: Like pseudopod if you like horror just subscribe to the pseudopod podcast.
Rym: never look back.
Scott: I mean, you know when people talk, you know And people.
Scott: the only recent horror movies I hear about are ones like the one where everyone had to be quiet.
Scott: I didn't see.
Scott: I saw the trailer.
Scott: I did actually watch the movie and I heard bad things about it.
Scott: Yeah, and then there's the one that's not even new anymore.
Scott: It's actually kind of old by now, but it's newer than alien.
Scott: Yeah is what's that cabin in the woods one?
Scott: Yeah, and everyone loved that but I thought it was hella overrated in May.
Rym: Yeah, it was okay.
Scott: Yeah, I did not a fan.
Rym: Ah What's my favorite horror movie?
Rym: I'm trying to think like what's my top like two or three.
Rym: The problem is I like horror comedies.
Scott: You just also big alien and thing and be smart like me.
Rym: Yeah, probably I gotta think on it.
Rym: I gotta think on it.
Rym: Us is up there.
Rym: us is very expertly crafted.
Scott: Yeah, it's not top ten, but it is good.
Rym: It's not it's top 50 Of course top 50 of all time horribly easily.
Rym: probably top 25 all time probably but I'm hedging here.
Rym: Yeah, I could have only only named 100 horror movies.
Scott: I mean the problem is, you know some you got it.
Scott: There's too much discussion.
Scott: We're not gonna have it now, but it's like, you know say You know old Dracula like nose for that count.
Scott: Is that a horror movie even?
Rym: Yeah, probably not Horror-efficient.
Scott: oughta go see Dracula.
Scott: Is that a horror movie?
Rym: Yeah, what about hocus-pocus?
Scott: Young Frankenstein, is that a horror movie?
Scott: Is it?
Scott: does it count?
Rym: No, that just definitely not count even though it has the proper noun tropes of horror.
Rym: That's its own subjoint.
Scott: So that's I'm saying that same sub-genre as the Munsters, right?
Scott: There's some kind of discussions you gotta have there before we can start making this list.
Rym: Yeah, but go see right now I want to make the menu Not the list just like when else is on Netflix or whatever like.
Rym: definitely see it it's really good.
Scott: I hung.
Rym: this has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night.
Rym: and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights Then I'm going to try to read as fast as possible with as few breaths as possible.
Rym: because why not challenge myself?
Rym: Craig Oliver Allen Joe's hiding me to go just like a dude guy care top shin linky Jim for his car Chris made If I stay that come shape and scootaloo.
Rym: Loretta Giggs Lee Shawn Yeager, Matthew brand not Shawnee or Nicholas brander, mr Strong stretch in 4 to 1 creations.
Rym: the elves know me as fang.
Rym: Yuck Sherman on horror.
Rym: Rory Michelle mountain known as super boy sailor vista.
Rym: George I just our Clinton Walton run from New Zealand Ryan parent rope and lighter fin day.
Rym: or finish on Chris farmer Thomas Hana.
Rym: now I leave you with One more time.
Scott: they bought a number number three.
Scott: what they can we use them to get through the Number turn?
Scott: what they.
Scott: can we use them to get through that?