Rym: It's Tuesday, June 4th, 2019.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights Tonight, Risk of Rain and Risk of Rain 2.
Scott: Should have said Risks of Rain.
Rym: That was a better title.
Rym: I ain't going back now.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: So I've been really doubling down.
Rym: I've been playing a lot of Overwatch lately.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: It's uh, It's hard to express again how much that game is exactly what I want of an FPS.
Rym: But at the same time I'm Finding that I'm getting better, and I think it might be because other people getting worse.
Rym: I think it's because other people are getting worse or not trying as hard or Players leaving so you're up against.
Scott: you know lesser.
Rym: Well, I think it's coupled with the fact that they added this whole system where you can cue for the random cue.
Rym: But you can be like I only play tank or me and my friend only play better team comps.
Rym: Yeah, so I just play straight random.
Rym: I've never used any of that nonsense.
Rym: I just say put me on a team so I get put on a team with a bunch of people who are like I can only play tank and I can only play DPS.
Scott: It would actually be a lot easier for me.
Scott: I might almost not I'm not going to.
Scott: but if they had that for MOBAs I might almost play one because part of the like.
Rym: the first problem I have playing a MOBA.
Rym: You don't want to learn every character.
Scott: Well, no is that when I turn a MOBA on It's like I want to pick the character.
Scott: It looks cool like the awesome wizard or some shit.
Scott: It's like you know and you could pick random, but that's no good.
Scott: It's like let someone else pick the good thing that fits on this team for me.
Scott: And then if I just keep doing that over and over again that takes a huge knowledge.
Rym: Back when I was like platinum overwatch like when I was actually really good or at least my rank was really good It was partly because I was playing in a group with other good people.
Rym: But the main difference was that those people Would do that work like they'd be like Rym play This kind of shield tank on this map.
Rym: because of this reason that you don't understand and I'd be like, yes, sir Yeah, and I would be great.
Rym: Yeah, but now when I play in like high silver low gold Everyone else on the team is just dumb as bricks.
Rym: So I got to be there and be like look you don't play Reaper on this map play Widow.
Rym: Oh, you can't snipe fine.
Rym: Can anyone snipe?
Rym: Can anyone snipe fine?
Rym: I will snipe.
Rym: you do this.
Rym: you do that you two are healers and then we win.
Scott: the people actually listen though.
Scott: Actually, they do.
Scott: Oh, that's good.
Rym: The community is like.
Rym: I am Continuously shocked and how good the community is in the actual games when I'm actually talking to human beings in the voice chat Like I'd say one out of ten games has someone who's a piece of shit Compared to counter-strike where it's one out of point five games because there's two shitheads per game.
Rym: Like I'm like they did everything right and I don't know how to make the game more popular.
Rym: I maybe it's just that kind of FPS like kids want to play fortnight.
Scott: Well, I think it's just.
Scott: this is a problem for all games that are all multiplayer.
Scott: You know competitive games games that you can just keep playing and playing and playing it with.
Scott: you know ladders and all this stuff.
Scott: They all have this common problem of maintaining player interest.
Scott: You can only do the same thing over and over again for so long No matter how Intricate it is and there are some people on earth who can go into that like people who just play chess and they just play Chess forever and they don't get tired of it.
Scott: people who play counter-strike forever.
Rym: If that's you still existed that would have been me.
Scott: but the vast majority of people I believe at least it's.
Scott: I think it's clear It's the majority of people Are not like that and they need novelty.
Scott: They need things to get changed and mixed up.
Scott: That's why you know magic needs like expansions and they rotate cards out and they keep shaking things up all the time.
Scott: You know character, you know changing things just for the sake of changing so you don't get bored and go to sleep.
Scott: And and you're you know, you're done with it, right?
Scott: So it's a challenge for these games because even if you shake your game up Right frequently and I think actually none of them shake things up frequently enough I see no reason to not shake your game or die does?
Scott: no I see no reason not to shake your game up daily.
Rym: Uh for died will sometimes just be like, oh we should.
Rym: Why then you then there?
Rym: no meta can evolve.
Scott: why do you need one?
Scott: You're not a competitive game.
Scott: You just got to keep interest.
Scott: but the point is no amount of changing of your games.
Scott: meta can compete with brand new game Right.
Rym: It's like but it's like.
Scott: it's like oh they mod it.
Scott: There's a new patch out for this game.
Scott: There's some novelty there.
Scott: Oh, this is a completely different game.
Scott: That is a hundred percent novel and new in every way shape and actually this gets back to the And then they play it every game until they're done with it and so on.
Rym: so look at most of the people are at like A pax playing board games.
Rym: They pretty much always play the newest board games like once and then they move on like they want to play new games every time They play a game, but then there's people like us where all right.
Rym: I've learned this game.
Rym: now I want to play it ten times in a row.
Scott: But with the thing is with an online game you need It's.
Scott: you can keep the game going as long as the community is above this critical count And as soon as I mean our counter-strike has been above that count for as long as it's existed.
Scott: Well, they kept mixing up and releasing new counter-strike barely.
Rym: Yeah, I mean go.
Rym: it counters like go is not had substantial updates.
Rym: Yeah, I'm saying they added.
Rym: they added that Basically fortnight clone into it that sucked anyway, we played it a little bit.
Rym: It was bad.
Scott: I thought that that was a PUBG clone.
Rym: I mean they're all cloning the same thing.
Rym: It's just they added a battle royale anyway.
Rym: I feel like the industry is finally realizing that you can't just turn every game into a battle royale.
Rym: I'll just let fortnight and PUBG have that space and do something different anyway.
Rym: So in some news if you didn't notice isn't this meta?
Scott: this is news.
Rym: okay PAX West badges and hotels went on sale and Liberty weekend 2019. obviously yep Badges are all available except Saturday sold out within like 30 seconds.
Rym: now you might say wasn't 30 seconds.
Rym: well Here's the thing you might say no Rym it took 10 minutes, but here's the problem.
Scott: What does it say on the spreadsheet?
Rym: I didn't check the spreadsheet for this time.
Rym: But here's the problem.
Rym: The time to sell out is not the time to sell out.
Rym: that is published when the last badge is sold and this turns to Sold out.
Rym: the time to sold out is when the last person enters the queue who will buy the last Saturday badge.
Rym: Mmm Debatable because say the queue fills with the people who will buy all the badges within a minute and then Ten minutes later that queue gets to the last person who buys the last Saturday badge.
Rym: if you logged in nine minutes After the announcement you could not buy a badge.
Rym: Maybe that's the problem, but more interestingly Saturday's sold out of course and the four days are sold out.
Rym: of course.
Rym: Sunday is running low Mm-hmm like Sunday's run low first.
Scott: Sunday is a day, which is Not Monday's a holiday right, but it's still Monday.
Rym: It's a short day and Friday is also the first day.
Rym: so I am a shorter.
Scott: day is a Friday's not shorter.
Rym: It's sorry if people feel like it starts a little later.
Rym: doesn't ramp up right away Not shorter in any way.
Scott: It's just on a day where people are at work.
Scott: It is a vacation day.
Scott: Yeah, Sunday is because four days now Sunday and Saturday are basically equivalent.
Scott: They are both full days of packs.
Scott: Yes at PAX West at least there is no difference between Saturday and Sunday.
Scott: I guess Saturday is just like the more free day than Sunday and just society.
Scott: yeah But they're both complete 100% full.
Scott: don't have to work Full packs hours, so if you are a local person who's planning to go to packs for only one day And not a whole weekend you would only go Saturday or only go Sunday,
Rym: so it's interesting though Is that I got into the queue basically instantly yep?
Rym: All the hotels were already sold out.
Scott: well You know exhibitors staff all kinds of other people get them hotels first.
Rym: yeah But they were already sold out to a degree that I've never seen before.
Scott: for PAX West well There's a new thing that's being built.
Scott: is it ready yet.
Rym: No it didn't look like it.
Scott: There's some digging going on.
Rym: we were there last year But the other thing that's interesting about that is that the hotel registration system was way different and made you put in Contact info like email addresses and names for every person For the past few packs.
Rym: is I guess I haven't booked.
Rym: it wasn't for what packs?
Rym: was it where I didn't have to do that?
Scott: I did it for the past packs or two.
Rym: I think for PAX East the previous PAX East I did not have to do that.
Scott: I definitely did.
Rym: I could do it But it did not require me.
Scott: I definitely did it for East and South this year.
Rym: Yeah, but I remember the previous ease.
Rym: it didn't force me to put in emails for every person.
Rym: It was just an option so they could check in on their own if they wanted to anyway.
Rym: but It looks like I Suspect what they're gonna do because they also have a bunch of notes about how you gotta have the right names in by July 15th.
Rym: because I think if the same email is in multiple rooms one of those rooms getting cancelled By packs because the hotel sell out so fast.
Rym: so we'll see how that all goes.
Scott: Well, we got two different rooms booked with similar.
Rym: We're gonna have to drop one of them in the next week or two.
Rym: let's decide if we want the Hyatt or the share.
Rym: it's cheaper and The Hyatt's cheaper cuz the Hyatt ain't cheap.
Scott: Oh, no wait the Sheraton's cheaper.
Rym: I forget I don't know how we got that Sheraton.
Scott: Well someone posted online.
Scott: It was like Sheraton's open.
Scott: so I'm like oh, okay Yeah, it seems like we both had Hyatt's and I switched from Hyatt to Sheraton.
Rym: Yep It seems like part of what happened was that there were a lot of rooms available but the rooms were all two people only and Did not cover Monday for some.
Scott: apparently though if you you could People were saying that if you booked and they didn't have all the days you needed you could then email them to get the extra Days.
Rym: what weird?
Rym: Anyway, I feel like room blocks.
Rym: Just the whole idea of room blocks for conventions has broken now that demand has far exceeded supply anyway.
Rym: So, uh in other news magfest announced their dates.
Rym: now you can't book hotel.
Scott: Yep, it's exactly what everyone would be right after fucking New Year's.
Rym: Yep So you can go to magfest.
Rym: but remember magfest is a weird thing.
Scott: Sorry super magfest.
Rym: Yeah, magfest does a complicated thing where you have to pre-register for badges first and then there's a thing to get hotels.
Rym: So if you're a magfest type of person Just watch the magfest website because as you know The hotel for magfest sells out faster than packs and magfest sucks if you don't stay right next to magfest.
Rym: Yep So we got some other news that's fun about fortnight, right?
Scott: So, you know we talk I bring up this point a lot about how the penalties for cheating need to be severe enough.
Scott: And my favorite thing to always say is how many Tour de France's did Lance Armstrong the cheater win?
Scott: Zero, right because the penalty was severe.
Scott: The penalty was you cheated.
Scott: Therefore you did not win.
Rym: I mean look at the old days and cotton right in college all shit like punk buster.
Rym: on their pcs They would install third-party Executables didn't know their origin.
Rym: that ostensibly would prevent people from cheating, right?
Scott: So in contrast, I always offer the example of.
Scott: you know The New England Patriots who supposedly probably cheated in various ways over the years But the penalties for those cheats were lost draft picks fine Suspensions from certain number of games but none of their Super Bowls were evoked.
Scott: and in fact during years in which they suffered Penalties they still won the Super Bowl.
Scott: Therefore they effectively just paid to win.
Scott: It's like sit out two games and gain an advantage.
Scott: to win right.
Scott: pay this fine and we'll let you have an advantage.
Scott: It's like right.
Scott: Yeah, it's just by.
Rym: if you really want to punch this guy in the face You're gonna sit in a box for between two and five minutes difference between.
Scott: you inflated the football you deflated the footballs.
Scott: therefore you must pay X dollars and Pay X dollars and we'll let you deflate the footballs.
Scott: There is no difference.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So here we have a case of this exact same thing happening in competitive fortnight except and Ronaldo, right?
Scott: to apparently very good fortnight players.
Scott: Were found cheating during qualifiers of basically the biggest fortnight tournament Apparently where the prize was just like some enormous amount of money or the prize pool was just huge.
Scott: They were cheating.
Scott: They were caught cheating.
Scott: They were definitely cheating and they were punished for cheating.
Scott: their punishment was that they were banned for I think like two weeks.
Scott: Like you can't play any fortnight.
Scott: for two weeks competitively You're out now.
Rym: the manner of their cheating was they were Getting friends to basically join games with them and feed them so they could get whatever they needed to get to qualify faster and easier right?
Scott: So they were banned for two weeks and after the two weeks are up they came back in and qualified.
Scott: Yeah, and it's like.
Scott: I think your penalty was not severe enough.
Scott: Also, I assume they didn't cheat when they qua.
Scott: so it's sort of debatable on this right because on the one hand the they supposedly Did not cheat when they came back from being suspended.
Scott: So they are really good.
Scott: Why were they cheating in the first place?
Rym: probably out of laziness right out of laziness is right.
Rym: Watch does these seasons for every season?
Rym: I got to do my 10 ranking matches to fit qualify before I can play again and I would gladly skip those.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I wish they didn't even do that.
Scott: I really really need to.
Scott: we need ranking systems that don't have grinding components.
Rym: But anyway, you hearthstone.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Anyway, the point is they They supposedly qualified without cheating, right?
Scott: Supposedly.
Scott: I don't know they are good, right?
Scott: They're good enough to qualify.
Scott: So Should they be in because they qualified legitimately or Should they be not allowed in and the penalty was not severe enough because they're cheating cheaters and we shouldn't have them around here And that that delegitimizes the whole competition to have such scoundrelous players involved scoundrelous.
Rym: Yes So I got two opposing views on that.
Rym: on one hand That kind of cheating and the message it sends for this light punishment hurts the community and the way to keep the community active engaged and feeling like the game is fair would be to When a pro is caught doing something like that.
Rym: They're just banned from professional life.
Rym: Yes, full stop agree on the other side for tonight isn't really a competitive game anyway.
Rym: also agree.
Rym: So it doesn't actually matter like who cares.
Scott: So I feel like someone cares because how much money is at stake?
Scott: So they get what if a cheating cheater gets a?
Scott: get some of those millions.
Rym: But they didn't cheat in a way that got them into the World Cup.
Scott: I Mean Pete Rose bet on games and was banned from baseball forever, but he didn't cheat to win baseball Necessarily.
Rym: We should Black Sox Fortnite.
Rym: That would be so easy to pull off.
Scott: Oh, you want a Black Sox eSports?
Scott: Yeah, we need someone that will let us bet on eSports though.
Scott: Yeah, and I and the only problem with black Bet on eSports, Australia, I guess If anyone knows a place we can legally bet on eSports, we will then illegally bribe the athletes.
Rym: Here's the important thing.
Rym: It cannot be Illegally betting on eSports because you don't try to Black Sox the mob, right?
Rym: Black Sox is you Getting cement?
Scott: I need to place legal wagers on the sport and then rig the sport by bribing the e-athletes.
Scott: Yeah being like look you might win this thing You might lose this thing.
Scott: if you win you'll get a million.
Scott: if you lose you'll get what.
Scott: 10,000 is the bottom of the prize.
Scott: 50,000 will give you a hundred thousand no matter what because we're gonna bet for you this to happen.
Scott: you make it happen.
Rym: Now the thing I do and I like about this at least like kind of an aside Is that the World Cup of Fortnite is at least doing things right in that they're doing it like golf.
Rym: There is a minimum prize for the last.
Scott: I think I think the prize pool is large enough that they can do it.
Scott: Yeah, right for tonight just has to make a money.
Rym: but eSports needs things like that to avoid some of the exploitative.
Scott: Yeah, there are a lot of yeah, we can go on and on about.
Scott: we talked about this Leads who don't make enough money to live because the you know, even our pros.
Scott: we talked about when magic changed.
Rym: Yeah sports could learn a lot from golf and tennis.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: So in some other news You may remember a game.
Rym: We never.
Rym: we never talked about it a lot.
Scott: I've even played it.
Scott: I just saw it and heard about it.
Rym: I watch YouTube videos about.
Rym: I watch some videos about it Also, but the best way to experience that game was to listen to Dave and Joel talk about it.
Rym: But the game was called Charles Barkley shut up and jam guy Dan.
Scott: So this this was a basically RPG maker game from like 2008.
Scott: That was just a hilarious joke.
Rym: JRPG Chrono Trigger and Final Fantasy 6 and Shaq food, but in a world where?
Rym: Charles Barkley did the ultimate.
Rym: the chaos dunk.
Rym: Yeah, and it like destroyed a city and it's a Final Fantasy Johnson is like the cop.
Rym: basketball is now banned because it's too dangerous and Magic Johnson is like the basketball cop And like it's.
Rym: it's a fucking experience like watch this game on YouTube.
Rym: We don't play it right, but they did a Kickstarter If you don't play it when I go.
Rym: there was a Kickstarter to make an unofficial Sequel to it.
Scott: was it made by the people made the first one?
Rym: I don't actually know cuz I didn't care that much.
Scott: I do remember seeing I think I remember seeing it at least one gaming event or PAX or something where they had a booth.
Rym: Yeah, PAX Prime 2015. the title of the game was actually the magical realms of Tiernanog escape from the Necron 7 Revenge of Kwok Chulam the official game of the movie chapter 2 of the hoops Barkley saga Okay, otherwise known as Barkley - anyway.
Scott: They kick-started this game.
Scott: How much money did they raise?
Rym: so I thought it was a lot more.
Rym: They only raised 120 grand.
Scott: That's a lot of money, and that is enough money to make an RPG maker game.
Rym: dude 120 grand It's I mean it's not myself 120 grand.
Scott: I could just like take a year off and make more than one game in RPG maker in that time that is these.
Rym: That is an annual salary For two indie developers who do not live in New York City.
Scott: right if I didn't live in New York City I could take probably at least two or three years off and make several JRPG RPG maker games.
Scott: I live the same quality level as Barkley.
Scott: shut up and Jam.
Scott: I would just need the creative talent to write such a masterpiece.
Rym: Yeah a game like this.
Rym: the thing is games like this.
Rym: people seem to keep making this mistake like I feel like that homestuck game At the same problem.
Rym: the game itself does not have to be a good game.
Rym: the game does not have to have good mechanics.
Scott: You're not making a game right a lot.
Scott: This is it.
Scott: This is the thing I make it like monkey island.
Scott: right?
Scott: I always complain that people try to make like.
Scott: you know that they're making a movie.
Scott: They're Hollywood people working in the game industry right you know.
Scott: and they admit that they like started Careers in film or trying going to film school or something.
Scott: and it's like.
Scott: you know they're making a game And they're focusing on the story and the narrative and all this stuff, and that's perfectly fine, right?
Scott: There's plenty of room in the world for software that entertains via story and art and whatever.
Scott: But it's like if you're not if you're just gonna have a cookie cutter game Just like generic FPS generic JRPG just why even put the game in there?
Scott: just admit that you're a software storytelling mechanism Which many games are now doing like monkey island actually like is an example of that kind of thing.
Rym: there were a lot of menu Options and puzzles that were just jokes yep.
Rym: So I feel like Charles Barkley shot up and jam guide and to Barkley - it's just one of those.
Scott: You should have been that yep, and you could have made that yep.
Rym: But I also want to point out that to make a real game $120,000 rounds to Zero dollars to make a triple-a game to make a single-a game is probably 400 grand any number of A's.
Scott: you need more money Than that.
Scott: yeah, you should make.
Scott: you can make an indie game with a couple of people.
Rym: our friend Joe just you know tweeted a perfect tweet to point out that she wrote and shipped like six games than the time that this Kickstarter game was in development.
Scott: oh Just saying so oh that's the story.
Scott: is that?
Rym: so yeah the story is this is failed.
Scott: How is it?
Scott: it's just they're not gonna make it.
Rym: as far as I can tell the team like fell apart.
Scott: It's gonna give the money back.
Rym: No of course not.
Rym: it's Kickstarter.
Rym: You don't give the money back.
Rym: Okay, the whole point of Kickstarter is that you don't get your money back.
Rym: Oh, that is like the basis of Kickstarter, so how many Kickstarters am I making tomorrow?
Rym: There was that old retro prey for a while was doing a thing where they would look at Kickstarter videos and be like wow This is fake.
Rym: This is clearly a scam.
Scott: So where the scams raising money though?
Rym: Yeah, some bull.
Rym: so they mostly focused on Kickstarters that were obvious scams that just failed to even get the scam money right.
Scott: That's what I figured.
Rym: what happened if I made one, but basically apparently there was a huge team trying to make this game Which is also how do you have a huge team with that amount of money?
Rym: Yeah, unless it's all volunteers.
Rym: But sure what do you use that money for?
Rym: like?
Rym: just buy art assets or something.
Scott: you don't need that any money to make the First one.
Scott: why do you money make the second one?
Rym: that is an interesting question?
Scott: There are a lot of me to buy everyone a copy RPG maker that doesn't cost 120 grand.
Rym: so Kotaku reached out to a lot of the people involved who would not reply.
Rym: The money ran out which is interesting.
Rym: on what hookers and blow according to the Kickstarter upstate?
Rym: Rom one of the guys intends to finish Barkley - Despite his inexperience and only having one part-time coder working on the game with him at the time who made the fucking first one.
Rym: I Feel like the moral is don't kickstart small games like.
Rym: I don't know what to do about this kind of thing.
Scott: I made the first one.
Scott: just make another one an RPG maker just like the first one only different story.
Rym: Yeah, I mean you can read this article to see all the details is this I'm sure there's gonna be a real expose of how this didn't make it.
Rym: But I feel like there's two problems here with this kind of game.
Rym: one Charles Barkley showed up and jam guide n is a lot like the black dynamite Not the blood the black bastard comic.
Rym: the concept itself is funny.
Rym: Nothing else really matters.
Rym: don't even need to execute that well Just like write something funny.
Rym: if you're gonna make a sequel to something like that Double down on it being a joke.
Rym: the best example of that ever is haul the RPG human occupied landfill.
Rym: Yeah, that is an RPG.
Scott: perfect analogy right there.
Rym: Yeah, you kids don't remember haul.
Rym: some always someone's all is pretty obscure in 2019.
Rym: Yeah Hall is an RPG in the sense that it is an RPG book that is intended to be consumed the way most RPG books are.
Rym: you read it cover to cover by yourself.
Rym: you imagine running the game You never actually find a group and you never actually play the game even once.
Rym: that's right.
Rym: the hall was just that experience Designed to be that experience.
Rym: I would be shocked if anyone actually played hall people have played.
Scott: ha I wouldn't be shocked Yeah, but I would be.
Rym: I would be a little shocked.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: Have you ever actually read?
Rym: ha ha I read.
Scott: I've read some pages.
Rym: It's it's a pretty long time ago.
Rym: Yeah, I read haul I read that book in God Before I got to 1990. something yeah but anyway, it's time for Things of the day.
Rym: So speaking of scams and games and all that when I was a kid There were real Nintendo games, and then there were clearly not real Nintendo games the action 52 kind of.
Scott: everyone could tell that there.
Scott: even little kids knew there was something up when there was real Tetris and Tangen Tetris like I remember as a kids very specifically the micro machines NES game.
Rym: That was the most fake, but I remember being shocked by it because I rented it to see Because I it was a bootleg game, and I knew it was a bootleg game, but it was actually a really good game.
Rym: It's like the only one Tangen Tetris and micro machine Tetris was.
Scott: I mean it was an okay Tetris, but it still wasn't as good as NES Tetris.
Rym: No, it was not as good as NES Tetris, but uh I remember vaguely like seeing this thing.
Rym: But as a kid I saw like I saw so clearly even as a young child that this was just a fake-ass scam To trick parents.
Rym: It's something called the Aladdin deck enhancer.
Rym: It is game genie adjacent For more reason.
Scott: I remember maybe seeing an ad for it in a video game magazine, but that's about it.
Scott: What did it do?
Rym: so basically the idea was?
Rym: Nintendo games are expensive like Zelda 2 was 70 bucks when it came out sure like 70 bucks in 90s dollars.
Rym: So the idea was they would make a cartridge that you'd stick into the Nintendo Mm-hmm, and it had all the common components of the cartridge.
Rym: So every to NES cartridge had all these common components.
Rym: And then you'd stick other mini cartridges into this cartridge and add full games on them.
Rym: But they were cheaper to physically manufacture.
Scott: So it was just basically just ROM chip.
Scott: They just physically separated the ROM chips from the rest of the cartridge So that you could just buy ROM chips and swap them in and out and those have cheaper games.
Rym: So the pitch was buy this thing for like 40 bucks.
Rym: But then all the games you buy for it will play in your Nintendo and those games are between 15 and 20 dollars Instead of the 60 70 dollar first party NES games.
Scott: You know that really makes you think it's like the NES could have included some chips Just fucking in the NES and the less in the cartridge.
Scott: yes But then the NES would have been on extra hundred dollars and the cartridges would have been more importantly.
Rym: Then the NES would have probably been more like the Atari 7800 for technical reasons.
Rym: Yeah, anyway, so this is a like pretty thorough history of this fucking thing.
Rym: But the TLDR version is that won all the games for it sucked ass.
Rym: Oh, yeah, they got a hundred percent.
Scott: But that's the biggest problem.
Rym: There were a lot of games like this.
Rym: They were the games that like Relatives would buy as gifts like your weird uncle would buy it for you as a gift because it was cheaper than the real NES games like they were aimed at adults who didn't know better, which is a Demographic that has mostly disappeared.
Rym: now that kids just buy their own games directly Like you don't see the fake games except at very very very young kids these days.
Rym: But in the 90s fake-ass games like this were a big part of the industry.
Rym: but the Aladdin deck enhancer was particularly notable because it came out as The Super Nintendo was coming out.
Rym: so it couldn't even Fulfill that basic purpose of tricking parents because it was already like mega.
Scott: Absolutely have done the same concept for the Super Nintendo.
Rym: That would have been a lot harder.
Scott: I'm sure it would have but a bit possible.
Scott: Yeah, those games look awful.
Rym: Oh, they are.
Rym: the scary thing is apparently these dizzy games Not really worse than like the average NES game.
Scott: I mean that's.
Rym: but all the other games on this platform are the worst.
Rym: this Robin Hood game.
Rym: Holy these are like action 52 territory.
Rym: Okay, so what do you got?
Scott: What do I have?
Scott: I forget?
Scott: Oh, yeah, so here's a video of a bunch of people On a people mover being moved and they are singing a song.
Scott: The song they're singing is to the tune of there's no limit.
Rym: No, no One of my favorite DDR songs.
Scott: Yes But they're.
Scott: they have changed all the lyrics to be to Something to it, right?
Scott: It is clearly in a. It is in a non English language.
Scott: I'm sure if we read the comments.
Scott: you could you know under this video You could understand what's happening here.
Scott: But basically they're all dressed as elves of some kind with pointy hats overall.
Scott: They're red green blue and yellow with white shirts underneath and they're drunk.
Scott: They're either drunk or acting like they're drunk, but they're not too drunk Right.
Scott: So basically the story is is that they are I believe soccer fans And I mean that tracks.
Scott: Yes that it makes sense.
Scott: I think they're on their way to a game at the airport or something like that.
Scott: and Oh, by the way, there's a snow white at the end.
Rym: The first comment on this video is a plus.
Rym: never saw this version of snow white and the hundred dwarves.
Rym: Yeah under it pornhub has and then nasty hobbits.
Scott: So basically, the deal is these two brothers who play soccer and their last name is today and And Basically, they played together and people created this chant and would sing this chant right when they're right when they're out there And I think the chant sort of lasted longer than the brothers.
Rym: possibly I feel like the chant is entering the same channel as well.
Scott: the chant outlived Those two people who had the name and became a thing of its own.
Rym: Well, like Potvin sucks Exactly largely.
Scott: This is a pot van sucks of The soccer team.
Rym: props to these for them for the to this flash mob for being so organized like it as they are.
Scott: incredibly it's a thing of the day because of the level of What's it called.
Rym: watch it Coordination watch it all the way to the end because it is slid escalates in a linear fashion, right?
Scott: They're so coordinated in their effort and also like so over the top like they put way more into this than Anyone should.
Rym: yeah, like take the most elaborate like cosplay Nonsense crap you've seen at an anime con.
Rym: This is way more organized than that.
Scott: Yeah, I've never seen it.
Scott: You know, I've seen cosplay groups at anime cons.
Scott: do stuff never like.
Scott: that's a hundred dwarves.
Rym: right in the moment the GeekNights book club book was pages of pain.
Scott: I have Consumed all of the painful pages.
Scott: There are no painful pages left in my future.
Rym: and the one thing that I remembered about this book that Surprised me was that I remembered.
Rym: Oh, they meet the demon and then it's over.
Rym: pretty much it actually goes on.
Scott: There's a lot more after they meet car for they made the demon about 75 60 something percent of the way 65 75 percent way through.
Rym: I remembered as a kid that like the book ends pretty quick after that.
Rym: but what really happens is the pace of the shit going on just Accelerates and gets more and more Disturbing anyway, but the other thing that I remembered that I've remembered accurately like very accurately was the Ridiculous abruptness with which the situation resolves.
Rym: It is just like we're going to go to go to go to go to go to go and pop.
Rym: You're done pretty much.
Rym: Good job Good luck.
Rym: Have fun with the rest of your fucking life Those of you who may have survived.
Rym: So we'll be talking about this on the next Thursday's show.
Rym: I'll talk about the book club.
Rym: So if you haven't read it read it because we are not going to explain the plot of this book to you.
Rym: We're going to react to it assuming you have read enough.
Scott: I can't explain the plot of this book to you.
Rym: I All I will say is that I feel like I can read a lot into it But I don't know if Troy Denning intended all of that.
Rym: I can I can weave a narrative but like with ikuhara and Gio Saito with utenna like it's clear They intended these things to be read with this.
Rym: I feel like if I try to read it too deeply.
Rym: I am putting way more Craft into this book than it has anyway, but we read it.
Rym: It is the first and probably last Officially canon Dungeons & Dragons licensed novel.
Scott: should I pick it?
Scott: There's a lot of officially canon licensed novels at the at the bookstore I could.
Scott: this is like battle tech and x-men Battle tech book.
Scott: halo has books.
Rym: I mean you can do one cuz I may have a whole pile of netrunner license books.
Rym: Oh god I mean I made you read this.
Rym: so I guess I can't complain if you made me read like the netrunner book.
Scott: But I don't know.
Scott: I haven't read any books.
Scott: Just have them because they were like a dollar.
Rym: like one thing I know is that if you that's the only reason I have them if you make me read one of those books I will take solace in the fact that you two have to read it.
Scott: I Own it.
Rym: I know I know what my next books gonna be.
Rym: Okay, I'm gonna go in a completely different direction all right like way different direction.
Rym: sure It's a book.
Rym: I doubt you've read to.
Rym: probably actually it's one of two books.
Scott: I haven't read most books.
Rym: I too have not read most books.
Rym: I Why almost started.
Rym: what was I?
Rym: I was skimming through a bunch of novels and stuff, and I flipped through a one of the earlier prince of nothing books because I wanted to find a quote and I had this urge to just read the darkness that came before again.
Rym: Go ahead.
Rym: I gotta I gotta avoid that.
Rym: So anyway, let's get into it.
Rym: risk of rain was a game that I played it like twice at go Joe's house.
Scott: I played this game when it came out on my PC solo for a few days, and then I forgot about it.
Rym: Yep, and then we tried.
Rym: we played it a bunch.
Scott: I played it quite a bit because when we opened it up just yesterday I had like four of the whatever number of characters unlocked and stuff.
Rym: yep I had nothing unlocked despite the fact that I own this game, and it said I played it for like an hours.
Scott: I don't know was yeah I didn't actually look at steam to see how many hours I played it But I did play it quite a bit for a short period of time Maybe a week or maybe two weeks at most and then that was it.
Scott: so risk of rain one was an indie game That was made very cheaply by a couple of people and the concept of the game at the time was basically Sort of it was one of the earlier games to combine roguelike nature with other genres And so it's a plat.
Scott: It's a shooter platform roguelike imagine sort of like Contra right, but the controls are nothing like Contra.
Scott: It's still a platform where you have guns and shoot things.
Scott: you also have four different abilities sort of like a moba Right bound to four buttons in a row.
Scott: I think the four abilities of the main guy are like yeah regular gun roll Rapid fire gun and armor piercing like single shot.
Scott: Yeah, and single shot That's like powerful right or something like that.
Scott: stuns a little bit.
Scott: Maybe I don't know.
Scott: yep And you could jump and stuff like that.
Rym: It's got like a really floaty feel like little guys.
Scott: Big problem with the game is that everything is really really tiny which I like in Theory, but in practice right.
Scott: so I think I read about it, and it was.
Scott: it was done intentionally obviously Yeah Because they wanted to make the to feel you know story-wise like you don't belong on this world.
Scott: You're some human who landed here or human ish thing.
Scott: I guess that landed here.
Scott: You don't belong here.
Scott: everything here is enormous.
Scott: You're tiny right and they couldn't really.
Scott: they didn't have the money or the art Assets or anything in the first game to actually make big stuff like say shadow of the colossus.
Scott: So they just made you really small yeah to get that feel and they succeeded in getting that feel.
Scott: they made the game very inaccessible And difficult to play.
Scott: People who can't don't have amazing vision cannot play.
Scott: risk of rain one.
Scott: It's just impossible.
Rym: You know I played it at why I tried it at work.
Scott: several articles online about people like I risk of rain one is unplayable.
Scott: I can't see yep now.
Rym: I had no problem with it, and I played it in Vision.
Scott: I could play.
Rym: I played it in 1x scaling on a 4k monitor.
Rym: that shit is like 1 millimeter tall Right and that was fine right.
Scott: so basically.
Scott: It's a platforming game.
Scott: you shoot guys.
Scott: Everything has health like HP.
Scott: So you don't just shoot a guy and they die like say contra.
Scott: yeah, you sort of have to like whittle the eyes down.
Scott: It's more like.
Rym: it's more like Borderlands in that regard.
Scott: Yeah, exactly right where you sort of you know remove your stats matter a little.
Scott: also in addition to your skills mattering.
Rym: Yeah, you can get items.
Rym: They're all kind of random.
Rym: They all do kind of random stuff yep, but it's roguelike.
Scott: So the way it works is obviously once you die It's game over you to start over.
Scott: in the beginning You spawn in a level.
Scott: you can go up and down and left and right and all over it.
Scott: It's not directional.
Scott: you explore the level sort of Metroid II, but it's not a maze.
Scott: It's just like a big open space with platforms and things you have to get over and things like that And you're looking for the teleporter.
Scott: when you find the teleporter you activate it and as long as you stay close enough to the teleporter It's sort of like you know Builds up to 100%.
Scott: after you activate it once it hits 100% You're sort of good, and you can leave the level.
Scott: you also have to kill all the enemies that are that are left, right?
Scott: It'll be like oh, there's five enemies left.
Scott: You can't exit a level and you get you get to fight like a kind of a boss thing And before you activate the teleporter enemies are basically constantly spawning all the time.
Scott: They actually don't stop spawning until that teleporter hits 100% all right.
Rym: now There's a very important like that And I think this is sort of a point where we'll talk about.
Rym: with both this and risk of rain, too.
Rym: There's a lot of unique or like very interesting mechanics.
Rym: Oh, yeah, but They don't really gel together into a fun game and risk of rain one.
Rym: but this one mechanic is that the monsters keep spawning and there's difficulty level as Time goes on.
Rym: you just see this meter and the difficulty just slowly getting higher.
Scott: the difficulty is always increasing with time.
Scott: If you just stand still the game gets harder and harder and harder and harder.
Scott: So you have this time pressure?
Scott: That's saying go go go find that teleporter hit it and get to the next level.
Scott: while the game is still easy You will get further in the game.
Scott: that way if you sit around because it is a stateful roguelike.
Scott: if you sit around collecting money Collecting items powering yourself up getting all sorts of drones to help you out Which are really fun because you don't have to deal with them They just either shoot for you getting really powerful stuff.
Scott: the more you sit around The harder the game will be to match your grinding.
Scott: so you have to sort of.
Scott: it's not you know It's sort of grinding.
Scott: But if you're gonna like go out of your way to not look for the teleporter and say collect a bunch of loot and money You better be collecting loot and money at a rate greater than the difficulty of the game is getting higher.
Scott: Right, you need to sort of outpace the difficulty meter with your pat with how much you power yourself up so that the game remains Easy.
Scott: because even if the game gets like middle medium or hard difficulty if you manage to collect enough powerful shit The game will still be basically easy for you.
Scott: Yeah But if you rush through the game super fast Okay, great.
Scott: You got to level three, and you're still only on medium difficulty, but you didn't stop to collect any stuff.
Scott: It's now the game actually is medium difficulty Yeah, and once it gets the hard you're just gonna die right because you didn't get enough stuff.
Scott: You're weak You don't have your goods now.
Rym: I'm not gonna lie like.
Rym: the game is clever and has a lot of really good stuff going for it.
Scott: Yeah, it was.
Rym: I remember it actually find it fun.
Scott: I remember it being way fun when I played originally But playing it now it was less fun than I remember it being.
Rym: yeah like the the accessibility problem did not affect us at all.
Rym: it's more just The combat is not actually that interesting because the a lot of it is a lot of really random and they're kind of random Crap, it's mostly passive upgrades.
Rym: like there are some cases where you choose a lot of stores where it's like choose one of these three Items yeah, but like most of the powers is you do more damage in some like vague capacity.
Rym: They don't really give you more options.
Scott: some of them give you interesting different ways to handle different enemies.
Rym: I think I got was cool.
Scott: Yes, some items might make it easier to deal with flying enemies.
Scott: some items I make it easy to do with ground enemies.
Scott: Right you might fight in a different way as if you choose a different character.
Scott: Then you definitely play in a drastically different way, but you start with nothing unlocked.
Rym: so when I started playing the game again I only have one dude unlocked.
Rym: so the game wasn't actually like.
Scott: there was a cut sort of like FTL unlock in different ships.
Rym: Use everything immediately right.
Scott: when you use a different ship in FTL you play the game differently.
Scott: yep, right Right if you're the rock boys you play the game a lot differently than if you're human.
Rym: I do not have time to wait for a game to to Immediately dole out like oh the fears the fun part of the game But when you play with different characters and risk of rain.
Rym: you play the game differently because their abilities are so different But I would argue not differently enough Because the Combat just comes down to DPS and the monster is just sort of swarm Depends on which level you're in.
Scott: It feels very samey in a hurry.
Scott: Oh, you know also one of the core things about this game that puts it a separate from the other ones is the co-op action.
Scott: Right you can do local or online and multiplayer Co-op where you and all your friends are all rogueliking together Plus you all spawned at the same time.
Scott: if someone dies they're dead permanently.
Scott: oh the rest of you keep going.
Scott: you can sort of share your gold and your items to some extent and You know and there are.
Scott: imagine you can play net hack where someone else is in there with you.
Scott: That'd be great.
Scott: I'm sure there are roguelikes like that, but I haven't played them.
Rym: But I guess in the end like the best thing I can say about it Is there's a lot of good ideas and an okay execution, and it's a good like proof of concept.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, it was definitely.
Scott: you know it was big and for a reason right.
Scott: you know I mean it's bigger than it was was worth right it out.
Scott: it outperformed its develop.
Scott: You know its development right now.
Rym: notably it was developed by hopu games But it was published by of all people chucklefish mm-hmm the same company that did.
Rym: they were a publisher But and they I guess they still are a publisher, but they also they independently developed wargroove, okay?
Scott: Indie games going on.
Scott: yeah anyway, so risk of rain.
Scott: 2 is currently in early access But it's not one of those early access situations where it's like oh, it's so early.
Scott: It's like you're playing some alpha garbage game.
Scott: It's like no it's like when minecraft was beta and everyone was playing it, and it's like yeah Yeah, it's out if they're just calling it beta.
Scott: It's like Gmail was beta.
Scott: right it's one of those situations And it's basically like.
Rym: it's kind of shocking when you play it like you look at some menus And you realize it's the exact same game, but in 3ds.
Scott: Yes Yeah, it's like it's when I usually when I see a sequel to a game take a massive turn like that.
Scott: It's sort of like hey You're going in a weird direction sort of like Nidhogg.
Scott: yeah Yeah, Nidhogg you see Nidhogg 2 and you're like oh, man I just wanted more Nidhogg 1 and you're going to this other direction.
Scott: god damn it right.
Scott: But risk of rain 2 they it's basically risk of rain.
Scott: 1 is now risk of rain 2.
Scott: It's just the same game third-person shooter.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: That's it.
Rym: otherwise It's almost exactly the same game which weird is how much of a same game It is like.
Rym: it feels very similar.
Scott: There's the same.
Scott: you know you.
Scott: you get money by shooting guys guys spawn all over the place.
Scott: You're searching for the teleporter a giant boss spawn.
Rym: It's the same monsters with the same attacks just in three dimensions.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: it's like this jellyfish and risk of rain 1.
Scott: Oh look his jellyfish in 3d coming at you, right?
Scott: They made the same exact goddamn game the same four abilities for the main character, it's like wow it's Literally, it's you know you think I'll.
Scott: Mario 64 is just Mario in 3d.
Scott: not really it's different in a lot of ways, right?
Scott: It's like this is the same goddamn game and notably they moved on.
Rym: Gearbox published this instead of Chucklefish.
Scott: Oh, yeah, okay?
Rym: Yeah, it's gonna officially come out in spring of 2020 so next year.
Rym: the only problem with it is that playing it a bunch I Feel the same things I felt playing risk of rain one, but so interesting.
Rym: This is a tech demo.
Rym: It's not.
Rym: it's fun, but it's not that fun.
Scott: I think the main problem with it is That the the core mechanic is fun right.
Scott: It's like playing a roguelike shooting.
Scott: getting stronger Balancing speed versus getting power-ups and money.
Scott: all that stuff is great.
Scott: the thing is is that the actual Abilities and weapons and the actual combat of the game not that fun It's not.
Scott: actually all I do is point towards enemies and hold the thing down.
Rym: It just don't even matter.
Scott: watch their health meter go down and hope that it goes down faster.
Rym: It's just in that regard.
Rym: It's just where's Borderlands right?
Scott: It's like the actual running around jumping and shooting action part of the game Is not exciting or fun.
Scott: It's just sort of like it feels very save me.
Rym: I'm holding down the mouse button and running while hoping guys die fast enough like the monsters all kind of swarm you in this generic way like their behaviors aren't that interesting and Half the game was wait.
Rym: What is damaging me?
Scott: Yep?
Scott: Wait?
Rym: What's damaging me now?
Scott: Like it it's like if you get engaging.
Scott: when you're engaging say one enemy at a time They have some behaviors that it's like.
Scott: okay that guy shoots a red laser, so I have to dodge at this exact moment.
Scott: Okay That bad guy like makes a sphere and if you get stuck in it if you don't run out of the sphere quickly enough you Get frozen, but then like there's 30 flying skulls individually the enemies are interesting But this just eventually a giant mob of enemies everywhere.
Scott: So it's like you can't engage You know in with that interesting mechanic of a single enemy because just you're taking damage from all over the fuck.
Scott: Yeah, run run run run run.
Rym: Just kite and shoot.
Rym: That's the whole game kite and shoot.
Scott: aim at the closest enemy while holding using your abilities waiting for them to refresh using them again immediately as soon as they refresh and Hoping that enough guys die and you live until the boss is dead and the teleporter lets you go to the next level.
Scott: Yeah Repeat it again.
Scott: Use all your money on all the shops as much as you can to get stuff and the environment on your way to find the teleporter.
Rym: But that like the loop of gameplay is the same.
Rym: every level is just wander around you find the teleporter There is no rhyme or reason to like where you might find the teleporter and there is nothing interesting.
Scott: Yeah, the levels are some sort of mix between Handcrafted and procedurally generated.
Scott: they're boring.
Scott: Yeah, there's not much going on.
Scott: It's just like, okay It's some sort of you know ruined.
Scott: Let me run in a spiral until I find the teleporter some stuff on it And I'm just kind of running around and moving as fast as I can looking for the.
Scott: you know, yeah It's like you walk slow.
Scott: There's a run fast button for sprinting.
Scott: I'm just sprinting all the time and it's not fast enough either.
Scott: No, I mean, I guess it would be too easy if it was fast because you'd find the teleporter right away, right?
Rym: But the only thing that was actually in.
Rym: the bosses were pretty interesting at first like they're.
Rym: they're really.
Scott: you almost wish It's like.
Scott: I know it's sort of the point of the game.
Scott: They're like, okay the boss spawns and there's still guys swarming everywhere.
Scott: But it'd be more interesting.
Scott: just engage the boss alone.
Scott: Yeah, you know, I don't know.
Rym: but as a result Like I'll play it a little more because I want to see like how it evolves because it's still early access and it is still Like buggy is shit.
Rym: There's a lot of like just bugs.
Scott: I'm sure they'll add way more to it.
Rym: You know if they're not like one very specific thing I was trying to bind mouse and keyboard and they have a lot of good stuff like.
Rym: invert mouse is an option.
Rym: No one else needs it, but they added horizontal invert mouse.
Scott: I don't know why you would have horizontal invert mouse as a mag.
Rym: You know what that is?
Rym: You know who wants that?
Rym: Warim warim warim needs horizontal mouse mirroring.
Scott: Yeah, there are other characters like.
Rym: I tried to bind some keys and if certain keys if you bound them to a button Would unbind other unrelated.
Scott: use the default fucking keys and get used to it.
Rym: Whatever it is Well, it's why why not change.
Rym: I I have a mouse with a bunch of buttons.
Rym: I'd like to bind.
Scott: Normal mouse doesn't have too many buttons on it.
Rym: what my mouse says I wanted to bind attack one attack to attack three effect attack for the defaults on the mouse.
Rym: Well, I know they weren't 100% anyway, but all I'm saying is that there are bugs where?
Rym: Random key combinations if you try to bind them would unbind other unrelated key combinations.
Scott: It's still early access.
Scott: send it in.
Scott: Yeah, I'm sure that they'll make a lot, you know, even though it is a very playable game That is not some you know, meet, you know.
Scott: early access nothing game I'm sure over the course of the next year They are going to be patching and adding a lot of content to it.
Scott: There were a bunch of characters in it, but it's not as many as in risk of rain one.
Scott: I'm sure more will be added but I do worry that like I unlocked one character the way that second character worked is Their ability was basically homing shots.
Scott: So he didn't aim really.
Scott: you just needed.
Scott: you just couldn't shoot unless an enemy was on screen And I think it would home in on whatever enemy was like closest to your you know center of looking.
Scott: Yep, at least that's what I could.
Scott: and then there's a special ability was jump in the air aim at the ground And then it would create a column of arrows hitting that spot on the ground.
Scott: You know abilities like that and I want to.
Rym: I like I'd be much more invested if I could try all these different characters without Having to grind and unlock them all Because the default guy pretty boring.
Scott: Yeah default guys way boring.
Scott: All he does is running around to shoot Yep.
Rym: But I guess the thing that worries me the most is that there's nothing interesting to find Anywhere in the levels except more of the goons the teleporter the boss or a huge variety of items Most of which have passive effects like some of your jobs do double damage your DPS.
Rym: Yeah, I think that's.
Scott: the thing is that you you know when I'm if I'm spending collecting money and grinding to collect stuff.
Rym: I wanted to get something awesome.
Scott: I want to get stuff.
Scott: That's interesting stuff, and you know it's like getting.
Scott: It's like one of the things I kept getting was like this banner.
Scott: It's like whenever you level up a banner will spawn where on your location and that banner if you're within its radius will make you Stronger somehow.
Rym: that was pretty cool.
Rym: I kept getting things.
Rym: It's just like you're slightly faster now right.
Rym: There were the wings that let you fly a little bit, and then they didn't work.
Rym: after that they were like Double jump you can get.
Rym: I wanted that more than I wanted life itself.
Scott: I got it You know, but it's like yeah, you do.
Scott: your first shot on an enemy does more damage.
Scott: your shot your shots explode.
Rym: You know most of the items come down to your attacks.
Scott: make enemies bleed.
Scott: The items never chance for crits here.
Rym: items that were fun.
Rym: flying little rock buddy that follows me around Rock buddy was a good one.
Rym: Yeah items that were boring of drones.
Scott: They just fly around and shoot for you.
Rym: But most of the boring items they came down to my main complaints about combat in dungeons and dragons third edition.
Rym: Everything just comes down to a flurry of blows.
Rym: do I do X attacks or do I do?
Rym: X+2 attacks at a -2 like to hit on?
Rym: all?
Rym: the attacks like those are not interesting decisions.
Scott: Yeah, I know it would be.
Scott: I think you know if a similar game that is also a roguelike platformer is dead cells Which I played some recently, but I wasn't good enough to get very far in it because it is very difficult and skill based.
Scott: But in that game there are lots and lots of weapons and equipment to unlock But all of them were unique and different.
Scott: there are freeze and freezing enemies Right stunning enemies moving enemies around Teleporting behind enemies all sorts of crazy different abilities that you know.
Scott: you would basically play the game differently and In risk of rain choosing different characters lets you play the game differently But the weapons don't really at all right.
Scott: the equipment doesn't.
Scott: yeah I found myself in risk of rain one.
Scott: it still had the same problem mostly but a risk of rain one.
Scott: I definitely wanted to equip more and risk of rain - it was just rush the teleporter.
Scott: Yeah, right those didn't feel like there was much incentive to get money and get stuff.
Rym: So I just I don't know if the game in one year's time Would get to the point to where I would play it a lot.
Scott: Yeah, the aesthetic and the.
Scott: you know the.
Scott: the story and atmosphere is kind of cool Yeah, but it's you know you see it all right away like the world.
Scott: the difference is like there Isn't like some terrible secret of space.
Scott: I'm waiting to see.
Scott: I feel like you know you two three levels in.
Scott: I've seen it all.
Rym: yep.
Rym: meanwhile like slay the spire you get a lot of environmental storytelling when you work through that game.
Scott: Oh, yeah, lots, so the world is not rich.
Scott: It's it's sparse.
Rym: It's the difference between fallout 3 and breath of the wild.
Scott: right it's like a big sparse empty space And the only thing that fills it is just a fuck ton of enemies that spawn More more and more rapidly
Rym: and a bunch of art assets that in no way interact with you and do nothing other than
Scott: Exploding pots you can shoot.
Scott: They're just Exploding barrels like in Doom.
Scott: they don't you know.
Scott: as far as I can tell they weren't even useful.
Rym: I couldn't even like get an enemy to be by one because they're like up high on these platforms.
Rym: They weren't on the ground which look like they'd be cool, but I went up there, and there was nothing up there.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know.
Rym: I guess if I were you do not buy risk of rain - at least not for the current price of $20.
Scott: yes Right maybe this is.
Scott: this is the kind of game wait until it comes out for real.
Scott: Maybe when it comes out in a year.
Scott: They will have added so much shit to it.
Scott: That'll be incredible.
Scott: Or be you'll wait a year.
Scott: It'll still be you know somewhat better than its current state.
Scott: But then when there's like a steam sale, and it's like $1 $5.00.
Scott: It'll be like oh, yeah, definitely fine.
Rym: Oh, yep, because the fact that you can just like the co-op just works like they got all right.
Scott: Risk of rain.
Scott: one you have to do some bullshit with your IP addresses risk of rain - is just invite steam friend play totally Works.
Scott: so the co-op aspect really makes this work a lot more a lot better a lot more fun Than if you just play it by yourself.
Scott: Yeah, especially if you mix up your characters you work together a little bit.
Scott: It needs more like with four people.
Rym: you can find the teleporter faster Yeah, but like all the technical aspects like they got everything right.
Rym: usually indie games mess that stuff up.
Rym: Yeah, this game got everything right and has a lot of really fascinating concepts together But they haven't really turned it into a satisfying repeatedly playable game yet.
Scott: I think it's definitely for the kind of player who is interested in mastery and going deep and getting good at it.
Scott: Yeah, right that kind of person is gonna Enjoy it a lot more.
Scott: who doesn't mind doing some you know same things over and over again, but because it's a brainy So who's seeking novelty is not gonna have as much fun, but the fighting is so grindy that I hate to say it.
Rym: I feel like you're but you would be better off playing borderlands 1.
Scott: yeah I feel like this game.
Scott: would you be more fun if they simply did this one thing which is?
Scott: Get rid of enemy health and end damage on weapons.
Scott: right just have All enemies die in like one hit, but have it.
Scott: you know the beginning enemies.
Scott: You just shoot him and they die, but then as the enemies get harder.
Scott: It's like shoot him at the right time Shoot him in the right spot Disable their shield and then shoot him.
Scott: get behind him and shoot him.
Rym: maybe bosses He got a good.
Scott: only shoot that you look only hurt these guys with fire.
Scott: You can only hurt these guys When they're in the air.
Scott: you can only hurt these guys during this time of their cycle.
Scott: Right all that that would make the game way more interesting.
Scott: You know shoot more like gauntlet where there's like a ton of guys and you're hosing down Right and they all die in one hit, but they just you know a mess of guys.
Rym: Yep, big money.
Scott: more like fries more like a shmup where it's like okay?
Scott: I keep getting different weapons But all the weapons are interesting and crazy in different ways a spread shot the big laser That's only in the middle right that kind of stuff.
Scott: Yeah, so Hold off on buying the game, and I'm sure the shmup roguelikes right.
Scott: let's yeah Let's go find one and play that.
Rym: but I'm gonna revisit this game once it comes out for real And it's definitely a game for revisiting.
Rym: I'm gonna keep an eye on it.
Rym: It's not ruled out, but don't spend 20 bucks on it today.
Scott: No unless you'd have to make a podcast.
Rym: yeah This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: be sure to visit our website At frontrowcrew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: remember GeekNights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night
Rym: and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Craig Oliver Allen, Joyce Heineck Hill, Just Like a Dude, Guy, John Toppish, and Link Agee, Jennifer Hitchcock, Chris Midgett, Mike State, Abraham J Band, Scooter Lonely, Roberto Kingsley, Shawn Yeager, Nicholas, Brando, Mr.
Rym: Strong, Strachan, Furtue and Creations, and there may be other secret names you do not even know Sean Harrell, Rory, Rochelle Montano, Superboy, Sailor Vista, Clinton, Walton, Rym from New Zealand, Ryan Perrin, Drew Openliner, Finn, Dreadily, Lily, Tenebrae, Sean Cline, Chris Reimer Thomas Hahn, and now I bring you something from an ancient past And it goes a little something like this I'm fucking ranting here, it's not no muck, it's on With Beam with the master plan, and I'm Babadu with the mic on my hand And we're loads of the rhymes from a far off land, and we'll rock this joint with a hobbit band.
Scott: Mira, Mira on the wall, who's the greatest hobbit of them all?
Scott: Bilbo, Bilbo Baggins is only three feet tall But my name is Gimli, I'm a fucking dwarf, I be slaying motherfuckers from the south to the north.
Scott: That ain't Markwood, I'm dropping with my battle axe, I'm on an orc stampede like Shadowfax.
Scott: Now all you bobbins and bulls is race girdles and proud feet, I'm the skinny hobbit with all the fat beats.
Scott: My name is Marianna, five feet tall, I used to fuck shit up at Brandybuck Hall.
Scott: My man Bilbo's older than Geront's just took, yeah, you can read about it in a big red book.
Scott: Beam on the scene, all the elf girls scream like a tree, that's me, I like to keep it green.
Rym: It's the chronic pipe weed that I'm smoking, and when I get high I spin tails like hokies.
Scott: Well, I'm a hobbit warrior, short and stout, I got the fucking beats.
Rym: that'll turn you out.
Scott: I'll light you up like Longbottom Leaf, 'cause the orcs smoke the swag, but we got the keef.
Rym: We got the keef, we got the keef, we got the keef.
Rym: I'm Quickbeam with the master plan And I'm Babadil with the mic in my hand And we're loads of the rhymes from a far off land And we'll rock this joint with a hobbit band.
Rym: Yo, B, yo, Dil, it's time to get ill.