Rym: It's Monday, April 15th, 2019.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, we are talking about The Humble Bookmark.
Rym: Let's do this.
Rym: So for the last like 10 years.
Scott: That's a long time.
Rym: Every time we do GeekNights, I have to futz a little bit with, well I had to for a long time, futz with both our microphone stands.
Rym: I'd like I'd rearrange everything.
Rym: So a while ago I just got a boom arm for my microphone and I bought the cheapest boom arm that money could buy.
Rym: And it lasted about two months before I just broke.
Rym: So then I bought the third cheapest boom arm that exists.
Rym: And so far it's going fine.
Rym: I feel like it'll last a while.
Rym: But for the last 10 years I have had to, every time we do GeekNights, futz with Scott's microphone stand because it was just falling apart.
Scott: We bought it in the Beacon days.
Rym: Yep, we bought it.
Scott: At a Radio Shack.
Rym: We bought it.
Scott: When Radio Shack was still in business.
Rym: We went to a Radio Shack and we bought two quarter-inch microphones.
Rym: I'm making a quote no emotion here because they were microphones in the barest possible sense.
Rym: We bought two Radio Shack branded microphone stands that were complete pieces of shit.
Scott: They were suitable for karaoke.
Rym: Yeah, at best, maybe.
Scott: I think that's what they were mostly there for was like if you have a karaoke machine you lost a mic or something in order to add one.
Rym: Yep, so when we had Judith on the show the other day I had to get out the other microphone stand that's of the same ilk and set it up and it was even more broken.
Rym: So I finally just I did that.
Rym: I avoided doing the thing that I'll often do.
Rym: Oh, that thing's broken.
Rym: I'll deal with that eventually and then proceed to never deal with it.
Scott: The thing you do is break the thing on purpose when you want to buy a new one.
Rym: Yeah, I really needed to break that shitty microphone stand to have an excuse to spend $12 on a microphone stand.
Scott: You love breaking stuff.
Rym: Yeah, next time when some of your technology breaks, I will remind you.
Scott: When does my stuff break?
Rym: I recall a conversation recently where something of yours broke.
Scott: You mean my monitor that broke?
Rym: Yeah, why did you break your monitor?
Scott: It wasn't an excuse to buy a new one.
Scott: If you notice I just stole one of yours rather than buying a new one.
Scott: If I wanted to buy a new one I could just buy new ones.
Rym: You just broke it to have an excuse to steal my monitor.
Scott: I'm waiting for actually new 4k monitor models to come out, then I'll buy some.
Scott: I will say though in terms of the current models have been around for quite a few years I don't want to get one and then have a new one suddenly come out.
Rym: Yeah, that is why I upgraded every monitor we had at the same time And I just got three of the same 4k Dell.
Scott: As soon as this new 4k monitors I'm gonna be like, "Daddy,
Scott: too.".
Rym: So I thought about someone in the stream was pointing out they're watching GeekNights on the third monitor while they're working on stuff.
Scott: Third monitor, whoa.
Rym: I had a use case for three monitors and my use case was I want, in the old days, two regular monitors side by side and then a third like 4x3 monitor to stick on the wall or something specifically for live streaming GeekNights-y type stuff.
Rym: There is no use for that once you have 4k monitors.
Rym: I have so many pixels here.
Scott: I don't really see people with three monitors very often except for like in financial offices.
Rym: Well when the third monitor is literally just like a status monitor.
Scott: But what I do see, at my work at least, is people who have a laptop and then they have two monitors on the desk and then the laptop becomes monitor three.
Scott: I just have one monitor on the desk and then it becomes two.
Scott: Especially since even though the laptop monitor is small, it's usually better than the desktop monitor because every laptop these days is like ultra tiny DPI.
Rym: Yep, Emily's Surface has a crazy...
Scott: Oh yeah, that's a great monitor.
Rym: That's such a good monitor.
Rym: I could use it as a main monitor if I needed to.
Scott: It's better than the Dell monitor.
Rym: It had more pixels than my old Dell UltraSharp, the 16x10.
Scott: The monitor that's built into a MacBook, a Retina MacBook, or a Surface Pro is like a crazy good monitor.
Scott: But no, the monitor in my laptop is like... This iPad screen right here is actually the best screen I own.
Scott: I own so many screens.
Scott: This is the best one.
Scott: It's like 1330 by...
Rym: like it's this ridiculous resolution.
Rym: Like some windows just won't fit, but holy crap once you have 4k pixels there's enough pixels even in one monitor to like do all the multitasking you want to do.
Rym: I am a big fan of the vertical monitor though.
Scott: I'm not a fan of the vertical monitor.
Scott: Because even people think though the use case for it is like when you're coding.
Scott: Nah, don't use it for that.
Scott: But the thing is when I'm coding I actually want... I do want more height than 16x9.
Scott: But I want to split it down the middle and get Daddy 2, right?
Scott: A vertical monitor is too wide and I can only see one file at a time.
Scott: I want to see two files at a time.
Scott: Basically what I wanted... Thermal and text editor next to each other.
Rym: What I wanted is two 4x3s to have the live stream thing and like the OBS thing.
Rym: And just putting a 4k monitor vertical cover that.
Rym: But yeah, the other notable opening bit because I was giving Scott time because he doesn't have an opening bit.
Rym: Apparently someone busted into my building and stole a bike from the bike room.
Scott: This room?
Scott: This building?
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: How'd they get in?
Rym: They must have snuck past the doorman while he was like doing something.
Scott: I mean I can get in but I mean how did they get in the bike room?
Rym: So the bike room was never locked but you lock your bike in the bike room.
Rym: There's like bike racks in there.
Scott: Someone had a bike in the bike room that was not locked in the room?
Scott: Yup.
Rym: And someone took it.
Scott: However, as far as I can... How did they know it was someone who busted in and not another person living here?
Rym: So here's the interesting thing.
Rym: I guess they have video footage of like it happening and they know it's not someone who lives here.
Rym: But no one like reported their bike was missing and I was talking to some people...
Scott: Maybe someone just left their bike in here.
Rym: So I went around again in the bike room and did an inventory.
Rym: I'm like one of the only people who actually uses this bike room apparently.
Rym: Most of the bikes in this bike room have had flat tires since we moved into this building.
Scott: Yeah it makes sense.
Rym: Even the doorman is pretty sure that most of the bikes in the bike room were owned by people who no longer live here.
Rym: And they're just garbage.
Rym: So I think there are six people who live in this building who actually use their bikes.
Scott: Why don't you just take possession of the other bikes and sell them all?
Scott: Well I was saying you could sell them or you could donate them.
Scott: There's a thing where it's like they... People... It's a place where people... Recycle a bike thing where you people learn how to maintain bikes.
Scott: And then well they also as a side effect...
Rym: You get the bike?
Scott: Well I think sometimes but they put together bikes for people that can't afford bikes.
Scott: They do the similar thing with computers.
Scott: You donate your computers, people learn how to build computers, and then they give computers to people who can't, you know, get a computer.
Rym: Not a bad thing.
Rym: But because of this bike stolen that no one noticed, now they lock the bike room and they won't give anyone a key but the doorman.
Rym: So what that means... So one day I go down, like I try to go down to the basement and all the stairways are locked.
Rym: Like I can't get in.
Rym: Okay.
Rym: So I take the elevator down, bike room's locked.
Rym: So now every time I want to ride my bike I go to the doorman.
Rym: He's got to come downstairs with me in the elevator and unlock the bike room.
Scott: So the building I'm working in now, which I'm not going to be working in too many months, but it is going to be for the summer so I'm going to have to do their shtick.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: I noticed they had a bike room over by the service elevator and it said it was locked.
Scott: And it had a sign on it.
Scott: that said not responsible if you put your bike in here and it gets stolen.
Rym: That's fine.
Rym: I lock my bike even if it's in a bike room.
Scott: Yeah, I guess I'd have to.
Rym: Well, because people...
Scott: I'd much rather take it up the service elevator, put it in our office.
Scott: But I went and asked the doorman in the building and I was like, "Hey, how do I get a key to the bike
Scott: room?".
Scott: And he's like, "Ah, you just go to this, you know, office and talk to the person there and fill out a paper and they'll give you a key,
Scott: right?".
Scott: But then I was like, "Can I just bring my bike in the service elevator and not do
Scott: that?".
Scott: And he's like, "No, that's why I made a bike
Scott: room.".
Scott: And I was like, "Aw, I'd really much rather just bring it to the
Scott: office.".
Rym: At least they have the bike room as opposed to the buildings that just make up a fake fire code.
Scott: Well, I don't know what's in that room.
Scott: I'm going to have to take a look in there, right, before I decide what to do.
Scott: Who knows?
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I've realized that one of the main problems not to turn into bike nights is that generally buildings... Like New York buildings are still really weird about bikes.
Rym: But basically, because of this, I talked to the doorman.
Rym: I was like, "Look, I bike to work every day once it's summer.
Rym: So you're literally going to have to come down and do this between two and four times a day, every single day, until it snows
Rym: again.".
Rym: And he looked at me and he was like, "Oh, goddammit, you're
Rym: right.".
Rym: So my hope, and he is encouraging me in this, is to...
Scott: That you just make keys for residents like you to the bike room.
Scott: Just like the building I'm working in.
Rym: Because so few people in this building actually use their bikes, pretty sure I will be able to convince the super after maybe a couple weeks of me being annoying and using the bike room constantly and causing a problem.
Rym: Because every time I want to get my bike, they have to lock the front door, unmanned the doorman spot, go down into the basement, deal with me, and come back up.
Rym: So I give the over/under his two weeks before the building just says, "Here's your goddamn
Rym: key.".
Rym: That's right.
Rym: So got some tech news?
Scott: Do have some tech news.
Scott: But first, I was just reminded of something that is tech news-ish.
Scott: That due to our discussion.
Scott: So there's a website people know about.
Scott: that is PC part picker.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Rym: I vaguely remember that.
Scott: Where if you want to build a PC, you go to this website and you can pick your parts for your PC and make sure that you don't pick anything that's incompatible.
Scott: You know, they update the collections of parts.
Rym: Oh, someone built... Use a Pelican key.
Rym: They built their PC in a Pelican.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Is that good for...
Rym: I guess you leave the door open when you're at the con.
Scott: Oh, okay.
Scott: Oh, like that.
Scott: That's cool.
Scott: I guess you can't do it when it's closed.
Scott: No.
Scott: So, but yeah, it's a really good website.
Scott: PC part picker, right?
Scott: If you want to build a computer, you might not use it for your actual buying because they do give you, like, affiliate links to buy all the parts at the places where they search for the lowest prices all around.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: But what my thing... It's not my thing of the day.
Scott: It's just a side news.
Scott: is they have... They're putting out a new website.
Scott: You can see the link right there, right in the blog section, down to the right.
Scott: Oh, oh.
Scott: They had... Now they're developing cyclingbuilder.com, where you can build a bicycle part by part and it will make sure you don't build an incompatible bicycle.
Scott: Like, no, those tires won't fit on that frame.
Scott: No, that chain ring doesn't go with that bottom bracket.
Rym: No, you might naively think, how can a bike be harder to build than a PC?
Scott: I can build 100 PCs.
Scott: Building a bike...
Rym: Building a bike today is harder than building a PC was in the late 90s.
Scott: The main problem with building a bike is not that it's so difficult to do.
Scott: It's that you need specialized tools, right?
Scott: You can build a PC with the screwdriver to get, like, the bottom bracket into the bike.
Scott: You need, like, a special bottom bracket, like, pushing tool, right?
Scott: To even get the chain on and off, you need a special tool to, like, pop the pin out of the chain.
Scott: You need all these specialized tools.
Rym: Gonna true your wheel, because it's a brand new wheel.
Rym: I hope you have a wheel truer.
Scott: If you made the wheel, or you could have bought a true wheel.
Rym: Even if you buy a wheel, you usually have to true it.
Scott: Maybe.
Scott: The point is, building a bike is not as easy as building a computer, but many people do it.
Scott: You can buy components and build a bike, just like you can in a computer.
Rym: You know all those accounts, like, cursed rhythm controllers?
Rym: There's gotta be a Twitter account for cursed bikes.
Scott: I'm sure there are.
Scott: But anyway, the point is, this website is still in its infancy.
Scott: It works great, but the selection of parts is very, very low, because they have to enter so many of them by hand.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So it's like, they don't even have all the major, like, you know, different, like, group sets available yet.
Scott: But they're working on it.
Scott: So, over time...
Rym: Now I can figure out what derailleur or cassette I should use, because I wouldn't use this to build a new bike, but I would use it to replace parts on my existing bike.
Scott: I would use it to build a new bike, if I was gonna make a custom bike, but those are a lot of money.
Scott: That's the thing, is like, when you build a computer, you save money.
Scott: When you build a custom bike, you usually don't save money.
Scott: Because you're actually, it's like, when you're building the computer, right, it's like, you're paying this extra fee to someone to, like, combine all the parts, right?
Scott: And it's like, you think, no, you should be saving money, because they're mass producing the same computer, right?
Scott: It's like, no, it doesn't.
Scott: But with a bike, it makes sense, actually.
Scott: It's the correct way of things, where, yeah, you bought the mass-produced bike, not the custom bike, you saved money by not building your own.
Scott: So it's like, it's completely opposite in that sense, money-wise.
Rym: But I've been in the boat with my old mountain bike of, I need a new cassette, and the bike shops weren't super knowledgeable by me.
Scott: Well, the bike shops are knowledgeable here, if you go to the good ones.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Anyway, so that's just the side news.
Scott: My actual news is, New York Times, "Big companies thought insurance covered a cyber attack.
Scott: They may be
Scott: wrong.".
Scott: So here's the deal, big company, right?
Scott: Get hit with a cyber attack.
Rym: Which happens.
Scott: Their computers are just like, it's like a serious cyber attack.
Scott: Their computers don't work.
Scott: They can't email, they can't do shit.
Scott: The whole business comes to a screeching halt.
Scott: They lose a fortune in money, right?
Scott: And they're like, "God damn it, that
Scott: sucks.".
Scott: But that's what you get for not being modern in your ways, right?
Scott: It's just the consequence.
Scott: So they go to their insurance, and they say, "Hey, are you going to pay for all these
Scott: damages?".
Rym: And of course, the insurance says no.
Scott: It's not that the insurance says no.
Scott: That's obvious that the insurance would find any excuse to say no.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: It's the reason they said no.
Scott: Why did the insurance get away with saying no?
Scott: The insurance said no.
Rym: I see it here.
Rym: I hadn't read the article yet, but I see it.
Scott: Because they said that this particular cyber attack wasn't just some, like, rando cyber attack, right?
Scott: That it was a cyber attack by the Russian government and is therefore an act of war and the insurance specifically does not include war.
Scott: If your building gets bombed in a war, insurance doesn't cover that.
Scott: If it starts fire because of an arsonist, it probably is covered.
Rym: Even our homeowner's insurance.
Rym: Like, if New York got attacked by fighter jets, I don't think my homeowner's insurance or my renter's insurance...
Scott: It's not only... It specifically does not...
Rym: Right.
Scott: Acts of war are almost never insured against because otherwise, if a war happens, the insurance company loses all their money because everything is destroyed.
Scott: Basically, they can't be responsible even though an act of war would be rare, right?
Scott: Like, yeah, we'll cover that.
Scott: It's super rare.
Scott: That'll never happen, right?
Scott: That's the kind of things they like to cover.
Scott: Things that never happen.
Scott: The thing is, if it did happen, the insurance company would be on the hook to rebuild society.
Scott: That's why they can't insure war.
Rym: This is extra interesting part.
Rym: Well, you know, it could be like Trigon.
Scott: But here's the case where they're claiming that it's war, even though this isn't the case where it destroyed all of society.
Scott: It only destroyed a few companies.
Rym: This is the case where they're saying it's a war, but it is an undeclared war.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: So it's like you could go to court and say this war wasn't declared.
Scott: It's not part of war.
Scott: If this was war, how come our government isn't warring back?
Rym: Well, I would argue that the Russian government...
Scott: There's so many arguments you could make in court to say it is or is not war.
Rym: I'd argue that the Russian government is engaging in warfare with Western democracies.
Scott: And we're just taking it in the chin.
Scott: We're just letting them... It's like, oh, we're getting bombed every day.
Scott: We're not fighting back.
Rym: My measles news actually comes back to this.
Scott: We're not fighting back very effectively.
Rym: There's a lot of evidence that Russian bots are the main promoters of anti-vax.
Scott: Anyway, regardless of the insurance reasons and the interesting topics business wise, right, it is nice to see someone get... It's not nice to see someone get cyber attacked, but it is nice to see someone suffer the consequences of not putting in the effort, time, and money to be cyber confident.
Scott: So no matter how dumb-o your company is, if you don't know them and their computers, you better pay people like us a lot of money to come who do know computers and then do what we say, or else you will not have your insurance pay you because of an act of war.
Rym: So counterpoint, though, when your adversary is just the seething mass of internet shitlords and hackers and mafia stuff, that's one thing.
Rym: When your adversary is actually state-sponsored, it's hard to defend against that.
Rym: Even good IT practices will not help you.
Scott: If it was a targeted attack, you are correct, like a Stuxnet.
Rym: Which in this case, it probably was.
Scott: No, it was not.
Scott: This doesn't seem to have been targeted.
Scott: This thing was just like spread around.
Rym: Oh, no, no.
Rym: So here's... If you are targeted by a state-sponsored actor, you're probably fucked.
Rym: But if Joey Jojo Shabadu is targeted by a state-sponsored actor, you get caught in the collateral damage of that, you're still just as fucked.
Rym: Yeah, yeah.
Scott: But I mean, this is mostly cases where like, yeah, there are some dumb dumbs who work for you who downloaded email attachments and your IT department was not the greatest, right?
Scott: That kind of situation.
Rym: So I feel like this issue, at least in the United States, will not be dealt with in any way for at least a decade or two.
Scott: Yeah, this case was actually in London.
Scott: It wasn't in New York.
Rym: Which brings up NATO ramifications.
Scott: A place that has been bombed much more.
Rym: Yeah, this is a big deal that's not going to get dealt with correctly anytime soon.
Scott: Nope.
Rym: So in some other news, I'm sure you saw a global tragedy has occurred.
Rym: Notre Dame is basically burned down over the course of the last several hours.
Scott: I got only one thing to say.
Rym: You already got to say.
Scott: Looky mighty.
Rym: I am thankful that I was in Paris recently enough to have seen it in person because the entire interior is gone.
Rym: All that beautiful woodwork is gone.
Scott: I'm sure it will be rebuilt again for the X time.
Rym: It does not seem like it was malfeasance.
Rym: Well, not direct malfeasance.
Scott: It doesn't seem to have been that the person burned it on purpose.
Rym: However, I have seen some vague stories mostly coming out of mostly coming out of right wing nut bags.
Scott: No.
Scott: Oh, you mean the arson story?
Scott: Yeah, they are talking about the stories I'm seeing that are saying that basically what happened, it was under renovation at the time, and basically it was a mistake.
Scott: Something happened during the renovation that caused this.
Scott: It seems to be what happened, right?
Scott: But apparently there was a lot of fighting between the government, which owns it, and the church, which is using it, leasing it, whatever, allowed to busy borrowing it right over.
Scott: who is going to take care of these renovations because they're basically mad at each other that the place is a dump and who is going to take care of it.
Scott: You know, finger pointing.
Scott: And then, you know, there's a lot of low bidding, embezzling, finagling, you know, kind of stuff going on with this renovation project.
Scott: This renovation project was apparently not 100% above board, full price, high quality deal.
Scott: And now all that dirty laundry, if any, will be aired, right?
Scott: It's like if you're under if you're bad deal goes and goes well, no one ever.
Scott: then everything is good.
Scott: But if you're bad deal, suddenly a building collapses or sets on fire.
Scott: Well, guess what?
Scott: Now your dirty laundry is out in the open.
Scott: Everyone can see it.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: So that's going to be.
Scott: the really interesting story is, you know, rebuilding the building.
Scott: It's like, yeah, they're going to rebuild it for the however many time.
Scott: It's a ship of Theseus anyway.
Rym: Yeah, right.
Scott: But, uh, you know, and they'll probably build it better than it's ever been built.
Scott: And it'll probably last way longer this time.
Scott: You know, Paris is pretty good about reducing the impact of fires.
Scott: They're not fireproof yet, but they're getting better.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Some red blood of angry men and such.
Scott: But the, uh, you know, the really interesting story is going to be seeing, you know, the people, the company hired to do this renovating and all that kind of fighting and see who gets in trouble.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: How much trouble they get it.
Rym: Maybe you shouldn't entrust maybe a national treasure to the lowest bidder.
Scott: Maybe some insurance things going down to.
Scott: We got shitty stuff too.
Scott: Washington monument, I think I wasn't had some problems or maybe still does.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's got some issues and that could fall and hurt somebody.
Rym: So in some other news that there don't seem to be a lot of super reliable news sources about this story, but it's really making the rounds.
Rym: I want to talk about it.
Scott: It's also funny because it's extremely related to a particular net runner car.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: So the story is that Pepsi announced a contract with a Russian startup to make an artificial constellation of cube satellites that will print fucking words for an advertisement in the sky.
Rym: Now there's two things to say about this one.
Rym: I am highly skeptical.
Rym: This will actually happen.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Because this story looks pretty bull.
Scott: Think about it.
Scott: The, the space station, which is up there, which is bigger than a cube satellite, right?
Scott: Uh, you can see it as like a dot.
Rym: No, this would be easier.
Scott: You know how many of these things you would need to see?
Rym: Yeah, because you'd have mylar pointed back at the earth.
Rym: I guess our sales, like that would like.
Rym: theoretically, I can see how to get them lit up.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: I don't know.
Scott: It's, it's very difficult to do it this way.
Scott: Uh, and yeah, in the U S it's actually illegal to advertise in space, but it's not illegal to do that in Russia.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: So I'll say two things.
Rym: One, I do not think this is a real story.
Rym: It is not going to happen, but two, if it does happen, we declare war.
Rym: That is a, I will become a revolutionary and shoot them down myself.
Rym: If I have to, that's right.
Scott: I'll go into space with a gun.
Rym: Yup.
Scott: Moonraker.
Scott: Uh, but yeah, there's a net runner card.
Scott: It was in the original, uh, at least Android net runner core set, not the old, old net runner, but you know, the newer anyway.
Scott: Uh, and it was the, it was an agenda called Astro script pilot program.
Scott: And the theme of the card was, was an NBN card, which is basically like, you know, cyberpunk CNN.
Scott: And the, the idea was that they were testing out using a laser to draw an advertisement on the moon so that everyone could see this ad all the time.
Scott: And it was one of the most broken OP cards that won me many tournaments until it was banned.
Rym: So last and not least, I said, this is similar to the thing with Russia before.
Rym: So New York city, uh, is in the midst.
Rym: If you haven't noticed, Elvay really bad measles.
Scott: I heard this, uh, you know, Westchester is pretty bad.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Scott: But there's a few places that are pretty bad.
Scott: The places you would expect.
Rym: in Williamsburg alone, there are 285 people known to have contracted the disease.
Scott: That's a lot more.
Scott: That's more people than in like the last many years combined, right?
Scott: Yup.
Rym: 465 cases across 19 states.
Rym: This is a big deal.
Rym: However, New York city has done something very important.
Scott: If you get measles, you are like gonna die.
Scott: It's not good.
Rym: Well, I mean, I have, I'm vaccinated, so I'm also vaccinated.
Scott: You know, but the point is you don't want to get it.
Rym: So New York city has ordered mandatory vaccinations in four area codes.
Scott: If we can do that, why can't we just order it for all people and say, if you don't vaccinate, you're kicked to exiled, even if you're a citizen.
Rym: So here's the problem.
Rym: Here's what's going on.
Rym: We've ordered this, but almost all of these cases are actually in one specific community in Brooklyn of Hasidic Jewish people who are specifically known for being extremely insular and kind of anti-government.
Scott: And there's a whole, it creates a lot of issues because, you know, when suddenly with your pro science, right?
Scott: You, it can now be misconstrued as being antisemite, right?
Scott: And also antisemites will jump on the bandwagon with you and use the and say, no, no, I'm just being pro science so that they can be their antisemite ways while, right?
Scott: For example, there was a story I read today that a bus passed by a Hasidic person without picking him up, which is not allowed.
Scott: That's inexcusable.
Scott: But the bus driver was like, I don't want to get measles.
Rym: It's like, well, that neighborhood has the private sexism buses and all sorts of nonsense.
Scott: Lots of stuff going on.
Rym: But, uh, quote, the doctors are trying to screw us.
Rym: I'm sure of it said fairy schmelts, a 28 year old Yeshiva student.
Rym: So the interesting thing, if you're not familiar with Judaism, is that no sect of Judaism says vaccines are bad.
Rym: Like this is not a thing.
Scott: No, no.
Scott: You're right.
Scott: So not only is the Hasidic Jews have nothing against vaccine, not only are the vaccines specifically rabbi approved as kosher.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And there's no reason not to get them in the in the Jewish religion.
Rym: The Jewish religion, actually, you know, with all its crazy rules about not wearing two kinds of cloth at one time, it does have this very important exception that a lot of other religions need to have.
Scott: It has lots and lots and lots of common sense exceptions.
Scott: For example, you're not allowed to drive in Shabbos, right?
Scott: Saturday, no car driving now because you're not allowed to start a fire, not allowed to work unless you're saving someone's life.
Scott: But guess what?
Scott: If you see somebody like dying, it's like, yes, you can drive the car.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: it's all these common sense exceptions, like don't do this.
Scott: But guess what?
Scott: Oh, it's like.
Scott: it's like, all right, you can only eat the unleavened bread.
Scott: Oh, you would die without some real bread.
Scott: Have some yeast.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Looking at you, Catholic Church, where celiac.
Rym: Well, if you have celiac disease, you just can't get communion because it doesn't count.
Scott: So even if even if the vaccine had like pig's blood in it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It would still.
Rym: Which it doesn't.
Scott: It doesn't.
Scott: It's totally kosher.
Scott: Even if it did, it would still be permitted by most rabbis.
Rym: I imagine there's the interesting part among the that community.
Rym: There's a sort of subset of them.
Rym: That's sort of very anti-government.
Rym: But even them, their own rabbi was like, most of us are vaccinated.
Rym: And frankly, he's paraphrasing this guy.
Rym: I am annoyed at the very small number of members of our community who are for no earthly reason anti-vaccine.
Rym: But the article points out something very specific.
Rym: The reasons for the explosion of cases, because they're almost all in this community.
Rym: Among members of insular, all the ultra-orthodox communities has to do with their frequent contacts with Israel, which is undergoing its own measles epidemic, combined with their insularity and general mistrust of the governments.
Rym: In addition, and this is the part I'm getting into, this is what's kind of fucked up.
Rym: There is a widespread, I'm paraphrasing the article now, but there is a widespread misinformation campaign of fake robot phone calls and Internet stuff specifically targeting this community with anti-vax propaganda.
Rym: There is some evidence that that anti-vax propaganda that is also targeting Israel appears to be another Russian psy-op.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like, hey, let's just convince these Jews we hate because we're anti-Semites to not get vaccinated and they'll die.
Rym: Yeah, part of it is that Israel has no requirement for children to be vaccinated before grade school.
Rym: So there's a measles epidemic going on there.
Scott: And then because how do they not get measles there?
Scott: before, though, from what I can gather, people were getting it, even though it wasn't required until recently.
Rym: I think measles has been more of a problem in Israel than it has been in other places.
Scott: Why don't we do these kind of psy-ops against, you know, it's not like the people that we're fighting against.
Scott: are that geniuses.
Scott: Let's do, let's call up all like the crazy yokels in the US and tell them stuff that will get them to hurt themselves.
Rym: Should this be our next Monday or Thursday topic?
Rym: Would like modern anti psy-op psy-ops?
Scott: No, I'm not saying anti.
Scott: I'm just saying me more me more fair instead of all these because all the people not doing vaccines are like ultra religious Jews who've been opt and crazy hipster new age people who think vaccines give you autism.
Scott: But meanwhile, the friggin, you know, Republican people in Louisiana or Alabama or whatever are all getting vaccines.
Scott: Why don't we call them and convince them to get measles?
Rym: So there's another way to go.
Rym: I saw a meme making the rounds that someone's trying to push where they're trying to do the thing we always talk about.
Rym: They're trying to make a like viral meme that will spread among idiots that will cause them to do the right thing.
Scott: Yeah, that's what I'm talking about.
Rym: The meme is around how vaccines are effective, but they have toxins in them and the government will tell you what they are.
Rym: If you take a raw potato, scrape it and apply it to the vaccination wound within six hours of getting the vaccine and hold it there and really rub it in, it'll draw the toxins from the vaccine out, but still give you the vaccination.
Rym: Obviously, this is bullshit.
Scott: Yeah, but I think this is made by some Idaho potato farmer.
Rym: It's.
Rym: but it's the kind of bullshit that the kind of person who thinks vaccines will give their baby autism because of a Facebook meme might believe.
Rym: Anyway, it's time for things of the day.
Rym: So you might have heard.
Rym: you might have heard of the extended one up sound that there's.
Rym: you might have heard that there's an alternate version of the one up sound in Mario three.
Scott: You might have played Mario three and occasionally while playing Mario three, notice that certain sounds override other sounds, certain sounds play strangely sometimes.
Scott: And you know, the sound is not the sound effects like the things that happen, like when you jump, shoot a fireball, hit a block, all the minor sound effects.
Scott: There's some inconsistency to them.
Scott: And you can kind of feel it and like understand it when you're playing Mario three, especially if you played Mario three a lot.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But here's the video of the day that I know more about than he does, apparently, because I've watched the whole thing.
Rym: I watched the whole thing, too.
Rym: So I would say like you might have heard this sound.
Rym: You might have heard people say, oh, there's a long version of the sound.
Rym: It's actually way more complicated than that.
Rym: The long version of the sound is not actually intended.
Rym: It's a glitch where the sound plays and based on a bunch of other parameters in memory, it plays part of a different sound with weird parameters.
Rym: You get this glitched out version of the sound.
Scott: And actually it's so it's like this video explains how they came up with an elegant system for the sound effects that it handles priority because you only have so many channels that can play audio.
Rym: You got to organize the sound.
Scott: B, they had too many sounds, so they hacked on an additional duct tape solution to add extra sounds, which was pretty elegant, all things considered.
Scott: And then C, they coded away for this to still work, even though it's hacky.
Scott: And then there was a bug in that duct tape that caused it to be messed up.
Scott: But if you can actually fix that bug, if you patch your ROM or whatever, and then the sounds will won't ever mess up.
Rym: Yeah, I won't spoil it.
Rym: But the video is only like 15 minutes long.
Rym: And it really even if you don't know anything about computers, it explains it well enough.
Rym: You'll understand.
Scott: You'll also start to understand computers, hopefully.
Rym: Yeah, because remember, this is an NES like the bug is in basically a single CPU instruction to move data from one register to another register.
Rym: Like that's the bug in the end.
Scott: So speaking of Nintendo console CPUs, I don't know when this was made.
Scott: This might be old.
Scott: Something similar might even think this might have been thing of the day at some point.
Scott: And I forget it, but it was making the rounds on the Internet very recently.
Scott: So I'll take that as like, you know, I saw it posted in multiple places, which makes me think it's new or at least updated.
Scott: So what this is, is this is a complete manual to the CPU on the original Game Boy.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Like, I guess.
Scott: also it applies to every other thing like, I guess, Game Boy Color, Game Boy Pocket, Game Boy, Super Game Boy, and it's got a bunch of typos.
Scott: I just noticed it applies to all the things that are game in the original Game Boy, anything that can play a gray cartridge.
Scott: But yeah, it's a complete CPU manual, tells you everything about how that Game Boy works.
Scott: And it was compiled by a whole bunch of people with very Internet names.
Scott: Go to the top.
Scott: Let's see where their names are.
Rym: Oh, I was like Koopa.
Scott: Let's see.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: All right.
Scott: This document was compiled by a fan of anthrax.
Scott: Gabby Merritt Faison.
Scott: That's that's a dude name.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Pascal Felber.
Scott: Paul Robson.
Scott: That's a normal name.
Scott: Martin Korth.
Scott: That's a Koopa and Bowser.
Scott: So it's like Bowser.
Scott: That's pretty, you know, for a non-official manual.
Scott: It's very complete and thorough.
Scott: And if you read this and you could write some assembly and you get little flash carts, you can actually load your programs into your Game Boy or get a Game Boy emulator.
Scott: You can use this to make Game Boy software.
Rym: I have a soft spot for like the kind of complete documentation that used to come with computer things.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: It's good stuff in the moment.
Rym: The we don't have any conventions for a while.
Rym: It's summer.
Rym: We're just hanging out, which means we're going to be making more like we're going to make Judge Anime by its cover.
Scott: recorded Judge Anime by its cover for the current season.
Scott: I just have to put it together.
Scott: They changed their website.
Scott: So I had to do some programming to get my script, creepy script to work.
Rym: Yeah, I'm getting our backlog of video together.
Rym: So I just uploaded our one of our panels for MagFest at the beginning of the year.
Rym: Rare game mechanics.
Scott: Yeah, I'll have the have the judge uploaded soon.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I just finished editing our most recent talk, The Real Harm of Games.
Rym: And I'm going to post it as soon as I feel like it.
Rym: It's already on YouTube.
Rym: I just haven't made it public yet because I don't want to blow my whole load in one go.
Rym: Those have to wait.
Rym: I did some pre-production for the next episode of the Utena show.
Rym: You might have noticed a few episodes of our Utena show got taken down yet again.
Scott: Oh, no.
Rym: I'm in the process of fighting that yet again.
Rym: That's why we don't make anime content after we finish the Utena show.
Rym: I'm just never making an analysis show of anything ever again.
Rym: It's just not worth it.
Scott: Just don't put clips of the show in the analysis show.
Rym: Yeah, but showing the clip while we're talking is a big part of why the show is good.
Scott: Let's put it up on a different site and not YouTube.
Rym: That's also a pain in the ass.
Rym: That's a big pain in the ass.
Scott: It's a thing.
Rym: Anyway, well, I'm working on it.
Rym: And The Geek Knights Book Club.
Rym: I have chosen a book which might be a terrible mistake.
Rym: We're reading Troy Dennings Pages of Pain.
Scott: I hope that reading it is not that the title is not taken literally.
Rym: Nominative determinism.
Scott: Yeah, I hope that doesn't happen.
Scott: But we'll see.
Rym: I have fond memories of this being shockingly good for being a branded Dungeons and Dragons book.
Rym: So we'll see.
Rym: And yeah, let's get right into it.
Rym: Because a long time ago in 1993, the concept of a bookmark appeared in the Mosaic browser.
Scott: So it's like we had web browsers.
Scott: People were typing in URLs and a really basic feature was added to the web browser.
Scott: Hey, you're visiting this web page a lot, right?
Scott: You're just going there over and over again.
Scott: You don't want to have to type in www.slashdot.org every freaking time.
Scott: Especially if they didn't really have auto-complete in the location bar.
Scott: They didn't have any of these features to make it easy to type in.
Rym: Dude, there were some websites I went to regularly.
Rym: that was literally just an IP address.
Rym: There was no DNS.
Scott: You didn't have tabs in the browser even in those days.
Rym: Dude, tabs didn't appear until we were in college.
Rym: Right.
Scott: So they made bookmarks where you would save the link to the web page and now you could just go to a menu.
Scott: They didn't even have the bookmarked bar then.
Scott: You go to a menu and then you could click an item in the menu and that would take you to the page.
Scott: So you could just click two times and you didn't have to type in all this URL all the time and you could all your favorite web pages, all 10 of them, you could go to them over and over and over again very easily by clicking.
Scott: And that was the idea of a bookmark.
Scott: So when we were thinking about doing this show, I also, if you came across something interesting that had like a crazy long URL, you could save it for later and you wouldn't lose it.
Rym: I'd like, that's how I'd remember.
Rym: Like, Oh, this was that great site that had all those anime gifts.
Scott: Oh, here was that Game Boy CPU manual.
Scott: Let me not lose this.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: Here's the link to that file share that has two hacked ROMs of Final Fantasy four and two, the NES one with the Japanese translated into English, like that kind of nonsense.
Scott: Over time, a lot of features are added to browsers, tabs, bookmark bar, all kinds of crazy stuff.
Rym: And also the internet changed seismically multiple times, right?
Scott: So the one, there are a couple of bookmark features though, that I'm upset that we're not, uh, Chrome doesn't have and Firefox does.
Scott: Well,
Rym: I got to back up a little bit further because I feel like if you chart a graph of how actively I curate my own bookmarks and use them in my day to day life, the graph just goes up and up and up and up and up and up.
Rym: And then there's a point where it starts going down and down and down and down and down and down and down.
Rym: I basically don't use bookmarks anymore.
Scott: That's what I'm saying is that all these other features that came along, made bookmarks get used less and less and less and less and less and less, right?
Scott: People keeps keeping tabs open because we have tabs now pinning the tabs to make them smaller, right?
Scott: All of these frequently used website just open all the time.
Rym: Also to quote a tweet that makes the rounds pretty regularly.
Rym: That is very relevant to this discussion.
Rym: Quote, I feel like there used to be more websites.
Rym: I mean, why not?
Rym: My old bookmarks, which I have saved somewhere, like on the NAS, I have like bookmarks from high school Rym.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Well, I mean, for example, web comics, I used to have a bookmark folder and in that bookmark folder was a link to every single web comic I read.
Scott: I had a bookmark folder called web comics.
Rym: And then I had a Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday, Thursday and Friday.
Scott: I didn't separate them.
Scott: What I did is every day I would open up when I woke up, I would go to that folder and right click on it and I would say open all in tabs and it would open up a new window with one tab for every comic.
Scott: And I would just press control tab going through each comic.
Scott: And if they were a new one, I would just tab over real quickly because it wasn't updated.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: And I would just go through all of them.
Scott: And that was when I was reading web comics regularly.
Scott: And the failure of that is why I haven't been keeping up.
Rym: So part of this was that this was an era for a long time where there was no effective way to search for things on the Internet, like searching didn't really work.
Rym: So if you found a website and it had good stuff, you needed to save it and remember how to get to it, or you might never find it again.
Rym: That's right.
Rym: That was that is literally what the Internet was like.
Rym: And there were a lot of websites.
Rym: None of them had URLs that meant anything to anyone.
Scott: So because you have tabs, because you have Google, because you have autocomplete in the browser bar, because we have so many things now that have made bookmarks obsolete.
Scott: And in fact, the two kinds of bookmarks.
Scott: There was the kind of bookmark where I need I go to the site all the time and the kind where this is an interesting article.
Scott: Let me save it.
Scott: The interesting article kind at even while bookmarks are still in use.
Scott: We started using Delicious to save those instead of using the browser.
Rym: I use Delicious so heavily until it disappeared.
Rym: And now it's not trustworthy.
Scott: No, you can't.
Scott: Delicious got bought and sold too many times.
Scott: Now it's dead.
Scott: But there's a website pinboard dot in that's not free, but it's really cheap.
Scott: It's like a couple of bucks a year or something.
Scott: And I just use that.
Scott: And then I use IFTTT.
Scott: And what I have it set up with IFTTT is basically if I favor to tweet and there's a link in it, it goes on the pin board.
Scott: If it automatically.
Scott: if I upvote something on Reddit or save something on Reddit or save something in Feedly or like any action I take on the Internet and any site that involves a link, I have it configured to put that link on the pin board dot in.
Scott: And so now any kind of things I want to remember are just automatically all aggregated there forever.
Scott: And all my old Delicious bookmarks are important, too.
Scott: What's interesting is I almost never need to remember a link to anything because I go there to find the thing of the day I save, you know, if I like a YouTube video, it goes there.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Rym: But I guess I like.
Rym: I just look at my own Twitter likes or I look at my own YouTube like.
Scott: they're all collected in one place.
Rym: That is true.
Rym: But I guess in terms of like when I'm using the Internet, like aside from the use case of Scott and I actually need to compile a list of things we're going to link to and talk about because we make gig nights in the rest of my life, I just start typing the name of the thing I'm going to and autocomplete and Google and everything just make it work.
Scott: They made some and I don't go to that many websites.
Scott: They made so many good features.
Scott: You don't need bookmarks.
Rym: What do I do?
Rym: I type I go to I type news that takes me to news that Google dot com.
Rym: And then I type the noun that I'm looking for news about.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Or I just start typing like I don't know you and then YouTube because I'm going to be in YouTube.
Scott: So one of the features that I really like in Firefox is you can make a bookmark and you can add a word to that bookmark.
Scott: So, for example, I can make a bookmark to our website and then I could give it a keyword FRC.
Scott: And now if I type FRC in the location bar, it goes to that bookmark.
Scott: So you basically don't have to actually click on bookmarks.
Scott: You can just put in codes for them.
Scott: Another thing you can do with that is you can actually make bookmarks of search bars.
Scott: So you could go to say, what's a site that has a search on it?
Scott: YouTube, Wikipedia, you can go to Wikipedia, find the search box, right click on the search box, create a bookmark for the search box, then create a keyword on that.
Scott: So here's why that doesn't matter.
Rym: I type any random thing into just Google and it immediately always returns in almost all cases.
Rym: First result, the Wikipedia for that.
Scott: But what I do is I go to the location bar and I type wiki space thing and press enter.
Scott: And I'm already on the Wikipedia page for that thing.
Scott: I can skip the Google page.
Scott: I save a whole page.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So those are some nice features.
Scott: But, you know, Chrome sort of kind of Firefox really implements.
Rym: Here's where this all breaks down.
Rym: Like I said, I used to use complex bookmark management things to do cool things, but I increasingly don't have the time.
Rym: It's that it's not worth the effort.
Rym: The payout is too low to curate really anything anymore.
Rym: No, like I'm not willing to curate my bookmarks.
Rym: So even if those features are incredibly useful, very intuitive.
Scott: I only have like those two.
Rym: But curating the data to make the features actually do it something better than just blindly typing nonsense into the browser URL thing isn't worth the effort.
Scott: So one there is one case.
Scott: I still use old school bookmarks in the bookmark bar.
Scott: Right.
Rym: So the bookmark bar was what's in my bookmark bar?
Rym: because I don't curate at all.
Rym: I've got Webcomic.
Scott: You don't just turn it off.
Scott: If you don't if you're not using it, just turn it off.
Rym: I think I turned it back on.
Scott: If I'm not using it at home, I have it completely turned off because I don't use it at home.
Scott: I only use it at work.
Scott: And at work, what I do is I basically fill up the bookmark bar with all the work shit that you can never remember the URL to.
Scott: Like click on this to go to Jira.
Scott: Click on this to go to Confluence.
Scott: Click on this to go to GitHub to go to.
Rym: I just type at work.
Rym: I type J and it takes me to my Jira dashboard.
Scott: But it's like, you know, I have all these different software as it takes me to the Confluence page and I have to use it work.
Scott: So I have basically buttons for each one of them right in that bookmark bar, you know, and now you don't have to use that to go to a menu to go to bookmarks.
Scott: Now I can just click on any of the ones in the bar.
Rym: Well, yeah.
Rym: So I realized my all I got in my bookmarks bar is one bookmark to this awesome looking website about wargame mechanics.
Scott: OK, is that the website with your adjacent triangle?
Rym: Uh, maybe.
Rym: It's just this looks like a really fascinating thing I want to read later.
Rym: I don't know why I bookmarked it.
Rym: And then I think of webcomics.
Scott: Did you press control D by accident?
Rym: Uh, probably.
Rym: Then I've got a list of webcomics.
Rym: One I still read.
Rym: One that's been done for years.
Rym: The admin link for Kineticons like CMS.
Rym: A chili recipe.
Scott: Why is it a chili recipe in your webcomics bookmarks?
Rym: I probably hit control D. The old front row crew forum.
Rym: Google News.
Rym: Oh, this place that had all the bootleg DDR roms that is totally still up.
Scott: Sweet.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Send me that one.
Rym: And my streaming dashboard.
Rym: So, yeah, I don't use bookmarks at all.
Scott: I do have a few bookmarks on my iPad iPhone.
Scott: They synchronize with iCloud.
Scott: They're the same.
Scott: because it's not like, you know, you can really it's not the same UI on a phone where you're keeping the tabs open and stuff like that.
Scott: So I just have like three bookmarks to go to like the forum and the pinboard.
Scott: And that's really pretty much it.
Scott: Like I've realized because the other thing is the things where I'm on my desktop, right?
Scott: A lot of the tabs I have open in my browser on my phone have their own app.
Scott: No, it's like on my my computer.
Scott: I'll have like Gmail open in a tab all the time.
Scott: Don't need a bookmark on my phone.
Scott: There's a Gmail app, but like the forum is like the only thing that I need the browser for that I keep going to on my phone.
Scott: So that has a bookmark on the phone.
Scott: But it's like the only bookmark on the phone.
Rym: I guess as a result of Web 2.0 and maybe Web 2.5 and like the way the Internet is used today, I only go to like seven websites.
Scott: Yeah, that's the thing I'm saying is like back in the day, you go to a different website for each thing.
Scott: If you were interested in like 10 different people, they each had 10 different blogs.
Scott: You had to read everyone's blog.
Rym: My Delicious was so curated that I would I would do is I would basically search my own bookmarks to find something and I would use my text.
Rym: I would look for like Tenchi anime minus a bunch like minus this tag plus that tag to find like the 40 websites I'd link to.
Rym: that had the one thing I'm looking for right now.
Scott: But nowadays you just instead of everyone having their own blog that you visit, everyone having their own GeoCities and all these different pages, you just follow everyone on Twitter and you go to one website, Twitter.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: It's like or even even if you go to your Twitter, Facebook, Instagram, you just go to one of every social network.
Scott: Dude, I don't ever run there.
Scott: Yeah, ready?
Scott: You know, but it's like.
Scott: you don't need, you know, to have so many different sites because everyone is posting this stuff on the same site.
Scott: Yeah, I think just click links from there to other places.
Scott: So I don't need to bookmark your actual blog post, even if you link to it with a tweet, because I just favorite that tweet.
Rym: Well, the other problem I've had with bookmarks is that throughout all of my life, websites just disappear.
Rym: And even if you go to one website, links disappear because no one I feel like.
Rym: for some reason, Scott and I are some of the last people on earth who are obsessed with maintaining link integrity forever.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Our fucking website.
Scott: Open source people do.
Scott: They're like, you know, to this day, good URLs don't change.
Rym: If you got a URL to the GeekNights podcast, like a particular episode back in like 2005, that fucking URL will still get you there.
Scott: The thing is that the day might not work, but the URL does.
Scott: All the URLs of an old forum still work, kept the whole thing up, even though it's read only and some of it's broken.
Scott: But you can still read everything there.
Rym: It is terrifying.
Rym: how much content is in there.
Scott: Yes.
Rym: So is there a future for bookmarks?
Rym: Because I feel like this comes down to a much more fundamental question.
Scott: I don't think it's that, you know, who cares about saving or not saving bookmarks themselves?
Scott: They're not the special thing.
Scott: They were just a solution to a problem and both the problem has been solved mostly like 90 plus percent by other solutions that are better.
Scott: And the problem itself has largely gone away also.
Rym: So people who are making bookmarks, features and browsers are saying, how do I make bookmarks usable and better when they're skipping?
Rym: There's the big question of why do you need a bookmark in the first place?
Scott: Yes, you built all these other things so that bookmarks are no longer needed and the world changed.
Scott: So bookmarks are no longer needed as nearly as much, right?
Rym: Though there is one thing that happens to me every now and then.
Rym: Every now and then I need to log into like, I don't know, trying to think of an example of this.
Rym: The fucking like the website to file a New York state royalty tax thing.
Rym: I don't fucking remember that URL and I definitely haven't been to it.
Scott: You can't Google it.
Scott: I'd have to Google for it and find the New York state tax website.
Rym: Yeah, and then maybe hunt around for it because usually there's like three different tax websites and they all do different things that are slightly.
Rym: so because it's got my website or what happens to me at work sometimes is I will be in a conference room as opposed to in my at my desk.
Rym: And I don't know the URL or even the domain of the thing I want to pull up.
Rym: But all I know is that if I start typing the letter I at my desk, it'll get me there.
Scott: Yeah, I mean, I guess there could be cases like, you know, the other day I got my my annual free credit report.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: And you know, there's a lot of sites.
Scott: They try to scam you without a credit report to make sure there's one that is the government sponsored website.
Scott: that's like, you know, there for government.
Rym: You know, you know, I actually stopped even I stopped using that.
Rym: I get the free one from my bank.
Scott: The one from the bank is apparently not going to talk about credit scores, but the one for the bank is a Vantage score, not a Fico eight score.
Scott: It's not exactly the same, but they're.
Rym: usually it's very rare that one of them is really bad and one of them is very rare.
Scott: But the point is, I wanted to get the real one.
Scott: Just I haven't done in so long.
Scott: I'm just curious.
Scott: The funny thing is I can do it once a year.
Rym: So I just check mine because, you know, tax season.
Rym: The only way my credit could possibly get better is if I am 20 years older.
Scott: You'll never create.
Rym: better is if I buy a house.
Rym: I've never had a mortgage.
Scott: If I was rich or bought a house.
Scott: Yeah, basically it's almost at the maximum.
Scott: The maximum is like eight fifty.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Mine's like eight twenty something.
Scott: Mine was eight thirty.
Scott: It might be eight thirty.
Scott: It was up there.
Scott: It was really high.
Rym: Yeah, I forget the exact at the bottom is literally like get a mortgage or be older.
Scott: Yeah, there wasn't much I could do to make it better because I've paid all my bills.
Scott: So I'll bet the only difference between yours and my point is bookmarking the the legit website, which I think is annual credit report.
Scott: Yeah, legit one.
Scott: Make sure you go to the legit one.
Rym: You can use Wikipedia to confirm what you are bookmarking, like the specific website you log into to manage like the vision plan you get from your company.
Rym: That's different.
Scott: That's the kind of stuff like a book market work where it's not something you can search for.
Scott: It's not like I can search for my company's H.R.
Scott: systems.
Scott: You are out, right?
Scott: It's a. it's a particular URL that like only people at our company.
Scott: It's funny because of the nature of bookmark, you know, our forum, our website, whatever, because it's like a particular URL for us.
Rym: I guess there is a fundamental question that we can ask, but not answer around this thing of that.
Rym: there were a lot of tools that we use and that people use related to the Internet in general that were really around the idea of if you curate a data set, you can make that data set extremely valuable to yourself and others.
Rym: But increasingly, it is.
Rym: no one is willing to curate data sets.
Scott: It's a lot of work.
Scott: Yeah, we want algorithms.
Scott: Just do it.
Scott: But the problem is we don't do it by hand.
Rym: Algorithms will just work like autocomplete just finds everything.
Rym: I want 99 percent of the time.
Rym: But no one can explain why the algorithm does A versus B. And that's why the fourth YouTube video in any search result is some Nazi shit.
Rym: So I don't know what to do about that because I like curating data.
Scott: People gamify the algorithm, right?
Scott: They try to trick it into showing their stuff.
Scott: And the people who try the hardest at that succeed to some extent.
Rym: I take a lot of photos and make a lot of video.
Rym: I cannot be asked to with the
Rym: A.S.S.,
Rym: like asked, not asked, but asked to bother actually fully tagging all the photos I take in Lightroom
Scott: or, you know, it's like I don't even watch I don't put the effort to like play Internet games and get like fake likes and do other stuff to promote my viz.
Scott: Yeah, it's not worth it.
Rym: I'm just talking about even my own content.
Rym: like my MP3 collection is curated to the point of obsession up until about 2003.
Rym: And then every music file I've gotten since then is just in a mess.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: And I will never fix that.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at FrontRowCrew.com for show notes, discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: SciTech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon Patrons for this episode of GeekNights are... Oh, I got my monitor speaker on.
Rym: Let me turn that off.
Rym: Much better.
Rym: And now I leave you with... The future, of course, being virtual reality.
Rym: Something that's being talked about by other people, but produced by Sega.
Rym: Well, I can't get to the right page, but check out this little demonstration of VR.