Rym: It's Tuesday January 15th 2019.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Rym: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We are back to talk about the hot tabletop game root Let's do this.
Rym: So something very important happened.
Rym: I wad a bridge north of us was blown up The Tappan Zee bridge.
Rym: yep now there was nothing wrong with it's weird.
Rym: a lot of people kept saying like oh that bridge sucked like How?
Rym: what was bad about it other than the fact that it's way too far north because of nonsense politics.
Rym: So that bridge was old and falling apart.
Rym: But that didn't a falling apart, but it being old and falling apart never actually affected one's experience driving over it.
Scott: There was mad traffic as didn't have enough lanes.
Scott: the new one I don't think it has significantly more capacity is twice as much and it has a bike lane and a pedestrian path.
Scott: But the old one was one bridge.
Scott: the new one is two bridges each larger than the previous bridge.
Rym: The thing is I am in no position to ever take advantage of that bike lane anytime soon.
Scott: Why not just bike up there?
Scott: It's a ways up as soon as it's warm.
Rym: What's on the other side of it if you bike over it?
Scott: What do you mean?
Scott: on one side is Westchester and the other side is like Nyack?
Scott: Yeah, it's like Nyack to Piermont.
Rym: Yeah, I want to buy.
Scott: I've biked farther than that frequently.
Rym: I would rather bike over the Verrazano Narrows bridge.
Rym: That's the one I want a bike lane.
Scott: Oh that bike that bridge sucks.
Scott: It's tall.
Rym: I'm into it.
Scott: Yeah It's hard to bike over the Verrazano.
Scott: We've both done it.
Scott: It sucks.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: This bridge is not tall.
Rym: Yeah, there was a live stream.
Rym: It got blown up.
Rym: bridges blowing up is actually not that interesting to watch.
Scott: So originally they were like, let's blow up the whole damn thing.
Scott: then they're like, no, no, no, we'll hurt the fishes.
Scott: So they were taking it apart one piece at a time slowly And then there and then using the pieces to make reefs for the fishes down near Rockaway and other places.
Scott: But then they're like, oh no We were taking apart this one piece and we heard a really loud bet noise and we checked it and the structure might not be Too good.
Scott: So if we take it apart slowly, it might just collapse.
Scott: while we're taking it apart slowly So we're gonna have to blow up this one piece and then we can take it apart after it's fallen in the water.
Rym: But no to be fair that bridge was an old piece of shit in terms of engineering.
Rym: Maybe next they gotta work on the white stone in the frogs neck.
Rym: Yeah, right those things are held up.
Scott: They blow those up.
Scott: that'll be something to say.
Rym: those two are held up as far as I can tell entirely by paint.
Scott: I feel like what they should do for the white stone and frogs neck Right is they should make new bridges that go straight across Yeah, and then make two more bridges in it because they're so close to each other.
Rym: Oh, yeah, just make one two three and then get rid of the old two, right?
Scott: Well make two get rid of the old two then make two new ones in an X shape so you could start at one end right.
Scott: Make like an like a bow tie shape with four bridges with like loops at all the corners.
Scott: That way you can start on like the white stone and an end on the other side of the frogs neck or vice versa.
Scott: They're so close.
Scott: Yeah, but they're like.
Scott: They're like, you know They might as well be next to each other.
Rym: The only reason I ever used one or the other because one of them had more traffic than the other.
Rym: one Like it was pretty random which one I ever used.
Scott: I would choose based on where I'm going on the other side.
Scott: So if I'm going northeast, I'm gonna use a frogs neck is a little further out.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: and If I'm going to like the baseball stadium, I'm using the white stone.
Scott: cuz it's right fucking there.
Rym: Yep I was usually going northwest.
Rym: So I ended up using the white stone.
Scott: Yeah, you know It's like where you're going is which one you're gonna use.
Rym: Yeah, that GeekNights' quality content.
Rym: You're looking for.
Rym: We're back talking about bridges.
Rym: We haven't done a show in a while because it was the holidays and we were all traveling and doing stuff and then it was Magfest.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: We had the New Year's party that we had to go to.
Scott: We're going to PAX South.
Scott: So you're not getting another show.
Scott: It's like next week.
Rym: Yep We can.
Rym: basically we can only fit in one show between all these cons and not too far.
Rym: after PAX South is paxis Kind of far out.
Scott: you're gonna be getting shows in February and March.
Scott: Yeah, it's far enough out.
Scott: We will be doing shows and the rest of January you're gonna get shows.
Scott: All right, Jen rest of January February and March.
Scott: They'll be nice.
Rym: So we are back from super mag fest.
Rym: So I think it's worthwhile to.
Rym: we don't.
Rym: in the old days We would do a whole show on every kind we went to but go to a lot of cons not a lot changes.
Rym: But there's always notable things to talk about for any big con we go to.
Rym: so mag fest 2019 was better than Previous mag fests in a lot of ways.
Rym: but mag fest has a problem that's starting to grow.
Scott: Man, this has always had a problem.
Rym: Yeah, but it's getting worse.
Scott: It's always been getting worse.
Rym: Yeah, it's getting worse.
Scott: worse, right?
Scott: Well, I mean that's the thing with getting worse is that every time it's worse than the last time.
Rym: So here's the deal.
Rym: mag fest is like the only non pax gaming con we like.
Rym: like Magfest is better than the worst pax in terms of the attendee experience But it's not quite on the level of like a pax West.
Rym: no But I really like mag fest and also mag fest is unique.
Rym: Some of the things that mag fest you make mag fest unique are really awesome Like the panel content at mag fest like especially if you want like academic.
Scott: Well, because mag fest is a nonprofit has to justify its nonprofit status So it does a lot of awesome things to justify its nonprofit status.
Rym: like mag fest panels are mostly fan panels Non gaming or like just fun stuff or they're like really like.
Scott: they're the kinds of panels that we do.
Rym: There's other people doing the kind of stuff.
Rym: We do at pax's at mag fest It's not just us.
Rym: so the panels are great.
Rym: Like I go to more panels at mag fest than I do at pax's.
Rym: But what they don't have are like big serious industry panels.
Scott: so much and a big serious industry presence at all.
Rym: Yeah, but it is it is all fan all the time Which is both a pro anacond because like there's better content in many regards.
Rym: But that content is often less polished a little more raw like pax will have a super polished panel.
Scott: The industry came to mag fest.
Scott: They'd be like we gotta shut this shit down.
Scott: Yeah, it's cannot have.
Scott: this cannot be.
Rym: yeah Like mag fest you'll go to a fire mag fest.
Rym: They'll go to a panel.
Rym: That's really good.
Rym: But it's a little unpolished because the panelists are literally hungover or possibly still drunk from the night before.
Rym: But I love mag fest.
Rym: I love going to mag fest and generally like the arcade was rocking this year mag fest Traditionally had a problem where Thursday was pretty weak and Sunday was pretty weak.
Rym: this year Thursday was a full-on goddamn day.
Scott: Yeah, usually it's like I told people right show up to mag fest late Thursday.
Scott: Nothing happens.
Scott: early Thursday I got there and leave mag fest early Sunday.
Scott: Everyone checks out of the hotel and then the whole place is empty.
Scott: on Sunday There's no reason to hang around get home get home.
Rym: Yeah, I got there at noon and like tabletops already bumping like there's already panels going.
Scott: Yeah, so next year got to get to mag fest earlier on Thursday The expo Hall said it would open it too and it opened it too.
Scott: Yeah, it was bumping and last year mag.
Scott: Well, yeah last year at mag fest on Sunday morning tabletop was a hundred percent empty.
Scott: It was just a ghost town.
Scott: No one was there this year.
Scott: It wasn't bumping on Sunday, but it was there.
Scott: It was activity on Sunday and that was like the library was open.
Scott: There were people there.
Scott: would you could?
Scott: you could play games in there on Sunday?
Scott: There was also not feel like you were wasting your time or that you should have gone home like on Thursday.
Rym: Sorry on the last day on Sunday when I went in the the arcade was still bumping and like I still had to wait In line to play DDR.
Scott: You always have to wait in line to play DDR or initial D.
Rym: The time where you don't have to wait in line to play DDR or initial D is between 5 a.m.
Rym: And 10 a.m.
Rym: That is the magic moment.
Scott: All right, I'll try to wake up early.
Rym: as I've said I remember last year I was like, well 2 a.m.
Rym: It's too crowded.
Rym: So if I wait till like 4 a.m There's no way anyone's playing DDR.
Rym: Nope.
Rym: There's still a line.
Rym: good God people.
Rym: But really the only problem with mag fest now like the fundamental problem The only thing that I have to say mag fest you got to do something about this.
Rym: Is that there are way Way too few staff for that crowd.
Scott: You can't get more staff.
Scott: It's not possible as long as it from mag fest remains mag fest.
Rym: Hey, well, I think they could but it's not my place to say because I am NOT staff at mag fest I don't officially represent mag fest.
Rym: I am just a guest to mag fest.
Rym: I show up to do panels and have a good time.
Rym: But the fundamental problem however mag fest solves it is a thing that packs has got.
Scott: so saw it packs is not 24 hours.
Scott: It's not you guys has money.
Scott: It's not a non-profit But in order for mag fest to fix it It has to a stop being non-profit and B stop being 24 hours.
Rym: I do think there are other ways to solve it because it's not get a lot of money from a generous donor.
Rym: It's not just that they don't have enough staff because they have a lot more staff than people realize due to the nature of how they deploy their staff.
Rym: the staffer and the way the stat like their staff uniform and like the Staff are largely invisible.
Scott: They could make minor improvements in that regard.
Scott: But because it's 24/7 you need so many more staff.
Rym: But you need moves to those staff.
Scott: like the problem time seems to be right to do the job I think about like one enforcer at packs.
Scott: They do an eight hour shift each day, right?
Scott: Yeah, it's like okay at mag fest.
Scott: You need three people to do the same job.
Scott: Yep, because it's 24 hours packs in the back.
Rym: when packs went till 2 a.m.
Rym: We needed three full shifts Her day.
Scott: Yep, and that fast when it needs like five or six shifts to packs is three.
Rym: Yep, now they could get away with a lot less staff if they had the staff that they had were deployed a little more broadly and More importantly they have to be way more visible.
Rym: because a big part of why packs has so many fewer problems of harassment and nonsense going on is that Even if there aren't a ton of enforcers like in an area doing stuff There's always an enforcer within eyesight pretty much anywhere you go.
Scott: Like even if it's a little it's also less physically sprawling than All the packs is except for maybe West right.
Scott: but in West it's like any if you're in any of the official packs areas.
Scott: indoors There's enforcers about standing but there's.
Rym: but as part of this is even mag fest fault.
Rym: So for example mag fest did have a much better staff presence in the arcade Expo hall console free play like that area had a good as the main zone.
Rym: Yeah, it had a good staff presence and they'd handled things pretty well.
Rym: The problem is is one the general Convention Center area has if there are staff I literally never saw any and to Magfest is not responsible for having staff in the hotel lobby and bad shit was happening in that hotel lobby.
Scott: Well, the hotel lobby is just an you know an area that's connected to mag fest.
Scott: that has nothing to do with mag fest.
Rym: the hotel needs to be on top of that and Mag fest needs to bring the hotel accountable to deal with harassers and like though there are panels in the hotel part.
Rym: Oh, no I'm talking like the hotel lobby itself.
Rym: Magfest can't like the staff aren't gonna maintain order in that area.
Rym: The hotel seemed to be just turning a blind eye to it and there were harassing pieces of shit.
Rym: It was mostly like I want to say 16 to 20 year old white dudes who were just like didn't even have mag fest badges mostly and we're just harassing people.
Rym: And it didn't seem like anyone was on top of that.
Rym: But other than that mag fuzz was great and like every other area of mag fest Stepped up its game like the arcade started on time because most of the staff of mag fest are Curating and managing the content of mag fest.
Scott: It's like, you know, there's you go to a panel room and it's like yeah There's people they're running the panel room.
Scott: Yep, right you go to the arcade.
Scott: There's people.
Scott: they're fixing arcade machines to go to the tournaments as people.
Scott: They're running tournaments.
Scott: Yeah, you know go you go to a place in mag fest for this mag fest content and there are mag fest staff.
Scott: We're running that content there just aren't excess mag fest staff just walking around.
Scott: Yep, every mag fest staff member is like do it?
Scott: you go to the the museum.
Scott: There's mag fest staff in the museum running the museum.
Scott: There's no mag fest staff.
Scott: Just walking around the hallway being staff.
Scott: They don't have people for that.
Rym: Yep, and I think the shortest term solution would be mag.
Rym: This needs like ten people Per eight hours.
Rym: so spread that over 24/7 and make sure that you know feel like it breaks.
Rym: They need a dedicated group of people whose sole job is to wear a very visible IMA mag fest staff person shirts and just Walk slowly around and be visible.
Rym: that alone would probably solve a huge percentage of mag fest remaining problems that are visible to the attendees.
Rym: and in terms of the invisible problems who cares like Stack on staff just hides all that stuff and it's fine Right.
Rym: I remember all the problems attendees never found out about back when I ran everything at Connecticut Mm-hmm, and that's that's right.
Rym: That's how to do it.
Rym: But mag this was a good time.
Rym: We will definitely be back for super mag fest.
Scott: Well, he's running mag fest.
Rym: as long as mag fest stands we will be there because I see how long it stands.
Scott: What's the over under?
Scott: I love this shit.
Rym: I think mag fest can survive the long run Mm-hmm.
Rym: I think it's the thing that the biggest danger to mag fest is probably beyond mag fest control and it's the same thing.
Rym: That's a danger to all nerd stuff big mass shooting big Incident like the incident that happened at ALA that anime con that we're gonna talk about on our next Wednesday show the fire.
Rym: Yeah we're basically One of those shitty harassing dudes set a bunch of cars on fire in the con parking lot Because he was mad that a girl he was stalking wouldn't talk to him.
Rym: Essentially, yep shit like that is a big danger.
Rym: I'm really shocked.
Rym: incidents like that have not happened more often.
Rym: They do happen but big ones haven't happened as much as I expected.
Rym: it's gonna happen someday Mm-hmm, and I don't know what the con world as a whole is gonna do when it happens.
Rym: metal detectors are not the answer I point out.
Rym: this is one area where mag fest is objectively superior to packs.
Rym: mag fest does not have security theater or metal detectors and probably Neville never will Mm-hmm.
Rym: I really really am disappointed that packs has these bullshit metal detect.
Scott: Yeah, and you think it's like mag fest probably needs if it wasn't theater.
Scott: Yeah, if I could art you it's argue that mag fest needs it more than faxed us being half music festival half gaming con.
Rym: If any nerd thing needed metal detectors that were real, it's mag.
Rym: Yet mag fest is the one con that's doing it right.
Rym: if they're not gonna have they're not gonna have fake security.
Rym: They're gonna have no security or the right amount of security, but they're not gonna have fake security.
Rym: That's one area where packs I think has deeply failed us is the fake security.
Rym: Yeah, so there is so much game industry news centered Specifically around Activision Blizzard that we can't even talk about all of it.
Rym: There's too much and it's all evolving like a lot of it.
Rym: We don't even know all the details yet, right?
Scott: So the trigger I think is the Moreheim the CEO of Blizzard.
Scott: This was a while ago.
Scott: There's a lot.
Scott: he announced he was leaving but now he's actually Really left like he gone.
Scott: Yep, and I think because of that it's like, alright now The whole boat is gonna get turned over.
Scott: you got CFOs getting like kicked out like one or two of them.
Rym: Yeah for and it's like one of them ended up at Netflix.
Rym: It's not really like.
Scott: it's not some kind of shenanigans going on.
Rym: So it's not yet clear Why these people left?
Rym: Specifically if they left because they were leaving or they were pushed out, right?
Scott: Some suggestions though.
Scott: No proof because it's you know, HR private info that like the one who went to Netflix was like kicked out for bad.
Scott: You know behavior and it's like Netflix.
Scott: You shouldn't be you know, people were like, hey Netflix Why are you hiring this person who had was badly behaving right?
Scott: There were some suggestions of that.
Scott: who knows if it's true?
Scott: Yeah, no idea.
Scott: Don't call me with your lawsuits of Slander or whatever.
Rym: Yep, but the Moreheim leaving was interesting partly because Moreheim.
Rym: Yeah, Moreheim.
Rym: I've never met him.
Rym: I don't know really a lot about him.
Scott: He's the blizzard guy.
Scott: He's like the number one other guy, but basically the has been until now.
Scott: now He's not a blizzard guy.
Rym: all the statements about like his leaving are just super neutral generic.
Rym: Like he is leaving Period.
Scott: Yeah, really read what gaming sites have to say about it.
Scott: Now ESPN has to say maybe you'll get more info.
Rym: Yep, according to the filing submitted this week on Monday He's leaving the company on April 7th Like he's actually leaving right because when he announced his departure he was then.
Rym: but then this is typical in many companies He stuck around as an advisor for various, you know ease the transition, etc.
Rym: There was no news release accompanying the filing which simply read.
Rym: I'm gonna read the entire filing short as Previously disclosed.
Rym: on October 3rd 2018 Michael Moreham entered into an agreement with a blizzard Yeah, Moreheim pursuant to which he would provide strategic advice to the company in an advisory capacity.
Rym: Anyway, employment to the company will conclude on April 7th 2019.
Rym: Full stop, right?
Rym: That's it.
Scott: And also so in somewhat related news.
Scott: There was this Unemployee of blizzard who's working in the Hearthstone eSports department, right?
Scott: wrote this big like story of how awful their job was and how you know It drove them to be have so much stress and be depressed and contemplate suicide And all this stuff and our HR didn't do anything and how blizzard presents itself as one of those companies that's doing it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like yeah, we're inclusive.
Scott: Look at us.
Scott: We're not evil like those bad game companies But on the inside still is not near perfect.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: So it's just an account by the employee.
Scott: You can go read it for yourself and gather from it what you will.
Scott: I read the whole thing because it was actually written somewhat compelling way.
Rym: Yep I'm linking to the variety article, but there's a lot of articles about writing.
Scott: Okay, so that's also in here in the blizzard shakeup, right?
Scott: Yeah, and on top of that you got the newest news, which is sort of a double news.
Scott: news.
Scott: Number one is that you know Activision Blizzard.
Scott: they brought Bungie in when after it got booted out of Microsoft or left Microsoft or whatever Happened there.
Scott: Yeah, right and they got the so and then they went through all the trouble of getting destiny and to battle net.
Scott: So it's like you're looking there.
Scott: It's like Warcraft Starcraft our stone Destiny Right.
Scott: It's like what's that?
Scott: What is?
Scott: one of these is not like the other.
Scott: right.
Scott: and now They kicking did the bungee out.
Scott: It's like I went through all the trouble bringing it in.
Rym: What what's really happening?
Rym: Are they kicking bungee out or is bungee escaping Activision?
Scott: I don't know what's happening.
Scott: It seems like that, you know, there's so many shakeups going down there.
Scott: Who knows what the hell?
Rym: Yeah, I'm back.
Rym: We were talking about like bungee and what's their deal?
Scott: because as Scott said well You don't know bungee is the company that made marathon which was an FPS for the Mac.
Scott: all the people on Windows and DOS had Wolfenstein doom and quake right the Mac people had marathon.
Rym: I never played marathon.
Scott: marathon was Basically like slightly better than doom and nowhere near quake.
Rym: I literally never knew anyone who played marathon.
Scott: Anyone had a Mac had marathon because it wasn't on PC.
Rym: what?
Rym: and remember this is 1994. so who had a Mac in 94?
Scott: and then ironically the people who made the Mac FPS ended up going to Microsoft to make Halo the windows, you know xbox FPS Oddly enough before marathon there.
Rym: I didn't realize they made operation desert storm.
Scott: I never heard of it.
Scott: I mean I heard of the actual operation desert.
Rym: Yeah I thought it's not a game of the same name and a minotaur labyrinths of Crete and pathways into darkness.
Rym: 91 92 93 and then marathon 94. right marathon marathon.
Rym: So, I mean full disclosure.
Rym: I Never liked any game bungee made but I think they're good at like.
Rym: destiny and halo are very good at being What they are like if you like that kind of game.
Scott: I've also never.
Scott: I have also never been a fan of any bungee game other than marathon But I respect which I played because when I went to schools and summer camps They usually had max and they usually had lands and we could play a marathon in land mode.
Rym: See, I just remember when halo came out.
Rym: all I could think was wow That is really sad compared to every PC FPS that I already play.
Rym: Like what is this game?
Scott: and well people who only had consoles in the US mostly?
Scott: Yeah, who had played Goldeneye, which was worse than also When gold and I came out all I remember thinking was wow Goldeneye came out.
Scott: We had quake one quake two.
Scott: We're like, wow, what's up with that Goldeneye, but and then when Marathon came.
Scott: Oh, no when halo came out.
Scott: It's like we got quake three and counter-strike.
Scott: Yep What's with this halo garbage?
Rym: But if you didn't have if you weren't a PC gamer cuz back then PC gaming was not like even today.
Rym: It's not that accessible though back then.
Rym: It was really not accessible.
Scott: So at least in the u.s.
Scott: Other countries They only had PC gaming.
Rym: but basically like I don't like these games.
Rym: But these games are very important to gaming and are very well made in the US.
Scott: Yeah, I don't think anyone.
Scott: I don't think Bungie even today has like audience outside the u.s.
Scott: It's it's right.
Rym: what I've gathered even in places any is mod is pretty popular outside of the u.s.
Scott: Yeah, cuz I mean even in places that do consoles like Japan, I don't think they're playing but he wasn't good.
Scott: Ah, I don't know what that is.
Rym: You don't remember Oni.
Scott: Let's show me a picture.
Rym: You probably remember Oni.
Scott: I Don't know.
Rym: It's gonna remember Oni.
Scott: I don't know The box art.
Scott: I remember that wasn't.
Scott: it wasn't just a third-person action.
Scott: walk around hit things game.
Rym: Yeah, I never actually played it.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: But yeah, so a lot of the gaming press like the.
Rym: the undercurrent is that?
Rym: Activision has the worst reputation of the Activision Blizzard Bungie.
Scott: Why can't we go back to the Activision that published pitfall for the Atari 2600?
Scott: That's my Activision.
Scott: Yeah, that's the good Activision.
Rym: It was all down from there ever raid.
Scott: That's good Activision right there To.
Scott: even then it was still good good Activision yet.
Rym: Shockingly River Raid holds up better than you would expect.
Scott: But I mean Activision published mech warrior - right that was still good Activision in those days.
Scott: are 90s right mid 90s.
Scott: Yeah, these you know that activism went to poop.
Rym: So on top of all this Investors into Activision Blizzard.
Rym: full disclosure.
Rym: I own a. I own a decent amount of Activision Blizzard stock.
Rym: Investors are launching a possible fraud like there's a fraud investigation around the bungee split.
Scott: Why?
Scott: because they invested because bungee came in and how bungees leaving.
Rym: so there because I own some stock and I work in finance I don't want to comment on this at all.
Scott: Okay, so don't I'll comment.
Scott: So I guess they're accusing them of fraud to say I guess the argument would be I bought your stock Because you were getting.
Scott: you told me bungee was coming in Right, and now they're going out and now the stock price went down.
Scott: That's you.
Scott: you lied to me, right?
Scott: I didn't get what I was paying for.
Scott: I'm mad.
Scott: And so I'm suing.
Rym: Yep, essentially and variety variety had all the good articles about this, but there's an article about this Specifically.
Scott: you can read and they get and then when they go to court They'll probably like you said this during the earnings call and it's not true.
Scott: That's probably the kind of stuff that they're gonna go for right?
Rym: Yeah, you know, there's all sorts of nonsense.
Scott: This is in your annual report, but look reality bungee gonna bye-bye.
Scott: Yeah So it's about your stock based on false information.
Rym: This is the kind of stuff that happens when false or misleading info a bunch of Separate game companies each of which is good at what they do end up being together in the same company.
Rym: and all of this is happening in parallel with the Massive rise of eSports where actually I think Blizzard is doing the most prudent thing.
Scott: Well, they're actually so for hearthstone.
Scott: They completely restructured the way hearthstone eSports works this year Yeah, and drastically and they haven't even announced all of it yet.
Scott: It's gonna be nothing like it was last year, right?
Scott: Who knows what the hell's gonna happen with overwatch League?
Scott: Yeah, but oh also a side news.
Scott: Overwatch League did one thing a small thing but a big thing.
Scott: Small small in scope but large in effect.
Scott: now that no sports league.
Scott: I know of not even like NFL.
Rym: Oh, yeah Right, I had a Gomer Gator coming at me.
Scott: that is fantastic.
Scott: They made a single page that you can go to a web page.
Scott: That's just a web page a small thing.
Scott: that web page lists every instance of Overwatch League players being suspended reprimanded Punished why they were punished what their penalty was in, you know, the whole history of everything all the players have done bad.
Scott: Can you show me like a page that's publicly accessible?
Scott: That's like every NFL player all the fines and suspensions they got all year forever, right?
Scott: No, there's no such thing right.
Scott: show me the list of like all the hockey players who got fined or suspended this year.
Scott: How much what it was for right?
Scott: No, it doesn't exist right?
Scott: not eat?
Scott: Not at least not available to the general public.
Scott: I'm like one easy-to-use page, but for Overwatch League, they got it.
Scott: Good job a plus.
Rym: so along those lines something really funny happened and I'll say This will be the last news.
Rym: then we'll get into route that you're all waiting for.
Rym: So we one of our magfest panels like we put the YouTube video out.
Rym: It's there and it was the top 40 games You should play.
Rym: like the 40 games you should play and one of the ones we said was overwatch because it is the modern incarnation of like action quake 2 and weapons factory and TFC and like all those other games like it's the It's the iteration of that kind of game that is playable today.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: And this Gomer Gator came into my mentions.
Scott: hard Mm-hmm, and they're like just block them.
Rym: So because because they're because they followed the template and it was pretty funny.
Rym: but basically I discovered based on this Gomer Gator that a ton of Shitty people are really mad that they're.
Rym: they have been banned from overwatch because they were harassing people outside of overwatch.
Rym: Because blizzard in turn not in just an eSports thing But they will go after people like they're pro players who do shitty things Even outside of the game.
Scott: blizzard is doing a thing where you they're gonna.
Scott: I think it's a. I'm not sure if it's a hundred Percent implemented yet, but the story I heard was to go.
Scott: it you'll be watching say some overwatch League on Twitch Yep, and you want to chat in the chat room.
Scott: You have to have in order to chat in the chat room.
Scott: They got like a plug-in that will prevent you from chatting in the chat room unless you have your battle net account Connected to your twitch account with Oh off.
Scott: so if it means then you can chat in the chat room.
Scott: But if you say some racial slurs say for example, they can now.
Scott: they now have your battle net account.
Rym: They don't just ban you from the twitch chat.
Rym: Now.
Rym: They ban you from playing overwatch, right?
Scott: They could just ban you from battle net and all you lose all your blizzard games.
Scott: But won't people just like make a separate battle net free account because the accounts are free and use that for twitch chatting
Rym: Another actual
Scott: account where they bought a thousand dollars of skins and Crates when they not use that one for twitch chatting,
Rym: so I'm not a hundred assuming
Scott: they're intelligent.
Scott: But as best I can tell, you know, they're probably not that smart if they're racial slurring but you get the idea.
Rym: the best I can tell is that if you are banned and Blizzard identifies that you have another account and it's actually yours.
Rym: They'll ban them all they have to find them though.
Scott: Yeah, if I if I made a separate account called like Rym Yeah, and I use the VPN to go on Twitch How would they ever know that?
Scott: that's?
Scott: you know, what my real battle net account is.
Rym: Yep, but It appears to be working because a lot of gummer giddy shitheads are really really mad about this.
Scott: I mean you can get suspended from school if you're robbed liquor store.
Rym: But anyway things of the day.
Rym: so a GDQ 2019 just happened.
Rym: It was a. it was an a-plus hype.
Rym: I Really enjoyed the first.
Scott: the only thing the only negative thing I can say about the most recent a GDQ No, was that I was less impressed with the prizes.
Scott: They're usually there's some prizes that I want.
Scott: the grant I usually pay like I usually donate the amount to qualify for the grand prize, even though I know there's no chance to win.
Scott: I'm donating what do I write?
Scott: but because the grand prize is still something like man.
Scott: It would be cool to have that yo, right this year.
Scott: The grand prize was kind of admittedly amazing.
Scott: It was like this replica Master Sword like to scale plus Hylian shield.
Scott: that was like super legit like Wow And definitely was more valuable than the amount you had to donate to qualify which I think was 250 But I only donated a hundred.
Scott: cuz like.
Scott: I really don't need that master short.
Scott: if I got the master What was I gonna do with it?
Scott: I'd probably eBay and donate the money.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: it's like what I'm gonna do with a fucking master sword not yourself with it, right?
Scott: It's like they didn't have you know in the past It would.
Scott: I would always be like, ooh, I want that this time.
Rym: Yeah, but Scott Imagine a younger you where the want swords meter is still really high.
Scott: Thankfully young Scott did not have two hundred and fifty dollars to donate Only maybe like fifty dollars, but one of the AGQ 2019 speed runs stood out above and beyond me and Rym.
Scott: So I've side haven't seen all the runs.
Scott: obviously there could be a better one, but me and Rym of the runs Unanimously agree.
Rym: Lord my best run of the week was my comment appears to be one of the top comments because basically Right after because I didn't watch this one live, but I caught it live and then I watched it again.
Rym: I caught the tail end of it live.
Scott: show someone else how good it was.
Rym: and as soon as they YouTube I watched it.
Rym: I've watched it two and a half times now.
Scott: Well, you watch it more than me Time more.
Rym: my comment on YouTube on this video will say literally everything needs to be said.
Rym: He is the most entertaining runner in AGDQ history, that's true.
Rym: quote there ain't no quiet time in this run.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: and quote god damn So big up shoutouts to grandpa and grandma.
Scott: Genesis, dr.
Rym: Fatbody has injected a new level of hype and Just amazing commentary.
Rym: He is.
Scott: It's not just that he is right cuz you I could go to GDQ and be hype.
Scott: You know, I have that skill at least to some degree.
Scott: maybe not as much as the master fatbody but I could do that.
Scott: He had the hype and he was pulling off the sub pixel frame.
Scott: perfect tricks left and right Yep.
Rym: and meanwhile You know cuz a DDQ like there's a culture and the culture up to this point all the runs have a similar cadence.
Rym: like they're doing The thing the couch is talking and then the runner will be like, all right time for the quiet.
Scott: And the thing is when the run started he brings out this enormous couch full of people and I got this vibe of oh It's like one of those anime panels with too many people on it.
Scott: He's even got a guy on a webcam on a laptop on the couch.
Scott: He's busy on the virtual couch and I'm like, oh no, I'm like, I'm like, oh, oh.
Scott: and then within five seconds I'm like, oh, yeah.
Rym: Oh, yeah He takes a slower strat at one point to hit something because I do this for my little.
Scott: he crashes the game Because it's funny because he just to show you that it's a thing even though it costs time and then goes back to the beginning Level select screen.
Rym: it was the best balance.
Rym: I cuz.
Rym: I do enjoy runs that are like a Super technical like for our run where the the commenter is literally.
Rym: just let's explain this glitch.
Rym: Let's explain this sub pixel nonsense.
Rym: This run was the perfect balance of amazing display of skill coupled with amazingly entertaining Situation.
Scott: I would say if you want someone to like introduce them to like.
Scott: why do it?
Scott: why does everyone watch this GDQ?
Scott: Why do they raise two million dollars every year?
Scott: What's the deal with this?
Scott: This is your first run to go to?
Scott: Yeah, go for this run.
Scott: the second run out if you.
Scott: if not this one.
Scott: there was one.
Scott: I don't know if it was the last summer games done quick.
Scott: I think it was.
Scott: if not, it was the one before.
Scott: that was definitely last year where they did a strider run.
Rym: Oh Yes,
Scott: Strider and the guy doing it had never done it before but someone was sitting next to him teaching him how to do it And this dude he was a speedrunner but it never speedrun any a Strider in his life and They taught him the speedrun and then made him do it himself and it's like a five-minute run.
Scott: So it's not a big deal and that is like the perfect intro for anyone watching to the world of speedrunning.
Scott: Yeah, and like how do you learn a speedrun?
Scott: How do you do it?
Rym: Right like imagine if up until this point like you go to the PGA Tour and everyone gets quiet on the important putt and then Someone walks up and they're about to golf and they're just as good as everyone else like they're a contender and they turn around.
Rym: They're like everybody allowed before I make this putt.
Scott: Yeah, everyone is good.
Rym: Hey gonna make the putt This speed you gotta watch this.
Scott: I think the rules of golf actually disallowed that.
Rym: yeah, you probably but dr Fatbody has elevated the bar of AGDQ commentary.
Rym: Mm-hmm.
Rym: So what do you got?
Rym: What's your thing of the day?
Scott: So, you know how y'all, you know go to museum right and they're like, oh such and such is restored, right?
Scott: They restore stuff at museums, right all kinds of old artworks.
Rym: Oh, that's your thing of the day.
Rym: I saw that tab open.
Rym: I didn't realize you sent it to me cuz I had it open myself already cuz I was saving it to be a day later, you know, you know Restoring, you know historic artworks, you know sculptures paintings, right?
Scott: But it's like you unless you do that or unless you're in the museum business.
Scott: It's like wait a minute.
Scott: I actually had no idea how they restore a thing like right how what what do you actually do?
Scott: Right, like what is the physical process?
Scott: What happens?
Scott: Here's a guy.
Scott: He works at Baumgartner restoration.
Scott: I think it's like his company and his job is restoring artworks and There's a lot of videos on his channel showing him restoring mostly paintings.
Rym: and after I found the video you're linking to I watched Like ten of his videos.
Rym: They're really good.
Scott: But this one is a really good one because the painting is a painting on a piece of paper that is glued to a piece of wood and is ridiculously old and grody.
Scott: and he You're like, what are you gonna do?
Scott: like imagine me trying to restore this painting like what do I do clean it with?
Rym: He's like, I gotta I gotta move the wood.
Scott: I gotta get the paper off the wood.
Scott: It's just like imagine I can't even get a sticker off something.
Scott: I bought an Amazon Right.
Scott: This guy's gonna get a piece of paper with a painting on it.
Scott: That's glued to an ancient piece of wood Right.
Scott: Anyway, so he's got this painting which is the assassination of Archimedes, which is an awesome frickin painting actually And he takes it from its grody state and restores it to a magnificent state.
Scott: is It's a lot like watching those knife sharpening videos and you get that same feeling of like ah the cleaning and the restoring ah, but also a fascinating explanation of the process and what goes into it and A plus to this whole channel.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: One of the other ones I watched It's the.
Rym: I think it's the restoration of the Mother Mary, which is another one that's on wood But he doesn't.
Rym: he wants to leave it on the wood for reasons.
Rym: He talks about why but Anyway, he starts and he's like so I'm starting with the face and normally professionals do the face last because it's the most important part.
Rym: But this video will be more entertaining if I start with the face and also I'm really good at this So that's not gonna be a problem.
Scott: Also he has to like touch up the paint and he's like, yeah We got this erasable paint.
Scott: It's like.
Scott: I'm like what he's like if someone in the future decides that you know I didn't do a good job because like he's like obviously not trying to paint over any of the.
Scott: the paint.
Rym: It's not like that famous Jesus that the lady messed up.
Rym: real bad, right?
Scott: And he's you know, he's just trying to fill in the blanks as closely to what the real artist did right, you know Taking instructions from the person who owns the thing who's paying for him his services, right?
Scott: So it seems like the bike.
Scott: he's like.
Scott: I always use erasable paint that way.
Scott: if someone buys this painting in the future And then doesn't like what I did they can erase it and do a different different thing.
Scott: So the theme without without erasing the paint from the original original.
Rym: I want to try a new thing Grebel's style the.
Rym: So regardless of what our things that they are I think we can always come up with a theme based on what we both pick.
Rym: the theme this week was or this episode Masters displaying the height of their craft In the meta moment the book club book that we haven't gotten there.
Rym: cuz we've been busy as 2001 a Space Odyssey.
Scott: I said we would read it and I lied.
Scott: I was wrong.
Scott: We did not read it.
Scott: Haven't read up any pages of it since I said that I've been too busy.
Rym: Stay tuned.
Scott: way too much shit going down.
Rym: None of you read it either.
Rym: I know you didn't.
Scott: Someone has someone.
Scott: the thing is I feel like people are either.
Scott: I don't feel like there's people like us listening.
Scott: I feel like the listeners who care about book club read it right away and listeners who don't care about book club Don't read.
Scott: I found a lot of their bed.
Scott: The people I've talked a lot of people like us who read.
Scott: eventually people Don't.
Rym: the people who really care about our book club don't tend to check what we're doing now and read it because they know our History.
Rym: instead they'll go into the archive of the book club.
Rym: pick a book that look good read it and then listen to that episode.
Scott: That's good because at least you're reading.
Scott: as long as you read books you get an A+.
Scott: if you don't read you get an F-.
Scott: There's not like a lot of in-between.
Scott: even if you read eventually like we do you still get the A+.
Rym: So we were just at magfest.
Rym: We did three panels there.
Rym: one of them, which is a brand new panel is already on YouTube.
Rym: I'm gonna link to it.
Rym: You can just go watch it right now.
Rym: Wow The other two panels will be on YouTube at some point in the near future.
Scott: That's good.
Scott: We're gonna record at least a panel at PAX South and put that online.
Rym: Yep, I don't think we're gonna record learn and win Carcassonne because we already did that.
Rym: We already did it.
Rym: We don't need another video of it.
Scott: No, we'll just concentrate on teaching Carcassonne.
Rym: Yep, but that one's online.
Scott: So also We were supposed to do this towards the end of last year and I told Rym about it months in advance But he still didn't make time even though I was on vacation all week.
Scott: So after we got back from magfest no or just before yeah after he got back from magfest We recorded judging anime by its cover which somehow this show has lasted like over a year.
Scott: I guess we actually it's really fun to do.
Scott: we're keep doing it even though it's you know, whatever.
Scott: But yeah, we did it for the winter at season of anime.
Scott: There's already like two episodes out of most of the shows for the season of anime, but we haven't seen any of them.
Scott: So we still we're doing a pre affair pre judging and I guess that's kind of okay because once I upload it I've only got a little bit of work to do.
Scott: Hopefully I'll do it tonight and get uploaded tonight if I can if not tomorrow No.
Scott: and then Once that's up You will be able to see our pre judges of the anime coming out this season and there's some good stuff coming - they'll be like Two or two maybe even three episodes for you to just watch right away.
Scott: If you something we talked about sounds good.
Rym: And last and least well not least this weekend.
Rym: The reason there's gonna be no show on Thursday We are gonna be at Pac South where we mention that already we are going to do two panels But specifically the new one.
Scott: So we're doing learn to win Carcassonne.
Rym: We talked about that and we're doing a new one nostalgia versus game design.
Scott: It's Rym's idea.
Scott: I'm not too hyped on it, but I get a free badge.
Scott: 40 games was also Rym's idea and I wasn't too hyped on it.
Rym: I was hyped on it.
Scott: Yeah, you're hyped on anything.
Rym: I there have been panels.
Rym: I've not been hyped on anyway.
Scott: I really want to do.
Scott: my games are harmful panel, but no one in for PAX East.
Scott: All right, let's do it But big stage.
Rym: so at PAX South we will be doing two panels so they will be our fiftieth and 51st packs panels and it will both be on panels total.
Rym: my birthday job panels total.
Rym: So I Have the list of all of them.
Scott: everyone, please bring edible birthday gifts for Rym that I should eat.
Scott: Yes that I will eat them.
Scott: Yes, and now Rym will not eat them.
Scott: Bring a cake a birthday cake that says Rym and has what 37.
Scott: I want to say number 37 on in 37 candles and then I will eat the cake.
Rym: I feel like we have done.
Rym: I want to say 370 panels total.
Scott: ever so you can watch a GeekNights panel every day for a year and not run out.
Rym: It's terrifying because remember there were time there were old days where we go to an Otakon and do like a panels.
Rym: There's one ConnectiCon where we did like 20.
Scott: So yeah Go and find us on the internet.
Scott: if you maybe discovered us at magfest or something or who knows or discovered us through YouTube I don't know.
Scott: go go to Google.
Scott: type GeekNights.
Scott: You will find us and our content on every single website that has content.
Scott: We even got an Instagram which I keep saying I'm gonna start using it and I forget we even have a G+ even though That's going away imminently.
Scott: We don't have that anymore.
Scott: We had a tumblr - I stopped updating the tumblr and the Facebook updates automatically, but even though you should probably delete your Facebook that's the only reason I don't delete my Facebook is so that page doesn't disappear and Even the Instagram is owned by Facebook.
Scott: I'm pretty sure we got Twitter's.
Scott: We're most active on Twitter and our forum.
Scott: you should go to and sign up.
Scott: in our forum There are no Nazis.
Rym: I'm pretty sure the yeah There are.
Rym: our forum is rocking and there are no Nazis.
Rym: if you.
Rym: that's far.
Rym: if you try
Scott: to apply to the forum and get rejected apply again and just make sure when you write Your reason for applying you write something that makes me know that you're a human who listens to GeekNights and not you know Robot from Russia,
Rym: yep, so and our tumblr is probably flagged as porn and gonna be deleted.
Scott: Anyway, I want to have it in my pixel.
Scott: meet tumblr.
Rym: I'm pretty sure that's also poor.
Scott: All right, what people waiting for we're now?
Scott: we're gonna talk about route for the rest of the show.
Rym: Yep, Scott has finally played route.
Scott: Well, I played it many times.
Scott: I played it at least three or four times.
Rym: Yep, I've played it a bunch of times.
Scott: I can't remember was I've either been green twice.
Scott: if I've played it four times I was green twice.
Scott: if I played it three times I was green then I was the raccoon and then I was the otters.
Rym: I've been the woodland Alliance and I've been the birds multiple times.
Scott: I get the idea of how the birds work though I don't know the super details because I haven't been the birds.
Rym: the birds are so fun.
Scott: I only vaguely get the idea of how the cats work because I've seen I've played against the cats every time but I've never been the cats and I know nothing about the lizard folk.
Rym: I Didn't even read the rules about the lizard folk.
Scott: I know nothing about the lizard folk other than that.
Scott: There are lizard folks.
Scott: So here's the deal and that's supposedly they're not.
Rym: that good route is the new hotness.
Rym: It came out last year in 2018 and it like sold out immediately.
Rym: It keeps getting reprinted.
Scott: It's unplugged It's sold out even sold out of the raccoon plushies.
Rym: Yep the vague the vagrant plushies vagabond route got Real real big and popular in a hurry.
Scott: It is popular big time.
Rym: Yeah, and that's interesting for a number of reasons because if I had to the before we talk about what root is Like.
Rym: you have to understand that the designer of root is Cole Worrell And if you don't know who that is from letter games.
Rym: all the other games that Cole Worrell is done are the ridiculous weird nonsense historical games that we play almost as Experiments like John company or an infamous traffic which Scott hasn't played.
Rym: but you should Pax Pamir which I haven't.
Scott: Oh, what are the Pax ones?
Rym: Yeah, you played Pax Pamir.
Scott: I think no, I've paid Pax Porphyriana.
Rym: Oh porphyriana.
Rym: Yeah Anyway, those kinds of games old
Scott: crusty war games that you would only expect Someone with a long beard and a large belly and a broken chair to take off the shelf at the game store
Rym: but not the
Scott: ones that are on the shelf near the Napoleon's and the the Rommel's Right in the back.
Rym: They're not war games.
Rym: Like here's a bunch of chips that represent the Rommel's.
Rym: these are more like here is a detailed simulation of the opium trade in China and you play European shitbags who are trying to literally buy fancy hats to increase their social standing and the terrible cost to China.
Rym: Right and the opium trade.
Scott: basically any game that this person made other than root is something you would never get on any table Of normal non crusty gore gamer.
Scott: You know grog nard players our friend Chris will bring these to the table and I love these games But they are an acquired taste right mostly because as we've now learned the theme of them is crusty.
Scott: Root is just another one of those games.
Scott: It isn't really mechanically different at all.
Scott: It's just that they put cute animal forest critters on it instead of putting crusty old war generals on it Or crusty old.
Rym: literally there's no war involved.
Rym: It's just training opium, right?
Rym: So this game root is a combination of a highly political Extremely asymmetric kind of war game where literally every player is playing with completely different rules.
Scott: There's.
Scott: there are a few rules you share in common with other players, right?
Scott: Which is that?
Scott: like you're just trying to get to 30 points?
Scott: It's like the default victory condition get to 30 points and win.
Scott: Yeah but you and the default rules are like if you Do something on the board like every piece of cardboard on the board you you hit gives you like a point.
Scott: Yeah, and that's like true for everyone.
Scott: But like everyone has similar like combat fighting rules because you can just fight your dudes.
Rym: But like one faction gets points by building things on the board another faction gets points by just selling things in their shop.
Rym: Yep, another faction gets points.
Rym: They're just.
Rym: they're not a faction.
Scott: They're one dude Just one raccoon wandering around in the woods and they get points for helping other people or potentially just fucking Murdering people in the night or just getting items.
Rym: Yep One of the factions is a lizard called.
Rym: I don't know what they do.
Rym: I've never read their rules.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: So it's it so like everyone's playing with these completely different rules.
Scott: It's like you're playing your own game.
Scott: Yeah, right You just happen to be on the same board and the only thing you share in common with the other players Is that board.
Scott: we're like.
Scott: the rules are all the same.
Scott: Right like that raccoon guy.
Scott: It's like you're at your whole.
Scott: your whole game is controlling this one, dude But if you fight you're a dude, yep now the game's not super complex.
Rym: Most of the people who say it's complex have just never actually played a complex game before.
Scott: I think it's complex for normal people.
Rym: It's complex for normal people a lot.
Scott: It is definitely above the heads of a lot of people but it is not above the heads of someone who was a nerd who?
Scott: Can listen to a GeekNights, but I've also realized having played it You can go to a gaming convention.
Scott: it is not above your head.
Rym: Well, here's the more important thing.
Rym: The reason so many people think it's so complex is that it is a very difficult game to teach Simply by the fact that it's so asymmetric.
Scott: Yes, you teach this game.
Scott: you have to teach like if you got three players, yeah It's like you teach three games.
Scott: you to teach someone how to be the the the woodland alliance.
Scott: You gotta teach someone how to be the cats and someone had to be the birds.
Rym: So my advice to you if you want to play this game is to regardless of any other circumstance even if you don't like to read the goddamn rules yourself to understand how to play and Force the people you want to play with to read the rules themselves.
Scott: and the other thing is that once you've learned one or two of the the You know the.
Scott: yeah Yeah, I was able when I played the otters.
Scott: I'd never played them before.
Scott: I didn't get a new rules explanation.
Scott: All I did was pick up the otter card, which is this the trading otters the river traders.
Scott: They sell stuff right.
Scott: and I just started reading the card.
Scott: I had already played the game two or three times as other Races and reading this card just reading it I 90% knew how to play the otters because I had played a few times before and I can read Right, and then I just had.
Scott: I only needed an explanation of these details That I probably could have got if I had read every single word on the card instead of just reading You know the major important words in the card.
Rym: So we've got this like asymmetric political like kind of crazy game But it's skinned with the cutest animal art my favorite art in the whole game.
Rym: Okay?
Rym: I'm curious.
Rym: is the card with the bunny Bank bunny Bank the bun the better Borough Bank?
Scott: Yes, the bunny Bank as the cutest bunny inside the bank is the bunny that's in the bank is like hey money I think for me.
Rym: It's the one.
Scott: it's the given a second carrots.
Rym: birdie bindle is really good already been on my bed But there's one.
Scott: not a lot of bad art at all.
Scott: But there's one card and the people's are way good.
Scott: all the meeples are way good, too.
Rym: It's the rabbit ambush card where the rabbit rise the rabbits rise up and kill all the troops.
Rym: Cuz it's just these really cute little rabbits like hey, but there were a little cloaks and they've just got this big fucking bomb.
Rym: Yeah This game is so cute.
Scott: So alright, so that's another the race.
Rym: Let's talk about the real deal with the game.
Rym: Let's talk about like how it plays out, right?
Scott: So you got this map and the maps depending on which races you got in the game Right that you're gonna deploy you dudes onto the map Right, and then you're gonna take turns and on your turn based on who you are.
Scott: Your turn is completely different.
Scott: Yeah, right what you do on your turn?
Scott: Usually you have some sort of you know Actions you can take of various kinds and different ways of paying to take the actions You know.
Scott: any actions usually involve moving dudes fighting, you know getting stuff there.
Scott: You have cards and the cards are multi-purpose cards have text on them.
Scott: that does stuff.
Scott: you can like build Cards, you can use cards to profess to pay costs of certain actions.
Rym: Oh, the screenshot has both birdie bindle and better bureau bank on it, right?
Scott: You can get some cards, you know by doing certain actions.
Scott: Sometimes draw a card will be an action right and you got to pay for those actions using various resources.
Scott: Sometimes cards are the resource used to pay for the action.
Scott: Yep, right.
Scott: So, of course, you know everything I said was super vague because every race is super different, right?
Rym: So the high level like we'll go through the races and kind of explain their high level deal, right?
Scott: So the first one you got to learn about is the red one the maquis de cat.
Scott: the maquis de cat Which is like he's basically like the Empire right?
Scott: He starts with cats all over the board.
Rym: Yeah, he's got his whole economy going on.
Scott: He's got this giant castle, right?
Scott: He's like deploying like all these wooden structures around and you know building stuff.
Scott: I'm not sure how the cat wins cuz never been the cat.
Rym: Okay, whenever I see that it's hard for the cat to win when everyone's skilled, right?
Scott: It's like whenever I've played I've only played against the cat and the cat's always been there.
Scott: and the feel I get from the cat Is they start spread out all over the board.
Rym: They start strong and slowly decline.
Scott: They slowly decline as basically everyone else is playing races that come on to the board Right, like all the birds start in one nest and spread out right.
Scott: the cat starts out like a blanket over the whole thing And then everyone rises up and pushes them back, but they're still pretty strong because they're all you know, they're the marquee They're like the Empire.
Scott: so they still.
Scott: they participate in a lot of combat a lot of making sure other people don't win Right while also building up resources and doing whatever their thing is.
Rym: So imagine like a big Empire that starts strong is beset by all sides.
Rym: think like Rome almost And slowly collapsing, but they can win by consolidating their power Holding all these enemies at bay and making the red alliances to eventually.
Scott: they definitely need alliances because if everyone goes against them they got Nothing, I guess it's true of anything in a political game.
Scott: demo.
Rym: weasel in the chat points out That's the card we all forgot about.
Rym: mouse in a sack might be the cutest card.
Scott: That is a good one.
Scott: I forgot all about that car is a good one.
Rym: So the birds are sort of like the antagonist like imagine.
Rym: the story is the cats are the Empire and there is Decline.
Scott: the birds are like the elf and for the elves.
Rym: right there the ancient proud race.
Scott: right there They're hidden away, and there's one spot in love laureate.
Scott: And then they got out of the world they got angered and they then they bust out.
Rym: yeah imagine like they're the old Empire That's trying to come back out of the scene now that the cat Romans are in decline.
Rym: right.
Rym: so their deal is they start in One spot and they expand and expand.
Scott: they have a shit ton of birds in that one spot.
Rym: So you've got this bird Empire and this cat Empire.
Rym: They're at war and that is the.
Rym: the primary crux of the game is the war between these two.
Scott: you don't have to.
Scott: you could play Without either of these two things, but in most all the games I've played both of them that you look.
Rym: in the rulebook depending on the number of players There's a list of the options that work.
Rym: Yeah, like mean you could this many players have the birds the cats and any of these other factions.
Scott: It's best if you obey those right.
Rym: it doesn't really.
Scott: Vagabonds is not gonna be too great.
Rym: depend if you have a lot of players You could have two different vagabonds two different raccoons that are independently wandering around stabbing people.
Scott: Yeah, but like if you only have two raccoons and a trading company That's gonna be a weird weird game, so the crux of the game is in the woodland.
Rym: in the woods There's this big war going on between the birds and the cats.
Rym: the third main faction is the woodland alliance.
Scott: These are basically the cute mice.
Rym: These are the forest communists right.
Scott: so what they do is They start not on the board at all really.
Rym: They're just the normal woodland citizens.
Rym: They're the.
Rym: they're the bunnies and the foxes but all the other people living in the woods and they get points by placing.
Scott: Basically when other people do stuff right they get these cards.
Scott: other people's cards end up in the mouse Stack on the mouse card.
Scott: the mouse the mouse playing mat right like your other people's cards And they use them will end up over there because they got to pay the mice and then the mice will put.
Scott: Use those cards to perform actions, and they'll put their little fists in different cities on the board like the little little you know in Insurrection fists.
Scott: so the might think of what are they actually called?
Scott: I forget the actual name for the woodland alliance.
Scott: No that name for the fist of the sympathy Wars going.
Scott: that city is now sympathetic to the rebellion.
Rym: the war is going on.
Rym: the more warring nonsense is happening between the birds And the cats the more sympathy the woodland alliance the rebels who are trying to kick everybody out right.
Scott: so the main action That you know.
Scott: they put these fist tokens out on the board and they get a lot of points And then they put little like you know a little bases out and they get a lot of points for that too.
Scott: And so they can win just like putting these tokens out.
Scott: so everyone else has to constantly quell the rebellion.
Scott: So and if you don't they will win.
Rym: so though so This is how the game gets political.
Rym: the cats and the birds are at war with each other But they will both sort of tacitly agree to maintain martial law in like the non disputed Territories.
Rym: so the woodland alliance can't get a foothold right.
Rym: so I got a war with Scott.
Rym: But we both have to while we're warring with each other keep the communists down right.
Scott: and what happens is it's like okay?
Scott: I got a fist here and a little base here.
Scott: I'm playing green, but there's a whole bunch of troops here from the birds.
Scott: well, okay I can't.
Scott: they're gonna.
Scott: not only can I not do much about it But they can totally destroy my stuff and get points and jump right.
Scott: But let's say I get my fist up and there's not a lot of guys There is not too strong.
Scott: now I can basically rise up in that place and kick ass.
Scott: so suddenly suddenly There's a bunch of mice on the board in that spot because they revolted.
Rym: the last game I played I was the birds and Chris was the cats and I was like.
Rym: suddenly the woodland alliance busted out.
Scott: real bad Yeah, so we you cannot let that happen too often otherwise They're just gonna.
Rym: So we basically had a truce to go fuck up the wood commune the woodland communists Before they presented a threat to all of us.
Rym: so we had to pause our war.
Rym: yeah for the greater good.
Scott: So then you got the vagabond.
Rym: so the vagabond is we've got three big warring factions And the vagabond is just one raccoon.
Scott: literally you get one token that you move around the map individually.
Scott: You're just a cute record or you're like an adventurer But actually you're not.
Scott: you can choose a sort of a subclass when the game starts.
Scott: Tinkerer is op.
Scott: not even gonna lie it just is.
Scott: I didn't even know it was op.
Scott: and then I looked through all that I was The one time I played vagabond.
Scott: I was looking through all the different choices, and I was like I Kind of want to be this one for theme, but tinkerer seems strong to me.
Scott: And then I googled it like which one is best.
Scott: and it was like tinker Oh my god, and I was like oh, I guess I was right.
Scott: Let me be tinker.
Scott: So the tinker is about making stuff right.
Scott: so the way that the vagabond works is you have all these items right now other?
Scott: People can craft items in in the game for various purposes.
Scott: they get victory points for crafting items.
Scott: But if you get a vagabond in the game suddenly the items do stuff Every all the items the vagabond has let them perform actions.
Scott: the more items They have the more actions they can perform right and do stuff.
Scott: They got hammers.
Scott: they can craft things and make their own items.
Scott: if they got Swords they can stab people and do attack actions if they got you know the boot they can move around better, right?
Scott: It's all the you know.
Scott: they start with a few items But there's more that they get.
Scott: some of them they get by going around and questing and some of them they get by trading with other players.
Scott: also The main way the vagabond gets victory points is not just by building and getting these items.
Scott: It's actually just by helping other people and other people can't refuse your help.
Scott: You just help them if you want to.
Scott: right you can.
Scott: you can deal with them I guess, but I just went around helping people.
Scott: yep And when you help people you get mad victory points.
Scott: so that you got this.
Scott: you're in it like a sole adventurer Whether you're a tinker or and you know a fighter or whatever you are.
Scott: you just one little raccoon token.
Scott: you go around the board And you know you do stuff to help people and you get points for that.
Scott: and if you can do more helping Before anyone else can win then you can win.
Rym: so think about this.
Rym: You're just this one little raccoon wandering around in the midst of this giant cataclysmic war.
Rym: You're just trying to make your way And you're trying to help everybody enough to where no one quite wins the war and then eventually you come out on top yep.
Scott: So then we got this the otters, so I played the otters most recently.
Scott: I came super close to winning.
Scott: I could have won if I would add just like a couple more victory points here.
Scott: there couldn't quite pull it off if I would Have micromanaged and fought a little harder.
Scott: I could have gotten two points somewhere right.
Scott: I could have built a card or something right yeah.
Rym: But at the same time if you'd been doing better I was gonna just pause my war.
Scott: you had no idea that I had that many points in the pocket.
Scott: Yeah, I did.
Scott: I put out.
Scott: I pulled out like what like eight points in the last turn like BAM Yeah, but I could have destroyed basically all of your things.
Scott: Yeah, but if I was you would you.
Scott: I was ten points away from winning.
Scott: if I was eight away from winning you would have destroyed all my things.
Scott: Come on anyway.
Scott: The otters are traders.
Scott: There's a river on the board and you can't really.
Scott: the river doesn't really mean anything unless the otter Means a little bit, but if the otters are in the game the river means a lot.
Scott: the otters live along the river.
Scott: They can help people travel on the river.
Scott: They can travel on the river.
Scott: kind of right.
Rym: basically the otters put up their prices like hey It'll cost you X to use.
Scott: the otters have various services that they sell.
Scott: the services that they sell are like river traveling.
Scott: They sell the cards in their hand face outwards on a little thing and they set those cards are for sale.
Scott: You can't deny some.
Scott: you set a price every turn.
Scott: you set your prices for your services.
Scott: But if someone wants to buy one of your cards, you can't say no they buy them, right?
Scott: And what's the other service you have that you sell?
Scott: I think oh, it's fight It's we fight with you.
Scott: You can hire us as mercenaries and we'll fight with you.
Rym: So if the otters have some people on the board and I need like say they're on a place and there's some cats there and on The birds I got to deal with the cats.
Rym: I could just pay the otters and now the I'm the otters.
Scott: I just leave some otters standing around in a city that I know is gonna have some warring and Someone else comes along and my services cost whatever.
Scott: I set the price at that turn.
Scott: Someone pays the price.
Scott: suddenly the otters get their Spears and join the fight, right?
Scott: So the thing is about the otters.
Scott: is that when you pay the otters you pay them with your own dudes.
Scott: You you don't pay them with like money or cards your dudes that are not on the board right now Just like your wooden meeples.
Scott: you give them to the otter player, right?
Scott: So it's like, okay I want to buy a card from you.
Scott: Mr.
Scott: Otter.
Scott: All right, give me three of your dudes that aren't on the board Okay.
Scott: Well, first of all, your dude supply starts running low.
Scott: if you do this, right?
Scott: You only have a limited number of dudes.
Rym: So for example in our last game The cats got kind of desperate and they gave you basically all their dudes to pull off a big play Which means even if they want to put a bunch of dudes on the board?
Scott: Well, I'm holding on to those dudes too bad.
Scott: And then when you're the otters and you want to perform actions you spend the dudes that you've got Not only the dudes other people gave you but also your own dudes.
Scott: if no one gave you any dudes you basically get two of Your own dudes into your into your purse for spending Right, and then it's sort of like buying nothing from yourself for two dudes automatically, right?
Scott: So you're gonna be able to do stuff and you spend these dudes in various actions.
Scott: some actions that you might perform just sort of put the dudes into a holding pen and then they go back to the purse next turn and Sometimes when for certain actions you actually have to give the dudes back to the player they came from in order to spend the dudes.
Rym: so basically imagine like I don't know Corsica or Venice you know, there's a big war going on and you're outside like not in the forest.
Rym: You're like, hey There's a war going on and you slide in along the river and start selling weapons to everybody and then eventually Everybody fighting the war owes you so much money that you are in fact control of the content in control of the country.
Scott: The primary way you score victory points when you're the otters is you know the same way everyone else's scores victory points.
Scott: but the number one way is Building trading posts which give you mad points when you put them out on the board.
Scott: So I basically and building a trading post cost you other people's dudes, right?
Scott: You just like every all your other actions building a trading post cause dudes.
Scott: So I basically had a bunch of dudes and it was getting close to the end of the game And I put out like three or four trading posts all at once.
Scott: I got a pile of points and was too short of winning.
Scott: if I just gotten two points earlier in the game Boom, I would have had it.
Rym: but you only had that capability because the cats who were desperate Spent a ton of money with you.
Scott: Well, they right they would have had to either right it They would have still done that if I had two more victory points, right?
Scott: I Don't know.
Scott: Yeah, maybe they.
Scott: maybe you would have looked carefully, but that's the thing the game.
Scott: But also if I looked carefully I would have had two more points by then.
Rym: So basically what this comes down to is it's a pretty abs like well abstracted asymmetric kind of realistic war gamey game With cute animals and the theme works really well and the game is just really fun to play.
Rym: It doesn't even take that long Mm-hmm.
Scott: Yeah, it's like people were so hype about root when it first came out and I was like my mood on.
Scott: It was like I like the cute animals You know, but I'm not unlike.
Scott: why is everyone so excited?
Scott: How great can it be?
Rym: And I saw other people who weren't our friends playing it and their games were taking like four hours, right?
Scott: You know, I was like.
Scott: I was like, all right.
Scott: I got to see what the deal is obviously right and then I played it once and I was like, all right.
Scott: And then I played it again and I was like, all right.
Scott: The second playthrough is when you see the fun of this game and then the third time I'm like, you know I think you know you.
Scott: the first few games of it that I played it was sort of like, all right I'll play root the the time I played most recently with the otters.
Scott: Yeah That was the first time where I was like bust out the root Scott.
Rym: wait till you try the birds Next time we play.
Scott: I don't really want to be the birds.
Scott: They have that whole failing thing.
Rym: So here's an example of like a detail because I played the birds twice and I really like the birds.
Rym: They're fun.
Rym: Their deal is that they're a Free so you choose a leader depending and there's two.
Rym: there's four things you can do on your turn.
Rym: You can recruit like make more birdies.
Rym: you can move your birdies around you can fight people with the birdies and you can build stuff and Depending on the leader you pick you have a wild card in two of those spots.
Rym: So say I have I start with a wild card and recruit in battle.
Rym: Every turn.
Rym: you must do Everything in the decree or your government collapses, right?
Scott: So in the first turn I recruit and I battle.
Rym: the next turn I have to add another card to the decree.
Scott: So now every single turn your decree keeps getting bigger.
Scott: So you have to do everything you did last turn and more every turn.
Scott: So now I have to recruit move in battle.
Scott: No next turn after recruit move battle battle and I have to recruit recruit move battle battle and even better a decision You can make at the start of your turn.
Rym: you must add one card to the decree.
Scott: Yeah, you may add two right now.
Scott: This is basically each turn.
Scott: It's like wow, I get more actions every single turn.
Scott: It's like you just keep getting stronger and stronger and stronger, but then that's true.
Rym: Oh, no, there's no one to fight.
Scott: It's like I have to do.
Scott: I recruit recruit.
Scott: Oh, I don't have enough guys to recruit recruit recruit recruit move.
Scott: I don't have any legal moves.
Scott: recruit recruit move battle battle.
Scott: There's no dudes in a spot that can battle because I didn't have enough move.
Scott: Yeah And as soon as you can't do all of the actions You fail.
Scott: your government just collapses.
Rym: you lose a bunch of points.
Rym: You got to pick a new leader and fun stuff happens.
Scott: Yeah So usually people fail a couple of times every game except for the game.
Rym: I just talked about where I never failed.
Scott: my family somehow managed to play the whole game and Never failed at the decree and therefore won.
Scott: I think I think if you're the birds and you never fail the decree You're gonna win.
Rym: Yeah, that is real hard to pull off.
Scott: It's sort of like a foregone thing.
Rym: I got to a point to where I literally needed someone to attack me to give me an opportunity to attack them back Or I was gonna fail in the.
Scott: you would have failed the next turn.
Rym: I would have definitely failed the next turn.
Scott: There's no way you could have because I had built everything I could possibly build.
Rym: all my roosts were on the board.
Rym: Oh, I literally could not have built another roost.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Yeah So my government would have collapsed.
Scott: even if you fail just once with the birds You're still likely.
Scott: you're still close to winning.
Scott: you need to so you need to fail twice.
Rym: I feel like a normal strategy for the birds is to pick a leader have a strategy push it hard fail Strategically at the right moment start your decree over and then use that to win the game.
Scott: The thing is when you start the decree over too late It will.
Scott: it won't become big and strong enough that right?
Scott: You're taking too few Points, you're trying to put yourself when you when you fail, right?
Scott: It's like oh shit.
Scott: I don't have enough actions.
Scott: It's late game and I'm taking like piddly actions.
Scott: There's no good.
Scott: I think you need to get big and fail fast So that way you could those the the second decree that I got reset.
Scott: the weak actions are still early enough in the game And you'll have strong but barely doable actions towards the end.
Scott: But assuming you can't pull off a miracle like never fail.
Rym: But then when stuff gets interesting is like other players like maybe the cats will work hard by buying the otters support to Make it impossible for the decree to work at a point when the birds did not prepare for that.
Rym: I think that can be fun and weird.
Scott: So I think that the thing with this game is right is like even though I've played it three four times It's still like a low-level like understanding even though I understand everyone's but the lizard folk and the cats kind of how they work.
Scott: Is that you're?
Scott: you have this so such an asymmetric?
Scott: you're playing your own game thing.
Scott: going on that until you completely understand everyone else's thing and Everyone else understands everyone else's thing then you can get into the play of like aha.
Scott: I Know how decrees work as I've played birds like three times.
Scott: Yeah, I'm not the birds now, but I know how to fuck those birds up.
Scott: Let's make sure Rym's decree fails next turn.
Scott: I don't think he can make three moves if we do this.
Rym: cuz like I wasn't.
Scott: Rym's like shit.
Rym: watch a first playthrough with naive players and three or four players like the wooden alliance just always wins because it wasn't.
Scott: Alliance is very Straightforward gets a lot of points and automatically wins if it's not quelled.
Rym: if yeah.
Rym: So you watch advanced players play this game and like the cats and the birds will both be like, all right Let's pause hostilities first.
Scott: take out the communist.
Scott: the first order of business is like always.
Scott: don't let green win now.
Scott: Let's see who else will win.
Scott: But then say some ingredients in the game.
Scott: You might have a green.
Scott: Yeah, you could play red, you know, you could play otters and red and blue.
Rym: I forget the list of like.
Rym: what are all the combinations that work?
Rym: Yeah But don't let any.
Rym: this game only takes a super long time to play if the people at your table just suck at playing game.
Scott: I'm sure there must also be teaching videos on YouTube to help you learn.
Scott: Yeah, you know cuz it is, you know Like I said if you're a gamer if you're listening to a podcast if you're going to a gaming con if you play other Board games you can play this game.
Scott: Don't be scared away by it.
Scott: The cute animal creatures should help you but it's not the simplest.
Scott: you do need You know some help learning it, but someone to teach you read the rules read them again Watch a video.
Rym: Do one thing I noticed that works that I like about this game like a big part of why I think it was fun even Though those learning games and I've never seen a game do that.
Rym: I've seen a few games.
Rym: do this.
Rym: Well, but it's rare.
Rym: You only need to to like to have fun with the game.
Rym: you only need to fully understand how to play your character and You only really need the flavor text of the rest of the characters to have a vague idea of how to handle them.
Rym: Yep Like just knowing that you can trade with the otters and the otter player will explain how to trade with them.
Rym: It's really straightforward.
Scott: knowing that if you do this that will help that play.
Rym: Yeah If I play with if I trade with the otters too much It'll make them strong is enough for me to play in a game where there are otters.
Scott: if I do this stuff I'll be giving too many cards to green.
Scott: Stop giving so many cards to green.
Scott: Yeah, if I do this then you know, the birds decree will be too easy.
Scott: Don't do that.
Rym: And that's the thing the game the fiction of the game.
Scott: Don't give.
Scott: don't give the vagabond all the good items that they want and this only give them some.
Rym: this what I think coal.
Rym: We're brought to that world brought to the table that the fiction of the game itself and the flavor text gives you Reasonably effective heuristics to play the game.
Scott: Absolutely.
Rym: Like that is a rare thing in games.
Rym: Treasure that when you find it.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: So yeah, there's expansion which adds the otters and lizards, right?
Scott: Yep The game's super hot.
Scott: Yeah, the lizard There's keep printing these things as long as people keep buying them.
Scott: The only reason I'm not buying one is because anytime I would play the game I would be with someone who already owns it.
Scott: So there's no reason for me to buy my own copy You know unless suddenly I've got like some people who want to play it with me who don't have one.
Rym: Yep, and if you find the game takes way too long like even after teaching games get better again.
Rym: Yeah, find better people to play with.
Scott: Yeah, it doesn't take that long for us to play.
Rym: I'm sure someone's implemented this in tabletop simulator or something.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew calm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Scott: It's actually recorded at night.
Rym: We're back.
Rym: We're bad and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are I Mean for this page to load.
Rym: Here we go.
Rym: It's coming.
Rym: It's coming out.
Rym: It's been a while since we've done this so I have to get my stuff set up again And I've committed to only ever doing this in one take.
Rym: So there we go Craig Oliver Allen Joyce, honey McNichol just like a dude guy Kajar Tobshon link eg Chris midkiff my stady calm.
Rym: That's m y st ad y dot-com.
Rym: J Bantz scooted only Roberto Kingsley Shawn Yeager Matthew Smith Nicholas Brandau, mr Strong distraction four to one creations Chris Reimer and Thomas Hahn Shervin von Horrell Rory Rochelle, Montanona Superboy sailor Vista Don Schleich Joe Shiro Joe star Clinton Walton written from New Zealand Ryan Perrin drew open Lander Finn Daniel Redmond Sean Klein Chris Reimer and Thomason.
Rym: and now I leave you with something from a show that was ahead of its time a rich Full-bodied wine sensibly priced at a dollar a jug.
Rym: now for a little magic.
Rym: I will make this jug disappear.
Rym: Roll.
Rym: the next clip Rosebud.
Rym: Yes, rosebud frozen peas full of country goodness and green penis.
Rym: Wait, that's terrible.
Rym: I quit just a handful for the road Hmm.
Rym: Oh what luck.
Rym: there's a french fry stuck in my beard.