Rym: It's Tuesday April 7th 2020.
Rym: I'm Rym I'm Scott and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We are talking about Animal Crossing New Horizons.
Rym: Let's do this So it's finally warm enough to get outside and that is really helping my sanity during the whole quarantine.
Scott: Yeah, this problem is is even though I can go outside.
Scott: I work I have to stay inside until 5 still.
Scott: so what I'm doing the whole thing is I wanted to work from home So that I could just do whatever the hell I wanted to The monkey spa.
Rym: monkey spa just curled.
Rym: now you get to work from home.
Scott: Yeah, but I can't do whatever I want while I'm working from home.
Scott: I wanted to like, you know, wake up and bike until like, you know noon.
Scott: come home do a little work Maybe see.
Rym: the problem is you didn't want to work from home.
Rym: You just wanted to not work.
Scott: Yeah But I could still do the amount of work that I do if I go to the office Eight hours, I wanted to do the same total hours of actual work and of all the other times spent doing something else.
Scott: Like for example, if I was legit working from home, right the good the way I wanted I could go out to lunch at us at a restaurant with service.
Rym: Yeah, of course, I can't just go to the baroness and get a burger if I want but you can't sit there and eat it During lunch.
Scott: Nope.
Rym: I gotta go back to my home.
Rym: Yeah But what I'm doing now is everyone.
Scott: I wanted to bring up a laptop to the park or the beach and be like Well, I'm doing I'm available to work But nope can't do that.
Rym: Yeah, I think I'm gonna start sitting with my laptop on the balcony doing work at least occasionally.
Scott: Yes, I can do that as long as the Sun is in the right position to not burn me.
Rym: Nah, but my plan now is every day if I'm during lunch I'm actually gonna go outside and go for a run or a bike first and then eat lunch.
Scott: Mmm, so say like for example today the meeting I had a meeting at 10 and a meeting at 1 So I had not enough time really To get my shit together between them.
Rym: Don't you doctor, you know, my job is mostly meetings.
Rym: Half of my job is literally just talking to people repeatedly and then having meetings with like my five meetings all day.
Rym: Mmm, luckily all the nerds I can just use instant messaging or you'd like to do the meetings and not actually have to talk out Because a lot of my good engineers they would much rather just instant message me.
Rym: then Actually, like get into a video call and talk for a half-hour But all the business side things it's got to be like video chat face-to-face ten people in the room.
Rym: Let's go.
Rym: So there is a bunch of news, but since there's no Sports happening right now Like normally this time of year is when we're starting to talk about NHL playoffs and like the Rangers Like are they gonna make the wild card, but we got nothing.
Rym: So I'm actually watching a lot more eSports instead.
Rym: Okay, cuz overwatch league is still going still trucking on.
Scott: Oh, yeah, the only sport that's not canceled the eSports.
Rym: So the thing about overwatch league is the.
Rym: I like watching eSports tournaments But I very rarely watch them live because I don't care that much who wins.
Scott: So usually I'll either watch highlight reels or like you want New York to end as a New York.
Rym: I mean, I do want New York to win and Excelsior always they're still like very good in the league.
Rym: Excelsior is a solid team to be a fan of but most of the other games.
Rym: I don't care that much or The game might not be exciting.
Rym: Sometimes they are sometimes they aren't.
Rym: so I tend to just wait for the VODs and I'll either watch highlight reels or I'll watch Like the game everyone was talking about from the previous day on YouTube.
Scott: That is a problem and I think a lot of eSports is that there is.
Scott: you know professional sporting leagues tend to have Often more parody.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, you know even in NHL It's like well teams that are clearly better than the other team will only beat the crappy team not a hundred percent of the time But maybe like 70% of the time, right?
Scott: Except the red wings right now Right, but in a lot of eSports, you know You watch say like a fighting game tournament.
Scott: towards the end of the tournament you get parody you get excitement, right?
Scott: Those early rounds.
Scott: Oof.
Scott: It's just like yeah, like watch the York play say Boston in overwatch Watch like Sonic Fox play against whoever it gets paired up with in round one.
Scott: Yeah, like boom
Rym: I'm thinking if you remember one must fall 2097 when you get the news commentator talking about the fight you just had and if you utterly Fucking crushed your opponent the commentator was like if you wanted to see a fair test of skill tonight was not your night.
Rym: However, if you were looking for a masochistic pounding have we got highlights for you, right?
Scott: You know usually other pro sports that have like opens like say US Open of golf.
Rym: You don't really see the Yeah, cameras not a direct in the last person, right?
Scott: You never see the guy who hits it into the trees 20 times up captain Joe plus 20, right?
Rym: They're following like Tiger Woods plus one or minus two or wherever they are something.
Scott: Well US Open is pretty hard even for the best people.
Scott: Yeah, but But like even in f1 there was a super aguri.
Scott: That's right, you know, but you but you don't see.
Scott: they don't keep the camera on the super aguri.
Scott: You can just watch.
Rym: you check in with them.
Scott: You know Mercedes is in the Ferraris and whoever's up front you can just keep your eyes on them.
Scott: the Red Bulls Whoever is now this year is the good car.
Rym: I don't need to watch Uprising lose but I get.
Rym: I like someone to check in and tell me that they lost Right.
Scott: So it's like when you're watching even NFL football was a less parody.
Scott: right.
Scott: when there's a game that's like Cleveland Browns Versus so-and-so you just don't watch that game because there's so many simultaneous games.
Scott: They got the red zone, right?
Rym: So you're always watching something, you know good Yep, so I think this when the other problem is Overwatch League is global.
Rym: so like the games are on weekends like Saturday and Sunday mostly but Some of the matches I want to watch or at like 4 a.m And the matches I don't give a shit about are like 6 when I would normally watch like I don't want to watch Houston and Like I just don't care.
Rym: so I'm gonna.
Rym: I'm gonna Try to watch some more live games But probably not this weekend because there's no live games during my time zone that I care that much about.
Scott: Yeah, most of what we've been watching eSports wise is linked to the past randomizer.
Scott: There was a tournament and we watched the tournament, which is great.
Scott: But now there's a league that's going on and the league has a lot Let like I just said less parody than the late rounds of the tournament which are super legit.
Scott: The league has a lot of you know, some teams are just better than others, right?
Scott: Yeah It's just like complete blowouts and it's not exciting close races.
Scott: Like the Tournament was towards the end there.
Rym: Yeah, I mean with these niche sports like when you get to randomizers that is already a subculture of a subculture of a subculture.
Scott: Yet the number of people watching those things is shocking Like it's really a link to the past.
Scott: randomizer community is shockingly large.
Scott: like they put together this league I think the teams are three or four people I don't know three or four people each and there's a ton of teams and Every even minor races have like hundreds or perhaps even like a thousand viewers Right.
Scott: It's way more popular than bringing GeekNights.
Rym: Yeah Girl, we serve a very specific audience.
Rym: The listener appreciates us Sure.
Rym: So in some other news one a lot of you like I didn't even notice this News about cooking mama at first because the few tweets I knew it but the few tweets I saw about it.
Rym: We're so obviously not true that I ignored it as like a ridiculous conspiracy bullshit thing, but it hit getting talked about.
Scott: Oh, yeah, so I saw this news in the beginning because it was in the Nintendo switch community.
Scott: Yeah, I shouldn't sorry.
Scott: and then basically people were saying hey this cooking mama came came out and that's a semi popular Second tier maybe third tier franchise.
Scott: that was really one of those like.
Scott: there's a lot of these game franchises that were big on the DS or Nintendo mobile platforms We're that we're sort of like big in the small pond, right?
Rym: Yeah, like brain age was that?
Scott: Well, I mean, that's a Nintendo first party title.
Scott: I'm talking about like your golden sons, right?
Rym: Oh, I forgot about golden son the nine door nine, whatever nine something's.
Scott: there's like Actually a whole bunch of third-party games, you know Phoenix, right?
Scott: I guess falls in that category to write these things that were really popular on Mobile Nintendo platforms.
Scott: they weren't on Consoles are right.
Scott: It was just in there.
Scott: But now that switches everything all those games are mixed up in the switch.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: So the new.
Scott: then if there are new games in those franchises suddenly they have the visibility Outside the the mobile realm.
Scott: and for anyone who hasn't like the Nintendo portable Gameboy You know D at GBA DS, right 3ds That is like this great.
Scott: I think still underrated underappreciated treasure trove of amazing games.
Scott: It's like this enormous library a lot of shovelware, but also a lot of amazing games that I think is really Underappreciated not talked about not cared about But anyway, so cooking mama was a pretty big game on the DS and a pretty nothing game to anyone Who wasn't paying attention to DS?
Rym: Yep And it's not having a game but it's like.
Rym: I know style like I see the appeal of this kind of game.
Rym: It was popular right.
Scott: so it was a new one that came out on the switch and It was even in stores.
Scott: cartridges in stores, right.
Scott: and then suddenly it was removed from the e-shop.
Rym: now We do not mysteriously as a dateline know Actually why it was removed.
Rym: like we do not know that there have been some compete conflicting.
Rym: It sounds like it's a dispute between the developers and the publisher and or Nintendo like we don't know Mm-hmm.
Scott: But anyway.
Scott: So imagine it instantly disappeared from the e-shop Right shortly after release.
Scott: people still have cartridges and they can play it but now people like whoa Hold on to that cartridge because it might be valuable.
Scott: It's gonna be some rare game right.
Rym: but then some some people started just tweeting this ridiculous rumor that it was removed because it was mining bitcoins on your switch and then Switch.
Rym: and I saw the baby and the baby looked at me, right?
Scott: So there are two reasons that I immediately knew that that was bullshit, right?
Scott: number one Obviously if you had a game that was mining bitcoins or cryptocurrency on a switch that it would get pulled from the store.
Rym: However, number one Nintendo switches are weak sauce CPU wise Yeah, the days he could mine a Bitcoin on a CPU as opposed to a dedicated nightmare machine.
Scott: Oh, it has a GPU but technically and I guess you have it if you can infect enough of them.
Scott: But how many people are buying cooking mama, even if that's true, right?
Scott: It's like and then it's end of the battery would just die.
Scott: It's like it's a weak sauce thing.
Scott: That's not a good idea.
Scott: and to every game that comes out on Nintendo switch is Thoroughly thoroughly thoroughly reviewed by Nintendo like if you got some malware onto the switch.
Scott: Officially like my head is off to you Nintendo doesn't fuck around Yeah, so it's like you think it's hard to get your app into like the Apple App Store.
Scott: It's like no no no no Right.
Scott: Nintendo is like it's completely examining every inch of your source Software.
Rym: the vector is in is implausible, but the the result is also implausible.
Rym: But it would be impossible to mine bitcoins on a Nintendo switch.
Scott: You could do a very small amount of mining Yeah, and if you got enough switches together Maybe you could mine a coin and so anyway, but the point is that was a bullshit story.
Rym: I could tell from the start Yep, and then all these reports like the so-called reports of like switches being bricked by the game literally all came from like one tweet.
Scott: Well, it does seem to be true At least more likely to be true.
Scott: I don't know this confirmed that the game is just poorly coded in unity in general Right.
Scott: Yeah Like that it was put together by like some you know first-time Dev team that didn't have mad skills and so the game is poorly coded and Inefficient.
Scott: so your switch will heat up and it'll use a lot of CPU and drop frames, and you know it's not well done.
Rym: Yeah, but there are a lot of games that have similar problems like that is not really evident of anything obviously.
Scott: so it somebody's claiming to be a Anonymous developer on the game or working at the developer Or perhaps a reporter possibly making up a source possibly having a real source Yeah, has told the story.
Scott: that is much more plausible, right?
Scott: So we'll take it as truth for the time being that there was a battle between the publisher and developer Right in the in the legal realm right and that is why the game has been pulled and there's some Shenanigans going on business wise which is totally what you would expect From that sort of thing yeah, and that's why this game has disappeared from the e-shop But it remains true that as it was a game and a somewhat significant known franchise that was in the e-shop and pulled and their cartridges out there and Hard to get.
Scott: so I would recommend Getting a cartridge wouldn't be If you got one hold on is probably not awful.
Scott: cookie mom is like I fun.
Scott: I can't imagine how bad a new cookie mama game could be if you play it.
Scott: If you don't play it and put it in the closet, you know.
Rym: So another another component of where this rumor seems to have come from is This talk about a company that was involved in the creation of the game Saying like that company was also involved not in cryptocurrency, but in blockchain Which is a generic ledger technology.
Rym: Bitcoin just happens to use a blockchain.
Rym: There are other ways to use blockchain now.
Scott: Also.
Scott: It seems that that is just messed up.
Scott: I mean like They were just made up.
Scott: yeah, but full disclosure they're not actually doing any blockchain anything.
Rym: Well, there were a bunch of companies trying to get investors.
Rym: I'm not saying this happened here But I've been privy to a lot of VC pitches and I saw a lot of this in other games in the industry.
Rym: People would basically to try to get idiots who want to invest in Bitcoin to invest in like a game studio or a publisher would Try to incorporate blockchain technology in some reasonably plausible feasible way Just so they can say that it is pushing the frontier of blockchain.
Scott: I think it's more like and there are there are people are investing in buzzwords.
Scott: Let's just attach the buzzword to our thing without actually doing whatever the buzzword is.
Rym: The most common thing to do if you did anything was just to use something like blockchain to record Transactions that multiple players have on their own systems without having to necessarily trust those systems.
Rym: for like trading like trading goods Like using it as the back end for item trading in games online like that's it.
Scott: It still seems like not the oh, no, it's blockchain is never the right database for anything.
Scott: the World of Warcraft way.
Scott: I have a database.
Rym: Yep like I'm not saying that is a reasonable technology to use for these purposes, but it's Plausible enough for to make a case more and more every day.
Scott: I'm starting to believe that pretty much almost all Business, you know, sir software problems.
Rym: Oh you're thinking about that because of a specific threat in our forum.
Scott: No, I'm just saying almost all business software problems in the world.
Scott: Whatever your business is right, whatever your problem is if it's an information Problem right that a computer can solve yeah Postgres probably solves it.
Scott: You probably don't need to do anything else.
Scott: You don't need any weird anything else.
Scott: You know what?
Scott: just well just start with Postgres.
Scott: yeah, do as much as you can with Postgres QL and towards solving your problem and Add a programming language on top of it.
Scott: You know to get an application running on a server Python or even see it doesn't for anything that can connect to Postgres.
Scott: Right and get those two pieces.
Scott: and if you can't solve your problem with those two pieces After putting a lot of effort in then you're allowed to add more pieces.
Rym: Yep It's like if you don't know why you need them, you don't need them.
Scott: if you don't know there's almost no information Problem that cannot be solved with a combination of Postgres and any modern programming language running on a server.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, you don't need anything else.
Rym: Well, you need a message bus.
Rym: I don't know.
Rym: throw like Kafka on top of it.
Scott: done might need that maybe maybe but you could also.
Scott: But you should implement your message bus as just like a fucking Q and JMS.
Scott: you first Right there.
Scott: must you know that Postgres probably has some queuing feature.
Rym: I you know built in something postgres a long way since the last time I mess right directly.
Scott: don't go using a Kafka until you Figured out that you can't do it directly in Postgres itself.
Rym: Yeah Well, I guess we actually we actually have a Kafka at work doing some stuff In terms of enterprise service bus like one of those like big iron like buses.
Scott: I'm not saying that other pieces are never to be used.
Scott: Okay, I'm saying that you know, they definitely have.
Scott: there are problems that do need more stuff.
Rym: Yeah, but I have seen that majority not solar Systems like Solr solar to handle amounts of data that could trivially be handled by Literally any other solution right?
Scott: For example, you postgres full-text search is pretty damn good.
Scott: Oh, right.
Rym: It's also go adding or performance and you might expect.
Scott: Oh, yeah, so don't go adding some kind of.
Scott: you know Lucene's solar elastic search whatever until you've proven that the full-text search in Postgres isn't good.
Scott: Yeah,
Rym: you know when I went in an old company when I brought some architecture that I owned from just a database to a Lucene Index that was when we got to the point of trade teeth keeping track of 50 million daily Transactions that were moderately large and wanting to keep six months of them.
Scott: Yep Ridiculous shit.
Scott: Not one day.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: It's Tuesday.
Rym: Yep, but cooking mama is not mining bitcoins.
Scott: Good God, like no, it's definitely not.
Rym: I get more than one source before you spread this crap like.
Rym: seriously I got a brief geek bite.
Rym: If you haven't dusted off slay the spire in a while.
Rym: single-player game available on Steam on switch like pretty much everywhere Except iOS.
Rym: I'm still waiting for it is great on the switch because the user interface is so good.
Rym: It is such a good.
Rym: lay in bed and play this game until you fall asleep Like the UX is just perfect or how you manipulate these cards.
Rym: This game is great but What I want a geek bite is that the switch has the new character that was added and all the balance changes that were added The watcher the new character.
Rym: if you even if you think you played slay the spire out I would definitely recommend picking it back up and going through the ascensions with the new character.
Rym: The new character is radically different from the other characters in a really fun ways Mm-hmm.
Rym: The main thing is the character has stances and cards will cards and potions.
Rym: things can put you into stances.
Rym: So you might get into aggressive stance.
Rym: That means you do double damage.
Rym: Just full stop.
Rym: You also take double damage.
Rym: Oh You can go to a column stance.
Rym: All that does is whenever you exit the column stance you get two more energy right then and there.
Rym: So you can like make clever combos.
Rym: It's really like a long play like you'll play this like you'll be fighting a boss.
Rym: You do no damage to this boss for like ten rounds setting up your ridiculous combo And then you play one turn that one shots the boss.
Rym: Like.
Rym: that's the kind of way that's the kind of style you play with this character.
Rym: It is crazy fun.
Scott: Oh So that actually reminds me just very quickly.
Scott: There was a early access game that I played called on steam called curse of the dead gods.
Scott: It is still that I still believe it is early access.
Scott: Let me just verify Yeah, it's early access game.
Scott: And yeah basically What this game is is it's a slay the spire kind of roguelike right where you have the mat the branching map and you choose Where you're going next and each different thing.
Scott: You could go to a gold room or an item room or a stats room to choose what kind of right?
Scott: But instead of playing a card game at each spot.
Scott: you play basically sort of a real-time Diablo esque action RPG.
Scott: So it's like you go.
Scott: I'll go to the gold room.
Scott: all right.
Scott: Here's a tiny two Diablo rooms And there's a lot of gold in them and also bad guys and it's a little bit more action real time than Diablo.
Scott: But it's still isometric view.
Scott: right you know use your spells and abilities and attacks and whatever.
Scott: you know parrying stuff like that.
Scott: It's very early access.
Scott: the amount of content is you know sparse?
Scott: But it still was pretty fun.
Scott: I played it for about an hour, and I'm probably gonna play it again once it gets more content.
Scott: It seems there was a major update today at 11 a.m.. Room variations see they're adding.
Rym: One of the reasons why I tend to avoid early access for games that I know I'm gonna like.
Scott: yeah, no no I just wanted to.
Scott: I just you know I like.
Scott: I said I put it in I checked it out And I probably won't go back to it until it's done.
Scott: ish right Because I sort of played out the amount of content.
Scott: They had very quickly.
Rym: So speaking of you know where this is like a prime season to dust off a steam library To play video games that you didn't have time to play like ah we're playing a lot of video games But the industry that is in deep shit right now is the board game industry.
Rym: things are not going well And some of the reasons you can anticipate But some of them you probably can't.
Rym: there were other problems that had happened in this industry like late last year that already put it in a precarious situation, so We're looking at maybe a lot of publishers like slowing down laying people off the project.
Scott: I just wonder what it means indirectly for the table because I don't care of.
Scott: if you know I already felt like one of the major problems of the board gaming industry which probably contributed to this was Making way too many games.
Rym: hundred percent I think a lot of which are a lot of the studios that are getting like gonna go down to be perfectly blunt Didn't really have a viable path to success anyway, and we're riding a bubble at best, right?
Scott: So The thing is that I don't care if all those games that weren't any good anyway stop gliding up the market with shovelware inventory Right, but what I do care is oh well if there's not as many game publishers Are there gonna be less gaming cons?
Rym: Yeah, or less gaming stores because the gaming stores are also not doing well.
Rym: But now they can't even.
Rym: they can't make money from selling because online that's there's not.
Rym: you can't make enough money with that.
Rym: And they can't make money with the impulse buys because people are playing games in their shops.
Rym: Yep, and you think oh everyone stuck at home everyone stuck at home isolated So very hard to get a board game going.
Rym: people who would normally buy and play a board game are going to tabletop simulator.
Rym: They're going to online implementations of these games.
Rym: They're going to the game like slay the spire.
Rym: They're just playing video games instead.
Rym: Yep, two-player games.
Rym: I think are having a minor Renaissance, but there aren't that many two-player games.
Rym: they're sold out everywhere the good two-player games I know of.
Rym: and You're not gonna be able to build and develop a new two-player game because you can't manufacture things in China.
Rym: Not just because of the virus and all that situation Not just because of all the supply chain distribution problems coming all the way up to the u.s.
Rym: And everywhere in the world but because of all the tariffs and all the other shit that was going down last year.
Rym: That's still happening.
Scott: Yep, there's also a lot of shenanigans going on.
Scott: with regards to you know, as mode a you know A lot of the though the return policy problems the right.
Scott: this did.
Scott: there have been distributor Situations.
Scott: they changed their distributors around FMG had huge cutbacks right on all their products that weren't selling.
Rym: basically The industry was entering a contraction and there was a lot of trouble going down.
Rym: and then this happened.
Scott: So basically what you're gonna see at minimum I think is the board game.
Scott: Hobby industry right is gonna retract back to only the successful things Right and you're gonna see a lot less of those like board game shelf with a million games including like obscure ones.
Scott: It's gonna be like no there's your Warhammer.
Scott: There's your magic.
Scott: There's your pandemic.
Scott: There's a Dominion.
Scott: is your Right?
Rym: the big boys cuz you might think even if I let's say like the crisis boils down a little bit and all the like.
Rym: Fall conventions happen like PAX West and PAX Unplugged for example.
Rym: The problem is right around now is when Expo space and publisher deals and all the things for those conventions would.
Scott: well, it's like you think Gen Con is gonna happen.
Scott: That's a lot earlier.
Rym: Yeah, I don't think Gen Con is gonna happen.
Scott: origins.
Scott: I don't know when.
Rym: that yeah but even the planning for those events is just in October.
Rym: is that gonna happen and Companies that are already in a retraction are not as able to dump their advertising budget on things?
Rym: They're probably gonna cannibalize that advertising budget to focus on core properties and monetization and just staying alive.
Rym: So it's gonna be a real rough time for the game like the board game industry as a whole.
Scott: I think it's actually though a good time.
Scott: well It's a bad time for a game publisher for
Rym: sure
Scott: who is trying to like gather up board games and sorry It's a good time if you're a board game author
Rym: Yep, if you're a core designer like if you're just doing a design if you're doing like that early research You're just you're building something, but you don't have to ship it right away.
Scott: There will be less shovelware clogging up the market Right, and so if you come up with like an actual legit hit big-time game Right, you can go the Kickstarter normal route, you know You're gonna have to get your game printed somewhere that can still print it at a probably a higher price.
Scott: Oh, you're still gonna be able to ship it somehow.
Rym: Right, I think you're also gonna see a pivot to companies that are good at taking an existing tabletop game and making an online implementation.
Rym: Your day has come.
Rym: Oh, yeah now is the time.
Rym: like the fact that the root video game is not out yet because they weren't in that much of a rush is Terrible.
Rym: because if if root were online now even just with the original game like the original factions I think it would like be near the top of the steam charts.
Scott: Maybe like that's.
Scott: the people doing that are the same people who did the Y&Y.
Scott: Yeah digital edition, which is good.
Scott: It is Yeah, it's I'm looking it up right now.
Rym: I earned something.
Rym: I always lose track of them.
Scott: dire wolf dire wolf.
Scott: Yeah Dire wolf digital right there.
Scott: They did a Sagrada They did eternal echoes of eternity Raiders of the North Sea yellow and yanxi and they're doing the digital root edition And they did a great job.
Scott: if anyone's got yellow and yanxi on steam Let's play.
Rym: Yeah, let's get a game going.
Rym: Yeah, I would love to play that together.
Scott: Let's do it.
Rym: All right, and last we'll go brief on this because I want to get talking about Animal Crossing But this is an Animal Crossing news.
Rym: We all know that nobody like zipper.
Scott: zipper the bunny because I only saw him on the first day and then he disappeared.
Rym: Yep, he came back because I'm a little.
Rym: Emily joined my island and then he came back so she could talk to her to him.
Scott: oh, I see I see.
Rym: but When I saw zipper, I kind of started because everyone kept saying oh, there's this bunny and I hate it.
Rym: But then I saw the bunny that is some five nights at Freddy's.
Rym: shit is clearly in a costume is clearly not a bunny And he's looking at me.
Scott: I think that's.
Rym: I think it's supposed to be that, you know, it's well It's supposed to be like a working person Like it's just a job like this person is wearing this costume and trying their hardest But it's either Tom Nook or someone Tom Nook hired.
Rym: Yeah, but in reality It just feels like it's five nights at Freddy's and this thing's gonna murder me.
Scott: He's trying to attract people to the island with his holiday.
Rym: Yeah, but the news is that Animal Crossing has the Easter event called Bunny Day in the u.s.
Rym: you know all the events that they do.
Rym: and Nobody liked the egg hunts either.
Rym: and people were so mad about it that Nintendo They actually dialed back the egg dropper rates because no one wants to get more eggs They want to find actual fish.
Scott: Well, they mostly dialed it back on The sky eggs because they were just too many.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: They were constant like balloons are coming.
Rym: I stopped shooting them down I didn't care anymore.
Scott: Well, I look at the balloon to see if it's a bunny one or a regular one.
Scott: Yeah, if it's a bunny one I ignore it, right?
Scott: But I don't think they dialed them back at the other day.
Scott: I think what it is is that the rate that they had makes sense From the standpoint of.
Scott: I've been playing this game for a while and I have all the stuff and I'm sure Need something like oh, I'm gonna craft all the Bunny Day stuff Let's go.
Scott: But it doesn't.
Scott: it doesn't make sense for a game that just came out.
Scott: people are still trying to like build up from nothing.
Rym: I'm still trying to get a second room like new players are buying this game by the day, right?
Scott: It's like you're trying to get your you know beginning of game stuff Like.
Scott: I need you know to get all I need to get all the basic common fish and it's like well half the fish you Pull are just water eggs, right and that gets in the way I'm like, what if I started the game today?
Rym: Like how am I even gonna like do anything right.
Scott: the other thing it'll be over in five days.
Scott: the thing that really I think for me made the vent less fun is That none of the Bunny Day goods ugly.
Scott: It's so ugly and bleh.
Scott: I don't want.
Rym: I was like Cool, and it's just like this bulb is monstrosity.
Scott: Yeah, if any of them were ones I wanted or right then it would be like, oh I need eggs to make the cool Bunny-day, whatever.
Rym: I want the cherry blossom stuff instead, right?
Scott: There actually isn't that much cherry blossom stuff.
Scott: It's very few.
Rym: I know but that's the only things I want.
Scott: Yeah, and cherry blossoms go away in three days.
Rym: Oh, I better deal with that.
Rym: But anyway things of the day.
Rym: So, uh, if you watch the wonderful sport of ice hockey one thing and you're not like in ice hockey culture One thing that always stands out to people is oh shit.
Rym: Are they just fighting?
Rym: why isn't anyone stopping them?
Rym: cuz like if someone tries to have a fistfight in like a basketball game a football match Malice at the palace like the police get involved like that is a problem like that does not.
Scott: I'm still of the opinion that if There is a like, you know a fight in ice hockey game You should be as you know, you show the press charges against the other.
Rym: But ice hockey's weird in that there are.
Rym: no they're the only written rules about fighting.
Rym: are that if you fight you and the person you fought with get five minutes?
Rym: and Then there's other penalties like if you instigated the fight.
Scott: Versus if you had that fight on the street, you'd at least have like a night in jail or a summons or something.
Scott: Yeah, right, but I'd like that.
Rym: but there's.
Rym: basically there's the written rules of fighting in hockey Which are very straightforward and very simple.
Rym: And then there's the actual rules because like all hockey fans who watch hockey know that the rule is if two people are fighting and They're fine They followed the rules to start the fight.
Rym: the refs really can't stop them unless Someone wins the fight hour.
Rym: It comes to the ground like and they follow these rules, but they're not written down anywhere.
Rym: So what this video is is a humorous 10-minute long video.
Rym: I think it's a Bruins fan.
Rym: They have a lot of March and in here, but that's because they're.
Scott: he's an ass.
Scott: Using him as an example, maybe they're not.
Scott: they're probably not a Bruins fan.
Rym: Yeah They use him as an example of The player who tricks you into starting a fight and then go but walks away and you just get a penalty for nothing.
Scott: Yeah scumbag.
Rym: Yeah, but what this video does is in ten minutes it Explains in a humorous way, but actually like in a really really accurate way what the actual Unwritten rules are for fighting in hockey.
Rym: So if you watch this video You'll understand why sometimes the refs break up a fight and why sometimes they don't like When fights get broken up how they get broken up and why like this video is actually really detailed and accurate.
Rym: So what you got?
Scott: Oh, so, you know our favorite word the f-word The most common word said in New York Yeah, supposedly according to scotsman calm and according to this new TV doc.
Rym: Wait a minute Scottsman calm.
Rym: did a Scotsman write this?
Scott: Maybe?
Scott: and also according to a BBC Scotland documentary still biased.
Scott: I sure hope this isn't like.
Scott: it seems to be a real news site, right?
Scott: This isn't one of those like fake Scottish news things.
Scott: It seems real to me.
Rym: I mean, no very few listeners called me out on a fake Scottish news.
Rym: I talked about a while ago.
Scott: That was uh, oh that was also Scottish.
Scott: Yes Can't trust these Scottish Scotts, right?
Rym: the one time I took the piss and like one person messaged me and they're like, uh There's no way that's true.
Rym: Is it?
Scott: and I was like, no, no anyway the point is According to this there used to be a thing called flighting or fleeting Which is basically a poetry duel or like a you know, a 16th century rap battle.
Scott: Whoo It's how they describe it.
Rym: I want to find a historic or an actor.
Rym: I want to see one of these.
Scott: but anyway in one such battle the flighting of Dunbar and Kennedy right in which which is a written account of The flighting that they had so it's like Dunbar and Kennedy had a rap battle a poetry battle, right?
Scott: Dunbar wrote down an account of it and in that account is supposedly the oldest known written You know occurrence of the word fuck.
Scott: That if true is amazing Some very juicy language and points out one of the insults traded between the two poets was the phrase one fuck it fun ling Which is probably not how that's pronounced.
Scott: We need a Scottish person to pronounce it, right?
Scott: But yeah, if true this is fascinating and great.
Rym: It's my most commonly it's all there is - it's very important word.
Rym: Yeah, I use it So in the meta moment of GeekNights sounds a little weird I guess.
Rym: we've said before we were doing the show remotely.
Rym: as of today We are now live streaming the show remotely.
Rym: that was more annoying to set up than you realize And I hope you well.
Rym: there are 12 people watching this.
Rym: So I think you were.
Rym: I think some people are hungry for the live streams to come back.
Rym: The book club book, we're not reading books for playing video games.
Rym: all that Hold on.
Scott: I'm reading comic books.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I'm mostly playing video games and reading nonfiction.
Rym: I started You know that shattered sword book.
Rym: now that Chris is reading it.
Rym: I reread a chapter of it.
Rym: That was a particularly good chapter.
Rym: So that's where I'm at in terms of books In terms of meta.
Scott: I want to remind people that we have a semi official GeekNights' Discord server that you can come to and we do some streams there.
Scott: They're low effort streams because it's way easier to do.
Scott: then you go on Twitch Which is a big time.
Scott: you know our YouTube which is a big time investment.
Rym: It's more like you want to hang out in the room with like me or Scott.
Rym: well Like I'm just playing XCOM or something, right?
Scott: It's like I'm playing.
Scott: civilization might as well click this one button that will make a stream happen and then if you can join in with a voice chat And you can even stream your own game or whatever, right?
Scott: I also want to remind people we have a forum.
Scott: that's on our website community.frontrecruit.com and I want to remind people that there's an official GeekNights' newsletter, which is the kind of thing that you have time to Remember about that when you got nothing else to do.
Rym: We do our other secret project of the other writing thing.
Scott: Yes, there are secret.
Scott: basically the GeekNights' newsletter is basically Secret.
Scott: emails that I write only go to 300 or so people that are subscribed to it probably a small percentage of who read it and You can.
Scott: actually there's actually a public archive of it that you can read the old emails But you know no one pays attention to it.
Scott: I write it rarely, but if I'm stuck at home Yeah, got nothing else to do.
Rym: similarly I'm restarting my Rym's-Rants where I did the Friday GeekNights on the patreon, so I'm gonna.
Rym: I'm starting those up again this week.
Scott: Got time to not cherish.
Rym: Yep must spend must waste it.
Rym: I must kill it.
Rym: Mustn't kill time boy.
Rym: I find as I get older unless I rewatch the Simpsons I start to lose my precise Simpsons quoting abilities, and I get more generic.
Rym: I gotta.
Rym: I gotta rewatch seasons two through nine.
Scott: I remember more quotes, and I forget like like.
Scott: I know you know mustn't kill time boy.
Scott: Cherish it, right?
Scott: That's the same.
Rym: Can I get five?
Scott: I couldn't tell you what episode it was.
Scott: I couldn't tell you which old man said it.
Rym: Oh, see I do remember the A plot and the B plots and where they line up though There's a occasional gaps.
Rym: past season seven like I forgot that a bunch of choice lines Were in.
Rym: the Homer learns how to box with Moe and I also forgot it ends with that montage of Moe saving everybody with the fan.
Rym: Okay, you don't remember this at all do you?
Scott: Nope.
Rym: Wow Homer boxes Mike Tyson and Don King is in it, but it's not Mike Tyson and Don King that one.
Rym: okay Yeah, they used to call me kid gorgeous.
Rym: So yeah follow us and all the stuff.
Rym: watch our YouTube channels, we're doing more and more.
Rym: we're streaming again bit by bit.
Rym: We're gonna crank out more and more content, but now something amazing happened.
Rym: both Scott and I are playing an Animal Crossing game which I Was aware that Animal Crossing existed But for much of my adult life I've all I knew was it's the game Where you just talk to animals in a little town and I didn't really know anything else about it
Scott: Right.
Scott: Well, I mean so Animal Crossing First appeared on the GameCube right and when it came out It was like the one first party in Nintendo GameCube game that I didn't go for.
Rym: Well, it came out on the n64, but I don't think that one came out in the US.
Scott: No, so actually so that the real story is in Japan the original one which I think is called it's like The Japanese name is like dobutsu something cuz dobutsu is animal.
Scott: Yep, right.
Scott: It's like dobutsu something which means forest.
Scott: I think it's animal forest and not crossing.
Scott: Anyway, the point is that original n64 one was Japan only.
Rym: Yep, and then enhanced and released with new right hand on the GameCube, right?
Scott: Then they made it like a. it was like an upgraded version on the GameCube But that upgraded version on the GameCube is what the original US release was.
Rym: Yep Similar shenanigans happened with some of the early advance Wars games like similar stuff went down.
Scott: It's similar to what happened with the Zelda game that came out on GameCube and Wii.
Rym: Oh, yeah.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: Was that Twilight Princess?
Scott: I think yeah, I'm on GameCube and we you know I never finished that one here.
Scott: Anyway, anyway So Yeah, but what I knew about Animal Crossing was this I knew that it was a game.
Scott: We're like you're a person who gets made it to be the mayor of a village.
Scott: You have to pay off debts and you do lots of basically no skill busy work right collecting and selling fruit Playing some sort of turnip stock market game fishing Collecting stuff.
Scott: Yep, right.
Scott: I was sort of just like and I knew character busy work collecting kind of game Like I knew.
Rym: I knew there's Tom Nook because people would talk about Tom Nook a lot like Animal Crossing was widely Represented in my social media and like in the wider gaming spaces I inhabited.
Rym: even though I did not play it myself and I didn't really know a lot of people who played it I would encounter it kind of often.
Scott: Yeah, no, I mean I knew and you know enough about it tangentially.
Scott: I just never actually played one.
Scott: Yep, right because I didn't feel like I needed to because I knew I felt I knew what kind of game it was.
Scott: Yeah, so but the new one came out which I probably also wasn't planning to buy.
Scott: I didn't buy on the first day But we're stuck inside and there's nothing else to do and all our friends are playing it like everyone's literally everyone's playing it.
Scott: So I'm like well when in Rome, whatever I'll do this for a while and then I'll stop right but
Rym: also partly because like a lot of our friends who were playing it are really into it like the people who like Animal Crossing Really like it and while we had tangential knowledge of it I feel like it's worth at least exploring and like playing what this game actually is.
Scott: and so I did play The Animal Crossing actually on iOS.
Scott: the happy whatever right?
Scott: wasn't that game?
Rym: mobile game though?
Scott: Yeah, no actually it wasn't really much of a game.
Scott: It wasn't really much like Animal Crossing for real.
Scott: basically all it was is Animal Crossing styled game where you can decorate your little area right.
Scott: it was all about decorating your area and The way to decorate the area was like basically pay money right there wasn't all the like this Do task wise really.
Rym: so I guess if I had to describe Animal Crossing Well, we're gonna review now because the only game we ever played is New Horizons, which we're playing actively.
Rym: now We've played another reviewing the old ones yep, but if I had to describe this game just as a reviewer.
Rym: I would say that it is.
Rym: it is a game about talking to animals and making them happy and everything else kind of.
Rym: and I will talk to animals try to make them happy while curating your little animal village and Slowly investing in it and then customizing it.
Scott: I think it's more basically just the world's most advanced cookie clicker.
Scott: So you think about some of that going on right.
Scott: so cookie clicker you click and you get stuff Right and you click and you get stuff and then eventually get enough stuff that you can buy.
Scott: Something the same could be said of all Diablo games sure But there's no.
Scott: there's no skill.
Scott: There's very little skill to the clicking.
Scott: Yeah There's some.
Scott: there's medicine.
Rym: the skill mess up catching a fish now And then the skill is more like the people who get to get into this game Will learn techniques and have patterns and like fastest pads to paying off debts and make charts to figure out a turnip market.
Scott: It's just simple.
Scott: You know an extra layer of management of the clicks, right?
Scott: It's not based on your skill right of pushing buttons is what I'm right.
Scott: It's just you get you.
Scott: the trees grow fruit.
Scott: some things are like an idle game.
Scott: They're time based.
Scott: you wait for the fruit to grow and then you write Yeah, but you have to because the game is attached to a real-time clock.
Scott: unless you cheat You know you have to pick.
Scott: you have to be on top of it, right?
Scott: You have to pick your fruit when it gets ready sort of like You know the real-time submarine game.
Rym: oh, yes Subterfuge yeah, right.
Scott: But I kind of like that in one sense like when I first want to sell your fruit on a different island Your native fruit on a different island to get more money and sell your other fruits locally to get more money, right?
Rym: Yeah, well, there's a bunch of like sort of meta games within like.
Rym: there's the cookie clicker aspect of get all the stuff.
Rym: then there's the like more of a playground like Lego aspect of Super customize your island because that's like the endgame like just make yes, but they it feeds into each other.
Scott: You can't super customize your island if you don't have enough money.
Scott: Yep, right you need to get.
Scott: you need to play the game of grinding away at the different lanes, right?
Scott: You can grind it fish.
Scott: You can grind it seashells.
Scott: You can grind at tree at farming Yeah, you can grind at the turnip stock market.
Rym: But then there's this other parallel game of.
Rym: you can grind at bug catching as you meet new villagers And get them to move into your island bit by bit and they come and go.
Rym: You can try to learn what each one's deal is because they all have like a pretty particular Deal and based on how they react and you give him right gifts and try to make him happy and like.
Rym: there's a whole like side game there.
Rym: Mmm, I guess I don't pay attention to that too much because it's like, you know I really want my villagers to like me and I really try to come up with like specific gifts based on.
Rym: like My bird bro was like he.
Rym: every time I talked to him for two days He was like complaining of it.
Rym: I can't catch fish.
Rym: So I gave him some bait and he got really fucking jazzed about it.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: Yeah, it's like I mostly like, you know, I Other people seem to really want particular villagers to move because some of them are ugly or weird or terrifying.
Scott: They're kicking out villagers.
Scott: They don't like for me.
Scott: All the villagers seem kind of equal in man.
Scott: I don't really care about any of them.
Rym: I like a few.
Rym: I like.
Scott: I like the choice like the list of all villagers and like none of them were like Like.
Scott: oh man, that's a great villager.
Rym: I there's a few.
Rym: I like.
Rym: Isabelle's pretty chill, but she's not really a villager She's special.
Scott: No, it's like I have.
Scott: one of the ones I got immediately was puck the hockey playing penguin.
Scott: Oh, I want him He's okay.
Scott: He's you know, I guess he's maybe the.
Scott: I guess the two.
Rym: I started like I got plucky Who's just like chill and see I got deep down for whatever and I got the bird bro Pierce the lift weightlifting guy.
Scott: I have a. I have a bird bro who likes Exercising but I don't think his name is Pierce.
Rym: I forget their names.
Rym: I think it's Pierce.
Rym: I don't know the Animal Crossing characters names me either but that's so.
Scott: I guess I'm not really care too much about that part of The game.
Scott: I guess it's just you want to eventually get the maximum number of houses onto your island full of People because that's how you like get to the end game of the k/k slider concert, I guess If there is such a thing as Pierce Right.
Scott: It's like the game provides for you this path of Upgrading stuff where you get you you actually get the stuff then you pay off the loan afterwards.
Scott: But you don't have to pay off the loan because there's no interest and there's no due date.
Rym: Yeah, everybody's about Tom Nook wanton bells.
Rym: He doesn't want that many bells.
Scott: You could get a loan for your house upgrade it and literally never pay off that loan if you're satisfied with the current state of Your house.
Scott: Yep So that's like if I like in the real world.
Scott: Imagine like if I got a loan and bought a car and they said alright You only need to pay off that loan if you want to actually get a loan to buy a better car.
Scott: if you're satisfied with that car never pay the loan and Will be never charge your interest or come after you.
Scott: it's like oh, so the lowest level car is free is what you're saying.
Scott: Yeah, and the third is amazing.
Scott: Oh, you are I suspect the price of one lower level car.
Scott: if you could have you would have stayed in the tent forever Like you could pay off the price of your Honda Civic and then you'll give you a loan for a mercy for a Mercedes or a BMW and you could just not pay that off.
Rym: but I love you could how Tom Nook will like give me the loan But then I could deposit the entirety of what I owe him into my savings account and he'll pay me interest.
Scott: Yeah It's it's kind of.
Scott: it's not a real saying.
Rym: there's villages.
Rym: You're like what?
Rym: Oh Matilda She looks angry and she's got.
Rym: she's a kangaroo and she's got a little baby in her pouch who also looks angry.
Scott: I'm just saying none of the villagers particularly appeal to me like I'm oh man I want that one in my village.
Rym: I can see.
Rym: I definitely see some I do not want.
Scott: All right, they all seem kind of equal to me.
Scott: I'm not excited.
Rym: Lopez looks pretty good.
Scott: Yeah Yeah, so if you're someone who wants a video game that you know is it's not a completely an idle game like a candy Box because you have to do stuff.
Scott: It's not completely a cookie clicker because the stuff you're doing has a little bit of Thinking and paying attention, you know Just click mindlessly like you have to push a when the the bait on the end of the fishing rod starts to shake, right?
Scott: You have to sneak up on the bug and catch it.
Scott: You have two different bugs work different ways sometimes Right.
Scott: Yeah, you know, it's a. there's some definitely a lot of lottery aspects to it to keep you be You know the human mind trapped.
Rym: Yeah, but I guess things are rare.
Rym: Yeah, but what I?
Scott: there's a lot of gotcha aspects to it as in not as in got you as in got you But gotcha, I got you on.
Rym: but I guess what draws me to it Like what I think its main strength is like on a real meta level is that it's a game about mooching around like you've got This world.
Rym: you can kind of move around in it and there's a lot of different paths.
Rym: like the lanes you were talking about all those different lanes and pads are Reasonably satisfying to fuss with on their own.
Rym: So if you're just idle or bored or like it's evening you're laying in bed It's just a very calming chill game to go Like let's go talk to my villagers and chop some wood or I think that's that's the main thing in this game.
Scott: Is that you know, even in those other like idle games I mentioned, right?
Scott: There is still some kind of like pressure.
Scott: It's either pressure from the back right trying to make you go forward Right, like you're playing you're playing cookie candy box.
Scott: It's like well, alright, you got nothing going on right now You got to go go go get more candies get more lollipops, right?
Scott: Or if you're playing a normal at your average video game as pressure from the front you turn on Mario Brothers The goob is coming at you.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: You got to do something.
Scott: Are you Even Super Mario Brothers right?
Scott: or pac-man?
Scott: the ghost is coming at you do something, right?
Scott: You have to do things, you know, the game is attacking you in Animal Crossing.
Scott: There is no pressure from the front or back.
Scott: You can go forward if you want But like I said, the loans have no interest and no due date.
Scott: Yeah You can just move forward at any pace you like.
Scott: if you don't want a bigger house if you don't want Progress and get more stuff if you don't have to no one's making you do anything Yeah, you can just chill and play in the space that has been provided for you.
Scott: Right, and if you choose to do more stuff at whatever pace you do it at you will get more stuff eventually.
Scott: Right, there's no time limit.
Scott: There's no losing right.
Scott: even if you only like sell your fruit once a week Eventually, you'll pay off the loan.
Rym: the worst thing that can happen to you is you get stung by wasps twice or by a Tarantula once and pass out and it's like.
Scott: it's like, you know Some people like so upset that they pass out and I'm like, I don't even care if a wasp gets me.
Scott: What happens like teleport a few feet away in two seconds and I could right.
Scott: so I think the good aspect of this game is that and also the I guess it's simultaneously awesome, but also Unrealized potential.
Scott: Yeah, is that the previous Animal Crossing games had multiplayer components?
Scott: I think I'm not sure.
Scott: but I think the GameCube one used the online connector on the game Might.
Scott: I don't know about that for sure, but I think I remember it doing that.
Scott: I don't not a hundred percent this one.
Scott: Yes, the switch DS had the local wireless connectivity.
Scott: It never worked Right, it worked.
Scott: barely The DS wanted anyway, but then this one it had.
Scott: if you have Nintendo online it has Internet.
Scott: that sucks but works.
Rym: Yep, like it actually does work I've gone to other people's islands and boots around and then gone back to my caveman Island.
Rym: cuz I'm taking.
Rym: I'm playing the game Much more casually than a lot of our other friends, right?
Scott: So like you and this when it works, right the parts of it that do work work great and that you can sort of Experience this sort of like childlike Play with dolls Situations together, but that's it.
Rym: Like.
Rym: the way I'm experiencing this game is.
Rym: I'm just making this little village and like I'm putting trees in my house in a way That feels aesthetic for no particular reason and it's exactly the kind of mooching around play I would do with Legos as a kid, right?
Scott: Everyone's got a dollhouse.
Scott: That's a whole island.
Scott: Right, you can customize yours as much as you want.
Scott: you can Visit other people's.
Scott: they can visit yours.
Scott: Oh, right.
Scott: You can do stuff together.
Scott: Some parts are automatic.
Scott: some part are still a game Right.
Scott: It's like I could throw a fish bait and you can catch the fish.
Scott: All right, you could be like, hey Let's both chop down trees here.
Scott: Well, it'll we'll get it done twice as fast.
Scott: All right, there's all sorts like these things you can do Together with other people in a in a in a true social way not like a fake social way.
Scott: Yep, well like look at our farm bill a farm bill social way, right which is bullshit, right?
Scott: Yeah, where as Animal Crossing is like?
Scott: no you guys saw people in Animal Crossing for example.
Scott: They went to a friend's island all together and they went to the museum and they took photos together in the museum.
Scott: Yep, right and they went just as if they were going to a real museum or like you see people will like.
Rym: well like our Friends right now they're making spreadsheets and tracking the stock market and like coordinating investments.
Rym: Like there's a lot of ways to have fun with this game No matter what you want to do because it's still the same shield all house, right?
Scott: You can do whatever if you're into house customizing if you're into just the fishing right the collecting part you can do whatever part you want at any pace you want and It's alright.
Rym: Yeah, I think it is magical that this game came out during our current crisis because I think this game came out at the exact right time.
Scott: this this Came out at any other time.
Scott: I wouldn't have even bought it or a bit like another Animal Crossing game out.
Scott: Okay, whatever.
Rym: Yep But this is I think a lot of people are gonna get in for the first time and also honestly for kids This game is great.
Rym: This is just a kind of game.
Rym: You can park it get in front of forever and It's fine.
Rym: Like what they're doing in this game is fine.
Rym: They'll learn they'll have fun.
Rym: They'll poke around.
Rym: It's not that different than what they do with their toys.
Scott: It's definitely I think for some people it's good.
Scott: It's their main game.
Scott: For me I see it more of.
Scott: it's my game right now because the situation right now a long run It's like it's basically always your backup game.
Rym: Like I would I feel like years from now I'll just like poke in and like poke at my island a little bit and go see what someone else's islands do in and then Just turn it off right?
Scott: It's like, you know, if you if you're it's like I did, you know, I played my serious game.
Scott: I played my multiplayer game.
Scott: I did all the stuff that I'm really into and now I'm just chilling for a minute All right.
Scott: Well see what's on my island.
Scott: I'll pick some weeds sell some fruit and save.
Rym: there is one Very big problem with this game though.
Rym: If you have multiple players in your household You cannot have two independent games unless you have two independent switches, right?
Scott: Well, you sort of can.
Rym: right is that you can't drive the game forward.
Rym: You can only drive your own house upgrades forward.
Rym: You can't write.
Rym: any other events happen on the island.
Scott: So me and Rym had one switch in the house and we both live together.
Scott: One the first person to turn the game on and start the game is the person who like is the village representative Person who has to pay off, you know The the loans and move the main plot of the game forward.
Scott: the other person can still do all the stuff fishing Give things to the museum right You know all stuff right they can play the game, but they can't drive the main game forward.
Scott: they would have to share their resources with the main person so that they could then Use those efforts towards driving the game forward.
Scott: Yep Which is a
Rym: real
Scott: sort of all living together and working together in the same place But one person is in charge running the show Which is
Rym: a real shame because if you have like someone who has more than one kid Which kid gets to be the primary player?
Rym: because I'm not buying two switches like that is right.
Scott: that has caused big Copies of the game.
Rym: you can't know.
Rym: Okay, even if you have two separate cartridges it stores everything in the switch so you can study.
Scott: you can't even put on the SD Card if it switches D cards.
Rym: Nope, if you if I give you my cart and And then you give me your switch and we hand it to a third person and they start a game.
Rym: They'll be on your island because it's your switch.
Scott: Okay but anyway But yeah, sometimes that situation of being on the same island could be correct.
Scott: right like you could imagine a family.
Scott: We're like a four-person family and they all have houses on the island and they all work together.
Rym: Like Emily just moved into my island and we just kind of hang out and do the thing, but it's like that could be cool.
Scott: But sometimes it's not what you want if it's two adults living in the house.
Scott: They both want their own islands.
Rym: you now need two switches or our friend Other Scott his Kid started the game first and then he made the second account like not knowing this problem and the child is not Particularly engaged in driving anything forward.
Rym: So the island you just log in as the child And yeah, but now you gotta play games like that.
Scott: I feel like the problem.
Scott: I don't see a problem with that.
Scott: Just log in as the child and do the thing.
Scott: Yeah, the kid child might notice What are they gonna notice?
Scott: that there's now a new building on the island right?
Scott: You just tell them you did it.
Rym: I just feel like this was a weird omission like it.
Rym: I can't believe Nintendo didn't anticipate this being a big problem for people.
Scott: Nintendo definitely You know.
Scott: It's like I said There's so much missed Potential like the way the online works.
Scott: only eight people on an island at a time.
Scott: the island can only be so big.
Scott: The egg thing is man, right and the when you join someone else's island, right?
Scott: it's like there's this huge cutscene.
Scott: that cutscene is so fucking long and There's a lot of connection issues.
Scott: and think it's because Nintendo I think was Expecting this to be like children playing the game together like someone joining the island.
Scott: They would come and stay and play a while Yeah and you wouldn't have people coming in and out and in and out and in and out and in and out just to sell their Turnips and leave like with a chain of right.
Scott: We're definitely not playing the game as intended, right?
Scott: Yeah Don't.
Scott: brains can understand You know the systems and exploit them because they're not meant for adult.
Rym: Yeah And exploiting the systems is part of the fun for adults to like.
Rym: it's.
Rym: it's kind of fun to sell all your turnips for 600 bells apiece and make a fortune.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Well, I have the fortune now and now I don't need to play the stupid turnip game Ever anymore.
Scott: That's mostly why I did it.
Scott: Yeah, like I just want to have enough money.
Scott: I can stop grinding.
Rym: Yep, I'm just gonna keep doing what I'm doing.
Rym: I feel like for the long haul I'll just like poke at this game every day a little bit and like laying in bed.
Rym: I might just log out and just see what's doing and just sort of mooch around.
Scott: Yeah, and one thing that's nice about it I got to say is that for you know as much of a cookie-clicker idle, you know grindy game.
Scott: it is.
Scott: One thing they did that I wish other grindy games would do.
Scott: is they sort of mostly put caps on grinding ability.
Scott: Yeah, you can.
Scott: on your island you hit all your rocks up to eight times each a day.
Scott: Maybe you accidentally have so many rocks.
Scott: You can only you pick all your fruit.
Scott: Okay, I picked all my fruit.
Scott: You can go around catching bugs.
Scott: Eventually, you've caught every bug right?
Scott: It's like you can go keep fishing.
Scott: It's like you can keep doing those things there as long as you want.
Rym: Maybe I'll go to other islands.
Rym: Well, I only got so many nook miles.
Rym: I can only get some right.
Scott: You can't use your nook miles to get tickets to go to other islands to get more stuff.
Scott: But eventually it's like you're sort of gated.
Scott: It's like okay.
Scott: I've crafted everything I've got.
Scott: It's like this can't go that far right and because of the real-time clock unless you cheat and move your clock forward It's like okay.
Scott: I've done everything I can do today.
Scott: I can't play anymore today.
Scott: put the game down.
Scott: It doesn't keep you locked in grinding like a MMO does like you've done basically what you can do for today.
Scott: if you keep grinding You're you won't really make that much progress.
Rym: Yep, and also real time and it just makes it a nice sort of conference with for the real world.
Rym: Like if I log in at night, it's night the first day.
Rym: I played the game.
Rym: It was pouring rain outside.
Rym: So I turned the game on pouring rain.
Scott: I don't think it checks the real weather.
Rym: It did.
Rym: seems it's definitely I'm seeing for now I haven't seen it rain in my game except when it's been rainy in the New York area.
Scott: I'll have to check and see if it actually uses GPS and some weather day Under the impression the weather was random, but I could be wrong about that.
Rym: Yeah, it's happened to be since I bought the game if it's been rainy in this area It's been rainy in the game.
Rym: And when it's been sunny out, it's been not rainy in the game.
Scott: It's interesting.
Scott: Might just be a weird coincidence I think it might be.
Rym: but the day-night cycle to like get I get up in the morning my villagers are up to different stuff and Like blathers is like falling asleep because he's an owl and he wants to sleep.
Rym: Yeah, and like I go at night really a lot of villages like wandered around a lot at night But the other one's always asleep at night and there's like I like watching my villagers just do stuff.
Scott: Yeah, I mean regardless of my not caring about villagers just the aesthetic of the game I think is a large part of the appeal.
Scott: Oh, yeah You said you want to make stuff look a certain way and you wanna.
Scott: you know A lot of cute things and a lot of dialogue.
Rym: I spent a lot of time thinking about how to decorate the outside of my house.
Scott: Yeah, that kind of thing right the decoration aspect right is is a large part of it.
Scott: That doesn't require that much grinding actually the game.
Scott: if like you just want to decorate or dress up The game gives you plenty of clothes and furniture without much effort Yep, and also it doesn't fall into the trap Nintendo is repeatedly fallen into in the past.
Rym: It does not tie guy and girl like hairstyles to guy and girl selections, right?
Scott: You have to choose sort of like, you know, one of the two character model shapes at the start, but they're just two blobs.
Scott: Yeah, there's mostly two blobs.
Scott: I think it's more like what they start with.
Scott: clothing and hair wise is different by default But then you can customize them quite a bit terms of eyes and hair and stuff and then once you're in the game You can do whatever.
Scott: I could wear a skirt and get long hair and do whatever.
Scott: Yeah, so You do you can do you.
Rym: so the other thing apparently the game the other flaw the save data does not sync to the Nintendo online.
Rym: Yeah, so if your switch gets destroyed, you're just fucked.
Rym: It's all gone forever.
Rym: Fuck you.
Scott: That's true.
Rym: That is I feel like that is an even more glaring omission because Nintendo cannot be under the misapprehension That people will not care that much if they lose the 10 year long Animal Crossing game.
Rym: They've poured into their ancient dying switch.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Yep Oh the one last thing that genius thing that they added is the custom Build the custom artwork thing.
Scott: Yeah so you can make custom artwork on squares which can be used for various things like hanging up on the wall or Simple clothing and stuff like that.
Scott: Just you do pixel art in the game Yep.
Scott: And then you can just advanced pixel art you can do in the game pro designs for specific articles of clothing.
Scott: It's like I want to make a hat I want to make a hoodie and you can do pixel art on these templates to make custom clothing.
Scott: So I made like a boo hoodie, which has boo the ghost on it, right?
Scott: And as long as no one like reports you because you right well And then you can share your things online with other people, right?
Scott: You can use them in the game this QR code system.
Scott: There's all kinds of systems for sharing all these custom clothing designs and that requires absolutely no grinding whatsoever Like you.
Scott: just have that so you could start the game up and do very little grinding and as soon as you.
Scott: I guess I don't know if it's immediately unlocked, but it's very early unlocked.
Scott: the custom designer I think I think you know it's like a hole and it didn't take much.
Scott: Yeah, like that's a whole game in and of itself.
Scott: Just making clothing a lot like Second Life did right?
Scott: And I'm seeing like every single internet community I'm a part of whether it's a nerdy one or not.
Scott: Like I seen every single sports community I'm in New York Rangers Animal Crossing.
Scott: people are in the New York Rangers community being like I made hats I made jerseys I made whatever.
Rym: right, you know, it's like literally every fan every other fandom the creativity Into it, you know this overlaps with Diorama making - you're basically making a diorama to show to people.
Scott: I see so many tweets that are just an extremely Intricately well-crafted scene in Animal Crossing and the same literally every other community has people posting custom Animal Crossing Clothing for whatever that community is.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Look I made a stormtrooper in Animal Crossing.
Scott: Look, I made a right literally everything.
Rym: So I love how many people made prisons to lock that rabbit away.
Rym: Yeah, I Didn't have anything.
Rym: I just wasn't gonna make a bunch of fences cuz I didn't have enough wood handy.
Rym: So I just dug a pit around him and left him there.
Scott: So I say if you got a Nintendo switch and you're looking for you know It's like my Nintendo switch.
Scott: experience up until now was always You know play a game beat it and then not go back to the switch until there was a new game.
Scott: Yeah, right.
Scott: And Pokemon games?
Scott: I you know, I always ever sit.
Scott: the only Pokemon games I beat were the first two maybe Two or three and then after that I played every Pokemon game, but I would only get so many gyms.
Rym: I think I actually hear Animal Crossing happening in the other room right now.
Scott: Yeah, every other Pokemon game I would play some number of gyms and then stop right?
Scott: Whereas?
Scott: and that Pokemon could be your go-to game to fall back on?
Scott: Yeah, right, but I think for most people the Animal Crossing is actually the alright.
Scott: You got your switch.
Scott: games come out you play them Mario Odyssey comes out Zelda comes out you play them and you beat them But instead of putting your switch away you fall back to the Animal Crossing as the thing for your switch does.
Scott: Yeah, and now you're using it all the time, right?
Rym: Someone even updated the Wikipedia to say the game's success has been partially attributed to its release during the coronavirus pandemic.
Scott: It is.
Scott: it's absolutely true.
Scott: players seeking a sense of exaggeration Yeah, or joke in any way.
Scott: it even says it right here with players seeking a sense of normality amidst worldwide shelter-in-place orders Seeking normality, but I absolutely would not have bought it if I was not stuck inside with this much free time.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So yeah animal cry.
Rym: if you want to mooch around on an island make a diorama Talk to some animals and catch some fish like this.
Scott: game's pretty fun and you know, it's way better.
Scott: It's way better if you have friends who are into it so that you can do stuff together.
Rym: Yeah, or and also like there's there's a level of effort.
Rym: I'm not willing to put into a game like this, but I can Experience that level of effort via some of our more hardcore friends, right?
Scott: It's like the other people I think are like gonna play that stock market weekly, right?
Scott: I just wanted to do it to cancel grinding and now that I have I might once.
Rym: I'm a millionaire I don't need to be in the stock market anymore.
Scott: Yeah, me I'm not.
Scott: if I have enough money that I don't have to do it again I won't I'm not.
Scott: I'm just not sure if I have enough money or if I need to do it one more time.
Scott: No And anyway, all right Cross the animal.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at front row.
Scott: crew comm for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: Remember GeekNights is not one but four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays and my comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows.
Rym: It's actually recorded at night And the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce hiding McNichol Marty green.
Rym: Yeah, just like a dude guy.
Rym: chart option link EJ.
Rym: You hold the key to my car my heart.
Rym: I got in one little fight and my mom got scared.
Rym: Clinton Walton J Bats read from New Zealand.
Rym: Ryan parent drew open letter.
Rym: Nicholas Brando the thirst for hydrated Gannon dread Lily Tenebrae Chris Reimer Finn Sean Klein Thomas Hahn Sherman von Horl Sean Yeager and a bunch of other people who don't want me to say their name.
Rym: as you Probably noticed we're live streaming the show again bit by bit.
Rym: We're getting all our pipelines in place to continue to work through all the crisis that comes.
Rym: so Stay tuned for more Rym's rants every Friday on the patreon.
Rym: stay tuned for Scott and myself streaming some games in the FRC on official official discord and Pay attention to that forum thread about our community code of conduct.
Rym: We are soliciting suggestions and are rewriting that thing currently mostly to keep the Nazis out but anyway now I leave you with.