Rym: It's Wednesday, September 2nd, 2020.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, we are talking about The Spider-Man.
Scott: Let's do this!
Rym: So I haven't really been, like, taking days off work.
Rym: 'Cause usually in my normal life, I spend, like, every goddamn vacation day doing, like, the required family visit trips, and, like, all the conventions we perform at, and, like, one vacation.
Rym: And I'm always, like, down to my last half day of vacation time by the end of every year.
Rym: Like, I just use them all.
Rym: But this year, I can't really go anywhere.
Rym: Like, it feels weird to take a day, like, a vacation day to just not sit at my desk and work for half the day.
Scott: Well, I mean, if I'm sitting at home doing nothing, right, on my work day, I'm not gonna use a vacation day to do the same exact fucking thing.
Rym: I do more work than you do when I'm at home.
Scott: If I can't vacation, why am I spending a vacation day?
Scott: I'm just wasting it as bullshit, but I think they're only gonna let--.
Scott: I don't know, it's already September.
Rym: I can carry 10 days over to next year.
Scott: I can also carry 10 over, but I already carried--.
Rym: I've got 14 left.
Scott: I already carried 10 over.
Scott: Am I just gonna take off, like, a whole month or something?
Rym: Well, one thing that helped me is I was nearing vacation debt almost, because I took more time than usual off for all the, like, end-of-year cons last year, and then the start-of-year cons this year.
Rym: Like, I basically took a lot of extra days off around, like, MagFest and PacSouth and all that, so I was running near, like, I was scraping the bottom of the barrel, so I didn't bring any over from last year, but now I have 14 to use, and I gotta use at least four of them by the end of the year or I lose them.
Rym: So I'm using one on Friday.
Scott: I got way more than that, so...
Rym: 'Cause I used so many already.
Scott: I put on my task list to tomorrow figure out what to do with them.
Scott: I think I'm gonna not be working a lot the rest of the year now, actually, 'cause it's already September.
Rym: Yup.
Rym: I'm in the middle of big stuff at work, so I'm not gonna do that.
Rym: Also, I don't wanna take, like-- I definitely don't wanna take, like, a whole week off.
Scott: I've got a little big stuff, but I don't care how it works.
Rym: Yeah, so I'm basically-- I'm taking a day off Friday, 'cause I had that day off, like, already set up, ready for PAX.
Scott: Yeah, I guess I could do that if everyone else is.
Rym: Yeah, so I'm gonna have a four-day weekend.
Rym: This is the longest time off I've had since the quarantine started from working.
Rym: And I'll see if the weather's nice.
Scott: It's very-- One thing I noticed-- Seems like it's gonna be.
Rym: Normally in our lives, like, this time of year, we always go to Seattle.
Rym: And not every time-- Like, don't think that I'm saying every time we go to Seattle, but I feel like 80-ish percent of the times we've gone to Seattle over the years, it's unseasonably sunny during PAX.
Rym: while we're there, and everyone local is like, "Yeah, it's never this
Rym: sunny.".
Rym: It's like we're there during, like, the sunny weekend.
Rym: But now, the first time since 2008, we are not flying to Seattle for PAX.
Rym: It's been Seattle weather, like, all week here.
Rym: It's just, like, humid and overcast and chilly, and maybe it's us.
Scott: You think the weather just follows you.
Rym: Maybe the weather just follows us.
Rym: Uh-huh.
Rym: You and me.
Rym: GeekNights.
Scott: It wasn't the RIT president controlling the weather at RIT.
Scott: It was you the whole time.
Rym: It could have been both of us.
Rym: It could have been our powers combined.
Scott: It's still you.
Rym: Might be you.
Scott: We're the weather twins.
Scott: We touch each other, and then weather comes down.
Rym: Man, I just had to-- You even saying that weather machine thing just gave me this weird flashback to, like, freshman year at RIT.
Rym: And GDT in particular.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Yeah, it's Wednesday.
Rym: Talking about animation, comics, manga, anime, all that stuff.
Rym: You got any news or Geek Bytes or something to talk about?
Scott: There's not a lot of news going on for me to talk about, so I went down the Geek Bite hole, right?
Scott: People are going to say, "Scott, why are you reading comics if you're not reading the book club
Scott: book?".
Scott: It's like, "Yo, comic book takes, like, 10 minutes to read,
Scott: right?".
Scott: You know, you don't got to, like, sit down and, like, you know, warm up anything to read.
Scott: a, you know, like you do to read a giant enormous book like Telegenji.
Rym: Like, some comics, you can finish the whole thing in one poop.
Scott: Yeah, so I've had this book for a while.
Scott: It has a number one on the side of it, implying that it is volume one of more than one, but I can assure you it is one of one.
Scott: So this was kickstarted about two years ago.
Scott: It's called Bingo Love.
Scott: It's pretty straightforward.
Scott: It's a story about two black girls who were lesbians in, like, the 60s, and then they were separated.
Scott: You know, it's not a nonfiction story, but it doesn't have anything supernatural in it, right?
Scott: It could be real, right?
Scott: And I guess it has some future stuff in it, because part of the story takes place after 2020.
Scott: But regardless, there's nothing like sci-fi about that, right?
Scott: It's just, you know, whatever.
Rym: Yeah, that's just near future, let's go.
Scott: They were lesbians in the 60s.
Scott: They were separated by their, you know, very conservative 60s parents and church and such, right?
Scott: And then for 50 years, they didn't, you know, see each other.
Scott: And then suddenly, they saw each other after 50 years.
Scott: So this is kickstarted about a few years ago, and I knew about it then, but I didn't pick it up until Image published it.
Scott: All right, so Image, you know, this was originally published by, I think, Inclusive Press.
Scott: And the graphic novel was only like 80 or so, 90 pages, something like that, when it was kickstarted.
Scott: When Image picked it up, right, it already had sort of a thing, right?
Scott: So the new edition that I have, which is the Bingo Love jackpot edition, after the 80 page graphic novel concludes, the rest of the trade paperback.
Scott: Oh, this wasn't hardcover.
Scott: Now it's softcover.
Scott: That's when I was waiting for it.
Scott: Includes many stories written by fans that are, they're not necessarily, I guess they count as fanfiction, right?
Rym: They're not canon.
Scott: I think they are canon, and that they all are sort of either zooming in on parts of the story that the original didn't go into great detail on.
Scott: So there would be like, you know, what was this character doing?
Scott: You know, there's like one page, this person was doing something, right?
Scott: And it's like, you know, or I think one of them was like, oh, a granddaughter finds diaries and learns stuff, right?
Scott: About the, you know, the women, right?
Scott: So, yeah, it's written by T. Franklin.
Scott: And they think the artist was Jen St.
Scott: Onge.
Scott: I'm sorry if I mispronounced that last name.
Scott: It's S-T hyphen O-N-G-E.
Scott: The colors are by Joyce Ann.
Scott: Yeah, if you want to read some awesome gay romance book.
Scott: The art's pretty good.
Rym: I'm flipping through this.
Scott: It's pretty A+ and you can read it really quickly.
Scott: And it's a lot of fun too, right?
Scott: It's not just like, you know, a lot of times, you know, people, I think especially people who don't actually, you know, read a lot of romance stuff.
Scott: They think, you know, you see something like this, you think it's going to be all serious or, and it is part of it is serious, right?
Scott: But it's actually, it's not entirely serious.
Scott: It's plenty funny, you know, and it's still a comic book, right?
Scott: You still got comic book stuff going on in here.
Scott: So, and it's just one volume and it's now a trade paperback.
Scott: I don't think you can go wrong with this.
Scott: Lend it to everyone, you know, is the Kickstarter was funded in like, I think like a couple of days or something like that.
Scott: It was so popular.
Rym: Oh yeah.
Rym: Back in 2017.
Scott: It's an, it's a, it just took a while for like, you know, image to pick it up and then publish the jackpot edition and then publish the jackpot edition and soft cover.
Scott: So it's like, now you can get the book, right?
Scott: Um, and you don't have to have some hardcover thing.
Rym: Maybe I should borrow this from you and read it.
Scott: All right.
Scott: Coming where you can come and get it without getting disease.
Rym: We got to do like a blind drop, you know, actually that's just a total aside.
Rym: I don't know like the term for it or anything, but there was a type of trading that has been practiced in many parts of the world.
Scott: that was, you know, caching spoke.
Rym: It was trading in olden times specifically to trade goods while avoiding plagues between like communities that generally don't interact often.
Rym: Where like one group would leave goods out and leave and another group would come, they take the goods they wanted, they'd leave payments, they'd leave.
Rym: The first group would come.
Scott: And obviously that requires how you exchange money for hostages.
Rym: Uh, yeah, it's probably the same thing, I guess, except there's, you have to, like, I guess you have to trust each other a lot more because with the hostage, no third parties come along and take all the stuff.
Rym: That would have, that would be a good story.
Rym: The pirates and all they do is find those bazaars and rob them in between and then let them, and then convince the two parties that they're fighting with each other and just slip away.
Rym: All right.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: So in some other really brief news, if you didn't notice, uh, I'm making this news partly because there's so many online cons, but people aren't really going to them that often.
Scott: You just can't stop talking about the online cons.
Scott: Can you?
Rym: No, I'm saying, well, I don't have any other news.
Rym: You got any news?
Scott: I feel like we've said or anything there is to say about that.
Rym: We even did a show on it.
Rym: I just want to point out that the crunchy roll.
Rym: online expo is actually happening like in two days.
Rym: It is this weekend.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: There is a whole online con.
Rym: It's free.
Rym: You don't have to pay anything.
Rym: Uh, you basically go and register and you'll ever attend.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Just like go to their website and you register for a badge and they give you like this badge and it tells you how to access all their stuff and there's a schedule, the whole ass con in there.
Scott: So, uh, yeah, not a half ass con, a whole ass con.
Rym: I mean, there are definitely some half ass online cons.
Rym: They're at least trying to make this a whole ass con.
Rym: They got some legit guests.
Rym: So if you've been missing all those online cons and you're interested in anime, this is probably the one to check out because hopefully you listen to this episode before the con happened.
Rym: As opposed to how most people go, we're like, Oh, wasn't there going to be some sort of anime con?
Rym: Oh yeah, it was two weeks ago, I guess.
Rym: Oh, well, that seems to be like the story that goes for most of these online cons.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: I just don't have that much anything new to say about the online con.
Rym: Other than that, I think I might actually do some stuff at this con.
Rym: I think I watch a few panels.
Scott: There's some decent- If I remember to, I will, I put a reminder of when our panel is, so I'm going to at least do that.
Rym: And there's, yeah, we'll, we'll like either live tweet or answer questions.
Rym: We'll figure out, we'll be accessible online during our panel to like answer questions or, uh, argue with you when you have a really stupid opinion and you really liked that titty anime that we made fun of.
Scott: I guess the thing is when you're at a con, right?
Scott: You're sort of like, all right, I'm here.
Scott: I'm going to get my time and I put effort to get here.
Scott: I spent money to get here.
Scott: I'm going to get my money's worth.
Scott: My job's worth.
Scott: You look at the schedule, you make a schedule, you stick to it.
Scott: You try to get, you try to squeeze entertainment at it.
Rym: You go to things you might not otherwise go to.
Rym: That's an important part.
Scott: Yeah, of course.
Scott: But if I'm at home, I'm not captive by that con, especially if it's a free one, like this Crunchyroll Expo.
Scott: So if I'm not a captive to it, it's like, if I don't, like, I could go through the schedule and like add stuff to my schedule, but if I don't feel like it, I'll just do something else.
Scott: I'm at home.
Scott: I didn't, I'm not losing anything.
Rym: If I don't, I won't pretend when I'm at a con that there aren't some panels I go to because no one's ready to play a game right now.
Rym: I've got an hour to kill.
Rym: It's not a good time to eat.
Rym: I'll go to that panel that looked like it might be okay.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like, you know, a GDQ, for example, I look at the schedule.
Scott: I've marked out which ones I kind of want to check out, but it's like, yeah, if I miss them, I miss them.
Scott: I don't care.
Scott: I don't, you know, if I, it's like, I'll just watch the VOD or something, or if they didn't even have the VOD, I would still wouldn't be that upset about it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I, I could just go find the person who does that speed run and watch them on Twitch or something.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, you know, if I miss a panel at a con and it's never, there's no video of it ever.
Scott: It's like, I can find that information if I really needed to find the person who did the panel, something, right.
Scott: It's not the end of the world.
Scott: I've missed a lot of panels in my day.
Rym: Oh, so there's one.
Rym: I was just flipping through the schedule.
Rym: There's one I saw.
Rym: I don't want to go to it, but it just, it's interesting.
Rym: Uh, you know, often at anime concert, we used to go, we would run the, how to run an anime club panel because that's someone else is doing it.
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Someone else is doing it here.
Rym: You know who it is?
Rym: It's our friends at UC Davis.
Rym: That was the other like big anime club that we would talk to sometimes.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: They would, uh, definitely, I remember contact them contacting us more than one time.
Rym: They contacted us once or twice with like collaboration ideas and they contacted us once to warn us about that one thing.
Scott: Oh, right.
Scott: That was them.
Rym: That was them.
Rym: They warned us about that thing.
Rym: And then, and we, uh, we didn't take their warning seriously.
Rym: And then the thing happened and it was, we did take their warning somewhat seriously.
Rym: Well, I took it seriously.
Scott: It wasn't like that.
Scott: much we could do about it.
Rym: The moment I saw the individual in question and my brain said, I'll bet that's him.
Rym: But anyway, things of the day.
Rym: So check this out.
Rym: There's been a lot of movement lately in AI rendering, like using neural networks and machine learning to either accelerate like rendering, like taking a project, like a video game, you know, a video card renders the things you're supposed to see and put some on the screen or rendering streaming video in real time.
Rym: And maybe you got to like get this 4k stream out there or something.
Rym: So there's been a lot of advancements recently in using AI to do that sort of thing, to take something that needs to be encoded or rendered and render it faster because the AI will maybe figure out efficient or clever ways to achieve the intent, even though it might not necessarily render exactly what the algorithm someone would have normally used would have rendered like that.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, we're using this a lot at the most, I guess, you know, the biggest use of machine learning these days is like image recognition technology is definitely one of the most advanced, you know, use cases for machine learning, but very closely related to that, you know, is, you know, prediction, right?
Scott: So you look at like, you know, deep fakes and stuff, right?
Scott: It's like, it's basically almost the same, the same kind of code does both things, right?
Scott: It's like, pick a face out of a picture.
Scott: Well, now I can put a face in a picture, right?
Scott: I can.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So that same stuff can now be used to animate.
Scott: It's like, okay, I drew two frames, right?
Scott: We already have just straight up interpolation that people use.
Rym: Yeah, but that tends to make that very like linear, like it looks cheap animation.
Scott: People use just straight up interpolation to make like a 30 FPS video into a 60 FPS.
Rym: And they just look weird at best.
Scott: Yeah, by just calculating the in between frames, just like by averages.
Rym: But what if an AI was like, oh, that is an object moving downward.
Rym: It should accelerate more like that kind of thing could happen.
Scott: Yeah, exactly.
Scott: So you could use that same technology to like in between some animations.
Scott: There's no technological reason that you couldn't.
Scott: And if it was good enough, it would look as good as deep fakes look, right?
Scott: At least given modern computing power and such.
Rym: Oh, no.
Rym: So my thing of the day, I was not going to talk about the algorithm and just talk about the thing, but I learned the name of the of the thing of the thing.
Rym: And now I have to talk about this.
Rym: God damn.
Rym: So basically, you know, those old Fleischer Studios Superman cartoons that were like rotoscoped and I just watched.
Scott: I just watched one the other day.
Rym: They're like, they're really like high quality animation.
Rym: Like those things look great, but they're old too.
Rym: This is from like the forties.
Rym: So this YouTuber took one of the episodes from that.
Scott: The bullet.
Scott: This is the thing I watched the other day.
Scott: I watched this.
Rym: Oh, this is why you watch the bullet tears.
Rym: OK, OK, that's good.
Rym: So you've seen this.
Rym: So they used an upscaler that is called waifu 2x, which is basically a convolutional neural network thing that was trained on anime, just like contemporary anime.
Rym: And they just applied it with some constraints to one of like the highest quality video we had of one of these old Fleischer Brothers cartoons.
Scott: And they chose it, by the way, because it's in the public domain, even though Superman, the character is not necessary.
Scott: This is just free.
Rym: I made this video, the original Superman.
Rym: So they upscaled this old thing to 4K and holy shit, like it just looks better.
Rym: There's been two ads detail that was not there.
Rym: And the detail makes sense, is consistent, is aesthetic.
Rym: It's kind of amazing.
Scott: It's also a really good cartoon.
Rym: It is a really good cartoon.
Rym: I love the concept, but like the the villain in this one episode, their superpower or their tool is just amazing.
Scott: Also, it's just.
Rym: it's a car that Rams shit, but it's really just a fighter jet.
Rym: that Rams shit.
Scott: It's also.
Scott: I love those old ones because it's still jumping Superman and not flying Superman.
Rym: Also, it's got like this is the kind of aesthetic like.
Rym: this is the same reason why I like BTS so much.
Rym: Like it's a striking aesthetic.
Scott: Oh, yeah.
Scott: It's art deco.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: So check this out.
Rym: Like you can watch my thing of the day.
Rym: The page is great.
Rym: It has a YouTube video of the original and YouTube video of the upscaled one.
Rym: And it's just kind of amazing how good this algorithm was at making this look better.
Scott: So what do you got?
Scott: So 14 years ago, when GeekNights wasn't even like a year old guy, Liam Kyle Sullivan uploaded a famous video music video to the Internet.
Scott: Oh, my God.
Scott: She's right.
Scott: And that was a thing of the day in 2006 when it was brand new.
Scott: And just like GeekNights has refused to die, Liam Kyle Sullivan is still at it.
Scott: Oh, my God.
Rym: I'm scrolling through their upload history.
Rym: Yeah, there's a lot there.
Scott: And just yesterday's 2020, Liam released a new video masks, which is so this isn't like someone else taking this.
Scott: Oh, my God.
Scott: Shoes and switching it to masks.
Scott: This is the original person doing it to themselves before you watch.
Scott: Oh, my God.
Scott: Masks.
Rym: You should really watch shoes.
Scott: You should rewatch or watch for the first time.
Scott: Oh, my God.
Scott: Shoes.
Rym: It's easy to find the first video on their channel, right?
Scott: I think this actually there's a more recent.
Scott: I think they did an HD.
Rym: They did a full version, too.
Scott: Yeah, there's an HD remaster of shoes.
Scott: But you can see that many of the things from the original shoes video managed to make a comeback like the guy in the purple costume and such.
Scott: It's like 14 years later, Liam managed to get those people, you know, to reprise their roles as necessary for a tale for the present times.
Scott: So, yeah, Liam still do a good work out there.
Scott: I hope 14 years from now, Liam puts out another great music video.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: I always enjoy when I find this has been a trend with us, you and me, like just not an Internet trend, just us where we'll find like a YouTube channel that does something that really, really like works for us.
Rym: And then we discover that that channel just keeps making that exact same thing.
Rym: I do remember the one that was that it was like Zelda characters licking each other with the weird tongues.
Scott: Yeah, that's you.
Rym: Yeah, I recall you laughing at that.
Rym: I think you're the one who showed that to me, not the other way around.
Rym: I don't know what Lincoln video you're thinking of.
Rym: I remember this is not Pokemon master sex.
Scott: No, oh, yeah, I guess that's just just a tiny note of the Pokemon master sex.
Scott: So we should explain that there was some Pokemon thing that got released recently that was called.
Scott: the actual name of it was Pokemon Masters EX.
Scott: This is a pan island situation, sort of like F zero G X. Yeah, it's Pokemon Masters EX.
Scott: But obviously you take the S off the end of the word master and now it's Pokemon master sex.
Scott: And that became a Twitter hashtag.
Scott: Go to Twitter and type hashtag Pokemon master sex and you will see some amazing tweets.
Rym: Yep.
Rym: So I would say it's one third really funny tweets, two thirds horny tweets.
Rym: But of the horny tweets, it felt like it was one third Pokemon character like sexy stuff.
Rym: And the other third was Pokemon characters with Pokemon sexy stuff.
Rym: Yeah, that hashtag was that was a trip.
Rym: And we'll leave it at that.
Rym: You can go look for this yourself if you want.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So we left plenty of time for the actual main bit in this show.
Rym: But first, I'm at a moment.
Rym: Of course, we are going to be live at the Crunchyroll Expo doing judge anime by its cover.
Rym: We talk about some anime that we had not seen since we recorded this.
Rym: I have actually looked at some of the shows we reviewed and we were pretty spot on.
Rym: Well, those shows were exactly what we said they were going to be like.
Rym: I don't think we are who we thought they were.
Rym: So Friday, like in a couple of days on the stage at seven thirty p.m.
Rym: Eastern Daylight Time, we will be presenting judge anime by its cover.
Rym: We'll probably put it up on YouTube somewhere later.
Rym: But for now, the only way to see it is to go to the free Crunchyroll Expo.
Scott: And of course, so have officially are on the now public schedule of PAX online, which is going to be a week long.
Scott: It's not only going to be a week long across three Twitch channels, but it's covering and West together combined.
Scott: So depending on what you look at the schedule, don't be confused.
Scott: At the top of the schedule, it's like late at night and like and it's showing you the Australian content.
Scott: You scroll down.
Scott: There'll be like a gap while everyone's sleeping and then there'll be the PAX West content.
Scott: And so basically it's like so many days long and 24 hours.
Scott: The content isn't running constantly.
Scott: For example, our panel is in packs the third channel, but that doesn't appear to yet be any content on the schedule and the other two channels at the same time as us.
Rym: Maybe that'll change.
Rym: Like, you know, cons go like we used to run.
Scott: Yeah, of course.
Scott: I'm sure the schedule isn't final, but there is a lot of content on there.
Scott: It's just because it's so many days and 24/7, it's not 100% full.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: And they'll be gaming and stuff like if nothing else.
Rym: during this packs, Scott and I and a bunch of our friends, the crew we normally go to PAX is with.
Rym: We're going to be online, like looking for people to just play games with.
Rym: If you want to play Rude, get into some tabletop simulator, play some Overwatch with me.
Rym: I'm going to take some days off, be playing some games, and I will gladly play games with random people on the internet.
Scott: Yeah, as long as depending on what game it is, sure.
Rym: Yeah, you want to play some Overwatch with us?
Rym: You want to try it?
Scott: I will also repeat my offer.
Scott: Anyone who wants to learn to play 18XX, I will give you free personal lessons on how to play train games.
Rym: He's not kidding.
Rym: He's done it.
Rym: I watched him do it.
Rym: It was great.
Rym: And then we played a game.
Rym: The listeners, we've actually now we've been playing this game with the listener quite a bit and the listeners are getting better and better.
Scott: Yeah, you could be the other listener.
Rym: Yeah, we could have two listeners playing the game.
Scott: If we get five listeners, they could play with themselves.
Rym: You don't need to play with them.
Rym: And then our mission is complete.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I'm feeling this 1882.
Rym: I was skimming through the rules of it.
Scott: No, whatever.
Rym: There could be a different number of one of the trains, like an extra two or an extra four.
Scott: All right.
Scott: The book called Book is still the Tale of Genji, the first novel that was ever written by human beings.
Scott: We still are going to continue reading it at some point.
Scott: when we read again, which is I don't know when that will be.
Rym: I think when it might be is when it is too cold for us to do long bike trips.
Rym: We'll be inside and we might actually like sit and read.
Scott: Maybe.
Rym: Or we might be working on another secret project.
Scott: So stay tuned.
Scott: Who knows?
Scott: Who knows what I have?
Rym: I read the first bit of it.
Rym: I was going to keep reading.
Rym: I do want to read it.
Rym: I enjoyed what I read so far.
Rym: Just don't have time.
Scott: Yeah, I think it's.
Scott: I think there's this thing people seem to think that, like, like somehow some people like just give up on this book and change books.
Scott: And I'm like, I got no problem doing that.
Scott: If we somehow pick a book that I didn't realize was garbage and we start reading it and it's just like, you know what?
Scott: Unpick.
Scott: I got no problem doing that, even though we haven't done it.
Scott: I got no problem.
Rym: But I want to read this.
Rym: If we pick a different book, I would be.
Rym: We haven't read the three body problem yet.
Scott: Yeah, it could have been any book.
Scott: It was just the timing of the book that was selected.
Scott: Not the not the book.
Rym: You know, you blame blame the coronavirus.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: Because I'm not on the subway reading a book like I normally would.
Scott: Granted, people were saying that, you know, just give up on it before the virus.
Scott: Yeah, but if it wasn't for the virus, I think I would have finished reading this.
Rym: Oh, definitely.
Rym: Also, I would have had like five or six international flights in the time that we have been stuck at home.
Rym: So I definitely would have cranked this out.
Scott: Like I would have had many sit, you know, go sit in the park despite it being crowded because there isn't a plague situations.
Rym: All right.
Scott: I would have had many bikes somewhere and take a train home and read on the train home situation.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: In fact, I probably would have read if we hadn't finished it somehow.
Rym: I probably would have read it on the flight to Seattle.
Scott: Yep, probably.
Rym: But here we are.
Rym: So otherwise, like Google for GeekNights, find our Discord, our forum, Scott's YouTube channel, my YouTube channel, us at these conventions.
Rym: We're in a lot of places.
Rym: We're making stuff and we've set up pipelines to make things more efficiently during this long running crisis.
Rym: So hopefully you'll start seeing more fruits of that labor.
Rym: But also we're doing a lot of low tier, low effort stuff.
Rym: that's just fun.
Rym: Like sometimes in the Discord, Scott will just stream a game he's playing or I'll just stream like some random thing I'm working on.
Scott: Yeah, lately these days on my Twitch channel, since I got the old bike trainer and I'm biking to nowhere, just biking in my apartment going nowhere.
Scott: But I got this little game that goes with it called Zwift, which is like the little bike training game.
Scott: And I've been doing that like more than every other day.
Scott: And then I set it up so it's very easy for me and low effort to stream it on Twitch, which is not really so much about you watching me bike to nowhere, even though you can do that.
Scott: It's more about like, hey, I'm doing nothing and I can chat with people on like, you know, I tried streaming other video games like Paper Mario.
Rym: That's why I stopped that Xcom stream.
Rym: That's a lot of effort to keep that energy up for like, it's hard to chat.
Scott: It's hard to chat with people and play the game and focus on the game and get enjoyment out of the game while chatting like it doesn't work too well.
Scott: But just biking in place like I kind of need someone to chat with.
Scott: So the streaming part is more like, hey, you know, come chat with if you want to just chat with me.
Scott: Wait, go look at follow my Twitch channel.
Scott: And then, you know, you'll see a notification like he's going live on bike.
Scott: You'll see me bike in there, but you can just chat with me.
Scott: And that I don't know.
Scott: I'm not looking for a lot of viewers.
Scott: I just need like one person to be like, hey, what you do?
Scott: It doesn't have to be about bikes.
Scott: I'll chat about whatever.
Rym: What you doing?
Scott: Yeah, that's going to get a ban.
Scott: Don't make me get off the bike and have to click the ban.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So this is a show that is very broad because we're covering a huge area.
Rym: The concept of the Spider-Man.
Scott: So, you know, I don't want to just like start a series of shows on like underwear.
Scott: Don't worry.
Rym: We're not next.
Rym: Two weeks from now is not Batman.
Scott: For sure it isn't.
Scott: No, but Spider-Man is like, you know, obviously a legendary iconic world famous hero, right?
Scott: That means many things to different people has a long history, right?
Rym: 1962 to today, pretty much nonstop.
Scott: So I think like, no matter who you are at this point in the world, right?
Scott: It's like, uh, you know, I think most people in some way have, at least depending on where you live, right?
Scott: At least, especially where we live in the English speaking world, but also the not English speaking world, the Spider-Man has touched your life in some way and not in an inappropriate way.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Not the Spider-Man experience in Wildwood.
Scott: No, not that.
Rym: There's, there's this old, there was this old like rundown amusement ride.
Rym: that like wasn't admin active for decades.
Rym: But so imagine seeing this like dilapidated trailer looking thing and there's a broken down sign that literally just says the Spider-Man experience and points at this boarded up door.
Scott: So I feel like, you know, and I, you know, a lot of, uh, you know, superhero academic people always try to go down this angle, but I don't think it's wrong to do so as they talk about some of the legendary superhero stuff as being just like, you know, the same way you would talk about like, you know, Greek mythology, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: It's like, you know, I think it's fair, like any random person I talked to, like, I assume they have a passing knowledge of Hercules.
Rym: Like if I referenced Hercules in any conversation I have with pretty much anyone, I expect that they would at least recognize, Oh, that big strong Greek guy who did some stuff like that.
Rym: If they got that far, that's enough.
Rym: Spider-Man's really the same way.
Rym: Like I assume anyone I talked to is, is familiar on some level with Spider-Man.
Scott: But also I imagine if you were in ancient Greece, right?
Scott: It's like Hercules means something to you, right?
Scott: It has like relevance to your life, right?
Scott: Like you could ask if you could speak ancient Greek and talk, go to Athens, you could say, Hey, what is, uh, what does Zeus mean to you?
Scott: And just about everyone would have some kind of answer, right?
Scott: Of how the story of Zeus, the fiction, the mythology of it has some relevance to their life or meaning to them positively or negatively.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So, yeah.
Scott: So of course, Spider-Man means something to us.
Rym: You know, all I can imagine is like, if you're in Athens, better watch out.
Rym: Diogenes might argue with you and then piss on you.
Scott: So for me, Spider-Man is like, compared to all the other superheroes, I just feel like.
Scott: there's a lot, you know, people always say like they identify with, right?
Scott: But it's like, I don't really identify with, I don't feel like I am Spider-Man.
Rym: You're not reincarnated Spider-Man about to form Spider-Man house?
Scott: No, but there's so many things about Spider-Man that I feel are about me also, right?
Scott: It's like, he's just some nerdy kid, right?
Scott: Obviously I was a nerdy kid.
Scott: I'm now a nerdy old guy.
Rym: Wisecracken New Yorker.
Rym: You got that down.
Scott: New York is big in Spider-Man, right?
Scott: He cares about New York.
Scott: He's from Queens, right?
Scott: I'm not as much from Queens as Spider-Man is, but at least I'm far.
Scott: And that's all, of course, this is only one of the Spider-Mans.
Scott: There are many Spider-Mans, which I think is also important, right?
Scott: It's like, oh, there's a Spider-Man who's like me.
Scott: Well, no matter who you are, there's this Spider-Man that's like you.
Scott: They've made so many Spider-Mans.
Rym: In fact, the Spider-Verse sort of makes that canonical that there's a Spider-Man for everybody.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, whatever Spider-Man you are, it's like, yeah, there's one that's you.
Scott: It's like, hey, that's me.
Scott: Only swinging around, right?
Rym: But even when I was a kid, I didn't read a lot of comics.
Rym: I didn't get into X-Men or floppy comics until way later elementary school, like early middle school, but I always knew the deal with Spider-Man specifically, way more than any other comic character to the point that I could not say when I encountered Spider-Man.
Scott: No, it's just like you just sort of always knew it existed, right?
Scott: It's like, when did you know Mickey Mouse existed?
Scott: Like it just always did.
Scott: It was just always there.
Scott: But you can imagine like old people, like there was a time when Spider-Man didn't exist.
Rym: Well, I got, you know, we're old enough to be like, yeah, I remember when Pokemon came out.
Rym: There was no Pokemon before that.
Rym: That was like, I was in like high school.
Scott: That's right.
Scott: Kids today, you know, Pokemon just always been there, right?
Rym: You know, I wonder this is a total aside.
Rym: Does Spider-Man or Pikachu have more name recognition among the population of the earth?
Scott: Tough to say.
Rym: I think that would be a real tough race.
Rym: I think that could be real close.
Scott: It used to be that just Mickey Mouse was just like number one by a landslide.
Scott: But now there's several competitors in that arena.
Scott: There's Hello Kitty.
Scott: There's, what's it called?
Scott: Obviously, Pikachu, Pokemon, Mario, Sonic.
Scott: the Hedgehog is up there.
Scott: In terms of like, you know, fictional cartoon characters.
Rym: Let's leave out the hell streamers and YouTube shouty men.
Rym: Hopefully they're a flash in the pan.
Scott: That are, that have the most recognition worldwide, right?
Scott: You know, the Bugs Bunny is still high up there, although less so than it used to be.
Scott: There's a lot.
Rym: But I guess I have this weird like memory of always liking Spider-Man before I really even consumed much Spider-Man media.
Rym: Like I liked Spider-Man before I read any Spider-Man, but I don't know why.
Rym: I just liked Spider-Man.
Rym: I liked the character and I liked the concept, but there was a time in my life where I felt that way, but I had literally not read a single Spider-Man comic of any kind at any point.
Scott: See, for me, it was like, you know, I didn't consider myself, like if you said things you like, like Spider-Man would not come on the list, would not come to mind, right?
Scott: It might not even come to mind if you ask me now.
Scott: Like, what are things you like, Scott?
Scott: It's like, I'm not gonna say Spider-Man.
Scott: K-Pop.
Scott: Right, yeah.
Scott: That'll come to mind right now, right?
Scott: But the thing is, if I actually go and read a Spider-Man, it's like, oh shit, this stuff is good, right?
Scott: It's like, I'm loving reading this Spider-Man right now, you know?
Scott: When I was a kid, I didn't even read a lot of actual Spider-Man.
Scott: I read Spider-Man 2099.
Scott: Yeah, I know.
Rym: That's why I kept telling you, go see Spider-Verse.
Rym: He's in it and I was not lying.
Scott: Not really.
Rym: But I was not lying.
Scott: But yeah, Spider-Man 2099 was cyberpunk plus Spider-Man.
Scott: But the character of, you know, Miguel O'Hara, which is Spider-Man 2099, is just sort of an asshole.
Scott: He's not like a good kid like Peter Parker.
Scott: He's just this jerk who gets power.
Scott: His brother's actually a good guy.
Rym: I feel like I did see a lot of the old like really low budget Spider-Man cartoon, but that was like kid brain.
Scott: Spider-Man and his amazing friends or Spider-Man the 90s one or...
Rym: The 60s like bad one.
Scott: Spider-Man and his amazing friends.
Rym: Yeah, I'm pretty sure it's that one.
Scott: Spider-Man, Spider-Man.
Rym: That's the one I remember.
Scott: That one?
Rym: I think so.
Rym: I think I was interested in that because I'm just trying to think back.
Rym: like these are memories coming as I really strive because when I was really, really, really young, we had to do the entire 2600 and one of the cartridges we had was really colorful compared to the other ones and it was Spider-Man.
Rym: And I think I want like my parents would always like when I put that game on, I just have memories of like my parents like, oh, Spider-Man, like they talk about Spider-Man because they read Spider-Man.
Rym: They were like deep into superhero comics and shit.
Rym: So like my uncle and my parents would like talk about Spider-Man a lot and I think I absorbed my fondness for Spider-Man from them and they were only talking about it because I was the little kid playing the Atari and they were adults probably like hanging out and drinking in the room and just like talking about Spider-Man.
Rym: So I wonder if the kids that are like around us at our parties will have like fond memories of the video games that we talked about.
Scott: So things about Spider-Man that are cool and I think this applies to all the different, most of the Spider-Man incarnations.
Rym: Yeah, we can ignore like the number one exception.
Scott: Spider-Man is usually, right, a, you know, he's primarily a journalistic photographer, right?
Scott: But he's also been like a teacher or, you know, he's always in some sort of admirable profession, right?
Scott: I guess he's sometimes a high school student.
Rym: Yeah, but he's doing good work, trying hard in his real life, irrespective of spider powers.
Scott: Which is also, you know, Superman as well is just a journalist straight up, right?
Scott: But, you know, he's always, you know, he's, so he's doing admirable, important work, right?
Scott: Alongside his Spider-Manning.
Scott: But unlike, you know, Superman is a journalist, right?
Scott: It's like he goes out and he'll, he's not journalisting while he's Superman, right?
Scott: Lois Lane is journal.
Scott: He's, he's sort of creating a scene, making sure Lois Lane sees him so she can write about what he's doing, right?
Scott: Spider-Man is like sticking a camera on the wall while he fights a villain to make sure he gets some photos of himself, right?
Scott: So it's sort of a different situation there.
Rym: I, that's, I think what I, one of my favorite bits about Spider-Man in general was like, he had to have a hustle to make it work with the like pictures of Spider-Man thing.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: I enjoyed like, it was just portrayed like he has to like get a picture of himself solving this crime.
Scott: I remember in the, uh, there was a, there's a super, uh, Sega Genesis, uh, Spider-Man game.
Scott: I think it might just be called Spider-Man.
Scott: It was, it was the first Spider-Man game for the Genesis.
Scott: And what you'd have to do is when you'd get like a boss, like I remember like is Dr.
Scott: Octopus fight him, but you take a photo of him first and then you'd fight him, right?
Scott: It had like a button to take photos of stuff.
Scott: That was like part of the thing.
Scott: Um, but also right, uh, much, you know, still relevant today as it was in the sixties.
Scott: Right.
Scott: You know, obviously the secret identity was a trope of all superheroes back then.
Scott: Um, but Spider-Man was, you know, a normal person living a normal life.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Whereas, you know, you look at some of the other superheroes that ha even if they had secret identities, they didn't necessarily always have a very good reason for them.
Scott: Like Batman.
Scott: It's like, if people knew Bruce Wayne was Batman, it's like Bruce Wayne's a rich dude.
Scott: It's not actually sort of a big problem for him.
Rym: Or he doesn't need an alter ego because based on many portrayals of Batman, he's just, he could just be like, Oh yeah, that's where the crazy old billionaire lives.
Rym: And just like be invisible to society and just be Batman full time.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But Spider-Man has like, you know, depending on what time it is, right.
Scott: He's got, he has a family, he's a normal person.
Scott: He has a wife, right.
Scott: At some points.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, he's protecting those people, not him himself.
Scott: In the same way that like doxing of internet celebrities is a thing these days.
Scott: Right.
Scott: It's like, you know, he wasn't so much protecting himself as he was protecting these other people around him.
Scott: You know, cause he had fame, right.
Scott: He didn't necessarily want to be famous.
Scott: You know, he just wanted to, you know, to, to do well, right.
Scott: With his powers.
Rym: And he's often very zoomed in like the wisecrack in like with one random kid on the street as a little aside before like the other story starts.
Scott: Spider-Man always, you know, the other superheroes, right.
Scott: They do, you know, the smallest thing Superman does is catch someone falling off a building.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Superman doesn't go and like play basketball with the kids.
Scott: But Spider-Man does that not only in comics, but like in real life, people put on a Spider-Man costume and play basketball with the kids.
Scott: And it's like, even though, right, like someone else putting on some other superhero costume, even a Spider-Man one doing shit, like shaking down tourists for money and photos or, you know, birthday parties and stuff.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But it's like, if you do that in a Spider-Man costume, as opposed to like an Iron Man costume, it feels kind of real actually, even as an adult.
Scott: It's like, yeah, that's your friend in a Spider-Man costume at the kid's birthday party.
Scott: But it's like Spider-Man, the real Spider-Man would totally do that.
Rym: So I'm pretty sure Spider-Man has like literally shown up at a kid's birthday more than once in it, in like all the different runs of Spider-Man.
Scott: I think I was in like, uh, I think I had like a high school.
Scott: I knew it was when I was in high school, it was my brother's friends in high school who did that, like as a job, just like being Spider-Man at kid's birthday parties.
Scott: And it's like, it's a good deal.
Scott: But also like you could take, if you're a kid in this fight, it's like, if you're a kid in Batman shows up, it's like, you sort of know it's not Batman.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: But, uh, the one thing I have not read is many Spider-Man comics.
Scott: I've read, I've
Rym: seen many of the movies, uh, with, but I never particularly liked that many of them until Spider-Verse, which was just such a triumph that
Scott: the live action movies may, some
Rym: of them were, some of them were better than others, but
Scott: I've only seen one and may.
Rym: I've seen several first one, the first Toby McGuire one I liked pretty well.
Scott: Is that's, that's the, probably the one I saw, right?
Scott: The upside down kiss one.
Rym: Yeah.
Scott: Yeah, whatever.
Rym: Cause in that era, like superhero movies were particularly bad and that one, the Spider-Man one was actually, they're also particular.
Scott: That was like when they started becoming a thing.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Now there's too much of a thing.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So, I mean, of the Spider-Man comics that I have read, right.
Scott: It's like, you know, there are sort of different kinds of them.
Scott: They go into different categories, right?
Scott: It's like a lot of the old ones, the super old ones, like the actual Stanley, Steve Ditko ones, some of them are obviously super corny and old.
Scott: But along with their corny and oldness, they also have some really impactful stories, really similar to what you get with Fantastic Four, which is also, you know, I guess that's a Stan Lee and Kirby joint, but I guess it's a Stan Lee thing, right.
Scott: Where it's like, you're sort of mixing the corniness with also, you know, they're very sort of powerful human tales, right.
Scott: And if you just, you can figure out which issues, right.
Scott: Like there's the famous one where he's trapped under all the, the, the machine that like collapsed in on him and there's like, it takes him several pages.
Scott: It's like lift the machine off of himself while he talks to himself.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's like, that's the same comics exactly where you get really corny stuff.
Scott: Like why is cracking it really corny as villains that no one remembers.
Rym: But one thing I liked is that the Spider-Man's wisecracking, even in the early comics was always just better written and fit better in the universe than most of the other superheroes that were trying to wisecrack or talk to themselves or talk to the, like talk to the reader.
Scott: Well, I think, uh, Dan Slott, who actually is an ex who's wrote Spider-Man for MIT for a long, long time, actually more recently.
Scott: Um, and Dan Slott, if you don't know, I, the first time I ever read a Dan Slott comic, it was a Ren and Stimpy Marvel comic.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Dan Slott is like a great, uh, great superhero writer.
Scott: Uh, he had a Twitter thread recently where he talked about how like, Hey, you know, these are the reasons, you know, if you're writing Spider-Man, you know, wisecracking at people, right.
Scott: Uh, these are like the do's and don'ts, right.
Scott: It's like, you know, Spider-Man sometimes so wisecrack at people to calm his own nerves, right.
Scott: Or his sense of humor is like this, right.
Scott: And people who've written Spider-Man haven't always followed those rules, right.
Scott: When writing him.
Scott: So it's like, you might pick up a Spider-Man comic and actually find an asshole Spider-Man in there because there's been so many different people writing it over the years.
Scott: But, you know, you view the good Spider-Man, right.
Scott: Is written the way Dan said in that Twitter thread.
Rym: Um, well also the spice Spider-Man seems to have a better continuity of character than a lot of other popular, like.
Rym: Batman is a similarly well-known popular character, but Batman is on this like widely swinging scale of from Adam West on one side to like, I'm Batman on the other side.
Scott: Oh, you're right.
Rym: Batman is so different.
Scott: I found that.
Scott: I found the thread and it won't take that long to read.
Scott: So it's like, it bugs me.
Scott: So Dan slot says, uh, spider rant.
Scott: It bugs me when spider fans say that Spidey only uses his jokes and quips to disorient his foes.
Scott: That is one way Spidey uses his sense of humor.
Scott: Spider-Man sense of humor is also one of his most versatile tools.
Scott: It's practically his superpower, right?
Scott: He also uses it to distract civilians when they're in stressful situations.
Scott: Like you're a Spider-Man picks someone up off the ground, swinging on a thing.
Scott: He always says something funny to him.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Every time, right.
Scott: To amuse himself and put himself at ease.
Scott: He's always talking to himself, even if there's no one else around.
Scott: Right.
Scott: He's just like, uh, you know, angsting on a, I mean, look, they even lampoon that in spider verse.
Rym: We're like, as he becomes Spider-Man spoilers, the kid becomes Spider-Man.
Rym: He, uh, he starts like having this inner monologue that was loud and wasn't there before.
Rym: Like he starts to wise crack.
Rym: Like that's almost part of his superpowers to make himself appear foolish.
Scott: So people underestimate him, which is very true.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Spider-Man it's like, he sort of like people forget the spider part, like insect, like you.
Scott: don't actually think of spiders too much.
Scott: When you think of Spider-Man, I think a wise cracking guy swinging through a city, He's.
Scott: the only thing really spider like about him, except for the fact that web spiders also make webs and he climbs on walls is that he's a pest, but insects are pests and the spiders aren't insects.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Um, but regardless, uh, you know, he's, he's like ridiculously strong, right?
Scott: Um, not Superman strong, but still ridiculously strong.
Scott: But yet, if you look at him next to the other heroes, even in just the Marvel universe, it's like he looks weak compared to them.
Scott: It's like Thor is there, the literal God and his Spider-Man, a guy who swings on a rope.
Rym: But it's pretty canonically consistent that Spider-Man is strong and powerful enough to hold his own in those environment.
Scott: Pick cars and up and throw them at people.
Scott: It's like he's not messing around.
Scott: Um, but also he, it, the final thing on the list is, uh, he uses jokes to strike back at jerks like Jonah, right?
Scott: His boss who he can't punch, but he can, uh, you know, harass them with a verbally and of course to goof around and bond with the other superheroes.
Scott: Right.
Scott: So pretty much anytime Superman, Spider-Man talks to another superhero, it's always making fun of them.
Scott: It's like, no matter what, he has a nickname for every other superhero, right?
Scott: He's just sort of making fun.
Scott: It's like he is a superhero, but all the other superheroes are sort of taking themselves seriously at being superheroes.
Scott: Whereas Spider-Man, despite being almost the first of those superheroes, right.
Scott: Is sort of meta, right?
Scott: Uh, and sort of outside of the rest of them.
Scott: He's like, oh, it's here before the re all of most of you, right?
Scott: Whether that's, you know, true or not.
Rym: I'm just doing my thing.
Rym: Don't mess up New York.
Scott: But, you know, he's just messing with the rest of them and sort of, you know, giving you, again, you're identifying with him, not only in that he's like you, right.
Scott: In some way, but also in that he's outside, not quite breaking entirely breaking in the fourth wall, but still outside of the rest of the universe that he is occupying from the reader's perspective.
Rym: Which is good because a lot of Spider-Man media is very like just Spider-Man, even if it's an alternate Spider-Man or a weird Spider-Man or Spider-Man's dead, but then he isn't or that's actually Venom or whatever.
Rym: It's still like Spider-Man.
Rym: stories are more often self-contained with not as much crazy crossover nonsense with the rest of the universe.
Rym: Not that that doesn't happen, though.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: You know, it depends which one you read or whatever.
Scott: It happens all the time.
Rym: It's tough because whatever Spider-Man I liked, like Spider-Verse was basically like the height of Spider-Man for me.
Scott: Well, I mean, how much Spider-Man have you read?
Scott: There's plenty of Spider-Men.
Rym: I haven't read a lot.
Rym: I've seen a lot.
Scott: I mean, if you read Miles Morales Spider-Man, that's what that is.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: Probably should just read that actually at some point.
Scott: You know, it's like, if you find yourself saying, man, you know, I watched all these I don't read a lot of comics, right?
Scott: I watched a bunch of Spider-Man movies or superhero movies, and I really liked this Spider-Verse one, right?
Scott: You look at me, I'm someone who's like, Hey, I read a lot of comics.
Scott: I don't like a lot of superhero movies.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Um, but I liked that one because it was like the comics.
Scott: Well, guess what?
Scott: If you like that movie, you're going to like the comics because they're like that movie, right?
Scott: It's more like comics than any superhero movie ever was.
Rym: Oh, I mean, look at how many people watch these like Marvel Cinematic Universe movies that aren't Spider-Man, but then they get excited like, Oh, I'll go read the comics.
Rym: And they, that usually doesn't go well.
Scott: The comic is not like those, right?
Scott: Which is a lot of reasons why I don't like those.
Scott: They're not like comics.
Scott: They're just the same characters, uh, you know, superficially or, you know, more than superficially sometimes.
Rym: The one thing I can say though, the only thing I've never like, even the Spider-Man comics I've read, I've never been super jazzed about the villains in the spot that Spider-Man is facing.
Rym: I'm usually really focused on Spider-Man.
Rym: Whereas with any other superhero stuff, I find myself often more interested in the villains.
Rym: Like I like Batman villains a lot.
Scott: Well, I think that's, that's exactly what I think most people would agree with, right?
Scott: Even it, even in Star Wars, it's like, yeah, the empire are bad guys.
Scott: I'm not rooting for them, but listen, there's no denying that at least aesthetically Darth Vader and the emperor are cooler than whiny.
Scott: Luke Skywalker, right?
Scott: There's Han Solo is cool, right?
Scott: Luke Skywalker.
Scott: How cool is he really?
Scott: Not, not cool.
Scott: Princess Leia is cool, right?
Scott: C-3PO is maybe cool.
Scott: R2D2 is cool, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, but like, you know, TIE fighters, they're cooler than, you know, X-wings mostly kinda, right?
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Same thing.
Scott: So Batman, it's like, yeah, it's like Batman.
Scott: He's okay.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But it's like, the Joker is cooler than Batman, right?
Rym: That was actually a long set up joke in the venture brothers where there's this assassin guy and the kid bonds with him because they both love superhero comics and Batman is their favorite comic.
Rym: It's like this long thing.
Rym: And the very end, it turns out the guy's the evil assassin.
Rym: The kid's like, but you love Batman.
Rym: How could you be this way?
Rym: And he's like, kid, I only like Batman for the villains.
Scott: Yeah, that's right.
Scott: The villains are cooler than, yup.
Rym: Well, I'm just poking at this fighter man Wikipedia and I'm scrolling through the list of villains because the list of like every major villain Spider-Man's ever fought.
Rym: Eh, like this is not the A-list of villains here.
Scott: No, I mean, you got guys like, you know, cause most of it is like corny stuff, right?
Scott: It's like guy who dresses up in a rhino.
Rym: I was, that was exactly why Rhino was the first one I was gonna...
Scott: You got the lizard guy, you got, uh, you know, a lot of times he'll be, he'll be like messing with other heroes.
Scott: He'll get tangled up with them, right?
Scott: Sometimes, um, you got Dr.
Scott: Octopus, right?
Scott: Who's okay.
Scott: I guess you got Green Goblins, Hobgoblin, all kinds of goblins involved, right?
Rym: The Jackal.
Scott: Oh yeah.
Scott: The Jackal.
Rym: I remember the Jackal.
Rym: I think the Jackal was very cartoon.
Scott: The Jackal was very lizard related.
Scott: He got Mysterio who's kind of cool a little bit, maybe.
Rym: I like Mysterio, Kingpin.
Rym: Uh, Venom was interesting.
Scott: Venom sort of, yeah.
Scott: Venom is like a whole thing unto itself.
Scott: That's again, that's sort of like the cool villain syndrome, right?
Scott: Where it's like, it was Spider-Man, but then it was someone else.
Scott: It was too cool.
Rym: So it had to be its own.
Scott: And then it was, and then it was Carnage.
Rym: Um, but like Electro missed me with that.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: It's like most Spider-Man villains are just like wacky dude, at least in, you know, it's like, yeah, there are stories where they're written well and they don't come across as wacky dude.
Scott: Right.
Scott: But it's like the classic Spider-Man comics, those villains are just, all right.
Scott: It's a, it's a different.
Scott: Right.
Rym: But I think that's cause the story is tended to focus more on Peter or whoever.
Rym: is Spider-Man navigating their real life and spider life simultaneously.
Rym: And that's usually.
Scott: that's the drama was, you know, aunt May something, something dealing with my wife, dealing with, you know, Jonah dealing with whatever.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And the villain was just sort of there to be like, Hey, this guy, Spider-Man is dealing with all this shit in his life.
Scott: And that's the parts you care about.
Scott: And while he's dealing with all that, he's got to find some nut dressed up like a rhino, really on top of everything else.
Rym: But that on top of everything else is just it.
Rym: If I had to really crystallize this idea, it's that with a lot of superhero things, the identity is just boring.
Rym: And as soon as there's a villain and a fight, like, yeah, that's all I'm here for.
Rym: Like, yes, finally, he's not just like in his house, but with Spider-Man, when the villain shows up, I'm like, ah, but I want to follow that.
Rym: I want to follow this story.
Rym: I want to see what happens.
Rym: Right.
Rym: Now I've got to go watch this fight.
Rym: What's Peter going to do?
Scott: And that's, and that's another way in that it is much like, you know, real life.
Scott: I think anyone is, you're going to find us Spider-Man in, you know, uh, you know, interpretation somewhere that is for you.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And I think in this way, it's for everyone and that it's like, yeah, you've got the shit you're dealing with in your real life.
Scott: And suddenly as it's fucking plague, all right.
Scott: That's just, it's just everyone's guy in a rhino costume, just coming up, right on top of everything else.
Scott: You know, you got a pandemic to deal with.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Also, Spider-Man feels the same way Spider-Man feels when someone robs a bank and he's got to do something about it.
Rym: We got to mention at least briefly that original, terrible Spider-Man theme is brilliant.
Scott: Oh, the original song.
Rym: Do you do Spider-Man?
Scott: That's from the original, the original Spider-Man cartoon way back when or whatever, like the continuity of that jingle.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, that song, I don't know who wrote that song.
Scott: You can probably, I'm sure I don't, you know, what do I know about the history of that song?
Scott: Nothing.
Scott: Go look it up.
Scott: You'll right.
Scott: I am looking it up to see if I can provide some commentary, but what I do know is that that's Jay Robert Harris wrote it.
Scott: Right.
Scott: My famous, my favorite Wikipedia article.
Scott: that I'm sure it does.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: My favorite thing about that song is when there was a TV commercial for Bomberman 64 that reuse that song.
Scott: And instead of doing Spider-Man, it was Bomberman.
Scott: It was Bomberman, Bomberman, right?
Scott: Drops bombs across the list.
Rym: All right.
Rym: So the story is kind of interesting.
Rym: So it was composed by this, uh, Paul Francis Webster and Robert Bob Harris.
Rym: It was recorded by RCA in Toronto, and they got together a whole bunch of CBC vocalist groups, like the Billy Van singers and all these other like groups that were famous in the day.
Rym: And then they add backing tracks added later from New York.
Scott: It was kind of cobbled together, just like any other low rent TV production.
Rym: It was the lowest rent.
Rym: Like we need a fucking jingle.
Rym: Just make it.
Rym: No one gives a shit.
Rym: The, the, all the people who sang were paid for the gig.
Rym: There were no residuals, like no one even thought that anyone would care about this song ever again.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I mean, if you go back to the, you know, sixties or whatever, there were plenty of similar jingles, right?
Scott: I mean, people in New York, right?
Scott: Noted noted Mets fan.
Scott: Spider-Man would know the song, meet the Mets, right?
Scott: Which is a jingle with a similar sort of history.
Scott: There was like a contest to make a song to, you know, for the Mets.
Scott: Right.
Scott: And it's a similar kind of, you know, sixties, you know, commercial jingle thing and there's tons of them, but only the ones that are associated with properties that survived like Spider-Man and the Mets are remembered and stuck in people's heads to this day.
Rym: So you're all thinking this song in your head right now.
Rym: You can't avoid it.
Scott: I'm sure there are plenty of other commercial jingles from the, the times that are similarly catchy and we're just associated with things that no longer exist and the jingles didn't get enough play to stick in the collective societal memory.
Rym: So I feel like I'm thinking about this cause.
Rym: actually the listener mentioned that they also loved Spider-Man 2099.
Rym: I feel like I should read Spider-Man 2099 because I don't know anything about it.
Scott: I have every, I have every issue of Spider-Man 2099.
Scott: You should absolutely read it.
Scott: And then we could do like a whole series of episodes on it for that.
Scott: Spider-Man 2099 is basically is a, it's the year 2099.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: The cyberpunk Spider-Man, the Marvel, the Marvel universe is now a cyberpunk universe where evil corporations run everything.
Scott: And, uh, Dr.
Scott: Doom eventually becomes president.
Rym: Wait, this might be a little too real.
Rym: Maybe I don't want to read this in 2020.
Scott: It's very real.
Scott: Uh, and Spider-Man is this, uh, dude called Miguel O'Hara and he is a genetics researcher for the big evil corporation.
Rym: And doesn't he accidentally Spider-Manify himself?
Scott: No.
Scott: He's a huge ass jerk, right?
Scott: Is he's not a nice person.
Scott: And he basically somewhat intentionally, uh, Spider-Man's himself, right?
Scott: Uh, he has a holographic, right?
Scott: Assistant just sort of like Blade Runner situation, right?
Scott: Um, you know, and he Spider-Man's himself and then shit happens and his brother is the good person.
Scott: He's the bad person.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Um, even though he does end up fighting people who are worse than him.
Scott: Uh, it's mostly a cyberpunk story, right?
Scott: And not really, uh, you know, and also a Spider-Man story, but he's not like a, um, he's not like doing a good job of anything, right?
Scott: He's like the drug addict.
Rym: Begrudgingly like, ah, I got a Spider-Man something.
Scott: Uh, yeah, pretty much I'm game for this.
Scott: Um, but yeah, they have Spider-Man.
Rym: we've gone on long enough.
Rym: We could stop the show there unless we have more to say.
Scott: I mean, as you could talk about Spider-Man's, there's so much material.
Rym: You can just talk forever, but like you could probably make an entire podcast that just talked about Spider-Man in film.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I'm sure there probably is such a podcast.
Rym: There is.
Rym: You'll listen to that.
Scott: How many Spider-Man things there are.
Rym: It's bring me, bring me podcasts of Spider-Man.
Scott: I think, I think there's just a property of media in general, right?
Scott: Is that when something gets big enough, right?
Scott: When something gets big enough and popular enough, then suddenly the meta of it becomes worthy of discussion.
Rym: It's like some sea creatures that get like their own ecosystem that just like surrounds them.
Scott: So like, did you know there's like a James Bond magazine?
Scott: I don't know how often it's comes out, but like the exact kind of person who subscribes to James Bond magazine, I don't know if it's monthly or quarterly or whatever, but like there's an official James Bond magazine.
Scott: It's like, that just keeps coming out all the time.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Um, you know, it's like Spider-Man is big enough.
Scott: that like, you know, this amazing Spider-Man, spectacular Spider-Man, so many Spider-Man is different Spider-Man comics all the time.
Scott: It's like, once you're big enough, you just create this fountain where just like you, you can't stop your own growth.
Scott: media wise, because even if you don't make things that are official Canon material,
Rym: fans, making stuff, you got fans,
Scott: meta stuff,
Rym: people talking about your stuff, you've got
Scott: for
Rym: a number
Scott: ending people
Rym: who just straight up steal it and make their own version of Spider-Man, which is, and
Scott: then you get, and every part of me, if you have media, you get the video games, you get the toys, you get like, you know, re you know, people just making things that have nothing to do with it.
Scott: Like someone will buy a bicycle, but they'll make it a Spider-Man bicycle.
Scott: They'll paint it red and blue and put webbing on it.
Rym: You know what I will say though?
Rym: You talk about a piece of Spider-Man media, that Atari 2,600 Spider-Man game, people make fun of it for being like an old bad Atari game.
Rym: But honestly, it's one of the best Atari 2,600 games.
Rym: It's a legit, a lot of, there's not a lot of competition there, but I'm saying it is like, it's a pretty good game.
Scott: Spider-Man makes much better video games than a lot of other superheroes.
Rym: I hesitate to speculate.
Rym: Why?
Scott: Cause I don't know, but I think it's just because the verbs of Spider-Man right is you can make.
Scott: the powers are simple.
Scott: Like there's a small set of, you walk down to a Batman game, you walk down the street, beaten up guys, and then you throw a battering, right?
Scott: Whereas a Spider-Man game, you have the verb of swinging on webs, which is what makes it, you know, or like I said, taking photos of bad guys, you have these extra verbs, right?
Rym: Um, whereas most other could have like the interrogation verb, which is most people who make games don't make, no one's made a Batman game like that.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: That's the problem.
Rym: For whatever reason, Batman games tend to be just side scrolling or right.
Scott: Most video games tend to be action games and no matter what superhero you have, it doesn't really make the game any different, right?
Scott: Captain America, he throws a shield, Hawkeye shoots a bow and arrow.
Rym: And then you do a palette swap and you could sell the same game for superheroes.
Scott: It's like you walk down the street, punch and stuff, or you fly around, punch and stuff.
Rym: Palette swap that Genesis game.
Rym: Someone's like, why is captain America taking pictures of the red?
Scott: So like there's that new ish.
Scott: So, you know, PlayStation, Spider-Man game.
Scott: That's supposed to be ridiculously good.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Right.
Rym: In fact, you know what, you know what I found in VR chat the other day, a Spider-Man world, and when I went into it to see what the deal was, you know what it is?
Rym: It's an infinite, endless New York city skyline and you can just web swing through it in VR.
Rym: That's it.
Rym: That's the whole fucking world.
Scott: There you go.
Scott: It's great.
Rym: It actually was real fun.
Rym: I, I had to go find like some bootleg Spider-Man avatar and I went in there and you know what it was?
Rym: 20 other people, everyone dressed as Spider-Man.
Rym: One person legit had a JJJ avatar instead and he was swinging around yelling at people for photos and it was all these like bootleg Spider-Man flying around in this virtual world, but no one's doing that in a Batman world.
Rym: Nope.
Rym: I don't know if I didn't even see anyone doing that.
Scott: The cats in America.
Scott: cats in America will be boring as hell.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: Not that I don't like cats in America for other reasons, but still that would be boring.
Rym: So yeah, uh, if you somehow, if not, like I'm sure all of you, a hundred percent of the listener is aware of the existence of Spider-Man, but if you've never consumed any Spider-Man media, honestly, I would recommend consuming some Spider-Man media directly instead of just absorbing it through osmosis.
Rym: Cause it's Spider-Man on the level pretty good overall.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: I would recommend if you don't know, this is like basically an infant.
Scott: You could read Spider-Man comics for the rest of your life unless you narrow yourself down like that silver age Spider-Man guy.
Scott: So what I would recommend doing right is read some of the original, original Spider-Man right by, you know, Stanley and Steve Ditko, right?
Scott: Uh, and then if you want to find other good Spider-Man's right, look for Spider-Man that is written by, uh, Dan slot, or if you're like in the spider verse, which you should be find some miles Morales Spider-Man or this end or some ultimate Spider-Man, uh, which you can, you know, just start reading from like issue one or whatever.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Uh, and those are going to be like, you know, you're good.
Scott: Go to Spider-Man's to start, you know, if you just want to read some Spider-Man comic, uh, Spider-Man 2099 is not really going to give you, it's going to give you some Spider-Man, but like I said, it's mostly going to give you some cyberpunk, which is also good.
Rym: I guess one nice thing though, is that most Spider-Man media is more close to the mean compared to other superheroes where like you read the wrong one and it's just super weird and the wrong is Spider-Man.
Scott: There's an infant.
Scott: I have it all over here actually.
Scott: Cause I want, I have five giant books, which I'm going to read and then get rid of, uh, there's an infamous Spider-Man, the clone saga, which is, uh, where that, the Jackal that you mentioned, right?
Scott: Basically this whole thing gets messed up where there's another guy who Spider-Man doesn't know he's Spider-Man.
Scott: There's a possibly a clone of Spider-Man and it's like all mixed up, right?
Scott: Like the, the, the guy who is Peter Parker doesn't know he is anymore.
Scott: The memories get, and basically it's the derided, you know, island episodes of, of Spider-Man.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Which a media franchise this big, like an IP this big, there's going to be some Island episodes.
Rym: There's no way to avoid that.
Scott: Another, also, if you, if you want to read some good Spider-Man, I could also recommend, I don't know exactly what issues it is, but you could find it easily by Googling.
Scott: I'm sure there's trade paperbacks of it.
Scott: There is the point at which I guess there was secret wars and it's during secret wars, which is a big crossover event, right?
Scott: Uh, Spider-Man finds a, so, uh, basically effectively a space sewing machine.
Scott: And in the space sewing machine, he sews himself the black costume, right.
Scott: And puts it on.
Scott: Um, and the black costume is obviously an alien that later becomes venom.
Scott: It's not just a costume.
Rym: But there's a whole arc that like leads to that.
Rym: Like people didn't know what this, what this was when they read this.
Scott: So you could read secret wars if you want to.
Scott: It's not that bad.
Scott: Uh, it's, it's, you know, it's, it's dated, but it's still a bit, it's one of the earlier comic crossover things.
Scott: You can understand it.
Scott: If you read it, you don't need to actually read all the crossover issues.
Scott: Um, but you read the Spider-Man comics that directly follow after that.
Scott: And they're easy to find because Spider-Man is wearing a different costume.
Scott: Right.
Scott: Uh, and if you read those and the saga of Spider-Man having that costume up to the point at which he gets rid of it and it becomes venom, right.
Scott: When it finds another host.
Scott: Um, those are pretty good Spider-Man's to read also.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: I've actually read a bunch of that.
Rym: I'm weirdly more familiar with the venom stuff than I am with Spider-Man stuff from that era.
Rym: Yep.
Scott: So I guess that might be like, I don't know exactly when that was.
Scott: Was that late eighties, early nineties?
Rym: Uh, this Wikipedia page is too long for me to scroll and find that right now.
Scott: Of course it is.
Scott: Secret wars came out in 84.
Scott: So I guess mid, mid eighties.
Scott: Oh, here we go.
Rym: Spider-Man 252, 1984, the black costume debut.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: That brought controversy to many fans.
Rym: The suit was later revealed as an alien semi-aut and was okay.
Rym: Thanks Wikipedia.
Scott: There you go.
Rym: So yeah, check out some Spider-Man's.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: And the Patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce, Heidi McNichol, Marty Garenya, Just Like a Dude, Gog, Shartavich, and Graham Finch.
Rym: You hold the key to my heart.
Rym: She gave me a kiss and she gave me my ticket.
Rym: Clinton Walton, Jay Bantz, Ren from New Zealand, Ryan Parent, Nicholas Brandau, Chris Midkiff, The Thirst, Horhydrated Gannon, Dread, Lily Tenebrae, Chris Reimer, Finn, Sean Klein, Shervin Von Harl, and a whole bunch of people who don't want me to say their names.
Rym: We're, uh, we're working on something.
Rym: We're going to something cool that we can't talk about yet, but we got something cool in the hopper.
Rym: We actually had a meeting about said cool thing today.
Rym: So, uh, we'll see where this goes, but you might see some things in the next, give it a month or so.
Rym: And I'll just leave it at that.
Rym: But for now I'll leave you with... When you're in Zoo-ba-lee, Zoo-ba-lee, Zoo-ba-lee, Zoo-ba-lee, Zoo-ba-lee, Magic and wonder are waiting for you.
Rym: So come on with us now and discover the wonder of you.
Rym: Welcome to Zoo-ba-lee, Zoo.