Rym: It's Wednesday, June 10th, 2020.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott and this is GeekNights.
Rym: tonight We are talking about the Netflix anime ghost in the shell standalone complex.
Scott: Let's do this.
Scott: So it's a little tough to bike right now Even though there is such beautiful weather outside.
Scott: and now if you know, I could bike all I want.
Scott: but not only is There a deadly virus out there that might get me.
Scott: I gotta be precarious, you know cautious about that.
Rym: Yeah, we got to bring all your was also with you, right?
Scott: There's also many protests out there that I fully support.
Scott: But protests, you know, you don't want a bike, you know to go with a bike protest.
Scott: I've seen a lot of those and it's like man.
Scott: I want to go on that bike protest so bad.
Scott: Yeah, but deadly virus.
Scott: I'll wait and see if any of those bike protesters get deadly virus the same way that like I'm gonna be second in line for Cybernetic implants.
Scott: Yeah, I'm gonna be second in line for will the bike protest?
Scott: give me the corona virus?
Scott: If none of the bike protesters end up with corona virus then expect to see me at your local bike protest soon.
Scott: But I'm waiting in the scene right now.
Rym: Yeah anyway briefly on a run because I could kind of stop and just walk along the edge of it for a while and Instead I took the solo action of harassing basically every cop I saw on my 14 mile run, which was 12 sets of cops Interestingly a lot.
Rym: while they were all out mostly Surrounding City Hall they had a barricade around Gracie Mansion wouldn't let anyone get anywhere near it.
Scott: You keep saying City Hall City Hall is so far away from there.
Rym: Yeah, Gracie Mansion, New York City has Gracie Mansion Which is basically the mayor's house.
Scott: Yeah, there's like a special house.
Rym: You can read about the history of it on the internet and it's like on the east side bike and running, right?
Scott: It's on the east side of Manhattan sort of north ish like Upper East Side on the water on the East River.
Scott: It's like a mansion.
Scott: It's old and if you become mayor of New York Congratulations, you get to live in it.
Scott: Yeah You don't have to live wherever you live before.
Scott: You can move into that house and sleep there and just sort of like the president can move into the White House, right?
Scott: You know so but the City Hall where the mayor works is hella downtown far away from there.
Scott: Yep so So yeah hard to bike right now like I was saying protests, right.
Scott: Part of the problem for them is if you want to bike around Even if you're not joining the protest that there's been a protest recently.
Scott: the street is full of crap Especially like broken glass.
Scott: You don't want to bike there.
Scott: Yeah, so it limits the places you can go.
Scott: So yeah, not a lot of biking outside going on especially and not commuting to any office.
Scott: So The option I have is to do some sort of stationary bicycling indoors.
Scott: That's perfectly safe, right?
Scott: the thing is I had a stationary bike trainer thing and I bought the cheapo crappiest one if way many years ago in my you know, and It wasn't broken.
Scott: It was only partially broken But it only seemed to work with the bike that I no longer have Like when I bought it.
Scott: when I bought it I had this hybrid bike and that was my only bike and it worked with that bike.
Scott: just fine, right?
Scott: It was a wheel on style, right?
Scott: You don't take the tire off your bike And it was loud as hell.
Rym: Loud as hell is a deal-breaker for me.
Scott: But when I tried to use my other bikes on it It just didn't fit properly even though they were also quick release bikes with the same tire size and everything.
Scott: so I got rid of that when I moved and I've since learned that the other style of bike trainer where you take your tire off and you direct drive a flywheel Are vastly superior and perfect and great And quiet as we get a good one, right and super awesome.
Scott: And but there's one that is made by the same company Wahoo that makes my bike computer.
Scott: So I was like, oh, I'll get that one.
Scott: It's a really good one.
Scott: Apparently It's like $1,100, which is a fortune.
Scott: Maybe I still might get one.
Scott: Maybe probably not though.
Rym: There will be a winter again someday, but the right.
Scott: but the point is that They're out of stock and they've been out of stock for a long time.
Scott: I saw one on the internet.
Scott: Someone was selling a used one.
Scott: I think that they were too stupid to get their bike to fit on it Like they didn't know how to adjust it properly.
Scott: and they were like, it doesn't fit on my bike I'm selling it.
Scott: and they were selling it for 700. and I was like, oh shit.
Scott: Oh shit.
Scott: Oh shit, and they didn't reply.
Scott: I think they sold it to someone else or figured it out.
Scott: So my building that I live in has a gym in it a game.
Scott: Yeah, oh Yeah that I never would go into what you know because I don't exercise.
Scott: But it has some stationary bicycles in it that I never investigated.
Scott: But but it's like.
Scott: well now's the time.
Scott: I'm stuck inside now, I actually want to go in there.
Scott: guess what.
Scott: they closed the guy.
Scott: Yeah Can't go in.
Scott: they close the guy.
Scott: I'm as soon as I'm about to use it, right.
Scott: and then just yesterday They opened the guy and I'm like, well still trapped inside.
Scott: So let's go check it out Scott.
Rym: And a guy I know right.
Scott: so I go and I check it out and actually it just so happens.
Scott: the XD stationary bicycles that are in my buildings game are Terrific.
Scott: Like it's a regular bike saddle.
Scott: It's not one of those weird seat things.
Scott: Right, it's fully adjustable.
Scott: It has a computer that has every feature you want except maybe for like connectivity.
Scott: It does have connectivity to like a heart monitor.
Scott: But I guess you have to get the one that goes with that bike which I don't know.
Rym: There are some open standards around that.
Rym: but you got a Google to make sure.
Scott: I don't think it follows any of them And I don't care anyway even has SPE clips in the pedals it's like and it was super silent and There's absolutely nothing wrong with it.
Scott: So I guess I don't need to buy some bike trainer for $1,100 But I still would much rather bike outside.
Rym: Well get there you can bike outside you just can't.
Rym: you have to bike the whole way there and back.
Rym: You can't like it on a train to get home.
Scott: I really but that's the thing is most of the bike riding I do nowadays is bike far And take a train home or take a train and bike home and I you know not being able to do either.
Rym: one is me You know, he's getting a mountain biking instead.
Scott: Mountain biking sucks.
Rym: My miking is awesome.
Rym: No So anyway in the news Just in case any of you think that somehow media can escape this or be a political like.
Rym: now it's here to black lives matter And there's a lot of protests going on for a reason.
Scott: I had a goal of Find black lives matter content for like every thread even unrelated threads.
Rym: I saw you doing that in the forum.
Scott: I'm gonna see but it was too easy.
Scott: It was like I got it in the kit.
Scott: I can get it in the kpop thread.
Scott: It's like it's like every sport.
Scott: it's like no matter what thing you pick that seems unrelated to the world.
Scott: It's like I can find a related black lives matter thing.
Scott: So it's like it was such not a challenge to do that.
Scott: I didn't I stopped doing it.
Rym: It's like Yep, but somehow these companies have a lot of trouble hiring black people.
Rym: Oh, I wonder why.
Rym: yeah, I wonder why.
Rym: so Yeah, if you're not paying attention to the news obviously there's a lot of protests going on.
Rym: they're all basically 100% justified.
Rym: We've mentioned this repeatedly.
Rym: We're still doing the show.
Rym: We skip shows last week because the momentum had to grow.
Rym: the momentum is still there.
Rym: We're doing GeekNights again But right now we're not live streaming and you'll notice if you follow us in social media.
Rym: We're not really talking about our nerdy stuff on social media.
Rym: We're really only talking about it here on GeekNights.
Rym: So no It's like.
Scott: really.
Scott: is anyone even listening to geek guys these days?
Scott: it's like I'm not listening to podcast.
Rym: Yeah, the only podcast.
Scott: I'm listening to our political podcast about the situation Although I might because you know with the heavy, you know bike nights being in one non moving location.
Rym: Yeah
Scott: The
Rym: other thing you could do is watch a really boring anime like the one we're about to talk about while you're fighting on a tablet but I'm gonna make sure we're gonna talk about some aspect of this every week in the news in addition to our normal nerdy stuff and If you're not up for that You don't really need to be a fan of ours.
Rym: You're welcome.
Scott: How are you?
Scott: How are you still a fan of ours?
Rym: Understand how people will like follow us for a decade and then one day be like who you've gotten political.
Rym: you have lost my Respect and It was a listener who is totally cool.
Scott: And there was one point where I was like, I think on some episode I said my phone number and I was like I challenged people to text me.
Scott: I remember that and this one dude texted me and he just had conversations with me about totally normal nerdy stuff.
Scott: You know so and like sometimes like instead of using the forum or email like occasionally after an episode Like like the day after I'd get a text from that listener.
Scott: Yeah Right and he would always just be some normal nerdy thing like just commenting on the episode like a normal person.
Scott: Right, totally totally chill until one day Texted me with like some Trump pro-trump Nonsense and I'm like what the fuck.
Scott: and I was just like don't text me again.
Scott: and they said, okay Of course.
Rym: The other thing I get on the YouTube channel pretty regularly on every random video is There'll be people who were like, hey, what are you guys gonna start with you ten a thing again?
Rym: I got one of those today But to the thing that gets the most comments is this dumb video I made a few years ago.
Rym: that's literally just that scene where Twilight Sparkle in my little pony becomes an alicorn and she like Disappears and I cut to the credits right after that and I was like the death of Twilight Sparkle at least once a week.
Rym: Someone will post a comment in that video Extremely angry trying to explain that you got to keep watching the show.
Rym: There's another episode.
Rym: She comes back.
Rym: She's not dead.
Rym: This video is a lie.
Rym: This person doesn't know what they're talking about and It just warms the cockles of my heart to see people like that.
Scott: They know they don't get it.
Rym: They don't have But at least they don't get it about something that doesn't matter.
Rym: the people who don't get it about the stuff that matters Hard block like if I see you out there on Twitter.
Scott: It's the same problem right.
Scott: it's like they.
Scott: you know the a person sees a thing and doesn't understand You know the thing isn't literally saying what it literally says.
Rym: yep So you're gonna get at least one.
Scott: the same kind of person who looks at death of Twilight Sparkle and says she's not dead Is the same person who looks at Black Lives Matter?
Scott: It says all lives matter.
Scott: They're caught up in the semantic Reality or they're willfully obtuse.
Rym: don't discount how many guys.
Scott: just willfully obtuse yes But you know the the meaning is lost.
Rym: true right but a guiding principle on GeekNights has always been that we try to cross Pollinate.
Rym: like this is the Wednesday anime show, but the news will do some anime news But we'll sprinkle in other things and things of the day we got.
Rym: we're trying to get the anime nerd to play video games And I've got all anime comic stuff to play a different game.
Scott: I don't have any cross stuff today.
Scott: I only go.
Rym: yeah But you're gonna see at least like news about the real world every GeekNights for the foreseeable future.
Rym: Cuz the protests are working.
Rym: so this news before we get into the nerdy stuff about comics is that you might have noticed a Whole lot of racist statues got torn down By concerned citizens in the last few days, and this is a vice.
Scott: got any racist statues near you, right?
Scott: Let's make a racist statue tear down our club.
Scott: Yeah, I help you tear down yours You help me tear down mine.
Rym: so vice put down at just a nice compilation of all the ones that were torn down like really recently Mmm, and they're good photos good stuff.
Rym: keep it also Please post.
Scott: I've seen other people posting threads of good statues.
Scott: Please post more good statues.
Scott: It's hard to top that Bruce Lee statue I mean the best statue on earth is still Freddie Mercury statue, right?
Rym: Yeah, I would say that at least in the top ten is Joe Louis's fist.
Scott: you like I could do.
Scott: I know you love a Joe Louis fist.
Scott: I'm down with that Yeah, but yeah frozen cuz.
Rym: I could critique that statue from a number of angles But I do appreciate that.
Rym: It is just a big fist.
Scott: Yeah, I do like, you know, I do like classic statues Even though they're very white right like a like a Michelangelo David or uh, you know that kind of statue Right, you know, but you know this, you know, they're better than a fucking racist.
Rym: So, yeah, keep your eyes on that stuff and if you have money to spare I would recommend donating it to one of the many causes We will link to related to the Black Lives Matter movement and the current situation.
Scott: So in other news diamond might finally get destroyed Mel half destroy, so we've talked about this on GeekNights Frequently, but for anyone who still doesn't know the deal The way comic book stores in the United States work is.
Scott: there is a company called diamond distributors Marvel and DC.
Scott: like 25 30 years ago Right signed exclusive distribution deals with diamond distributors.
Scott: So if you the floppy ass comic books that you get in comic book stores Right would only be sold through diamond distributors and through no one else.
Scott: So your comic book store You put your order in with diamond distributors.
Scott: They send you comic books and it was a special direct Distribution deal, right?
Scott: so if you're a bookstore and you buy a book and you don't sell it you tear the cover off and you tell or you destroy it completely and you tell the Distributor that you bought books from.
Scott: you didn't sell the book.
Scott: Yeah, and they give you your money back Right because you return the book, right?
Scott: They just don't want you to actually return the paper, right?
Scott: But you're only paying for books that you sell through to customers.
Scott: comic book stores doesn't work that way.
Scott: comic book stores pay for all the comics and They can't return them.
Scott: They either sell them or they're stuck with them.
Scott: Which is why you see like dollar bins and bargain basement comic bins because comic book stores are stuck with these things.
Rym: Now sometimes this happens in other areas.
Rym: there was stuff way back with D&D books and TSR where a similar weird situation happened.
Rym: So this right district supply chain distribution semi monopolies and weird structures are a thing in a lot of places.
Scott: But comics are particularly noteworthy and egregious right but by having this monopoly distribution with the no returnables They were able to sell comic books for cheaper.
Scott: if they had to be returnable the price would go way up Right.
Scott: comic books would be too expensive.
Scott: They print them in color.
Scott: They have to pay artists and writers a lot, right?
Scott: They don't have as many advertisers, but then they used to don't sell as many copies as they used to.
Scott: They still put them out every month, right?
Scott: There's a whole whole thing.
Scott: so People have been complaining about this whole situation Because while it had a purpose when it started which is to save comics from fucking themselves It's now, you know since then obviously it's been a bad deal for comic book stores and for readers overall.
Scott: and What happened was is because of the virus situation?
Scott: Diamond stopped distributing for a little bit right a couple months there.
Scott: So DC which was coming up to the end of its exclusive contract term with D with diamond said alright We're gonna try a little bit with some other distributors while you're shut down.
Scott: We'll see how it goes, right?
Scott: We'll take this opportunity.
Scott: So to comic retailers right one that I am a customer of Discount complex service DCB service calm and another one that I don't know.
Scott: I would mention it if I knew.
Scott: I'm not trying to like favor one over the other.
Rym: Yeah, you probably have a friend who's into comics who mentions DCBS.
Rym: That's basically like hope nerds who like know exactly right?
Scott: So it right.
Scott: so what DCBS and this and does is they they?
Scott: they're a customer of diamonds Just like everyone else right, but they're an online Shop.
Scott: so they have so many customers and they order.
Scott: they have such a large order with diamond that they get the highest Discount level and they passed most of that discount on to the customer.
Scott: So if you order from DCBS you get a huge discount.
Scott: and also because you pre-order Right DCBS doesn't have.
Scott: they're not stuck holding a bunch of comics.
Scott: They can't sell the way local comic shop has to buy a hundred copies of spider-man and doesn't know how many they're gonna sell.
Scott: Right they had to guess.
Scott: and they're stuck with extra spider.
Rym: And if they buy these men they'll either run out and have a problem or they have to get a lower dis or get a lower.
Rym: Just pay more per spider-man right?
Scott: so DCBS says how many pure orders we got for spider-man?
Scott: And it's always enough to reach the highest discount level because they're an online shop with tons of customers.
Scott: Oh, and they say oh we need exactly 462 spider-man's.
Scott: I guess that's how many we're gonna order.
Scott: will order 475 or whatever?
Scott: the Number is right.
Scott: you have to order.
Scott: I don't think they'll let you order for 62.
Scott: You get the idea.
Scott: They're not stuck holding a bunch of extra spider-man's.
Scott: they pass that savings on to the customer.
Scott: It's a great deal.
Scott: and of course because of the way they do this business.
Scott: They have a huge warehouse.
Scott: That's all a fucking distributor is is a huge warehouse that gets visited by UPS and FedEx every day constantly.
Scott: Yeah, that's all a distributor is right.
Scott: You don't own trucks right?
Scott: so DCBS and some other people doing similar businesses were in a position to be distributors because they were huge retailers.
Scott: right and Diamond said I DCBS started a company called lunar distribution and someone else so I don't know started a company called UCS comic book distributors.
Scott: And DC is like.
Scott: you know what.
Scott: we tried these two out during the virus situation when diamond wasn't working.
Scott: That's what we're going with.
Scott: fuck you diamond.
Rym: Yep right now honestly to be clear that the virus situation is almost definitely just the excuse.
Rym: People have been having issues with diamond for a long time.
Scott: It's sort of like DC was thinking about moving away, and the virus just gave him the chance to Try out the alternative to seal the deal the same way that like I wouldn't have.
Scott: I only thought about Going to use that stationary bike in my building, and I wouldn't have if it were not for this.
Scott: Okay, it's the same deal.
Scott: so now DC comic books will no longer distribute through diamond and They will only distribute through lunar and UCS Which means if you are a comic book store who wants DC comic books you want Batman on your shelf Which I bet you do.
Scott: if you're a comic book store You need some Batman's.
Scott: you now have to send an order form to diamond every month to get your spider-man.
Scott: You're gonna have to also pick UCS and or lunar to send an order form to order your Batman.
Rym: But as soon as I have to deal with two distributors Then it I have to have infrastructure to deal with more than one.
Rym: Dealing with three is not much harder than dealing with two But dealing with two is a way harder than dealing with one.
Scott: also means that if you're gonna look at your pre-order form Right so now I'm gonna.
Scott: Well.
Scott: I'm using I'm a DC BS customer.
Scott: So this is actually gonna be great because I probably won't order that many DC things, but if I were to I Would be getting them straight from the distributor, right?
Scott: But everything else I'm ordering through a retailer that's buying from diamond as I always have.
Scott: it's not any different.
Scott: Yeah, but if you are to say go and order comic books right you get.
Scott: you know.
Scott: There's a catalog of the previews catalog Which is the catalog you order diamond things from.
Scott: there is now presumably going to be a second catalog that is like the DC only Catalog that will come out on some basis, or maybe there'll be two DC catalogs one from UCS and one from lunar.
Scott: I don't even know how that's gonna work but the previews catalog that comes from diamond won't have any DC products in it and Those products will be in some separate catalog you have to get separately somewhere.
Scott: You know.
Scott: maybe I don't know if the comic book shop will have it.
Scott: the comic shop usually has previews.
Rym: Yeah, we'll see what happens.
Rym: what I wonder is interesting Smaller distribution like people who don't wouldn't work with diamond like smaller shops like really small comic publication shops And those sorts of things.
Rym: I think it might be easier for them to start getting in the door with lower-tier distributors.
Scott: Exactly this opens up so many possibilities.
Scott: will Indy you know cuz Marvel I guess is stuck with diamond for however long.
Scott: who knows what they're gonna do right?
Rym: yeah I'd love to see when their contract is up for renewal because that is a date that I would just Set a reminder for to see what's in the news the next day.
Scott: Yeah, also remember that the books that are going to Barnes & Noble borders They're going through yet another distributor.
Scott: They're not going through diamond right because those are returnable.
Scott: But like okay does this mean Indy?
Scott: comic book companies say from you know image IDW But also little guys right manga is sold through diamond right yeah Could they switch to lunar or UCS or someone else.
Scott: yeah, right?
Scott: What about you know you just start up out of nowhere right?
Scott: you know you want to make.
Scott: come you make a comic book in Your garage.
Scott: maybe lunar will distribute it for you.
Scott: who knows?
Rym: yeah?
Rym: Or maybe literally more willing to work with whoever you get to do your primary distribution because you're low-tier like They'll be more willing to take on this weird stuff to build a big report.
Scott: Go on to get listed in previews.
Scott: you have to have a certain like quantity or whatever.
Scott: so there's certain rules about it.
Scott: Maybe the rules will be different.
Scott: Yeah, I'm in.
Scott: comic books ships their comic books to comic book stores on Wednesdays right.
Scott: typically I believe that's comic day right.
Scott: so a lot of comic stores have new product on Wednesday slash Thursday.
Scott: Will lunar have a different day?
Scott: Does this mean if you're the person who shops at a physical comic book store that you got to go in twice a week?
Scott: Right under your underwear pervert guy you got to get your comic books the day they come out.
Scott: You got to go to comic store twice a week once to get the Batman's the day it comes out and once to get the Spider-man the day.
Rym: well no because that person has that person has their pull list anyway.
Scott: I'm just saying right like these are things that I'm not saying.
Scott: it could still be Wednesdays, right?
Scott: But it's like these small things can make a big difference.
Scott: if people of customers are coming to the complex store more frequently right or maybe less frequently or Me you know maybe the comic book prices will be different for DZ comic.
Rym: yeah But look at how disruptive this is gonna be to the existing comic distribution model because frankly Floppy comics in the US are a weird niche market that doesn't behave like almost any other market.
Scott: There's all sorts of other products too, right if you're a comic book store that you go to decides to go with lunar versus UCS.
Scott: Will there be a difference between the two?
Scott: yeah well the complex store order from both.
Rym: What if lunar starts also distributing paintball gear?
Scott: I'm just.
Rym: I'm just thinking back to how many comic shops make their actual money by also selling airsoft or paintball.
Scott: well Diamond doesn't distribute airsoft and paintball, but they distribute toys games magazine t-shirts apparel Gundam models like the.
Scott: Every nerdy thing that you need to put on the shelves in a comic book store is in the diamond previews catalog.
Scott: So what will be in the lunar catalog?
Scott: right there's so many doors this opens in terms And will the competition drive down prices right between the distributors there?
Scott: They get a margin to will they?
Scott: will diamond try to shrink their margin, right?
Rym: How much take slack exists within diamond?
Rym: how much of diamond was just rent seeking from this niche market where they're basically the only Game in time because they were a monopoly?
Scott: now the non monopoly competition has appeared, right?
Scott: There's so many things that can happen now for nerds acquiring nerdy things in the US especially comic books.
Rym: It's exciting times Yeah and it hits at a time when like floppy comic distribution and like how people interact with comics is already changing rapidly like Irrespective of the virus or any of these changes.
Scott: So really yeah talk to you if you're a person that goes to the comic store Talk to your local comic book store provider About this situation and see what they have to say about it.
Scott: if it's an old white guy they'll probably be cranky and upset.
Scott: or Maybe they're the one or the but they might be cranky and upset at Diamond or cranky and upset at the change.
Scott: It's 50/50, right?
Scott: You know, basically complex store owner is always going to be complaining about no matter what they're.
Rym: that kind of person Stereotypically, so real real brief geek bite because I watched a bunch of a show that a lot of you I've seen a lot of people talking about.
Rym: it's got a couple seasons.
Rym: It's on Netflix.
Rym: It's called Kipo and the age of wonder beasts, it's just not heard of it.
Rym: really not at all.
Scott: No, I've heard of Kupo.
Scott: the thing how says because you realize this is a DreamWorks?
Scott: Okay.
Rym: Yeah DreamWorks.
Scott: I don't think I've liked.
Scott: I don't think I've ever watched and liked any DreamWorks thing.
Scott: Let me look at a list.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: Well, this is specifically DreamWorks animation television.
Scott: Yeah list of DreamWorks animated productions.
Scott: If I like you can just keep going.
Scott: I'm gonna see if I liked any of this.
Rym: This one is Prince of Egypt Shrek spirit Madagascar coming through pain.
Scott: I know I just never saw most of those.
Rym: I've seen a bunch of them.
Rym: They're all okay.
Rym: the ones I've seen Comfort panda was probably the best of the ones that I've seen here.
Rym: Never actually shot saw Shrek.
Rym: nor did I have any interest in seeing Shrek at any point?
Scott: I think I've actually seen Zero Dream.
Rym: you didn't even see how to train your dragon.
Rym: That's actually legit good.
Scott: I've seen the trailer.
Scott: It's a huge watch at some points that because there was a time when I went to the movies and it was the trail There was all the trailer was always how to train your dragon or how to train your dragon two or three.
Rym: It's actually pretty good Like it's a good movie.
Rym: But Kipo is a television show like an animated TV show on Netflix obviously aimed at kids an adventure time Kind of world like post-apocalypse.
Rym: There's mutants everywhere.
Rym: humans live in basically like vaults underground.
Rym: a girl gets trapped outside of her vault and has to find her way back.
Rym: Oh Hmm.
Scott: Well fallout.
Rym: Yeah, but one goes on one hand.
Rym: It's much more light-hearted than those things and to go for leave with Yeah, but on the other hand, it's actually a lot dark light.
Rym: It looks a lot less dark than it is and it's a very dangerous show where the characters almost get literally killed on a regular basis.
Rym: But if I had to say anything about it It's actually a pretty solid kid show.
Rym: like if you haven't seen Shira or by all means watch Shira first or Steven Universe or Adventure time or any of those top tier shows.
Rym: But if you've watched all those shows and you're just looking for something to watch like over dinner Kipo is not bad.
Rym: It's funny enough to just kind of keep going.
Rym: it's Interesting.
Rym: It's a diverse cast and I think I like the meta plot that's starting to evolve to a degree.
Scott: Adventure time on HBO's coming sooner.
Rym: Ah, yeah The first one is gonna be the short about BMO going into space with that rabbit girl.
Scott: Yeah, give me that pump that right in my veins.
Rym: Yeah, I'm Adventure time even though the end of the show was perfect like oh they just went on living their lives good like that that bit At the end was perfect.
Rym: I am glad that there's gonna be more adventure time because I got a whole pile of Adventure Time comics.
Rym: Yeah, so Adventure Time and pony comics are both still like a plus things but anyway things Of the day, so this is a real simple troll video.
Rym: It's about seven minutes long, but it explains what a quartermaster does on a pirate ship and you might think that sounds boring and To a degree it is born.
Scott: Oh, you mean pirate ship specifically not regular Navy ship.
Rym: Well, they basically do the same job like quartermaster is quartermaster no matter where you go?
Scott: Yeah, but you know, I figure pirates a little less organized.
Rym: I mean you've played the game quartermaster general.
Rym: I have.
Scott: yeah.
Rym: So what did the quartermaster do of a pirate crew and how important were they compared to the captain?
Rym: They were probably more important than the captain even though they got paid less.
Scott: But this is what they weren't in charge right, you know?
Scott: The captain can still tell the quartermaster what to do.
Rym: Yep to a point but the crew could overturn could vote to shut down the captain depending on how the pirate crew was set up.
Scott: It's called mutiny Pirates.
Scott: you're talking about pirates.
Scott: You're not talking about navies.
Rym: Yeah, not talking about navies in this case, but this video is pretty good.
Rym: It's just in seven minutes.
Rym: It actually explains pretty succinctly and with a lot of Not subtle humor but dry humor that you might like.
Rym: you'll laugh at jokes a minute after they happen in this video.
Rym: But it's a very very good explanation of what a quartermaster is and I found it fascinating.
Rym: I hope you do too.
Scott: okay, so Traveling around the world is kind of hard to do right now even still
Rym: still weird Like I was looking at Google photos the other day looking for a picture from a packs of a board game We played and I scrolled past like it's weird to think that not that long ago I was like flying around in Asia and seems like I've been in my apartment for the last thousand years
Scott: Right, but you know what?
Scott: The good thing is you look at your window.
Scott: You see any airplanes?
Rym: No What does it smell like in New York City right now?
Rym: It smells like Not New York City, it just smells like flowers and trees.
Scott: it's weird Like tweeting like crazy.
Rym: Oh my god, the birds are so loud.
Rym: I'm not saying it's a problem, but they're.
Rym: they're notably loud.
Scott: Anyway, the point is People including, you know us May have traveled to you know, the Japan land with the home of all nerdery.
Scott: Yeah You know soon But that didn't happen.
Scott: Yep This is not gonna happen for quite a while.
Scott: so One of the key things pretty much any nerd wants to do when they go to Japan at least nowadays Is go to that there Ghibli Museum.
Rym: It's amazing.
Scott: I've been to it, which is a very Hallowed nerdy place because it's so secret, right?
Scott: It's like you don't see too many photos of it, right?
Scott: Even right you see some photos the outside.
Rym: Yep, like when you go they show you a short.
Rym: The shorts generally like aren't available anywhere else.
Scott: Animations that Animations that they show there that are randomly selected and not available to watch anywhere.
Scott: They're not on DVD.
Scott: They're not streaming.
Scott: You can't record them in there, right?
Scott: You can't watch, you know, there's nowhere to get them.
Scott: But like we show them in that one room, you can't pirate that.
Rym: Yeah, and that room is amazing.
Rym: But think about how like you go to Disney and like there's this experience The Ghibli Museum is like that except the experience is actually aimed at the kids in a very like Visceral and direct way like there'll be a little hole near the floor that an adult might not even notice.
Rym: But a kid who's walking along would not only see it but might just crawl into it and disappear and there's stuff in there anyway Because the Ghibli Museum is closed.
Scott: You can't even go there if you wanted to.
Scott: But they still feel like hey We need to share the magic of the Ghibli Museum with the world.
Scott: They opened up a YouTube channel.
Rym: Oh, whoa This is like a week old.
Rym: Yeah Why are there ten dislikes on this video?
Scott: My thing of the days are high quality, not like your garbage thing of the days.
Scott: The Ghibli Museum has an official YouTube channel where they're uploading official videos Showing you trying to give you some experience of their museum because no one can go there.
Scott: How would you miss this something that you would you know there.
Scott: even if it was open and the tickets weren't sold out and you Didn't have to pre-order them.
Scott: Most people on earth could never go there.
Scott: Now you can go on YouTube.
Scott: That's a huge huge advancement.
Scott: Can't miss this incredible a-plus thing of the day.
Scott: Yep.
Scott: This is pretty good stuff.
Scott: I'm also very curious right?
Scott: you know Studio Ghibli is still mostly about Miyazaki right and he's a cranky old man.
Scott: How does he feel about this museum?
Scott: that seems very un-cranky and very un-old man?
Rym: He doesn't seem to be cranky and old man-y about like getting kids to experience things.
Scott: Yeah, I don't know But it's like.
Scott: I just wonder how he feels about the museum.
Scott: is there like an interview with him about the museum?
Scott: because I've seen Him a lot of interviews with him and like documentaries and him talking, but he's always talking about animation and things like that.
Scott: He's not.
Scott: I haven't seen him talk about the museum specifically like why he made it What he thinks about it, and I'm curious if I could ask him something.
Scott: That's what I'd ask him about because everything else to ask him has already been asked right why?
Rym: Yep, I mean the only thing I know is that he did design the entire thing himself.
Scott: Yeah, I mean he.
Scott: obviously he's approves of it right.
Scott: He's not gonna be like.
Scott: I hated that museum if they did that to make money.
Scott: I didn't.
Scott: I'm not a fan of it.
Scott: Yeah, obviously.
Scott: Yeah, it's not that he's gonna say.
Scott: If that was what he was gonna say it wouldn't.
Rym: the Ghibli museum was a mistake In a moment.
Rym: we can't go anywhere.
Rym: no conventions for the foreseeable future.
Scott: if there is an online Convention that you think will not fail because I'm already seeing some failing Spectacularly and and is a good convention that is you know stands on the right side of history Yeah, we're not.
Scott: we're not going to know garbo.
Scott: You know white dude convention.
Scott: Yeah, if it's even if it's only digital, right?
Scott: Yeah, and we're white dudes, so you know if we're if we're gonna be the white dudes at the online convention We can't be the only ones.
Rym: the one I'm definitely gonna go to as an attendee Obviously not as a lecturer or anything.
Rym: But game devs of color is gonna be online.
Rym: the expo and I the people who are setting that up are a plus people.
Rym: I'm really good.
Scott: game devs of color.
Scott: I just found out has a twitch channel.
Scott: I didn't I don't know.
Scott: I didn't know about that Until recently, but I'm on.
Scott: I got that now.
Rym: Yep So yeah, you want us to appear in one of those conventions.
Rym: Maybe you run one or something.
Rym: Let us know.
Rym: I mean we can redo panels we've done.
Rym: if you're a fan of us, you know kind of the kinds of panels we do.
Rym: We're also very happy to do the ideas that Places like packs have never really given us the chance to try are more out there or more angry or more weird Content.
Rym: like we got a bunch of stuff.
Rym: Eventually, we might just start making those panels on our own and just videoing them and putting them on YouTube.
Scott: Also our panels.
Scott: everything we do is creative comments license.
Scott: So even if you were the worst convention imaginable you could go to the YouTube channel.
Scott: You could take our panel that we've already done on YouTube and just show it at your convention.
Scott: digital convention Yeah, and there's nothing we could do to stop you.
Scott: But if you're shitty and you did that and we found out we will denounce you.
Scott: Yep.
Rym: It's Creative Commons attribution.
Rym: You have to say who we are.
Rym: You can't like overdub.
Rym: I'm Rym and I'm Scott with two different names.
Scott: Yes, but yeah, well, we'll denounce you if you're bad, but you can do it if you're good.
Rym: Yeah The old the convention that I know did that but it was a DVD because there's just an ancient time was of all places Anime Boston.
Scott: No, that wasn't them going to our YouTube and showing.
Rym: I said they use the DVD because the YouTube thing wasn't necessary but they only did it because we had panels scheduled at both anime Boston and at what if we made?
Scott: what if we made a Convention panels track out of?
Scott: we don't invite anyone.
Scott: We just take YouTube videos.
Rym: That is actually one of the things I proposed to Otakon long ago before they kicked us off the staff.
Scott: we go to discord right.
Scott: we open up a discord chat and we Show YouTube videos of panels that we have selected.
Scott: Convention one after the other with breaks in between breaks in between Q&A color commentary, right?
Scott: We just talk in between about what we just watched.
Scott: We call it meta meta con For like a few hours.
Rym: Yeah Not a terrible idea
Scott: Mmm,
Rym: but anyway, yeah The tale of Hanzo tale of Genji where hopefully I'll start reading it again now that I can just bike somewhere and sit under a Tree for a while,
Scott: but maybe I'll see if I can successfully read while biking in one place.
Rym: I I do read while I'm biking on the shitty exercise bike, but I cannot read while I'm running.
Scott: so Yeah, yeah, obviously.
Rym: So we watch some more anime.
Rym: We're gonna talk about this anime now.
Rym: I want to preface this by saying something very important goes to the show.
Rym: standalone complex first and second gig are some of our favorite anime ever.
Rym: like it's a class anime through the kind of show.
Scott: so goes to the show the original movie also a Plus anime and the original manga a plus.
Scott: Yep
Rym: But like standalone complex is the kind of thing where like when I was doing a little bit of research before we did this show I pulled up a clip last night of a random scene from second gig and It was real hard to not just start watching all of second gig again Mm-hmm, so I'd gotten excited
Scott: a
Rym: while ago when I found out that there was gonna be more ghost in the shell standalone complex.
Rym: A little bit of a hide.
Rym: even Homer Simpson with the program.
Scott: Yeah, I didn't finish watching all of the arise.
Rym: No one did cuz it was boring.
Rym: It wasn't going anywhere.
Scott: I think we only watched one episode.
Rym: Watch a bunch more and I kept stopping.
Rym: cuz I kept forgetting to watch more cuz it didn't leave any impression on me.
Rym: I watched.
Scott: I think we watched one episode in the theater.
Scott: Yeah, we did and and then I don't think I've watched it anymore since even though it seems to all be on Netflix.
Rym: So I've watched all of it and I've seen some of the episodes more than once.
Rym: I am at a loss to remember enough to even tell you what happened in it.
Rym: That is how forgettable it was.
Scott: I can't remember anything.
Rym: standalone complex was the good one.
Rym: So I got excited that there's gonna be more standalone complex But because it was announced like a while ago like a long time ago years ago, but then I forgot about it.
Rym: I just forgot that was the thing.
Rym: I just slipped my mind didn't think about it.
Rym: And then one day Anna Twitter was making fun of a naked backwards flipping guy And they said something ghost in the shell.
Rym: and then I discovered that not only had it come out But it's bad or at least people were saying it was bad.
Scott: Everyone said ghost is a new ghost in the shell.
Scott: It's all CG.
Scott: It's on Netflix and it's.
Scott: they were saying it's way way bad and I was like, oh, okay I guess I'll avoid that then because you know, there hasn't been.
Scott: you know Ghost in the shell isn't something where it's guaranteed to be good.
Rym: I mean the majority of the ghost in the shell.
Rym: content that exists in the universe is not great.
Scott: If you look at all of it It's like it's pretty much.
Scott: It's like the original movie the original manga Get sack one get sack two innocence.
Scott: the movie.
Rym: I like innocence, but it's not.
Rym: it's got problems Like.
Rym: it's not a great movie, but I really.
Scott: and then there's man-machine interface, which would come next I guess in the rankings and that's even more.
Rym: But I figured reviewing this would be good one because I want to give it a chance to see if The story the plot like anything can get through the fact that it looks worse than PUBG, right?
Scott: It's like what we've been every I sort of realize.
Scott: it's like hey all the only things we talked about in GeekNights.
Scott: So things we watch or play or whatever and it's always stuff that we've you know We've judged it beforehand and it's usually gonna be good has a good chance of being good before we go for it.
Scott: So it's pretty rare that we watch something that's bad.
Scott: I said, you know what everyone says this is bad, but you know, let's Write a verify.
Scott: Yeah and be even if it turns out that it's bad It's like well we can at least do a GeekNights on something that's bad and not always something that's good.
Rym: We made a pact that we would watch two episodes and no more and if either one of us felt the urge to watch the Third episode we would tell the other one advance.
Rym: I note that I did not at any point tell you to watch episode 3 and I did not receive a message from you telling me To watch episode 3.
Scott: Well, I didn't.
Scott: I didn't remember it till today.
Scott: So I watched The first episode earlier today and the second one like just before the show, yep, so Even if I wanted to watch 3 I didn't have time.
Rym: So on one hand the animation like it just did.
Rym: this show looks like a kind say a cutscene from a video game But it's worse than that.
Rym: It looks like a cutscene from one generation ago video game.
Scott: Yeah, I think the biggest problem in the animation is that it's not low quality, right?
Scott: It's like you can take certain stills and say wow, look at that.
Scott: It's pretty good CG.
Scott: Yeah, okay All right, it's that the way the characters move Combined with the cel shading on the characters Contrasted with this extremely highly detailed Background.
Rym: Oh my god, like an Aramaki's office the wooden door has the work.
Scott: The worst part is Aramaki's on that Exquisite door.
Rym: that door looks photorealistic.
Scott: and then there's this that was the scene where I noticed the CG being the worst was Aramaki's Standing around.
Rym: Yep, and then both Aramaki looks like weird like Aramaki looks worse than any other character.
Scott: Oh, yeah, he's bad.
Rym: He's the weirdest hairs.
Rym: weird like he's outlined wrong and like yeah It's almost like there's a different shader on him from everyone else in the show.
Scott: anyway, the other thing is that unlike say a b-star which has minimal action scenes Right that are done in a in a different kind of way as to like not actually show most of the action explicitly.
Scott: Yeah, right Ghost, you know this ghost in the shell at least focuses more on action scenes Even though ghost in the shell usually is mostly top heads with like one action scene.
Scott: This focuses a lot on action scenes.
Scott: Yeah, calm, you know military paramilitary combat and those parts are are weird too, but the They're weird for a bunch of reasons.
Rym: Like I got I had a lot to say about this show the more it is it so that?
Scott: but the point is the contrast With the the Celsius the moving parts against the non moving background makes it look Yeah way it ends up being one of the weird CGs and not one of the good CGs like honestly I'd like say a dragon prince or a b-star.
Rym: Well, like dragon dragon prince I was gonna bring up myself too because dragon prince has some awkward animation.
Rym: But the characters the story everything else made it very easy for me to just see past that and enjoy the show.
Rym: this There's nothing to see like.
Rym: the characters don't even feel like the ghost in the shell characters.
Rym: The dialogue is stilted and Like really prosaic.
Rym: like the like the characters don't say anything interesting to each other really ever.
Rym: the setting is vague Unrealistic and also almost a betrayal of like the arc of ghost in the shell up to this point.
Rym: Like you look at where standalone complex second gig ended This show is almost like a reversion like they step back into.
Rym: well section 9 got disbanded again.
Rym: now We're gonna reform it again.
Rym: vague political plot again But it's a slightly different political plot that has way less nuance.
Scott: Yeah, I think so plot wise right?
Scott: It's something about.
Scott: the world is now in perpetual war and there's one percenters But there's an evil good one percenter whose funding.
Rym: it's Mad Max world.
Rym: now because of economic warfare You get this.
Rym: the show starts with just this long Narration of right.
Rym: here is the state of the world.
Rym: It doesn't even like that's in the shell anymore.
Scott: I think that's part of the.
Scott: that's a huge part of the problem because Ghost in the shell has never like doesn't usually explicitly Tell you all how like the world is.
Rym: Yeah, it's all incidental storytelling like they don't tell you.
Rym: Oh section 9 does this because section 8 does this and section 7 does this.
Rym: and so, you know The kind of stuff that nerds love that I hate that like that World building for no purpose other than world building goes in the shell will just be like you run into section public security section 6 Because reasons and they're not their deal is not fully explained because it doesn't matter right
Scott: there.
Scott: Don't explain how the world is structured or how the economy is doing or the any of the big picture, right?
Scott: You're seeing and ghost in the shell.
Scott: You're all you're seeing, you know section 9 plays this small Role in this on these, you know, the what's you know their mission?
Scott: Yeah, right that they're odd.
Rym: They're basically the terrorist.
Scott: Yeah, there's a terrorist here doing this.
Scott: You got to stop them.
Scott: It's obviously in the interest of whoever's commanding them and you're it's always a mystery who's commanding them that the Surroundings of like.
Scott: why is this guy doing this?
Scott: Why are they bad?
Scott: Why did they?
Scott: why did it go?
Scott: Why did you know section 9's bosses want this done?
Scott: Right, you know the opposition they meet.
Scott: What are their motivations who are their bosses and what is their bigger picture?
Scott: You don't see any of that directly.
Scott: It's always indirect inference figuring it out.
Scott: Maybe you never find out at all.
Scott: That's how ghost in the shell is always point of view
Rym: of soldiers I would almost say professionals but professionals in the master Keaton way who have basically given up any semblance of a life to Live this life, but you see it from their perspective of you got your marching orders.
Rym: Go do the thing, right?
Scott: And Here by explicitly in some detail not perfect detail But in some detail like explaining the state the world is in and focusing on that.
Scott: It's sort of like me.
Rym: it's not like ruins that whole aspect and it keeps like reminding you like Oh, well, the setting is like this.
Rym: for these reasons, right?
Rym: You know what?
Rym: It feels like watching this feels like reading the Wikipedia page about this show Right, like there's no watching goes.
Rym: Michelle PD is the same, right?
Scott: So when I watch a ghost in the shell, the reason I like it is because a you care about the characters, right?
Scott: Be careful what the characters are doing, right?
Scott: See there's some Usually something going on that's always asking.
Scott: It's constantly asking you all sort of like transhumanist cyberpunk kind of questions Right and scenarios and morals right along right?
Scott: So it's like, okay the you know They got orders to go stop this hacking guy, but what's that hacking guy about?
Scott: Oh, he's doing this thing and that guy is you know, there's some moral Cyber moral related to what that guy's up to.
Scott: that they're after.
Rym: Yeah, and I this one's gonna have that same plot.
Rym: It feels like from like what I read of spoilers after I watched the first two episodes.
Rym: But it just.
Rym: it feels like someone Barfing out a list of spoilers or like a comic book that someone would read literally just to find out what happened to spider-man.
Rym: But they don't care about the artistry of it.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: So another thing all right is a ghost in the shell and most of its iterations that I can think of has a somewhat Consistent mood to it where it's sort of like dark eerie Cyberpunk II
Rym: often very zoomed in action scenes tend to be very sharp and punctuating Surrounded by long silences and tension.
Rym: This one's just like what like literally watching a PUBG match.
Scott: very very surreal.
Scott: Yeah, I think about the episode where there's like a brain like that.
Rym: They find that a bizarre that the Yeah, they like jack into it to see what's going on in there.
Scott: And it's like a weird kind of.
Rym: you know the one where it gets into the majors past with her hallucinations Right exactly the same kind of deals right?
Scott: or you know the one where was like Batou goes to a dojo or something.
Rym: the best my favorite are monkey with the wine cellar in all of standalone Complex is still the one where you find out where Saito the sniper like how he joined the major Mm-hmm.
Scott: The point is is you get those are a character episodes Yeah, which you're not getting anything out of here B.
Rym: They actually show it.
Scott: They don't just tell you right But they have this this mood to them right.
Scott: all of ghost in the shell has this same mood and and ghost Michelle was a 2045.
Scott: Right that mood is just completely obliterated in the opener with its weird-ass song.
Rym: Oh my god no right I was almost okay with that opener because it's an okay song.
Scott: It just does not fit ghost in the shell.
Rym: Yeah I could see it fitting.
Rym: if the show were better in the sense that This is the like.
Rym: this would be the standalone complex like third gig Where it gets into the fact that really section 9 just does what money wants it to do.
Rym: Like you can see there.
Rym: There's a direction you could go with that, but I don't think that's the direction the show's going.
Rym: also, you didn't watch Westworld.
Rym: the opening is like Almost identical to the Westworld opening, but Westworld is very like serious Like music build-up and this one is running mmm.
Rym: This one is more like Westworld.
Scott: you'll print.
Scott: I don't know any other Westworld's.
Rym: Yeah, you haven't seen the new Westworld at all.
Scott: Have you'll printer it?
Rym: Actually, yes, you'll they.
Rym: there is a you hold better cameo in the new Westworld, but he died before they made the new West.
Rym: Yeah, but the new Westworld is about the same thing as the old Westworld and at one point they go into this like warehouse Of a bunch of old like previous generation Westworld stuff and there's a yule Brenner.
Rym: just stand in there right in the front.
Scott: Okay, I'll watch that episode.
Rym: Yeah, you can find a clip of it on YouTube.
Rym: search for like yule Brenner new Westworld And you'll see him there, okay?
Rym: Yeah, but the opener reminds me of the Westworld opener and Westworld deals with a lot of these same transhumanist themes.
Rym: But I don't think the money makes the world go round.
Rym: song is like this Subversion of you thought the standalone complex and like section 9 we're doing these noble things But really they just do what money and government like.
Rym: I don't feel like that subversion is there.
Rym: I don't feel like I know all of that on purpose.
Scott: all of the cyberpunk stuff has basically been removed.
Rym: Right it is in the rest of the show.
Rym: the rest of the show is about these post humans are trying to get rid of The regular humans and all sorts of stuff.
Scott: Okay, maybe but regardless it's like You're just watching at least in the first two episodes.
Scott: What is otherwise?
Scott: Just you know like a Mission Impossible Kind of deal right like team of people have to go out and do a military thing.
Scott: alright.
Rym: So let's talk about that.
Rym: so let's see and there's.
Scott: no you know it's like yeah the weapons They're using it's like oh they hack someone's brain, and they have.
Scott: there's a crazy drone with AI But there's no it that doesn't play into the moral or the plot.
Scott: it just plays into the the action on But also the action on the screen.
Rym: Like wait I could see if the show was doing that sort of subversive Twist on Ghost in the Shell.
Rym: and then you get these scenes were like it's heavy action like they're just mercenaries now because the plot Of episode one is they literally are just mercenaries working in like America in Palm Springs Just in a Mad Max apocalypse.
Scott: I think here's the best way to describe it right.
Scott: so here in 2045 We see them using Tachikomas Yeah, which we also see them doing in standalone complex.
Scott: right, but in standalone complex They're not just using the Tachikomas in battle.
Scott: There is a major plot line.
Scott: Yeah Perhaps the most major plot line it is.
Scott: it shows about the Tachikomas in their AI and what the deal is.
Scott: yeah Right and the show.
Scott: this show is not in any way about that.
Rym: it might get that way later But if I don't think it's gonna do it in a satisfying way, but right the Tachikoma is also.
Rym: even action scenes Would have little like things the Tachikomas did that continued to tell that story of what's up with the Tachikomas.
Rym: Right like they would make a decision that people were surprised by.
Rym: but then that like they wouldn't focus on that as the plot.
Rym: But that sort of incidental storytelling would build up to the climax of the show and these transhumanist ideas.
Rym: The show does does not feel like it's going there.
Scott: Here the Tachikomas are literally just talking weapons.
Scott: They're not Doing anything.
Scott: yeah, they're not characters.
Rym: But even if let's say this was this was all on purpose the action scenes themselves are also really badly done like the fight.
Rym: Choreography doesn't make any goddamn sense at all.
Rym: Like though these cars are driving behind them shooting at them for like five minutes while they talk and yet not a single bullet even comes Near.
Rym: anybody like it doesn't even make sense from the perspective of an action scene.
Scott: Yeah, no not a lot of the stuff doesn't make sense, but it seems like someone just came up with scenes They wanted to see yeah Oh, we want to see the her go into the sky and grab a drone right and it's like okay.
Scott: And then they found a way to make it happen.
Rym: yep But the characters also don't really feel like the characters You know from ghost in the shell like they have the same voice actors and nominally the same character.
Rym: But their dialogue is bad.
Rym: the dialogue is so like clipped and prosaic like the conversations They have.
Rym: you could swap which character says what line and it really wouldn't matter.
Scott: for the most part The character with the most character is actually the new guy.
Scott: yeah clown clown right Who you know is probably just kind of like is a traitor or is gonna get killed or something something's up?
Scott: Yeah, something's up with that new guy, but they actually even though the new guy's character is very flimsy He's basically you know guy who has some skills, but way less skills way less experience a way less discipline Yeah, and sort of silly right?
Scott: You know likes to act up and get on a line like a. you know It's pretty stereotypical for a new guy on a team right in any sort of Team based like you know action kind of thing.
Scott: But that paper-thin You know personality he has is more than the other characters have which is zero
Rym: Yeah, but like the things that all their personality
Scott: from the previous shows has been removed
Rym: like they don't make sense like vato like acting They're actually going to drink this beer in a party when really they're on the way to a mission.
Rym: like the dialogue didn't really make Sense.
Rym: it felt like they were just filling time and like I have the characters talk before the fight scene But they also subverted.
Rym: some of the characters like Toga say is now like divorced like they've just changed whole cloth.
Rym: How some of the characters exist in the universe?
Scott: Right and it's like.
Rym: that's the kind of thing where like the whole point of that character was that he's the only one who's holding On to a normal life outside of this paramilitary life Like that was and that was across multiple seasons and both movies.
Scott: Right and that was like a constant.
Scott: I was like a thing that made that was like made his him like have a deal.
Scott: right is like This guy actually has like a family and a life every single other person is completely alone in the world.
Rym: yep, right?
Scott: They have no family they have no friends.
Rym: you ever see like they throw themselves into their work because there's no Right.
Scott: no nothing right.
Scott: Toga Has this family this wife and kid.
Scott: right and it's like and he's involved.
Scott: He's the only one involved who knows anyone else and He's you know also mostly human right and almost entirely human right and it sets him apart.
Scott: But yet you still see him doing the job, and he's awesome And that's like his whole reason for being there right is to you know connect.
Scott: You know make that connection.
Rym: I do want to say I feel like Paz and Borma do.
Rym: both have lives outside But they keep it secretive like it because the show really focuses on the major and Bato and like a really limited set of the Characters.
Scott: well you see like in standalone complex.
Scott: I just mentioned right it was.
Scott: you know those episodes You know Bato and the dojo and you know our Maki and the wine cellar.
Scott: Yeah, right do show they have some outside connections to some people right professional people who really don't are like the major.
Scott: Yeah, the major doesn't know anybody.
Scott: yeah.
Scott: But anyway the point is is that's what that character is about.
Scott: so by removing that it's like Oh, what's togas about now?
Scott: right well the only thing he's about now is being mostly human I guess, but they don't ever bring that up.
Scott: Yeah, they've removed all cyberpunk moral storytelling, so that doesn't matter anymore.
Rym: Yeah.
Rym: But then what really rankled me that pushed me over the line of not caring about the show was when The plot in the second episode it gets revealed that Aramaki's reforming section 9 that is literally how it's like second gig starts.
Rym: That's how every ghost in the shell starts either the form in section 9 or the reform in section 9.
Scott: And it's so the way the reform is just like.
Scott: well the prime minister wants us to reform it.
Scott: ok Yeah, we'll do it.
Scott: Then.
Scott: It's like you didn't have any like.
Rym: And then they explain about how the prime minister is actually an American who's gonna Just be a puppet of American interests.
Rym: like it says out loud the things that one don't fucking matter to a show Like this.
Rym: and two in a good ghost in the shell.
Rym: you figure that out if you care in the background But it doesn't if it matters.
Rym: and but even then even if it doesn't matter if it matters You still don't need to figure it out to understand the rest of the show.
Scott: Because a good a good ghost in the shell is the type of anime where they're you know trying to catch Like a hacker in a random neighborhood who's right and they hacked into.
Scott: I guess I remember some ghosts in the shell.
Scott: seems They're like hacking the garbage man or something right something like that.
Scott: and on a TV that the garbage man is watching It says new prime minister elected first American new American Prime Minister of Japan yeah, and it cuts away because you're actually focusing on the garbage men's conversation Yeah,
Rym: but then five episodes later that Prime Minister like suddenly It's like oh the Prime Minister cut our funding and they're like what shit.
Scott: Oh, no Yeah, the Prime Minister like makes an announcement something something, and then that's all you see.
Scott: right you know.
Rym: But then the final final line was the closer.
Rym: Why can't the show look like that?
Scott: The closing close I did note it looks I was gonna say as bad as the opener is with its with its song that doesn't fit.
Scott: that's not a bad song It's just a non-fitting song.
Scott: yeah when the closer started I was like oh this closer seemed like is a completely normal closer that belongs in a ghost in the show felt like ghost in the shell closer.
Rym: and Also, the animation looked good.
Rym: the character designs look good Mmm.
Scott: I mean there are parts of the animation that look good, but yeah well like but like.
Rym: the thing that looked good in the Fight scene was that robot dog, but they set up that robot dog like oh, what's that kind of robot?
Rym: I was that was the weirdest bad check-offs dog Yeah But they did like that scene and a different ghost in the shell would have had an appropriate amount of menace like we don't know What that box is.
Rym: we got to worry about it and when the box does its thing it's gonna be something fucking insane.
Rym: But it's like oh, it's just a guard dog, and how did they defeat it?
Rym: They just shot it.
Scott: Yeah, I mean it was strange to me.
Scott: It's like the the power level of the characters.
Rym: Seems it was like it was all over the place.
Scott: It's like in you know It's like the major and the original ghost in the shell movie like ripped the tank apart right with their pants so it damaged her too.
Scott: right, but the You know they're really fucking strong.
Scott: So it's like even that dog and the drone that they try to make scary.
Scott: It's like Why were those?
Scott: Scary, it's like the major.
Scott: like should have just like like.
Scott: oh, it's a little robot dog Whatever like.
Rym: they could have shot it immediately, but they don't scare.
Rym: it causes a bunch of problems.
Rym: And then like ten minutes later in the episode or I think the next episode They just shoot it like they could have done.
Scott: It's not scary for them at all.
Scott: I don't know why they.
Scott: they acted scared of it, and they tried to present it as being dangerous But it wasn't for them.
Scott: you and the drone could have been scary, but it's like no Why did the majors hack the drone to bring it down?
Scott: She's good enough.
Scott: It's like they.
Rym: they lampshaded that by saying that the drone was running autonomous.
Scott: Sure It was still strange.
Rym: Yeah It's just the show also.
Scott: that also gives you another point.
Scott: right is like all right.
Scott: so the major does some crazy action scene stuff And gets up there to the drone.
Scott: right okay, the drone does not have any networking.
Scott: It's running autonomously.
Scott: right something like that.
Rym: Yeah, instead of complex.
Scott: She would like a little call into it.
Scott: She would have plugged into that shit and been and hacked in it.
Scott: like who's controlling this drone?
Scott: who programmed it?
Rym: Right yeah, and then it would have to like an evil guy like pulling.
Scott: Oh, there's an AI.
Scott: drone is an AI?
Scott: there's an AI.
Scott: someone has actually been trapped in this drone.
Scott: Who is it right?
Rym: The AI who's trapped wants to get the message out and tells the major something that we don't get to see and then that comes up five episodes later.
Scott: Right you know something like that as opposed to all right.
Scott: She dragged it to the ground and destroyed it.
Rym: Yeah, mostly oh, but it's still got a missile off which I guess we was trying to do all along.
Rym: So I still don't understand what all these pub G like fortnight looking kids are doing in this show in the first place.
Rym: Yeah Anyway, but one thing.
Rym: when I was watching with Emily And she pointed out that the character designs looked like this one designer, and it was Ili I cushion off And those character designs look great Except in the actual show like in the closer or on like that designers Instagram.
Rym: They look great.
Rym: It's just in the show.
Rym: They're animated in this kind of weird ugly one generation to go video game way.
Scott: So I also want to talk about right.
Scott: so we talk about almost all the characters except for Ishikawa right who's basically always been like the hacking dude.
Rym: Yeah, he just sits in the base hacking right He does.
Scott: he does some other stuff.
Scott: He does some action also, but you know it's like.
Scott: you know his main plots are like aha I've hacked all the brains of the old dudes in the pachinko parlor to power up my computer right.
Scott: so He doesn't do any of that.
Scott: He's basically drives and shoots a machine gun.
Scott: It doesn't do anything else.
Rym: What about Saito the the second I know?
Rym: it's still history of the world.
Scott: at least he's still sniper guy.
Rym: Yeah But he also like it doesn't really solve their problem.
Rym: what in regular goes to the shell?
Rym: when Saito gets out his gun The whole point of the show is hit.
Rym: that solves the problem.
Scott: He doesn't miss.
Scott: yeah I think he missed.
Rym: actually I think he did miss.
Rym: he was.
Scott: he was like he tried to shoot the drone and missed.
Scott: it's like.
Rym: well cuz it like it hacked him and saw his satellite feed.
Rym: and Just the show just doesn't feel like ghost in the shell at all.
Scott: yeah, no.
Scott: Anyway, so even though the show is not good.
Scott: It is far away from good, right I do want to say it is not the worst.
Rym: Oh, I've seen worse.
Rym: I've seen I see a lot worse.
Scott: So I think what you're seeing I think the reaction to the show saying how bad it is.
Scott: It's not incorrect It is bad.
Rym: well cuz we're comparing it to what the ghost in the shell we like.
Scott: Exactly.
Scott: I think this is a situation much like Death Note where if you haven't read or watched any Death Note Right Death Note has two phases.
Scott: There is the beginning like most of Death Note is about this battle between these two characters.
Scott: that battle reaches his climax and conclusion and then some new characters come in and Continue the battle right and then that and and then the month when that battle ends the story ends and that When that second battle begins right?
Scott: People who are fans of Death Note like that a lot less.
Scott: they thought that like they were like.
Scott: oh it turned to garbage.
Scott: Right it's like it sucks now only that first battle.
Rym: Yeah good, but the second part wasn't bad It just wasn't.
Scott: a second part wasn't bad.
Scott: It.
Scott: Just wasn't as good and didn't include characters that you had already grown close to and loved right.
Scott: so it felt the relational Feelings right made it seem awful because it's like one second You're eating the best steak on earth and the next second you're eating serviceable steak.
Scott: So it tastes awful, but relatively speaking right.
Scott: whereas if I had just given you serviceable steak you would have said That's pretty good right, but because you were just eating delicious Amazing steak the second one was meh.
Rym: Yeah, right.
Rym: the problem is I feel like anyone who has not already seen all the other ghosts in the shell Wouldn't have anything to even hook them on this show at all.
Rym: they'd watch the first episode and go well.
Scott: I would be very interested to see what someone who is doesn't know anything about ghosts in the show would write the show Because I think the problem would be why would you care at all?
Rym: yep?
Scott: And because the characters doesn't have the character right it's like not having the character stuff at all.
Scott: At least somebody who's seen other ghosts in the shells might care about the characters because they already care about them because they watched a good Show, but then they're mad because these characters don't live up to those characters.
Scott: right exactly, but If you have not seen anything at all Why do you care at all?
Scott: You weren't made to care to start with.
Scott: yeah, right where you see something like you know if you read You know it's really always really good at.
Scott: this is What's it called?
Scott: Noki Urasawa, right You read a Noki Urasawa manga, and there'll be like a character who's there for one chapter.
Rym: right like you Read a chapter you look at it start as if you're like who's this guy?
Rym: end of the chapter.
Rym: You're literally crying master Keaton.
Scott: meet someone at the beginning of this chapter And they're dead at the end and you just met them and you dirt.
Scott: They only exist for 20 pages, and he made you care about them in 20 pages.
Scott: Yeah, right It's like you might even cry over that person ghost in the shell thinking about a specific Pluto thing.
Rym: that happens right.
Scott: It's like the shell.
Scott: I've seen two movies and two TV series and two mangas and You can't make me.
Scott: you made me uncare About the character yep.
Rym: so Don't recommend actually watching this one.
Rym: really like no.
Scott: I just I'm saying it's like.
Scott: it's not a zero.
Scott: It's like well cuz the zero is like Legend of Len mere right.
Scott: It's not trash.
Scott: It's just man It's below man.
Scott: Yeah, it's more like.
Scott: it's like it's fart noise, but poop doesn't come out.
Rym: Yeah, like you won't you know you're not forced to flee But it's sad trombone Yeah, which is such a shame, but on the other hand it reminded me that I could just watch standalone complex.
Rym: again.
Scott: I forgot most of it.
Scott: Let's go.
Scott: Yeah.
Rym: I want to get all that.
Scott: I remember the big parts.
Scott: I just don't remember any of the details cuz it's been how many years yep.
Rym: So uh yeah, that was our review.
Scott: I'm curious to see what any of you think if you've even watched this because we're ever but in the in the future if there is Even bad stuff right don't.
Scott: if some people are saying something's bad don't subject yourself to it.
Scott: We will do that service for you, and then add our opinion to the pile of everyone else's opinion.
Rym: I think we'll only do that though if it's plenty to also Could be good things that are like bad like things that in judge anime by its cover We would just say as bad outright.
Rym: We're not gonna bother doing this way.
Scott: Yeah, we'll see But yeah, we're gonna.
Scott: You know I don't want to just always have GeekNights be.
Scott: We watched played read a good thing and then told you about it, and we knew it was good before we started.
Scott: Yeah, we got to go into some uncharted or questionable You know.
Scott: go pass some warning signs into dangerous territories to report our findings and do some reconnaissance.
Rym: Yeah We used to do a lot more bad reviews especially of anime and video games And board games.
Rym: part of the reason why we avoid bad reviews of board games is that?
Rym: most board games are bad.
Rym: like most things are bad and We just don't even bother playing bad board games like we don't even have anything to say about them.
Scott: It takes such a time investment.
Scott: I think yeah, it took me less than an hour to watch these two episodes But to but to play a bad board game enough to be able to properly critique Why it's bad.
Rym: that would take like eight hours of work, and that is not worth it for a bad board game.
Rym: This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ pretzel for the opening music cat leave for web design and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: be sure to visit our website At frontrowcrew.com for show notes discussion news and more.
Rym: remember GeekNights is not one But four different shows sci-tech Mondays gaming Tuesdays anime comic Wednesdays and indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: GeekNights is distributed under a creative commons attribution 3.0 license.
Rym: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience, but unlike those other late shows It's actually recorded at night and the patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce, Hygma nickel of Mardi Grini just like a dude guy Kjartavich and Graham Finch.
Rym: you hold the key to my heart But she packed my suitcase and sent me on my way.
Rym: Clinton Walton J Bants Ren from New Zealand with three exclamation points Ryan Perrin Nicholas Brando Chris midkiff sailor Vista The thirst for hydrated Gannon dread Lily Tenebrae Chris Reimer Finn Sean Klein sure about horrible and a whole bunch of people who don't want me to say their name.
Rym: Stay safe out there.
Rym: Tear down racist monuments anytime you see them and now I leave you with and you people you're all astronauts on Some kind of Star Trek Some sort of scanning device sir.
Scott: It's a tracking device of some kind
Rym: a cloaking device of some sort some sort of magnetic device in his belt some kind of coercive device some sort of medical instrument Apparatus of some sort some kind of power waveguide Conduits some sort of neural matrix some sort of debris some sort of corrosion some kind of damage.
Rym: There's some kind of damage some kind of continuing disintegration kind of chromosomal damage some kind of trauma some kind of Psychic trauma some sort of disease aboard.
Rym: the Enterprise picked up some disease from them some form of respiratory Ailment some sort of rash some sort of viral infection some sort of tryptamine residue in the cerebral cortex.
Rym: It's some kind of system-wide histaminic reaction some kind of inversion reaction some sort of plasma reaction.
Rym: It's some kind of reaction to our phase of our maps some kind of weapon.
Rym: There's some sort of magnetometric guided charges some kind of an arrow some kind of high-energy tachyon pulse some kind of phased pulse technology.