Rym: It's Wednesday, May 13th, 2020.
Rym: I'm Rym.
Scott: I'm Scott.
Rym: And this is GeekNights.
Rym: Tonight, we're talking about a webcomic.
Rym: We're talking about Katie Cook's "Nothing
Rym: Special.".
Scott: Let's do this.
Rym: So you may remember, a while ago, right when the quarantine started, I mentioned, uh, kind of just in the middle of a show, like, "I'm working on a project.
Rym: I got this wood hurdy-gurdy kit.
Rym: I'm gonna make a hurdy-gurdy.
Rym: I'll see how that
Rym: goes.".
Scott: Finish your hurdy-gurdy?
Rym: I finished it a long time ago.
Scott: -And it works.
Scott: -Are you playing it?
Rym: So I did play it.
Rym: I can make music come out of it.
Scott: Are you annoying everybody?
Rym: So the cool thing is, someone posted a YouTube video where they made that kit and it sounded like shit.
Rym: But that video, literally, once I built it and actually investigated it, the only reason that one sounded like shit is that they did not, at any point, they did not tune it at all.
Rym: They built it and it started cranking the stupid thing.
Rym: Imagine if you just bought a random guitar, like, in a garage sale and tried to play on it without even touching all those little knobblies -at the top.
Rym: -Mm-hmm.
Rym: So I tuned it, and it sounded okay.
Rym: Like, it sounded as good as I would have expected it to sound.
Rym: I could play some songs on it.
Rym: I tuned the drone string to a D.
Scott: Is it succeed in annoying everyone around you?
Rym: It's not that loud.
Rym: It basically could only annoy at most one person because we're in a quarantine.
Scott: Well, that's what you're best at.
Rym: Yeah, that was my goal.
Rym: So I was annoying with it for maybe two days, and then one of the strings snapped.
Scott: -Wah-wah-wah.
Rym: -Because the strings are basically just nylon fishing line.
Scott: I mean, that's what guitar strings are for every guitar.
Scott: that's not, you know...
Rym: Oh, nah, all the lower strings are at least, like, brass-wrapped or whatever.
Scott: Yeah, but I mean...
Rym: Every guitar I've ever had, only a couple strings were just nylon.
Scott: Right, but the point is that, like, you know, all the cheap guitars of the world have plastic nylon strings, right?
Scott: The fancy electric guitars have metal strings, right?
Rym: But anyway, these strings were not just cheap nylon.
Rym: They were, like, literally just fishing line.
Rym: So I bought some real guitar strings, and I'm going to restring it, but I'm going to have to be delicate with it.
Rym: I might have to actually reinforce it a little bit, because a real string...
Scott: Are the guitar strings the same, like, notes as what the hurdy-gurdy is?
Rym: I mean, it wouldn't matter, because with the frequencies, like, the way this thing would work, I just need a string that I could tune to a D vibration, and I'm good to go.
Rym: I could probably tune it to something else.
Scott: I was saying, you might want to, like, you know, it might be better to look for piano strings, right, that are the right...
Rym: - What do you think's in a piano?
Rym: - You have more choices.
Rym: Piano is a piano wire.
Scott: Oh, right, but I was saying, you get the right, you can have more choices.
Rym: Oh, yeah, I mean, yes, that is the kind of thing I did.
Rym: So I got some strings that I could tune to D. The thing I'm curious about is if I can do this without snapping the hurdy-gurdy, because if any of you don't play string instruments, not that I play string instruments, I was told at a young age that I should never play a string instrument, because I was terrible at it, preternaturally so.
Rym: But, like a violin, look at a violin.
Rym: If you string it, there's, like, 30 or 40 pounds of force trying to snap the violin in two right at the middle, because the strings are tight.
Scott: Right, but almost always, it's the strings that break and go doing.
Rym: Oh, no, I'm saying the violin would just collapse if you, like, tightened everything too tight.
Scott: Yes, but that hardly ever happens.
Rym: - Yes, however...
Scott: - Usually the strings will break first.
Rym: Or the bridge will... Anyway, this thing, because it is not, like, a crafted instrument, but a woodcraft that I piece together like a big jigsaw puzzle, I'm not confident that it could actually hold the tension of two real strings fully tensioned.
Scott: Why not buy some cheapo nylon guitar strings instead of the good ones?
Rym: Even nylon guitar strings, to tension them to the point where this would sound good, as opposed to just as good as I expected it to sound.
Rym: based on the kit, I don't know.
Rym: So I'm gonna play with it and see what I can do.
Scott: Why not go and buy a fucking fishing line?
Scott: 'Cause that's what it came with.
Rym: I could do that, but it will never sound better than it sounded when I first made it.
Scott: Why not?
Scott: You could buy some cheap... You could buy, right?
Scott: I don't know if ukulele strings are a good idea, but...
Rym: - Ukulele!
Scott: - Right.
Scott: You could buy, you know, those, like, souvenir, cheapo, like, children guitar.
Scott: that, like, you basically... - It's gonna break and you throw it out.
Rym: - That's just that fishing line in 'em.
Scott: Right, that's like... You know what I'm talking about?
Rym: Yep, so the other thing I might do is...
Scott: The ones that are, like, party favor guitars.
Scott: Like, you'll hand them out at, like, a party or a compartment or some shit, and, like, they have a couple strings and go jing, jing, jing, and that's about it.
Rym: So the good news is I did an experiment...
Scott: It's like a plastic thing in the shape of a guitar.
Rym: This thing only needs two strings.
Rym: It's a simple hurdy-gurdy.
Rym: There's a drone string and there's a melody string.
Rym: - Oh, okay.
Rym: - So I put just one... I replaced the drone string with, like, a G, like, a metal, like, a full-on guitar string, and I tensioned it to the point where it would play a sound.
Rym: that was, like, the note I wanted, and it seemed that the structural integrity was totally fine with that.
Rym: So I just have to try to figure out if it can take about double that amount of tension.
Rym: - All right.
Rym: - I might just have to reinforce the bridge.
Scott: Yeah.
Scott: - But... - You could always... You know, like, a lot of people make, you know, that are sound actually pretty good, like, you know, cigar box guitars with, like, you know... So you could just get, like, you know, Rubberband or something.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: Or what I might just do, if I really want to play this, I mean, the right answer is just to buy or make a real hurdy-gurdy instead of one that is basically a giant jigsaw puzzle.
Rym: - Sure.
Rym: - So we'll see.
Scott: Or just give up on this and stop making annoying noises and find something for you.
Rym: No, no, no, because the magic of a hurdy-gurdy is that it does not require the skills that I'm preternaturally bad at, which is fingering on frets, I just can't fucking do.
Rym: Like, that's just, like, I have a weird blind spot where I cannot play stringed instruments to any capacity.
Rym: And also I'm not good with a bow.
Rym: So with my powers combined, like, it's a perfect storm of a violin sounding worse, as bad as possible.
Scott: Why don't you, if your goal is to make annoying noises, why don't you just buy one of those, like, automatones where you, like, you know...
Rym: Oh, wait, wait till we get to my thing of the day.
Scott: Okay, isn't it another automaton thing of the day?
Rym: Do you remember the Sing-a-ma-jig?
Rym: The Sing-a-ma-jig?
Scott: -It was a toy?
Scott: -Yeah, the thing you're obsessed with, right?
Scott: -That guy?
Scott: No?
Scott: -What?
Rym: No?
Scott: Oh, I thought that was the name of the big...
Rym: No, it was a toy from, like, a long time ago.
Scott: Oh, okay, I just Googled it and I've never seen it before.
Rym: Okay, good, that's my thing of the day.
Rym: But, uh, remember...
Scott: But it looks like an automaton inside a stuffed animal.
Rym: Sort of, yeah, but it predates the automaton by a wide margin.
Rym: -All right.
Rym: -But, yeah, basically, if I want to be a true Annoy-a-tron, I have my trumpet.
Rym: That is louder than any stringed instrument could ever possibly be.
Scott: Annoy-a-tron is a character in Hearthstone/World of Warcraft.
Rym: Ah.
Rym: All right, it's Wednesday.
Rym: You guys want to hear about anime and comics, you don't want to hear about my hurdy-gurdy.
Rym: So, there is actually a lot of anime news, even though a lot of it follows a theme that you're going to see momentarily.
Rym: So, what do you got?
Scott: I just wanted to first, you know, make people aware that certain... I think we might have said this on recent Wednesday episodes, but it bears repeating, that certain animes that were recently the ones that we talked about on the show, because they were the kind that are in the movie theater in the US, when you can still go to the movie theater, are now available streaming in various forms.
Scott: So, I know that you can see Promare streaming somewhere, you might have to pay money for it.
Rym: -Yep, it's worth it.
Scott: -I know that... Um, Song of the Sea, I think, is streaming somewhere, right?
Scott: Uh, yeah.
Scott: So, go back and look at all past GeekNights Wednesdays, and I think the vast majority of the anime that we discussed there, movie-wise, should mostly all now be available streaming somewhere, or, you know, pay a few dollars, like four dollars on Amazon to watch it, or, yarr.
Rym: Honestly, though, the pay four-ish dollars to watch it on Amazon option, it worked.
Rym: Like, if you've never used that option, it works real well.
Scott: I've been opening myself up to that option more and more, because when you think about it...
Rym: Like, you wanna watch Parasite?
Rym: Like, I'm pretty sure you can do that.
Scott: Oh, yeah, yeah, you can, absolutely.
Scott: But it's like, think about it, what's Netflix?
Scott: a month, 20 bucks, something like that, 15, I don't know.
Scott: -I don't even know anymore, right?
Rym: -When I was a kid, to rent a movie, I would go to Blockbuster, and it cost four dollars to rent a VHS tape.
Rym: -But that was for 19, like, 91.
Rym: -That was a lot of money.
Scott: Right, so let's think about, you know, let's say you pay one of those, like, annual subscriptions for, like, a niche streaming site.
Scott: Like, I think the Criterion Channel is, like, 100-something dollars a year is their cheapest price, right?
Scott: So, 100-something dollars a year divided by 12 is, you know, like, eight-something bucks a month, maybe, right?
Scott: Seven, eight, somewhere in there, I guess.
Scott: I don't know, math.
Scott: The point is, let's see, 100 -- I don't want to be wrong and stupid.
Scott: 8.3, I was good, okay.
Scott: Eight dollars a month.
Scott: The point is, okay, so if you watch two movies a month, you're paying, like, four dollars a movie, right?
Scott: So, if you're watching movies every day, you're gonna watch every movie on that whole frickin' channel.
Scott: It's not that big.
Rym: -I mean, remember back when we lived in Beacon and weren't doing a podcast yet?
Rym: We got, like --.
Scott: -And we watched every --.
Rym: -We got, like, five Netflix DVDs a week, and we watched them all.
Scott: -So, with the streaming services, if you're watching several times a week or if you're one of those people, you know, binge-watching the TV shows, then you're getting your money's worth, right?
Scott: If you're like me, where all you really watch is, like, a few, like, the excellent movies, right, and you don't even watch the man movies and you don't watch the TV shows too much, right?
Scott: It's like Netflix is -- I'm watching "The Castlevanias" and "Dragon Prince," that sort of thing, so it's kind of worth it, right?
Scott: But, you know, the A-plus movies are not really on most of these services, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, you want to even watch fucking -- I guess, you know, Disney has all Star Warses, but those aren't the Star Warses you want to --.
Rym: -Well, you know, I'll put it this way.
Rym: Every time, 100% of the times in recent memory, I've typed the name of a movie into, like, Netflix, 'cause I thought, "Oh, I'd like to watch that
Rym: movie.".
Rym: They have not had it.
Scott: -It's almost never there, almost, right?
Scott: So, often, these days, when I search for a movie I want to watch legally, for some reason, right, it almost always pops up and says, "You can watch this on YouTube, Amazon Prime," right?
Scott: You can watch it at, like, these four different places, and they all cost, you know, iTunes.
Rym: -Like, four-ish dollars.
Rym: -Right.
Scott: Three to four dollars to watch it once, right?
Scott: Actually, "Lord of the Rings" trilogy extended edition, I own digitally on Amazon.
Scott: -Yeah.
Rym: Oh, yeah, buying -- like, promo.
Rym: right now, actually, you can't stream promo, you can't rent it on Amazon, but you can buy it for 20 bucks.
Scott: -I mean, are you gonna buy a Booray?
Rym: -No, you can buy the digital access forever.
Scott: -That's what I'm saying, is, like, why would you buy a Booray?
Rym: -Yeah, exactly, 'cause I don't think Amazon will disappear, and if Amazon disappears and I lose whatever movies I have bought over the years, then --.
Scott: -The point is, even though you're buying it, that's still streaming.
Scott: You're not downloading it.
Rym: -True.
Rym: But I can watch it an infinite number of times at very high quality.
Scott: -The movies that you're thinking that you should be watching are now available to watch legally online if you want to.
Rym: -Oh, like here, "The Night is Short, Walk on
Rym: Girl.".
Rym: Rent it, $3.99 from Amazon.
Rym: You can just watch it.
Rym: That movie's beautiful.
Scott: -Maybe I will.
Rym: -I would watch that movie again.
Rym: That movie is so good.
Scott: -It's good.
Scott: All right, so, that's news one.
Scott: News two, speaking of movies, right, the movie you want to watch is, you know, Miyazaki, the man who is retired 20 times and come out of retirement 21 times.
Scott: Michael Jordan is jealous of how many times Miyazaki has come out of retirement to animate again.
Scott: It's been a while since he's come out for his not, I don't believe, final time.
Scott: The point is that --.
Rym: -You're talking about the 36 minutes of that film.
Scott: -Right.
Scott: The film that he is working on, which is called "Kimitachiwa do Ikiruka," which means -- "How Do You Live," which is supposed to be amazing.
Scott: Who knows?
Scott: It's a film Miyazaki's making, right?
Scott: Despite the coronavirus delaying or severely hindering the production of many other cinematic works, this movie, they've managed to animate by hand 36 minutes.
Scott: There is no computer involved.
Scott: They're animating it by hand the old-fashioned way.
Scott: -Interesting.
Scott: -'Cause he's got nothing better to do.
Scott: He doesn't care how much money it costs.
Scott: He wants to die.
Scott: making the movie, most likely, right?
Scott: That's what it looks like.
Rym: -I feel that he says they say the movie is a big fantastical story.
Rym: I don't know anything about it other than that.
Scott: -Who knows anything about it except him, right?
Scott: But the point is, he looks like a captain who wants to go down with the ship, so he keeps going out for another one.
Rym: -God, I just keep thinking that one episode of "Horatio" where the captain's like, "Run up to that fort and attack it so that I may
Rym: die.".
Scott: -Right, like Antoine de Saint-Éjourpéry, who went out in his plane in the horrible situation, right, because clearly he was asking for it, right?
Rym: -Or a scene involving a character in "BoJack Horseman" that I will not say any more on because that would be a spoiler.
Scott: -Okay.
Scott: But anyway, yeah, they're still making it.
Scott: They've animated 36 minutes, so at this rate, if he lives for a few more years, it will come out.
Rym: -But this article with that promise also comes a threat.
Scott: -Yes.
Scott: Well, so his son, his son Goro, with four arms.
Rym: -Goro made a good movie.
Scott: -The four-armed animator is making a completely computer-generated anime 'cause his dad's not using the computers, so he's like, "All right, I'll use all the computers while you're not using them.
Scott: They're just sitting there not working and not doing
Scott: anything.".
Rym: -Yeah, just come on.
Rym: That's how you get that ghost in the shell.
Scott: -Right, so Goro is making an animated film that is an adaptation of a book from England about a very wise girl.
Scott: Somebody, I'm sure, knows what book that is.
Scott: I don't.
Scott: -Yep.
Rym: I feel like you can narrow it down to a couple.
Scott: -That's going to be a CG-animated film that will probably come out well before "How Do You
Scott: Live?"
Scott: comes out.
Scott: -Yep.
Scott: So we'll see.
Scott: -And it probably has a higher chance of being finished also because computers and young person and trying to actually make money and not trying to die while working on an anime.
Rym: -Yep, though while some films like that are continuing to make progress, other films are just being delayed.
Rym: Like, there is a general broad slowdown in anime production for all the reasons you can imagine.
Rym: So, for example, the 23rd Pokemon film has now been delayed due to COVID, and the studio can't work on it effectively, so they've delayed it.
Scott: -I think we also mentioned probably last Wednesday episode that Cartoon Saloon working on "Wolfwalkers" also has an excellent work-at-home situation, and they're progressing just fine, and we also talked about how that's going to be supposedly maybe only on Apple+ when a TV+ goes.
Rym: -Which means I will literally, like, DM Tom Moore, "Cash," and then pirate it.
Rym: because -- -We'll see what happens.
Rym: -'Cause I'm not using that Apple platform.
Rym: I'm not paying for that.
Scott: -We'll see how it goes.
Scott: Maybe go to someone's house who has an Apple TV, watch it.
Scott: I don't know.
Rym: -I'm telling you, just DM him, like, a link to, like, send him some cash.
Rym: It'll work.
Scott: -We'll see what happens.
Rym: -Here's 20 bucks.
Rym: But what I'm surprised about there is that I knew there were a lot of Pokemon movies, but I don't think about them.
Rym: We've reviewed, like, two of them on "Geeknights" ever.
Rym: I didn't realize it was the 23rd Pokemon movie that is being delayed.
Scott: -Oh, yeah, I know.
Scott: All those franchises that don't die just keep having movies -- "One Piece" movies,
Scott: "Naruto.".
Rym: -Why can't I have 23 "Ghost in the Shell" standalone complex movies?
Scott: -'Cause they're a lot harder to make, and they make less money.
Rym: -Yep, exactly.
Scott: -It costs more money to make.
Rym: -Instead, we get "Ghost in the Shell" goes to work.
Scott: -But the thing is, there are plenty of movies for things like
Scott: "Modica.".
Scott: "Modica" is like, "I got a handful of
Scott: movies.".
Rym: -Yeah, but they didn't need a mod.
Rym: The show "Modica" ended perfectly.
Scott: Any more -- Like, "Cowboy
Scott: Bebop.".
Scott: "Cowboy Bebop" didn't even need a movie.
Rym: It was okay that they made one movie, but they did not need to make more movies.
Scott: -Anyway.
Rym: -Anyway, the real delay news that's a big deal is that, for the first time in 45 years, "Sazai-san" is airing reruns.
Rym: -Mm-hmm.
Rym: -Because they can't keep producing the show.
Scott: -So, people don't know about
Scott: "Sazai-san.".
Scott: "Sazai-san" is sort of -- It's not -- The content isn't very
Scott: "Simpsons-esque.".
Rym: -It's not the "Simpsons of Japan," like people like to say, except in the sense that it is a very long-running animated series about a family that is broadly popular.
Scott: -Yes, it is a very popular, very long-running animated series in Japan.
Scott: that doesn't look like anime that people outside Japan don't care about, right?
Rym: -And you might already take issue, but "Simpsons" isn't popular anymore.
Rym: If it wasn't popular, they wouldn't still be making it.
Rym: It's more popular than you think.
Scott: -Right, and also, "Sazai-san," the feeling I get is that it's about as popular in Japan as "Simpsons" is in the US, right, relatively speaking.
Rym: -Everyone at least knows about it.
Scott: -And they just -- You know, yeah, it's like people -- Anyone in Japan, if you showed them characters from "Sazai-san," you'd say, "What is
Scott: this?".
Scott: They go, "It's
Scott: Sazai-san.".
Scott: They know exactly what it is.
Scott: -But what's fascinating is why.
Rym: This is why I list these three things.
Rym: The "Pokemon" movie is probably --.
Scott: -Well, I think, didn't some of the voice actors pass away 'cause they were so old, I think, was also with it?
Rym: -Their age is actually part of the problem, but the specifics are --.
Rym: Well, contrast these three.
Rym: So, Goro can probably move on with the CG stuff 'cause that's easy to do work from home, and Ghibli has infinite resources to make this situation work, so they're still animating.
Rym: "Pokemon" movie needs, like, a big -- Like, there's a lot of contributors to that kind of, like, crank-it-out movie for a franchise, so it's probably easier to just delay it than try to keep that team going.
Rym: But "Sazai-san," I'm just gonna quote this article because it says it pretty eloquently.
Rym: "Recording new episodes seems especially difficult for the program.
Rym: Many of the actors are older and might not have the necessary equipment or environment at home to voice the
Rym: show.".
Rym: It's the voice acting, primarily.
Rym: The voice acting -- Like, you can't just change the voice of one of these kind of characters.
Scott: -As far as I'm aware, they voice act that show with everyone in the same room, and they've been doing it that way forever.
Rym: -I've heard that, but I never confirmed that, but I do believe it's true.
Scott: -Right, and they've been doing it so long that, much like "The Simpsons," the voice actors are very old now, right?
Scott: It's like, when they started doing it, they were young, and they've had that same job for a super long time, right?
Scott: It's like, find a picture of the lady who's, like, the voice of Bart now.
Scott: How old is she?
Scott: -Oh, and I got to point something out.
Rym: I got to point something out to you kids.
Rym: This is the first time in 45 years "Sazai-san" has run reruns, but "Sazai-san" is older than 45 years.
Rym: You realize the first time they ran reruns was during the oil crisis in 1973.
Rym: The show had already been running for a long time before that.
Scott: -Yeah, you can't even begin to -- It's like, other things you might try to, like, watch all of.
Scott: Like, you could watch all of "The
Scott: Simpsons.".
Scott: You can't even begin to try to watch all of
Scott: "Sazai-san.".
Scott: Even if you were fluent in Japanese and had it all on a hard drive, you couldn't -- It's, like, impossible.
Rym: -Like, "Sazai-san" started airing in 1969 and has not stopped.
Scott: -Nope.
Rym: -But, yeah, even "The Simpsons" is a fairly difficult challenge.
Rym: "The Simpsons" has been airing continuously for all -- for pretty much as long as I've been alive because I watched it continuously up until it got bad, and I stopped in season 12.
Scott: -"The Simpsons" started when I was in, like, fourth or fifth grade.
Rym: -Yep.
Rym: I even saw the "Tracy Ullman Show" stuff before "The Simpsons" came out.
Scott: -That's why I said fourth or fifth.
Scott: I think the actual show was fifth.
Scott: -Yeah.
Scott: -Great.
Scott: Anyway.
Rym: -So, anyway, that's all.
Rym: So, the anime industry is gonna have trouble just like every other industry is, but, thankfully, so many things were far enough along in the pipeline to where there is still a lot of new and newish content that we're gonna get.
Rym: And, also, honestly, if you're running out of stuff to watch, there's a lot of great anime just, like, randomly on Crunchyroll that you might have never thought to watch.
Rym: Like, that was the time to go into the backlog.
Scott: -Oh, I just remembered one more news that I didn't send Rym a link for, but I did post it in our forum, so you should come to our forum, and you would have gotten this news early.
Rym: -'Cause I got a bunch more news I can crank out.
Scott: -Okay, no, just a short one.
Scott: -All right.
Scott: -So, Jeff Lemire, favorite comic writer of "GeekNights," did, a while ago, when Vertigo Comics was still a thing, did a series called "Sweet Teeth" that I own all of.
Rym: -Oh, yeah, I only read the beginning of that.
Rym: I never read it anymore.
Rym: -Yeah.
Scott: I have all the volumes.
Scott: I didn't finish it, but I will.
Scott: I enjoyed every page that I did read of it.
Rym: -It gave me that Jeff Lemire feeling.
Scott: -Yeah, so, that series is being made for Netflix, supposedly.
Scott: We'll see how far along that gets, but it looks like, you know, I think someone else had, like, paid to do it and then ended up not doing it, and now Netflix is paying somebody to produce.
Scott: I think it's gonna be live-action, not animated, but it's still based on a comic book, right?
Scott: So, that's gonna be pretty interesting, and I think it might get people to read the book, as usually happens.
Rym: -Yep, DC Comics Suite 2, the set to be adapted to Netflix by Robert Downey
Rym: Jr.'
Rym: 's production company.
Scott: -Yep, there you go.
Scott: So, that's gonna be fascinating.
Scott: Give me "The
Scott: Descender.".
Scott: "The Descender" -- -Oh,
Scott: "Driller."
Scott: -That would make me watch a TV show as if you made -- I've already read the whole thing,
Scott: "Descender.".
Rym: -Oh, I have not, but I do know that the thing I know that I know will just keep coming up, the Chekhov's "Driller," because "Driller" is a goddamn killer.
Scott: -"Killer" is a real killer.
Rym: Real killer.
Scott: Let me tell you, you don't even know.
Rym: -Speaking of killers, Scott talked about this.
Rym: I'm not gonna belabor the point, but I'm catching up on
Rym: "Castlevania.".
Rym: I just watched all of season two.
Rym: All I will say is that I did not expect certain things to be resolved so quickly and relatively easily.
Scott: -Season two is a lot -- Season two is a lot, like, extravagant, right?
Scott: "Dracula's Castle," "Dracula," big bad guys, right?
Rym: -Season two, you said this, but I just have to reiterate.
Rym: Season two escalates rapidly, and when a character's like, "I'm gonna do the thing," and the thing is something ridiculous and crazy, you might think, "Okay, that's the arc,".
Rym: and then they do it in the next scene.
Scott: -Season two is definitely made.
Scott: You could tell when they were making it.
Scott: This could be the last season, right?
Scott: So they had to do the big ending.
Scott: -It could have been the last season.
Scott: -Yeah, and still leave opening for a third.
Scott: The third season, it definitely feels like it was made knowing there was gonna be a fourth season.
Scott: It's just a bridge, right?
Scott: The third season is all the characters left over from the second season are all separated, and you're skipping and looking.
Scott: The camera's switching between the different groups of characters, seeing what they're up to.
Rym: -It's an old trope, but I love the hell out of that trope.
Scott: -But they do not converge in a snatch moment.
Scott: The season three ends, and the snatch moment is clearly early in season four, if not the very beginning of season four.
Rym: -And based on now that I know more about the threads of, like, all those different bits, I'm real excited for season three, which I'm gonna watch pretty quick.
Scott: -Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Rym: -All right, so I guess now it's time for... Things of the Day!
Rym: So, speaking of annoy-a-trons, there was an old toy called a Sing-a-ma-jig.
Rym: I got to look up exactly when this thing came out.
Rym: It was, like, early 2000s or maybe early 2010s.
Rym: Like, it's this old --.
Scott: -I mean, the name definitely sounds like the name of an old toy, but I've never heard of it before, and I didn't have any memory of it whatsoever, and I searched for it, and I'm like, "Okay, there it
Scott: is.".
Rym: -So, the story is that supposedly -- Like, basically, it's a little doll, and you're like -- Every time you squeeze the doll, it'll sing, like, one more word in a song that's programmed into it, and that's it.
Rym: That's what it does.
Scott: -So, it's not Teddy Ruxpin with a cassette player in his ass.
Rym: -Do you?
Rym: You can, like, control the rate that it sings, and its mouth will move, and, like, that's pretty much it.
Rym: But there was a promotional, special, limited-edition one that was made to sing the All-Star song, and the little Sing-a-ma-jig is wearing the suspenders and the black shirt and the tie.
Scott: -Okay.
Rym: -And it's really hard to find.
Rym: So, Hank Green --.
Scott: -So, you went on eBay and got one, or you made one?
Rym: -So, Hank Green, like, told John Green that this thing existed, and then John Green, like, waited his mission to find one of them, and he got one, and there's a video of him playing it and then him explaining the deal with it, and that's my thing of the day.
Rym: You're an All-Star.
Rym: -Okay.
Rym: -And the video ends with someone else got a bunch of Sing-a-ma-jigs, reprogrammed them, and then made them sing an All-Star chorus with all the parts.
Scott: -All right.
Scott: So, this is a thing of the day that would be best for Monday or Tuesday, but you know what?
Scott: You're getting it on Wednesday.
Scott: Deal with it, right?
Scott: So, here's a YouTube channel called Some Computer Guy that only has 309 subscribers.
Rym: -It's got 310 as of dateline now, and guess what?
Scott: -Whoa.
Scott: And, basically, this guy, he -- You know, a lot of people know about old computers with vacuum tubes or paper tape or punch cards, right?
Scott: But few people have actually seen those or know how to operate them.
Scott: -Yep.
Scott: -Right?
Scott: I don't know how to operate one.
Scott: I would need to read a manual and get help.
Rym: -I learned in RIT --.
Scott: -Even though I know the principle behind the mechanism of computation that it uses, right, I don't know the physical interface and how to use the machine.
Rym: -There was an Altair emulator that was, like, in a web browser that I remember we found when we were at RIT.
Scott: -That's at least -- Oh, Altair, right.
Rym: -Yeah, but I did learn it enough.
Rym: Like, I made it do a thing, and then I was bored with that and done with it.
Scott: -Yeah, this would actually be quite similar to an Altair with a row of switches on the front, only this is, like, an Altair was a home PC, right?
Scott: So you could think of, like, an Altair being basically, like, one of these for the home, sort of, right?
Scott: Anyway, so this computer he's got is a cell, an SEL-810A.
Scott: It was used for a lot of things back in the '60s.
Scott: This particular one he's got was used for managing the pressure of, like, a gas pipeline somewhere, and it was in operation between 1969 and 2006.
Rym: -Okay, so this computer started operation the same year that Sunlight-san started airing.
Scott: -Sure, yes.
Scott: But, yeah, so he's got this computer.
Scott: He knows how to fix it.
Scott: He did fix it.
Scott: -Whoa.
Scott: -And in this video, he shows you it working.
Scott: He fast-forwards the slow parts.
Scott: He has to punch in the binary to load.
Scott: 'Cause first he has to -- When you turn your computer on, you have, like, a BIOS or UFI, and then you have a master boot record, right?
Scott: So the computer turns on, and it can sort of start itself.
Scott: -Yep.
Scott: -Right?
Rym: -Computers didn't used to do that.
Scott: -You turn on.
Scott: Right, this computer turns on, and it's nothing.
Scott: So the first thing you need to do is input a program by hand to tell it how to load things.
Rym: -Yep, I had to do that.
Scott: -The loading program.
Rym: -I did that a handful of times at IBM.
Scott: -It has absolutely no memory whatsoever when it's been off.
Scott: You turn it on.
Scott: You input the loading program on the switches.
Scott: Then you can load programs, right?
Scott: -Yep.
Rym: -Well, then you had to do the IPL, the initial program load.
Rym: That is, initializing the computer with anything.
Scott: -Right, exactly.
Scott: So he shows you him doing all that, and he's got on tape, right?
Scott: First, he loads in the basic compiler, right?
Scott: Because it doesn't have that.
Scott: And then he loads in, he has to patch it because it's written for a slightly different computer.
Scott: So he has to manually edit it after it's loaded into the memory.
Scott: And then he loads in Lunar Lander off of paper tape, and then he plays Lunar Lander on the terminal, which is pretty awesome.
Rym: -This is amazing.
Scott: -Yeah, it's great.
Rym: -In the meantime, we're stuck at home.
Rym: We're doing the show remotely.
Rym: We're doing live streams on YouTube.
Rym: You can watch them.
Rym: There's some people watching this one right now.
Rym: The pipeline seems fine.
Rym: People keep making this point, and I've watched a bunch of professional video game people and sports people.
Rym: All the people who are professionals, who do this kind of thing for a living, who are stuck at home and are trying to make content at home, and across the board, they all have the worst possible quality and also often aren't that entertaining.
Rym: I feel like without their writers and their technology, they have a lot of trouble.
Rym: But it's all just blown-out mics and nonsense.
Rym: So I can at least say that even if our content is not as great as some of those people you love, we will at least have a high production quality.
Scott: -Well, could you imagine being a pro video guy, right?
Scott: And normally, your job is to make all the video, and you're behind the camera, and there's professional -- there's, like, actors or famous people in front of the camera, and they just show up and do their thing.
Scott: You put microphones on them, right, with your hands.
Scott: You go up in their coat and stuff, right?
Scott: And now that person's at home.
Scott: You mail them a bunch of stuff, and you have to get them to do it on their own without fucking up.
Scott: -Yep.
Scott: -And all they do is see your face and hear your voice, and you have to explain to them what to press, what to do.
Rym: Right?
Rym: -The other day, we were watching or listening to and watching this live stream that some people were doing, a sports thing, and one of them, their mic was clipping, like, so bad.
Rym: It was crazy, and the comments in their stream was just a sea of, "Dude, fix your mic.
Rym: Here are links to what clipping is.
Rym: Please, please, please fix your
Rym: mic.".
Rym: But the guy was getting increasingly salty and mad that his fans were yelling at him for his clipping mic, so he was clipping even more, and it was just, like, this weird feedback loop.
Scott: -Ew.
Rym: -I think that the real difference is, well, like you said, if we had a production company, I would probably never fuck around with cameras again in my life.
Rym: I would just let someone else do that, and I'd probably start forgetting how to do things.
Scott: -I do have a friend who's an acquaintance who's very camera-y, and I've thought about getting them to come over.
Scott: They posted, like, "Hey, I'm looking for freelance videoing work," and I was like, "Oh, maybe I'll have them come over to do, like, one fancy project or
Scott: something.".
Rym: -The sad part is the thing I would want people to do the most -- -And now I can't have anyone come over.
Rym: -The thing I want people to do the most would be follow us around a PAX and, like, record a lot of the games we play so we can then have the footage.
Scott: -This friend would do that for enough money.
Rym: -That we could do, but part of that is, when we're doing our panel, I'd like them to actually operate the camera, but the union in four of the five PAXes we would go to would not let someone touch our camera while we're on stage
Scott: because we would have
Rym: to pay the convention center to put their camera person on our camera.
Scott: -I know, but this friend would, for example, you know, come over, help me set up the lighting, right, give me advice because they're better video than me, right, operate the several cameras to record me from angles and edit the video, right, and all that, you know, put the graphics on it and stuff.
Scott: So that would be well worth paying for, but that plan is dead for a while.
Rym: -Even when things start to open up, most likely you might see me and Scott doing content together in one of our apartments again, but we're not gonna be inviting third parties into that mix anytime soon.
Scott: -Undone third parties, right?
Scott: -Yeah.
Scott: -It's like, I know Rym hasn't left his house, and he knows I haven't left my house, right, so we can sort of trust, right, that we're, you know, at equal risk here, right?
Rym: -So, otherwise, you know, the booklet book is still the tale of Hanzo.
Rym: We'll get to it when we get to it.
Scott: -Hanzo.
Rym: -I'm playing a lot of Overwatch.
Scott: -The sword maker.
Scott: I'm pretty sure it's not the sword maker.
Rym: It's the --.
Rym: -Hanzo and Genji.
Scott: -The sex haver.
Rym: -So, yeah, follow us in all the places, especially our forum.
Rym: Hang out in there.
Rym: Hang out in our Discord.
Rym: There's stuff going on, and we're gonna talk about something we haven't talked about in a long time, a webcomic.
Scott: -So it's sort of a webcomic.
Scott: If you don't know, there's a company called Naver, N-A-V-E-R.
Scott: It's spelled like naval, like your belly button naval, only you replace the R with an L, and this Naver is basically Google in South Korea, right?
Scott: It's like they are everything in South Korea.
Scott: You know, like, it's shocking how much of the South Korean Internet is Naver.
Scott: It's the same amount of the Internet in the US that's Google and Amazon, a lot, right?
Scott: Like, there'll be websites you go to, and it's like, "Oh, that's -- It doesn't even look like it's a Naver
Scott: site.".
Scott: It's like, "Oh, yeah, Naver runs
Scott: that.".
Scott: Yep.
Scott: Okay.
Scott: So one of the websites they run that is actually a worldwide website is this Webtoons site.
Scott: So webcomics are actually kind of big in South Korea, bigger than they are in the United States, at least relative to the country, right?
Scott: So, for example, you know, what's a big webcomic in the US, right?
Scott: Like, you know, Penny Arcade is big, right?
Rym: -Art of the Stake is bigger than it looks.
Scott: -Yeah, exactly, right?
Scott: But a big webcomic in Korea would have the prominence that a big newspaper comic would have in the US in the '90s.
Scott: So, like, I have seen on Korean television webcomic artists on television, right, where normally you would see in the US, like -- -Like Penny Arcade -- -Jim Davis from
Scott: "Garfield.".
Rym: -Yeah, but, like, Penny Arcade might be one of the most, like, lucrative webcomics in American history.
Scott: -Right, but it has no prominence on television, mainstream, whatever.
Rym: -Yeah, Leno wasn't gonna interview Mike and Jerry.
Scott: -Gabe and Tycho aren't on -- Right, like, an NBC talk show.
Scott: They're not even "Good Morning America" level.
Rym: -Yeah, the press at New York Comic-Con wouldn't even mention they were there.
Scott: -Right, exactly.
Rym: -So, they made their own comic-con.
Rym: Anyway.
Scott: -Right, but webcomics have that level of popularity there.
Scott: You know, a lot of people read them on their phones, I think.
Scott: So, Webtoons is a site, Naver Webtoons.
Scott: It's actually an international site.
Scott: You don't have to read any Korean whatsoever.
Scott: And you can make an account or not.
Scott: Making an account helps you sort of save your spot, right, in your different comics.
Rym: -Which is real important.
Scott: -Yep.
Rym: -That's why I stopped reading a lot of webcomics, 'cause I forget where I was, then I forget to go to the site 'cause I didn't bookmark it, and then I'm done.
Rym: -Right.
Scott: There's nice apps for it on your phone or your tablet or whatever.
Scott: You can publish your own comics on the site.
Scott: And I think that, you know, I don't know all the details of it, but there are lots of extremely high-quality color comics on here that are, like -- The format of a lot of them is basically long-paid.
Rym: -Which that's part of why I think it's interesting to talk about this, because a lot of webcomics tended to, especially in the early days, have either the four-panel format or they'd be formatted in a way that could then be put in a book later.
Rym: These comics, very much like it feels right to read them on a screen.
Scott: -These were designed to be read on your phone.
Scott: It's a long thing.
Scott: So, you go to say, "Here, I'll pick a random
Scott: one.".
Rym: -I picked a random one.
Rym: I'm scrolling down in the stream, too.
Scott: -In the bleak midwinter, right, it looks like angsty dude in snow with some sci-fi and whatever, right?
Scott: And you click, and first of all, it's separated into episodes, which are separated into seasons, right?
Scott: So, and each episode is one page, one vertically long page, and you just scroll down and down and down as you read the page, and that's the episode.
Scott: And then several of those will make up a season, and the creator will, you know, release, like, page, page, page -- episode, episode, episode -- on a regular schedule until the season is over, and then there'll be a break while this next season is getting ready, right?
Scott: And that's the format of pretty much all of these.
Scott: The creators are getting money for these.
Scott: I don't know if it's based on popularity or if they're being contracted or whatever, but I think it's actually a good deal based on what I've heard.
Scott: The artists who are working and making "Webtoons" seem to be happy with it.
Scott: I haven't seen them complaining and saying it's no good.
Scott: And there's a lot of readers, right?
Scott: Some of these comics, it's like the one I just mentioned, "Randomly,".
Scott: it has 334,000 hearts, right?
Scott: There is one called "True Beauty," some romance one.
Scott: 20.1 million hearts, right?
Scott: My giant nerd boyfriend, 31.8 million hearts.
Scott: So there's millions of people using this app, if you're not aware of it, to read comics in this format.
Rym: -And think about this, 'cause webcomics, they're, like, they're their own thing, and especially as paper media is in decline, where do people want to read stuff?
Rym: There's no good way to read traditional comics on technology yet.
Rym: Like, all the readers that exist, even tablets, there's not a great experience in many cases, but...
Scott: -That's why I buy the paper ones.
Rym: -But this format, if you design it for the format that most people will access it in, it just works, and it's great.
Rym: I think a lot of people don't even think about that.
Scott: -The quality is extremely high art-wise, right?
Scott: It's like you scroll down the page with, like, list of comics, and every single thumbnail looks like it was made by, like, one of the best artists in the artist alley at the convention.
Rym: -There's got to be a bad comic in there somewhere, but...
Scott: -That one might be meh, but it might be funny, though.
Scott: Anyway, and the comics are extremely diverse, covering so many genres and, you know, styles and types of characters and all sorts of crazy stuff.
Scott: Anyway, today, we want to talk about just one of these, right, even though there's so many of them, done by someone we've been a fan of for a long time, Katie Cook.
Scott: If you don't know, Katie Cook is someone who's been in the U.S.
Scott: Comics Convention art scene for a long time.
Scott: Katie Cook did a lot of the early official licensed My Little Pony comics.
Rym: -I think she's a big part of why that comic was so good.
Rym: early on, like, she set a tone.
Rym: She did cover art for it and writing.
Scott: -Yep, Katie Cook has done -- When you go to conventions, she'll do this thing where she makes a tiny watercolor on these little cards that are very cute.
Scott: She, for a long time, if you went to the store, it's about a collectible card series.
Scott: Like, let's say you were buying Indiana Jones trading cards, right, because those were a thing.
Scott: You know, you buy them, and these collectible cards that don't do anything, they're not like baseball cards.
Scott: They're just like pictures from the movies or whoever, right?
Scott: And then, randomly, if you were super lucky, what they were doing to promote these trading card sets was they would randomly insert cards into the packs that had hand-drawn art.
Scott: Like, the artist drew on that card.
Scott: They gave the artist a blank white card that they painted or drew on, and then they sent those back to the company, and they shuffled them in with all the manufactured printed cards.
Scott: And if you're lucky, you would get one of those.
Scott: Katie Cook did a lot of those in various trading card sets.
Scott: She's done some books, a lot of Star Wars licensed art.
Scott: I think she did books like ABC 3PO, like a little children's Star Wars book.
Rym: - Yep, Gronk is what a lot of people, I think, would know Katie's work from.
Scott: - Yeah, Gronk was her webcomic that she did on her own, right, just like I think on her own website.
Scott: I don't even think it was with another website at all.
Scott: But anyway, the thing we're talking about today is her webtoon, right, which is called Nothing Special.
Scott: Its third season just started, so there are two seasons to read.
Scott: Just like all these other webtoons, each page is really long.
Scott: The two seasons have like 30 something-ish chapters, I guess, each.
Scott: So you can read it all pretty quickly.
Scott: I read it all in like a few days.
Rym: - And I think one main thing I like about it is that all webcomics, especially like when they start, have to do their sort of like establishing origin, like who are these characters, why do you care about them?
Rym: But a lot of them sort of, like a lot of amateur ones tend to fail in that they'll spend so long doing that that everyone loses interest, or like they never get to the part they wanted to get to and then their career changes or anything.
Scott: This moves-- - Right, or the Naruto can happen where that establishing part is good or bad, right?
Scott: And then when they switch, they sort of switch modes to the actual story and you don't like one or the other.
Scott: So if you don't like the first part, you don't get to the story.
Scott: And if you don't like the story, you fall off once you're done with the beginning part, which is Naruto, right?
Scott: Naruto is like, "Funny ninja school, yes.
Scott: "Tournaments, I'm
Scott: done.".
Scott: Forget this.
Rym: - Yuhaka Show, I even was tricked for a few episodes.
Scott: - Exactly, Yuhaka Show, before they start having tournaments is an amazing A+ shounen show.
Scott: After that, it's just like, "Okay, fighting, what
Scott: else?".
Rym: - But this one, but nothing special moves pretty-- - Is something special.
Rym: - It's good.
Rym: It moves quick past that establishing thing and gets right to its sort of kickoff plot.
Rym: And it's very consistent in quality.
Rym: Like it just moves at a good steady pace.
Rym: You never get bored with it.
Rym: Like as I read, or as I read, I haven't read season three yet, secrets are revealed early enough to keep it going and to keep it interesting.
Scott: - Right, it's not like there isn't really, like with a lot of other stories, right?
Scott: There's usually like a big secretive space.
Scott: And while they go through the smaller stories, right?
Scott: It's like, "No, just get to the big story, right?
Scott: "X-Files, just tell me about the fucking smoking
Scott: man.".
Rym: - Until he did, and then please, I wish I didn't know about the smoking man.
Rym: That is so dumb.
Scott: - Right, it's like, you know, but it's the same feeling you usually get, right?
Scott: With nothing special, it's like the big story isn't really a thing.
Scott: There's a big setting that has mysteries about it, right?
Scott: Like what's the deal with this, right?
Scott: But there isn't like a big bad guy.
Scott: There isn't a big threat really of any kind.
Rym: - Not to spoil anything, but the deal with her mom.
Rym: Like she lives alone with her dad, the main character, and there's magic afoot, obviously.
Rym: It's a fantasy thing.
Rym: There's like the real normal world.
Rym: And then there's the fantasy world.
Rym: And there's some reason why multiple magical non-human people just happen to live in the normal world.
Rym: Like there's a whole setting here, but like the mystery is her dad disappears, and then you meet her mom, and her mom's deal is just very like interesting and environmental.
Scott: - And then, but that's take, it's like, you know, you would think, oh, whenever there's like a missing family member, that's like a big deal, right?
Scott: It's like, no, they just take care of that.
Rym: - Like right away, like, oh.
Scott: - And season one, and they take care of it fully.
Rym: - That's where dad went.
Scott: - It's like, they don't, right.
Scott: It's like, they don't leave it hanging.
Scott: It's like, oh, here it is, solved.
Scott: Boom, done, move on.
Rym: - The mystery, and I'm just avoiding, I don't want to spoil it, 'cause it's short.
Rym: Like just read it.
Rym: But the mystery of that, like that bit about her parents and like how she came to be is very straightforward.
Rym: It's not like a big secret of space.
Rym: It's just like, oh, I guess that happened.
Rym: Like dad met this person and that's what happened.
Rym: And this isn't like a big epic plot.
Rym: This is just going to resolve itself.
Rym: - It's hard to talk about it in any circumspect way, unfortunately.
Scott: - Right, so also it's like usually in shows when there's like a romance situation, right?
Scott: The romance is like very like, ooh, are they going to kiss?
Rym: - Miyaka, Tomohome, it doesn't get to that for like 40 episodes.
Scott: - Right, nothing special.
Scott: It's like, all right, you know, there's some romance back and forth thing going on, but then boom, they kissing, right?
Scott: And then they basically don't stop kissing.
Scott: They're always kissing and people are like, oh, come on.
Rym: - That was like the anime with the big guy and the smaller girl and they start dating.
Scott: - Exactly, my love story.
Rym: - Yes, my love story.
Rym: The fact that they start dating and try to make it work right away is the only reason that show was good.
Scott: - Right, they start dating pretty quickly in this, right?
Scott: And they keep on dating and you know, they don't keep it a secret from anybody.
Scott: They don't, you know.
Rym: - It's, I guess one of the thing I like about Nothing Special.
Rym: specifically without like spoiling anything is kind of that.
Rym: It just, it skips past what would normally be in like a typical more amateur web comic, a full arc.
Rym: Like they'll spend a year telling the story of how they fell in love.
Scott: - Right, well, I think the number one thing is that you never get that situation where someone's not saying something just because, right?
Scott: It's like people say stuff to each other and things keep moving along.
Scott: No one's really, some of the characters are weird 'cause they're in a fantasy world.
Scott: Like the little fairy old man.
Rym: - Yeah, but I like those characters because they're weird, but they're not just like hiding the big secret.
Rym: Like, oh, I'll tell you when you're older and then like it's a big mystery.
Rym: It's like, oh, here's the deal.
Scott: - Right, well, there's the demon guy who doesn't want to talk about his demon family, but it's like, he tells you about the demon family.
Scott: He's like, yeah, they're bad.
Scott: It's not like, he's not like hiding.
Scott: Like, oh no, my family's, you know.
Scott: It's like, yeah, you know the deal basically.
Scott: He's like, oh shit, that's my brother.
Scott: He's evil, watch out.
Scott: Anyway, he's a demon.
Scott: I'm basically the only good demon.
Rym: - And I'm not even that good.
Scott: - Demon brothers, yeah.
Scott: Right?
Scott: Yeah, it's, you know, in other things, right?
Scott: It's like, you know, when there are mysteries, like, oh, he's got the, it's like they foreshadow a little bit of mystery or like a little Chekhov's guns here and there, like he's got a pink broken wing, Chekhov's gun, that gun fires in a few pages.
Scott: And it's like, boom, there it is.
Scott: It's not like Chekhov's gun's hanging on the wall.
Scott: Chekhov's gun's always in someone's hand, right?
Scott: When it gets pulled out, it's in the hand and then it fires, there's no--.
Rym: - Maybe it's 'cause I just watched it, but aspects of that are part of what I liked about "Castlevania" season two as well, in that it's like a character learned something and the next scene is that character, like either telling everyone who needs to know it or doing a thing based on that information.
Scott: - Right, so we gotta talk about everyone's favorite character, the radish, radishes.
Scott: - So there's these little, so basically in the, it's a fantasy world situation where there's a real world and a fantasy world and they're connected, but unlike "Escaflowne," it's not like one of those, what do they call it, transported to another world situations.
Scott: It's like the worlds are connected and they can freely move between them and it's not a big deal.
Rym: - Like she could just go home any time.
Scott: - Yeah, it's like, it's not a thing, right?
Scott: It's taking care of immediately.
Rym: - And it also, there's no central mystery of why is this other world?
Rym: Like it's just part of the world.
Rym: That's just how the world is.
Scott: - There are two worlds, but you need magic to go between them, but her dad is a magic dude so they can't.
Rym: - Not like "Escaflowne" where like someone going between the worlds is like an entire arc of a story.
Scott: - Right, everyone else in the human world doesn't know.
Scott: Presumably, most of them don't know there's another world or worlds and everyone in the magic world doesn't really have a reason to go to the real world.
Rym: - They know about it.
Scott: - Real human world.
Rym: - Like a lot of them know about it and just don't care about it.
Scott: - Yeah, it's like, why would they go to the not magic world?
Scott: Whatever, I guess it's a lot of effort and no reason to do it.
Scott: I imagine at some point they might do, there's no foreshadowing for this whatsoever, but I could see when they need more plots, do the old cliche, bad guys, demons, go to the real human world plot, right?
Scott: That's always a good one.
Scott: - That happens.
Rym: I mean, Inuyasha had that.
Scott: - There's absolutely no, right.
Scott: But anyway, so this is radishes, which are like ghosts of dead vegetables.
Rym: - And the main character for reasons can see them and communicate with them.
Scott: - Right, so some characters can see them and some can't, but the main character can, and they sort of semi-worship the main character?
Rym: - Yep, that's sort of the theme of the show is that people will worship the main character for reasons that aren't entirely explained and all characters in the world sort of assume that everyone knows the deal and talk about it like, "Oh, of course everyone worships
Rym: her.".
Scott: - Right, and she doesn't know what the deal is 'cause she's grown up in the not-magic world and only came to the magic world somewhat recently.
Scott: It doesn't even know that much magic yet, but she has inborn magic, right?
Scott: She thinks she's nothing special, but she's like super special.
Rym: - And a lot of the themes just seem to follow that idea of what does it mean to be special and what is special?
Scott: - Yep, so yeah, if you are looking for web comics to read and most of the web comics you read ended, Dr.
Scott: Vignetja, or are hard-to-read websites.
Rym: - Or don't update that frequently.
Scott: - Even if they're-- - Order the stick.
Scott: - Right, or they're just on Twitter, like Penny Arcade or whatever, and you read one strip in like, it's a little tiny three-panel thing, and you're not getting your long story situation, right?
Scott: And you don't wanna pay for graphic novels on paper or comixology 'cause that costs a lot of money.
Scott: You just wanna read something long-form comics for free in English with lots and lots of choices, lots and lots of content, stuff you won't see published by Marvel, DC, or even manga publishers, Shonen Jump, whoever.
Scott: This is the place to go.
Rym: - And you can read these without buying anything?
Rym: You can read these without going outside?
Scott: - You can read 'em on your tablet, read 'em on your phone.
Scott: Totally free.
Scott: I highly recommend the site, especially the comic, Nothing Special, which is the one that I have read the most of on this site.
Scott: But yeah, a Webtoons, Naver Webtoons is the stuff.
Rym: - All right.
Scott: - There you go.
Rym: - This has been GeekNights with Rym and Scott.
Rym: Special thanks to DJ Pretzel for the opening music, Kat Lee for web design, and Brando K for the logos.
Scott: - Be sure to visit our website at frontrowcrew.com for show notes, discussion news, and more.
Rym: - Remember, GeekNights is not one, but four different shows.
Rym: Sci-Tech Mondays, Gaming Tuesdays, Anime Comic Wednesdays, and Indiscriminate Thursdays.
Scott: - GeekNights is distributed under a Creative Commons Attribution 3.0 license.
Scott: GeekNights is recorded live with no studio and no audience.
Scott: But unlike those other late shows, it's actually recorded at night.
Rym: - And the Patreon patrons for this episode of GeekNights are Alan Joyce, Heidi McNichol, Marty Gradius, just like a dude, Guy Chartobish, and Link Ege, you hold the key to my heart.
Rym: But she packed my suitcase and sent me on my way.
Rym: Clinton Walton, Jay Banch, friend from New Zealand, Ryan Parent, Drew Openlander, Nicholas Brando, Sailor Vista, The Thirst, For Hydrated Ganon, Dread Lily, Tenebrae, Chris Reimer, Finn, Sean Klein, Shervin Van Horl, and a bunch of people who don't want me to say their name.
Rym: We are continuing to work on stuff.
Rym: I know I say that every night, but we are still working on stuff.
Rym: You'll see our pipeline get better and better.
Rym: The quality of our streams is improving a little bit.
Rym: We're tweaking some stuff.
Rym: I sent back that dodgy RTMP device that I think I talked about on a Monday show.
Rym: But all that aside, right now, I leave you with something that some of you will remember, but I suspect many of you are too young for.
Rym: - Code Z, code Z 1212.
Rym: Code Z 1212.
Rym: Code Z, code Z 1212.
Scott: - These people, these people, these people shot the faith.
Scott: These people, these people, these people shot the faith.
Rym: These people- These people- These people start to fade!
Rym: (Fade me!lett).
Rym: These people start to FADE ME!
Rym: (I can't handle it).
Rym: C-C-C-C-C-C-call me on my cell phone!
Scott: (I get
Scott: busy!).
Rym: These people start to FADE ME!
Rym: (I can't handle
Rym: it!).
Scott: C-C-C-C-C-call me on my cell phone!
Rym: (I get
Rym: busy!).
Rym: Coach Z's got money, but not much!
Rym: I could use a dollar, I could use a couple bucks, I'm so old school.
Scott: (1-2-1-2) They tore the school downward!
Scott: (1-2-1-2) Where my lazer's at?
Scott: Where my lasers at, y'all?
Rym: Where my lasers at?
Scott: All the people tried to tell me where my lasers at.
Scott: And your mother tried to show me all the laser crabs.
Scott: And I got a bunch of types of laser dabs.
Rym: These people tried to fade me.
Rym: I can't handle it.
Rym: Call me on my cell phone.
Scott: I get busy.
Scott: These people tried to fade me.
Scott: I can't handle it.
Scott: Call me on my cell phone.
Rym: I get busy.
Rym: I got to see the sweet doctor.
Rym: I'm doctor sweet.
Rym: I got the grown up beats.
Scott: I'm doctor sweet.
Scott: I got the grown up beats.
Rym: I'm doctor, doctor, doctor beats.
Rym: These people, these people, these people tried to fade.
Scott: I can float.
Scott: One, two, one, two.
Scott: I can freak.
Scott: I can freak and flow at the same time.